<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>The case for ending Amazon’s dominance</title>
<link>http://timharford.com/2018/02/the-case-for-ending-amazons-dominance/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://timharford.com/2018/02/the-case-for-ending-amazons-dominance/</guid>
<description>&lt;a href=&quot;http://timharford.com/articles/undercovereconomist/&quot; title=&quot;Undercover Economist&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;article-perm&quot; src=&quot;http://timharford.com/wp-content/themes/timharford-v4/img//icon-ue.png&quot; width=&quot;36&quot; height=&quot;36&quot; alt=&quot;Undercover Economist&quot; title=&quot;Undercover Economist&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;h2&gt;The case for ending Amazon’s dominance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should not be difficult to love Amazon. To consumers, it offers choice and convenience. Countless internet ventures have relied on its cheap, flexible cloud computing services to start and scale up. Amazon makes titans such as Walmart work hard for their revenue, offers a shopping search engine that is Google’s only serious rival, raises the bar for television networks and sells tablet computers at a price to make Apple loyalists stop and think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon is also giving the US economy what it needs. Two economists, Germán Gutiérrez and Thomas Philippon, have argued that corporate America is underinvesting. One reason is that companies are impatiently funnelling cash to investors and executives rather than take a long-term view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If that is a worrisome state of affairs — and it should be — then Amazon is the shining counterexample. The online retailer’s strategy is driven not by short-term profit but by investment, innovation and growth. If only there were a few more companies like Amazon, capitalism would be in a happier spot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there’s the rub: there aren’t more companies like it. It’s unique, and an increasingly terrifying force in online commerce. Should regulators act? If so, how? It’s worth first disposing of a bad argument: that Amazon must be challenged because it makes life miserable for its competitors, some of which are plucky mom-and-pop operations. However emotionally appealing this might seem, it should not be the business of regulators to prop up such businesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regulators have a tendency to slip into the role of protecting incumbents with surprising ease. Marc Levinson’s history of container shipping, &lt;em&gt;The Box &lt;/em&gt;(&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/2Drf8Dh&quot;&gt;UK&lt;/a&gt;) (&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/2DmO97u&quot;&gt;US&lt;/a&gt;), describes Malcom McLean — the entrepreneur behind containerisation, a risk-taking visionary reminiscent of Amazon’s founder Jeff Bezos. When McLean tried to expand his operations, one of his largest obstacles was the Interstate Commerce Commission in the US, which regulated US railways from 1887 and interstate trucking from 1935.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ICC, writes Mr Levinson, had to approve each new route, every new commodity and any new price schedule. When McLean wanted to start a trucking route at a low price, he had to hire lawyers and argue his case at the ICC, while his competitors protested bitterly — “unfair and destructive”, said the railways. He did not always get his way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Antitrust authorities should not be in the business of making life easy for incumbents. What, then, should they do? There are two schools of thought. One is to focus on consumers’ interest in quality, variety and price. This has been the standard approach in US antitrust policy for several decades. Since Amazon makes slim profits and charges low prices, it raises few antitrust questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The alternative view — which harks back to an earlier era of antitrust during which Standard Oil and later AT&amp;amp;T were broken up — argues that competition is inherently good even if it is hard to quantify a benefit to consumers and that society should be wary of large or dominant companies even if their behaviour seems benign. The collapse of companies from Lehman Brothers to construction services business Carillion reminds us that size can be a problem when a company is weak as well as when it is strong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The narrowing in antitrust thinking is described by Lina Khan in a much-read article, “Amazon’s Antitrust Paradox”. Ms Khan berates modern antitrust thinking for its “hostility to false positives”, arguing that it has become incapable of saying anything insightful about modern tech companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike Ms Khan, I share modern antitrust’s hostility to false positives; there is a real cost to cumbersome and unnecessary meddling in a dynamic and rapidly-evolving marketplace. Donald Trump’s history of publicly attacking Mr Bezos is worth pondering too: do we really want the US government to have more discretion as to who is targeted, and why? We should not wish to return to a world in which a plucky new competitor must beg regulators — over the objections of incumbents — for permission to cut prices. We should be grateful that Mr Bezos did not face in the 1990s the regulatory obstacles that Malcom McLean dodged in the 1950s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet for all this, I am deeply uneasy about Amazon’s apparently unassailable position in online retail. Yes, customers are being well served at the moment. Yet the company has acquired formidable entrenched advantages, from the information about customers and the suppliers who sell through it, to the bargaining power it has over delivery companies, to the vast network of warehouses. Those advantages were earned, but they can also be abused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Antitrust authorities face a difficult balancing act. Regulate Amazon and you may snuff out the innovation that we all say we want more of. Punish it for success and you send a strange message to entrepreneurs and investors. Ignore it and you risk leaving vital services in the hands of an invincible monopolist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are no easy options, but it is time to look for a way to split Amazon into two independent companies, each with the strength to grow and invest. If Amazon is such a wonderful company, wouldn’t two Amazons be even better?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written for and first published in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ft.com/content/aba8d444-fb94-11e7-a492-2c9be7f3120a&quot;&gt;Financial Times&lt;/a&gt; on 19 January 2018.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;My recent book is “Fifty Inventions That Shaped The Modern Economy”. Grab yourself a copy in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/2q2Tdq8&quot;&gt;US&lt;/a&gt; or in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/2rye7jg&quot;&gt;UK&lt;/a&gt; (slightly different title) or through your local bookshop.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;robots-nocontent sd-block sd-social sd-social-icon sd-sharing&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Share this:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 15:02:09 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>imartin2k</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>The case for ending Amazon’s dominance</og:title>
<og:url>http://timharford.com/2018/02/the-case-for-ending-amazons-dominance/</og:url>
<og:description>It should not be difficult to love Amazon. To consumers, it offers choice and convenience. Countless internet ventures have relied on its cheap, flexible cloud computing services to start and scale…</og:description>
<og:image>https://s0.wp.com/i/blank.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://timharford.com/2018/02/the-case-for-ending-amazons-dominance/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How UK Spies Hacked a European Ally and Got Away with It</title>
<link>https://theintercept.com/2018/02/17/gchq-belgacom-investigation-europe-hack/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://theintercept.com/2018/02/17/gchq-belgacom-investigation-europe-hack/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The covert operation was the first known example of a European Union member state hacking the critical infrastructure of another. The malware infection triggered a massive cleanup operation within Belgacom, which has since renamed itself Proximus. The company – of which the Belgian government is the majority owner – was forced to replace thousands of its computers at a cost of several million Euros. Elio di Rupo, Belgium’s then-prime minister, was furious, calling the hack a “violation.” Meanwhile, one of the country’s top federal prosecutors opened a criminal investigation into the intrusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The criminal investigation has remained open for more than four years, but no details about its activities have been made public. Now, following interviews with five sources close to the case, The Intercept – in collaboration with Dutch newspaper &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.volkskrant.nl/4570187&quot;&gt;de Volkskrant&lt;/a&gt; – has gained insight into the probe and uncovered new information about the scope of the hack. The sources, who are subject to confidentiality agreements and not authorized to talk to the media, spoke on the condition of anonymity. Their accounts reveal an extraordinary investigation that was hindered from the outset by political, diplomatic, technical, and legal difficulties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Belgacom breach sparked outrage in Europe’s political institutions and made global headlines. But Belgium’s effort to identify the spies responsible and hold them accountable faced roadblocks at almost every turn. Europol, the European Union’s law enforcement agency, refused to assist. Prosecutors overseeing the case feared triggering a major diplomatic dispute and were reluctant to pursue it aggressively. Meanwhile, British spies tried to destroy the evidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We wanted to show that as a small country, we would not be bullied,” said a source close to the investigation. “But we were fighting against two big cyberarmies from the U.K. and the U.S. We knew we could never win this.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap align-bleed full-bleed width-fixed&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/02/GettyImages-94813782-1518810644.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-171685&quot; src=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/02/GettyImages-94813782-1518810644.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&amp;amp;w=1024&amp;amp;h=568&quot; alt=&quot;BELGIUM - APRIL 06: The Belgacom network control center is seen in Brussels, Belgium, Thursday, April 6, 2006. Belgacom SA, Belgium's biggest phone company, said first-half profit rose as the purchase of a 25 percent stake in its mobile unit Proximus from Vodafone Group Plc last year reduced minority interest payments. (Photo by Paul O'Driscoll/Bloomberg via Getty Images)&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;The Belgacom network control center is seen in Brussels, Belgium, Thursday, April 6, 2006.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;At first, it&lt;/u&gt; was not clear how severely Belgacom’s systems were compromised or who was responsible for the breach. Inside a grayish four-story office building on Lebeau Street in Brussels, one of the company’s email servers kept malfunctioning. The problem, first identified in the summer of 2012, was assumed then to be a routine technical fault. But about a year later – in June 2013 – the issue flared up again, and Belgacom’s security experts realized there was a more sinister explanation: The company’s systems had been hacked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Belgacom notified the authorities that it had been targeted, and in July 2013, filed a formal complaint with a federal prosecutor. The complaint triggered a major investigation that was code-named “Trinity,” led by a group that included members of Belgium’s federal police, domestic secret service, military intelligence, and a specialist unit known as a Computer Emergency Response Team. Belgacom also recruited help in the form of Netherlands-based cybersecurity firm Fox-IT; it called in the U.S. technology company Cisco to assess the damage, as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once they had the chance to analyze Belgacom’s infected computers, the Belgian authorities realized that they were not dealing with a routine cyberattack. Instead, they assessed that it was an “advanced persistent threat” – a deep-reaching hack perpetrated by a well-funded, highly skilled actor. They had never encountered anything like it before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The malware that had infected Belgacom’s systems was disguised as legitimate Microsoft software, the investigators found. It was secretly collecting data from the company’s networks before storing it in compressed containers with several layers of encryption. Assessing the extent of the damage was no easy task. The Belgians could not completely decrypt the files and were therefore unable to identify exactly what had been taken from Belgacom’s computers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hackers were retrieving the stolen information from Belgacom’s systems during business hours, masking their activity within the normal flows of data passing to and from the company’s networks. But in late August 2013, the malware suddenly began deleting itself, vanishing in minutes from Belgacom’s infected computers. “The attackers knew they’d been discovered,” said a security expert who worked on the case. “They pushed a button to destroy the malware.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;stylized pull-none&quot; data-shortcode-type=&quot;pullquote&quot; data-pull=&quot;none&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their prime suspects were people who did not exist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, the investigators had already made copies of the bug. They followed the digital evidence, forensically analyzing it for clues. They found that the stolen data had been sent out of Belgacom’s systems to a network of servers seemingly operated by the hackers. They identified the servers by tracing IP addresses – a series of numbers assigned to computers when they connect to the internet – to countries including India, the Netherlands, Indonesia, and Romania.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hackers had rented the servers from private companies operating in each of these countries. Belgian police contacted the companies and asked them to turn over any information they had about the customers who had purchased the servers. The companies complied, providing the police with names, addresses, and payment records. The police now had a list of people they believed could be responsible for the hack. But that’s where the trail began to go cold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The addresses were for people who appeared to live in Germany and Denmark. Belgian federal police officers reached out to their counterparts in these countries, sharing the details about their suspects. But there were no records of anyone with the suspects’ names having lived at the addresses. In Germany, the address the hackers had used turned out to be a theater. It quickly became obvious to the investigators that the information was fraudulent. Their prime suspects were people who did not exist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“There was nothing there – just ghosts,” said a source close to the investigation. “They are spies. They put up smokescreens.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One detail would later take on significance, however. The servers had in some cases been purchased with payment cards that appeared to have been issued to people based in the U.K.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap align-bleed full-bleed width-auto&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/02/GettyImages-917248136-1518810738.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-171687&quot; src=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/02/GettyImages-917248136-1518810738.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&amp;amp;w=1024&amp;amp;h=629&quot; alt=&quot;STRASBOURG, FRANCE - FEBRUARY 11, 2018: The building of the European Parliament (EP) as seen from Rue Lucien Febvre Street in the city of Strasbourg. Alexei Vitvitsky/TASS (Photo by Alexei VitvitskyTASS via Getty Images)&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption overlayed&quot;&gt;The building of the European Parliament (EP) as seen from Rue Lucien Febvre Street in the city of Strasbourg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption source pullright&quot;&gt;Photo: Alexei VitvitskyTASS/Getty Images&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;In June 2013,&lt;/u&gt; shortly before the discovery of the intrusion at Belgacom, journalists began publishing documents leaked by National Security Agency whistleblower Edward Snowden. The documents exposed controversial mass surveillance programs operated by the NSA and its British counterpart, GCHQ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the Belgacom investigators initially suspected that the NSA was involved in the hack, partly due to the complexity of the malware. It bore similarities to Stuxnet and Flame, U.S.-created digital viruses designed to sabotage and collect intelligence about Iran’s uranium enrichment program. “This was by far the most sophisticated malware I’ve ever seen,” recalled Frank Groenewegen, a researcher who analyzed Belgacom’s infected systems for the cybersecurity firm Fox-IT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was not until September 2013 that the Belgians would learn the truth: The Belgacom intrusion had in fact been carried out by another of their close allies, the British. Documents from Snowden, published that month by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.spiegel.de/international/europe/british-spy-agency-gchq-hacked-belgian-telecoms-firm-a-923406.html&quot;&gt;Der Spiegel&lt;/a&gt;, showed that a GCHQ unit called the Network Analysis Centre had hacked into the computers of three Belgacom engineers who had access to sensitive parts of the company’s systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap align-center width-fixed&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/02/Untitled-1518813688.png?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-171721&quot; src=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/02/Untitled-1518813688.png?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&amp;amp;w=1024&amp;amp;h=737&quot; alt=&quot;Untitled-1518813688&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Layout of a GCHQ office from which the hack of Belgacom was planned and carried out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption source&quot;&gt;Image: GCHQ/Snowden archive&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
When the details about the hack went public, Belgacom tried to play down the extent of the breach. The company circulated a &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20131211170608/http://www.belgacom.com/be-en/newsdetail/ND_20130916_Belgacom.page&quot;&gt;press release&lt;/a&gt; insisting there was “no indication of any impact” for its customers and their data. But the reassurance turned out to be false. As The Intercept &lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.com/2014/12/13/belgacom-hack-gchq-inside-story/&quot;&gt;revealed&lt;/a&gt; in December 2014, the most sensitive parts of Belgacom’s networks were compromised in stages between January and December 2011. After installing malware on the engineers’ computers by luring them to a fake version of the LinkedIn website, GCHQ was able to steal their keys to the secure parts of Belgacom’s networks and begin monitoring the data flowing across them. The agency boasted in classified reports that the operation was “hugely successful.” It gained access to Belgacom “both deep into the network and at the edge of the network” and hacked into data links carrying information over a protocol known as GPRS, which handles cellphone internet browsing sessions and multimedia messages.
&lt;p&gt;The British spies appear to have targeted Belgacom due to its role as one of Europe’s most important telecommunications hubs. Through a subsidiary company called Belgacom International Carrier Services, it maintains data links across the continent and also processes phone calls and emails passing to and from the Middle East, North Africa, and South America. But tapping into a broad range of global communications is only one possible motive. GCHQ may also have sought access to Belgacom’s networks to snoop on NATO and key European institutions, such as the European Commission, the European Parliament, and the European Council. All of those organizations have large offices and thousands of employees in Belgium. And all were Belgacom customers at the time of the intrusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the last decade, as the internet and smartphone use have boomed, GCHQ has increasingly turned to hacking to collect intelligence on matters related to economics, geopolitics, and security. Aside from Belgacom, the agency has broken into the computer systems of the oil production organization OPEC; the Netherlands-based security company Gemalto; and organizations that process international cellphone billing records, including Switzerland’s Comfone. The agency has also hacked several governments and companies from countries including Ireland, South Africa, Pakistan, India, Turkey, Iran, Argentina, Russia, North Korea, the United Arab Emirates, and Zimbabwe, according to previously undisclosed lists of some of its targets, contained in the archive of classified documents that The Intercept obtained from Snowden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hacking attacks are among GCHQ’s most sensitive and risky operations, mainly because the method is not as discrete as more traditional forms of electronic surveillance, like monitoring a phone line. Challenges the agency faces during its computer intrusions include “avoiding detection by [the] target or another agency” and “remaining within the law,” according to a previously undisclosed &lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.com/document/2018/02/17/computer-network-exploitation-presentation&quot;&gt;top-secret GCHQ document&lt;/a&gt; from the Snowden archive. All of GCHQ’s hacking activities “must be U.K. deniable,” the document says, meaning it should be impossible for those targeted by the hacks to trace them back to GCHQ’s computers. The agency’s hackers use what they call “intermediary machines” and “covert infrastructure” to disguise themselves before they steal information from hacked computers or phones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Belgacom case, these protections failed and GCHQ’s biggest fear was realized. Its operation was discovered and its identity as the perpetrator was publicly exposed. For the authorities in Belgium, however, seeking justice for the damage that the agency caused still proved a remarkable challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap align-bleed full-bleed width-auto&quot; readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/02/AP_17270419322056-1518810879.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-171691&quot; src=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/02/AP_17270419322056-1518810879.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&amp;amp;w=1024&amp;amp;h=683&quot; alt=&quot;In this Jan. 16, 2015 file photo, the head of the European Union's police agency Europol, Rob Wainwright, answers questions during an interview in The Hague, Netherlands. The European Union's police agency is calling for better awareness and tougher, targeted legislation to tackle cybercrime in the wake of devastating malware and ransomware attacks in recent months. (AP Photo/Peter Dejong, File)&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption overlayed&quot;&gt;In this Jan. 16, 2015 , the head of the European Union’s police agency Europol, Rob Wainwright, answers questions during an interview in The Hague, Netherlands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption source pullright&quot;&gt;Photo: Peter Dejong/AP&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;As news organizations&lt;/u&gt; began publishing the Snowden documents in 2013, the Belgians studied them with interest. The classified files revealed details about the planning and execution of the hack. But because the documents appeared in the press, were partly redacted, and had not been handed straight to the police, the law enforcement officials overseeing the criminal investigation did not consider them direct evidence, though they did enter the documents into their case file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to a source close to the investigation, there were informal discussions over whether it would be possible to ask Snowden to testify as a witness in the case, so he could verify the documents and potentially provide his own statement about the hack of Belgacom. However, senior prosecutor Frederic Van Leeuw poured cold water on the idea, on the grounds that it would be too damaging diplomatically. Snowden was in Russia, where he had sought asylum, and interviewing him could upset the U.S., a powerful ally of the Belgian government. At the time, there were rising concerns about the movement of potential Islamist terrorists in Europe. The Belgians needed U.S. assistance in tracking that threat and feared any move that could jeopardize the cooperation. (A spokesperson for Van Leeuw declined to comment for this story.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The investigators knew the U.K. was responsible for the hack. But they wanted to build their own case, based on their own sources, that nailed GCHQ as the perpetrator. Some of the forensic evidence they had obtained from Belgacom’s systems pointed toward the U.K., but it was not conclusive and could still be denied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;stylized pull-right&quot; data-shortcode-type=&quot;pullquote&quot; data-pull=&quot;right&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Belgians believed Europol had stonewalled them for political reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were the payments they had been able to trace to the U.K., but those turned out to have been made using pre-paid credit cards that were obtained anonymously – in the Kent area of England and elsewhere – and not linked directly to GCHQ. The investigators also found the names “Daredevil” and “Warriorpride” embedded within the code of the malware that had infected Belgacom’s systems. These are the names of a hacking tool used by GCHQ and NSA, according to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.spiegel.de/media/media-35688.pdf&quot;&gt;the Snowden documents&lt;/a&gt;, and their discovery within Belgacom was as close as the investigators got to a smoking gun. But the Belgians felt these details were still too circumstantial. They needed more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In late 2013, Belgian police decided to approach the European Union’s law enforcement agency, Europol, for assistance. Europol helps E.U. member states fight terrorism and serious crime. It has a specialist unit called the European Cybercrime Centre, whose mandate is to “strengthen the law enforcement response to cybercrime in the E.U.” The Belgians hoped the unit would help them gather more evidence about the hack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, Europol wanted nothing to do with the investigation and refused to assist, according to two sources familiar with the interaction. Europol asserted that it would not carry out investigations into other European Union member states – in this case, the U.K. The Belgians were frustrated and believed Europol had stonewalled them for political reasons; they noted with suspicion that the organization was led by Rob Wainwright, who is British.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jan Op Gen Oorth, a spokesperson for Europol, told The Intercept in an email that regulations restricted the organization to “investigating acts affecting two or more EU Member States, involving serious and organized crime and terrorist actors only.” Questioned on which regulations he meant, Op Gen Oorth pointed to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.europol.europa.eu/newsroom/news/europols-new-regulation&quot;&gt;a policy&lt;/a&gt; that did not exist at the time the Belgians asked for assistance with the hack of Belgacom. (The policy was in fact brought into force in May 2017; it states that Europol is empowered to investigate hacks “of suspected criminal origin,” but says nothing about hacks perpetrated by governments.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At every turn in the case, the Belgian investigators encountered a dead end. They knew that even if they identified specific GCHQ personnel responsible for the hack, they would likely never be able to arrest or extradite them from the U.K. It might have been possible to place the names of particular GCHQ employees on a watch list, and if they ever traveled to Belgium, police could detain and interrogate them. But that would pose its own set of problems. Arresting a British spy would trigger a massive public dispute with the U.K. and there was insufficient political appetite for such a showdown. As such, the Belgian Trinity investigation came to be viewed as little more than symbolic in value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We could see GCHQ was behind it, but we knew it was never going to go to court,” said a source close to the case. “But still, we wanted to gather information and make it known to the world that in Belgium if you try to hack our national telecoms we won’t look away, we will investigate.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap align-bleed full-bleed width-auto&quot; readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/02/AP_251756135026-1518810932.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-171692&quot; src=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/02/AP_251756135026-1518810932.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&amp;amp;w=1024&amp;amp;h=799&quot; alt=&quot;British Foreign Secretary William Hague walks in to attend the EU foreign ministers meeting, at the European Council building in Brussels, Monday, Dec. 16, 2013. European Union foreign ministers meeting Monday argue that the door remains open for Ukraine to sign an association agreement the EU, even though they criticized the delaying tactics and mixed messages sent by Ukraine President Viktor Yanukovych. (AP Photo/Yves Logghe)&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption overlayed&quot;&gt;British Foreign Secretary William Hague walks in to attend the EU foreign ministers meeting, at the European Council building in Brussels, Monday, Dec. 16, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption source pullright&quot;&gt;Photo: Yves Logghe/AP&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;The British government&lt;/u&gt; has never publicly acknowledged any role in the Belgacom hack. GCHQ declined to answer questions for this story and instead issued a statement asserting that its work is carried out “in accordance with a strict legal and policy framework, which ensures that our activities are authorised, necessary and proportionate.” Any GCHQ hack that targets foreign organizations must be approved at a senior level within the agency, and particularly sensitive operations sometimes require the sign-off of the government’s foreign secretary, who at the time of the Belgacom intrusion was William Hague. A spokesperson for Hague refused to discuss the case, saying he would not comment on “national intelligence matters.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the aftermath of the incident, it is likely that the Belgian government lodged diplomatic protests with its British counterparts. According to U.K. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/4380802-UK-Belgium-meetings-Sept-Dec-2013.html&quot;&gt;government records&lt;/a&gt; obtained by The Intercept through the Freedom of Information Act, British officials held a series of meetings with Belgian government representatives after the Belgacom intrusion was publicly exposed. In October 2013, for instance, foreign secretaries of each country and senior diplomats attended a two day “Belgian-British conference” at Lancaster House in London’s West End. Two weeks later, the British ambassador to Belgium met in Brussels with Johan Delmulle, a top Belgian federal prosecutor, who was overseeing the Belgacom investigation at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even within the Belgian government and law enforcement community, however, there was a lack of clarity about how the case was being handled. The country’s law enforcement personnel were not informed about whether a diplomatic dialogue was underway with the British. Meanwhile, Alexander De Croo, the Belgian government minister responsible for telecoms services, appears to have been kept in the dark about the incident. During a January 2016 talk at the World Economic Forum in Davos, Switzerland, De Croo made the extraordinary suggestion that his own government might even have secretly allowed the British to go ahead with the hack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The whole question is: Did we agree or not,” De Croo said. “I am not the Minister of Justice so I don’t get access to everything .… It might very well be that the Belgian intelligence services said, ‘Yes please go ahead, why not?’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;De Croo declined to be interviewed for this story. Belgium’s Ministry of Justice and intelligence services refused to discuss De Croo’s comments, citing an ongoing investigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap align-bleed full-bleed width-auto&quot; readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/02/GettyImages-678577132-1518811014.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-171696&quot; src=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/02/GettyImages-678577132-1518811014.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&amp;amp;w=1024&amp;amp;h=683&quot; alt=&quot;CHELTENHAM, CHELTENHAM. OCTOBER 07. Aerial photograph of the Government Communications Headquarters, also known as GCHQ, Cheltenham Gloucestershire. (Photograph by David Goddard/Getty Images)&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption overlayed&quot;&gt;Aerial photograph of the Government Communications Headquarters, also known as GCHQ, Cheltenham Gloucestershire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption source pullright&quot;&gt;Photo: David Goddard/Getty Images&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;The police file&lt;/u&gt; on the Belgacom hack numbers thousands of pages and is expected to be handed over soon to the prosecutor now overseeing the case. That prosecutor, Geert Schoorens, will decide what to do next, including whether to charge anyone over the breach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the political uproar the incident triggered in 2013, it is unlikely that any action will be taken. That GCHQ was responsible is beyond doubt, but the agency will face no consequences, say sources with knowledge of the case. There will be no sanctions for the U.K., no compensation to cover the damage caused, no arrests, no interrogations, no apology, and no admission of guilt. Rather, Schoorens will turn over a report to the Belgian parliament and the investigation will be quietly closed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite this, the hack has had a palpable impact in Belgium. Belgacom – or Proximus, as it is now known – committed to spend more than $55 million to reform its internal security procedures. The company created a cyberdefense unit and recruited “ethical hackers” who routinely try to break into its networks, which helps identify and fix any potential vulnerabilities. It has also trained its employees in how to spot potential hacking attempts, introduced new systems that constantly monitor activity within its internal networks, and reduced the number of its computers that have access to sensitive parts of its systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Belgian authorities, too, were forced to embrace changes after the breach. The criminal investigation brought the country’s law enforcement and secret services closer together, and now the agencies are more cooperative on cybersecurity issues. For them, GCHQ’s actions were a rude awakening – and the sign of a looming new threat, for which they are now preparing. “In the next few years, this malware is going to be in the hands of criminals and terrorists,” said a source close to the investigation. “Belgacom was a learning curve. We learned how to respond to a crisis before the next crisis.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;———&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Documents published with this article:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;———&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Top photo: The Belgacom Group is the largest telecommunications company in Belgium, headquartered in Brussels.Belgacom flag, Belgian national flag hang together at the entrance mirrored in the windows.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 08:03:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>DyslexicAtheist</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://theintercept.com/2018/02/17/gchq-belgacom-investigation-europe-hack/</og:url>
<og:description>A British spy agency secretly hacked a company in Belgium then evaded an extraordinary police investigation.</og:description>
<og:image>https://cdn01.theintercept.com/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/02/belgacom-feature-1518810564-feature-hero.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>How UK Spies Hacked a European Ally and Got Away With It</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://theintercept.com/2018/02/17/gchq-belgacom-investigation-europe-hack/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>React Native and Yoga Both Given MIT Licence by Facebook</title>
<link>https://github.com/facebook/react-native/commit/26684cf3adf4094eb6c405d345a75bf8c7c0bf88</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/facebook/react-native/commit/26684cf3adf4094eb6c405d345a75bf8c7c0bf88</guid>
<description>&lt;colgroup&gt;&lt;col width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;col width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;col/&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;&lt;tr data-position=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;td id=&quot;diff-9879d6db96fd29134fc802214163b95aL0&quot; class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-hunk non-expandable&quot; data-line-number=&quot;...&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td id=&quot;diff-9879d6db96fd29134fc802214163b95aR0&quot; class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-hunk non-expandable&quot; data-line-number=&quot;...&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-code blob-code-inner blob-code-hunk&quot;&gt;@@ -1,30 +1,21 @@&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td id=&quot;diff-9879d6db96fd29134fc802214163b95aL1&quot; data-line-number=&quot;1&quot; class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-deletion js-linkable-line-number&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-deletion empty-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-code blob-code-deletion&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;blob-code-inner&quot;&gt;-&lt;span class=&quot;x x-first x-last&quot;&gt;BSD&lt;/span&gt; License&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-addition empty-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td id=&quot;diff-9879d6db96fd29134fc802214163b95aR1&quot; data-line-number=&quot;1&quot; class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-addition js-linkable-line-number&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-code blob-code-addition&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;blob-code-inner&quot;&gt;+&lt;span class=&quot;x x-first x-last&quot;&gt;MIT&lt;/span&gt; License&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td id=&quot;diff-9879d6db96fd29134fc802214163b95aL2&quot; data-line-number=&quot;2&quot; class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-context js-linkable-line-number&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td id=&quot;diff-9879d6db96fd29134fc802214163b95aR2&quot; data-line-number=&quot;2&quot; class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-context js-linkable-line-number&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-code blob-code-context&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td id=&quot;diff-9879d6db96fd29134fc802214163b95aL3&quot; data-line-number=&quot;3&quot; class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-deletion js-linkable-line-number&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-deletion empty-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-code blob-code-deletion&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;blob-code-inner&quot;&gt;-&lt;span class=&quot;x x-first x-last&quot;&gt;For React Native software&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-addition empty-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td id=&quot;diff-9879d6db96fd29134fc802214163b95aR3&quot; data-line-number=&quot;3&quot; class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-addition js-linkable-line-number&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-code blob-code-addition&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;blob-code-inner&quot;&gt;+&lt;span class=&quot;x x-first x-last&quot;&gt;Copyright (c) 2015-present, Facebook, Inc.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td id=&quot;diff-9879d6db96fd29134fc802214163b95aL4&quot; data-line-number=&quot;4&quot; class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-context js-linkable-line-number&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td id=&quot;diff-9879d6db96fd29134fc802214163b95aR4&quot; data-line-number=&quot;4&quot; class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-context js-linkable-line-number&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-code blob-code-context&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;td id=&quot;diff-9879d6db96fd29134fc802214163b95aL5&quot; data-line-number=&quot;5&quot; class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-deletion js-linkable-line-number&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-deletion empty-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-code blob-code-deletion&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;blob-code-inner&quot;&gt;-Copyright (c) 2015-present, Facebook, Inc. All rights reserved.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-addition empty-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td id=&quot;diff-9879d6db96fd29134fc802214163b95aR5&quot; data-line-number=&quot;5&quot; class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-addition js-linkable-line-number&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-code blob-code-addition&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;blob-code-inner&quot;&gt;+Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-addition empty-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td id=&quot;diff-9879d6db96fd29134fc802214163b95aR6&quot; data-line-number=&quot;6&quot; class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-addition js-linkable-line-number&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-code blob-code-addition&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;blob-code-inner&quot;&gt;+of this software and associated documentation files (the &quot;Software&quot;), to deal&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-addition empty-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td id=&quot;diff-9879d6db96fd29134fc802214163b95aR7&quot; data-line-number=&quot;7&quot; class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-addition js-linkable-line-number&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-code blob-code-addition&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;blob-code-inner&quot;&gt;+in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-addition empty-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td id=&quot;diff-9879d6db96fd29134fc802214163b95aR8&quot; data-line-number=&quot;8&quot; class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-addition js-linkable-line-number&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-code blob-code-addition&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;blob-code-inner&quot;&gt;+to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-addition empty-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td id=&quot;diff-9879d6db96fd29134fc802214163b95aR9&quot; data-line-number=&quot;9&quot; class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-addition js-linkable-line-number&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-code blob-code-addition&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;blob-code-inner&quot;&gt;+copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-addition empty-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td id=&quot;diff-9879d6db96fd29134fc802214163b95aR10&quot; data-line-number=&quot;10&quot; class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-addition js-linkable-line-number&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-code blob-code-addition&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;blob-code-inner&quot;&gt;+furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td id=&quot;diff-9879d6db96fd29134fc802214163b95aL6&quot; data-line-number=&quot;6&quot; class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-context js-linkable-line-number&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td id=&quot;diff-9879d6db96fd29134fc802214163b95aR11&quot; data-line-number=&quot;11&quot; class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-context js-linkable-line-number&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-code blob-code-context&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;td id=&quot;diff-9879d6db96fd29134fc802214163b95aL7&quot; data-line-number=&quot;7&quot; class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-deletion js-linkable-line-number&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-deletion empty-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-code blob-code-deletion&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;blob-code-inner&quot;&gt;-&lt;span class=&quot;x x-first x-last&quot;&gt;Redistribution and use in source&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class=&quot;x x-first x-last&quot;&gt;binary forms, with or without modification,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td id=&quot;diff-9879d6db96fd29134fc802214163b95aL8&quot; data-line-number=&quot;8&quot; class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-deletion js-linkable-line-number&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-deletion empty-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-code blob-code-deletion&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;blob-code-inner&quot;&gt;-&lt;span class=&quot;x x-first x-last&quot;&gt;are permitted provided that&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class=&quot;x x-first x-last&quot;&gt;following conditions are met:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-addition empty-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td id=&quot;diff-9879d6db96fd29134fc802214163b95aR12&quot; data-line-number=&quot;12&quot; class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-addition js-linkable-line-number&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-code blob-code-addition&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;blob-code-inner&quot;&gt;+&lt;span class=&quot;x x-first x-last&quot;&gt;The above copyright notice&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class=&quot;x x-first x-last&quot;&gt;this permission notice shall be included in all&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-addition empty-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td id=&quot;diff-9879d6db96fd29134fc802214163b95aR13&quot; data-line-number=&quot;13&quot; class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-addition js-linkable-line-number&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-code blob-code-addition&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;blob-code-inner&quot;&gt;+&lt;span class=&quot;x x-first x-last&quot;&gt;copies or substantial portions of&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class=&quot;x x-first x-last&quot;&gt;Software.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td id=&quot;diff-9879d6db96fd29134fc802214163b95aL9&quot; data-line-number=&quot;9&quot; class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-context js-linkable-line-number&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td id=&quot;diff-9879d6db96fd29134fc802214163b95aR14&quot; data-line-number=&quot;14&quot; class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-context js-linkable-line-number&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-code blob-code-context&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;td id=&quot;diff-9879d6db96fd29134fc802214163b95aL10&quot; data-line-number=&quot;10&quot; class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-deletion js-linkable-line-number&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-deletion empty-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-code blob-code-deletion&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;blob-code-inner&quot;&gt;- * Redistributions of source code must retain the above copyright notice, this&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td id=&quot;diff-9879d6db96fd29134fc802214163b95aL11&quot; data-line-number=&quot;11&quot; class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-deletion js-linkable-line-number&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-deletion empty-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-code blob-code-deletion&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;blob-code-inner&quot;&gt;- list of conditions and the following disclaimer.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td id=&quot;diff-9879d6db96fd29134fc802214163b95aL12&quot; data-line-number=&quot;12&quot; class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-deletion js-linkable-line-number&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-deletion empty-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-code blob-code-deletion&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;blob-code-inner&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;td id=&quot;diff-9879d6db96fd29134fc802214163b95aL13&quot; data-line-number=&quot;13&quot; class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-deletion js-linkable-line-number&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-deletion empty-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-code blob-code-deletion&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;blob-code-inner&quot;&gt;- * Redistributions in binary form must reproduce the above copyright notice,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td id=&quot;diff-9879d6db96fd29134fc802214163b95aL14&quot; data-line-number=&quot;14&quot; class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-deletion js-linkable-line-number&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-deletion empty-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-code blob-code-deletion&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;blob-code-inner&quot;&gt;- this list of conditions and the following disclaimer in the documentation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td id=&quot;diff-9879d6db96fd29134fc802214163b95aL15&quot; data-line-number=&quot;15&quot; class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-deletion js-linkable-line-number&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-deletion empty-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-code blob-code-deletion&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;blob-code-inner&quot;&gt;- and/or other materials provided with the distribution.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td id=&quot;diff-9879d6db96fd29134fc802214163b95aL16&quot; data-line-number=&quot;16&quot; class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-deletion js-linkable-line-number&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-deletion empty-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-code blob-code-deletion&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;blob-code-inner&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td id=&quot;diff-9879d6db96fd29134fc802214163b95aL17&quot; data-line-number=&quot;17&quot; class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-deletion js-linkable-line-number&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-deletion empty-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-code blob-code-deletion&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;blob-code-inner&quot;&gt;- * Neither the name Facebook nor the names of its contributors may be used to&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td id=&quot;diff-9879d6db96fd29134fc802214163b95aL18&quot; data-line-number=&quot;18&quot; class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-deletion js-linkable-line-number&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-deletion empty-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-code blob-code-deletion&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;blob-code-inner&quot;&gt;- endorse or promote products derived from this software without specific&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td id=&quot;diff-9879d6db96fd29134fc802214163b95aL19&quot; data-line-number=&quot;19&quot; class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-deletion js-linkable-line-number&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-deletion empty-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-code blob-code-deletion&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;blob-code-inner&quot;&gt;- prior written permission.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td id=&quot;diff-9879d6db96fd29134fc802214163b95aL20&quot; data-line-number=&quot;20&quot; class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-deletion js-linkable-line-number&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-deletion empty-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-code blob-code-deletion&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;blob-code-inner&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td id=&quot;diff-9879d6db96fd29134fc802214163b95aL21&quot; data-line-number=&quot;21&quot; class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-deletion js-linkable-line-number&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-deletion empty-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-code blob-code-deletion&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;blob-code-inner&quot;&gt;-THIS SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED BY THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS AND CONTRIBUTORS &quot;AS IS&quot; AND&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;td id=&quot;diff-9879d6db96fd29134fc802214163b95aL22&quot; data-line-number=&quot;22&quot; class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-deletion js-linkable-line-number&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-deletion empty-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-code blob-code-deletion&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;blob-code-inner&quot;&gt;-ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td id=&quot;diff-9879d6db96fd29134fc802214163b95aL23&quot; data-line-number=&quot;23&quot; class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-deletion js-linkable-line-number&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-deletion empty-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-code blob-code-deletion&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;blob-code-inner&quot;&gt;-WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE ARE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td id=&quot;diff-9879d6db96fd29134fc802214163b95aL24&quot; data-line-number=&quot;24&quot; class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-deletion js-linkable-line-number&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-deletion empty-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-code blob-code-deletion&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;blob-code-inner&quot;&gt;-DISCLAIMED. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE COPYRIGHT HOLDER OR CONTRIBUTORS BE LIABLE FOR&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;td id=&quot;diff-9879d6db96fd29134fc802214163b95aL25&quot; data-line-number=&quot;25&quot; class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-deletion js-linkable-line-number&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-deletion empty-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-code blob-code-deletion&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;blob-code-inner&quot;&gt;-ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;td id=&quot;diff-9879d6db96fd29134fc802214163b95aL26&quot; data-line-number=&quot;26&quot; class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-deletion js-linkable-line-number&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-deletion empty-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-code blob-code-deletion&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;blob-code-inner&quot;&gt;-(INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;td id=&quot;diff-9879d6db96fd29134fc802214163b95aL27&quot; data-line-number=&quot;27&quot; class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-deletion js-linkable-line-number&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-deletion empty-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-code blob-code-deletion&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;blob-code-inner&quot;&gt;-LOSS OF USE, DATA, OR PROFITS; OR BUSINESS INTERRUPTION) HOWEVER CAUSED AND ON&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;td id=&quot;diff-9879d6db96fd29134fc802214163b95aL28&quot; data-line-number=&quot;28&quot; class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-deletion js-linkable-line-number&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-deletion empty-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-code blob-code-deletion&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;blob-code-inner&quot;&gt;-ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, WHETHER IN CONTRACT, STRICT LIABILITY, OR TORT&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td id=&quot;diff-9879d6db96fd29134fc802214163b95aL29&quot; data-line-number=&quot;29&quot; class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-deletion js-linkable-line-number&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-deletion empty-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-code blob-code-deletion&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;blob-code-inner&quot;&gt;-(INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE OR OTHERWISE) ARISING IN ANY WAY OUT OF THE USE OF THIS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;td id=&quot;diff-9879d6db96fd29134fc802214163b95aL30&quot; data-line-number=&quot;30&quot; class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-deletion js-linkable-line-number&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-deletion empty-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-code blob-code-deletion&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;blob-code-inner&quot;&gt;-SOFTWARE, EVEN IF ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-addition empty-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td id=&quot;diff-9879d6db96fd29134fc802214163b95aR15&quot; data-line-number=&quot;15&quot; class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-addition js-linkable-line-number&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-code blob-code-addition&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;blob-code-inner&quot;&gt;+THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED &quot;AS IS&quot;, WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-addition empty-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td id=&quot;diff-9879d6db96fd29134fc802214163b95aR16&quot; data-line-number=&quot;16&quot; class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-addition js-linkable-line-number&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-code blob-code-addition&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;blob-code-inner&quot;&gt;+IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-addition empty-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td id=&quot;diff-9879d6db96fd29134fc802214163b95aR17&quot; data-line-number=&quot;17&quot; class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-addition js-linkable-line-number&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-code blob-code-addition&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;blob-code-inner&quot;&gt;+FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-addition empty-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td id=&quot;diff-9879d6db96fd29134fc802214163b95aR18&quot; data-line-number=&quot;18&quot; class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-addition js-linkable-line-number&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-code blob-code-addition&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;blob-code-inner&quot;&gt;+AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-addition empty-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td id=&quot;diff-9879d6db96fd29134fc802214163b95aR19&quot; data-line-number=&quot;19&quot; class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-addition js-linkable-line-number&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-code blob-code-addition&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;blob-code-inner&quot;&gt;+LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING FROM,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-addition empty-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td id=&quot;diff-9879d6db96fd29134fc802214163b95aR20&quot; data-line-number=&quot;20&quot; class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-addition js-linkable-line-number&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-code blob-code-addition&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;blob-code-inner&quot;&gt;+OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER DEALINGS IN THE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-addition empty-cell&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td id=&quot;diff-9879d6db96fd29134fc802214163b95aR21&quot; data-line-number=&quot;21&quot; class=&quot;blob-num blob-num-addition js-linkable-line-number&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;blob-code blob-code-addition&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;blob-code-inner&quot;&gt;+SOFTWARE.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 02:41:52 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dabit3</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars3.githubusercontent.com/u/6820?s=200&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>Update to MIT license · facebook/react-native@26684cf</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/facebook/react-native/commit/26684cf3adf4094eb6c405d345a75bf8c7c0bf88</og:url>
<og:description>Summary: Manual changes. Reviewed By: TheSavior, yungsters Differential Revision: D7012152 fbshipit-source-id: de7459be3db13c687868b45059856f125c4f2eb1</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/facebook/react-native/commit/26684cf3adf4094eb6c405d345a75bf8c7c0bf88</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Type 2 diabetes can be reversed with a low-calorie diet</title>
<link>https://discover.dc.nihr.ac.uk/portal/article/4000931/type-2-diabetes-can-be-reversed-with-a-low-calorie-diet?utm_content=bufferf8b4a&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=twitter.com&amp;utm_campaign=buffer</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://discover.dc.nihr.ac.uk/portal/article/4000931/type-2-diabetes-can-be-reversed-with-a-low-calorie-diet?utm_content=bufferf8b4a&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=twitter.com&amp;utm_campaign=buffer</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;extended-article-content&quot; readability=&quot;55.859820089955&quot;&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;18&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;font-nihr-research&quot;&gt;Why was this study needed?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Type 2 diabetes is a growing epidemic, costing the NHS £23.7 billion per year. By 2016 there were nearly 3.6 million people diagnosed with diabetes in the UK and a further one million estimated to have undiagnosed type 2 diabetes. Rates of diabetes appear to be increasing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bariatric surgery has been shown to put people into remission from diabetes. However, this is not a feasible solution for all people with type 2 diabetes, and there can be serious complications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study aimed to see if a very low-calorie diet program delivered in primary care could lead to at least 15kg weight loss and remission of type 2 diabetes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;18&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;font-nihr-research&quot;&gt;What did this study do?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The DiRECT cluster-randomised trial involved 49 GP practices in Scotland and Tyneside. The practices were assigned to either provide an intense weight management program or usual care according to NICE guidelines for overweight adults with type 2 diabetes. The 298 participants had been diagnosed within the last six years and were not on insulin injections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The program involved stopping diabetic and high blood pressure medications and going on a formula replacement diet. This consisted of 825 to 853 calories per day for three to five months. Food was then reintroduced over two to eight weeks and walking encouraged through the use of a pedometer. Structured support for long-term weight loss maintenance was provided by a nurse or dietitian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a well-conducted study, and the results are likely to be reliable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;font-nihr-research&quot;&gt;What did it find?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By 12 months:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Weight loss of 15kg or more was achieved by 24% of the intervention group compared to none of the usual care group. Average weight loss was 10kg in the intervention group versus 1kg in the usual care group (adjusted difference ‑8.8kg, 95% confidence interval [CI] ‑10.3 to ‑7.3).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Diabetes remission occurred in 46% of the intervention group compared to 4% of the usual care group. It only occurred in people who had lost weight.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remission was 20 times more likely with the intervention (odds ratio 19.7, 95% CI 7.8 to 49.8).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Better adherence to the regime increased the amount of weight loss and the chance of diabetes remission.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Diabetes medication did not need to be reintroduced for 74% of the intervention group. This was compared to 18% of the usual care group who were able to stop them. Blood pressure tablets were also no longer required for 68% of the intervention group compared to 39% of the usual care group.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;font-nihr-research&quot;&gt;What does current guidance say on this issue?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The NICE guideline on type 2 diabetes (2015) recommends the same dietary advice that is given to the general population. This includes eating a high-fibre, low glycaemic index, low-fat diet with plenty of fruit and vegetables. They encourage weight loss and exercise but do not specify very low-calorie diets to go into remission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;font-nihr-research&quot;&gt;What are the implications?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study shows that it is possible to achieve remission from type 2 diabetes by dieting. Admittedly this was a very motivated group - but the results show that it can be done, and so should encourage more people to give it a go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resource implications include the eight hours of training the nurse or dietitian received. This included cognitive behavioural therapy techniques to facilitate behaviour change. The likely increased number of regular appointments would also need to be factored in. Nevertheless, this is a promising relatively low resource intervention which is likely to be cost-saving in the long run if the results can be maintained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;extended-article-content-alt&quot; readability=&quot;55.859820089955&quot;&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;18&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;font-nihr-research&quot;&gt;Why was this study needed?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Type 2 diabetes is a growing epidemic, costing the NHS £23.7 billion per year. By 2016 there were nearly 3.6 million people diagnosed with diabetes in the UK and a further one million estimated to have undiagnosed type 2 diabetes. Rates of diabetes appear to be increasing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bariatric surgery has been shown to put people into remission from diabetes. However, this is not a feasible solution for all people with type 2 diabetes, and there can be serious complications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study aimed to see if a very low-calorie diet program delivered in primary care could lead to at least 15kg weight loss and remission of type 2 diabetes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;18&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;font-nihr-research&quot;&gt;What did this study do?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The DiRECT cluster-randomised trial involved 49 GP practices in Scotland and Tyneside. The practices were assigned to either provide an intense weight management program or usual care according to NICE guidelines for overweight adults with type 2 diabetes. The 298 participants had been diagnosed within the last six years and were not on insulin injections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The program involved stopping diabetic and high blood pressure medications and going on a formula replacement diet. This consisted of 825 to 853 calories per day for three to five months. Food was then reintroduced over two to eight weeks and walking encouraged through the use of a pedometer. Structured support for long-term weight loss maintenance was provided by a nurse or dietitian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a well-conducted study, and the results are likely to be reliable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;font-nihr-research&quot;&gt;What did it find?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By 12 months:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Weight loss of 15kg or more was achieved by 24% of the intervention group compared to none of the usual care group. Average weight loss was 10kg in the intervention group versus 1kg in the usual care group (adjusted difference ‑8.8kg, 95% confidence interval [CI] ‑10.3 to ‑7.3).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Diabetes remission occurred in 46% of the intervention group compared to 4% of the usual care group. It only occurred in people who had lost weight.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remission was 20 times more likely with the intervention (odds ratio 19.7, 95% CI 7.8 to 49.8).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Better adherence to the regime increased the amount of weight loss and the chance of diabetes remission.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Diabetes medication did not need to be reintroduced for 74% of the intervention group. This was compared to 18% of the usual care group who were able to stop them. Blood pressure tablets were also no longer required for 68% of the intervention group compared to 39% of the usual care group.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;font-nihr-research&quot;&gt;What does current guidance say on this issue?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The NICE guideline on type 2 diabetes (2015) recommends the same dietary advice that is given to the general population. This includes eating a high-fibre, low glycaemic index, low-fat diet with plenty of fruit and vegetables. They encourage weight loss and exercise but do not specify very low-calorie diets to go into remission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;font-nihr-research&quot;&gt;What are the implications?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study shows that it is possible to achieve remission from type 2 diabetes by dieting. Admittedly this was a very motivated group - but the results show that it can be done, and so should encourage more people to give it a go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resource implications include the eight hours of training the nurse or dietitian received. This included cognitive behavioural therapy techniques to facilitate behaviour change. The likely increased number of regular appointments would also need to be factored in. Nevertheless, this is a promising relatively low resource intervention which is likely to be cost-saving in the long run if the results can be maintained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;published-article&quot; readability=&quot;50.5&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;padding: 16;&quot; readability=&quot;46&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BACKGROUND: Type 2 diabetes is a chronic disorder that requires lifelong treatment. We aimed to assess whether intensive weight management within routine primary care would achieve remission of type 2 diabetes. METHODS: We did this open-label, cluster-randomised trial (DiRECT) at 49 primary care practices in Scotland and the Tyneside region of England. Practices were randomly assigned (1:1), via a computer-generated list, to provide either a weight management programme (intervention) or best-practice care by guidelines (control), with stratification for study site (Tyneside or Scotland) and practice list size (&amp;gt;5700 or &amp;lt;/=5700). Participants, carers, and research assistants who collected outcome data were aware of group allocation; however, allocation was concealed from the study statistician. We recruited individuals aged 20-65 years who had been diagnosed with type 2 diabetes within the past 6 years, had a body-mass index of 27-45 kg/m(2), and were not receiving insulin. The intervention comprised withdrawal of antidiabetic and antihypertensive drugs, total diet replacement (825-853 kcal/day formula diet for 3-5 months), stepped food reintroduction (2-8 weeks), and structured support for long-term weight loss maintenance. Co-primary outcomes were weight loss of 15 kg or more, and remission of diabetes, defined as glycated haemoglobin (HbA1c) of less than 6.5% (&amp;lt;48 mmol/mol) after at least 2 months off all antidiabetic medications, from baseline to 12 months. These outcomes were analysed hierarchically. This trial is registered with the ISRCTN registry, number 03267836. FINDINGS: Between July 25, 2014, and Aug 5, 2017, we recruited 306 individuals from 49 intervention (n=23) and control (n=26) general practices; 149 participants per group comprised the intention-to-treat population. At 12 months, we recorded weight loss of 15 kg or more in 36 (24%) participants in the intervention group and no participants in the control group (p&amp;lt;0.0001). Diabetes remission was achieved in 68 (46%) participants in the intervention group and six (4%) participants in the control group (odds ratio 19.7, 95% CI 7.8-49.8; p&amp;lt;0.0001). Remission varied with weight loss in the whole study population, with achievement in none of 76 participants who gained weight, six (7%) of 89 participants who maintained 0-5 kg weight loss, 19 (34%) of 56 participants with 5-10 kg loss, 16 (57%) of 28 participants with 10-15 kg loss, and 31 (86%) of 36 participants who lost 15 kg or more. Mean bodyweight fell by 10.0 kg (SD 8.0) in the intervention group and 1.0 kg (3.7) in the control group (adjusted difference -8.8 kg, 95% CI -10.3 to -7.3; p&amp;lt;0.0001). Quality of life, as measured by the EuroQol 5 Dimensions visual analogue scale, improved by 7.2 points (SD 21.3) in the intervention group, and decreased by 2.9 points (15.5) in the control group (adjusted difference 6.4 points, 95% CI 2.5-10.3; p=0.0012). Nine serious adverse events were reported by seven (4%) of 157 participants in the intervention group and two were reported by two (1%) participants in the control group. Two serious adverse events (biliary colic and abdominal pain), occurring in the same participant, were deemed potentially related to the intervention. No serious adverse events led to withdrawal from the study. INTERPRETATION: Our findings show that, at 12 months, almost half of participants achieved remission to a non-diabetic state and off antidiabetic drugs. Remission of type 2 diabetes is a practical target for primary care. FUNDING: Diabetes UK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;extended-article-definitions&quot; readability=&quot;34.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The structured support included cognitive behavioural therapy techniques. The time in each phase - diet replacement, food reintroduction and maintenance - was tailored to the individual. Increased exercise was encouraged, aiming for up to 15,000 steps per day. However, this was not achieved by many as there was no difference in reported exercise in either group between baseline and 12 months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 22:57:28 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>DanBC</dc:creator>
<og:description>Nearly half of people given a formula replacement diet of 830 calories per day for three to five months, followed by food reintroduction, went into remission from type 2 diabetes. They were supported to achieve and maintain weight reduction by primary care nurses or dieticians. This trial involved 298 adults who had been diagnosed with type 2 diabetes within six years. Those that stuck with the program were more likely to lose weight (average 10kg was lost) and to go into remission compared to usual care. More than two-thirds of them were also able to stop both diabetic and high blood pressure tablets. These results were seen after one year. The challenge will be to see if the results can be maintained over the planned four year follow-up period. If successful, the program could be easily replicated by other GP surgeries with minimal training requirements.</og:description>
<og:title>Type 2 diabetes can be reversed with a low-calorie diet</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https:/discover.dc.nihr.ac.uk:443/portal/article/4000931/type-2-diabetes-can-be-reversed-with-a-low-calorie-diet</og:url>
<og:image>https://discover.dc.nihr.ac.uk:443/asset/image/9000321.png?636545088871500888</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://discover.dc.nihr.ac.uk/portal/article/4000931/type-2-diabetes-can-be-reversed-with-a-low-calorie-diet</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Fired Google Engineer Loses Diversity Memo Challenge</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-02-16/google-firing-of-damore-was-legal-u-s-labor-panel-lawyer-said</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-02-16/google-firing-of-damore-was-legal-u-s-labor-panel-lawyer-said</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lede-media-image__caption caption&quot;&gt;James Damore, right, speaks at a news conference with his attorney, Harmeet Dhillon, on Jan. 8, in San Francisco.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;99.928070175439&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google’s firing of an engineer over his &lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-08-08/google-fires-employee-behind-controversial-diversity-memo&quot; title=&quot;Google Fires Author of Divisive Memo on Gender Differences (3)&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;controversial memo&lt;/a&gt; criticizing its diversity policies and “politically correct monoculture” didn’t violate U.S. labor law, a federal agency lawyer concluded.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Statements in James Damore’s 3,000-word memo “regarding biological differences between the sexes were so harmful, discriminatory, and disruptive” that they fell outside protections for collective action in the workplace, an associate general counsel for the National Labor Relations Board wrote in a six-page memo disclosed Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Damore withdrew his complaint in January and his lawyer has said she’s focusing instead on the engineer’s &lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-01-08/google-engineer-sues-over-firing-for-memo-on-gender-differences&quot; title=&quot;Google Sued for Anti-Conservative Bias by Fired Engineer (2)&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; accusing the internet giant of harassing him and others over their conservative political views.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;When he was dismissed in August, Damore accused Google of violating the employee right to engage in &quot;concerted activity&quot; to address workplace issues, a category which the labor board has found can include forms of activism ranging from lawsuits to strikes to social media posts.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;“Much of&quot; Damore’s memo was probably protected under the law, the labor board’s attorney, Jayme Sophir, said in the Jan. 16 memo. But Sophir went on to find that Google discharged Damore only for his &quot;discriminatory statements,&quot; which aren’t shielded by labor law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because companies have a duty to comply with equal employment laws and an interest in promoting diversity, “employers must be permitted to ‘nip in the bud’ the kinds of employee conduct that could lead to a ‘hostile workplace,’ rather than waiting until an actionable hostile workplace has been created before taking action,&quot; Sophir wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company “carefully tailored&quot; its messages in firing Damore and in addressing employees afterward &quot;to affirm their right to engage in protected speech while prohibiting discrimination or harassment.&quot; Google also disciplined one of Damore’s co-workers for sending him a threatening email in response to the memo, Sophir said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-08-08/fired-googler-faces-headwinds-making-legal-case-he-s-the-victim&quot; title=&quot;Fired Google Engineer Faces Headwinds Seeking Legal Recourse (1)&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Fired Google Engineer Faces Headwinds Seeking Legal Recourse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google declined to comment on Sophir’s memo. Damore’s attorney didn’t immediately respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The labor board lawyer’s conclusion is &quot;consistent with board precedent for decades, which has viewed speech which creates a hostile environment likely to produce both discord and divisiveness as unprotected,&quot; said William Gould IV, who chaired the board under President Bill Clinton.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;In the course of protesting working conditions you can be profane and aggressive and unpleasant, you can be militant, and it’s still protected,&quot; Gould said. However, he said, &quot;What separates this is its derisiveness and stereotypical characterization of one gender.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For more on diversity in tech, check out the &lt;em&gt;Decrypted&lt;/em&gt; podcast:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;— With assistance by Hassan Kanu, and Ellen Huet&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 21:31:15 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>JoshTriplett</dc:creator>
<og:description>Google’s firing of an engineer over his controversial memo criticizing its diversity policies and “politically correct monoculture” didn’t violate U.S. labor law, a federal agency lawyer concluded.</og:description>
<og:image>https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/ic.8wfG_zdok/v0/1200x800.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Fired Google Engineer Loses Diversity Memo Challenge</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-02-16/google-firing-of-damore-was-legal-u-s-labor-panel-lawyer-said</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-02-16/google-firing-of-damore-was-legal-u-s-labor-panel-lawyer-said</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Borneo Lost More Than 100k Orangutans from 1999 to 2015</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/02/15/science/orangutans-endangered-species.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2018/02/15/science/orangutans-endangered-species.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;65&quot; data-total-count=&quot;1334&quot; id=&quot;story-continues-3&quot;&gt;[READ: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/11/04/world/africa/ape-trafficking-bonobos-orangutans.html&quot;&gt;Smuggled, Beaten and Drugged:The Illicit Global Ape Trade&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;193&quot; data-total-count=&quot;1527&quot;&gt;Orangutans, which inhabit both the Indonesian and Malaysian sides of Borneo, as well as the Indonesian region of Sumatra, are an endangered species, with some populations critically endangered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;213&quot; data-total-count=&quot;1740&quot;&gt;Their prime habitat in Borneo is lowland rain forests, which have been ravaged for decades by illegal logging operations and slash-and-burn land clearing for palm oil plantations and other agricultural activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;Photo&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/02/16/science/16TB-ORANGUTANS2/merlin_133865345_e205a453-81de-46f3-9912-b9d8b44b7758-master675.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;media-viewer-candidate&quot; data-mediaviewer-src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/02/16/science/16TB-ORANGUTANS2/merlin_133865345_e205a453-81de-46f3-9912-b9d8b44b7758-superJumbo.jpg&quot; data-mediaviewer-caption=&quot;Forest on Borneo abutting an oil palm plantation. Researchers say deforestation has been a significant driver of the orangutan&amp;#x2019;s decline.&quot; data-mediaviewer-credit=&quot;Marc Ancrenaz&quot; itemprop=&quot;url&quot; itemid=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/02/16/science/16TB-ORANGUTANS2/merlin_133865345_e205a453-81de-46f3-9912-b9d8b44b7758-master675.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;Forest on Borneo abutting an oil palm plantation. Researchers say deforestation has been a significant driver of the orangutan’s decline.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt; Marc Ancrenaz&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;336&quot; data-total-count=&quot;2076&quot;&gt;To estimate changes in the size of Borneo’s orangutan population over time, researchers representing 38 international institutions compiled field surveys conducted between 1999 and 2015. They extrapolated the overall size of the island’s population from the number of orangutan nests found throughout the species’ range in Borneo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;292&quot; data-total-count=&quot;2368&quot;&gt;The team observed 36,555 nests and estimated a loss of 148,500 orangutans during that period. The data also suggested that only 38 of the 64 identified groups of orangutans now include more than 100 individuals, which the researchers say is the lower limit to be considered a viable grouping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;73&quot; data-total-count=&quot;2441&quot;&gt;[READ: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2016/04/06/world/asia/indonesia-orangutan-borneo-fires.html&quot;&gt;Indonesia’s Orangutans Suffer as Fires Rage and Businesses Grow&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;211&quot; data-total-count=&quot;2652&quot;&gt;That would leave the surviving number at around 148,000, according to the report. However, the World Wildlife Fund estimates that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldwildlife.org/species/orangutan&quot;&gt;the remaining population of Borneo orangutans is much smaller&lt;/a&gt;, at around 105,000.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;160&quot; data-total-count=&quot;2812&quot;&gt;To identify the likely causes of orangutan population losses, the researchers relied on maps of estimated land cover change on Borneo during the 16-year period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;378&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3190&quot;&gt;The comparison of orangutan and habitat losses suggested that land clearance caused the most dramatic rates of decline. However, a much larger number of orangutans were lost in areas where there was less logging and deforestation. While the rates of decline were less in those areas, the additional forest cover means far more orangutans are found in them, the researchers said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;69&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3259&quot;&gt;[READ: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/04/25/world/asia/indonesia-borneo-orangutans-palm-oil.html&quot;&gt;A Refuge for Orangutans, and a Quandary for Environmentalists&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;436&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3695&quot;&gt;By 2015, they reported, about half of the orangutans estimated to live in Borneo in 1999 were found in areas in which human resource use has caused significant changes to the surrounding environment. Based on predicted future losses of forest cover and the assumption that orangutans ultimately cannot survive outside forest areas, the researchers predicted that more than 45,000 additional orangutans will die during the next 35 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;261&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3956&quot;&gt;“Orangutans are flexible and can survive to some extent in a mosaic of forests, plantations and logged forest, but only when they are not killed,” said Serge Wich, a professor at Liverpool John Moores University in Britain and a member of the research team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;story-ad-2&quot; class=&quot;story-ad ad ad-placeholder nocontent robots-nocontent&quot;&gt;

&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/02/15/science/orangutans-endangered-species.html#story-continues-4&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;290&quot; data-total-count=&quot;4246&quot; id=&quot;story-continues-4&quot;&gt;“So, in addition to protection of forests, we need to focus on addressing the underlying causes of orangutan killing. The latter requires public awareness and education, more effective law enforcement, and also more studies as to why people kill orangutans in the first place,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;addenda&quot; class=&quot;addenda&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Correction: February 15, 2018&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Because of an editing error, an earlier version of a headline on this article misstated the years during which a study was completed. It from 1999 to 2015, not 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/02/15/science/orangutans-endangered-species.html#whats-next&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 21:10:51 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>montrose</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/02/15/science/orangutans-endangered-species.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Borneo Lost More Than 100,000 Orangutans From 1999 to 2015</og:title>
<og:description>Deforestation on the island has harmed the primates, but a study found they also disappeared from more intact forests, suggesting people may be killing them.</og:description>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/02/16/science/16TB-ORANGUTANS1/16TB-ORANGUTANS1-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/02/15/science/orangutans-endangered-species.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Graphical linear algebra: from matrices to monoids</title>
<link>https://graphicallinearalgebra.net/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://graphicallinearalgebra.net/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Applications are open for the ACT &lt;a href=&quot;https://graphicallinearalgebra.net/2017/10/03/act-2018-applied-category-theory-research-school/&quot;&gt;Applied Category Theory Research School 2018!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And because arithmetic science and geometric science are connected, and support one another, the full knowledge of numbers cannot be presented without encountering some geometry, or without seeing that operating in this way on numbers is close to geometry; the method is full of many proofs and demonstrations that are made with geometric figures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fibonacci, preface to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Liber_Abaci&quot;&gt;Liber Abaci&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(first published 1202, 1228 manuscript translated by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.springer.com/gp/book/9780387407371&quot;&gt;Lawrence E. Sigler&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://graphicallinearalgebra.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/dec4.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;3897&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://graphicallinearalgebra.net/index/the-spanish-treasure-a-story-of-love-and-the-love-of-gold-etc-2/#main&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://graphicallinearalgebra.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/dec4.jpg&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;966,188&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Public Domain, from the British Library's collections, 2013&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;The Spanish Treasure. A story of love and the love of gold, etc&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;The Spanish Treasure. A story of love and the love of gold, etc&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://graphicallinearalgebra.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/dec4.jpg?w=414&amp;amp;h=80&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://graphicallinearalgebra.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/dec4.jpg?w=966&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-3897 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://graphicallinearalgebra.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/dec4.jpg?w=414&amp;amp;h=80&quot; alt=&quot;The Spanish Treasure. A story of love and the love of gold, etc&quot; width=&quot;414&quot; height=&quot;80&quot; srcset=&quot;https://graphicallinearalgebra.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/dec4.jpg?w=411&amp;amp;h=80 411w, https://graphicallinearalgebra.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/dec4.jpg?w=822&amp;amp;h=160 822w, https://graphicallinearalgebra.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/dec4.jpg?w=150&amp;amp;h=29 150w, https://graphicallinearalgebra.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/dec4.jpg?w=300&amp;amp;h=58 300w, https://graphicallinearalgebra.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/dec4.jpg?w=768&amp;amp;h=149 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 414px) 100vw, 414px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you like this blog, please subscribe to get email updates when new articles are published. You will find a subscription link at the bottom of this page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Graphical linear algebra is a work in progress, and there are many open research threads. We are &lt;a href=&quot;https://graphicallinearalgebra.net/thinking-about-a-phd-join-us/&quot;&gt;looking for PhD students&lt;/a&gt;, so please consider applying!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This blog is written in English. To read and contribute to translations (Dutch, French, German,…) see &lt;a href=&quot;http://vincentverheyen.com/node/38&quot;&gt;this page&lt;/a&gt; by Vincent Verheyen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Makélélé and Linear Algebra&quot; href=&quot;https://graphicallinearalgebra.net/2015/04/23/makelele-and-linear-algebra/&quot;&gt;Episode 1 &lt;/a&gt;– Makélélé and Linear Algebra&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Methodology, Handwaving, and Diagrams&quot; href=&quot;https://graphicallinearalgebra.net/2015/04/24/methodology-handwaving-and-diagrams/&quot;&gt;Episode 2&lt;/a&gt; – Methodology, Handwaving and Diagrams&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adding and Copying&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Adding (Part 1) and Mr Fibonacci&quot; href=&quot;https://graphicallinearalgebra.net/2015/04/26/adding-part-1-and-mr-fibonacci/&quot;&gt;Episode 3&lt;/a&gt; – Adding (Part 1) and Mr Fibonacci&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Dumbing Down, Magic Lego and The Rules of the Game (Part 1)&quot; href=&quot;https://graphicallinearalgebra.net/2015/04/29/dumbing-down-magic-lego-and-the-rules-of-the-game-part-1/&quot;&gt;Episode 4&lt;/a&gt; – Dumbing Down and Magic Lego&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Spoilers, Adding (Part 2) and Zero&quot; href=&quot;https://graphicallinearalgebra.net/2015/04/30/spoilers-adding-part-2-and-zero/&quot;&gt;Episode 5&lt;/a&gt; – Spoilers, Adding (Part 2) and Zero&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Crema di Mascarpone, Rules of the Game (Part 2) and Diagrammatic Reasoning&quot; href=&quot;https://graphicallinearalgebra.net/2015/05/06/crema-di-mascarpone-rules-of-the-game-part-2-and-diagrammatic-reasoning/&quot;&gt;Episode 6&lt;/a&gt; – Crema di Mascarpone and Diagrammatic Reasoning&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Copying, Discarding and The Slogan&quot; href=&quot;https://graphicallinearalgebra.net/2015/05/09/copying-discarding-and-the-slogan/&quot;&gt;Episode 7&lt;/a&gt; – Copying, Discarding and The Slogan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;When Adding met Copying…&quot; href=&quot;https://graphicallinearalgebra.net/2015/05/12/when-adding-met-copying/&quot;&gt;Episode 8&lt;/a&gt; – When Adding met Copying…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Natural numbers, diagrammatically&quot; href=&quot;https://graphicallinearalgebra.net/2015/05/16/natural-numbers-diagrammatically/&quot;&gt;Episode 9&lt;/a&gt; – Natural numbers, diagrammatically&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Matrices and PROPs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Paths and Matrices (Part 1)&quot; href=&quot;https://graphicallinearalgebra.net/2015/05/19/paths-and-matrices-part-1/&quot;&gt;Episode 10&lt;/a&gt; – Paths and Matrices&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;From diagrams to matrices&quot; href=&quot;https://graphicallinearalgebra.net/2015/05/23/from-diagrams-to-matrices/&quot;&gt;Episode 11&lt;/a&gt; – From Diagrams to Matrices&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Monoidal Categories and PROPs (Part 1)&quot; href=&quot;https://graphicallinearalgebra.net/2015/05/26/monoidal-categories-and-props-part-1/&quot;&gt;Episode 12&lt;/a&gt; – Monoidal Categories and PROPs (Part 1)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;PROPs (Part 2) and Permutations&quot; href=&quot;https://graphicallinearalgebra.net/2015/06/01/props-part-2-and-permutations/&quot;&gt;Episode 13&lt;/a&gt; – PROPs (Part 2) and Permutations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Homomorphisms of PROPs&quot; href=&quot;https://graphicallinearalgebra.net/2015/06/05/homomorphisms-of-props/&quot;&gt;Episode 14&lt;/a&gt; – Homomorphisms of PROPs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://graphicallinearalgebra.net/2015/06/09/matrices-diagrammatically/&quot;&gt;Episode 15&lt;/a&gt; – Matrices, diagrammatically&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://graphicallinearalgebra.net/2015/06/13/trust-the-homomorphism-for-it-is-fully-faithful/&quot;&gt;Episode 16&lt;/a&gt; – Trust the Homomorphism, for it is Fully Faithful&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Integers and Relations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://graphicallinearalgebra.net/2015/06/16/maths-with-diagrams/&quot;&gt;Episode 17&lt;/a&gt; – Maths with Diagrams&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://graphicallinearalgebra.net/2015/06/30/introducing-the-antipode/&quot;&gt;Episode 18&lt;/a&gt; – Introducing the Antipode&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://graphicallinearalgebra.net/2015/07/08/integer-matrices/&quot;&gt;Episode 19&lt;/a&gt; – Integer matrices&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://graphicallinearalgebra.net/2015/08/04/causality-feedback-and-relations/&quot;&gt;Episode 20&lt;/a&gt; – Causality, Feedback and Relations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://graphicallinearalgebra.net/2015/09/08/21-functions-and-relations-diagrammatically/&quot;&gt;Episode 21&lt;/a&gt; – Functions and Relations, diagrammatically&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://graphicallinearalgebra.net/2015/10/01/22-the-frobenius-equation/&quot;&gt;Episode 22&lt;/a&gt; – The Frobenius Equation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://graphicallinearalgebra.net/2015/10/21/23-frobenius-snakes-and-spiders/&quot;&gt;Episode 23&lt;/a&gt; – Frobenius Snakes and Spiders&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fractions and Spaces&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://graphicallinearalgebra.net/2015/11/18/24-bringing-it-all-together/&quot;&gt;Episode 24&lt;/a&gt; – Bringing it all together&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://graphicallinearalgebra.net/2015/11/24/25-fractions-diagrammatically/&quot;&gt;Episode 25&lt;/a&gt; – Fractions, diagrammatically&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://graphicallinearalgebra.net/2015/12/14/26-keep-calm-and-divide-by-zero/&quot;&gt;Episode 26&lt;/a&gt; – Keep Calm and Divide by Zero&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://graphicallinearalgebra.net/2015/12/26/27-linear-relations/&quot;&gt;Episode 27&lt;/a&gt; – Linear Relations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://graphicallinearalgebra.net/2016/02/03/28-subspaces-diagrammatically/&quot;&gt;Episode 28&lt;/a&gt; – Subspaces, diagrammatically&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://graphicallinearalgebra.net/2016/06/22/29-inverting-matrices-and-dividing-by-zero/&quot;&gt;Episode 29&lt;/a&gt; – Dividing by zero to invert matrices&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://graphicallinearalgebra.net/2016/08/26/30-the-essence-of-graphical-linear-algebra/&quot;&gt;Episode 30&lt;/a&gt; – The essence of graphical linear algebra&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Redundancy – A trilogy by Jason Erbele&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://graphicallinearalgebra.net/2017/10/23/episode-r1-redundancy-and-zebra-snakes/&quot;&gt;Episode R1&lt;/a&gt; – Redundancy and Zebra Snakes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interlude – string diagrams and resource-sensitive syntax&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://graphicallinearalgebra.net/2017/04/24/why-string-diagrams/&quot;&gt;Why string diagrams?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sequences and Signal Flow Graphs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://graphicallinearalgebra.net/2016/09/07/31-fibonacci-and-sustainable-rabbit-farming/&quot;&gt;Episode 31&lt;/a&gt; – Fibonacci and sustainable rabbit farming&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Out of order (for now)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://graphicallinearalgebra.net/2017/08/09/orthogonality-and-projections/&quot;&gt;Orthogonality and projections&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://graphicallinearalgebra.net/2017/09/12/eigenstuff-diagrammatically/&quot;&gt;Eigenstuff, diagrammatically&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contributions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;post__title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://graphicallinearalgebra.net/2017/07/31/determinants-and-the-lindstrom-gessel-vienot-lemma/&quot;&gt;Determinants and the Lindström-Gessel-Vienot Lemma&lt;/a&gt; – by Solomon Maina&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Offtopic&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes this blog actually looks like a blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://graphicallinearalgebra.net/2016/09/17/leicester-and-the-battle-for-universities/&quot;&gt;16 September 2016&lt;/a&gt; – Leicester and the battle for universities&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://graphicallinearalgebra.net/2017/04/16/a-monoid-is-a-category-a-category-is-a-monad-a-monad-is-a-monoid/&quot;&gt;16 April 2017&lt;/a&gt; – …, a monoid is a category, a category is a monad, a monad is a monoid, …&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://graphicallinearalgebra.net/2017/05/10/1st-workshop-on-string-diagrams-in-computation-logic-and-physics/&quot;&gt;10 May 2017&lt;/a&gt; – 1st Workshop on String Diagrams in Computation, Logic, and Physics&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://graphicallinearalgebra.net/2017/10/03/act-2018-applied-category-theory-research-school/&quot;&gt;3 October 2018&lt;/a&gt; – ACT 2018 – Applied Category Theory Research School&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;wpcnt&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wpa wpmrec&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;wpa-about&quot;&gt;Advertisements&lt;/span&gt;



&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;jp-post-flair&quot; class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-like-enabled sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;robots-nocontent sd-block sd-social sd-social-icon-text sd-sharing&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Share this:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 20:10:39 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jxub</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:title>Graphical Linear Algebra</og:title>
<og:url>https://graphicallinearalgebra.net/</og:url>
<og:image>https://graphicallinearalgebra.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/dec4.jpg?w=300</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://graphicallinearalgebra.net/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Vim Anywhere</title>
<link>https://github.com/cknadler/vim-anywhere</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/cknadler/vim-anywhere</guid>
<description>&lt;h3&gt;README.md&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, you edit text outside of Vim. These are sad times. Enter vim-anywhere!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cknadler/vim-anywhere/blob/master/assets/demo.gif&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/cknadler/vim-anywhere/raw/master/assets/demo.gif&quot; alt=&quot;demo&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cknadler/vim-anywhere#keybinding&quot;&gt;invoked&lt;/a&gt;, vim-anywhere will open a buffer. Close it and its contents are copied to your &lt;strong&gt;clipboard&lt;/strong&gt; and your previous application is refocused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Requirements&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OSX:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;MacVim (&lt;code&gt;brew install macvim&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Linux:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Gnome (or a derivative)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;gVim&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Install&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
curl -fsSL https://raw.github.com/cknadler/vim-anywhere/master/install &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; bash
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OSX caveat:&lt;/strong&gt; key binding is unbound by default. See &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cknadler/vim-anywhere#keybinding&quot;&gt;keybinding&lt;/a&gt; for details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Update&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;~&lt;/span&gt;/.vim-anywhere/update
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Uninstall&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;~&lt;/span&gt;/.vim-anywhere/uninstall
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Keybinding&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OSX:&lt;/strong&gt; ( default = unbound, suggested = &lt;code&gt;ctrl+cmd+v&lt;/code&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The keyboard shortcut for invoking vim-anywhere is unbound by default on OSX. The installation script will automatically open &lt;code&gt;System Preferences &amp;gt; Keyboard &amp;gt; Shortcuts&lt;/code&gt;. Fill in the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cknadler/vim-anywhere/blob/master/assets/shortcut.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/cknadler/vim-anywhere/raw/master/assets/shortcut.png&quot; alt=&quot;keyboard shortcut&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Linux:&lt;/strong&gt; ( default = &lt;code&gt;ctrl+alt+v&lt;/code&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gnome&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
$ gconftool -t str --set /desktop/gnome/keybindings/vim-anywhere/binding &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;custom binding&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I3WM&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
$ &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;bindsym &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;$mod&lt;/span&gt;+Alt+v exec ~/.vim-anywhere/bin/run&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;~&lt;/span&gt;/.i3/config &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; remember to reload your config after&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adjust in case &lt;code&gt;$mod&lt;/code&gt; is not set to ctrl.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;History&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;vim-anywhere creates a temporary file in &lt;code&gt;/tmp/vim-anywhere&lt;/code&gt; when invoked. These files stick around until you restart your system, giving you a temporary history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;View your history:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
$ ls /tmp/vim-anywhere
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reopen your most recent file:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
$ vim &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;$(&lt;/span&gt; ls /tmp/vim-anywhere &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; sort -r &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; head -n 1 &lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use Vim for &lt;em&gt;almost&lt;/em&gt; everything. I wish I didn't have to say &lt;em&gt;almost&lt;/em&gt;. My usual workflow is to open Vim, write, copy the text out of my current buffer and paste it into whatever application I was just using. vim-anywhere attempts to automate this process as much as possible, reducing the friction of using Vim to do more than just edit code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love vim-anywhere? Hate it? Want to change it completely? Email me or open an issue and lets talk. Pull requests, suggestions and issues of any kind are welcome with open arms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MIT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 19:44:36 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jstrieb</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars2.githubusercontent.com/u/476505?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>cknadler/vim-anywhere</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/cknadler/vim-anywhere</og:url>
<og:description>vim-anywhere - Use Vim everywhere you've always wanted to</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/cknadler/vim-anywhere</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Deodorants, perfumes, soaps pollute air at levels as high as cars</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/02/16/climate/perfume-pollution-smog.html?emc=edit_ca_20180216&amp;nl=california-today&amp;nlid=6834504&amp;te=1</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2018/02/16/climate/perfume-pollution-smog.html?emc=edit_ca_20180216&amp;nl=california-today&amp;nlid=6834504&amp;te=1</guid>
<description>&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;top-wrapper&quot; class=&quot;ResponsiveAd-topAd--3uZAv&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;top-slug&quot; class=&quot;ResponsiveAd-hide--3eu5-&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advertisement&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ResponsiveMedia-credit--3F-q_ Media-credit--1ZFho&quot; itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;accessibility-visuallyHidden--OUeHR&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Simone Noronha for The New York Times&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph--2eXNE elementStyles-paragraph--3EIcW elementStyles-toneNews--sRTft&quot;&gt;The &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2015/03/05/fashion/spray-deodorants-are-rehabilitated-with-help-from-europeans.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;styles-link--1Tap3&quot;&gt;deodorants, perfumes and soaps&lt;/a&gt; that keep us smelling good are fouling the air with a harmful type of pollution — at levels as high as emissions from today’s cars and trucks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph--2eXNE elementStyles-paragraph--3EIcW elementStyles-toneNews--sRTft&quot;&gt;That’s the surprising finding of &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://science.sciencemag.org/content/359/6377/760&quot; title=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;styles-link--1Tap3&quot;&gt;a study published Thursday in the journal Science&lt;/a&gt;. Researchers found that petroleum-based chemicals used in perfumes, paints and other consumer products can, taken together, emit as much air pollution in the form of volatile organic compounds, or V.O.C.s, as motor vehicles do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph--2eXNE elementStyles-paragraph--3EIcW elementStyles-toneNews--sRTft&quot;&gt;The V.O.C.s interact with other particles in the air to create the building blocks of smog, namely ozone, which can trigger asthma and permanently scar the lungs, and another type of pollution known as PM2.5, fine particles that are linked to heart attacks, strokes and lung cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph--2eXNE elementStyles-paragraph--3EIcW elementStyles-toneNews--sRTft&quot;&gt;Smog is generally associated with cars, but since the 1970s regulators have pushed automakers to invest in technologies that have substantially reduced V.O.C. emissions from automobiles. So the rising share of air pollution caused by things like pesticides and hair products is partly an effect of cars getting cleaner. But that breathing room has helped scientists see the invisible pollutants that arise from a spray of deodorant or a dollop of body lotion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph--2eXNE elementStyles-paragraph--3EIcW elementStyles-toneNews--sRTft&quot;&gt;The researchers said their study was inspired by &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.esrl.noaa.gov/csd/projects/calnex/synthesisreport.pdf&quot; title=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;styles-link--1Tap3&quot;&gt;earlier measurements of V.O.C.s in Los Angeles&lt;/a&gt; that showed concentrations of petroleum-based compounds at levels higher than could be predicted from fossil-fuel sources alone. Concentrations of ethanol, for example, were some five times higher than expected. And those levels were increasing over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph--2eXNE elementStyles-paragraph--3EIcW elementStyles-toneNews--sRTft&quot;&gt;“You can see these really rapid decreases in tailpipe emissions,” said Brian C. McDonald, a scientist at the Cooperative Institute for Research in Environmental Science at the University of Colorado, Boulder, who led the study. “It just made sense to start looking at other sources and seeing whether they could be growing in relative importance.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph--2eXNE elementStyles-paragraph--3EIcW elementStyles-toneNews--sRTft&quot;&gt;While people use far more fuel, by weight, than they do lotions and paints, Dr. McDonald and his colleagues found a marked difference in how much of the pollutants from those products end up in the air.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph--2eXNE elementStyles-paragraph--3EIcW elementStyles-toneNews--sRTft&quot;&gt;Even though drivers can use gallons of gasoline each week, “it’s stored in an airtight tank, it’s burned for energy, and converted mostly to carbon dioxide,” said Jessica B. Gilman, a research chemist at the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration also involved in the study. Those carbon dioxide emissions are not smog-forming V.O.C.s, though they are a major driver of human-caused climate change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph--2eXNE elementStyles-paragraph--3EIcW elementStyles-toneNews--sRTft&quot;&gt;“But these V.O.C.s that you use in everyday products — even though it may just be a teaspoon or a squirt or a spray — the majority of those kinds of compounds will ultimately end up in the atmosphere, where they can react and contribute to both harmful ozone formation and small-particle formation,” Dr. Gilman said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph--2eXNE elementStyles-paragraph--3EIcW elementStyles-toneNews--sRTft&quot;&gt;Forty percent of the chemicals added to consumer products wind up in the air, the researchers found.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph--2eXNE elementStyles-paragraph--3EIcW elementStyles-toneNews--sRTft&quot;&gt;To make their calculations, the study’s authors constructed a computer model that simulated air quality in Los Angeles, weaving in data from the chemical composition of consumer goods and tailpipe emissions. Using the model, they could see the fingerprints of the chemical compounds coming from personal care products and also estimate how many V.O.C.s from paints and finishes inside buildings were being released to the outside world. Roughly half of the V.O.C.s in Los Angeles air could be attributed to consumer products, the authors found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;ResponsiveMedia-captionText--2WFdF Media-captionText--2e27a&quot;&gt;Air pollution in Los Angeles last year.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ResponsiveMedia-credit--3F-q_ Media-credit--1ZFho&quot; itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;accessibility-visuallyHidden--OUeHR&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Frederic J. Brown/Agence France-Presse — Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph--2eXNE elementStyles-paragraph--3EIcW elementStyles-toneNews--sRTft&quot;&gt;Ravi Ramalingam, who leads the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://topics.nytimes.com/top/reference/timestopics/organizations/c/california_air_resources_board/index.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;styles-link--1Tap3&quot;&gt;California Air Resources Board’s&lt;/a&gt; consumer products and air quality efforts, said he was not surprised that paints and perfumes were making up a bigger share of emissions as cars and trucks became cleaner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph--2eXNE elementStyles-paragraph--3EIcW elementStyles-toneNews--sRTft&quot;&gt;He said his agency was surveying the chemical makeup of about 300,000 consumer products sold or used in California, and preliminary results also suggested that emissions from those products were higher than previously estimated, though by a lesser amount than Dr. McDonald and his colleagues found. He said their different methodologies likely accounted for the disparity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph--2eXNE elementStyles-paragraph--3EIcW elementStyles-toneNews--sRTft&quot;&gt;“We’re still looking for opportunities to reduce emissions from consumer products,” Mr. Ramalingam added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph--2eXNE elementStyles-paragraph--3EIcW elementStyles-toneNews--sRTft&quot;&gt;California has regulated emissions from consumer products since the late 1980s, and federal regulations have followed suit, setting &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.epa.gov/stationary-sources-air-pollution/consumer-products-national-volatile-organic-compound-emission&quot; title=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;styles-link--1Tap3&quot;&gt;V.O.C. emissions limits for a range of items&lt;/a&gt;, including paints, varnishes and lacquers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph--2eXNE elementStyles-paragraph--3EIcW elementStyles-toneNews--sRTft&quot;&gt;Concerned consumers may be tempted to turn to “natural” products, though the researchers say that isn’t a cure-all. For example, one class of compounds called terpenes gives many cleaning products a pine or citrus smell. These terpenes can be produced synthetically, or naturally from oranges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph--2eXNE elementStyles-paragraph--3EIcW elementStyles-toneNews--sRTft&quot;&gt;“But whether it’s synthetic or natural, once it gets into the atmosphere it’s incredibly reactive,” Dr. Gilman said. Similar natural compounds give the Blue Ridge Mountains in Appalachia their name, from the blue haze formed by terpenes emitted from the trees there, Dr. Gilman added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph--2eXNE elementStyles-paragraph--3EIcW elementStyles-toneNews--sRTft&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;styles-bold--rNKfn&quot;&gt;[Also read: “&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;styles-bold--rNKfn&quot;&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/1964/07/26/what-makes-the-blue-ridge-mountains-blue.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;styles-link--1Tap3&quot;&gt;What Makes the Blue Ridge Mountains Blue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;styles-bold--rNKfn&quot;&gt;,” a Times article from 1964]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph--2eXNE elementStyles-paragraph--3EIcW elementStyles-toneNews--sRTft&quot;&gt;Galina Churkina, a research fellow at the Yale School of Forestry and Environmental Studies who was not involved in the study, noted that the study did not consider emissions related to biological sources like trees and animals. But the authors said their study was not the end of this line of research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph--2eXNE elementStyles-paragraph--3EIcW elementStyles-toneNews--sRTft&quot;&gt;There are tens of thousands of chemicals in consumer products, and researchers have not yet pinpointed which chemicals are most likely to form ozone or PM2.5 particles. “One of the things that we’re hoping the public takes away from this is that our energy sources and the consumer products we use every day are continually changing the composition of our atmosphere,” Dr. Gilman said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph--2eXNE elementStyles-paragraph--3EIcW elementStyles-toneNews--sRTft&quot;&gt;Notably, some of the V.O.C.s used in consumer products were replacements for chlorofluorocarbons, or CFCs. Those chemicals were phased out beginning in the 1980s because they &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2016/07/01/science/ozone-hole-shrinking-montreal-protocol.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;styles-link--1Tap3&quot;&gt;thinned the Earth’s ozone layer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph--2eXNE elementStyles-paragraph--3EIcW elementStyles-toneNews--sRTft&quot;&gt;For consumers looking for a greener solution, Dr. McDonald offered some advice. “Use as little of the product as you can to get the job done,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-of-article&quot; readability=&quot;29.245283018868&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;elementStyles-addendums--1S4tV elementStyles-toneNews--sRTft&quot; readability=&quot;7.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;elementStyles-item--3LqVB&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;elementStyles-type--1unKw&quot;&gt;Correction:&lt;/strong&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;An earlier version of this article misstated researchers’ findings about the concentrations of ethanol found in Los Angeles’s air. The concentrations were five times higher than expected, not 10 times higher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;elementStyles-bios--3rrhp elementStyles-toneNews--sRTft&quot; readability=&quot;9.1706161137441&quot;&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;8.2822085889571&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kendra Pierre-Louis is a reporter on the climate team. Before joining The Times in 2017, she covered science and the environment for Popular Science. &lt;a class=&quot;elementStyles-biolink--aF6NI&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kendrawrites&quot;&gt;@kendrawrites&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;10.062015503876&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hiroko Tabuchi is a business reporter. She joined The Times in 2008, and was part of the team awarded the 2013 Pulitzer Prize for Explanatory Reporting. She previously wrote about Japanese economics, business and technology from Tokyo. &lt;a class=&quot;elementStyles-biolink--aF6NI&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/HirokoTabuchi&quot;&gt;@HirokoTabuchi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;elementStyles-biolink--aF6NI&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/hirokotabuchinyt&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;elementStyles-printInformation--2VtfI elementStyles-toneNews--sRTft&quot; readability=&quot;7.2727272727273&quot;&gt;A version of this article appears in print on , on Page A11 of the New York edition with the headline: Want to Save the Planet? Try Using Less Deodorant&lt;span&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytreprints.com/&quot;&gt;Order Reprints&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/pages/todayspaper/index.html&quot;&gt;Today’s Paper&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/subscriptions/Multiproduct/lp8HYKU.html?campaignId=48JQY&quot;&gt;Subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;bottom-wrapper&quot; class=&quot;ResponsiveAd-bottomAd--1hHJW ResponsiveAd-storyBodyAd--35v2w&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;bottom-slug&quot; class=&quot;ResponsiveAd-adSlug--3H3QM&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advertisement&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 19:44:09 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>joshwa</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/02/16/climate/perfume-pollution-smog.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Want Cleaner Air? Try Using Less Deodorant</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/02/15/climate/15cli-smog-illo/15cli-smog-illo-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Consumer products like perfume, pesticides and paint can contribute as much to city air pollution as cars.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/02/16/climate/perfume-pollution-smog.html?emc=edit_ca_20180216&amp;nl=california-today&amp;nlid=6834504&amp;te=1</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Learning to program is getting harder</title>
<link>http://allendowney.blogspot.com/2018/02/learning-to-program-is-getting-harder.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://allendowney.blogspot.com/2018/02/learning-to-program-is-getting-harder.html</guid>
<description>I have written several books that use Python to explain topics like Bayesian Statistics and Digital Signal Processing.  Along with the books, I provide code that readers can download from GitHub.  In order to work with this code, readers have to know some Python, but that's not enough.  They also need a computer with Python and its supporting libraries, they have to know how to download code from GitHub, and then they have to know how to run the code they downloaded.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;And that's where a lot of readers get into trouble.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;Some of them send me email.  They often express frustration, because they are trying to learn Python, or Bayesian Statistics, or Digital Signal Processing.  They are not interested in installing software, cloning repositories, or setting the Python search path!&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;I am very sympathetic to these reactions.  And in one sense, their frustration is completely justified:  it should not be as hard as it is to download a program and run it.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;But sometimes their frustration is misdirected.  Sometimes they blame Python, and sometimes they blame me.  And that's not entirely fair.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;Let me explain what I think the problems are, and then I'll suggest some solutions (or maybe just workarounds).&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;The fundamental problem is that the barrier between &lt;em&gt;using&lt;/em&gt; a computer and &lt;em&gt;programming&lt;/em&gt; a computer is getting higher.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;When I got a Commodore 64 (in 1982, I think) this barrier was non-existent.  When you turned on the computer, it loaded and ran a software development environment (SDE).  In order to do anything, you had to type at least one line of code, even if all it did was another program (like &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Archon:_The_Light_and_the_Dark&quot;&gt;Archon&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;Since then, three changes have made it incrementally harder for users to become programmers&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;1) Computer retailers stopped installing development environments by default.  As a result, anyone learning to program has to start by installing an SDE -- and that's a bigger barrier than you might expect.  Many users have never installed anything, don't know how to, or might not be allowed to.  Installing software is easier now than it used to be, but it is still error prone and can be frustrating.  If someone just wants to learn to program, they shouldn't have to learn system administration first.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;2) User interfaces shifted from command-line interfaces (CLIs) to graphical user interfaces (GUIs).  GUIs are generally easier to use, but they hide information from users about what's really happening.  When users really don't need to know, hiding information can be a good thing.  The problem is that GUIs hide a lot of information &lt;em&gt;programmers&lt;/em&gt; need to know.  So when a user decides to become a programmer, they are suddenly confronted with all the information that's been hidden from them.  If someone just wants to learn to program, they shouldn't have to learn operating system concepts first.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;3) Cloud computing has taken information hiding to a whole new level.  People using web applications often have only a vague idea of where their data is stored and what applications they can use to access it.  Many users, especially on mobile devices, don't distinguish between operating systems, applications, web browsers, and web applications.  When they upload and download data, they are often confused about where is it coming from and where it is going.  When they install something, they are often confused about what is being installed where.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;For someone who grew up with a Commodore 64, learning to program was hard enough.  For someone growing up with a cloud-connected mobile device, it is much harder.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;Well, what can we do about that?  Here are a few options (which I have given clever names):&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;1) &lt;strong&gt;Back to the future&lt;/strong&gt;: One option is to create computers, like my Commodore 64, that break down the barrier between using and programming a computer.  Part of the motivation for the Raspberry Pi, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6xFzVuxldqs&quot;&gt;according to Eben Upton&lt;/a&gt;, is to re-create the kind of environment that turns users into programmers.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;2) &lt;strong&gt;Face the pain&lt;/strong&gt;: Another option is to teach students how to set up and use a software development environment before they start programming (or at the same time).&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;3) &lt;strong&gt;Delay the pain&lt;/strong&gt;: A third option is to use cloud resources to let students start programming right away, and postpone creating their own environments.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;In one of my classes, we face the pain; students learn to use the UNIX command line interface at the same time they are learning C.  But the students in that class already know how to program, and they have live instructors to help out.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;For beginners, and especially for people working on their own, I recommend delaying the pain.  Here are some of the tools I have used:&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;div&gt;2) Entire development environments that run in a browser, like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pythonanywhere.com/&quot;&gt;PythonAnywhere&lt;/a&gt;; and&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;3) Virtual machines that contain complete development environments, which users can download and run (providing that they have, or can install, the software that runs the virtual machine).&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;4) Services like &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybinder.org/&quot;&gt;Binder&lt;/a&gt; that run development environments on remote servers, allowing users to connect using browsers.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;On various projects of mine, I have used all of these tools.  In addition to the interactive version of &quot;&lt;em&gt;How To Think...&lt;/em&gt;&quot;, there is also this &lt;a href=&quot;https://books.trinket.io/thinkjava/&quot;&gt;interactive version of &lt;em&gt;Think Java&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, adapted and hosted by &lt;a href=&quot;https://trinket.io/&quot;&gt;Trinket&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;





&lt;div&gt;These options help people get started, but they have limitations.  Sooner or later, students will want or need to install a development environment on their own computers.  But if we separate learning to program from learning to install software, their chances of success are higher.&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: Nick Coghlan suggests a fourth option, which I might call &lt;strong&gt;Embrace the Future&lt;/strong&gt;: Maybe beginners can start with cloud-based development environments, and stay there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-7tyt8mwAIfc/WociHw7ingI/AAAAAAAAEwY/-6CBZaeLv-ENh-DBjiM7gML5UlEb1UlygCLcBGAs/s1600/Screenshot%2Bat%2B2018-02-16%2B13%253A24%253A32.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;288&quot; data-original-width=&quot;613&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-7tyt8mwAIfc/WociHw7ingI/AAAAAAAAEwY/-6CBZaeLv-ENh-DBjiM7gML5UlEb1UlygCLcBGAs/s320/Screenshot%2Bat%2B2018-02-16%2B13%253A24%253A32.png&quot; width=&quot;320&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 18:59:41 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>henrik_w</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://allendowney.blogspot.com/2018/02/learning-to-program-is-getting-harder.html</og:url>
<og:title>Learning to program is getting harder</og:title>
<og:description>I have written several books that use Python to explain topics like Bayesian Statistics and Digital Signal Processing.  Along with the books...</og:description>
<og:image>https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-7tyt8mwAIfc/WociHw7ingI/AAAAAAAAEwY/-6CBZaeLv-ENh-DBjiM7gML5UlEb1UlygCLcBGAs/w1200-h630-p-k-no-nu/Screenshot%2Bat%2B2018-02-16%2B13%253A24%253A32.png</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://allendowney.blogspot.com/2018/02/learning-to-program-is-getting-harder.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>