<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Remove.bg – A service to remove the background of any photo</title>
<link>https://remove.bg</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://remove.bg</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Copyright 2018-2019 - All rights reserved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All trademarks, service marks, trade names, product names, logos and trade dress appearing on our website are the property of their respective owners. We are not affiliated with any brand or company listed in the &quot;As seen on&quot; section of our website.  This template is made with by &lt;a href=&quot;https://colorlib.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Colorlib&lt;/a&gt;. Demo Images: &lt;a href=&quot;http://unsplash.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://pexels.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Pexels&lt;/a&gt;. removebg-7b5cd567f7-8zwq6&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 02:18:26 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>August-Garcia</dc:creator>
<og:title>Remove Background from Image – remove.bg</og:title>
<og:image>https://www.remove.bg/images/samples/combined/s1.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>https://www.remove.bg</og:url>
<og:description>Remove Image Background: 100% automatically – in 5 seconds – without a single click</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.remove.bg/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Alan Kay on the Meaning of “Object-Oriented Programming” (2003)</title>
<link>http://www.purl.org/stefan_ram/pub/doc_kay_oop_en</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.purl.org/stefan_ram/pub/doc_kay_oop_en</guid>
<description>&lt;br/&gt;Date: Wed, 23 Jul 2003 09:33:31 -0800&lt;br/&gt;To: Stefan Ram [removed for privacy]&lt;br/&gt;From: Alan Kay [removed for privacy]&lt;br/&gt;Subject: Re: Clarification of &quot;object-oriented&quot;&lt;br/&gt;[some header lines removed for privacy]&lt;br/&gt;Content-Type: text/plain; charset=&quot;us-ascii&quot; ; format=&quot;flowed&quot;&lt;br/&gt;Content-Length: 4965&lt;br/&gt;Lines: 117&lt;p&gt;Hi Stefan --&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sorry for the delay but I was on vacation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At 6:27 PM +0200 7/17/03, Stefan Ram wrote:&lt;br/&gt;&amp;gt;   Dear Dr. Kay,&lt;br/&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;&amp;gt;   I would like to have some authoritative word on the term&lt;br/&gt;&amp;gt;   &quot;object-oriented programming&quot; for my tutorial page on the&lt;br/&gt;&amp;gt;   subject. The only two sources I consider to be &quot;authoritative&quot;&lt;br/&gt;&amp;gt;   are the International Standards Organization, which defines&lt;br/&gt;&amp;gt;   &quot;object-oriented&quot; in &quot;ISO/IEC 2382-15&quot;, and you, because,&lt;br/&gt;&amp;gt;   as they say, you have coined that term.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm pretty sure I did.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;&amp;gt;   Unfortunately, it is difficult to find a web page or source&lt;br/&gt;&amp;gt;   with your definition or description of that term. There are&lt;br/&gt;&amp;gt;   several reports about what you might have said in this regard&lt;br/&gt;&amp;gt;   (like &quot;inheritance, polymorphism and encapsulation&quot;), but&lt;br/&gt;&amp;gt;   these are not first-hand sources. I am also aware that later&lt;br/&gt;&amp;gt;   you put more emphasis on &quot;messaging&quot; - but I still would like&lt;br/&gt;&amp;gt;   to know about &quot;object oriented&quot;.&lt;br/&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;&amp;gt;   For the records, my tutorial page, and further distribution&lt;br/&gt;&amp;gt;   and publication could you please explain:&lt;br/&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;&amp;gt;     When and where was the term &quot;object-oriented&quot; used first?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At Utah sometime after Nov 66 when, influenced by Sketchpad, Simula, &lt;br/&gt;the design for the ARPAnet, the Burroughs B5000, and my background in &lt;br/&gt;Biology and Mathematics, I thought of an architecture for &lt;br/&gt;programming. It was probably in 1967 when someone asked me what I was &lt;br/&gt;doing, and I said: &quot;It's object-oriented programming&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The original conception of it had the following parts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;- I thought of objects being like biological cells and/or individual &lt;br/&gt;computers on a network, only able to communicate with messages (so &lt;br/&gt;messaging came at the very beginning -- it took a while to see how to &lt;br/&gt;do messaging in a programming language efficiently enough to be &lt;br/&gt;useful).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;- I wanted to get rid of data. The B5000 almost did this via its &lt;br/&gt;almost unbelievable HW architecture. I realized that the &lt;br/&gt;cell/whole-computer metaphor would get rid of data, and that &quot;&amp;lt;-&quot; &lt;br/&gt;would be just another message token (it took me quite a while to &lt;br/&gt;think this out because I really thought of all these symbols as names &lt;br/&gt;for functions and procedures.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;- My math background made me realize that each object could have &lt;br/&gt;several algebras associated with it, and there could be families of &lt;br/&gt;these, and that these would be very very useful. The term &lt;br/&gt;&quot;polymorphism&quot; was imposed much later (I think by Peter Wegner) and &lt;br/&gt;it isn't quite valid, since it really comes from the nomenclature of &lt;br/&gt;functions, and I wanted quite a bit more than functions. I made up a &lt;br/&gt;term &quot;genericity&quot; for dealing with generic behaviors in a &lt;br/&gt;quasi-algebraic form.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;- I didn't like the way Simula I or Simula 67 did inheritance &lt;br/&gt;(though I thought Nygaard and Dahl were just tremendous thinkers and &lt;br/&gt;designers). So I decided to leave out inheritance as a built-in &lt;br/&gt;feature until I understood it better.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My original experiments with this architecture were done using a &lt;br/&gt;model I adapted from van Wijngaarten's and Wirth's &quot;Generalization of &lt;br/&gt;Algol&quot; and Wirth's Euler. Both of these were rather LISP-like but &lt;br/&gt;with a more conventional readable syntax. I didn't understand the &lt;br/&gt;monster LISP idea of tangible metalanguage then, but got kind of &lt;br/&gt;close with ideas about extensible languages draw from various &lt;br/&gt;sources, including Irons' IMP.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The second phase of this was to finally understand LISP and then &lt;br/&gt;using this understanding to make much nicer and smaller and more &lt;br/&gt;powerful and more late bound understructures. Dave Fisher's thesis &lt;br/&gt;was done in &quot;McCarthy&quot; style and his ideas about extensible control &lt;br/&gt;structures were very helpful. Another big influence at this time was &lt;br/&gt;Carl Hewitt's PLANNER (which has never gotten the recognition it &lt;br/&gt;deserves, given how well and how earlier it was able to anticipate &lt;br/&gt;Prolog).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The original Smalltalk at Xerox PARC came out of the above. The &lt;br/&gt;subsequent Smalltalk's are complained about in the end of the History &lt;br/&gt;chapter: they backslid towards Simula and did not replace the &lt;br/&gt;extension mechanisms with safer ones that were anywhere near as &lt;br/&gt;useful.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;&amp;gt;     What does &quot;object-oriented [programming]&quot; mean to you?&lt;br/&gt;&amp;gt;     (No tutorial-like introduction is needed, just a short&lt;br/&gt;&amp;gt;     explanation [like &quot;programming with inheritance,&lt;br/&gt;&amp;gt;     polymorphism and encapsulation&quot;] in terms of other concepts&lt;br/&gt;&amp;gt;     for a reader familiar with them, if possible. Also, it is&lt;br/&gt;&amp;gt;     not neccessary to explain &quot;object&quot;, because I already have&lt;br/&gt;&amp;gt;     sources with your explanation of &quot;object&quot; from&lt;br/&gt;&amp;gt;     &quot;Early History of Smalltalk&quot;.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;(I'm not against types, but I don't know of any type systems that &lt;br/&gt;aren't a complete pain, so I still like dynamic typing.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;OOP to me means only messaging, local retention and protection and &lt;br/&gt;hiding of state-process, and extreme late-binding of all things. It &lt;br/&gt;can be done in Smalltalk and in LISP. There are possibly other &lt;br/&gt;systems in which this is possible, but I'm not aware of them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cheers,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alan&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;&amp;gt;   Thank you,&lt;br/&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;&amp;gt;   Stefan Ram&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;-- 
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 19:34:32 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tosh</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://userpage.fu-berlin.de/~ram/pub/pub_jf47ht81Ht/doc_kay_oop_en</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Are Human Teeth So Messed Up? (2017)</title>
<link>https://www.sapiens.org/body/human-teeth-evolution/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.sapiens.org/body/human-teeth-evolution/</guid>
<description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article was originally published at &lt;a href=&quot;https://aeon.co/ideas/its-not-that-your-teeth-are-too-big-your-jaw-is-too-small&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Aeon&lt;/a&gt; and has been republished under Creative Commons.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;first-letter letter-W&quot;&gt;W&lt;/span&gt;e hold in our mouths the legacy of our evolution. We rarely consider just how amazing our teeth are. They break food without themselves being broken, up to millions of times over the course of a lifetime; and they do it built from the very same raw materials as the foods they are breaking. Nature is truly an inspired engineer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;first-letter letter-B&quot;&gt;B&lt;/span&gt;ut our teeth are, at the same time, really messed up. Think about it. Do you have impacted wisdom teeth? Are your lower front teeth crooked or out of line? Do your uppers jut out over your lowers? Nearly all of us have to say yes to at least one of these questions, unless we’ve had dental work. It’s as if our teeth are too big to fit properly in our jaws, and there isn’t enough room in the back or front for them all. It just doesn’t make sense that such an otherwise well-designed system would be so ill-fitting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;first-letter letter-O&quot;&gt;O&lt;/span&gt;ther animals tend to have perfectly aligned teeth. Our distant hominin ancestors did too; and so do the few remaining peoples today who live a traditional hunting and gathering lifestyle. I am a dental anthropologist at the University of Arkansas, and I work with the Hadza foragers of Africa’s Great Rift Valley in Tanzania. The first thing you notice when you look into a Hadza mouth is that they’ve got a lot of teeth. Most have 20 back teeth, whereas the rest of us tend to have 16 erupted and working. Hadza also typically have a tip-to-tip bite between the upper and lower front teeth, and the edges of their lowers align to form a perfect, flawless arch. In other words, the sizes of Hadza teeth and jaws match perfectly. The same goes for our fossil forebears and for our nearest living relatives, the monkeys and apes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;drop-cap&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;first-letter letter-S&quot;&gt;S&lt;/span&gt;o why don’t&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt;our&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;teeth fit properly in the jaw? The short answer is not that our teeth are too large, but that our jaws are too small to fit them in. Let me explain. Human teeth are covered with a hard cap of enamel that forms from the inside out. The cells that make the cap move outward toward the eventual surface as the tooth forms, leaving a trail of enamel behind. If you’ve ever wondered why your teeth can’t grow or repair themselves when they break or develop cavities, it’s because the cells that make enamel die and are shed when a tooth erupts. So the sizes and shapes of our teeth are genetically preprogrammed. They cannot change in response to conditions in the mouth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;first-letter letter-B&quot;&gt;B&lt;/span&gt;ut the jaw is a different story. Its size depends both on genetics and environment; and it grows longer with heavy use, particularly during childhood, because of the way bone responds to stress. The evolutionary biologist Daniel Lieberman at Harvard University conducted an elegant&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S004724840400051X&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;study&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;in 2004 on hyraxes&lt;/a&gt; fed soft, cooked foods and tough, raw foods. Higher chewing strains resulted in more growth in the bone that anchors the teeth. He showed that the ultimate length of a jaw depends on the stress put on it during chewing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sapiens.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/02-Skull-X-Ray-Nevit-Dilmen-Wikimedia-Commons.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.sapiens.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/02-Skull-X-Ray-Nevit-Dilmen-Wikimedia-Commons-1076x717.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;messed up teeth - Human jaws, seen here in this x-ray of a torso, grow and develop any number of ways thanks to both genetics and the environment.&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-6639 size-large&quot; width=&quot;845&quot; height=&quot;563&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.sapiens.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/02-Skull-X-Ray-Nevit-Dilmen-Wikimedia-Commons-1076x717.jpg 1076w, https://www.sapiens.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/02-Skull-X-Ray-Nevit-Dilmen-Wikimedia-Commons-408x272.jpg 408w, https://www.sapiens.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/02-Skull-X-Ray-Nevit-Dilmen-Wikimedia-Commons-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.sapiens.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/02-Skull-X-Ray-Nevit-Dilmen-Wikimedia-Commons.jpg 1280w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 845px) 100vw, 845px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;The way the human jaw grows depends on a combination of genetics and diet.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;small itemprop=&quot;publisher&quot;&gt;Nevit Dilmen/&lt;a href=&quot;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Rad_1706_False_color_skull_nevit.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Wikimedia Commons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;first-letter letter-S&quot;&gt;S&lt;/span&gt;election for jaw length is based on the growth expected, given a hard or tough diet. In this way, diet determines how well jaw length matches tooth size. It is a fine balancing act, and our species has had 200,000 years to get it right. The problem for us is that, for most of that time, our ancestors didn’t feed their children the kind of mush we feed ours today. Our teeth don’t fit because they evolved instead to match the longer jaw that would develop in a more challenging strain environment. Ours are too short because we don’t give them the workout nature expects us to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;first-letter letter-T&quot;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;here’s plenty of evidence for this. The dental anthropologist Robert Corruccini at Southern Illinois University has seen the effects by&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/journal/00039969?sdc=1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;comparing&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;urban dwellers and rural peoples&lt;/a&gt; in and around the city of Chandigarh in northern India—soft breads and mashed lentils on the one hand, coarse millet and tough vegetables on the other. He has also&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/ajpa.1330620311/abstract&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;seen&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;it from one generation to the next&lt;/a&gt; in the Pima peoples of Arizona, following the opening of a commercial food-processing facility on the reservation. Diet makes a huge difference. I remember asking my wife not to cut our daughters’ meat into such small pieces when they were young. “Let them chew,” I begged. She replied that she’d rather pay for braces than have them choke. I lost that argument.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;drop-cap&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;first-letter letter-C&quot;&gt;C&lt;/span&gt;rowded, crooked, misaligned, and impacted teeth are huge problems that have clear aesthetic consequences, but can also affect chewing and lead to decay. Half of us could benefit from orthodontic treatment. Those treatments often involve pulling out or carving down teeth to match tooth row with jaw length. But does this approach really make sense from an evolutionary perspective? Some clinicians think not. And one of my colleagues at Arkansas, the bioarchaeologist Jerry Rose, has joined forces with the local orthodontist Richard Roblee with this very question in mind. Their recommendation? That clinicians should focus more on growing jaws, especially for children. For adults, surgical options for stimulating bone growth are gaining momentum, too, and can lead to shorter treatment times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;first-letter letter-A&quot;&gt;A&lt;/span&gt;s a final thought, tooth crowding isn’t the only problem that comes from a shorter jaw. Sleep apnea is another. A smaller mouth means less space for the tongue, so it can fall back more easily into the throat during sleep, potentially blocking the airway. It should come as no surprise that appliances and even surgery to pull the jaw forward are gaining traction in treating obstructive sleep apnea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;first-letter letter-F&quot;&gt;F&lt;/span&gt;or better and for worse, we hold in our mouths the legacy of our evolution. We might be stuck with an oral environment that our ancestors never had to contend with, but recognizing this can help us deal with it in better ways. Think about that the next time you smile and look in a mirror.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 19:33:23 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>BerislavLopac</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Why Are Human Teeth So Messed Up?</og:title>
<og:description>Many of us have had crooked, ill-fitting teeth at some point in our lives. The reason has a lot to do with what we eat.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.sapiens.org/body/human-teeth-evolution/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.sapiens.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/01-Braces-Monica-y-Garza-Flickr-1200x628.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.sapiens.org/body/human-teeth-evolution/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Vim Anti-Patterns (2012)</title>
<link>https://sanctum.geek.nz/arabesque/vim-anti-patterns/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://sanctum.geek.nz/arabesque/vim-anti-patterns/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The benefits of getting to grips with Vim are immense in terms of editing speed and maintaining your “flow” when you’re on a roll, whether writing code, poetry, or prose, but because the learning curve is so steep for a text editor, it’s very easy to retain habits from your time learning the editor that stick with you well into mastery. Because Vim makes you so fast and fluent, it’s especially hard to root these out because you might not even notice them, but it’s worth it. Here I’ll list some of the more common ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Moving one line at a time&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have to move more than a couple of lines, moving one line at a time by holding down &lt;code&gt;j&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;k&lt;/code&gt; is inefficient. There are many more &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.benorenstein.com/blog/jumping-long-distances-in-vim&quot;&gt;ways to move vertically&lt;/a&gt; in Vim. I find that the two most useful are moving by paragraph and by screenful, but this depends on how far and how precisely you have to move.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;{&lt;/code&gt; — Move to start of previous paragraph or code block.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;}&lt;/code&gt; — Move to end of next paragraph or code block.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Ctrl+F&lt;/code&gt; — Move forward one screenful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Ctrl+B&lt;/code&gt; — Move backward one screenful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you happen to know precisely where you want to go, navigating by searching is the way to go, searching forward with &lt;code&gt;/&lt;/code&gt; and backward with &lt;code&gt;?&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s always useful to jump &lt;em&gt;back&lt;/em&gt; to where you were, as well, which is easily enough done with two backticks, or &lt;code&gt;gi&lt;/code&gt; to go to the last place you inserted text. If you like, you can even go back and forth through your entire change list of positions with &lt;code&gt;g;&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;g,&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Moving one character at a time&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, moving one character at a time with &lt;code&gt;h&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;l&lt;/code&gt; is often a waste when you have &lt;code&gt;t&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;f&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;t&amp;lt;char&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; — Move &lt;em&gt;forward until&lt;/em&gt; the next occurrence of the character.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;f&amp;lt;char&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; — Move &lt;em&gt;forward over&lt;/em&gt; the next occurrence of the character.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;T&amp;lt;char&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; — Move &lt;em&gt;backward until&lt;/em&gt; the previous occurrence of the character.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;F&amp;lt;char&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; — Move &lt;em&gt;backward over&lt;/em&gt; the previous occurrence of the character.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moving wordwise with &lt;code&gt;w&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;W&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;b&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;B&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;e&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;E&lt;/code&gt; is better, too. Again, searching to navigate is good here, and don’t forget you can &lt;em&gt;yank&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;delete&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;change&lt;/em&gt; forward or backward to a search result:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;y/search&amp;lt;Enter&amp;gt;
y?search&amp;lt;Enter&amp;gt;
d/search&amp;lt;Enter&amp;gt;
d?search&amp;lt;Enter&amp;gt;
c/search&amp;lt;Enter&amp;gt;
c?search&amp;lt;Enter&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Searching for the word under the cursor&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t bother typing it, or yanking/pasting it; just use &lt;code&gt;*&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;#&lt;/code&gt;. It’s dizzying how much faster this feels when you use it enough for it to become automatic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Deleting, then inserting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deleting text with intent to replace it by entering insert mode immediately afterward isn’t necessary:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;d2wi
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s quicker and tidier to use &lt;code&gt;c&lt;/code&gt; for change:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;c2w
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has the added benefit of making the entire operation repeatable with the &lt;code&gt;.&lt;/code&gt; command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Using the arrow keys&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vim lets you use the arrow keys to move around in both insert and normal mode, but once you’re used to using &lt;code&gt;hjkl&lt;/code&gt; to navigate, moving to the arrow keys to move around in text feels clumsy; you should be able to spend the vast majority of a Vim session with your hands firmly centered around &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Touch_typing&quot;&gt;home row&lt;/a&gt;. Similarly, while the Home and End keys work the same way they do in most editors, there’s no particular reason to use them when functional equivalents are closer to home in &lt;code&gt;^&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;$&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So wean yourself off the arrow keys, by the simple expedient of disabling them entirely, at least temporarily:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;noremap &amp;lt;Up&amp;gt; &amp;lt;nop&amp;gt;
noremap &amp;lt;Down&amp;gt; &amp;lt;nop&amp;gt;
noremap &amp;lt;Left&amp;gt; &amp;lt;nop&amp;gt;
noremap &amp;lt;Right&amp;gt; &amp;lt;nop&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The benefits of sticking to home row aren’t simply in speed; it &lt;em&gt;feels&lt;/em&gt; nicer to be able to rest your wrists in front of the keyboard and not have to move them too far, and for some people it has even &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/vim/comments/mgt9q/vim_can_even_fix_my_body/&quot;&gt;helped prevent repetitive strain injury&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Moving in insert mode&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s an additional benefit to the above in that it will ease you into thinking less about insert mode as a mode in which you move around; that’s what normal mode is for. You should, in general, spend as little time in insert mode as possible. When you want to move, you’ll get in the habit of leaving insert mode, and moving around far more efficiently in normal mode instead. This distinction also helps to keep your insert operations more &lt;em&gt;atomic&lt;/em&gt;, and hence more useful to repeat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Moving to Escape&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Escape key on modern keyboards is a lot further from home row than it was on &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:KB_Terminal_ADM3A.svg&quot;&gt;Bill Joy’s keyboard&lt;/a&gt; back when he designed vi. Hitting Escape is usually unnecessary; Ctrl+[ is a lot closer, and more comfortable. It doesn’t take long using this combination instead to make reaching for Escape as you did when you were a newbie feel very awkward. You might also consider mapping the otherwise pretty useless Caps Lock key to be another Escape key in your operating system, or even mapping uncommon key combinations like &lt;code&gt;jj&lt;/code&gt; to Escape. I feel this is a bit drastic, but it works well for a lot of people:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;inoremap jj &amp;lt;Esc&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Moving to the start or end of the line, then inserting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just use &lt;code&gt;I&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;A&lt;/code&gt;. Again, these make the action repeatable for other lines which might need the same operation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Entering insert mode, then opening a new line&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just use &lt;code&gt;o&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;O&lt;/code&gt; to open a new line below and above respectively, and enter insert mode on it at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Entering insert mode to delete text&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a pretty obvious contradiction. Instead, delete the text by moving to it and using &lt;code&gt;d&lt;/code&gt; with an appropriate motion or text object. Again, this is repeatable, and means you’re not holding down Backspace. In general, if you’re holding down a key in Vim, there’s probably a faster way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Repeating commands or searches&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just type &lt;code&gt;@:&lt;/code&gt; for commands or &lt;code&gt;n&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;N&lt;/code&gt; for searches; Vim doesn’t forget what your last search was as soon as you stop flicking through results. If it wasn’t your most recent command or search but it’s definitely in your history, just type &lt;code&gt;q:&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;q/&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://sanctum.geek.nz/arabesque/vim-command-window/&quot;&gt;find it in the list&lt;/a&gt;, and hit Enter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Repeating substitutions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just type &lt;code&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/code&gt; to repeat the last substitution on the current line. You can repeat it on &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; lines by typing &lt;code&gt;g&amp;amp;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Repeating macro calls&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just type &lt;code&gt;@@&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are really only just a few of the common traps to avoid to increase your speed and general efficiency with the editor without requiring plugins or substantial remappings. Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://vim.wikia.com/wiki/Vim_Tips_Wiki&quot;&gt;Vim Tips wiki&lt;/a&gt; for some other really helpful examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;related-posts&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;related-posts-MRP_all&quot; class=&quot;related-posts-type&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Related Posts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 19:06:59 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>lelf</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://sanctum.geek.nz/arabesque/vim-anti-patterns/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Rust Cookbook</title>
<link>https://rust-lang-nursery.github.io/rust-cookbook/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://rust-lang-nursery.github.io/rust-cookbook/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;This &lt;em&gt;Rust Cookbook&lt;/em&gt; is a collection of simple examples that demonstrate good practices to accomplish common programming tasks, using the crates of the Rust ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://rust-lang-nursery.github.io/rust-cookbook/about.html&quot;&gt;Read more about &lt;em&gt;Rust Cookbook&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, including tips for how to read the book, how to use the examples, and notes on conventions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project is intended to be easy for new Rust programmers to contribute to, and an easy way to get involved with the Rust community. It needs and welcomes help. For details see &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang-nursery/rust-cookbook/blob/master/CONTRIBUTING.md&quot;&gt;CONTRIBUTING.md&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


























&lt;nav class=&quot;nav-wrapper&quot; aria-label=&quot;Page navigation&quot;&gt;

&lt;/nav&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 17:18:02 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ingve</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://rust-lang-nursery.github.io/rust-cookbook/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>737 MAX Explanation by a Software Engineer</title>
<link>https://twitter.com/trevorsumner/status/1106934369158078470?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1106934369158078470&amp;ref_url=https:%2F%2Fwww.zerohedge.com%2Fnews%2F2019-03-17%2Fbest-analysis-what-really-happened-boeing-737-max-pilot-software-engineer</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://twitter.com/trevorsumner/status/1106934369158078470?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1106934369158078470&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.zerohedge.com%2Fnews%2F2019-03-17%2Fbest-analysis-what-really-happened-boeing-737-max-pilot-software-engineer</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/trevorsumner/status/1106934369158078470?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1106934369158078470&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.zerohedge.com%2Fnews%2F2019-03-17%2Fbest-analysis-what-really-happened-boeing-737-max-pilot-software-engineer&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/trevorsumner/status/1106934369158078470?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1106934369158078470&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.zerohedge.com%2Fnews%2F2019-03-17%2Fbest-analysis-what-really-happened-boeing-737-max-pilot-software-engineer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19414775&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19414775&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 666&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 208&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 16:25:25 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>paulsutter</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mobile.twitter.com/trevorsumner/status/1106934369158078470?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1106934369158078470&amp;ref_url=https:%2F%2Fwww.zerohedge.com%2Fnews%2F2019-03-17%2Fbest-analysis-what-really-happened-boeing-737-max-pilot-software-engineer</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Nile shipwreck discovery proves Herodotus right</title>
<link>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2019/mar/17/nile-shipwreck-herodotus-archaeologists-thonis-heraclion</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theguardian.com/science/2019/mar/17/nile-shipwreck-herodotus-archaeologists-thonis-heraclion</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;In the fifth century BC, the Greek historian Herodotus visited &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/egypt&quot; data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Egypt&lt;/a&gt; and wrote of unusual river boats on the Nile. Twenty-three lines of his &lt;em&gt;Historia&lt;/em&gt;, the ancient world’s first great narrative history, are devoted to the intricate description of the construction of a “baris”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For centuries, scholars have argued over his account because there was no archaeological evidence that such ships ever existed. Now there is. A “fabulously preserved” wreck in the waters around the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/cities/2016/aug/15/lost-cities-6-thonis-heracleion-egypt-sunken-sea&quot; title=&quot;&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;sunken port city of Thonis-Heracleion&lt;/a&gt; has revealed just how accurate the historian was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It wasn’t until we discovered this wreck that we realised Herodotus was right,” said Dr Damian Robinson, director of &lt;a href=&quot;http://projects.arch.ox.ac.uk/ocma.html&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Oxford University’s centre for maritime archaeology&lt;/a&gt;, which is publishing the excavation’s findings. “What Herodotus described was what we were looking at.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;u-responsive-ratio&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;gu-image&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; alt=&quot;An artistic treatment of the discovered shipwreck&quot; src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/8c94b1d224fb6a40da23599aa9da78291544e576/151_0_1520_912/master/1520.jpg?width=300&amp;amp;quality=85&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=38e156d06cb78de5c755360944a3093c&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

An artistic treatment of the discovered shipwreck. The upper half of the model illustrates the wreck as excavated. Below this, unexcavated areas are mirrored to pro­duce a complete vessel outline. Photograph: Christoph Gerigk/Franck Goddio/Hilti Foundation
&lt;p&gt;In 450 BC Herodotus witnessed the construction of a baris. He noted how the builders “cut planks two cubits long [around 100cm] and arrange them like bricks”. He added: “On the strong and long tenons [pieces of wood] they insert two-cubit planks. When they have built their ship in this way, they stretch beams over them… They obturate the seams from within with papyrus. There is one rudder, passing through a hole in the keel. The mast is of acacia and the sails of papyrus...”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robinson said that previous scholars had “made some mistakes” in struggling to interpret the text without archaeological evidence. “It’s one of those enigmatic pieces. Scholars have argued exactly what it means for as long as we’ve been thinking of boats in this scholarly way,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;u-responsive-ratio&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;gu-image&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; alt=&quot;Bust of Herodotus&quot; src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/49c824a54e05d39eaa84880ea46748be41eae79e/62_292_2351_2937/master/2351.jpg?width=300&amp;amp;quality=85&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=336af3d57b63f685aa941454d948708f&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

Bust of Herodotus of Halicarnassus (c484-425 BC) Photograph: G Nimatallah/De Agostini/Getty Images
&lt;p&gt;But the excavation of what has been called Ship 17 has revealed a vast crescent-shaped hull and a previously undocumented type of construction involving thick planks assembled with tenons – just as Herodotus observed, in describing a slightly smaller vessel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Originally measuring up to 28 metres long, it is one of the first large-scale ancient Egyptian trading boats ever to have been discovered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robinson added: “Herodotus describes the boats as having long internal ribs. Nobody really knew what that meant… That structure’s never been seen archaeologically before. Then we discovered this form of construction on this particular boat and it absolutely is what Herodotus has been saying.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;u-responsive-ratio&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;gu-image&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; alt=&quot;The wooden hull of ship 17.&quot; src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/54272aa61d713677be76f6304cb86f3e6c7b0f4c/0_370_7087_4252/master/7087.jpg?width=300&amp;amp;quality=85&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=67c2c03c7c2a9630bf9a4691629f09c0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

The wooden hull of ship 17. Photograph: Christoph Gerigk/Franck Goddio/Hilti Foundation
&lt;p&gt;About 70% of the hull has survived, well-preserved in the Nile silts. Acacia planks were held together with long tenon-ribs – some almost 2m long – and fastened with pegs, creating lines of ‘internal ribs’ within the hull. It was steered using an axial rudder with two circular openings for the steering oar and a step for a mast towards the centre of the vessel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robinson said: “Where planks are joined together to form the hull, they are usually joined by mortice and tenon joints which fasten one plank to the next. Here we have a completely unique form of construction, which is not seen anywhere else.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alexander Belov, whose book on the wreck, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://projects.arch.ox.ac.uk/OCMA-publications.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Ship 17: a Baris from Thonis-Heracleion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, is published this month, suggests that the wreck’s nautical architecture is so close to Herodotus’s description, it could have been made in the very shipyard that he visited. Word-by-word analysis of his text demonstrates that almost every detail corresponds “exactly to the evidence”.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 13:54:03 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>longdefeat</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://www.theguardian.com/science/2019/mar/17/nile-shipwreck-herodotus-archaeologists-thonis-heraclion</og:url>
<og:description>Greek historian’s description of ‘baris’ vessel vindicated by archaeologists at sunken city of Thonis-Heraclion</og:description>
<og:image>https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/9522c358b4bb4c154bedec572676a3d231dffef6/0_228_7113_4267/master/7113.jpg?width=1200&amp;height=630&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;overlay-align=bottom%2Cleft&amp;overlay-width=100p&amp;overlay-base64=L2ltZy9zdGF0aWMvb3ZlcmxheXMvdG8tZGVmYXVsdC5wbmc&amp;s=0096cd71a8e22d3b1b8aa368be32d594</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Nile shipwreck discovery proves Herodotus right – after 2,469 years</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2019/mar/17/nile-shipwreck-herodotus-archaeologists-thonis-heraclion</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Japan’s elaborate, colorful manhole covers</title>
<link>https://www.atlasobscura.com/articles/japanese-manhole-covers</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.atlasobscura.com/articles/japanese-manhole-covers</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;item-body-text-graf&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;section-start-text&quot;&gt;In Japan’s glittering cities, all&lt;/span&gt; hustle and light, they can be easy to miss. With all that sensory assault, who thinks to look down and take notice of something as mundane as a manhole cover? But these are no ordinary bits of civic infrastructure. In Japan, many manhole covers are &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/28074232@N06/sets/72157612036691185/&quot;&gt;works of urban art&lt;/a&gt;—elaborate, curious, distinctive, even colorful. They have become a tourist destination unto themselves, and attract a legion of dedicated manhole enthusiasts who travel the country to visit some of the thousands of unique designs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;item-body-text-graf&quot;&gt;Japan’s decorated manhole covers—broadly encompassing storm drain, domestic water supply, electrical and other utility access covers—initially took shape as a public relations campaign for sewers. Beginning in the 1950s, the cast plates featured simple geometric patterns, such as the “&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.yahoo.co.jp/coolnobby777/folder/570411.html?m=lc&amp;amp;p=1&quot;&gt;Tokyo&lt;/a&gt;” and “Nagoya” designs. Japanese civil servant Yasutake Kameda conceived of the intricate, artistic versions in 1985, to help warm a &lt;a href=&quot;http://jgma.gr.jp/mame/history/&quot;&gt;skeptical rural population&lt;/a&gt; to the idea of the costly but necessary modernization of the country’s sewer system. From these humble, practical beginnings, manhole covers have become a cultural phenomenon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;article-image with-structured-caption lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.atlasobscura.com/assets/blank-11b9c95a68e295dddd0ea924647536578ce285b2c8469a223c01df1ff3166af1.png&quot; alt=&quot;That's 80 pounds of Hello Kitty in Tama City. &quot; width=&quot;auto&quot; data-kind=&quot;article-image&quot; id=&quot;article-image-63698&quot; data-src=&quot;https://assets.atlasobscura.com/article_images/lg/63698/image.jpg&quot;/&gt;That’s 80 pounds of Hello Kitty in Tama City. &lt;span class=&quot;caption-credit&quot;&gt;BEHROUZ MEHRI/AFP/Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;item-body-text-graf&quot;&gt;Typically, “local manholes” or “design manholes” feature elements special to a particular location: a town emblem, landmark, event, or official bird or flower. For instance, Takasaki, 60 miles northwest of Tokyo in mountainous Gunma Prefecture, has manhole covers that commemorate the city’s popular summer fireworks festival. Local mascots (known as &lt;em&gt;yurukyara&lt;/em&gt;, such as Fukaya City’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://charazoo.com/FUKKACHAN&quot;&gt;adorable rabbit-deer Fukkachan&lt;/a&gt;) and cartoon characters also appear. In Tokyo’s Tama ward, home of the Sanrio Puroland amusement park, one can find covers featuring the ever-popular Hello Kitty. Local sports franchises are also represented near the teams’ home arenas and stadiums—such as the well-known colorful depiction of the logo of the Hiroshima Carp baseball team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;item-body-text-graf&quot;&gt;While there is some logic to the placement of the covers, particularly those graced with color—usually near a landmark, theme park, or stadium—others appear to have been placed without rhyme or reason. Indeed, it is not unusual to walk down an otherwise unremarkable side street and spot a special one underfoot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;article-image with-structured-caption lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.atlasobscura.com/assets/blank-11b9c95a68e295dddd0ea924647536578ce285b2c8469a223c01df1ff3166af1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Popular baseball team Hiroshima Carp graces local manhole covers. &quot; width=&quot;auto&quot; data-kind=&quot;article-image&quot; id=&quot;article-image-63704&quot; data-src=&quot;https://assets.atlasobscura.com/article_images/63704/image.jpg&quot;/&gt;Popular baseball team Hiroshima Carp graces local manhole covers. &lt;a class=&quot;caption-credit&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Manhole_hiroshima.jpg&quot;&gt;VKaeru/Wikimedia/cropped from original/CC-BY-SA-3.0&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;item-body-text-graf&quot;&gt;The ornate manhole covers are initially carved from aluminum, which is used to make &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nippon.com/en/views/b06305/japan-and-the-art-of-making-manhole-covers-photo-gallery.html?pnum=1&quot;&gt;sand molds&lt;/a&gt; for casting. The majority of the designs are selected by local municipalities, in conjunction with manufacturers. In most cases, the design is just imprinted in the cover, but in some cases the covers get another touch—colored resins flooded into voids like enamel on jewelry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;item-body-text-graf&quot;&gt;Today an estimated &lt;a href=&quot;https://japantoday.com/category/features/drainspotting-japanese-manhole-covers&quot;&gt;95 percent&lt;/a&gt; of Japan’s 1,718 municipalities, across all 47 prefectures, now host their own unique covers. In Osaka, &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20150510072430/http:/www.sankei.com/region/news/150308/rgn1503080006-n1.html&quot;&gt;approximately 10 percent&lt;/a&gt; of the city’s 180,000 manhole covers feature ornate designs, of which roughly 1,900 get the color treatment. Typically, a designed manhole cover, which weighs more than 80 pounds, excluding the frame, costs approximately $585—a five percent premium over the cost of a plain cover. The color, however, is applied carefully by hand, and nearly doubles the price of a manhole to more than $900.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;item-body-text-graf&quot;&gt;Such is the popularity of these little urban treasures that they have a devout, organized following. There is the industry-led Japan Ground Manhole Association, and the fan-based Japanese Society of Manhole Covers, whose &lt;a href=&quot;http://usagigasi1f2.starfree.jp/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; features thousands of photographs submitted by users across Japan, who have snapped everything from large sewer covers to tiny local utility access panels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;article-image with-structured-caption lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.atlasobscura.com/assets/blank-11b9c95a68e295dddd0ea924647536578ce285b2c8469a223c01df1ff3166af1.png&quot; alt=&quot;There are some 12,000 different manhole cover designs in Japan, including this one in Kawaguchi. &quot; width=&quot;auto&quot; data-kind=&quot;article-image&quot; id=&quot;article-image-63699&quot; data-src=&quot;https://assets.atlasobscura.com/article_images/lg/63699/image.jpg&quot;/&gt;There are some 12,000 different manhole cover designs in Japan, including this one in Kawaguchi. &lt;span class=&quot;caption-credit&quot;&gt;BEHROUZ MEHRI/AFP/Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;item-body-text-graf&quot;&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.straitstimes.com/asia/east-asia/manhole-spotting-a-new-tourism-beat&quot;&gt;Manholers&lt;/a&gt;,” as they’re known, may travel to distant areas of the country just to photograph covers or collect pencil rubbings known as &lt;em&gt;takuhon&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gk-p.jp/mhcard/&quot;&gt;Trading cards&lt;/a&gt; featuring manhole designs are also popular collectors’ items, and can &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tokyoweekender.com/2016/03/japanese-decorative-manhole-covers-get-their-own-trading-cards/&quot;&gt;command&lt;/a&gt; steep prices in online auctions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;item-body-text-graf&quot;&gt;One prominent fan is &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/keibambooty&quot;&gt;Kei Takebuchi&lt;/a&gt;, a popular Tokyo-based singer-songwriter. Takebuchi traces her fascination with them to the covers of Nagoya, which feature a charming cartoon water strider insect, while she was on tour in 2015. Since then, she has regularly &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/keibambooty/status/857198046999855105&quot;&gt;tweeted&lt;/a&gt; photos of manhole covers to her nearly 200,000 followers on social media. “Every manhole cover design has [a meaning] … it tells me that we can create art with almost anything,” she says, in an interview for this story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;item-body-text-graf&quot;&gt;Like many places, Japan is full of people with unusual hobbies or obsessions, but love for the country’s manhole covers has gone mainstream: a “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.designboom.com/art/japanese-manhole-covers-festival-02-01-2019/&quot;&gt;manhole festival&lt;/a&gt;” was held near a major train station in Tokyo last month, featuring trading cards, baked goods, and replica covers from around the country. Retailer &lt;a href=&quot;https://shinjuku.tokyu-hands.co.jp/item/-2019-in.html&quot;&gt;Tokyu Hands&lt;/a&gt; ran an extended campaign at its central Shinjuku location, with a range of manhole cover–related goods for sale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;article-image with-structured-caption lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.atlasobscura.com/assets/blank-11b9c95a68e295dddd0ea924647536578ce285b2c8469a223c01df1ff3166af1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Singer Kei Takebuchi spent hours in Kawagoe City to capture this photograph of a manhole cover depicting a historic bell tower. &quot; width=&quot;auto&quot; data-kind=&quot;article-image&quot; id=&quot;article-image-63701&quot; data-src=&quot;https://assets.atlasobscura.com/article_images/63701/image.jpg&quot;/&gt;Singer Kei Takebuchi spent hours in Kawagoe City to capture this photograph of a manhole cover depicting a historic bell tower. &lt;span class=&quot;caption-credit&quot;&gt;Kei Takebuchi&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;item-body-text-graf&quot;&gt;The affinity for manhole covers also seems to tap in to Japan’s fondness for hobbies that involve lots of domestic travel. &lt;a href=&quot;http://voyapon.com/notebook-stamp-hobby/&quot;&gt;Stamp rallies—&lt;/a&gt;featuring rubber stamps at train stations and other landmarks—encourage hobbyists to travel to overlooked or lesser-visited locales to add one more stamp to their collections. “Rail-fans” similarly scour the country to document or experience a rare train carriage, an unusual station melody, or other rail-related minutia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;item-body-text-graf&quot;&gt;It is the same for manholers, with the occasionally far-flung or seemingly random placement of coveted covers—and directions of varying accuracy—adding to the sense of a scavenger hunt. Indeed, Takebuchi recounts once spending three hours on a bitterly cold day in Kawagoe City in Saitama Prefecture to snap a photo of a particular manhole cover, beautifully designed with an images of Toki no Kane, a historic bell tower. Similar stories are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thetimes.co.uk/article/manhole-covers-depicting-legends-captivate-japanese-j9mr9zlsr&quot;&gt;common currency&lt;/a&gt; in manholing circles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;item-body-text-graf&quot;&gt;Easy to overlook, but curious and rewarding, Japan’s unique manhole covers are a charming reminder that the mundane can be exciting, and that you should never forget to look down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;article-image with-structured-caption lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.atlasobscura.com/assets/blank-11b9c95a68e295dddd0ea924647536578ce285b2c8469a223c01df1ff3166af1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Not every manhole cover gets a colorful design, like this one in Matsumoto, so sometimes enthusiasts must search for them. &quot; width=&quot;auto&quot; data-kind=&quot;article-image&quot; id=&quot;article-image-63707&quot; data-src=&quot;https://assets.atlasobscura.com/article_images/63707/image.jpg&quot;/&gt;Not every manhole cover gets a colorful design, like this one in Matsumoto, so sometimes enthusiasts must search for them. &lt;a class=&quot;caption-credit&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Manhole-cover-matsumoto-colour.jpg&quot;&gt;HAL-Guandu/Wikimedia/cropped from original/CC-BY-SA-4.0&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img class=&quot;article-image with-structured-caption lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.atlasobscura.com/assets/blank-11b9c95a68e295dddd0ea924647536578ce285b2c8469a223c01df1ff3166af1.png&quot; alt=&quot;A manhole cover in Nagoya depicts a water strider. &quot; width=&quot;auto&quot; data-kind=&quot;article-image&quot; id=&quot;article-image-63702&quot; data-src=&quot;https://assets.atlasobscura.com/article_images/63702/image.jpg&quot;/&gt;A manhole cover in Nagoya depicts a water strider. &lt;a class=&quot;caption-credit&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Manhole_cover_in_Nagoya,_2014.jpg&quot;&gt;bryan…/Wikimedia/CC-BY-SA-2.0&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img class=&quot;article-image with-structured-caption lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.atlasobscura.com/assets/blank-11b9c95a68e295dddd0ea924647536578ce285b2c8469a223c01df1ff3166af1.png&quot; alt=&quot;A manhole cover in Tokyo depicting &amp;quot;fireboys.&amp;quot; &quot; width=&quot;auto&quot; data-kind=&quot;article-image&quot; id=&quot;article-image-63700&quot; data-src=&quot;https://assets.atlasobscura.com/article_images/63700/image.jpg&quot;/&gt;A manhole cover in Tokyo depicting “fireboys.” &lt;span class=&quot;caption-credit&quot;&gt;Vcarceler/Wikimedia/cropped from original/CC-BY-SA-3.0&lt;/span&gt; &lt;img class=&quot;article-image with-structured-caption lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.atlasobscura.com/assets/blank-11b9c95a68e295dddd0ea924647536578ce285b2c8469a223c01df1ff3166af1.png&quot; alt=&quot;A fish manhole in Hiroshima. &quot; width=&quot;auto&quot; data-kind=&quot;article-image&quot; id=&quot;article-image-63706&quot; data-src=&quot;https://assets.atlasobscura.com/article_images/63706/image.jpg&quot;/&gt;A fish manhole in Hiroshima. &lt;a class=&quot;caption-credit&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Manhole_fish_2.jpg%20&quot;&gt;VKaeru/Wikimedia/cropped from original/CC-BY-SA-3.0&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img class=&quot;article-image with-structured-caption lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.atlasobscura.com/assets/blank-11b9c95a68e295dddd0ea924647536578ce285b2c8469a223c01df1ff3166af1.png&quot; alt=&quot;A manhole depicting Osaka Castle. &quot; width=&quot;auto&quot; data-kind=&quot;article-image&quot; id=&quot;article-image-63705&quot; data-src=&quot;https://assets.atlasobscura.com/article_images/63705/image.jpg&quot;/&gt;A manhole depicting Osaka Castle. &lt;a class=&quot;caption-credit&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/dunhillcapina/5453277526&quot;&gt;dunhilaryu/Flickr/cropped from original/CC BY 2.0&lt;/a&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 13:40:24 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>bookofjoe</dc:creator>
<og:title>On the Hunt for Japan's Elaborate, Colorful Manhole Covers</og:title>
<og:url>http://www.atlasobscura.com/articles/japanese-manhole-covers</og:url>
<og:image>https://assets.atlasobscura.com/media/W1siZiIsInVwbG9hZHMvYXNzZXRzLzllMTAyMGM4NWI1YmEyNWM3OF9HZXR0eUltYWdlcy05MDQ2NDU1OTQuanBnIl0sWyJwIiwiY29udmVydCIsIiJdLFsicCIsImNvbnZlcnQiLCItcXVhbGl0eSA4MSAtYXV0by1vcmllbnQiXSxbInAiLCJ0aHVtYiIsIjYwMHg-Il1d/GettyImages-904645594.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Dedicated enthusiasts travel the country and scour the ground to see them.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.atlasobscura.com/articles/japanese-manhole-covers</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>What the Hell Is Going On? Effects of Information Abundance</title>
<link>https://www.perell.com/blog/what-the-hell-is-going-on</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.perell.com/blog/what-the-hell-is-going-on</guid>
<description>&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How Commerce and Mass Media are Connected&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Commerce and media are interdependent. You can’t understand commerce without understanding the media environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The union of advertisers and Mass Media shaped post-World War II commerce. Major media outlets, such as television networks and newspapers, had a monopoly on distribution to customers. Centralization in distribution mirrored the centralization in advertising agencies and media conglomerates. The four major advertising agency holding companies (Omnicom, WPP, Interpublic, and Publicis) were built for a Mass Media world with limited media outlets. These agencies lived at the heart of cultural influence. They influenced advertising, design, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.perell.com/blog/that-is-marketing&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;marketing&lt;/a&gt;, media buying, and public relations. Likewise, six global media conglomerates (Time Warner, Disney, NewsCorp, Vivendi Universal, Bertelsmann, and Viacom) controlled the production and distribution of content. Financed, in part, by relationships with the aforementioned advertising agencies, these powerful conglomerates cross-promoted their own films, magazines, books, and television series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skeptical and unaware of obscure brands, people with money to spend flocked to big brands with big-time name recognition. Habits formed. Once a person trusted a brand, they kept buying its products. From 1923-1983, in the top 25 CPG categories, 20 market leaders maintained #1 share the entire time. Spurred by steep barriers to entry for emerging competitors, advertising and shopping environments—which were defined by scarcity—ensured the continual success of America’s biggest &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.perell.com/blog/that-is-marketing&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;brands&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fueled by economies of scale, the big got bigger. In 1958, the average company in the S&amp;amp;P 500 had been there an average of 61 years. Only the biggest brands could afford television advertising and endure costly funnel inefficiencies. As Charlie Munger, Warren Buffett’s longtime business partner observed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“In effect, if you didn’t have a big volume, you couldn’t use network TV advertising — which was the most effective technique. So when TV came in, the branded companies that were already big got a huge tailwind.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a near-monopoly on television advertising, America’s biggest brands sold average products for average people in average households. Here’s how Simon Cowell, the famous American Idol judge explained his gift for identifying musical talent:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&quot;I have average tastes. If you looked in my collection of DVDs, you’d see Jaws and Star Wars. In the book library, you’d see John Grisham and Sidney Sheldon. And if you look in my fridge, it’s children’s food — chips, milkshakes, yogurt.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big brands lined the shelves of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.perell.com/blog/wal-mart&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Wal-Mart&lt;/a&gt; and the aisles at Walgreens. Small brands with unique value propositions were impossible to find. Television equalized culture. The rich and poor consumed the same entertainment at the same time. In the 1950s, 70 percent of American television sets sometimes tuned into &lt;em&gt;I Love Lucy.&lt;/em&gt; Millions of Americans were in sync. They watched the same shows at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social cohesion, at the scale of major events like &lt;em&gt;I Love Lucy&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Super Bowl&lt;/em&gt;, was impossible without Mass Media. Before television, so many people had never watched the exact same event at the exact same time. The Super Bowl is the biggest collective event left. It’s a national ritual. Every year, on the first Sunday of February, America stops to watch helmets clash on the field and celebrities perform at halftime. For most of the game, our attention is scattered between food, friends and the game. We care mostly about the chips and guacamole until the commercials,  when all conversation stops and across America, 100 million sets of eyes focus on the television in front of them. At work the next day, as you wait for your coffee to brew, everybody talks about their favorite commercials. Television networks and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.perell.com/blog/that-is-marketing&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;advertisers&lt;/a&gt; grew on the same prosperous vine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a kid, back when I was no taller than Spongebob Squarepants, I read the sports section of the newspaper every morning. Growing up in San Francisco, I had four choices: The &lt;em&gt;San Francisco Chronicle, The Oakland Tribune, The San Jose Mercury News,&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The New York Times.&lt;/em&gt; Reading the newspaper was my favorite ritual. But now, my daily sports entertainment comes from internet bloggers who tweet in their underwear. Unless I’m on an airplane with no Wi-Fi and out of battery on my phone, I won’t read the newspaper. The internet is better on every dimension: cost, convenience, depth, speed, personalization. You name it. Location no longer limits my choices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mass Media ecosystem worked in perfect balance: television networks were intertwined with the advertisers who supported them, the products they sold, and the ways consumers bought and sold products. Television. Cars. Newspapers. Beer. Radio. Deodorant. It’s an integrated system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mass market products were designed to reach the largest group of people. They served the broadest tastes. Procter &amp;amp; Gamble, which topped the list of America’s largest advertisers operated with a simple formula. As Ben Thompson wrote in &lt;a href=&quot;https://stratechery.com/2016/dollar-shave-club-and-the-disruption-of-everything/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dollar Shave Club and the Disruption of Everything&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&quot;P&amp;amp;G leveraged these resources in a simple formula that led to repeated success:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;1. Spend significant resources on developing new products (more blades!) that can command a price premium.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;2. Spend even more resources on advertising the new product (mostly on TV) to create consumer awareness and demand.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;3. Spend yet more resources to ensure the new product is front-and-center in retail locations everywhere.&quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For multiple decades, Procter &amp;amp; Gamble dominated consumer goods. You undoubtedly know their products, such as Charmin, Old-Spice, Vicks, Oral-B, Swiffer, Tide, and Mr. Clean. P&amp;amp;G grew its total addressable market with mass media advertising and distribution agreements with every major supermarket and pharmacy. They went into big box retailers, purchased finite shelf space, and expanded in-store real estate through brand extensions and favorable product placement. Gillette (owned by Procter &amp;amp; Gamble) raised prices, increased their margins, and sold “more blades for more money,” sometimes without improving the underlying product. Here’s Ben Thompson:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&quot;That’s exactly what had happened with the Mach 3, Gillette’s previous top-of-the-line model: Gillette increased blade and razor revenue by nearly 50% with basically no change in underlying demand, easily making back the $750 million it cost to research and develop the razor, simply through its ability to charge a premium for new technology, create awareness and demand through advertising, and capture consumers through retail shelf dominance.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Procter &amp;amp; Gamble's success was locked-in and impossible to deny. That lock-in was made stronger by P&amp;amp;G’s long roster of brands, which gave the company massive scale efficiencies in logistics and manufacturing. The world’s largest advertiser basically doubled its revenue every decade from 1950 to 2010. Without the consent of Retail Buyers, products didn’t make it to the shelves. Propelled by strong relationships with those buyers and access to shelf space, a scarce resource in the pre-internet economy, Procter &amp;amp; Gamble ensured prime product placement in retail stores and commanded a price premium as a result.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 13:17:25 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tosh</dc:creator>
<og:title>What the Hell is Going On?</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.perell.com/blog/what-the-hell-is-going-on</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Let’s play a game. I’m going to describe your least favorite politician: Everything they say goes viral. The establishment despises them, donors can’t influence them, and the media can’t tame them. They’ve ignored the traditional rules of politics and now, politics will never be the same. Their su</og:description>
<og:image>http://static1.squarespace.com/static/55576406e4b02e4679105dc2/55576b2ae4b0a213bdd2fc6a/5c854a740d9297e183c20fff/1552876564862/wojtek-witkowski-275-unsplash.jpg?format=1500w</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.perell.com/blog/what-the-hell-is-going-on</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Thinkpad X210</title>
<link>https://geoff.greer.fm/2019/03/04/thinkpad-x210/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://geoff.greer.fm/2019/03/04/thinkpad-x210/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;A couple years ago, &lt;a href=&quot;https://geoff.greer.fm/2017/01/23/oldest-viable-laptop/&quot;&gt;I used an old Thinkpad while my MacBook was being repaired&lt;/a&gt;. I enjoyed the experience so much that &lt;a href=&quot;https://geoff.greer.fm/2017/07/16/thinkpad-x62/&quot;&gt;I ended up getting a Thinkpad X62&lt;/a&gt; (an X61 chassis with modern internals). Last September, the maker of the X62 announced that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/lcdfans/posts/2144170785850022&quot;&gt;a 3rd batch of X210s would be made&lt;/a&gt;. I ordered one and received it in January. China has a bunch of laws that make it hard to move money across borders, so payment involved wiring $1200 to someone’s personal bank account in China, then e-mailing a qq.com address. It was a rather harrowing experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://geoff.greer.fm/images/x210.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My X210. Fonts are huge so that you can read screenfetch.&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like the X62, the X210 is made by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/lcdfans&quot;&gt;51NB&lt;/a&gt;, a group of enthusiasts in Shenzhen. The X210 is an X201 chassis with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;https://ark.intel.com/products/122589/Intel-Core-i7-8550U-Processor-8M-Cache-up-to-4-00-GHz-&quot;&gt;Core i7 8550u&lt;/a&gt; (4 cores, turbo boost up to 4GHz)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2× DDR4 SODIMM slots. I put 32 GB of RAM in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2× mini PCI Express slots. There’s an 802.11/Bluetooth card in one. The other is empty but could be used for LTE or a second wireless card.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An M.2 NVMe slot. I put a 2TB SSD in it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A 3.5” SATA bay. I left it empty, but it’s possible to put a second SSD in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An upgraded screen (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.panelook.com/NV126A1M-N52_BOE_12.6_LCM_overview_28762.html&quot;&gt;12.6 inch, 2880×1920, 450 nits, wide gamut&lt;/a&gt;). The bezel is cut to make room for the 3:2 aspect ratio. There is no webcam.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mini DisplayPort &amp;amp; VGA out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3× USB 3.1 ports (no USB-C).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SD card reader.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gigabit ethernet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Physical switch to toggle Wifi/Bluetooth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Headphone &amp;amp; microphone jacks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Internal microphone &amp;amp; speakers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The X210 is sold as either a motherboard that you install into your own chassis or as a barebones laptop where you bring your own RAM, SSD, and battery. I got the barebones kit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-impressions&quot;&gt;My Impressions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I slightly prefer the X62’s more compact keyboard, but everything else is much better on the X210. The CPU is over twice as fast and runs cooler. The wifi is faster. The SSD is faster. The screen is &lt;em&gt;gorgeous&lt;/em&gt;. it’s a 12.6” screen with a higher resolution than the 15” MacBook Pro. Overall, it’s just plain better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linux worked out of the box. I had to install non-free drivers for the Broadcom wireless card, then tweak a few module options to get better power saving. Battery life is a little over 4 hours with the flush battery (55Wh) and 6-7 hours with the extended battery (80Wh). I haven’t finished tweaking all the power saving options, so the lowest idle state is PC3. Battery life would increase by 50% if I got PC6 or PC8 idle states. The fan only turns on if I’m doing something intensive like compiling go or scrolling in Slack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update (2017-03-17): I managed to get PC7 idle by upgrading my kernel to 4.18 and replacing the r8168 module with r8169. Battery life has increased significantly. I now get 6 hours with the flush battery and 10 hours with the extended battery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like most older Thinkpads, the X210 is easily repaired and upgraded. You can swap the battery in seconds without any tools. If the SSD fails, you can replace it. If the RAM fails, you can replace it. If the wifi card fails, you can replace it. If the screen fails, you can replace it. You can even replace the Trackpoint and the little rubber feet without much trouble. The laptop can be entirely disassembled with two Philips screwheads (#0 and #1). At no point do you encounter tape, glue, or pentalobe screws.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;caveats&quot;&gt;Caveats&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The X210 isn’t perfect. It’s made by a group of enthusiasts, not a big company. With that comes some disadvantages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Like the X62, the mini DisplayPort cannot output in HDMI alternate mode. This means that miniDP→HDMI dongles won’t work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I sometimes notice &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pulse-width_modulation&quot;&gt;PWM&lt;/a&gt; flicker on the screen. This only happens at the lowest brightness in a dark room when displaying mostly black content. I can see afterimages when my eyes &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Saccade&quot;&gt;saccade&lt;/a&gt;, similar to some brake lights at night. It’s about as noticeable as the PWM flicker on my iPhone X.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the motherboard breaks, you can’t walk into a store and get it replaced or repaired. Your only recourse is to e-mail the manufacturer and ship it back to China. I’ve only read about one case of this happening, and in that case the motherboard was DOA. The unfortunate user was shipped a new one within a few weeks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love this laptop. It addresses almost all of the issues I had with the X62: better screen, better performance, and better microphone quality. More than anything, the X210 demonstrates just how much potential is being squandered by laptop manufacturers. If a small group in Shenzhen can make this laptop, Lenovo or Apple should be able to build something far better. Instead they make laptops with integrated batteries, fewer ports, soldered RAM, sub-par keyboards, and touchbars. Many professionals want something better.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:hn&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope 51NB continues to build new internals for old chassis, because I doubt the major laptop manufacturers will get their heads out of their asses any time soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 11:21:16 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>MYEUHD</dc:creator>
<og:title>Thinkpad X210</og:title>
<og:url>https://geoff.greer.fm/2019/03/04/thinkpad-x210/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://geoff.greer.fm/me-2017.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>A couple years ago, I used an old Thinkpad while my MacBook was being repaired. I enjoyed the experience so much that I ended up getting a Thinkpad X62 (an X61 chassis with modern internals). Last S…</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://geoff.greer.fm/2019/03/04/thinkpad-x210/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>