<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>How We Saved Dot Org</title>
<link>https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2020/12/how-we-saved-org-2020-review</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2020/12/how-we-saved-org-2020-review</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;If you come at the nonprofit sector, you’d best not miss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nonprofits and NGOs around the world were stunned last November when the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2019/11/20/org_registry_sale_shambles/&quot;&gt;Internet Society (ISOC) announced that it had agreed to sell the Public Interest Registry&lt;/a&gt;—the organization that manages the .ORG top-level domain (TLD)—to private equity firm Ethos Capital. EFF and other leaders in the NGO community sprung to action, writing a letter to ISOC &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2019/11/nonprofit-community-stands-together-protect-org&quot;&gt;urging it to stop the sale&lt;/a&gt;. What follows was possibly &lt;a href=&quot;https://savedotorg.org/&quot;&gt;the most dramatic show of solidarity from the nonprofit sector of all time&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/05/01/technology/dot-org-sale.html&quot;&gt;And we won&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;pull-quote&quot;&gt;Oversight by a nonprofit was always part of the plan for .ORG.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to the announcement, EFF had spent six months &lt;a href=&quot;https://mm.icann.org/pipermail/comments-org-renewal-18mar19/2019q2/003200.html&quot;&gt;voicing our concerns to the Internet Corporation for Assigned Names and Numbers (ICANN)&lt;/a&gt; about the 2019 .ORG Registry Agreement, which gave the owner of .ORG new powers to censor nonprofits’ websites (the agreement also &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.namecheap.com/blog/ensuring-icann-keep-domain-prices-in-check/&quot;&gt;lifted a longstanding price cap&lt;/a&gt; on .ORG registrations and renewals).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Registry Agreement gave the owner of .ORG the power to implement processes to suspend domain names based on accusations of “activity contrary to applicable law.” It effectively created a new pressure point that repressive governments, corporations, and other bad actors can use to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2019/12/we-need-save-org-arbitrary-censorship-halting-private-equity-buy-out&quot;&gt;silence their critics without going through a court&lt;/a&gt;. That should alarm &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; nonprofit or NGO, especially those that work under repressive regimes or frequently criticize powerful corporations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout that six-month process of navigating ICANN’s labyrinthine decision-making structure, none of us knew that ISOC would soon be selling PIR. With .ORG in the hands of a private equity firm, those fears of censorship and price gouging became a lot more tangible for nonprofits and NGOs. &lt;a href=&quot;https://apnews.com/article/4b4c0687283f774b855e7d5b5bee4744&quot;&gt;The power to take advantage of .ORG users was being handed to a for-profit company&lt;/a&gt; whose primary obligation was to make money for its investors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oversight by a nonprofit was always part of the plan for .ORG. When &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.icann.org/en/meetings/bucharest/captioning-evening-26jun02.htm&quot;&gt;ISOC competed in 2002 for the contract to manage the TLD&lt;/a&gt;, it used its nonprofit status as a major selling point. As ISOC’s then president Lynn St. Amour put it, PIR would “draw upon the resources of ISOC’s extended global network to drive policy and management.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More NGOs began to take notice of the .ORG sale and the danger it posed to nonprofits’ freedom of expression online. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2019/12/global-ngo-community-demands-stop-sale-org&quot;&gt;Over 500 organizations and 18,000 individuals had signed our letter by the end of 2019&lt;/a&gt;, including big-name organizations like Greenpeace, Consumer Reports, Oxfam, and the YMCA of the USA. At the same time, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.icann.org/en/system/files/correspondence/mitchell-woodcock-to-jeffrey-12dec19-en.pdf&quot;&gt;questions began to emerge&lt;/a&gt; (PDF) about whether Ethos Capital could possibly make a profit without some drastic changes in policy for .ORG.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the beginning of 2020, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2020/01/icann-needs-ask-more-questions-about-sale-org&quot;&gt;the financial picture had become a lot clearer&lt;/a&gt;: Ethos Capital was paying $1.135 billion for .ORG, nearly a third of which was financed by a loan. No matter how well-meaning Ethos was, the pressure to sell “censorship as a service” would align with Ethos’ obligation to produce returns for its investors. The sector’s concerns were well-founded: the registry Donuts entered a private deal with the Motion Picture Association in 2016 to fast-track suspensions of domains that MPA claims infringe on its members’ copyrights. It’s fair to ask whether PIR would engage in similar practices under the leadership of Donuts co-founder Jonathon Nevett. Six members of Congress &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.warren.senate.gov/oversight/letters/lawmakers-urge-internet-governing-body-to-block-private-equity-firm-ethos-capital-from-taking-over-the-org-internet-domain-name-registry&quot;&gt;wrote a letter to ICANN in January&lt;/a&gt; urging it to scrutinize the sale more carefully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few days later, EFF, nonprofit advocacy group NTEN, and digital rights groups Fight for the Future and Demand Progress participated in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/press/releases/eff-activists-demonstrate-against-sell-out-org-private-equity-los-angeles-protest&quot;&gt;rally outside of the ICANN headquarters&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;in Los Angeles&lt;/span&gt;. Our message was simple: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NMBh3C9o5gQ&quot;&gt;stop the sale and create protections for nonprofits&lt;/a&gt;. Before the protest, ICANN staff reached out to the organizers offering to meet with us in person, but on the day of the protest, ICANN canceled on us. That same week, Amnesty International, Access Now, the Sierra Club, and other global NGOs held a press conference at the World Economic Forum to tell world leaders that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2020/01/after-nonprofits-protest-icann-californias-attorney-general-steps-org-battle&quot;&gt;selling .ORG threatens civil society&lt;/a&gt;. All of the noise caught the attention of California Attorney General Xavier Becerra, who &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.icann.org/en/system/files/correspondence/jeffrey-to-nevett-30jan20-en.pdf&quot;&gt;wrote to ICANN&lt;/a&gt; (PDF) asking it for key information about its review of the sale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;pull-quote&quot;&gt;COVID-19 demonstrated that the NGO community doesn’t need fancy “products and services” from a domain registry: it needs simple, reliable, &lt;em&gt;boring&lt;/em&gt; service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recognizing that the heat was on, Ethos Capital and PIR hastily tried to build bridges with the nonprofit sector. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2020/02/empty-promises-wont-save-org-takeover&quot;&gt;Ethos attempted to convene a secret meeting with NGO sector leaders in February&lt;/a&gt;, and then abruptly canceled it. Ethos then announced that it would voluntarily limit price increases on .ORG registrations and renewals and establish a “stewardship council.” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2020/03/ngo-community-urges-icann-scrutinize-org-sale&quot;&gt;Like many details of the .ORG sale&lt;/a&gt;, what level of influence the stewardship council would have over PIR’s decisions was unclear. EFF executive director Cindy Cohn and NTEN CEO Amy Sample Ward &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thenonprofittimes.com/npt_articles/commentary-org-still-wouldnt-be-safe/&quot;&gt;responded in the Nonprofit Times&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The proposed “Stewardship Council” would fail to protect the interests of the NGO community. First, the council is not independent. The Public Interest Registry (PIR) board’s ability to veto nominated members would ensure that the council will not include members willing to challenge Ethos’ decisions. PIR’s handpicked members are likely to retain their seats indefinitely. The NGO community must have a real say in the direction of the .ORG registry, not a nominal rubber stamp exercised by people who owe their position to PIR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even Ethos’ promise to limit fee increases was rather hollow: if Ethos raised fees as allowed by the proposed rules, the price of .ORG registrations would more than double over eight years. After those eight years, there would be no limits on free increases whatsoever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the while, Ethos and PIR kept touting that with the new ownership would come &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2020/03/org-isnt-broken-and-we-dont-need-private-equity-fix-it&quot;&gt;new “products and services” for .ORG users&lt;/a&gt;, but it failed to give any information about what those offerings might entail. Cohn and Ward responded:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The product NGOs need from our registry operator is domain registration at a fair price that doesn’t increase arbitrarily. The service that operator must provide is to stand up to governments and other powerful actors when they demand that it silence us. It is more clear than ever that you cannot offer us either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s almost poetic that the debate over .ORG reached a climax just as COVID-19 was becoming a worldwide crisis. Emergencies like this one are when the world most relies on nonprofits and NGOs; therefore, they’re also &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2020/04/eff-other-nonprofits-and-californias-ag-tell-icann-stop-private-equity-takeover&quot;&gt;pressure tests for the sector&lt;/a&gt;. The crisis demonstrated that the NGO community doesn’t need fancy “products and services” from a domain registry: it needs simple, reliable, &lt;em&gt;boring&lt;/em&gt; service. Those same members of Congress who’d scrutinized the .ORG sale wrote a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.warren.senate.gov/imo/media/doc/2020.03.18%20Follow-up%20letter%20to%20ICANN%20about%20sale%20of%20.ORG%20registry.pdf&quot;&gt;more pointed letter to ICANN in March&lt;/a&gt; (PDF), plainly noting that there was no way that Ethos Capital could make a profit on its investment without making major changes at the expense of .ORG users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, in April, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2020/04/victory-icann-rejects-org-sale-private-equity-firm-ethos-capital&quot;&gt;the ICANN board rejected the transfer of ownership of .ORG&lt;/a&gt;. “ICANN entrusted to PIR the responsibility to serve the public interest in its operation of the .ORG registry,” they wrote, “and now ICANN is being asked to transfer that trust to a new entity without a public interest mandate.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While .ORG is safe for now, the bigger trend of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/free-speech-weak-link&quot;&gt;registries becoming chokepoints for free speech online&lt;/a&gt; is as big a problem as ever. That’s why &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2020/11/icann-can-stand-against-censorship-and-avoid-another-org-debacle-keeping-content&quot;&gt;EFF is urging ICANN to reconsider its policies&lt;/a&gt; regarding public interest commitments—or as the Internet governance community has recently started calling them, registry voluntary commitments. Those are the additional rules that ICANN allows registries to set for specific top-level domains, like the new provisions in the .ORG Registry Agreement that allow the owner of .ORG to set policies to fast-track censoring speech online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story of the attempted .ORG sale is really the story of the power and resilience of the nonprofit sector. Every time Ethos and PIR tried to quell the backlash with empty promises, the sector responded even more loudly, gaining the voices of government officials, members of Congress, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.icann.org/en/system/files/correspondence/kaye-voule-to-marby-20dec19-en.pdf&quot;&gt;two UN Special Rapporteurs&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nasconet.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/NASCO-ltr-011720.pdf&quot;&gt;U.S. state charities regulators&lt;/a&gt;. As I said to that crowd of activists in front of ICANN’s offices, I’ve worked in the nonprofit sector for most of my adult life, and I’ve never seen the sector respond this unanimously to &lt;em&gt;anything&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you to everyone who stood up for .ORG, especially NTEN for its partnership on this campaign as a trusted leader in the nonprofit sector. If you were one of the 27,183 people who signed our open letter, or if you work for or support one of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/pages/coalition-letter-internet-society&quot;&gt;871 organizations that participated&lt;/a&gt;, then you were a part of this victory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article is part of our Year in Review series. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2020/12/2020-review&quot;&gt;Read other articles about the fight for digital rights in 2020&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 20:31:12 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>thomasahle</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>How We Saved .ORG: 2020 in Review</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2020/12/how-we-saved-org-2020-review</og:url>
<og:description>If you come at the nonprofit sector, you’d best not miss.Nonprofits and NGOs around the world were stunned last November when the Internet Society (ISOC) announced that it had agreed to sell the Public Interest Registry—the organization that manages the .ORG top-level domain (TLD)—to private equity...</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.eff.org/files/banner_library/2020-dark-2.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2020/12/how-we-saved-org-2020-review</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Google/Fitbit will monetise health data and harm consumers [pdf]</title>
<link>https://cepr.org/sites/default/files/policy_insights/PolicyInsight107.pdf</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://cepr.org/sites/default/files/policy_insights/PolicyInsight107.pdf</guid>
<description>&lt;a href=&quot;https://cepr.org/sites/default/files/policy_insights/PolicyInsight107.pdf&quot;&gt;Download PDF&lt;/a&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 18:50:41 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>partingshots</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>How We Saved .ORG: 2020 in Review</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2020/12/how-we-saved-org-2020-review</og:url>
<og:description>If you come at the nonprofit sector, you’d best not miss.Nonprofits and NGOs around the world were stunned last November when the Internet Society (ISOC) announced that it had agreed to sell the Public Interest Registry—the organization that manages the .ORG top-level domain (TLD)—to private equity...</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.eff.org/files/banner_library/2020-dark-2.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://cepr.org/sites/default/files/policy_insights/PolicyInsight107.pdf</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Comic Mono</title>
<link>https://dtinth.github.io/comic-mono-font/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://dtinth.github.io/comic-mono-font/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;A legible monospace font… the very typeface you’ve been trained to recognize since childhood. This font is a fork of &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/shannpersand&quot;&gt;Shannon Miwa&lt;/a&gt;’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/shannpersand/comic-shanns&quot;&gt;Comic Shanns&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;website-hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dtinth.github.io/comic-mono-font/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://repository-images.githubusercontent.com/164606802/cd83d680-894c-11e9-83f7-c353c70df1cb&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;download&quot;&gt;Download&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;differences-from-comic-shanns&quot;&gt;Differences from Comic Shanns&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;All glyphs have been adjusted to have exactly the same width (using code based on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cpitclaudel/monospacifier&quot;&gt;monospacifier&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The glyph metrics have been adjusted to make it display better alongside system font, based on &lt;a href=&quot;https://fonts.google.com/specimen/Cousine&quot;&gt;Cousine&lt;/a&gt;’s metrics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The name is changed to &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Comic Mono&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A bold version of the font is generated using &lt;a href=&quot;https://fontforge.github.io/Styles.html#Embolden&quot;&gt;FontForge’s Embolden&lt;/a&gt; operation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have no font creation skills; I’m just a software developer. This font family is created by patching the original font, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/shannpersand/comic-shanns&quot;&gt;Comic Shanns&lt;/a&gt;, using a Python script, &lt;a href=&quot;https://dtinth.github.io/comic-mono-font/generate.py&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;generate.py&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-does-it-look-like&quot;&gt;What does it look like?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;website-hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dtinth.github.io/comic-mono-font/#what-does-it-look-like&quot;&gt;Check it out!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-python highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;21.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;38&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#!/usr/bin/env python2
# -*- coding: utf-8 -*-
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;&quot;&quot;
Generates the Comic Mono font files based on Comic Shanns font.

Required files:
- vendor/comic-shanns.otf
- vendor/Cousine-Regular.ttf

Based on:
- monospacifier: https://github.com/cpitclaudel/monospacifier/blob/master/monospacifier.py
- YosemiteAndElCapitanSystemFontPatcher: https://github.com/dtinth/YosemiteAndElCapitanSystemFontPatcher/blob/master/bin/patch
&quot;&quot;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;kn&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;os&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;kn&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;re&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;kn&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;sys&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;reload&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;sys&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;sys&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;setdefaultencoding&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;'UTF8'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;kn&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;fontforge&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;kn&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;psMat&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;kn&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;unicodedata&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;height&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;font&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;):&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;float&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;font&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;capHeight&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;adjust_height&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;source&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;template&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;scale&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;):&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;source&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;selection&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;all&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;source&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;transform&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;psMat&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;scale&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;height&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;template&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;height&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;source&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)))&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;attr&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;'ascent'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;'descent'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;'hhea_ascent'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;'hhea_ascent_add'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;'hhea_linegap'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;'hhea_descent'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;'hhea_descent_add'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;'os2_winascent'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;'os2_winascent_add'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;'os2_windescent'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;'os2_windescent_add'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;'os2_typoascent'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;'os2_typoascent_add'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;'os2_typodescent'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;'os2_typodescent_add'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]:&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;setattr&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;source&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;attr&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;getattr&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;template&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;attr&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;source&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;transform&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;psMat&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;scale&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;scale&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;font&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;fontforge&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;open&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;'vendor/comic-shanns.otf'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ref&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;fontforge&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;open&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;'vendor/Cousine-Regular.ttf'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;g&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;font&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;glyphs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;():&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;uni&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;g&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;unicode&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;category&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;unicodedata&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;category&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;unichr&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;uni&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;uni&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;sys&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;maxunicode&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;else&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;None&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;g&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;width&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;category&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;not&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;'Mn'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;'Mc'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;'Me'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]:&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;target_width&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;510&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;g&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;width&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;!=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;target_width&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;delta&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;target_width&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;g&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;width&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;g&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;left_side_bearing&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;delta&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;g&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;right_side_bearing&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;delta&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;g&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;left_side_bearing&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;g&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;width&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;target_width&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;font&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;familyname&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;'Comic Mono'&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;font&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;version&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;'0.1.1'&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;font&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;comment&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;'https://github.com/dtinth/comic-mono-font'&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;font&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;copyright&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;'https://github.com/dtinth/comic-mono-font/blob/master/LICENSE'&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;adjust_height&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;font&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ref&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mf&quot;&gt;0.875&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;font&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;sfnt_names&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;# Get rid of 'Prefered Name' etc.
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;font&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;fontname&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;'ComicMono'&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;font&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;fullname&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;'Comic Mono'&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;font&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;generate&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;'ComicMono.ttf'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;font&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;selection&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;all&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;font&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;fontname&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;'ComicMono-Bold'&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;font&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;fullname&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;'Comic Mono Bold'&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;font&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;weight&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;'Bold'&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;font&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;changeWeight&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;32&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;LCG&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;squish&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;font&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;generate&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;'ComicMono-Bold.ttf'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;cdn&quot;&gt;CDN&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use this font in your web pages by including the stylesheet. CDN is provided by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jsdelivr.com/package/npm/comic-mono&quot;&gt;jsDelivr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-html highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;link&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;rel=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;stylesheet&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;href=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/npm/comic-mono@0.0.1/index.css&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;npm-package&quot;&gt;npm Package&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This package is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npmjs.com/package/comic-mono&quot;&gt;published to npm&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;packages-published-by-third-parties&quot;&gt;Packages published by third parties&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;license&quot;&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is licensed under the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dtinth.github.io/comic-mono-font/LICENSE&quot;&gt;MIT License&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 18:29:50 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>thesephist</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://repository-images.githubusercontent.com/164606802/cd83d680-894c-11e9-83f7-c353c70df1cb</og:image>
<og:title>Comic Mono</og:title>
<og:description>A legible monospace font… the very typeface you’ve been trained to recognize since childhood</og:description>
<og:url>https://dtinth.github.io/comic-mono-font/</og:url>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://dtinth.github.io/comic-mono-font/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>No, Cellebrite Cannot “Break Signal Encryption”</title>
<link>https://signal.org/blog/cellebrite-and-clickbait/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://signal.org/blog/cellebrite-and-clickbait/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, the BBC ran a story with the factually untrue headline, “Cellebrite claimed to have cracked chat app’s encryption.” This is false. Not only can Cellebrite not break Signal encryption, but Cellebrite never even claimed to be able to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we weren’t actually given the opportunity to comment in that story, we’re posting this to help to clarify things for anyone who may have seen the headline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;this-world-of-ours&quot;&gt;This world of ours&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week, Cellebrite posted a pretty embarrassing (for them) technical article to their blog documenting the “advanced techniques” they use to parse Signal on an Android device they physically have with the screen unlocked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a situation where someone is holding an unlocked phone in their hands and could simply open the app to look at the messages in it. Their post was about doing the same thing programmatically (which is equally simple), but they wrote an entire article about the “challenges” they overcame, and concluded that “…it required extensive research on many different fronts to create new capabilities from scratch.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This made us scratch our heads. If this required “research,” it doesn’t inspire much awe for their existing capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to know how a post like that got out the door or why anyone thought revealing such limited abilities was in their interest. Based on the initial reception, Cellebrite must have realized that amateur hour was not a good look, and the post was quickly taken down. They then must have realized that a 404 error isn’t any better, and replaced that again with a vague summary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s also hard to know how such an embarrassing turn of events became anything other than a disaster for Cellebrite, but several news outlets, including the BBC, published articles about Cellebrite’s “success,” despite the existence of clarifying information already available online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-really-happened&quot;&gt;What really happened&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you have your device, Cellebrite is not your concern.&lt;/strong&gt; It is important to understand that any story about Cellebrite Physical Analyzer starts with someone other than you physically holding your device, with the screen unlocked, in their hands. Cellebrite does &lt;em&gt;not even try&lt;/em&gt; to intercept messages, voice/video, or live communication, much less “break the encryption” of that communication. They don’t do live surveillance of any kind.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cellebrite is not magic.&lt;/strong&gt; Imagine that someone is physically holding your device, with the screen unlocked, in their hands. If they wanted to create a record of what’s on your device right then, they could simply open each app on your device and take screenshots of what’s there. This is what Cellebrite Physical Analyser does. It automates the process of creating that record. However, because it’s automated, it has to know how each app is structured, so it’s actually &lt;em&gt;less reliable&lt;/em&gt; than if someone were to simply open the apps and manually take the screenshots. It is not magic, it is mediocre enterprise software.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cellebrite did not “accidentally reveal” their secrets.&lt;/strong&gt; This article, and others, were written based on a poor interpretation of a Cellebrite blog post about adding Signal support to Cellebrite Physical Analyzer. Cellebrite posted something with a lot of detail, then quickly took it down and replaced it with something that has no detail. This is not because they “revealed” anything about some super advanced technique they have developed (remember, this is a situation where someone could just open the app and look at the messages). They took it down for the exact opposite reason: it made them look bad. Articles about this post would have been more appropriately titled “Cellebrite accidentally reveals that their technical abilities are as bankrupt as their function in the world.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you are concerned about a situation where someone else might end up physically holding your device with the screen unlocked in their hands, Signal can still help. Features like disappearing messages and view-once media messages allow you to communicate more ephemerally and keep your conversations tidy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is unfortunate such misleading and inaccurate stories like these spread so quickly, particularly because so many people will see that headline and so few will see the correction. If you see people confused by this kind of irresponsible reporting, please help by sharing this with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;social-sharing has-text-centered&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=No,%20Cellebrite%20cannot%20'break%20Signal%20encryption.'&amp;amp;url=https://signal.org/blog/cellebrite-and-clickbait/&amp;amp;via=signalapp&amp;amp;related=signalapp&quot; title=&quot;Share on Twitter&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;btn btn-twitter&quot;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://facebook.com/sharer.php?u=https://signal.org/blog/cellebrite-and-clickbait/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; title=&quot;Share on Facebook&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;btn btn-facebook&quot;&gt; Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;semibold&quot;&gt;Want to get involved with Signal? &lt;a href=&quot;https://signal.org/workworkwork/&quot;&gt;We're hiring!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 18:27:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>hprotagonist</dc:creator>
<og:title>No, Cellebrite cannot 'break Signal encryption.'</og:title>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:description>Yesterday, the BBC ran a story with the factually untrue headline, “Cellebrite claimed to have cracked chat app’s encryption.” This is false.Not only can Cellebrite not break Signal encryption, but Cellebrite never even claimed to be able to.Since we weren’t actually given the opportunity to comm...</og:description>
<og:url>https://signal.org/blog/cellebrite-and-clickbait/</og:url>
<og:image>https://signal.org/assets/og/og-image-ff2096df535eee499356de64b19fa8cebb9681ab1e78cca7330e7f8b8d5ec6d5.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://signal.org/blog/cellebrite-and-clickbait/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Tokio 1.0 – async runtime for Rust</title>
<link>https://tokio.rs/blog/2020-12-tokio-1-0</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://tokio.rs/blog/2020-12-tokio-1-0</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tokio-rs/tokio/releases/tag/tokio-1.0.0&quot;&gt;1.0 release&lt;/a&gt; of Tokio, an asynchronous runtime for the Rust programming language. Tokio provides the needed building blocks for writing reliable networking applications without compromising speed. It comes with asynchronous APIs for TCP, UDP, timers, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://tokio.rs/blog/2019-10-scheduler&quot;&gt;multi-threaded, work-stealing scheduler&lt;/a&gt;, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the years, we have been delighted watching our users build amazing things. For example, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.discord.com/why-discord-is-switching-from-go-to-rust-a190bbca2b1f&quot;&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt; used Tokio to reduce tail latencies 5x. &lt;a href=&quot;https://fly.io&quot;&gt;Fly.io&lt;/a&gt; found that, with Tokio, they can effortlessly meet their performance requirements and focus on delivering features to their customers. For &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zfnd.org/blog/futures-batch-verification/&quot;&gt;the Zcash Foundation&lt;/a&gt;, building on Tokio enables them to design misuse-resistant APIs. For AWS, their &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/lambda/&quot;&gt;Lambda&lt;/a&gt; team used Tokio to implement more reliable and flexible services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://tokio.rs/tokio/tutorial&quot;&gt;tutorial&lt;/a&gt; is the best place to learn how to get started with Tokio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We first &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@carllerche/announcing-tokio-df6bb4ddb34&quot;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; Tokio over four years ago. Since then, it has evolved significantly. The most notable change happened a year ago with the addition of &lt;a href=&quot;https://tokio.rs/blog/2019-11-tokio-0-2&quot;&gt;async and await&lt;/a&gt; to Rust. Today, Tokio is easier to use and more powerful. This evolution has also caused some friction. It has required libraries to track these changes, and could result in confusing error messages when accidentally depending on multiple versions of Tokio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tokio 1.0 release ends this churn. As part of the release, we are committing to providing a stable foundation for the ecosystem. We have no current plans for Tokio 2.0 and we commit to holding back on a Tokio 2.0 release for at least 3 years. We plan to maintain the Tokio 1.0 branch for a minimum of 5 years. Tokio will keep a rolling MSRV (minimum supported rust version) policy of 6 months. When increasing the MSRV, the new Rust version must have been released at least six months ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This stability does not mean Tokio will stagnate. We still have a lot of work to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We expect to focus on a few areas this coming year: &lt;code&gt;Stream&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;io_uring&lt;/code&gt;, tracing integration, and the Tokio stack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;stream&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Stream&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.rs/tokio-stream&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;tokio-stream&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; crate provides asynchronous iteration utilities based on the Stream trait. An &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rfcs/pull/2996&quot;&gt;RFC&lt;/a&gt; to move the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.rs/futures-core/0.3/futures_core/stream/trait.Stream.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Stream&lt;/code&gt; trait&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.rs/futures-core/&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;futures-core&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to the Rust standard library is pending approval.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the standard library provides the Stream trait, Tokio’s stream utilities will move into the Tokio crate itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;io_uring&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;io_uring&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://kernel.dk/io_uring.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;io_uring&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a new Linux interface providing asynchronous operations for all types of I/O, including disk, while reducing the required number of syscalls. Currently, on Linux, Tokio uses the &lt;code&gt;epoll(7)&lt;/code&gt; interface, which notoriously does not work for disk access. To work around this, Tokio provides asynchronous filesystem APIs by dispatching synchronous operations to a thread pool. While this works, it is not optimal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By leveraging &lt;code&gt;io_uring&lt;/code&gt;, Tokio will be able to provide genuinely asynchronous filesystem operations. Additionally, early benchmarks of &lt;code&gt;io_uring&lt;/code&gt; are very promising and we are hopeful that these performance improvements will carry over to Tokio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;tracing&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;tracing&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Defining a first-class story around operating Tokio applications will be a focus for 2021. A big part of this story will be tooling around tracing and metrics. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://crates.io/crates/tracing&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;tracing&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; crate already provides much of the needed infrastructure. It implements a facade layer and data model for structured diagnostics, allowing both libraries and applications to emit machine-readable data that can be consumed in a variety of ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the coming year, we will build deeper integration between tracing and the rest of the Tokio stack. This integration will help provide the needed visibility into Tokio's internals to answer questions. Questions like how you can tune the Tokio runtime to reduce tail latencies, know what tasks are currently running, or which locks are the most contended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, we will continue to improve and grow the rest of the &lt;code&gt;tracing&lt;/code&gt; ecosystem. This includes work towards new releases of the core &lt;code&gt;tracing&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;tracing-core&lt;/code&gt; crates, adding richer instrumentation to the libraries in the Tokio stack, and providing integrations with other diagnostics and observability tools, such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://crates.io/crates/tracing-opentelemetry&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;tracing-opentelemetry&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-tokio-stack&quot;&gt;The Tokio stack&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tokio provides a runtime and asynchronous APIs for standard primitives such as sockets and timers, but networking applications will often use higher-level protocols such as HTTP and gRPC. The Tokio stack includes Hyper for HTTP and Tonic for gRPC to address these needs. Today, we &lt;a href=&quot;https://seanmonstar.com/post/638320652536922112/hyper-v014&quot;&gt;released Hyper 0.14&lt;/a&gt; with Tokio 1.0 support. Tonic will be updated shortly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Tokio 1.0 out the door, we will also focus on &lt;a href=&quot;https://crates.io/crates/tower&quot;&gt;Tower&lt;/a&gt;, a set of reusable components for building reliable clients and servers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tokio would not be possible without our many contributors, especially &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/darksonn&quot;&gt;Alice Ryhl&lt;/a&gt;, who has been invaluable to the project. Thanks to the leaders of the Tokio stack libraries: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/seanmonstar/&quot;&gt;Sean McArthur&lt;/a&gt; (Hyper), &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/luciofranco&quot;&gt;Lucio Franco&lt;/a&gt; (Tonic), &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/hawkw&quot;&gt;Eliza Weisman&lt;/a&gt; (Tracing), and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Thomasdezeeuw&quot;&gt;Thomas De Zeeuw&lt;/a&gt; (Mio). Also, Tokio would not have been possible without &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/aturon&quot;&gt;Aaron Turon&lt;/a&gt;'s and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/alexcrichton&quot;&gt;Alex Crichton&lt;/a&gt;'s early involvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, a big thanks is due to the companies who have financially supported Tokio: &lt;a href=&quot;https://mozilla.org/&quot;&gt;Mozilla&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://dropbox.com&quot;&gt;Dropbox&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://buoyant.io&quot;&gt;Buoyant&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/&quot;&gt;AWS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 18:16:49 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>carllerche</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://tokio.rs/blog/2020-12-tokio-1-0</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Interview advice that got me offers</title>
<link>https://www.zainrizvi.io/blog/the-interviewing-advice-no-one-shares/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.zainrizvi.io/blog/the-interviewing-advice-no-one-shares/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;“What would you say if I asked you to design me a service capable of responding to thousands of user requests every second and latency was critical?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Umm...that you have to solve this problem at work. But you’re out of ideas, and are looking to interviewees for suggestions”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s the actual response I gave the interviewer the first time I was asked a design question. He had a good laugh. But then still made me design the service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the decade since I’ve lost track of how many hours I’ve spent in the interview room, on both sides of the table. I’ve worked at Microsoft, Google, and Stripe, and received offers from many other companies. As I interviewed, I realized one thing: standard interviewing advice falls woefully short.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What good does it do to practice coding problems for weeks if your mind goes blank in an interview room? Everyone says to be wary of the recruiters, but what if you weren’t? How can you show your “best self” if you’re too afraid to let it out?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tested the answers to these questions multiple times (sometimes by accident). Turns out conventional wisdom gets you conventional results. But you can do better. Interviewing is a skill and anyone can learn it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For some reason no one talks about these aspects of interviewing, but I’ve found them helpful time and time again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll cover:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Using recruiters to your advantage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Going to real interviews for practice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being open to learning during interviews&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keeping those skills sharp even when you’re not job hunting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;tip-1-use-recruiters-to-your-advantage&quot;&gt;Tip #1: Use recruiters to your advantage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their voice sounds so friendly and helpful when you chat with them on the phone. “Zain, I’m looking forward to seeing you when you come for your interview!” Clearly it’s all an act, past-me assumed. I was sure they were secretly judging me, deciding if I was good enough to work at the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And they do judge. But not in the way I was expecting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recruiters aren’t evaluating you technically, not by the time you pick up the phone anyways. Their decision on whether you have the technical chops to be worth interviewing was made well before that call. If you’re being offered an interview: Congratulations, you've already passed that bar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the recruiter wants to work &lt;em&gt;with&lt;/em&gt; you. Their whole job is to, you know, recruit. They know that you statistically have poor interview prep skills, and are happy to help fix that flaw. Why discard strong candidates who can’t interview well? They’ll level the playing field by helping everyone show their best selves when interviewing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How can you take advantage of this?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask them questions! Things like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;“What should I do to prepare for the interview?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“What are the company values that would be good to highlight during the interview?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;And be forthright about any problems you run into:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;If you get sick the day before the interview, call up the recruiter and ask to reschedule. They want to test you when you're at your best!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work pressures left you with no time to prepare? You can still try rescheduling. At worst they'll say &quot;sorry, we can't do that&quot;. It will not hurt your chances of getting in&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your mad technical skills no longer matter to them. If anything, humility and an openness to learning will show you in the best light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;tip-2-go-to-real-interviews-for-practice&quot;&gt;Tip #2: Go to real interviews for practice&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need to build up your interviewing skills. LeetCode is great, but it doesn’t come close to the real thing. Try to interview at actual companies as much as possible. And don't limit yourself to the companies you care about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learn to deal with pressure&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you're in a real interview the world changes: You're locked in a cage with a lion. Every heartbeat is a gorilla bashing against the walls. Your mental gears gunk up as your body goes into fight or flight mode. Your clammy hands struggle to write half legible code on the white board. A threat hides behind every shadow. Even an innocuous &quot;Would you like something to drink?&quot; is a nefarious test: do I pick coke or coffee?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You only get that experience in a real interview. And only real interviews teach you how to deal with it. The first interview will kick your ass. So will the second. But once you get a few under your belt you'll get used to the adrenaline rush. Perhaps enjoy it even. You'll become a bullfighter, confidently facing down the charging bull. That’s how you get over the fear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may even find that these practice interviews are much easier! When the stakes are low that lion doesn't look so fierce. I've found that I perform the best in the interviews where I don't care about the outcome. I'm much more relaxed and at ease. I can think faster, my brain reaches out to more possibilities. Now, even in important interviews I try to convince myself that I don't really care. That mindset shift is only possible because I got to experience it in the low stakes games first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learn to answer the more ambiguous questions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what about the questions? After each interview write down all the questions you were asked. The same evening look over the questions while they’re still fresh in your mind. Focus especially on the behavioral and design ones which have no clear right answer. Consider how you could have responded better. Are there stories from your life you could have referenced? Wait a few days and look at them again. You’ll find better answers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each answer you prepare this way becomes a blob of paint on your pallet. Chances are high that you'll come across similar questions in future interviews. Over time you'll be able to mix the answers from your pallet to paint a picture highlighting how your abilities make you a valuable asset to the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stay open to serendipity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you do these interviews, you may discover that the “practice” company is actually interesting after all. Recruiters count on that. I’ve had recruiters suggest I interview even when I told them I didn’t find the company interesting. “Maybe you’ll change your mind after seeing us up close”, they suggest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I did. More than once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;tip-3-be-open-to-learning-during-the-interview&quot;&gt;Tip #3: Be open to learning during the interview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned this one by accident, but boy does it pay off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a college career fair once I was walking through the booths with my bag full of swag. My eyes caught a pile of rubik’s cubes being given away by some company I'd never heard of. I wanted one! Of course I couldn't just go up and ask for it directly, so I went and chatted with the guy manning the booth. His name was Vince. A few minutes later I walked away with my prized rubik's cube in hand. That evening I got a call from Vince offering to conduct a full interview loop on campus. I already had a job offer from a company I liked, but I thought &quot;Sure, why not? I could use the experience&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had no intention of joining the company, they were some boring finance business. There was nothing to lose. So during the interview I felt free to ask any question I wanted. When I thought I got the answer to an interview question wrong, I'd ask &quot;I don't think I did so great here. What's the right answer to this problem?&quot; (I wanted to learn the answer for future interviews!). When I was asked a challenging question I could grin and delight in the problem solving aspect instead of worrying about how badly it would reflect on me. (Remember my smart aleck remark in the intro? That was this interview.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turns out they liked that: the next day I had a second job offer. At a significantly higher salary than my first one. Oh, and they wanted to fly me to New York in two weeks for an introduction to the company. I still didn’t want to join, but a free trip to New York? Sign me up! The company's name: Bloomberg&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bloomberg was a practiced hand at recruiting. They had a full two days of events to leave us starry eyed about the company (I came thiiiiis close to accepting their offer). While there, Vince told me I’d made a great impression by fearlessly asking questions, even when I was stumped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since then I’ve stopped hesitating before asking any question in an interview. Let your curiosity run free! Don’t cage it! And as an interviewer, I can attest: sincere interest is always a good sign.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;tip-4-keep-your-skills-sharp-even-when-you-re-not-job-hunting&quot;&gt;Tip #4: Keep your skills sharp even when you’re not job hunting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/docjamesw&quot;&gt;James Whittaker&lt;/a&gt; recommends trying to get a job offer every year, just to make sure you can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's an extremely liberating feeling knowing that even if you lose your job you'll be able to find another one quickly. That's a huge stress off your back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven't been very good about this myself, but every once in a while I'll accept an invitation from a recruiter (it helps to set up your LinkedIn account). I don't bother doing any prep for these interviews, at least not initially. Those interviews show me the areas I need to brush up on or where the industry practices are changing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, in a tech screen I did last summer there was some miscommunication and I didn’t realize they expected actual working code. Instead of the usual pseudocode written in a google doc, the interviewer told me to select my language of choice on an online IDE. Now, I don't have a particular language I consider myself super proficient in. I touch many different tools at work and end up having to use a different language about every 5 months. So even basic things like &quot;create an array&quot; tends to require googling the syntax. Given that, what's my favorite language of choice? C#, hands down. So I selected that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What hadn't occurred to me at the time is that C# is a very verbose language which Visual Studio beautifully automates away the tedious parts of. This online IDE automated nothing. Even for a basic task like creating an array I had to spend precious interview minutes looking up the right package to import and the exact syntax to use. Needless to say, I ran out of time. I crashed and burned there, but it opened my eyes to the way interviews are changing and how I needed to prepare in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Four months later a company called Stripe reached out to me. They also expect you to write working code and even let you use your own IDE. This time I was ready. And now I work there. (Psst, &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/jobs/search&quot;&gt;we're hiring&lt;/a&gt;!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These four strategies have helped me over and over again to perform well in the interview room: leveraging the recruiters, doing real interviews for practice, asking questions during interviews, and keeping those skills sharp even after getting the job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do all these tactics have in common? They eliminate your fear. The fear that holds you back from letting your best self out. Do them often enough and interview rooms will transform from a threatening    jungle into Tarzan’s playground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Remember, never let them see you sweat” Vince told me. But when the stakes are low and you’re having fun, who sweats?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Want to learn about how to develop the skills required to grow as an engineer and get interview offers in the first place? Subscribe below to get tips based on engineering and psychology sent to you every week.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can also &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ZainRzv&quot;&gt;find me on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 17:13:57 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ZainRiz</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Interview advice that got me offers from Google, Microsoft, and Stripe</og:title>
<og:description>“What would you say if I asked you to design me a service capable of responding to thousands of user requests every second and latency was critical?” “Umm...that you have to solve this problem at work. But you’re out of ideas, and are looking to interviewees for suggestions”</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.zainrizvi.io/blog/the-interviewing-advice-no-one-shares/</og:url>
<og:image>https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1573497491208-6b1acb260507?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;q=80&amp;fm=jpg&amp;crop=entropy&amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;w=2000&amp;fit=max&amp;ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjExNzczfQ</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.zainrizvi.io/blog/the-interviewing-advice-no-one-shares/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Windows 0day privilege escalation still not fixed</title>
<link>https://bugs.chromium.org/p/project-zero/issues/detail?id=2096</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://bugs.chromium.org/p/project-zero/issues/detail?id=2096</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.chromium.org/p/project-zero/issues/detail?id=2096&quot;&gt;https://bugs.chromium.org/p/project-zero/issues/detail?id=2096&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25519678&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25519678&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 299&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 116&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 17:09:56 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>zaltekk</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://bugs.chromium.org/p/project-zero/issues/detail?id=2096</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Anti-diarrhoea drug drives cancer cells to cell death</title>
<link>https://aktuelles.uni-frankfurt.de/englisch/anti-diarrhoea-drug-drives-cancer-cells-to-cell-death/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://aktuelles.uni-frankfurt.de/englisch/anti-diarrhoea-drug-drives-cancer-cells-to-cell-death/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://aktuelles.uni-frankfurt.de/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/beitragsbild_durchfallmittel-krebszellen.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-48436&quot; srcset=&quot;https://aktuelles.uni-frankfurt.de/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/beitragsbild_durchfallmittel-krebszellen.jpg 650w, https://aktuelles.uni-frankfurt.de/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/beitragsbild_durchfallmittel-krebszellen-300x208.jpg 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 650px) 100vw, 650px&quot;/&gt;&lt;em&gt;In glioblastoma cells, the antidiarrheal drug loperamide triggers the degradation of the endoplasmic reticulum. In the normal state, it is coloured yellow in these microscopic images. In the degradation state, it glows as a red signal (marked with arrows). Left scale bar: 20 µm, right scale bar (inset): 5 µm (Photos: Svenja Zielke et. al.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In cell culture, loperamide, a drug commonly used against diarrhoea, proves effective against glioblastoma cells. A research team at Goethe University has now unravelled the drug’s mechanisms  of action of cell death induction and – in doing so – has shown how this compound could help attack brain tumours that otherwise are difficult to treat.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research group led by Dr Sjoerd van Wijk from the Institute of Experimental Cancer Research in Paediatrics at Goethe University already two years ago found evidence indicating that the anti-diarrhoea drug loperamide could be used to induce cell death in glioblastoma cell lines. They have now deciphered its mechanism of action and, in doing so, are opening new avenues for the development of novel treatment strategies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When cells digest themselves&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In certain types of tumour cells, administration of loperamide leads to a stress response in the endoplasmic reticulum (ER), the cell organelle responsible for key steps in protein synthesis in the body. The stress in the ER triggers its degradation, followed by self-destruction of the cells. This mechanism, known as autophagy-dependent cell death occurs when cells undergo hyperactivated autophagy. Normally, autophagy regulates normal metabolic processes and breaks down and recycles the valuable parts of damaged or superfluous cell components thus ensuring the cell’s survival, for example in the case of nutrient deficiency. In certain tumour cells, however, hyperactivation of autophagy destroys so much cell material that they are no longer capable of surviving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Our experiments with cell lines show that autophagy could support the treatment of glioblastoma brain tumours,” says van Wijk. Glioblastoma is a very aggressive and lethal type of cancer in children and adults that shows only a poor response to chemotherapy. New therapeutic approaches are therefore urgently required. The research group led by van Wijk has now identified an important factor that links the ER stress response with the degradation of the ER (reticulophagy):  The “Activating Transcription Factor” ATF4 is produced in increased amounts both during ER stress and under the influence of loperamide. It triggers the destruction of the ER membranes and thus of the ER.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anti-diarrhoea drug triggers cell death in glioblastoma cells&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Conversely, if we block ATF4, far fewer cells in a tumour cell culture die after adding loperamide,” says van Wijk, describing the control results. In addition, the research group was able to detect ER debris in loperamide-treated cells under the electron microscope. “ER degradation, that is, reticulophagy, visibly contributes to the demise of glioblastoma cells,” says van Wijk. The team also showed that loperamide triggers only autophagy but not cell death in other cells, such as embryonic mouse fibroblasts. “Normally, loperamide, when taken as a remedy against diarrhoea, binds to particular binding sites in the intestine and is not taken up by the bowel and is therefore harmless”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mechanism of action also applicable to other diseases&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The loperamide-induced death of glioblastoma cells could help in the development of new therapeutic approaches for the treatment of this severe form of cancer. “However, our findings also open up exciting new possibilities for the treatment of other diseases where ER degradation is disrupted, such as neurological disorders or dementia as well as other types of tumour,” says van Wijk. However, further studies are necessary before loperamide can actually be used in the treatment of glioblastoma or other diseases. In future studies it has to be explored, for example, how loperamide can be transported into the brain and cross the blood-brain barrier. Nanoparticles might be a feasible option. The research team in Frankfurt now wants to identify other substances that trigger reticulophagy and examine how the effect of loperamide can be increased and better understood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research group led by Sjoerd van Wijk is funded by the Frankfurt Foundation for Children with Cancer (&lt;em&gt;Frankfurter Stiftung für krebskranke Kinder&lt;/em&gt;) and the Collaborative Research Centre 1177 “Molecular and Functional Characterisation of Selective Autophagy” funded by the German Research Foundation (Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft). The work is the result of collaboration with Dr Muriel Mari and Professor Fulvio Reggiori (University of Groningen, The Netherlands) and Professor Donat Kögel (Experimental Neurosurgery, Goethe University).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;has-background has-very-light-gray-background-color&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Publication:&lt;/strong&gt; Svenja Zielke, Simon Kardo, Laura Zein, Muriel Mari, Adriana Covarrubias-Pinto, Maximilian N. Kinzler, Nina Meyer, Alexandra Stolz, Simone Fulda, Fulvio Reggiori, Donat Kögel and Sjoerd van Wijk: &lt;strong&gt;ATF4 links ER stress with reticulophagy in glioblastoma cells&lt;/strong&gt;. Taylor &amp;amp; Francis Online &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1080/15548627.2020.1827780&quot;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1080/15548627.2020.1827780&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 15:52:34 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>gmays</dc:creator>
<dc:language>de-DE</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://aktuelles.uni-frankfurt.de/englisch/anti-diarrhoea-drug-drives-cancer-cells-to-cell-death/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Tips for a Better Life</title>
<link>https://www.lesswrong.com/posts/7hFeMWC6Y5eaSixbD/100-tips-for-a-better-life</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.lesswrong.com/posts/7hFeMWC6Y5eaSixbD/100-tips-for-a-better-life</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The other day I made an advice thread based on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lesswrong.com/posts/HJeD6XbMGEfcrx3mD/100-ways-to-live-better&quot;&gt;Jacobian’s&lt;/a&gt; from last year! If you know a source for one of these, shout and I’ll edit it in. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong id=&quot;Possessions&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Possessions&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 .If you want to find out about people’s opinions on a product, google &lt;em&gt;&amp;lt;product&amp;gt; reddit&lt;/em&gt;. You’ll get real people arguing, as compared to the SEO’d Google results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. Some banks charge you $20 a month for an account, others charge you 0. If you’re with one of the former, have a good explanation for what those $20 are buying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lesswrong.com/posts/wnnsqR784yx7KNtmk/how-can-i-spend-money-to-improve-my-life&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;3.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Things you use for a significant fraction of your life (bed: 1/3rd, office-chair: 1/4th) are worth investing in. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4. “Where is the good knife?” If you’re looking for your good X, you have bad Xs. Throw those out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5. If your work is done on a computer, get a second monitor. Less time navigating between windows means more time for thinking. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6. Establish clear rules about when to throw out old junk. Once clear rules are established, junk will probably cease to be a problem. This is because any rule would be superior to our implicit rules (“keep this broken stereo for five years in case I learn how to fix it”). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7. Don’t buy CDs for people. They have Spotify. Buy them merch from a band they like instead. It’s more personal and the band gets more money. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8. When buying things, time and money trade-off against each other. If you’re low on money, take more time to find deals. If you’re low on time, stop looking for great deals and just buy things quickly online. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong id=&quot;Cooking&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Cooking&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/teassentialteas/?hl=en&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;9.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Steeping minutes: Green at 3, black at 4, herbal at 5. Good tea is that simple! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10. Food actually can be both cheap, healthy, tasty, and relatively quick to prepare. All it requires is a few hours one day to prepare many meals for the week. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11. Cooking pollutes the air. Opening windows for a few minutes after cooking can dramatically improve air quality. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;12. Food taste can be made much more exciting through simple seasoning. It’s also an opportunity for expression. Buy a few herbs and spices and experiment away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;13. When googling a recipe, precede it with ‘best’. You’ll find better recipes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong id=&quot;Productivity&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Productivity&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;14. Advanced search features are a fast way to create tighter search statements. For example:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;img html &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;will return inferior results compared to:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;img html -w3&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gwern.net/Search#preparation&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;15.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; You can automate mundane computer tasks with Autohotkey (or AppleScript). If you keep doing a sequence “so simple a computer can do it”, make the computer do it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;16. Learn keyboard shortcuts. They’re easy to learn and you’ll get tasks done faster and easier. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jessegalef.com/2020/08/09/a-pretty-good-mathematical-model-of-perfectionism/&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;17.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Done is better than perfect. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;18. Keep your desk and workspace bare. Treat every object as an imposition upon your attention, because it is. A workspace is not a place for storing things. It is a place for accomplishing things. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;19. Reward yourself after completing challenges, even badly. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong id=&quot;Body&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Body&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;20. The 20-20-20 rule: Every 20 minutes of screenwork, look at a spot 20 feet away for 20 seconds. This will reduce eye strain and is easy to remember (or program reminders for). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en/article/ne5zg8/this-is-the-effect-working-out-has-on-your-bones&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;21.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Exercise (weightlifting) not only creates muscle mass, it also improves skeletal structure. Lift!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lesswrong.com/posts/PhXENjdXiHhsWGfQo/lifestyle-interventions-to-increase-longevity&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;22.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Exercise is the most important lifestyle intervention you can do. Even the bare minimum (15 minutes a week) has a huge impact. Start small. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2009/02/17/health/17well.html&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;23.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (~This is not medical advice~). Don’t waste money on multivitamins, they don’t work. Vitamin D supplementation does seem to work, which is important because deficiency is common. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;24. Phones have gotten heavier in the last decade and they’re actually pretty hard on your wrists! Use a computer when it’s an alternative or try to at least prop up your phone. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong id=&quot;Success&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Success&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thehistoryoftheweb.com/the-origin-of-the-img-tag/#:~:text=The%20img%20tag%20was%20included,hard%20to%20change%20its%20implementation.&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;25.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; History remembers those who got to market first. Getting your creation out into the world is more important than getting it perfect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://80000hours.org/2018/08/randomised-experiment-if-youre-really-unsure-whether-to-quit-your-job-or-break-up-you-really-probably-should/&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;26.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Are you on the fence about breaking up or leaving your job? You should probably go ahead and do it. People, on average, end up happier when they take the plunge. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;27. Discipline is superior to motivation. The former can be trained, the latter is fleeting. You won’t be able to accomplish great things if you’re only relying on motivation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;28. You can improve your communication skills with practice much more effectively than you can improve your intelligence with practice. If you’re not that smart but can communicate ideas clearly, you have a great advantage over everybody who can’t communicate clearly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;29. You do not live in a video game. There are no pop-up warnings if you’re about to do something foolish, or if you’ve been going in the wrong direction for too long. You have to create your own warnings. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Survivorship_bias&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;30.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; If you listen to successful people talk about their methods, remember that all the people who used the same methods and failed did not make videos about it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;31. The best advice is personal and comes from somebody who knows you well. Take broad-spectrum advice like this as needed, but the best way to get help is to ask honest friends who love you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;32. Make accomplishing things as easy as possible. Find the easiest way to start exercising. Find the easiest way to start writing. People make things harder than they have to be and get frustrated when they can’t succeed. Try not to. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;33. Cultivate a reputation for being dependable. Good reputations are valuable because they’re rare (easily destroyed and hard to rebuild). You don’t have to brew the most amazing coffee if your customers know the coffee will always be hot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brainpickings.org/2013/06/07/annie-dillard-the-writing-life-1/&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;34.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; How you spend every day is how you spend your life. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong id=&quot;Rationality&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Rationality&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/quotes/497611-science-is-a-way-of-trying-not-to-fool-yourself&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;35.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Noticing biases in others is easy, noticing biases in yourself is hard. However, it has much higher pay-off. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rubber_duck_debugging&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;36.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Explaining problems is good. Often in the process of laying out a problem, a solution will present itself. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lesswrong.com/posts/qNZM3EGoE5ZeMdCRt/reversed-stupidity-is-not-intelligence&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;37.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Foolish people are right about most things. Endeavour to not let the opinions of foolish people automatically discredit those opinions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lesswrong.com/posts/N47M3JiHveHfwdbFg/hammertime-day-10-murphyjitsu&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;38.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; You have a plan. A time-traveller from 2030 appears and tells you your plan failed. Which part of your plan do you think is the one that fails? Fix that part. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;39. If something surprises you again and again, stop being surprised. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://betterexplained.com/articles/an-intuitive-and-short-explanation-of-bayes-theorem/&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;40.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Should you freak out upon seeing your symptoms on the worst diseases on WebMD? Probably not! Look up the base rates for the disease and then apply Bayes’ Theorem &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://betterexplained.com/articles/an-intuitive-and-short-explanation-of-bayes-theorem/&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;41.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Selfish people should listen to advice to be more selfless, selfless people should listen to advice to be more selfish. This applies to many things. Whenever you receive advice, consider its opposite as well. You might be filtering out the advice you need most. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;42. Common systems and tools have been designed so everybody can handle them. So don’t worry that you’re the only one who can’t! You can figure out doing laundry, baking, and driving on a highway. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong id=&quot;Self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Self&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;43. Deficiencies do not make you special. The older you get, the more your inability to cook will be a red flag for people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Know_thyself&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;44.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; There is no interpersonal situation that can’t be improved by knowing more about your desires, goals, and structure. ‘Know thyself!’ &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;45. If you’re under 90, try things. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theamericanconservative.com/dreher/on-white-people-acting-white/&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;46.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Things that aren’t your fault can still be your responsibility. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://putanumonit.com/2020/09/12/against-victimhood/&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;47.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Defining yourself by your suffering is an effective way to keep suffering forever (ex. incels, trauma). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;48. Keep your identity small. “I’m not the kind of person who does things like that” is not an explanation, it’s a trap. It prevents nerds from working out and men from dancing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;49. Don’t confuse ‘doing a thing because I like it’ with ‘doing a thing because I want to be seen as the sort of person who does such things’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/quotes/7457932-death-hangs-over-thee-while-thou-livest-while-it-is&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;50.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Remember that you are dying. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;51. Events can hurt us, not just our perceptions of them. It’s good to build resilience, but sometimes it isn’t your fault if something really gets to you. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;52. If you want to become funny, try just saying stupid shit (in the right company!) until something sticks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/QiaochuYuan/status/1276515256504774656&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;53.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; To start defining your problems, say (out loud) “everything in my life is completely fine.” Notice what objections arise. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;54. Procrastination comes naturally, so apply it to bad things. “I want to hurt myself right now. I’ll do it in an hour.” “I want a smoke now, so in half an hour I’ll go have a smoke.” Then repeat. Much like our good plans fall apart while we delay them, so can our bad plans. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sensophy.com/why-epiphanies-dont-work/&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;55.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Personal epiphanies feel great, but they fade within weeks. Upon having an epiphany, make a plan and start actually changing behavior. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;56. Sometimes unsolvable questions like “what is my purpose?” and “why should I exist?” lose their force upon lifestyle fixes. In other words, seeing friends regularly and getting enough sleep can go a long way to solving existentialism. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong id=&quot;Hazards&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Hazards&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;57. There are two red flags to avoid almost all dangerous people: 1. The perpetually aggrieved ; 2. The angry. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;58. Some people create drama out of habit. You can avoid these people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;59. Those who generate anxiety in you and promise that they have the solution are grifters. See: politicians, marketers, new masculinity gurus, etc. Avoid these. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=d-7o9xYp7eE&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;60.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (~This is not legal advice!~)&lt;br/&gt;DO NOT TALK TO COPS. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;61. It is cheap for people to talk about their values, goals, rules, and lifestyle. When people’s actions contradict their talk, &lt;em&gt;pay attention! &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;62. “If they’ll do it with you, they’ll do it to you” and “those who live by the sword die by the sword” mean the same thing. Viciousness you excuse in yourself, friends, or teammates will one day return to you, and then you won’t have an excuse. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong id=&quot;Others&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Others&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;63. In choosing between living with 0-1 people vs 2 or more people, remember that ascertaining responsibility will no longer be instantaneous with more than one roommate (“whose dishes are these?”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DwfnRCwZZWk&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;64.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Understand people have the right to be tasteless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://putanumonit.com/2020/02/27/seeing-the-smoke/&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;65.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; You will prevent yourself from even having thoughts that could lower your status. Avoid blocking yourself off just so people keep thinking you’re cool. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;66. Being in groups is important. If you don’t want to join a sports team, consider starting a shitty band. It’s the closest you’ll get to being in an RPG. Train with 2-4 other characters, learn new moves, travel from pub to pub, and get quests from NPCs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;67. It’s possible to get people to do things that make you like them more but respect them less. Avoid this, it destroys relationships. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;68. Think a little about why you enjoy what you enjoy. If you can explain what you love about Dune, you can now communicate not only with Dune fans, but with people who love those aspects in other books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;69. When you ask people, “What’s your favorite book / movie / band?” and they stumble, ask them instead what book / movie / band they’re currently enjoying most. They’ll almost always have one and be able to talk about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/quotes/631074-banality-is-like-boredom-bored-people-are-boring-people-people&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;70.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Bored people are boring. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;71. A norm of eating with your family without watching something will lead to better conversations. If this idea fills you with dread, consider getting a new family. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;72. If you bus to other cities, consider finding a rideshare on Facebook instead. It’s cheaper, faster, and leads to interesting conversations. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong id=&quot;Relationships&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Relationships&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;73. In relationships look for somebody you can enjoy just hanging out near. Long-term relationships are mostly spent just chilling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;74. Sometimes things last a long time because they’re good (jambalaya). But that doesn’t mean that because something has lasted a long time that it is good (penile subincisions). Apply this to relationships, careers, and beliefs as appropriate. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;75. Don’t complain about your partner to coworkers or online. The benefits are negligible and the cost is destroying a bit of your soul. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;76. After a breakup, cease all contact as soon as practical. The potential for drama is endless, and the potential for a good friendship is negligible. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;77. If you haven’t figured things out sexually, remember that there isn’t a deadline. If somebody is making you feel like there is, consider the possibility that they aren’t your pal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;78. If you have trouble talking during dates, try saying whatever comes into your head. At worst you’ll ruin some dates (which weren’t going well anyways), at best you’ll have some great conversations. Alcohol can help. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thingofthings.wordpress.com/2018/05/25/models-a-summary/&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;79.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; When dating, de-emphasizing your quirks will lead to 90% of people thinking you’re kind of alright. Emphasizing your quirks will lead to 10% of people thinking you’re fascinating and fun. Those are the people interested in dating you. Aim for them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.psychologytoday.com/ca/blog/changepower/201005/can-the-novelty-habit-boost-couples-commitment&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;80.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Relationships need novelty. It’s hard to have novelty during Covid--but have you planned your post-Covid adventure yet?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;81. People can be the wrong fit for you without being bad. Being a person is complicated and hard. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong id=&quot;Compassion&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Compassion&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pAtGGZjVRdo&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;82.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Call your parents when you think of them, tell your friends when you love them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;83. Compliment people more. Many people have trouble thinking of themselves as smart, or pretty, or kind, unless told by someone else. You can help them out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;84. If somebody is undergoing group criticism, the tribal part in you will want to join in the fun of righteously destroying somebody. Resist this, you’ll only add ugliness to the world. And anyway, they’ve already learned the lesson they’re going to learn and it probably isn’t the lesson you want. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;85. Cultivate compassion for those less intelligent than you. Many people, through no fault of their own, can’t handle forms, scammers, or complex situations. Be kind to them because the world is not. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;86. Cultivate patience for difficult people. Communication is extremely complicated and involves getting both tone and complex ideas across. Many people can barely do either. Don’t punish them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=17fRzsbcME0&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;87.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Don’t punish people for trying. You teach them to not try with you. Punishing includes whining that it took them so long, that they did it badly, or that others have done it better. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/quotes/222576-we-are-as-forlorn-as-children-lost-in-the-wood&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;88.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Remember that many people suffer invisibly, and some of the worst suffering is shame. Not everybody can make their pain legible. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;89. Don't punish people for admitting they were wrong, you make it harder for them to improve. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;90. In general, you will look for excuses to not be kind to people. Resist these. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong id=&quot;Joy&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Joy&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;91. Human mood and well-being are heavily influenced by simple things: Exercise, good sleep, light, being in nature. It’s cheap to experiment with these.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://studiahumana.com/pliki/wydania/In%20Praise%20of%20Passivity.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;92&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. You have vanishingly little political influence and every thought you spend on politics will probably come to nothing. Consider building things instead, or at least going for a walk. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sturgeon%27s_law#:~:text=Sturgeon's%20law%20(or%20Sturgeon's%20revelation,science%20fiction%20author%20and%20critic.&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;93.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Sturgeon’s law states that 90% of everything is crap. If you dislike poetry, or fine art, or anything, it’s possible you’ve only ever seen the crap. Go looking!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;94. You don’t have to love your job. Jobs can be many things, but they’re also a way to make money. Many people live fine lives in okay jobs by using the money they make on things they care about. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;95. Some types of sophistication won’t make you enjoy the object more, they’ll make you enjoy it less. For example, wine snobs don’t enjoy wine twice as much as you, they’re more keenly aware of how most wine isn’t good enough. Avoid sophistication that diminishes your enjoyment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;96. If other people having it worse than you means you can’t be sad, then other people having it better than you would mean you can’t be happy. Feel what you feel. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lesswrong.com/posts/HmfxSWnqnK265GEFM/are-wireheads-happy&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;97.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Liking and wanting things are different. There are things like junk food that you want beyond enjoyment. But you can also like things (like reading) without wanting them. If you remember enjoying something but don't feel a desire for it now, try pushing yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lesswrong.com/posts/HmfxSWnqnK265GEFM/are-wireheads-happy&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;98.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; People don’t realize how much they hate commuting. A nice house farther from work is not worth the fraction of your life you are giving to boredom and fatigue. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://psycnet.apa.org/record/2019-43492-001&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;99.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; There’s some evidence that introverts and extroverts both benefit from being pushed to be more extroverted. Consider this the next time you aren’t sure if you feel like going out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;100. Bad things happen dramatically (a pandemic). Good things happen gradually (malaria deaths dropping annually) and don’t feel like ‘news’. Endeavour to keep track of the good things to avoid an inaccurate and dismal view of the world. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 15:44:43 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>CapitalistCartr</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://res.cloudinary.com/lesswrong-2-0/image/upload/v1503704344/sequencesgrid/h6vrwdypijqgsop7xwa0.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>100 Tips for a Better Life - LessWrong</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.lesswrong.com/posts/7hFeMWC6Y5eaSixbD/100-tips-for-a-better-life</og:url>
<og:description>The other day I made an advice thread based on Jacobian’s from last year! If you know a source for one of these, shout and I’ll edit it in. Possessions 1 .If you want to find out about people’s opinions on a product, google &lt;product&gt; reddit. You’ll get real people arguing, as compared to the SEO’d Google results. 2. Some banks charge you $20 a month for an account, others charge you 0. If you’re with one of the former, have a good explanation for what those $20 are buying. 3. Things you use for a significant fraction of your life (bed: 1/3rd, office-chair: 1/4th) are worth investing in. 4. “Where is the good knife?” If you’re looking for your good X, you have bad Xs. Throw those out. 5. If your work is done on a computer, get a second monitor. Less time navigating between windows means more time for thinking. 6. Establish clear rules about when to throw out old junk. Once clear rules are established, junk will probably cease to be a problem. This is because any rule would be superior to our implicit rules (“keep this broken stereo for five years in case I learn how to fix it”). 7. Don’t buy CDs for people. They have Spotify. Buy them merch from a band they like instead. It’s more personal and the band gets more money. 8. When buying things, time and money trade-off against each other. If you’re low on money, take more time to find deals. If you’re low on time, stop looking for great deals and just buy things quickly online. Cooking 9. Steeping minutes: Green at 3, black at 4, herbal at 5. Good tea is that simple! 10. Food actually can be both cheap, healthy, tasty, and relatively quick to prepare. All it requires is a few hours one day to prepare many meals for the week. 11. Cooking pollutes the air. Opening windows for a few minutes after cooking can dramatically improve air quality. 12. Food taste can be made much more exciting through simple seasoning. It’s also an opportunity for expression. Buy a few herbs and spices and experiment away. 13.</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.lesswrong.com/posts/7hFeMWC6Y5eaSixbD/100-tips-for-a-better-life</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How bad is your Spotify?</title>
<link>https://pudding.cool/2020/12/judge-my-spotify</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://pudding.cool/2020/12/judge-my-spotify</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://pudding.cool/2020/12/judge-my-spotify&quot;&gt;https://pudding.cool/2020/12/judge-my-spotify&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25517868&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25517868&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 715&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 483&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 14:22:57 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>feross</dc:creator>
<og:title>How Bad Is Your Spotify?</og:title>
<og:url>https://pudding.cool/2020/12/judge-my-spotify/</og:url>
<og:description>Our sophisticated A.I. judges your awful taste in music.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://pudding.cool/2020/12/judge-my-spotify/assets/social/social-facebook.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://pudding.cool/2020/12/judge-my-spotify/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>