<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Facebook Security Chief Said to Leave After Clashes Over Disinformation</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/03/19/technology/facebook-alex-stamos.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2018/03/19/technology/facebook-alex-stamos.html</guid>
<description>&lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;Photo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/03/20/business/20STAMOS/merlin_135735063_e1713ceb-7155-48a9-bd7e-3b58798a2ac5-master768.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;media-viewer-candidate&quot; data-mediaviewer-src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/03/20/business/20STAMOS/merlin_135735063_e1713ceb-7155-48a9-bd7e-3b58798a2ac5-superJumbo.jpg&quot; data-mediaviewer-caption=&quot;Alex Stamos, the chief information security officer for Facebook. He has urged more disclosure over Russian activity on Facebook.&quot; data-mediaviewer-credit=&quot;Steve Marcus/Reuters&quot; itemprop=&quot;url&quot; itemid=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/03/20/business/20STAMOS/merlin_135735063_e1713ceb-7155-48a9-bd7e-3b58798a2ac5-master768.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;Alex Stamos, the chief information security officer for Facebook. He has urged more disclosure over Russian activity on Facebook.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt; Steve Marcus/Reuters&lt;/span&gt; &lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;261&quot; data-total-count=&quot;261&quot;&gt;Facebook’s chief information security officer, Alex Stamos, will leave the company after internal disagreements over how the social network should deal with its role in spreading disinformation, according to current and former employees briefed on the matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;353&quot; data-total-count=&quot;614&quot;&gt;Mr. Stamos had been a strong advocate inside the company for investigating and disclosing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/02/17/technology/indictment-russian-tech-facebook.html&quot;&gt;Russian activity on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, often to the consternation of other top executives, including Sheryl Sandberg, the social network’s chief operating officer, according to the current and former employees, who asked not to be identified discussing internal matters.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;499&quot; data-total-count=&quot;1113&quot;&gt;After his day-to-day responsibilities were reassigned to others in December, Mr. Stamos said he would leave the company. He was persuaded to stay through August to oversee the transition of his duties because executives thought his departure would look bad, the current and former employees said. He has been overseeing the transfer of his security team to Facebook’s product and infrastructure divisions. His group, which once had 120 people, now has three, the current and former employees said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;202&quot; data-total-count=&quot;1315&quot;&gt;Mr. Stamos would be the first high-ranking employee to leave Facebook since controversy erupted over disinformation on its site. His departure is a sign of heightened leadership tensions at the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;407&quot; data-total-count=&quot;1722&quot;&gt;Mark Zuckerberg, Facebook’s chief executive, Ms. Sandberg and other company leaders have struggled to address a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/03/18/us/cambridge-analytica-facebook-privacy-data.html&quot;&gt;growing set of problems&lt;/a&gt;, including Russian interference on the platform, the rise of false news, and the disclosure this past weekend that 50 million of its user profiles had been &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/03/17/us/politics/cambridge-analytica-trump-campaign.html&quot;&gt;harvested by Cambridge Analytica&lt;/a&gt;, a voter-profiling company that worked on President Trump’s election campaign.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;44&quot; data-total-count=&quot;1766&quot;&gt;Facebook did not immediately have a comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/03/19/technology/facebook-alex-stamos.html#whats-next&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 22:23:41 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>aaronbrethorst</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/03/19/technology/facebook-alex-stamos.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Facebook Security Chief Said to Leave After Clashes Over Disinformation</og:title>
<og:description>Alex Stamos, the chief information security officer, will leave after disagreements over how Facebook should deal with its role in spreading disinformation, according to people briefed on the matter.</og:description>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/03/20/business/20STAMOS/20STAMOS-facebookJumbo-v2.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/03/19/technology/facebook-alex-stamos.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Cambridge Analytica scandal isn’t a scandal: this is how Facebook works</title>
<link>https://www.independent.co.uk/voices/camridge-analytica-scandal-how-facebook-works-harvesting-data-politics-trump-brexit-a8264051.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.independent.co.uk/voices/camridge-analytica-scandal-how-facebook-works-harvesting-data-politics-trump-brexit-a8264051.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;It is easy to be misled into believing that the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/americas/facebook-cambridge-analytica-millions-users-data-massachusetts-investigation-maura-healy-trump-a8261526.html&quot;&gt;Cambridge Analytica&lt;/a&gt; story is about rogue data miners taking advantage of an innocent Facebook. Facebook’s decision to suspend Cambridge Analytica’s access, the use of terms like “data breach”, and a good deal of coverage in the media seems to follow these lines. That, however, misses the key point. This is not a data breach by any means – and nor is it something that could not have been predicted or could easily have been avoided. This is, in many ways, Cambridge Analytica using Facebook exactly as the social media platform was designed to be used. This is how Facebook works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three key parts of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.independent.co.uk/topic/Facebook&quot;&gt;Facebook’s&lt;/a&gt; model come into play: gathering data from people in order to profile them, both &lt;em&gt;en masse&lt;/em&gt; and individually, designing systems that allow that data to be used to target people for advertising and content, then allowing third parties (generally advertisers) to use the data and those targeting systems for their own purposes. The power of these systems is often underestimated, but Facebook themselves know it, and have tested it in a number of ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They have demonstrated, through their “emotional contagion” experiment in 2014, that they can make people happier or sadder, simply by manipulating the order things appear in people’s timelines. They have demonstrated that they can make people more likely to vote, testing it in the 2010 US congressional elections. They can profile people based on the most mundane of information – the sheer scale of Facebook’s user-base and the amount of information given to them means that “big data” analysis can make connections that might seem bizarre, revealing insights into intelligence, politics, ethnicity and religion without people actually discussing any of those things directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They allow advertisements to be targeted to particular “racial affinity” groups – or tailored according to “racial affinity”. Not actual race, because that might conflict with various laws, but the race that your profile suggests you have the most “affinity” towards. Racial profiling without the name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dnd-widget-wrapper context-sdl_editor_representation type-video&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;dnd-caption-wrapper&quot;&gt;Cambridge &lt;span class=&quot;scayt-misspell-word&quot; data-scayt-lang=&quot;en_GB&quot; data-scayt-word=&quot;Analytica&quot;&gt;Analytica&lt;/span&gt;: Chris Wylie tells Channel 4 News data for 50 million Facebook profiles was obtained&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This all seems relatively harmless when it is just restricted to advertising for products – it might be a bit creepy to find carefully targeted advertisements for holidays in places you like or musicians you admire – but a few changes in parameters for targeting change things completely. The benefits of this profiling for electoral purposes are huge. Profiling the electorate has long been a part of political campaigning, but this makes it much more detailed, much more surreptitious, and much more effective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parties can target and influence voters directly; make their own supporters happier and opponents’ supporters sadder; make their own more likely to vote. They can spread stories tailored to individuals’ views, focussing on the aspects of a campaign that they know the individual cares about – both positively and negatively. When you add “fake news” to this, the situation becomes even worse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is the real point here. When thought about in terms of profiling and micro-targeting advertising for products, this just sounds efficient and appropriate, and harmless. It is a tiny shift, however to take this into politics – and a shift that groups like Cambridge Analytica found easy to do. All they did was understand how Facebook works, and use it. On a big scale, and in a big way, but this is how Facebook works. Profiling, targeting, persuasive manipulation are the tools of the advertiser on steroids, provably effective and available to those with the money and intent to use them. Unless Facebook changes its entire business model, it will be used in ways that interfere with our lives – and in particular that interferes with our politics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is more, it is only going to get &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; effective. Facebook is gathering more data all the time – including through its associated operations in Instagram, WhatsApp and more. Its analyses are being refined and becoming more effective all the time – and more people like Cambridge Analytica are becoming aware of the possibilities and how they might be used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How it might be stopped, or at least slowed down, is another matter. This is all based on the fundamental operations of Facebook, so while we rely on Facebook, it is hard to see a way out. By choosing to let ourselves become dependent, we have built this trap for ourselves. Until we find our way out of Facebook, more of this is inevitable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Paul Bernal is Senior Lecturer in IT, IP and Media Law, UEA Law School&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;a href=&quot;/syndication/reuse-permission-form?url=http://www.independent.co.uk/voices/camridge-analytica-scandal-how-facebook-works-harvesting-data-politics-trump-brexit-a8264051.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;syndication-btn&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.independent.co.uk/sites/all/themes/ines_themes/independent_theme/img/reuse.png&quot; width=&quot;25&quot;/&gt;Reuse content&lt;/a&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 18:58:55 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>auxbuss</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Cambridge Analytica: This isn't a scandal, it's how Facebook works</og:title>
<og:url>http://www.independent.co.uk/voices/camridge-analytica-scandal-how-facebook-works-harvesting-data-politics-trump-brexit-a8264051.html</og:url>
<og:description>It is easy to be misled into believing that the Cambridge Analytica story is about rogue data miners taking advantage of an innocent Facebook. Facebook’s decision to suspend Cambridge Analytica’s access, the use of terms like “data breach”, and a good deal of coverage in the media seems to follow these lines. That, however, misses the key point.</og:description>
<og:image>https://static.independent.co.uk/s3fs-public/thumbnails/image/2018/02/28/11/facebook-democracy.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.independent.co.uk/voices/camridge-analytica-scandal-how-facebook-works-harvesting-data-politics-trump-brexit-a8264051.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Announcing Microsoft DirectX Raytracing</title>
<link>https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/directx/2018/03/19/announcing-microsoft-directx-raytracing/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/directx/2018/03/19/announcing-microsoft-directx-raytracing/</guid>
<description>&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3D Graphics is a Lie&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the last thirty years, almost all games have used the same general technique—rasterization—to render images on screen.  While the internal representation of the game world is maintained as three dimensions, rasterization ultimately operates in two dimensions (the plane of the screen), with 3D primitives mapped onto it through transformation matrices.  Through approaches like z-buffering and occlusion culling, games have historically strived to minimize the number of spurious pixels rendered, as normally they do not contribute to the final frame.  And in a perfect world, the pixels rendered would be exactly those that are directly visible from the camera:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/raytracing-fig1a.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;362&quot; height=&quot;636&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-1065 aligncenter&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/raytracing-fig1a.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Figure 1a: a top-down illustration of various pixel reduction techniques. Top to bottom: no culling, view frustum culling, viewport clipping&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/raytracing-fig1b.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;382&quot; height=&quot;452&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-1115 aligncenter&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/raytracing-fig1b.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Figure 1b: back-face culling, z-buffering&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through the first few years of the new millennium, this approach was sufficient.  Normal and parallax mapping continued to add layers of realism to 3D games, and GPUs provided the ongoing improvements to bandwidth and processing power needed to deliver them.  It wasn’t long, however, until games began using techniques that were incompatible with these optimizations.  Shadow mapping allowed off-screen objects to contribute to on-screen pixels, and environment mapping required a complete spherical representation of the world.  Today, techniques such as screen-space reflection and global illumination are pushing rasterization to its limits, with SSR, for example, being solved with level design tricks, and GI being solved in some cases by processing a full 3D representation of the world using async compute.  In the future, the utilization of full-world 3D data for rendering techniques will only increase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/raytracing-fig-2.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;422&quot; height=&quot;358&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-1095 aligncenter&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/raytracing-fig-2.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Figure 2: a top-down view showing how shadow mapping can allow even culled geometry to contribute to on-screen shadows in a scene&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, we are introducing a feature to DirectX 12 that will bridge the gap between the rasterization techniques employed by games today, and the full 3D effects of tomorrow.  This feature is DirectX Raytracing.  By allowing traversal of a full 3D representation of the game world, DirectX Raytracing allows current rendering techniques such as SSR to naturally and efficiently fill the gaps left by rasterization, and opens the door to an entirely new class of techniques that have never been achieved in a real-time game. Readers unfamiliar with rasterization and raytracing will find more information about the basics of these concepts in the appendix below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is DirectX Raytracing?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the highest level, DirectX Raytracing (DXR) introduces four, new concepts to the DirectX 12 API:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;The &lt;em&gt;acceleration structure&lt;/em&gt; is an object that represents a full 3D environment in a format optimal for traversal by the GPU.  Represented as a two-level hierarchy, the structure affords both optimized ray traversal by the GPU, as well as efficient modification by the application for dynamic objects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A new command list method, &lt;em&gt;DispatchRays&lt;/em&gt;, which is the starting point for tracing rays into the scene.  This is how the game actually submits DXR workloads to the GPU.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A set of new HLSL shader types including &lt;em&gt;ray-generation&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;closest-hit&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;any-hit&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;miss&lt;/em&gt; shaders.  These specify what the DXR workload actually does computationally.  When DispatchRays is called, the ray-generation shader runs.  Using the new &lt;em&gt;TraceRay&lt;/em&gt; intrinsic function in HLSL, the ray generation shader causes rays to be traced into the scene.  Depending on where the ray goes in the scene, one of several hit or miss shaders may be invoked at the point of intersection.  This allows a game to assign each object its own set of shaders and textures, resulting in a unique material.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;em&gt;raytracing pipeline state&lt;/em&gt;, a companion in spirit to today’s Graphics and Compute pipeline state objects, encapsulates the raytracing shaders and other state relevant to raytracing workloads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may have noticed that DXR does not introduce a new GPU engine to go alongside DX12’s existing Graphics and Compute engines.  This is intentional – DXR workloads can be run on either of DX12’s existing engines.  The primary reason for this is that, fundamentally, DXR is a compute-like workload. It does not require complex state such as output merger blend modes or input assembler vertex layouts.  A secondary reason, however, is that representing DXR as a compute-like workload is aligned to what we see as the future of graphics, namely that hardware will be increasingly general-purpose, and eventually most fixed-function units will be replaced by HLSL code.  The design of the raytracing pipeline state exemplifies this shift through its name and design in the API. With DX12, the traditional approach would have been to create a new CreateRaytracingPipelineState method.  Instead, we decided to go with a much more generic and flexible &lt;em&gt;CreateStateObject&lt;/em&gt; method.  It is designed to be adaptable so that in addition to Raytracing, it can eventually be used to create Graphics and Compute pipeline states, as well as any future pipeline designs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anatomy of a DXR Frame&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step in rendering any content using DXR is to build the acceleration structures, which operate in a two-level hierarchy.  At the bottom level of the structure, the application specifies a set of &lt;em&gt;geometries&lt;/em&gt;, essentially vertex and index buffers representing distinct objects in the world.  At the top level of the structure, the application specifies a list of instance descriptions containing references to a particular geometry, and some additional per-instance data such as transformation matrices, that can be updated from frame to frame in ways similar to how games perform dynamic object updates today.  Together, these allow for efficient traversal of multiple complex geometries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/raytracing-fig3.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;404&quot; height=&quot;276&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-1125 aligncenter&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/raytracing-fig3.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Figure 3: Instances of 2 geometries, each with its own transformation matrix&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second step in using DXR is to create the raytracing pipeline state.  Today, most games batch their draw calls together for efficiency, for example rendering all metallic objects first, and all plastic objects second.  But because it’s impossible to predict exactly what material a particular ray will hit, batching like this isn’t possible with raytracing.  Instead, the raytracing pipeline state allows specification of multiple sets of raytracing shaders and texture resources.  Ultimately, this allows an application to specify, for example, that any ray intersections with object A should use shader P and texture X, while intersections with object B should use shader Q and texture Y.  This allows applications to have ray intersections run the correct shader code with the correct textures for the materials they hit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third and final step in using DXR is to call DispatchRays, which invokes the ray generation shader.  Within this shader, the application makes calls to the TraceRay intrinsic, which triggers traversal of the acceleration structure, and eventual execution of the appropriate hit or miss shader.  In addition, TraceRay can also be called from within hit and miss shaders, allowing for ray recursion or “multi-bounce” effects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/raytracing-fig-4.png&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;434&quot; height=&quot;298&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-1105 aligncenter&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/raytracing-fig-4.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Figure 4: an illustration of ray recursion in a scene&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that because the raytracing pipeline omits many of the fixed-function units of the graphics pipeline such as the input assembler and output merger, it is up to the application to specify how geometry is interpreted.  Shaders are given the minimum set of attributes required to do this, namely the intersection point’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Barycentric_coordinate_system&quot;&gt;barycentric coordinates&lt;/a&gt; within the primitive.  Ultimately, this flexibility is a significant benefit of DXR; the design allows for a huge variety of techniques without the overhead of mandating particular formats or constructs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PIX for Windows Support Available on Day 1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As new graphics features put an increasing array of options at the disposal of game developers, the need for great tools becomes increasingly important.  The great news is that PIX for Windows will support the DirectX Raytracing API from day 1 of the API’s release.  PIX on Windows supports capturing and analyzing frames built using DXR to help developers understand how DXR interacts with the hardware. Developers can inspect API calls, view pipeline resources that contribute to the raytracing work, see contents of state objects, and visualize acceleration structures. This provides the information developers need to build great experiences using DXR.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/Multithreading.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;771&quot; class=&quot;size-large wp-image-1235 aligncenter&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/Multithreading-1024x771.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What Does This Mean for Games?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DXR will initially be used to supplement current rendering techniques such as screen space reflections, for example, to fill in data from geometry that’s either occluded or off-screen.  This will lead to a material increase in visual quality for these effects in the near future.  Over the next several years, however, we expect an increase in utilization of DXR for techniques that are simply impractical for rasterization, such as true global illumination.  Eventually, raytracing may completely replace rasterization as the standard algorithm for rendering 3D scenes.  That said, until everyone has a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Light_field&quot;&gt;light-field&lt;/a&gt; display on their desk, rasterization will continue to be an excellent match for the common case of rendering content to a flat grid of square pixels, supplemented by raytracing for true 3D effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to our friends at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ea.com/seed&quot;&gt;SEED, Electronic Arts&lt;/a&gt;, we can show you a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LXo0WdlELJk&quot;&gt;glimpse of what future gaming scenes could look like&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/SEED-screenshot.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;576&quot; class=&quot;size-large wp-image-1045 aligncenter&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/SEED-screenshot-1024x576.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Project PICA PICA from SEED, Electronic Arts&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, while today marks the first public announcement of DirectX Raytracing, we have been working closely with hardware vendors and industry developers for nearly a year to design and tune the API.  In fact, a significant number of studios and engines are already planning to integrate DXR support into their games and engines, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/frostbite.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;652&quot; height=&quot;367&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-1245 aligncenter&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/frostbite.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Electronic Arts, Frostbite&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/seed-working.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;381&quot; height=&quot;381&quot; class=&quot; wp-image-1285 aligncenter&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/seed-working.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Electronic Arts,  SEED&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/Unreal_Engine_Black.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;341&quot; height=&quot;388&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-1265 aligncenter&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/Unreal_Engine_Black-900x1024.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Epic Games, Unreal Engine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/3dmarkworking.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;696&quot; height=&quot;145&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-1275 aligncenter&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/3dmarkworking.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Futuremark, 3DMark&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/unitylogo.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;448&quot; height=&quot;182&quot; class=&quot; wp-image-1155 aligncenter&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/unitylogo.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Unity Technologies, Unity Engine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And more will be coming soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What Hardware Will DXR Run On?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developers can use currently in-market hardware to get started on DirectX Raytracing.  There is also a fallback layer which will allow developers to start experimenting with DirectX Raytracing that does not require any specific hardware support.  For hardware roadmap support for DirectX Raytracing, please contact hardware vendors directly for further details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Available now for experimentation!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want to be one of the first to bring real-time raytracing to your game?  Start by attending our &lt;a href=&quot;http://schedule.gdconf.com/session/directx-evolving-microsofts-graphics-platform-presented-by-microsoft/856594&quot;&gt;Game Developer Conference Session on DirectX Raytracing &lt;/a&gt;for all the technical details you need to begin, then download the &lt;a href=&quot;http://aka.ms/dxrsdk&quot;&gt;Experimental DXR SDK&lt;/a&gt; and start coding!  Not attending GDC?  No problem!  We'll be posting the slides on this blog after the session.&lt;/p&gt;






&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Appendix – Primers on rasterization, raytracing and DirectX Raytracing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intro to Rasterization&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of all the rendering algorithms out there, by far the most widely used is &lt;strong&gt;rasterization&lt;/strong&gt;. Rasterization has been around since the 90s and has since become the dominant rendering technique in video games. This is with good reason: it’s incredibly efficient and can produce high levels of visual realism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rasterization is an algorithm that in a sense doesn’t do all its work in 3D. This is because rasterization has a step where 3D objects get projected onto your 2D monitor, before they are colored in. This work can be done efficiently by GPUs because it’s work that can be done in parallel: the work needed to color in one pixel on the 2D screen can be done independently of the work needed to color one the pixel next to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a problem with this: in the real world the color of one object will have an impact on the objects around it, because of the complicated interplay of light.  This means that developers must resort to a wide variety of clever techniques to simulate the visual effects that are normally caused by light scattering, reflecting and refracting off objects in the real world. The shadows, reflections and indirect lighting in games are made with these techniques.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Games rendered with rasterization can look and feel incredibly lifelike, because developers have gotten extremely good at making it look as if their worlds have light that acts in convincing way. Having said that, it takes an incredible deal of technical expertise to do this well and there’s also an upper limit to how realistic a rasterized game can get, since information about 3D objects gets lost every time they get projected onto your 2D screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intro to Raytracing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Raytracing calculates the color of pixels by tracing the path of light that would have created it and simulates this ray of light’s interactions with objects in the virtual world. Raytracing therefore calculates what a pixel would look like if a virtual world had real light. The beauty of raytracing is that it preserves the 3D world and visual effects like shadows, reflections and indirect lighting are a natural consequence of the raytracing algorithm, not special effects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Raytracing can be used to calculate the color of every single pixel on your screen, or it can be used for only some pixels, such as those on reflective surfaces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How does it work?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A ray gets sent out for each pixel in question. The algorithm works out which object gets hit first by the ray and the exact point at which the ray hits the object. This point is called the first point of intersection and the algorithm does two things here: 1) it estimates the incoming light at the point of intersection and 2) combines this information about the incoming light with information about the object that was hit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1)      To estimate what the incoming light looked like at the first point of intersection, the algorithm needs to consider where this light was reflected or refracted from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2)      Specific information about each object is important because objects don’t all have the same properties: they absorb, reflect and refract light in different ways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-          different ways of absorption are what cause objects to have different colors (for example, a leaf is green because it absorbs all but green light)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-          different rates of reflection are what cause some objects to give off mirror-like reflections and other objects to scatter rays in all directions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-          different rates of refraction are what cause some objects (like water) to distort light more than other objects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often to estimate the incoming light at the first point of intersection, the algorithm must trace that light to a second point of intersection (because the light hitting an object might have been reflected off another object), or even further back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Savvy readers with some programming knowledge might notice some edge cases here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes light rays that get sent out never hit anything. Don’t worry, this is an edge case we can cover easily by measuring for how far a ray has travelled so that we can do additional work on rays that have travelled for too far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second edge case covers the opposite situation: light might bounce around so much that it’ll slow down the algorithm, or an infinite number of times, causing an infinite loop. The algorithm keeps track of how many times a ray gets traced after every step and gets terminated after a certain number of reflections. We can justify doing this because every object in the real world absorbs some light, even mirrors. This means that a light ray loses energy (becomes fainter) every time it’s reflected, until it becomes too faint to notice. So even if we could, tracing a ray an arbitrary number of times doesn’t make sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the state of raytracing today?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Raytracing a technique that’s been around for decades. It’s used quite often to do CGI in films and several games already use forms of raytracing. For example, developers might use offline raytracing to do things like pre-calculating the brightness of virtual objects before shipping their games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No games currently use real-time raytracing, but we think that this will change soon: over the past few years, computer hardware has become more and more flexible: even with the same TFLOPs, a GPU can do more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How does this fit into DirectX?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We believe that DirectX Raytracing will bring raytracing within reach of real-time use cases, since it comes with dedicated hardware acceleration and can be integrated seamlessly with existing DirectX 12 content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means that it’s now possible for developers to build games that use rasterization for some of its rendering and raytracing to be used for the rest. For example, developers can build a game where much of the content is generated with rasterization, but DirectX Raytracing calculates the shadows or reflections, helping out in areas where rasterization is lacking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the power of DirectX Raytracing: it lets developers have their cake and eat it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 17:26:02 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>nnx</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Announcing Microsoft DirectX Raytracing!</og:title>
<og:url>https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/directx/?p=975</og:url>
<og:description>3D Graphics is a Lie For the last thirty years, almost all games have used the same general technique—rasterization—to render images on screen.  While the internal representation of the game world is maintained as three dimensions, rasterization ultimately operates in two dimensions (the plane of the screen), with 3D primitives mapped onto it through transformation...</og:description>
<og:image>https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/raytracing-fig1a.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/directx/2018/03/19/announcing-microsoft-directx-raytracing/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Facebook suspended the account of whistleblower who exposed Cambridge Analytica</title>
<link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/facebook-suspended-account-whistleblower-exposed-221429183.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.yahoo.com/news/facebook-suspended-account-whistleblower-exposed-221429183.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;Maw(100%) Pos(r) H(0)&quot; data-reactid=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Facebook has suspended the account of the whistleblower who exposed Cambridge Analytica&quot; class=&quot; StretchedBox W(100%) H(100%) ie-7_H(a)&quot; itemprop=&quot;url&quot; src=&quot;https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/3ECjwE_6jNJoiUi.fOWcGg--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjtzbT0xO3c9ODAw/http://media.zenfs.com/en-US/homerun/techcrunch_350/4445a4efdd593f5d4b2c45e8ef00abfa&quot; data-reactid=&quot;8&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript data-reactid=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Facebook has suspended the account of the whistleblower who exposed Cambridge Analytica&quot; class=&quot;StretchedBox W(100%) H(100%) ie-7_H(a)&quot; src=&quot;https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/3ECjwE_6jNJoiUi.fOWcGg--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjtzbT0xO3c9ODAw/http://media.zenfs.com/en-US/homerun/techcrunch_350/4445a4efdd593f5d4b2c45e8ef00abfa&quot; itemprop=&quot;url&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div itemprop=&quot;caption description&quot; class=&quot;Ov(h) Pos(r) Ff(ss) Mah(80px)&quot; data-reactid=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure-caption&quot; data-reactid=&quot;12&quot;&gt;Tech hath no fury like a multi-billion dollar social media giant scorned.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;button class=&quot;C($c-fuji-blue-1-b) Cur(p) W(100%) T(63px) Bgc(#fff) Ta(start) Fz(13px) P(0) Bd(0) O(0) Lh(1.5) Pos(a)&quot; data-reactid=&quot;13&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-reactid=&quot;14&quot;&gt;More&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;canvas-body Wow(bw) Cl(start) Mb(20px) Lh(30px) Fz(18px) Ff(s) C(#000) D(i)&quot; data-reactid=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;canvas-atom canvas-text Mb(1.0em) Mb(0)--sm Mt(0.8em)--sm&quot; type=&quot;text&quot; content=&quot;Tech hath no fury like a multi-billion dollar social media giant scorned.&quot; data-reactid=&quot;16&quot;&gt;Tech hath no fury like a multi-billion dollar social media giant scorned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;canvas-atom canvas-text Mb(1.0em) Mb(0)--sm Mt(0.8em)--sm&quot; type=&quot;text&quot; content=&quot;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/17/trump-campaign-linked-data-firm-cambridge-analytica-reportedly-collected-info-on-50m-facebook-profiles/&amp;quot; rel=&amp;quot;nofollow noopener&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;In the latest turn of the developing scandal&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; around how &amp;lt;a class=&amp;quot;crunchbase-link&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/facebook/&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot; rel=&amp;quot;nofollow noopener&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Facebook's &amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; user data wound up in the hands of Cambridge Analytica -- for use in the in development in psychographic profiles that may or may not have played a part in the election victory of Donald Trump -- the company has taken the unusual step of suspending the account of the whistleblower who helped expose the issues.&quot; data-reactid=&quot;17&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/17/trump-campaign-linked-data-firm-cambridge-analytica-reportedly-collected-info-on-50m-facebook-profiles/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;In the latest turn of the developing scandal&lt;/a&gt; around how &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/facebook/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Facebook's&lt;/a&gt; user data wound up in the hands of Cambridge Analytica -- for use in the in development in psychographic profiles that may or may not have played a part in the election victory of Donald Trump -- the company has taken the unusual step of suspending the account of the whistleblower who helped expose the issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;canvas-atom canvas-text Mb(1.0em) Mb(0)--sm Mt(0.8em)--sm&quot; type=&quot;text&quot; content=&quot;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&amp;quot; rel=&amp;quot;nofollow noopener&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&quot; data-reactid=&quot;19&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;canvas-atom canvas-text Mb(1.0em) Mb(0)--sm Mt(0.8em)--sm&quot; type=&quot;text&quot; content=&quot;In &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://www.theguardian.com/news/2018/mar/17/data-war-whistleblower-christopher-wylie-faceook-nix-bannon-trump&amp;quot; rel=&amp;quot;nofollow noopener&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;a fantastic profile in&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;The Guardian&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, Wylie revealed himself to be the architect of the technology that Cambridge Analytica used to develop targeted advertising strategies that arguably helped sway the U.S. presidential election.&quot; data-reactid=&quot;20&quot;&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/news/2018/mar/17/data-war-whistleblower-christopher-wylie-faceook-nix-bannon-trump&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a fantastic profile in &lt;em&gt;The Guardian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Wylie revealed himself to be the architect of the technology that Cambridge Analytica used to develop targeted advertising strategies that arguably helped sway the U.S. presidential election.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;canvas-atom canvas-text Mb(1.0em) Mb(0)--sm Mt(0.8em)--sm&quot; type=&quot;text&quot; content=&quot;A self-described gay, Canadian vegan, Wylie eventually became -- as he told The Guardian -- the developer of “&amp;lt;a class=&amp;quot;u-underline in-body-link--immersive&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/steve-bannon&amp;quot; rel=&amp;quot;nofollow noopener&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Steve Bannon&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;’s psychological warfare mindfuck tool.&amp;quot;&quot; data-reactid=&quot;21&quot;&gt;A self-described gay, Canadian vegan, Wylie eventually became -- as he told The Guardian -- the developer of “&lt;a class=&quot;u-underline in-body-link--immersive&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/steve-bannon&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Steve Bannon&lt;/a&gt;’s psychological warfare mindfuck tool.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;canvas-atom canvas-text Mb(1.0em) Mb(0)--sm Mt(0.8em)--sm&quot; type=&quot;text&quot; content=&quot;The goal, as&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;The Guardian&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;reported, was to combine social media's reach with big data analytical tools to create psychographic profiles that could then be manipulated in what Bannon and &amp;lt;a class=&amp;quot;crunchbase-link&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/cambridge-analytica/&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot; rel=&amp;quot;nofollow noopener&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Cambridge Analytica &amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; investor Robert Mercer allegedly referred to as a military-style psychological operations campaign -- targeting U.S. voters.&quot; data-reactid=&quot;22&quot;&gt;The goal, as &lt;em&gt;The Guardian &lt;/em&gt;reported, was to combine social media's reach with big data analytical tools to create psychographic profiles that could then be manipulated in what Bannon and &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/cambridge-analytica/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Cambridge Analytica&lt;/a&gt; investor Robert Mercer allegedly referred to as a military-style psychological operations campaign -- targeting U.S. voters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;canvas-atom canvas-text Mb(1.0em) Mb(0)--sm Mt(0.8em)--sm&quot; type=&quot;text&quot; content=&quot;In a series of Tweets late Saturday, Wylie's former employer, Cambridge Analytica, took issue with Wylie's characterization of events (and much of the reporting around the stories from&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;The Times&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt; and &amp;lt;em&amp;gt;The Guardian).&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&quot; data-reactid=&quot;23&quot;&gt;In a series of Tweets late Saturday, Wylie's former employer, Cambridge Analytica, took issue with Wylie's characterization of events (and much of the reporting around the stories from &lt;em&gt;The Times&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Guardian). &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;canvas-atom canvas-text Mb(1.0em) Mb(0)--sm Mt(0.8em)--sm&quot; type=&quot;text&quot; content=&quot;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&amp;quot; rel=&amp;quot;nofollow noopener&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&quot; data-reactid=&quot;25&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;canvas-atom canvas-text Mb(1.0em) Mb(0)--sm Mt(0.8em)--sm&quot; type=&quot;text&quot; content=&quot;Meanwhile, Cadwalldr noted on Twitter earlier today she'd received a phone call from the aggrieved whistleblower.&quot; data-reactid=&quot;26&quot;&gt;Meanwhile, Cadwalldr noted on Twitter earlier today she'd received a phone call from the aggrieved whistleblower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;canvas-tweet canvas-atom Ov(a) W(100%)&quot; data-type=&quot;tweet&quot; data-reactid=&quot;27&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Plaintive phone call from Chris: he's also banned from WhatsApp.&lt;br/&gt;And - outraged voice! - Instagram.&lt;br/&gt;&quot;But how am I going to curate my online identity?&quot; he says.&lt;br/&gt;The Millennials' first great whistleblower? And &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/facebook?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@facebook&lt;/a&gt; hitting him where it hurts &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/abjfh4td4g&quot;&gt;https://t.co/abjfh4td4g&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Carole Cadwalladr (@carolecadwalla) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/carolecadwalla/status/975429619317923840?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;March 18, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;canvas-atom canvas-text Mb(1.0em) Mb(0)--sm Mt(0.8em)--sm&quot; type=&quot;text&quot; content=&quot;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&amp;quot; rel=&amp;quot;nofollow noopener&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&quot; data-reactid=&quot;28&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;canvas-atom canvas-text Mb(1.0em) Mb(0)--sm Mt(0.8em)--sm&quot; type=&quot;text&quot; content=&quot;Not cool, Facebook. Not cool at all.&quot; data-reactid=&quot;29&quot;&gt;Not cool, Facebook. Not cool at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;canvas-atom canvas-text Mb(1.0em) Mb(0)--sm Mt(0.8em)--sm&quot; type=&quot;text&quot; content=&quot;&amp;lt;span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;For more &amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://view.yahoo.com/browse/tv/genre/news-and-information?utm_campaign=tout&amp;amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;amp;utm_source=yahoo/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;news videos&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt; visit &amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://view.yahoo.com/?utm_campaign=tout&amp;amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;amp;utm_source=yahoo&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Yahoo View&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;. &amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&quot; data-reactid=&quot;32&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;For more&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://view.yahoo.com/browse/tv/genre/news-and-information?utm_campaign=tout&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=yahoo/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;news videos&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;visit&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://view.yahoo.com/?utm_campaign=tout&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=yahoo&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yahoo View&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;canvas-atom canvas-text Mb(1.0em) Mb(0)--sm Mt(0.8em)--sm&quot; type=&quot;text&quot; content=&quot;&amp;amp;nbsp;&quot; data-reactid=&quot;33&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 17:23:09 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rock57</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Tech hath no fury like a multi-billion dollar social media giant scorned.</og:description>
<og:image>https://s.yimg.com/uu/api/res/1.2/PxPlOKD9plJkdNvEEpivPA--~B/aD0xNDQwO3c9MjU2MDtzbT0xO2FwcGlkPXl0YWNoeW9u/http://media.zenfs.com/en-US/homerun/techcrunch_350/4445a4efdd593f5d4b2c45e8ef00abfa</og:image>
<og:title>Facebook has suspended the account of the whistleblower who exposed Cambridge Analytica</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.yahoo.com/news/facebook-suspended-account-whistleblower-exposed-221429183.html</og:url>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.yahoo.com/news/facebook-suspended-account-whistleblower-exposed-221429183.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>SEC Announces Its Largest-Ever Whistleblower Awards</title>
<link>https://www.sec.gov/news/press-release/2018-44</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.sec.gov/news/press-release/2018-44</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The Securities and Exchange Commission today announced its highest-ever Dodd-Frank whistleblower awards, with two whistleblowers sharing a nearly $50 million award and a third whistleblower receiving more than $33 million.  The previous high was a $30 million award in 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“These awards demonstrate that whistleblowers can provide the SEC with incredibly significant information that enables us to pursue and remedy serious violations that might otherwise go unnoticed,” said Jane Norberg, Chief of the SEC’s Office of the Whistleblower.  “We hope that these awards encourage others with specific, high-quality information regarding securities laws violations to step forward and report it to the SEC.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SEC has awarded more than $262 million to 53 whistleblowers since issuing its first award in 2012.  All payments are made out of an investor protection fund established by Congress that is financed entirely through monetary sanctions paid to the SEC by securities law violators.  No money has been taken or withheld from harmed investors to pay whistleblower awards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whistleblowers may be eligible for an award when they voluntarily provide the SEC with original, timely, and credible information that leads to a successful enforcement action. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whistleblower awards can range from 10 percent to 30 percent of the money collected when the monetary sanctions exceed $1 million. As with this case, whistleblowers can report jointly under the program and share an award.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By law, the SEC protects the confidentiality of whistleblowers and does not disclose information that might directly or indirectly reveal a whistleblower’s identity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information about the whistleblower program and how to report a tip, visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sec.gov/whistleblower&quot;&gt;www.sec.gov/whistleblower&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 17:08:22 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ColinFCodeChef</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.sec.gov/news/press-release/2018-44</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Self-driving Uber car kills Arizona woman crossing street</title>
<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-autos-selfdriving-uber/self-driving-uber-car-kills-arizona-woman-crossing-street-idUSKBN1GV296</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.reuters.com/article/us-autos-selfdriving-uber/self-driving-uber-car-kills-arizona-woman-crossing-street-idUSKBN1GV296</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;first-p_2htdt&quot;&gt;TEMPE, Ariz./SAN FRANCISCO (Reuters) - An Uber self-driving car hit and killed a woman crossing the street in Arizona, police said on Monday, marking the first fatality involving an autonomous vehicle and a potential blow to the technology expected to transform transportation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The ride services company said it was suspending North American tests of its self-driving vehicles, which are currently going on in Arizona, Pittsburgh and Toronto.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;So-called robot cars, when fully developed by companies including Uber, Alphabet Inc and General Motors Co, are expected to drastically cut down on motor vehicle fatalities and create billion-dollar businesses. But Monday’s accident underscored the possible challenges ahead for the promising technology as the cars confront real-world situations involving real people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;U.S. lawmakers have been debating legislation that would speed introduction of self-driving cars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“This tragic accident underscores why we need to be exceptionally cautious when testing and deploying autonomous vehicle technologies on public roads,” said Democratic Senator Edward Markey, a member of the transportation committee, in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Elaine Herzberg, 49, was walking her bicycle outside the crosswalk on a four-lane road in the Phoenix suburb of Tempe about 10 p.m. MST Sunday (0400 GMT Monday) when she was struck by the Uber vehicle traveling at about 40 miles per hour (65 km per hour), police said. The car was in autonomous mode with an operator behind the wheel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Herzberg later died from her injuries in a hospital, police said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“The pedestrian was outside of the crosswalk. As soon as she walked into the lane of traffic she was struck,” Tempe Police Sergeant Ronald Elcock told reporters at a news conference. He said he did not yet know how close Herzberg was to the vehicle when she stepped into the lane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Elcock said he believed Herzberg may have been homeless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Volvo, the Swedish car brand owned by China’s Geely [GEELY.UL], confirmed its XC90 SUV was involved in the crash but said the software controlling the car was not its own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;U.S. federal safety regulators were sending teams to investigate the crash. Canada’s transportation ministry in Ontario, where Uber conducts testing, also said it was reviewing the accident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Video footage would aid the ongoing investigation, and the case would be submitted to the district attorney, Elcock said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“Our investigators have that information, and they will be using that in their investigation as well as the Maricopa County Attorney’s Office as part of their investigation,” said Elcock. “They are going to attempt to try to find who was possibly at fault and how we can better be safe, whether it’s pedestrians or whether it’s the vehicle itself.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;container_1tVQo&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;


&lt;span class=&quot;caption_KoNH1&quot;&gt;Tempe Police Sergeant Ronald Elcock speaks to the media after a female pedestrian was struck and killed by an Uber self-driving sport utility vehicle in Tempe, Arizona, U.S., March 19, 2018. REUTERS/Rick Scuteri&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;WILD WEST&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Uber and Waymo on Friday urged Congress to pass sweeping legislation to speed the introduction of self-driving cars into the United States. Some congressional Democrats have blocked the legislation over safety concerns, and Monday’s fatality could hamper passage of the bill, congressional aides said Monday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Safety advocates called for a national moratorium on all robot car testing on public roads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“Arizona has been the wild west of robot car testing with virtually no regulations in place,” said Consumer Watchdog, a non-profit consumer advocacy group, in a statement. “That’s why Uber and Waymo test there. When there’s no sheriff in town, people get killed.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;inline-container_1QqKC mega_19SOz&quot;&gt;

Slideshow &lt;span class=&quot;count_3OPtf&quot;&gt;(6 Images)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Arizona has opened its arms to companies testing self-driving vehicles as a means to economic growth and jobs. Republican Governor Doug Ducey reached out to Uber in 2016 after California regulators cracked down on the company over its failure to obtain testing permits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Self-driving cars being tested routinely get into fender-benders with other vehicles. Last week, a self-driving Uber crashed with another vehicle in Pittsburgh, local news reported. There were no injuries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;A year ago, Uber temporarily grounded its self-driving cars for a few days following a crash with another car in Tempe. The company has been the subject of a number of complaints about its autonomous vehicles, but the company has said the cars were being driven by a human driver at the time of the incidents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;ESSENTIAL TO UBER’S SUCCESS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Uber has said its ability to build autonomous cars is essential to its success in the rapidly changing transportation industry. The company envisions a network of autonomous cars that would be summoned through the Uber app that would supplement - and eventually replace - human-driven cars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Uber has logged 2 million self-driving miles (3.2 million km) through December. The company has more than 100 autonomous cars testing on the roads of the greater Phoenix area, the company’s prime testing ground due to the state’s loose regulations and hospitable weather. Rain, snow and ice are particularly challenging for autonomous cars. The company also tests in Pittsburgh and Toronto.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Concerns over the safety of autonomous vehicles flared after a July 2016 fatality involving a Tesla Inc automobile with a partially autonomous system that required human supervision. Safety regulators later determined Tesla was not at fault.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Uber has weathered a series of crises, including sexual harassment claims, using a tracking tool to avoid government officials, and a lawsuit brought by competitor Waymo alleging theft of self-driving trade secrets. Uber settled that lawsuit last month for $245 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;That settlement was largely seen as a means for Uber to resume work on autonomous cars without the distraction of litigation, as it hustles to catch up with Waymo, widely seen as having the most advanced cars in the industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;container_28wm1&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;attribution_o4ojT&quot; readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;content_27_rw&quot;&gt;Reporting by Sydney Maki and Alexandria Sage; Additional reporting by Dave Shepardson in Washington, Tina Bellon in New York, Heather Somerville in San Francisco, David Schwartz and Andres Guerra Luz in Phoenix, and Allison Lampert in Montreal; Editing by Jonathan Oatis and Lisa Shumaker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 16:47:22 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kgwgk</dc:creator>
<og:title>Self-driving Uber car kills Arizona woman crossing street</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-autos-selfdriving-uber/woman-dies-in-arizona-after-being-hit-by-uber-self-driving-car-idUSKBN1GV296</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>An Uber self-driving car hit and killed a woman crossing the street in Arizona, police said on Monday, marking the first fatality involving an autonomous vehicle and a potential blow to the technology expected to transform transportation.</og:description>
<og:image>https://s3.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;d=20180319&amp;t=2&amp;i=1242652594&amp;w=1200&amp;r=LYNXMPEE2I1Y6</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-autos-selfdriving-uber/self-driving-uber-car-kills-arizona-woman-crossing-street-idUSKBN1GV296</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Creator</title>
<link>https://www.magicleap.com/creator</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.magicleap.com/creator</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.magicleap.com/creator&quot;&gt;https://www.magicleap.com/creator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16619505&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16619505&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Points: 239&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 89&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 16:10:12 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>runesoerensen</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.magicleap.com/creator</og:url>
<og:title>Creator | Magic Leap</og:title>
<og:description>Magic Leap Creator Portal. Developers can download Lumin SDK, discover tutorials and other learning resources, and join the Magic Leap Community.</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.magicleap.com/static/icons/magicleap-og.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.magicleap.com/creator</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Building a chat app in 8 minutes with Phoenix</title>
<link>https://elixircasts.io/chat-room-in-8-minutes</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://elixircasts.io/chat-room-in-8-minutes</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Phoenix is the most popular Framework for web development in Elixir.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And one of it’s most exciting parts is the ability to add realtime functionality, which we can do with Channels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this episode let’s see how can build a simple chat application with Phoenix using websockets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s start this from project from the ground-up, so the first thing we’ll need is a fresh Phoenix app - let’s create a new one with the very unoriginal name ‘chat’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;$ mix phx.new chat&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we’ll install the dependencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then we’ll cd into the ‘chat’ directory and create our database:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;$ mix ecto.create&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And let’s start our app to make sure everything looks good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;$ mix phx.server&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And great - we see the familiar “Welcome to Phoenix!” page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we know everything is working let’s get started on building our chat room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll need to generate a new channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phoenix provides a generator we can use, we’ll just need to give it a name. Let’s play with the idea of a chat-room and call ours &lt;code class=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;water_cooler&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;$ mix phx.gen.channel water_cooler&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it creates a &lt;code class=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;water_cooler_channel.ex&lt;/code&gt; module&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll look at it in a minute, but first let’s add our channel to the user socket handler.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll send any events with the &lt;code class=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;water_cooler&lt;/code&gt; topic to our new ‘WaterCoolerChannel’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The asterisk is a wildcard, catching any events coming into the water_cooler topic - regardless of the subtopic - and sending them to our &lt;code class=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;WaterCoolerChannel&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
lib/chat_web/channels/user_socket.ex
&lt;code&gt;
defmodule ChatWeb.UserSocket do
  use Phoenix.Socket

  ##channels
  channel &quot;water_cooler:*&quot;, ChatWeb.WaterCoolerChannel

  ...
end
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that updated let’s open the &lt;code class=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;water_cooler_channel.ex&lt;/code&gt; that we generated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has a &lt;code class=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;join&lt;/code&gt; callback that will handle events for the &lt;code class=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;water_cooler:lobby&lt;/code&gt; topic/subtopic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this example that Phoenix creates, it’s giving us an &lt;code class=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;authorized?&lt;/code&gt; function that will always return true. It’s a nice guide for where we could put authorization logic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our example we won’t do any authorization, so let’s remove the logic and have it always return the OK tuple with our socket. And since we won’t be using the &lt;code class=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;payload&lt;/code&gt; we can ignore it with the underscore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;handle_in&lt;/code&gt; ping function we wont use, so let’s remove it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;handle_in&lt;/code&gt; shout function is in charge of broadcasting any chat events to everyone that’s joined our channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice that this is set to pattern match on “shout” - we’ll need to remember to use this when we push events out from the client .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we’ll remove the &lt;code class=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;authorized?&lt;/code&gt; function since we removed our authorization logic in the &lt;code class=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;join&lt;/code&gt; callback .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
lib/chat_web/channels/water_cooler_channel.ex
&lt;code&gt;
defmodule ChatWeb.WaterCoolerChannel do
  use ChatWeb, :channel

  def join(&quot;water_cooler:lobby&quot;, _payload, socket) do
    {:ok, socket}
  end

  #It is also common to receive messages from the client and
  #broadcast to everyone in the current topic (water_cooler:lobby).
  def handle_in(&quot;shout&quot;, payload, socket) do
    broadcast socket, &quot;shout&quot;, payload
    {:noreply, socket}
  end
end
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now let’s go to our &lt;code class=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;assets/js/socket.js&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we see some code has already been populated that imports and connects our socket to the socket path in our &lt;code class=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;endpoint.ex&lt;/code&gt; module which is then handled by our &lt;code class=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;UserSocket&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our default code also shows how we can join channels with a topic. The topic we defined in our WaterCoolerChannel is &lt;code class=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;water_cooler:lobby&lt;/code&gt; so let’s update that here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It then logs out a message to our browser’s console letting us know if we’ve joined successfully or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
assets/js/socket.js
&lt;code&gt;
...
let channel = socket.channel(&quot;water_cooler:lobby&quot;, {})
...
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then we’ll open &lt;code class=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;app.js&lt;/code&gt; and import our socket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
assets/js/app.js
&lt;code&gt;
import &quot;phoenix_html&quot;

import socket from &quot;./socket&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now let’s go to the command line and start our server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;$ mix phx.server&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s give it a shot. We’ll open our browser and in the console - we see our success message is printed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we’re joining successfully let’s create a chat window and form we’ll use to post messages with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Let’s first customize our site a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll remove the &lt;code class=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;phoenix.css&lt;/code&gt; stylesheet. And in the &lt;code class=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;app.css&lt;/code&gt; I’ll paste in some custom css, which is available in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/elixircastsio/038-chat-app-in-8-minutes/blob/master/assets/css/app.css&quot;&gt;linked GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then we’ll open our &lt;code class=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;app.html.eex&lt;/code&gt; template and let’s remove the Phoenix logo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Template path:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code class=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;lib/chat_web/templates/layout/app.html.eex&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;html&quot;&gt;    ...
    &amp;lt;div class=&quot;container&quot;&amp;gt;
    
          &amp;lt;p class=&quot;alert alert-info&quot; role=&quot;alert&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;%= get_flash(@conn, :info) %&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
          &amp;lt;p class=&quot;alert alert-danger&quot; role=&quot;alert&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;%= get_flash(@conn, :error) %&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
    ...&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then in our page’s &lt;code class=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;index.html.eex&lt;/code&gt; template we’ll paste in the chat window and and form that will have a username and message field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Template path:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code class=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;lib/chat_web/templates/page/index.html.eex&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;html&quot;&gt;    &amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;The Water Cooler&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;div id=&quot;chat-box&quot;&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
    
    &amp;lt;form id=&quot;chat-form&quot;&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;input type=&quot;text&quot; placeholder=&quot;Username&quot; id=&quot;user-name&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/input&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;textarea placeholder=&quot;Your comment&quot; id=&quot;user-msg&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/textarea&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;button type=&quot;submit&quot;&amp;gt;Post&amp;lt;/button&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/form&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then let’s open our browser and see what it looks like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we see our chat box and form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now let’s add some JavaScript to get our chat working, so that when we post a message it’s displayed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll create a new file in our &lt;code class=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;assets/js&lt;/code&gt; named &lt;code class=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;water_cooler.js&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we’ll create our &lt;code class=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;WaterCooler&lt;/code&gt; object.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The we’ll create a function &lt;code class=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;init&lt;/code&gt; that will take our socket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And with our socket we’ll join the channel with our “water_cooler:lobby” topic. Now that we’ve joined our channel, we need to send and receive events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s create a new function &lt;code class=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;listenForChats&lt;/code&gt; that will take our channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll paste in our code for sending events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But let’s walk through this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re get our chat form with the id &lt;code class=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;chat-form&lt;/code&gt; and then listening for when it’s submitting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the form is submitted we’re preventing any further action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;then we’re getting the username from the form&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the message from the form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then we’re calling channel.push with “shout” and payload of our username and the message. This will send our event to the server, where it will be picked up by our &lt;code class=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;WaterCoolerChannel&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we’re setup to send events, we need to receive them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll use channel.on to subscribe to channel events, matching on “shout”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then we’ll get our &lt;code class=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;chatBox&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And our create a new message block&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then we’ll build up our message by getting the name and message from the received payload.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll then append that message to our chatBox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
assets/js/water_cooler.js
&lt;code&gt;
let WaterCooler = {
  init(socket) {
    let channel = socket.channel('water_cooler:lobby', {})
    channel.join()
    this.listenForChats(channel)
  },

  listenForChats(channel) {
    document.getElementById('chat-form').addEventListener('submit', function(e){
      e.preventDefault()

      let userName = document.getElementById('user-name').value
      let userMsg = document.getElementById('user-msg').value

      channel.push('shout', {name: userName, body: userMsg})

      document.getElementById('user-name').value = ''
      document.getElementById('user-msg').value = ''
    })

    channel.on('shout', payload =&amp;gt; {
      let chatBox = document.querySelector('#chat-box')
      let msgBlock = document.createElement('p')

      msgBlock.insertAdjacentHTML('beforeend', `&lt;strong&gt;${payload.name}:&lt;/strong&gt; ${payload.body}`)
      chatBox.appendChild(msgBlock)
    })
  }
}

export default WaterCooler
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now let’s open our &lt;code class=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;app.js&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we’ll import &lt;code class=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;WaterCooler&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then we’ll call init, passing in our socket to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
assets/js/app.js
&lt;code&gt;
...
import WaterCooler from &quot;./water_cooler&quot;

WaterCooler.init(socket)
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if we go back to our browser and try typing a message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We see our message is received and broadcasted out to everyone that’s joined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And let’s try sending a message back - and that works too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is great, but when we refresh the page - our chat disappears because it’s not being persisted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll fix that by saving our chats to the database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s have Phoenix do the heavy lifting for us here and use the context generator to build out the modules and database migration that we’ll need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll go to the command line - and we’ll stop our server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And let’s our new context ‘Chats’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;our ecto schema module will be ‘Message’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And our table will be messages with a name column that’s a string&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and body column that’s a text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;$ mix phx.gen.context Chats Message messages name:string body:text&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then we’ll migrate our database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;$ mix ecto.migrate&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And let’s take a quick look at the message module that was created.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We see our schema with our body and name fields.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and our changeset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;then let’s open the chats context&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it’s been populated with some functions to save and get our messages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great, now we need to save our messages when someone posts one in the chat. Let’s do that in our channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we’ll open our &lt;code class=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;water_cooler_channel.ex&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then let’s alias our ‘chats’ context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And in our &lt;code class=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;handle_in&lt;/code&gt; function we’ll save the message before it’s broadcasted out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we could make this asynchronous, but let’s keep it simple for the purposes of this episode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
lib/chat_web/channels/water_cooler_channel.ex
&lt;code&gt;
...
alias Chat.Chats
...
def handle_in(&quot;shout&quot;, payload, socket) do
  Chats.create_message(payload)
  broadcast socket, &quot;shout&quot;, payload
  {:noreply, socket}
end
...
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we’re saving our messages we need to load any existing ones into the chat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s open our &lt;code class=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;page_controller.ex&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll alias our &lt;code class=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;Chat.Chats&lt;/code&gt; module&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then let’s get all our messages&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we’ll pass them in our assigns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
lib/chat_web/controllers/page_controller.ex
&lt;code&gt;
defmodule ChatWeb.PageController do
  use ChatWeb, :controller

  alias Chat.Chats

  def index(conn, _params) do
    messages = Chats.list_messages()
    render conn, &quot;index.html&quot;, messages: messages
  end
end
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we can open our &lt;code class=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;index.html.eex&lt;/code&gt; template and render any messages that were returned in our chat box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Template path:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code class=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;lib/chat_web/templates/page/index.html.eex&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;html&quot;&gt;    &amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;The Water Cooler&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;div id=&quot;chat-box&quot;&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;%= for message &amp;lt;- @messages do %&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;%= message.name %&amp;gt;:&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; &amp;lt;%= message.body %&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;% end %&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
    ...&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then let’s restart our server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And go back to the browser and post some messages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then if we do a quick check of the database - we see our messages are there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if we go back to our chat and refresh the page - we see our existing messages are loaded.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 14:51:13 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>alekx</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://elixircasts.io/chat-room-in-8-minutes</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Epic Games releases $12M worth of Paragon assets for free</title>
<link>https://www.unrealengine.com/en-US/blog/epic-games-releases-12-million-worth-of-paragon-assets-for-free</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.unrealengine.com/en-US/blog/epic-games-releases-12-million-worth-of-paragon-assets-for-free</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;qa-unreal-engine-4-supports-microsoft-s-directx-raytracing-and-nvidia-rtx&quot; readability=&quot;20.324022346369&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;activityGridRow-date __post-date__&quot; data-date_=&quot;Mar 19, 2018&quot;&gt;Mar 19, 2018&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;By Dana Cowley&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, Microsoft has announced DirectX Raytracing (DXR), which brings real-...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;qa-unreal-engine-4-supports-magic-leap-one&quot; readability=&quot;23.099337748344&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;activityGridRow-date __post-date__&quot; data-date_=&quot;Mar 19, 2018&quot;&gt;Mar 19, 2018&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;By Chance Ivey&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unreal Engine 4 developers can create content for Magic Leap One™ starting ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;qa-optimizing-battle-breakers-for-chunked-downloading&quot; readability=&quot;22.490445859873&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;activityGridRow-date __post-date__&quot; data-date_=&quot;Mar 15, 2018&quot;&gt;Mar 15, 2018&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;By Ben Zeigler&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We explore the tools and techniques we used when making Battle Breakers, en...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 14:36:16 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>program</dc:creator>
<og:title>Epic Games Releases $12 Million Worth of Paragon Assets for Free</og:title>
<og:description>Developers can access a wealth of richly detailed Paragon characters and environment assets for use in Unreal Engine 4 projects, no strings attached.</og:description>
<og:image>https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/Unreal+Engine%2Fblog%2Fepic-games-releases-12-million-worth-of-paragon-assets-for-free%2FFB_ParagonAsetsReleased-1200x630-316cb9fe0b13caf62771dc3cb8a3305b119bad24.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.unrealengine.com/en-US/blog/epic-games-releases-12-million-worth-of-paragon-assets-for-free</og:url>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.unrealengine.com/en-US/blog/epic-games-releases-12-million-worth-of-paragon-assets-for-free</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>#deletefacebook</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/19/deletefacebook/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/19/deletefacebook/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/facebook/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;facebook&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; is using us. It is actively giving away our information. It is creating an echo chamber in the name of connection. It surfaces the divisive and destroys the real reason we began using social media in the first place – human connection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve begun the slow process of weaning myself off of the platform by methodically &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/social-book-post-manager/ljfidlkcmdmmibngdfikhffffdmphjae&quot;&gt;running a script that will delete my old content&lt;/a&gt;. And there’s a lot. There are likes and shares. There are long posts I wrote to impress my friends. There are thousands of WordPress notifications that tell the world what I’m doing. In fact, I would wager I use Facebook more to broadcast my ego than interact with real humans. And I suspect that most of us are in a similar situation.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;breakout alignnone size-medium wp-image-1608636&quot; src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/screen-shot-2018-03-19-at-8-34-18-am.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a method to my madness. I like Facebook &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/messenger/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;messenger&quot;&gt;Messenger&lt;/a&gt; and I like that Facebook is now a glorified version of OAuth. It’s a useful tool when it is stripped of its power. However, when it is larded with my personal details it is a weapon and a liability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about it: any posts older than about a week are fodder for bots and bad actors. Posts from 2016? 2017? Why keep them? No one will read them, no one cares about them. Those “You and Joe have known each other for five years” auto-posts are fun but does anyone care? Ultimately you’ve created the largest dossier on yourself and you’ve done it freely, even gleefully. This dossier reflects your likes, your dislikes, your feelings, and political leanings. It includes clear pictures of your face from all angles, images of your pets and family, and details your travels. You are giving the world unfettered access to your life. It’s wonderful to imagine that this data will be used by a potential suitor who will fall in love with your street style. It’s wonderful to imagine you will scroll through Facebook at 80 and marvel at how you looked at the turn of the century. It’s wonderful to imagine that Facebook is a place to share ideas, dreams, and hopes, a human-to-human connection engine that gives more than it takes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None of that will happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook is a data collection service for those who want to sell you products. It is the definitive channel to target you based on age, sex, geographic location, political leanings, interests, and marital status. It’s an advertiser’s dream and it is wildly expensive in terms of privacy lost and cash spent to steal that privacy. It is the perfect tool for marketers, a user-generated paradise that is now run by devils.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will you delete Facebook? Probably not. Will I? I’m working on it. I’ve already been &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tweetdeleter.com/en&quot;&gt;deleting old tweets after&lt;/a&gt; realizing that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thenation.com/article/trumps-border-security-may-search-your-social-media-by-tone/&quot;&gt;border police&lt;/a&gt; and potential employers may use what I write publicly against me. I’m clearing out old social media accounts and, as I mentioned before, deleting old Facebook posts, thus ensuring that I will no longer be a target for companies like &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/16/facebook-suspends-cambridge-analytica-the-data-analysis-firm-that-worked-for-the-trump-campaign/&quot;&gt;Cambridge Analytica&lt;/a&gt;. But we love our social media, don’t we? The power it affords. The feeling of connection. In the absence of human interaction we cling to whatever dark simulacrum is available. In the absence of the Town Square we talk to ourselves. In the absence of love and understanding we join the slow riot of online indifference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/topic/person/travis-kalanick/&quot;&gt;Travis Kalanick&lt;/a&gt; led his ride-sharing company down the dark path to paranoia, bro culture, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://money.cnn.com/video/technology/2017/03/01/uber-travis-kalanick-rant-against-driver.cnnmoney/index.html&quot;&gt;classist rantings&lt;/a&gt; we reacted by deleting the app. We didn’t want to do business with that particular brand of company. Yet we sit idly by while Facebook sells us out and its management pummels and destroys all competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish it didn’t have to be this way. There is plenty of good in these platforms but the dangers far outweigh the benefits. Try to recall the last time you were thankful for social media. I can. It happened twice. First, it happened when I posted on my &lt;a href=&quot;https://bigwidelogic.com/2018/01/15/in-memoriam-robert-lee-biggs-age-79/&quot;&gt;“wall” a eulogy for my father who died in January&lt;/a&gt;. The outpouring of support was heartening in a dark time. It was wonderful to see friends and acquaintances tell me their own stories, thereby taking the sting out of my own. But months later that good feeling is gone, replaced by ads for fancy shoes and political rants. Out of the Facebook swamp sometimes surfaces a pearl. But it sinks just as quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One more sad example: I found out, accidentally, that my friend’s wife died. It appeared on my feed as if placed there by some divine hand and I was thankful it surfaced. It beat out videos of Mister Rogers saying inspiring things and goofy pictures of Trump. It beat out ads and rants and questions about the best sushi restaurant in Scranton. The stark announcement left me crying and breathless. There it was in black and blue, splashed across her page: she was gone. There was the smiling photo of her two little children and there was the outpouring of grief under these once innocuous photos. Gone, it said. She was gone. I found out from her wall where her memorial service would be held and I finally reached back out to my old friend to try to comfort him in his grief. Facebook, in those two instances, worked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Facebook isn’t the only thing that can give us that feeling of connectedness. We’ve had it for centuries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook simply replaced the tools we once used to tell the world of our joys and sorrows and it replaced them with cheap knock-offs that make us less connected, not more. Decades ago, on one coal-fogged winter morning in Krakow, Poland where I was living, I passed &lt;em&gt;Kościół św. Wojciecha&lt;/em&gt; with its collection of &lt;em&gt;nekrologi&lt;/em&gt; – necrologies – posted on a board in front of the church. There you saw the names of the dead – and sometimes the names of the newly born – and it was there you discovered what was happening in your little corner of the world. The church wasn’t far from the central square – the &lt;em&gt;Rynek&lt;/em&gt; – and I walked there thinking about the endless parade of humanity that had walked across those cobbles, stopping for a moment in their hustle at the church yard to see who had died. I stood in the crisp air, flanked by centuries old brickwork, and imagined who once populated this place. This was the place you met your friends and your future partners. It was there you celebrated your successes and mourned your failures. It was there, among other humans, you told the world the story of your life, but told it slant. You witnessed kindnesses and cruelties, you built a world entire based on the happenings in a few square miles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;breakout alignnone size-medium wp-image-1608665&quot; src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/1280px-deathnotices.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No more. Or, at least, those places are no longer available to most of us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve moved past the superstitions and mythologies of the past. Tools like Facebook were designed to connect us to the world, giving us an almost angelic view of daily happenstance. We replaced the churchyard with the “timeline.” But our efforts failed. We are still as closed, still full of superstition, as we were a hundred years ago. We traded a market square for the Internet but all of the closed-mindedness and cynicism came with it. We still disparage the outsider, we still rant against invisible enemies, and we still keep our friends close and fear what lies beyond our door. Only now we have the whole world on which to reflect our terror.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t have to be this way. Maybe some day we’ll get the tools we need to interact with the world. Maybe they’re already here and we just don’t want to use them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until we find them, however, it’s probably better for us to delete the ones we use today.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 14:18:49 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>middle1</dc:creator>
<og:title>#deletefacebook</og:title>
<og:description>Facebook is using us. It is actively giving away our information. It is creating an echo chamber in the name of connection. It surfaces the divisive and destroys the real reason we began using social media in the first place – human connection. It is a cancer. I’ve begun the slow proces…</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/delete-facebook.png?w=753</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2018/03/19/deletefacebook/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/19/deletefacebook/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>