<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Gmail having issues</title>
<link>https://www.google.com/appsstatus#hl=en&amp;v=issue&amp;sid=1&amp;iid=a8b67908fadee664c68c240ff9f529ab</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.google.com/appsstatus#hl=en&amp;v=issue&amp;sid=1&amp;iid=a8b67908fadee664c68c240ff9f529ab</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/appsstatus#hl=en&amp;v=issue&amp;sid=1&amp;iid=a8b67908fadee664c68c240ff9f529ab&quot;&gt;https://www.google.com/appsstatus#hl=en&amp;v=issue&amp;sid=1&amp;iid=a8b67908fadee664c68c240ff9f529ab&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25435916&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25435916&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 282&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 174&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 22:12:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mangoman</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.google.com/appsstatus</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Facebook to move UK users to California terms, avoiding EU privacy rules</title>
<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/britain-eu-facebook-exclusive-idUSKBN28P2HH</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.reuters.com/article/britain-eu-facebook-exclusive-idUSKBN28P2HH</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;ArticleBody-byline-container-3H6dy&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Byline-byline-1sVmo ArticleBody-byline-10B7D&quot;&gt;By &lt;a class=&quot;TextLabel__text-label___3oCVw TextLabel__black-to-orange___23uc0 TextLabel__serif___3lOpX Byline-author-2BSir&quot; href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/journalists/joseph-menn&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Joseph Menn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ArticleBody-read-time-and-social-2VOIr&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;TextLabel__text-label___3oCVw TextLabel__gray___1V4fk TextLabel__small-all-caps-spaced-out___3O9H4 ReadTime-read-time-1s3CG ArticleBody-read-time-29pGN&quot;&gt;4 Min Read&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;SAN FRANCISCO (Reuters) - Facebook Inc will shift all its users in the United Kingdom into user agreements with the corporate headquarters in California, moving them out of their current relationship with Facebook’s Irish unit and out of reach of Europe’s privacy laws.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FILE PHOTO: The Facebook logo is displayed on a mobile phone in this picture illustration taken December 2, 2019. REUTERS/Johanna Geron/Illustration/File Photo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;The change takes effect next year and follows a similar move announced in February by Google &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/article/us-google-privacy-eu-exclusive-idUSKBN20D2M3&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Those companies and others have European head offices in Dublin, and the UK's exit from the EU will change its legal relationship with Ireland, which remains in the Union.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;Initially, sources briefed on the matter told Reuters about the move. Facebook later confirmed it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;“Like other companies, Facebook has had to make changes to respond to Brexit and will be transferring legal responsibilities and obligations for UK users from Facebook Ireland to Facebook Inc. There will be no change to the privacy controls or the services Facebook offers to people in the UK,” the company’s UK arm said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;Facebook’s UK users will remain subject to UK privacy law, which for now tracks the European Union’s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). Facebook is making the change partly because the EU privacy regime is among the world’s strictest, according to people familiar with the company. The EU rules give granular control to users over data about them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;In addition, the U.S. Cloud Act, passed in 2018, set a way for the UK and United States to more easily exchange data about cloud computing users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;Privacy advocates fear the UK may move to an even looser data privacy regime, especially as it pursues a trade deal with the United States, which offers far fewer protections. Some also worry that UK Facebook users could more easily be subject to surveillance by U.S. intelligence agencies or data requests from law enforcement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;“The bigger the company, the more personal data they hold, the more they are likely to be subject to surveillance duties or requirements to hand over data to the U.S. government,” said Jim Killock, executive director of the UK-based nonprofit Open Rights Group. U.S. courts have held that constitutional protections against unreasonable searches do not apply to non-citizens overseas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;UK information industry regulators said they had been in touch with Facebook along with companies keeping European headquarters as Brexit nears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;“We are aware of Facebook’s plans and will continue to engage with the company in the new year,” said a spokeswoman at the Information Commissioner’s Office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;A Twitter spokesman said its UK users will continue to be handled by the company’s Dublin office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;Facebook will inform users of the shift in the next six months, a spokesman said, giving them the option to stop using the world’s largest social network and its Instagram and WhatsApp services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;Facebook’s decision comes at a time when the UK is escalating efforts to ban strong encryption, which Facebook is moving to implement on all its products. The UK, like the European Union, is also pressuring Facebook on a number of other fronts, including hate speech and terrorism policies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;The United States may also pursue new laws on privacy and social media content, and federal and state prosecutors recently launched antitrust lawsuits against both Facebook and Alphabet Inc’s Google. Still, tech lobbyists expect that U.S. tech regulations will remain more industry-friendly than those in the UK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;5.136690647482&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Attribution-attribution-Y5JpY&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reporting by Joseph Menn in San Francisco; Editing by Jonathan Weber and Matthew Lewis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 21:43:07 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>EB-Barrington</dc:creator>
<og:title>Exclusive-Facebook to move UK users to California terms, avoiding EU privacy rules</og:title>
<og:description>Facebook Inc will shift all its users in the United Kingdom into user agreements with the corporate headquarters in California, moving them out of their current relationship with Facebook's Irish unit and out of reach of Europe's privacy laws.</og:description>
<og:image>https://static.reuters.com/resources/r/?m=02&amp;d=20201215&amp;t=2&amp;i=1544660891&amp;r=LYNXMPEGBE1K2&amp;w=800</og:image>
<og:url>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-britain-eu-facebook-exclusive-idUSKBN28P2HH</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.reuters.com/article/britain-eu-facebook-exclusive-idUSKBN28P2HH</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>EU reveals plan to regulate Big Tech</title>
<link>https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-55318225</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-55318225</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;style data-emotion-css=&quot;yidnqd-InlineLink&quot;&gt;&lt;![CDATA[.css-yidnqd-InlineLink:link{color:#3F3F42;}.css-yidnqd-InlineLink:visited{color:#696969;}.css-yidnqd-InlineLink:link,.css-yidnqd-InlineLink:visited{font-weight:bolder;border-bottom:1px solid #BABABA;-webkit-text-decoration:none;text-decoration:none;}.css-yidnqd-InlineLink:link:hover,.css-yidnqd-InlineLink:visited:hover,.css-yidnqd-InlineLink:link:focus,.css-yidnqd-InlineLink:visited:focus{border-bottom-color:currentcolor;border-bottom-width:2px;color:#B80000;}@supports (text-underline-offset:0.25em){.css-yidnqd-InlineLink:link,.css-yidnqd-InlineLink:visited{border-bottom:none;-webkit-text-decoration:underline #BABABA;text-decoration:underline #BABABA;-webkit-text-decoration-thickness:1px;text-decoration-thickness:1px;-webkit-text-decoration-skip-ink:none;text-decoration-skip-ink:none;text-underline-offset:0.25em;}.css-yidnqd-InlineLink:link:hover,.css-yidnqd-InlineLink:visited:hover,.css-yidnqd-InlineLink:link:focus,.css-yidnqd-InlineLink:visited:focus{-webkit-text-decoration-color:currentcolor;text-decoration-color:currentcolor;-webkit-text-decoration-thickness:2px;text-decoration-thickness:2px;color:#B80000;}}]]&gt;&lt;/style&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ec.europa.eu/commission/presscorner/detail/en/ip_20_2347&quot; class=&quot;css-yidnqd-InlineLink e1no5rhv0&quot;&gt;The measures are intended to overhaul&lt;/a&gt; how the EU regulates digital markets.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 18:05:33 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>adrian_mrd</dc:creator>
<og:description>Facebook, Google and others face yearly checks and limits on what they can do with users' data.</og:description>
<og:image>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/5648/production/_116088022_mediaitem116088021.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>EU reveals plan to regulate Big Tech</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-55318225</og:url>
<dc:language>en-GB</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-55318225</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Record Breaking Number of Journalists Arrested in the U.S. This Year</title>
<link>https://freedom.press/news/2020-report-journalists-arrested-us/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://freedom.press/news/2020-report-journalists-arrested-us/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Today, Freedom of the Press Foundation is releasing a report on the unprecedented number of journalists arrested in the United States this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the comprehensive data compiled by &lt;a href=&quot;https://pressfreedomtracker.us/&quot;&gt;the U.S. Press Freedom Tracker&lt;/a&gt;, a project of Freedom of the Press Foundation and Committee to Protect Journalists, our new report shows that there have been at least 117 verified cases of a journalist being arrested or detained on the job in the United States in 2020. The Tracker is also still investigating more than a dozen additional reports of arrests or detentions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The numbers are staggering. Arrests of journalists skyrocketed by more than 1200% in comparison to 2019. In just one week, from May 29 - June 4, more reporters were arrested in the U.S. than in the previous three years &lt;em&gt;combined&lt;/em&gt;. Arrests occurred in more than two dozen cities across the country. And more than 36% of the arrests were accompanied by an assault: journalists were beaten, hit with rubber bullets or other projectiles or covered in chemical agents, like tear gas or pepper spray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vast majority of these arrests occurred while journalists were documenting the historic, nationwide protests over the police killing of George Floyd and in support of Black Lives Matter.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 17:32:16 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>infodocket</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://freedom.press/news/2020-report-journalists-arrested-us/</og:url>
<og:title>New report: A record breaking number of journalists arrested in the U.S. this year</og:title>
<og:description>New report, &quot;U.S. Press Freedom in Crisis: Journalists Under Arrest in 2020,&quot; details how more than 117 journalists were arrested across the country in 2020.</og:description>
<og:image>https://freedom.press/media/images/image_12.original.png</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://freedom.press/news/2020-report-journalists-arrested-us/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Sponsoring Open Source Developers</title>
<link>https://cognitect.com/blog/2020/12/15/sponsoring-open-source-developers</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://cognitect.com/blog/2020/12/15/sponsoring-open-source-developers</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce today that Cognitect and &lt;a href=&quot;https://nubank.com.br&quot;&gt;Nubank&lt;/a&gt; will be &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/orgs/cognitect/sponsoring&quot;&gt;sponsoring&lt;/a&gt; dozens of contributors to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://clojure.org&quot;&gt;Clojure&lt;/a&gt; ecosystem with regular monthly support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open source is a critical part of the economy but it is an ecosystem still without a viable economic model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open source development feels like devs giving to devs, and that is the popular narrative. The reality is: most companies are taking economic advantage of the generous spirit of open source developers. That needs to stop. The value of programs, and thus of programming and people who pursue it as a profession, is eroding. Little of the vast wealth derived from open source flows intentionally and systematically to its creators. This is neither fair nor sustainable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open source licenses effectively preclude developers from charging for their work. Nevertheless, companies should pay for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine if every company using open source were to provide tangible sponsorship, on an ongoing basis, directly to the developers of the open source libraries and tools they use and rely upon. Sponsorship should be an expected and manageable cost of doing business and would have a tremendous impact on the nature of open source development and the lives of those who pursue it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With ongoing sponsorship, open source devs could move away from the gamification and RPG-like narratives around craft and guilds (rewarded with stars and likes) and actually be considered professional, independent craftspeople. People could work full-time pursuing their open source visions. Leaders of popular projects with large user bases and commensurate support demands could hire people to help them. Companies would be assured that these non-employees, who contribute critically to their business, are able to pay their bills, afford health care, educate their kids, buy houses and have a life, just as they do with their employees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/orgs/cognitect/sponsoring&quot;&gt;sponsorship&lt;/a&gt; represents a six-figure per year investment, and part of our attempt to walk this talk. We encourage other companies to join us in valuing and supporting the open source developers who contribute to our business success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rich, Stu and Justin&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 17:09:03 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>puredanger</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Sponsoring Open Source Developers</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.cognitect.com/blog/2020/12/15/sponsoring-open-source-developers</og:url>
<og:description></og:description>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://cognitect.com/blog/2020/12/15/sponsoring-open-source-developers</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Lonely people&amp;#039;s brains are different due to excess of imaginary social contact</title>
<link>https://www.psychnewsdaily.com/lonely-people-have-a-unique-brain-signature-perhaps-due-to-so-much-imagined-social-contact/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.psychnewsdaily.com/lonely-people-have-a-unique-brain-signature-perhaps-due-to-so-much-imagined-social-contact/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; href=&quot;https://dx.doi.org/10.1038/s41467-020-20039-w&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;new study of almost 40,000 adults&lt;/a&gt; has found that the brains of lonely people differ from those of people who are not lonely, in significant and detectable ways.&lt;span id=&quot;ezoic-pub-ad-placeholder-111&quot; class=&quot;ezoic-adpicker-ad&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ezoic-ad medrectangle-3 adtester-container adtester-container-111&quot; data-ez-name=&quot;psychnewsdaily_com-medrectangle-3&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;div-gpt-ad-psychnewsdaily_com-medrectangle-3-0&quot; ezaw=&quot;580&quot; ezah=&quot;400&quot; class=&quot;ezoic-ad ezoic-adl&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This loneliness “signature” consists of variations in the volume of different brain regions, and the way those brain regions communicate. And these variations may be related by the typical thinking patterns of lonely people, which include for example higher than average amounts of reminiscence and imaginary conversations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study compared the MRI scans of people who said they “often” feel lonely with the scans of people do not report feeling that way. The data comes from the &lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ukbiobank.ac.uk/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;UK Biobank&lt;/a&gt;, which is an open-source database with genetic and health information from about half a million people in the UK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 38,701 participants consisted of 47.5% men and 52.5% women. Their ages ranged from 40 – 69, with an average age of 55. About 13% of them answered “yes” to the question “Do you often feel lonely?” Of those who answered yes, about 39% were men, and 61% women.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new paper appeared today (December 15) in &lt;em&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/ncomms&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Nature Communications&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;span id=&quot;ezoic-pub-ad-placeholder-107&quot; class=&quot;ezoic-adpicker-ad&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ezoic-ad medrectangle-4 adtester-container adtester-container-107&quot; data-ez-name=&quot;psychnewsdaily_com-medrectangle-4&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;div-gpt-ad-psychnewsdaily_com-medrectangle-4-0&quot; ezaw=&quot;250&quot; ezah=&quot;250&quot; class=&quot;ezoic-ad ezoic-adl&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Lonely people and the default network&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers behind the study, from McGill University in Montreal, found that the key differences involved the brain’s “&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Default_mode_network&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;default network&lt;/a&gt;.” This network is responsible for a wide range of mental processes that take place when the brain is at rest. These processes are often referred to as the “inner voice”, or the “self.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The default network plays a crucial role in memory, social cognition (i.e. thinking about other people), and mental time travel (“What will I do tomorrow?”). It involves the medial prefrontal cortex, and the posterior cingulate cortex, along with a number of other structures. It is also responsible for hallucinations and internal imagery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers discovered, unexpectedly, that volumes in several of these default network regions were larger in lonely people. They also found equally unexpected patterns of positive associations between some of these regions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Feeling lonely: the typical thought patterns of lonely people&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The association between the default network and loneliness may be because of the way lonely people tend to think. Lonely people have been found, for example, to focus more on internal thoughts, perhaps to compensate for their lack of actual social experiences. Their thought patterns tend to include above-average levels of reminiscing and imaginned social exchanges. And this increase in thoughts about the self might well influence the relationship between the regions of the default network.&lt;span id=&quot;ezoic-pub-ad-placeholder-108&quot; class=&quot;ezoic-adpicker-ad&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ezoic-ad box-4 adtester-container adtester-container-108 ezoic-ad-adaptive&quot; data-ez-name=&quot;psychnewsdaily_com-box-4&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ezoic-ad box-4 adtester-container adtester-container-108&quot; data-ez-name=&quot;psychnewsdaily_com-box-4&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;div-gpt-ad-psychnewsdaily_com-box-4-0&quot; ezaw=&quot;290&quot; ezah=&quot;250&quot; class=&quot;ezoic-ad&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ezoic-ad box-4 adtester-container adtester-container-108&quot; data-ez-name=&quot;psychnewsdaily_com-box-4&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;div-gpt-ad-psychnewsdaily_com-box-4-0_1&quot; ezaw=&quot;290&quot; ezah=&quot;250&quot; class=&quot;ezoic-ad&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“In the absence of desired social experiences,” the authors write, “lonely individuals may be biased towards internally directed cognitions,” as if “to fill the social void.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In that sense, then, the physical effects of loneliness on the brain are not surprising. Paying “greater attention to one’s inner milieu, and a heightened focus on the self and self-reflective thoughts,” the authors write, “would naturally engage memory-based functions of the default network.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, past research has found that lonely people are more likely to engage in &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1037%2F0022-3514.85.3.409&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;imaginary social interactions&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1111%2Fj.1467-9280.2008.02194.x&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;nostalgic reminiscences&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1037%2F0033-295X.114.4.864&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;hypothetical conversations&lt;/a&gt;, and are also more likely to &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1111%2Fj.1467-9280.2008.02056.x&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;treat pets like people&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;So lonely: why studying loneliness matters&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researchers are increasingly recognizing loneliness as a major health problem. A recent study, for example, found that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.psychnewsdaily.com/loneliness-among-older-americans-doubled-during-pandemic-poll-shows/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;loneliness has more than doubled among older people&lt;/a&gt; since the Covid-19 pandemic began.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Past research has also shown older people who experience loneliness have a higher risk of cognitive decline and dementia. Lonely people get sick more often, and take longer to get over infections. Loneliness also increases blood pressure and levels of stress hormones. Socially isolated people are more likely to be depressed, suffer from memory loss, and use alcohol and drugs. Likewise, evidence suggests that loneliness contributes to ageing in a number of ways, and leads to reduced longevity. In fact, the health risks of loneliness are &lt;a href=&quot;https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/10.1177/1745691614568352&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;equivalent to those related to obesity or smoking 15 cigarettes a day&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding how loneliness works in the brain could one day help prevent neurological disease, and lead to better treatments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We speculate that the associations between the default network and loneliness revealed here,” the researcher write, “reflect increased demands on episodic mental simulation of inner social events in the absence of desired social experience in the external world.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator is-style-wide&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Study:&lt;/strong&gt; “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-020-20039-w&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;The default network of the human brain is associated with perceived social isolation&lt;/a&gt;“&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Nathan Spreng et al.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Published in:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/ncomms&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Nature Communications&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Publication date:&lt;/strong&gt; December 15, 2020&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DOI:&lt;/strong&gt; http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/s41467-020-20039-w&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Photo:&lt;/strong&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@anthonytran?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Anthony Tran&lt;/a&gt; via &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a weekly summary of the latest psychology news, subscribe to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.psychnewsdaily.com/the-psych-news-weekly-newsletter/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;Psych News Weekly newsletter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 16:32:11 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Bologo</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Lonely people have a unique brain signature, perhaps due to so much imagined social contact</og:title>
<og:description>PsychNewsDaily.com brings you the latest psychology news, from neuroscience and psychometrics to mental health and more.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.psychnewsdaily.com/lonely-people-have-a-unique-brain-signature-perhaps-due-to-so-much-imagined-social-contact/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.psychnewsdaily.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/lonely-people-brain-scan.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.psychnewsdaily.com/lonely-people-have-a-unique-brain-signature-perhaps-due-to-so-much-imagined-social-contact/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>AWS CloudShell</title>
<link>https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/aws-cloudshell-command-line-access-to-aws-resources/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/aws-cloudshell-command-line-access-to-aws-resources/</guid>
<description>&lt;table id=&quot;amazon-polly-audio-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td id=&quot;amazon-polly-audio-tab&quot;&gt;



&lt;div id=&quot;amazon-polly-by-tab&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/polly/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://a0.awsstatic.com/aws-blog/images/Voiced_by_Amazon_Polly_EN.png&quot; width=&quot;554&quot; height=&quot;56&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;No matter how much automation you have built, no matter how great you are at practicing &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Infrastructure_as_code&quot;&gt;Infrastructure as Code&lt;/a&gt; (IAC), and no matter how successfully you have transitioned from &lt;a href=&quot;http://cloudscaling.com/blog/cloud-computing/the-history-of-pets-vs-cattle/&quot;&gt;pets to cattle&lt;/a&gt;, you sometimes need to interact with your AWS resources at the command line. You might need to check or adjust a configuration file, make a quick fix to a production environment, or even experiment with some new AWS services or features.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some of our customers feel most at home when working from within a web browser and have yet to set up or customize their own command-line interface (CLI). They tell is that they don’t want to deal with client applications, public keys, AWS credentials, tooling, and so forth. While none of these steps are difficult or overly time-consuming, they do add complexity and friction and we always like to help you to avoid both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introducing &lt;span title=&quot;&quot;&gt;AWS CloudShell&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Today we are launching &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/cloudshell/&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;AWS CloudShell&lt;/a&gt;, with the goal of making the process of getting to an AWS-enabled shell prompt simple and secure, with as little friction as possible. Every shell environment that you run with &lt;span title=&quot;&quot;&gt;CloudShell&lt;/span&gt; has the &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/cli/&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;AWS Command Line Interface (CLI)&lt;/a&gt; (v2) installed and configured so you can run &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/cli/latest/reference/&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;aws&lt;/code&gt; commands&lt;/a&gt; fresh out of the box. The environments also include the Python and Node runtimes, with many more to come in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get started, I simply click the &lt;span title=&quot;&quot;&gt;CloudShell&lt;/span&gt; icon in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://console.aws.amazon.com&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;AWS Management Console&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2020/cs_icon_1.png&quot; width=&quot;489&quot; height=&quot;179&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My shell sets itself up in a matter of seconds and I can issue my first &lt;code&gt;aws&lt;/code&gt; command immediately:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2020/cs_open_3.png&quot; width=&quot;902&quot; height=&quot;587&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The shell environment is based on &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/amazon-linux-2/&quot;&gt;Amazon Linux 2&lt;/a&gt;. I can store up to 1 GB of files per region in my home directory and they’ll be available each time I open a shell in the region. This includes shell configuration files such as &lt;code&gt;.bashrc&lt;/code&gt; and shell history files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can access the shell via &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/singlesignon/latest/userguide/iam-auth-access.html&quot;&gt;SSO&lt;/a&gt; or as any IAM principal that can login to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://console.aws.amazon.com&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;AWS Management Console&lt;/a&gt;, including federated roles. In order to access &lt;span title=&quot;&quot;&gt;CloudShell&lt;/span&gt;, the &lt;strong&gt;AWSCloudShellFullAccess&lt;/strong&gt; policy must be in effect. The shell runs as a normal (non-privileged) user, but I can &lt;code&gt;sudo&lt;/code&gt; and install packages if necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are a couple of features that you should know about:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Themes &amp;amp; Font Sizes&lt;/strong&gt; – You can switch between light and dark color themes, and choose any one of five font sizes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2020/cs_config_3.png&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;718&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tabs and Sessions&lt;/strong&gt; – You can have multiple sessions open within the same region, and you can control the tabbing behavior, with options to split horizontally and vertically:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2020/cs_tabs_3.png&quot; width=&quot;428&quot; height=&quot;415&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also download files from the shell environment to your desktop, and upload them from your desktop to the shell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Things to Know&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Here are a couple of important things to keep in mind when you are evaluating &lt;span title=&quot;&quot;&gt;CloudShell&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Timeouts &amp;amp; Persistence&lt;/strong&gt; – Each &lt;span title=&quot;&quot;&gt;CloudShell&lt;/span&gt; session will timeout after 20 minutes or so of inactivity, and can be reestablished by refreshing the window:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2020/cs_refresh_1.png&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;309&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Regions&lt;/strong&gt; – &lt;span title=&quot;&quot;&gt;CloudShell&lt;/span&gt; is available today in the &lt;span title=&quot;&quot;&gt;US East (N. Virginia)&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span title=&quot;&quot;&gt;US East (Ohio)&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span title=&quot;&quot;&gt;US West (Oregon)&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Europe (Ireland)&lt;/span&gt;, and &lt;span title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Asia Pacific (Tokyo)&lt;/span&gt; Regions, with the remaining regions on the near-term roadmap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Persistent Storage –&lt;/strong&gt; Files stored within $HOME persist between invocations of &lt;span title=&quot;&quot;&gt;CloudShell&lt;/span&gt; with a limit of 1 GB per region; all other storage is ephemeral. This means that any software that is installed outside of $HOME will not persist, and that no matter what you change (or break), you can always begin anew with a fresh CloudShell environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Network Access&lt;/strong&gt; – Sessions can make outbound connections to the Internet, but do not allow any type of inbound connections. Sessions cannot currently connect to resources inside of private VPC subnets, but that’s also on the near-term roadmap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Runtimes&lt;/strong&gt; – In addition to the Python and Node runtimes, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/bash/&quot;&gt;Bash&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PowerShell&quot;&gt;PowerShell&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://stedolan.github.io/jq/&quot;&gt;jq&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cli/cli&quot;&gt;git&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/cli/latest/reference/ecs/index.html&quot;&gt;ECS CLI&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/serverless-application-model/latest/developerguide/serverless-sam-cli-command-reference.html&quot;&gt;SAM CLI&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Npm_(software)&quot;&gt;npm&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://pypi.org/project/pip/&quot;&gt;pip&lt;/a&gt; already installed and ready to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pricing&lt;/strong&gt; – You can use up to 10 concurrent shells in each region at no charge. You only pay for other AWS resources you use with CloudShell to create and run your applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Try it Out&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/cloudshell/&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;AWS CloudShell&lt;/a&gt; is available now and you can start using it today. Launch one and give it a try, and let us know what you think!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jeffbarr&quot;&gt;Jeff&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 16:30:19 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jeffbarr</dc:creator>
<og:title>AWS CloudShell – Command-Line Access to AWS Resources | Amazon Web Services</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/aws-cloudshell-command-line-access-to-aws-resources/</og:url>
<og:description>No matter how much automation you have built, no matter how great you are at practicing Infrastructure as Code (IAC), and no matter how successfully you have transitioned from pets to cattle, you sometimes need to interact with your AWS resources at the command line. You might need to check or adjust a configuration file, […]</og:description>
<og:image>https://d2908q01vomqb2.cloudfront.net/da4b9237bacccdf19c0760cab7aec4a8359010b0/2020/12/15/Site-Merch_AWS-Cloudshell_SocialMedia_2.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/aws-cloudshell-command-line-access-to-aws-resources/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>SuperRT – Realtime Raytracing on the SNES</title>
<link>https://www.shironekolabs.com/posts/superrt/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.shironekolabs.com/posts/superrt/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video links for this article:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’m pleased to finally have some results to show for a project I’ve been working on in my spare time for the last year or so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea originated when I was trying to think of an interesting idea for a project to help me learn Verilog and FPGA design, and the notion of building a simple raytracer came to mind (partly inspired by a scarily smart friend of mine who is building his own GPU). A bit later - because sometimes my brain hates me and delights in coming up with silly things to do - this turned into “wouldn’t it be interesting to try making a SNES do raytracing?”, and thus the SuperRT chip idea was born.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I wanted to try and do was something akin to the Super FX chip used in titles such as Star Fox, where the SNES runs the game logic and hands off a scene description to a chip in the cartridge to generate the visuals. To that end I’ve deliberately tried to restrict myself to just using a single custom chip for the design, not making use of the ARM core available on the DE10 board or any other external processing resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The end results look something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SuperRT scene example video&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apologies for the poor screenshot quality, incidentally - for some reason my capture card produces terrible results when capturing from my SNES, so I had to resort to the good old “photograph the screen in a darkened room” approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.shironekolabs.com/posts/superrt/Hardware.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;SuperRT development hardware&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Super Nintendo (technically a Super Famicom) seen here has had the case removed to make room for the cabling, but other than that is totally unmodified. Attached to it is the PCB from a copy of an &lt;em&gt;awful&lt;/em&gt; Pachinko game I picked up for 100 yen at a local second-hand store, with the game ROM removed and replaced with a cable breakout. This then passes through a set of level shifters to convert the SNES’s 5v down to 3.3v and then into a DE10-Nano FPGA development board with a Cyclone V FPGA. The level shifter boards are anything but pretty - and assembling them was a nightmare thanks to the necessary ICs only being available in surface-mount packages - but they do the job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.shironekolabs.com/posts/superrt/Slide3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hardware layout diagram&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SuperRT chip constructs the scene using a specialised command language which is executed by one of three parallel execution units on the chip - essentially specialised CISC processors - to perform ray intersection tests. The scene description allows objects to be constructed using a subset of CSG operations, using spheres and planes as the basic building blocks and then performing OR, AND and subtraction operations using them to build up the desired geometry. AABBs are also supported, although primarily for use in culling tests (they can be rendered if desired, but they have a lower positional accuracy than other primitives and thus this is not generally very useful except for debugging purposes).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SuperRT scene example video&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The renderer casts up to four rays per screen pixel, calculating direct shadows from a directional light source and a single reflection bounce. Surfaces each have a diffuse colour and reflectivity property, and it’s possible to apply modifiers to these based on CSG results or specialised functions - this is used to generate the checkerboard pattern on the floor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.shironekolabs.com/posts/superrt/Slide2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;SuperRT screenshot&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ray colour for each pixel is calculated by a “ray engine”, which handles the overall ray lifecycle and uses an “execution engine” module to run the command program describing the scene as many times as is required to resolve the ray. The command program itself is uploaded from the SNES and stored in a local 4K RAM buffer - animation is performed by writing modified commands into this buffer as required. A disassembled command buffer looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;0000 Start
0001 Plane 0, -1, 0, Dist=-2
0002 SphereSub OH 2, 1, 5, Rad=5
0003 SphereSub OH 4, 1, 4, Rad=4
0004 SphereSub OH 5, 1, 9, Rad=9
0005 SphereSub OH 2, 1, 2, Rad=2
0006 SphereSub OH -0.5, 1, 2, Rad=2
0007 RegisterHitNoReset 0, 248, 0, Reflectiveness=0
0008 Checkerboard ORH 48, 152, 48, Reflectiveness=0
0009 ResetHitState
0010 Plane 0, -1, 0, Dist=-2.150146
0011 RegisterHit 0, 0, 248, Reflectiveness=153
0012 AABB 4, -2.5, 11,    8, 3.5, 13
0013 ResetHitStateAndJump NH 44
0014 Origin 6, 2, 12
0015 Plane -0.2929688, 0, -0.9570313, Dist=0.2497559
0016 PlaneAnd OH 0.2919922, 0, 0.9560547, Dist=0.25
0017 PlaneAnd OH 0, 1, 0, Dist=1
0018 PlaneAnd OH 0, -1, 0, Dist=4
0019 PlaneAnd OH -0.9570313, 0, 0.2919922, Dist=-1
0020 PlaneAnd OH 0.9560547, 0, -0.2929688, Dist=1.499756
0021 RegisterHit 248, 0, 0, Reflectiveness=0
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each execution engine is a processor module with a 14 cycle pipeline, and in general one instruction is retired per cycle, so each execution unit can calculate about 50 million sphere, plane or AABB intersections per second. The exception to this is that branch operations have to flush the entire pipeline and thus have a 16 cycle overhead (14 cycles to flush the pipeline + 2 cycles instruction fetch delay). To try and avoid this as much as possible a branch prediction system is used - fortunately a lot of the time the spatial coherency of nearby rays means that a high prediction hit rate is achievable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.shironekolabs.com/posts/superrt/Slide5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;SuperRT screenshot&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intersections in the execution engine are carried out by two pipelines, one handling AABBs and the other spheres and planes. The system as a whole works exclusively using 32-bit integer maths in 18.14 fixed point format, with 16-bit (2.14) format used where values are known to be in the +-1 range, and the sphere/plane intersection pipeline has two dedicated additional maths units that calculate reciprocal and square root operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SuperRT scene example video&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once a frame is rendered, the PPU converter module turns the framebuffer into a format that can be DMAed directly to the SNES VRAM for display, reducing it to 256 colours and swizzling it into character tile bitplanes. The screen resolution is 200x160 - this results in exactly 32000 bytes of image data for a full frame, which is transferred to VRAM in two 16000 bytes chunks over successive frames due to bandwidth constraints. Thus the full image can only be refreshed once every two frames, effectively limiting the maximum framerate to 30FPS - although the test scene runs at closer to 20FPS (primarily due to some bottlenecks with the logic on the SNES side at present).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5.5849056603774&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many thanks to the participants in &lt;a href=&quot;https://forums.nesdev.com/viewtopic.php?f=12&amp;amp;t=20068&quot;&gt;this thread&lt;/a&gt; over at SNESdev for a lot of useful ideas on fullscreen expansion chip DMA that inspired the solution used here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.shironekolabs.com/posts/superrt/Slide4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;SuperRT screenshot&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chip also implements a number of other basic functions - there is an interface to the SNES cartridge bus, along with a small program ROM holding 32K of code for the SNES (this is constrained by the fact that the interface board currently only connects up the SNES Address Bus A lines, and thus the effective usable address space is a mere 64K, of which 32K is used for memory-mapped IO registers to communicate with the SuperRT chip). There is also a multiplication accelerator unit that lets the SNES perform 16x16bit multiply operations rapidly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.shironekolabs.com/posts/superrt/Shot13.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;SuperRT screenshot&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For debugging, I used the HDMI interface on the DE10 board to output data to a second monitor, along with a Megadrive joypad connected to the GPIO pins to manipulate the debug system. Resource constraints mean that this has to be disabled if all three ray engine cores are enabled, however.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that’s a broad overview of the system - I intend to post some articles giving more details of how individual components work in the near future. In the meantime, though, if you have any questions or thoughts then please get in touch and I’ll do my best to answer!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many thanks to Matt, Jaymin, Rick and everyone else who has helped with advice, inspiration and support!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SuperRT scene example video&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“SNES” and “Super Nintendo” are trademarks of Nintendo Co Ltd. This is a hobby project and completely unassociated with Nintendo.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 15:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mkeeter</dc:creator>
<og:title>SuperRT</og:title>
<og:description>Video links for this article: Short trailer Walkthrough and technical details I’m pleased to finally have some results to show for a project I’ve been working on in my spare time for the last year or so. The idea originated when I was trying to think of an interesting idea for a project to help me learn Verilog and FPGA design, and the notion of building a simple raytracer came to mind (partly inspired by a scarily smart friend of mine who is building his own GPU).</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.shironekolabs.com/posts/superrt/</og:url>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.shironekolabs.com/posts/superrt/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Firefox 84.0</title>
<link>https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/84.0/releasenotes/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/84.0/releasenotes/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;We'd like to extend a special thank you to all of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/community/2020/12/15/the-new-faces-in-firefox-84/&quot;&gt;new Mozillians&lt;/a&gt; who contributed to this release of Firefox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2020 was a year like no other. By March, the world dramatically changed. Despite that, we kept our schedule to release a new Firefox every month to keep Firefox working for you. While we eagerly look to the end of 2020, we thought to take stock of this unprecedented year. Along with all that is new with this release, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/blog/2020/12/15/our-year-in-review-how-weve-kept-firefox-working-for-you-in-2020/&quot;&gt;see our list of top features that made 2020 a little easier&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 15:01:35 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>easton</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/84.0/releasenotes/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.mozilla.org/media/protocol/img/logos/firefox/browser/og.4ad05d4125a5.png</og:image>
<og:title>Firefox 84.0, See All New Features, Updates and Fixes</og:title>
<og:description></og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/84.0/releasenotes/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Welcome Yari: MDN Web Docs has a new platform</title>
<link>https://hacks.mozilla.org/2020/12/welcome-yari-mdn-web-docs-has-a-new-platform/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://hacks.mozilla.org/2020/12/welcome-yari-mdn-web-docs-has-a-new-platform/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;After several intense months of work on such a significant change, the day is finally upon us: &lt;a href=&quot;https://hacks.mozilla.org/2020/10/mdn-web-docs-evolves-lowdown-on-the-upcoming-new-platform/&quot;&gt;MDN Web Docs’ new platform&lt;/a&gt; (codenamed &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yari&quot;&gt;Yari&lt;/a&gt;) is finally launched!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-46853&quot; src=&quot;https://2r4s9p1yi1fa2jd7j43zph8r-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/files/2020/12/yari.png&quot; alt=&quot;icon for yari, includes a man with a spear, plus the text yari, the mdn web docs platform&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; srcset=&quot;https://hacks.mozilla.org/files/2020/12/yari.png 600w, https://hacks.mozilla.org/files/2020/12/yari-250x250.png 250w, https://hacks.mozilla.org/files/2020/12/yari-500x500.png 500w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Between November 2 and December 14, we ran a beta period in which a number of our fabulous community members tested out the new platform, submitted content changes, allowed us to try out the new contribution workflow, and suggested improvements to both the platform and styling. All of you have our heartfelt thanks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post serves to provide an update on where we are now, what we’re aiming to do next, and what you can do to help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Where we are now&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve pulled together a working system in a short amount of time that vastly improves on the previous platform, and solves a number of tangible issues. There is certainly a lot of work still to do, but this new release provides a stable base to iterate from, and you’ll see a lot of further improvements in the coming months. Here’s a peek at where we are now:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Contributing in GitHub&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most significant difference with the new platform is that we’ve decentralized the content from a SQL database to files in a git repository. To edit content, you now submit pull requests against the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mdn/content&quot;&gt;https://github.com/mdn/content&lt;/a&gt; repo, rather than editing the wiki using the old WYSIWYG editor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has a huge advantage in terms of contribution workflow — because it’s a GitHub repo, you can insert it into your workflow however you feel comfortable, mass changes are easier to make programmatically, and you can lump together edits across multiple pages in a single pull request rather than as scattered individual edits, and we can apply intelligent automatic linting to edits to speed up work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The content repo initially comes with a few basic CLI tools to help you with fundamental tasks, such as &lt;code&gt;yarn start&lt;/code&gt; (to create a live preview of what your document will look like when rendered on MDN), &lt;code&gt;yarn content create&lt;/code&gt; (to add a new page), &lt;code&gt;yarn content move&lt;/code&gt; (to move an existing page), etc. You can find more details of these, and other contribution instructions, in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mdn/content/blob/main/README.md&quot;&gt;repo’s README file&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Caring for the community&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Community interactions will not just be improved, but transformed. You can now have a conversation about a change over a pull request before it is finalized and submitted, making suggestions and iterating, rather than worrying about getting it perfect the first time round.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We think that this model will give contributors more confidence in making changes, and allow us to build a much better relationship with our community and help them improve their contributions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Reducing developer burden&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our developer maintenance burden is also now much reduced with this update. The existing (Kuma) platform is complex,  hard to maintain, and adding new features is very difficult. The update will vastly simplify the platform code — we estimate that we can remove a significant chunk of the existing codebase, meaning easier maintenance and contributions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is also true of our front-end architecture: The existing MDN platform has a number of front-end inconsistencies and accessibility issues, which we’ve wanted to tackle for some time. The move to a new, simplified platform gives us a perfect opportunity to fix such issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What we’re doing next&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a number of things that we could do to further improve the new platform going forward. Last week, for example, we already talked about our &lt;a href=&quot;https://hacks.mozilla.org/2020/12/an-update-on-mdn-web-docs-localization-strategy/&quot;&gt;plans for the future of l10n on MDN&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing we’ll be working on in the new year is ironing out the kinks in the new platform. After that, we can start to serve our readers and contributors much better than before, implementing new features faster and more confidently, which will lead to an even more useful MDN, with an even more powerful contribution model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sections below are by no means definite, but they do provide a useful idea of what we’ve got planned next for the platform. We are aiming to publish a public roadmap in the future, so that you can find out where we’re at, and make suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Moving to Markdown&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At its launch, the content is stored in HTML format. This is OK — we all know a little HTML — but it is not the most convenient format to edit and write, especially if you are creating a sizable new page from scratch. Most people find Markdown easier to write than HTML, so we want to eventually move to storing our core content in Markdown (or maybe some other format) rather than HTML.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Improving search&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a long time, the search functionality has been substandard on MDN. Going forward, we not only want to upgrade our search to return useful results, but we also want to search more usefully, for example fuzzy search, search by popularity search by titles, summaries, full text search, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Representing MDN meta pages&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently only the MDN content pages are represented in our new content repo. We’d eventually like to stop using our old home, profile, and search pages, which are still currently served from our old Django-based platform, and bring those into the new platform with all the advantages that it brings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;And there’s more!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’d also like to start exploring:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Optimizing file attachments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implementing and enforcing CSP on MDN&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automated linting and formatting of all code snippets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gradually removing the old-style KumaScript macros that remain in MDN content, removing, rendering, or replacing them as appropriate. For example, link macros can just be rendered out, as standard HTML links will work fine, whereas all the sidebar macros we have should be replaced by a proper sidebar system built into the actual platform.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;What you can do to help&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you’ll have seen from the above next steps, there is still a lot to do, and we’d love the community to help us with future MDN content and platform work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;If you are more interested in helping with content work, you can find out how to help at &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/MDN/Contribute&quot;&gt;Contributing to MDN&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you are more interested in helping with MDN platform development, the best place to learn where to start is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mdn/yari/blob/master/README.md&quot;&gt;Yari README&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In terms of finding a good general place to chat about MDN, you can join the discussion on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://chat.mozilla.org/#/room/#mdn:mozilla.org&quot;&gt;MDN Web Docs chat room&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.mozilla.org/Matrix&quot;&gt;Matrix&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;about&quot; readability=&quot;14.944680851064&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris Mills is a senior tech writer at Mozilla, where he writes docs and demos about open web apps, HTML/CSS/JavaScript, A11y, WebAssembly, and more. He loves tinkering around with web technologies, and gives occasional tech talks at conferences and universities. He used to work for Opera and W3C, and enjoys playing heavy metal drums and drinking good beer. He lives near Manchester, UK, with his good lady and three beautiful children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;url&quot; href=&quot;https://hacks.mozilla.org/author/cmillsmozilla-com/&quot;&gt;More articles by Chris Mills…&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 12:09:42 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Garbage</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://hacks.mozilla.org/2020/12/welcome-yari-mdn-web-docs-has-a-new-platform</og:url>
<og:title>Welcome Yari: MDN Web Docs has a new platform – Mozilla Hacks - the Web developer blog</og:title>
<og:description>After several intense months of work on such a significant change, the MDN Web Docs’ new platform (codenamed Yari) is finally launched!</og:description>
<og:image>https://hacks.mozilla.org/files/2020/12/yari.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://hacks.mozilla.org/2020/12/welcome-yari-mdn-web-docs-has-a-new-platform/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>