<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>The Roots of Boeing’s 737 Max Crisis: A Regulator Relaxes Its Oversight</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/07/27/business/boeing-737-max-faa.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2019/07/27/business/boeing-737-max-faa.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;SEATTLE — In the days after the first crash of Boeing’s 737 Max, engineers at the Federal Aviation Administration came to a troubling realization: They didn’t fully understand the automated system that helped send the plane into a nose-dive, killing everyone on board.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Engineers at the agency scoured their files for information about the system designed to help avoid stalls. They didn’t find much. Regulators had never independently assessed the risks of the dangerous software known as MCAS when they approved the plane in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;More than a dozen current and former employees at the F.A.A. and Boeing who spoke with The New York Times described a broken regulatory process that effectively neutered the oversight authority of the agency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The regulator had been &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/03/26/us/politics/boeing-faa.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;passing off routine tasks&lt;/a&gt; to manufacturers for years, with the goal of freeing up specialists to focus on the most important safety concerns. But on the Max, the regulator handed nearly complete control to Boeing, leaving some key agency officials in the dark about &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/04/11/business/boeing-faa-mcas.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;important systems like MCAS&lt;/a&gt;, according to the current and former employees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;While the agency’s flawed oversight of the Boeing 737 Max has attracted much scrutiny since the first crash in October and a second one in March, a Times investigation revealed previously unreported details about weaknesses in the regulatory process that compromised the safety of the plane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The company performed its own assessments of the system, which were not stress-tested by the regulator. Turnover at the agency left two relatively inexperienced engineers overseeing Boeing’s early work on the system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The F.A.A. eventually handed over responsibility for approval of MCAS to the manufacturer. After that, Boeing didn’t have to share the details of the system with the two agency engineers. They weren’t aware of &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/02/03/world/asia/lion-air-plane-crash-pilots.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;its intricacies,&lt;/a&gt; according to two people with knowledge of the matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Late in the development of the Max, Boeing decided to expand the use of MCAS, to ensure the plane flew smoothly. The &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/06/01/business/boeing-737-max-crash.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;new, riskier version&lt;/a&gt; relied on a single sensor and could push down the nose of the plane by a much larger amount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Boeing did not submit a formal review of MCAS after the overhaul. It wasn’t required by F.A.A. rules. An engineering test pilot at the regulator knew about the changes, according to an agency official. But his job was to evaluate the way the plane flew, not to determine the safety of the system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The agency ultimately certified the jet as safe, required little training for pilots and allowed the plane to keep flying until a second deadly Max crash, less than five months after the first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The plane remains grounded as regulators await a fix from Boeing. If the ban persists much longer, Boeing said this past week that it &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/07/24/business/boeing-earnings-737-max.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;could be forced to halt production&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The F.A.A. and Boeing have defended the plane’s certification, saying they followed proper procedures and adhered to the highest standards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“The agency’s certification processes are well-established and have consistently produced safe aircraft designs,” the regulator said in a statement Friday. “The 737 Max certification program involved 110,000 hours of work on the part of F.A.A. personnel, including flying or supporting 297 test flights.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Boeing said “the F.A.A.’s rigor and regulatory leadership has driven ever-increasing levels of safety over the decades,” adding that “the 737 Max met the F.A.A.’s stringent standards and requirements as it was certified through the F.A.A.’s processes.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;[If you have worked at Boeing or the F.A.A. and want to discuss your experience,&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/tips?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;contact The Times confidentially here&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;.]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-79elbk&quot; data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-wrapper&quot;&gt;

&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-children&quot; class=&quot;css-1a48zt4 ehw59r15&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1xdhyk6 erfvjey0&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;While Ali Bahrami was the Federal Aviation Administration&amp;amp;rsquo;s top official in Seattle, some engineers believed that he had installed managers who would be deferential to Boeing.&quot; class=&quot;css-1m50asq&quot; src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/07/28/business/28boeing3/merlin_152643222_fdb4e1c8-150f-4d36-863b-94c35dfff0bd-articleLarge.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;disable=upscale&quot; srcset=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/07/28/business/28boeing3/merlin_152643222_fdb4e1c8-150f-4d36-863b-94c35dfff0bd-articleLarge.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 600w,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/07/28/business/28boeing3/merlin_152643222_fdb4e1c8-150f-4d36-863b-94c35dfff0bd-jumbo.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 1024w,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/07/28/business/28boeing3/merlin_152643222_fdb4e1c8-150f-4d36-863b-94c35dfff0bd-superJumbo.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 2048w&quot; sizes=&quot;((min-width: 600px) and (max-width: 1004px)) 84vw, (min-width: 1005px) 60vw, 100vw&quot; itemprop=&quot;url&quot; itemid=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/07/28/business/28boeing3/merlin_152643222_fdb4e1c8-150f-4d36-863b-94c35dfff0bd-articleLarge.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;disable=upscale&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;While Ali Bahrami was the Federal Aviation Administration’s top official in Seattle, some engineers believed that he had installed managers who would be deferential to Boeing.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e1z0qqy90&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Jonathan Ernst/Bloomberg&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Federal prosecutors and lawmakers are now investigating whether the regulatory process is fundamentally flawed. As planes become more technologically advanced, the rules, even when they are followed, may not be enough to ensure safety. The new software played a role in both disasters, involving &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/10/travel/what-you-need-to-know-about-boeings-737-max.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Lion Air and Ethiopian Airlines&lt;/a&gt;, which together killed 346 people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“Did MCAS get the attention it needed? That’s one of the things we’re looking at,” said Chris Hart, the former chairman of the National Transportation Safety Board, who is now leading a multiagency task force investigating how the Max was approved. “As it evolved from a less robust system to a more powerful system, were the certifiers aware of the changes?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Boeing needed the approval process on the Max to go swiftly. Months behind &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/03/23/business/boeing-737-max-crash.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;its rival Airbus&lt;/a&gt;, the company was racing to finish the plane, a more fuel-efficient version of its best-selling 737.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The regulator’s hands-off approach was pivotal. At crucial moments in the Max’s development, the agency operated in the background, mainly monitoring Boeing’s progress and checking paperwork. The nation’s largest aerospace manufacturer, Boeing was treated as a client, with F.A.A. officials making decisions based on the company’s deadlines and budget.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;It has long been a cozy relationship. Top agency officials have shuffled between the government and the industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;During the Max certification, senior leaders at the F.A.A. sometimes overruled their own staff members’ recommendations after Boeing pushed back. For safety reasons, many agency engineers wanted Boeing to redesign a pair of cables, part of a major system unrelated to MCAS. The company resisted, and F.A.A. managers took Boeing’s side, according to internal agency documents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;After the &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/27/world/asia/indonesia-lion-air-crash-.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;crash of the Lion Air&lt;/a&gt; plane last October, F.A.A. engineers were shocked to discover they didn’t have a complete analysis of MCAS. The safety review in their files didn’t mention that the system could aggressively push down the nose of the plane and trigger repeatedly, making it difficult to regain control of the aircraft, as it did on the doomed Lion Air flight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Despite their hazy understanding of the system, F.A.A. officials decided against grounding the 737 Max. Instead, they &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://rgl.faa.gov/Regulatory_and_Guidance_Library/rgad.nsf/0/83ec7f95f3e5bfbd8625833e0070a070/$FILE/2018-23-51_Emergency.pdf&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;published a notice&lt;/a&gt; reminding pilots of existing emergency procedures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The notice didn’t describe how MCAS worked. At the last minute, an F.A.A. manager told agency engineers to remove the only mention of the system, according to internal agency documents and two people with knowledge of the matter. Instead, airlines learned about it from Boeing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;css-ani50b eoo0vm40&quot; id=&quot;link-3c707497&quot;&gt;‘He really wanted abdication.’&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The F.A.A. department that oversaw the Max development had such a singular focus that it was named after the company: The Boeing Aviation Safety Oversight Office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Many F.A.A. veterans came to see the department, created in 2009, as a symbol of the agency’s close relationship with the manufacturer. The top official in Seattle at the time, Ali Bahrami, had a tough time persuading employees to join, according to three current and former employees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Some engineers believed that Mr. Bahrami had installed managers in the office who would defer to Boeing. “He didn’t put enough checks and balances in the system,” Mike McRae, a former F.A.A. engineer, said of Mr. Bahrami. “He really wanted abdication. He didn’t want delegation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Before the certification of the Max began, Mr. Bahrami called a group of F.A.A. engineers into his office, the current and former employees said, and asked some of them to join the group. Many didn’t want to change jobs, according to a complaint filed by the National Air Traffic Controllers Association, the union representing F.A.A. engineers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“I got dragged kicking and screaming,” said Richard Reed, a former systems engineer at the F.A.A. Mr. Reed said he had just left surgery when agency officials called to ask whether he would work in the office. “I always claimed that I was on drugs when I said ‘yes.’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The F.A.A. said in a statement that Mr. Bahrami “dedicated his career to the advancement of aviation safety in both the private and public sectors.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-79elbk&quot; data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-wrapper&quot;&gt;

&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-children&quot; class=&quot;css-1a48zt4 ehw59r15&quot;&gt;

&lt;span aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;F.A.A. offices in Des Moines, Wash. The way the agency dealt with Boeing left engineers at the agency demoralized, two employees said.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e1z0qqy90&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Ruth Fremson/The New York Times&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;For decades, the F.A.A. relied on engineers inside Boeing to help certify aircraft. But after intense lobbying to Congress by industry, the agency adopted rules in 2005 that would give manufacturers like Boeing even more control. Previously, the agency selected the company engineers to work on its behalf; under the new regulations, Boeing could choose them, though the F.A.A. has veto power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Many of the agency’s top leaders embraced the approach. It would allow the F.A.A. to certify planes more efficiently and stretch its limited resources. The regulator had also been finding it harder to compete for talented engineers, their government salaries unable to keep up with the going rates in the industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;For Boeing, the changes meant shedding a layer of bureaucracy. “The process was working well,” said Tom Heineman, a retired Boeing engineer who worked on the Max. “The F.A.A. was delegating more of the work and the review and the oversight to the manufacturers than it used to.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;But some F.A.A. engineers were concerned that they were no longer able to effectively monitor what was happening inside Boeing. In a PowerPoint presentation to agency managers in 2016, union representatives raised concerns about a “brain drain” and the “inability to hire and retain qualified personnel.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;By 2018, the F.A.A. was letting the company certify 96 percent of its own work, according to an agency official.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Nicole Potter, an F.A.A. propulsion and fuel systems engineer who worked on the Max, said supervisors repeatedly asked her to give up the right to approve safety documents. She often had to fight to keep the work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“Leadership was targeting a high level of delegation,” Ms. Potter said. When F.A.A. employees didn’t have time to approve a critical document, she said, “managers could delegate it back to Boeing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;It was a process Mr. Bahrami championed to lawmakers. After spending more than two decades at the F.A.A., he left the agency in 2013 and took a job at the Aerospace Industries Association, a trade group that represents Boeing and other manufacturers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“We urge the F.A.A. to allow maximum use of delegation,” Mr. Bahrami told Congress in his new lobbying role, arguing it would help American manufacturers compete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In 2017, Mr. Bahrami returned to the F.A.A. as the head of safety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;css-ani50b eoo0vm40&quot; id=&quot;link-629d5275&quot;&gt;An internal battle at the F.A.A.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;With Boeing taking more control, F.A.A. engineers found they had little power, even when they did raise concerns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Early on, engineers at the F.A.A. discovered a problem with one of the most important new features of the Max: its engines. The Max, &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/04/08/business/boeing-737-max-.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;the latest version of the 50-year-old 737,&lt;/a&gt; featured more fuel-efficient engines, with a larger fan and a high-pressure turbine. But the bigger, more complex engines could do more damage if they broke apart midair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The F.A.A. engineers were particularly concerned about pieces hitting the cables that control the rudder, according to five people with knowledge of the matter and internal agency documents. A cable severed during takeoff would make it difficult for pilots to regain control, potentially bringing down the jet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The F.A.A. engineers suggested a couple solutions, three of the people said. The company could add a second set of cables or install a computerized system for controlling the rudder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Boeing did not want to make a change, according to internal F.A.A. documents reviewed by The Times. A redesign could have caused delays. Company engineers argued that it was unlikely that an engine would break apart and shrapnel would hit the rudder cable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Most of the F.A.A. engineers working on the issue insisted the change was necessary for safety reasons, according to internal agency emails and documents. But their supervisors balked. In a July 2015 meeting, Jeff Duven, who replaced Mr. Bahrami as the head of the F.A.A.’s Seattle operation, sided with Boeing, said two current employees at the agency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-79elbk&quot; data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-wrapper&quot;&gt;

&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-children&quot; class=&quot;css-1a48zt4 ehw59r15&quot;&gt;

&lt;span aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;Boeing Max planes in Renton, Wash. The company downplayed the risks of the software, MCAS, to federal officials.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e1z0qqy90&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Ruth Fremson/The New York Times&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;F.A.A. managers conceded that the Max “does not meet” agency guidelines “for protecting flight controls,” according to an agency document. But in another document, they added that they had to consider whether any requested changes would interfere with Boeing’s timeline. The managers wrote that it would be “impractical at this late point in the program,” for the company to resolve the issue. Mr. Duven at the F.A.A. also said the decision was based on the safety record of the plane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Engineers at the agency were demoralized, the two agency employees said. One engineer submitted an anonymous complaint to an internal F.A.A. safety board, which was reviewed by The Times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“During meetings regarding this issue the cost to Boeing to upgrade the design was discussed,” the engineer wrote. “The comment was made that there may be better places for Boeing to spend their safety dollars.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;An F.A.A. panel investigated the complaint. It found managers siding with Boeing had created “an environment of mistrust that hampers the ability of the agency to work effectively,” the panel said in a 2017 report, which was reviewed by The Times. The panel cautioned against allowing Boeing to handle this kind of approval, saying “the company has a vested interest in minimizing costs and schedule impact.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;By then, the panel’s findings were moot. Managers at the agency had already given Boeing the right to approve the cables, and they were installed on the Max.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;css-ani50b eoo0vm40&quot; id=&quot;link-c392ddc&quot;&gt;Playing down risks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In the middle of the Max’s development, two of the most seasoned engineers in the F.A.A.’s Boeing office left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The engineers, who had a combined 50 years of experience, had joined the office at its creation, taking on responsibility for flight control systems, including MCAS. But they both grew frustrated with the work, which they saw as mostly paper pushing, according to two people with knowledge of the staff changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In their place, the F.A.A. appointed an engineer who had little experience in flight controls, and a new hire who had gotten his master’s degree three years earlier. People who worked with the two engineers said they seemed ill-equipped to identify any problems in a complex system like MCAS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;And Boeing played down the importance of MCAS from the outset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;An early review by the company didn’t consider the system risky, and it didn’t prompt additional scrutiny from the F.A.A. engineers, according to two agency officials. The review described a system that would activate only in rare situations, when a plane was making a sharp turn at high speeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The F.A.A. engineers who had been overseeing MCAS never received another safety assessment. As Boeing raced to finish the Max in 2016, agency managers gave the company the power to approve a batch of safety assessments — some of the most important documents in any certification. They believed the issues were low risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;One of the managers, Julie Alger, delegated the review of MCAS. Previously, the F.A.A. had the final say over the system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The F.A.A. said that decision reflected the consensus of the team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Boeing was in the middle of overhauling MCAS. To help pilots control the plane and avoid a stall, the company allowed MCAS to trigger at low speeds, rather than just at high speeds. The overhauled version would move the stabilizer by as much as 2.5 degrees each time it triggered, significantly pushing down the nose of the plane. The earlier version moved the stabilizer by 0.6 degrees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;When company engineers analyzed the change, they figured that the system had not become any riskier, according to two people familiar with Boeing’s discussions on the matter. They assumed that pilots would respond to a malfunction in three seconds, quickly bringing the nose of the plane back up. In their view, any problems would be less dangerous at low speeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;So the company never submitted an updated safety assessment of those changes to the agency. In several briefings in 2016, an F.A.A. test pilot learned the details of the system from Boeing. But the two F.A.A. engineers didn’t understand that MCAS could move the tail as much as 2.5 degrees, according to two people familiar with their thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Under the impression the system was insignificant, officials didn’t require Boeing to tell pilots about MCAS. When the company asked to remove mention of MCAS from the pilot’s manual, the agency agreed. The F.A.A. also did not mention the software in 30 pages of detailed descriptions noting differences between the Max and the previous iteration of the 737.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Days after the Lion Air crash, the agency invited Boeing executives to the F.A.A.’s Seattle headquarters, according to two people with knowledge of the matter. The officials sat incredulous as Boeing executives explained details about the system that they didn’t know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In the middle of the conversation, an F.A.A. employee, one of the people said, interrupted to ask a question on the minds of several agency engineers: Why hadn’t Boeing updated the safety analysis of a system that had become so dangerous?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2019 16:53:59 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tafda</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/07/27/business/boeing-737-max-faa.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>The Roots of Boeing’s 737 Max Crisis: A Regulator Relaxes Its Oversight</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/07/25/business/00boeing1-copy/00boeing1-copy-facebookJumbo-v2.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>A Times investigation found that the F.A.A. regulatory process, which gave Boeing significant oversight authority, compromised the safety of the plane.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/07/27/business/boeing-737-max-faa.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Adblocking: How about Nah?</title>
<link>https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2019/07/adblocking-how-about-nah</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2019/07/adblocking-how-about-nah</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;For more than a decade, consumer rights groups (including EFF) worked with technologists and companies to try to standardize &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2015/08/clear-rules-road-do-not-track-policy-0&quot;&gt;Do Not Track&lt;/a&gt;, a flag that browsers could send to online companies signaling that their users did not want their browsing activity tracked. Despite long hours and backing from the FTC, foot-dragging from the browser vendors and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/issues/do-not-track&quot;&gt;outright hostility from the big online media companies&lt;/a&gt; mean that &lt;a href=&quot;https://gizmodo.com/do-not-track-the-privacy-tool-used-by-millions-of-peop-1828868324&quot;&gt;setting Do Not Track in your browser does virtually nothing to protect your privacy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do Not Track grew out of widespread public concern over invasive &quot;behavioral advertising&quot; that relied on tracking to target ads; despite a generation of promises from the ad industry that consumers would welcome more relevant advertising, the consistent result has been that users are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pewresearch.org/fact-tank/2012/03/13/internet-users-dont-like-targeted-ads/&quot;&gt;freaked out by &quot;relevant&quot; ads&lt;/a&gt; because they understand that relevancy is synonymous with privacy invasion. Nothing is so creepy as ads for a product you looked into earlier following you from site to site, then from app to app, as you are tracked and retargeted by a desperate vendor's algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Internet users didn't take this situation lying down. They wanted to use the Web, but not be tracked, and so they started to install ad-blockers. &lt;a href=&quot;https://deloitte.wsj.com/cmo/2018/04/03/are-consumers-adlergic-a-look-at-ad-blocking-habits/&quot;&gt;A &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of ad-blockers&lt;/a&gt;, and more every year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ad-blockers don't just stop users from seeing ads and being tracked (and indeed, some ad-blockers actually track users!). They can also stop the publishers and marketers who rely on tracking and ad-clicks from earning money. Predictably, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.marketingdive.com/news/30-of-top-publishers-adopt-anti-ad-blockers-new-study-finds/516729/&quot;&gt;industry responded with ad-blocker-blockers&lt;/a&gt;, which prevented users from seeing their sites unless they turned off their ad-blocker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You'll never guess what happened next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually, it's obvious what happened next: users started to install &lt;a href=&quot;https://reek.github.io/anti-adblock-killer/&quot;&gt;ad-blocker-blocker-blockers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Biggest Boycott in History&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rise and rise of ad-blockers (and ad-blocker-blocker-blockers) is without parallel: 26% of Internet users are now blocking ads, and the figure is rising. It’s been called &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs-test.harvard.edu/doc/2015/09/28/beyond-ad-blocking-the-biggest-boycott-in-human-history/&quot;&gt;the biggest boycott in human history&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's also something we've seen before, in the earliest days of the Web, when pop-up ads ruled the world (wide web), and users went to war against them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1994, Hotwired (the defunct online adjunct to Wired magazine) displayed the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2017/04/the-first-ever-banner-ad-on-the-web/523728/&quot;&gt;first banner ad in Internet history&lt;/a&gt;. Forty-four percent of the people who saw that ad clicked on it. At the time, it felt like advertising had taken a great leap, attaining a conversion rate that bested print, TV, direct mail, or display advertising by orders of magnitude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it turned out that the click-rate on that Hotwired ad had more to do with novelty than any enduring persuasive properties of banner ads. Even as Web companies were raising millions based on the fabulous performance of early ads, the efficacy of those ads was falling off a cliff, with clickthrough rates plummeting to low single digits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This created a desperate situation, where publishers needed to do something -- anything -- to goose their clickthrough rates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enter the Pop-Up Ad&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's when Ethan Zuckerman&lt;span class=&quot;ILfuVd&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;e24Kjd&quot;&gt;—&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;then an employee at Tripod&lt;span class=&quot;ILfuVd&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;e24Kjd&quot;&gt;—&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;invented the pop-up ad (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2014/08/advertising-is-the-internets-original-sin/376041/?single_page=true&quot;&gt;he has since apologized&lt;/a&gt;). These ads spawned in new windows and were much harder to ignore&lt;span class=&quot;ILfuVd&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;e24Kjd&quot;&gt;—&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;for a while. Human beings' response to stimulus &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Regression_toward_the_mean&quot;&gt;tends to regress to the mean&lt;/a&gt; (the refrigerator hum gets quieter over time because you adapt to it, not because the decibel level decreases) and so pop-up ads evolved into ever-more &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pop-up_ad#Techniques&quot;&gt;virulent forms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ILfuVd&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;e24Kjd&quot;&gt;—&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;pop-under ads, pop-ups with fake &quot;close&quot; boxes, pop-up ads that respawned, pop-up ads that ran away from your mouse when you tried to close them...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the height of the pop-up wars, it seemed like there was no end in sight: the future of the Web would be one where humans adapted to pop-ups, then pop-ups found new, obnoxious ways to command humans' attention, which would wane, until pop-ups got even more obnoxious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that's not how it happened. Instead, browser vendors (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Features_of_the_Opera_web_browser#Pop-up_blocking&quot;&gt;beginning with Opera&lt;/a&gt;) started to ship on-by-default pop-up blockers. What's more, users&lt;span class=&quot;ILfuVd&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;e24Kjd&quot;&gt;—&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;who hated pop-up ads&lt;span class=&quot;ILfuVd&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;e24Kjd&quot;&gt;—&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;started to choose browsers that blocked pop-ups, marginalizing holdouts like Microsoft's Internet Explorer, until they, too, added pop-up blockers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chances are, those blockers are in your browser today. But here's a funny thing: if you turn them off, you won't see a million pop-up ads that have been lurking unseen for all these years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because once pop-up ads became invisible by default to an ever-larger swathe of Internet users, advertisers stopped demanding that publishers serve pop-up ads. The point of pop-ups was to get people's attention, but something that is never seen in the first place can't possibly do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How About Nah?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet is full of take-it-or-leave-it offers: click-through and click-wrap agreements that you can either click &quot;I agree&quot; on or walk away from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/issues/competition&quot;&gt;online world has grown more concentrated&lt;/a&gt;, with more and more power in fewer and fewer hands, it's become increasingly difficult for Web publishers to resist advertisers' insistence on obnoxious tracking ads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Internet users have never been willing to accept take-it-or-leave-it as the last word in technological self-determination. Adblockers are the new pop-up blockers, a way for users to do what publishers can't or won't do: demand a better deal from advertisers. When you visit a site, the deal on offer is, &quot;Let us and everyone we do business with track you in every way possible or get lost&quot; and users who install adblockers push back. An adblocker is a way of replying to advertisers and publishers with a loud-and-clear &quot;How about nah?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adversarial Interoperability&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2019/06/adversarial-interoperability-reviving-elegant-weapon-more-civilized-age-slay&quot;&gt;Adversarial interoperability&lt;/a&gt; occurs when someone figures out how to plug a new product or service into an existing product or service, against the wishes of the company behind that existing product or service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adblocking is one of the most successful examples of adversarial interoperability in modern history, along with third-party printer ink. When you visit a website, the server sends your browser a bunch of material, including the code to fetch and render ads. Adblockers throw away the ad parts and show you the rest, while ad-blocker-blocker-blockers do the same, and then engage in an elaborate technological game of cat-and-mouse in a bid to fool the server into thinking that you are seeing the ads, while still suppressing them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Browsers have always been playgrounds for adversarial interoperability, from the pop-up wars to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTML/Quirks_Mode_and_Standards_Mode&quot;&gt;browser wars&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks to open standards and a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/Consortium/Patent-Policy-20040205/&quot;&gt;mutual disarmament rule for software patents&lt;/a&gt; among browser vendors, it's very hard to use the law to punish toolsmiths who make adblocking technologies (not that that's &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/04/20/adblock-plus-v-axel-springer/&quot;&gt;stopped people from attempting it&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adversarial interoperability is often a way for scrappy new upstarts to challenge the established players&lt;span class=&quot;ILfuVd&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;e24Kjd&quot;&gt;—&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/cases/lexmark-v-static-control-case-archive&quot;&gt;the company that got sued by IBM's printer division for making its own toner cartridges&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kentucky.com/news/business/article72913972.html&quot;&gt;grew so big it now owns that printer division&lt;/a&gt; (!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But adversarial interoperability is also a way for the &lt;em&gt;public&lt;/em&gt; to assert its rights and push back against unfair practices. Take-it-or-leave it deals are one thing when the market is competitive and you can shop around for someone with better terms of service, but in highly concentrated markets where everyone has the same rotten deal on offer, adversarial interoperability lets users make a &lt;em&gt;counteroffer&lt;/em&gt;: &quot;How about nah?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But for How Long?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Concentration in the tech industry—including the “vertical integration” of browsers, advertising networks, and video content under one corporate umbrella—has compromised the Internet's openness. In 2017, the World Wide Web Consortium published its first-ever &quot;standard&quot; that could not be fully implemented without permission from the giant tech and media companies (who have since &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-05-28/google-s-chrome-becomes-web-gatekeeper-and-rivals-complain&quot;&gt;refused that permission to anyone who rocks the boat&lt;/a&gt;). In publishing that standard, the W3C &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2017/09/open-letter-w3c-director-ceo-team-and-membership&quot;&gt;explicitly rejected a proposal to protect adversarial interoperability&lt;/a&gt; by extracting legally binding nonaggression promises from the companies that make up the consortium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The standard the W3C published&lt;span class=&quot;ILfuVd&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;e24Kjd&quot;&gt;—&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Encrypted Media Extensions (EME), for restricting playback of video&lt;span class=&quot;ILfuVd&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;e24Kjd&quot;&gt;—&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;comes with many dangers for would-be adversarial interoperators, notably the risk of being &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/press/releases/eff-lawsuit-takes-dmca-section-1201-research-and-technology-restrictions-violate&quot;&gt;sued under Section 1201 of the Digital Millennium Copyright Act&lt;/a&gt;, which bans tampering with “access controls” on copyrighted works and holds out both criminal and civil liability for toolsmiths who traffic in programs that let you change the rules embodied by EME.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One driving force behind the adoption of EME was the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2018/11/google-chromes-users-take-back-seat-its-bottom-line&quot;&gt;ever-tighter integration&lt;/a&gt; between major browser vendors like Google, video distributors, and advertising networks. This created a lopsided power-dynamic that ultimately ended up in the standardization of a means of undoing the configurable Web&lt;span class=&quot;ILfuVd&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;e24Kjd&quot;&gt;—&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;where the user is king. EME is the first crack in the wall that protected browsers from those who would thwart adversarial operability and take &quot;how about nah?&quot; off the table, leaving us with the kind of take-it-or-leave-it Web that the marketing industry has been striving for since the first pop-up ad.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2019 14:10:58 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dredmorbius</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Adblocking: How About Nah?</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2019/07/adblocking-how-about-nah</og:url>
<og:description>For more than a decade, consumer rights groups (including EFF) worked with technologists and companies to try to standardize Do Not Track, a flag that browsers could send to online companies signaling that their users did not want their browsing activity tracked. Despite long hours and backing from...</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.eff.org/files/banner_library/interoperable-2.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2019/07/adblocking-how-about-nah</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Claiming your $125 from Equifax is a “moral duty”</title>
<link>https://boingboing.net/2019/07/26/soak-em.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://boingboing.net/2019/07/26/soak-em.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;story&quot; readability=&quot;70.066632756867&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;metadata&quot;/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;metadata&quot;&gt;If you fill in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.equifaxbreachsettlement.com/&quot;&gt;this form&lt;/a&gt;, Equifax will send you $125 as part of its settlement with the Consumer Finance Protection Bureau, the FTC, and 48 out of 50 states.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;metadata&quot;/&gt;

&lt;span id=&quot;metadata&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-728646&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Equifax doxed the nation and profited handsomely from it. $125 is a laughably small sum given how much damage the data they hemorrhaged all over the internet could cause you. Equifax should have faced the corporate death penalty, the execs who oversaw the disaster should have had their assets seized and diverted to anti-identity-theft measures and charities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, the FTC et al are &lt;a href=&quot;https://boingboing.net/2019/07/20/america-doxed-2.html&quot;&gt;hitting the company for a maximum of $700m&lt;/a&gt; (how much they pay depends in part on whether you fill in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.equifaxbreachsettlement.com/&quot;&gt;this form&lt;/a&gt;. Equifax's market cap stands today at $16.6B, and it posted $3.412B in earnings in 2018, up 1.48% increase from 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As meaningless as the $125 is, as piddling as the $700m is, you should still do this. As Josephine Wolff &lt;a href=&quot;https://slate.com/technology/2019/07/equifax-settlement-money-how-to-claim.html&quot;&gt;writes for Slate&lt;/a&gt;, breaches should be &lt;em&gt;as expensive as possible&lt;/em&gt;. Anything you can do to make them more expensive will help people inside companies who are arguing against data-collection and retention, making the world safer for everyone else. Anything you can do to make breaches more expensive will hit the share price of companies that overcollect our data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go on, do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;26&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may be thinking, But I don’t want to give Equifax the last six digits of my Social Security number and my birthdate and mailing address after it’s demonstrated just how much it can’t be trusted! Believe me, the company already knows all that information—and so much more. But it’s so much work to fill out the entire form! It’s really not, unless you want to claim additional lost time or expenses beyond the base $125 payout, in which case you have to submit a description of the time you lost or receipts for any identity protection services or other security purchases you made in the aftermath of the breach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If, for instance, you went ahead and purchased LifeLock or some other credit monitoring service after the Equifax breach, go ahead and submit that receipt too. Each individual is eligible to receive up to $20,000 as part of the settlement; $125 is just the amount you can receive without having to do any extra work or claim any extra losses. The settlement also includes provisions to reimburse you for your lost time at a rate of $25 per hour. If you spent hours on the phone trying to clear up suspicious credit activity or figure out whether you had been affected, go ahead and submit that as well. One of the notable things about this claims process, in fact, is its recognition of the fact that people lose time dealing with these incidents and that time is, in itself, valuable to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://slate.com/technology/2019/07/equifax-settlement-money-how-to-claim.html&quot;&gt;https://slate.com/technology/2019/07/equifax-settlement-money-how-to-claim.html&lt;/a&gt; [Josephine Wolff/Slate]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jwz.org/blog/&quot;&gt;JWZ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Image: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/rollercoasterphilosophy/39059469075&quot;&gt;Jeremy Thompson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/deed.en&quot;&gt;CC-BY&lt;/a&gt;, modified&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;next-post-thumbnails&quot; readability=&quot;40.066382171645&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;nextstory&quot; readability=&quot;26.621621621622&quot;&gt;

&lt;a href=&quot;https://boingboing.net/2019/07/26/doj-approves-26-billion-t-mob.html?utm_source=moreatbb&amp;amp;utm_medium=nextpost&amp;amp;utm_campaign=nextpostthumbnails&quot; onclick=&quot;clickTrack(this.href, 'Next Post Button', 'Next Post Thumbnails');&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/media.boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/U-54GYJc.jpeg?fit=600%2C300&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; class=&quot;attachment-medium size-medium wp-post-image&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/media.boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/U-54GYJc.jpeg?w=900&amp;amp;ssl=1 900w, https://i1.wp.com/media.boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/U-54GYJc.jpeg?resize=300%2C150&amp;amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i1.wp.com/media.boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/U-54GYJc.jpeg?resize=600%2C300&amp;amp;ssl=1 600w, https://i1.wp.com/media.boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/U-54GYJc.jpeg?resize=768%2C384&amp;amp;ssl=1 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, it’s finally official. After more than a year in regulatory limbo, The United States Justice Department has approved a $26 billion dollar deal between mobile carriers T-Mobile and Sprint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://boingboing.net/2019/07/26/doj-approves-26-billion-t-mob.html&quot;&gt;READ THE REST&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;nextstory&quot; readability=&quot;23.479245283019&quot;&gt;

&lt;a href=&quot;https://boingboing.net/2019/07/26/trump-apple-wont-get-a-tari.html?utm_source=moreatbb&amp;amp;utm_medium=nextpost&amp;amp;utm_campaign=nextpostthumbnails&quot; onclick=&quot;clickTrack(this.href, 'Next Post Button', 'Next Post Thumbnails');&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/media.boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/RTX2V24O.jpg?fit=600%2C400&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; class=&quot;attachment-medium size-medium wp-post-image&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/media.boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/RTX2V24O.jpg?w=4511&amp;amp;ssl=1 4511w, https://i0.wp.com/media.boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/RTX2V24O.jpg?resize=300%2C200&amp;amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/media.boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/RTX2V24O.jpg?resize=600%2C400&amp;amp;ssl=1 600w, https://i0.wp.com/media.boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/RTX2V24O.jpg?resize=768%2C512&amp;amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/media.boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/RTX2V24O.jpg?resize=930%2C620&amp;amp;ssl=1 930w, https://i0.wp.com/media.boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/RTX2V24O.jpg?w=1940&amp;amp;ssl=1 1940w, https://i0.wp.com/media.boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/RTX2V24O.jpg?w=2910&amp;amp;ssl=1 2910w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Donald Trump says his administration will not provide any waivers or relief for Apple Mac Pro components built in China, and said Apple should instead build its products in the U.S.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://boingboing.net/2019/07/26/trump-apple-wont-get-a-tari.html&quot;&gt;READ THE REST&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;nextstory&quot; readability=&quot;34.238578680203&quot;&gt;

&lt;a href=&quot;https://boingboing.net/2019/07/25/largest-boycott-in-history.html?utm_source=moreatbb&amp;amp;utm_medium=nextpost&amp;amp;utm_campaign=nextpostthumbnails&quot; onclick=&quot;clickTrack(this.href, 'Next Post Button', 'Next Post Thumbnails');&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/media.boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/interoperable-2-3.png?fit=600%2C300&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; class=&quot;attachment-medium size-medium wp-post-image&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/media.boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/interoperable-2-3.png?w=1200&amp;amp;ssl=1 1200w, https://i0.wp.com/media.boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/interoperable-2-3.png?resize=300%2C150&amp;amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/media.boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/interoperable-2-3.png?resize=600%2C300&amp;amp;ssl=1 600w, https://i0.wp.com/media.boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/interoperable-2-3.png?resize=768%2C384&amp;amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/media.boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/interoperable-2-3.png?resize=930%2C465&amp;amp;ssl=1 930w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more than a decade, consumer rights groups (including EFF) worked with technologists and companies to try to standardize Do Not Track, a flag that browsers could send to online companies signaling that their users did not want their browsing activity tracked. Despite long hours and backing from the FTC, foot-dragging from the browser vendors […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://boingboing.net/2019/07/25/largest-boycott-in-history.html&quot;&gt;READ THE REST&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;nextstory&quot; readability=&quot;29.1388101983&quot;&gt;

&lt;a href=&quot;https://boingboing.net/2019/07/27/these-japanese-precision-knive.html?utm_source=moreatbb&amp;amp;utm_medium=nextpost&amp;amp;utm_campaign=nextpostthumbnails&quot; onclick=&quot;clickTrack(this.href, 'Next Post Button', 'Next Post Thumbnails');&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; src=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/media.boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/product_29378_product_shots4.jpg?fit=600%2C450&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; class=&quot;attachment-medium size-medium wp-post-image&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/media.boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/product_29378_product_shots4.jpg?w=630&amp;amp;ssl=1 630w, https://i1.wp.com/media.boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/product_29378_product_shots4.jpg?resize=300%2C225&amp;amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i1.wp.com/media.boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/product_29378_product_shots4.jpg?resize=600%2C450&amp;amp;ssl=1 600w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey, we get it. Not everybody’s a master chef – or even a chef. And when all you see on the recipe is prep time, cooking even the simplest meals can seem like a hassle. But trust us, the simple act of dicing up some fresh veggies can make you feel in control of your […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://boingboing.net/2019/07/27/these-japanese-precision-knive.html&quot;&gt;READ THE REST&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;nextstory&quot; readability=&quot;30.048661800487&quot;&gt;

&lt;a href=&quot;https://boingboing.net/2019/07/25/need-security-as-well-as-speed.html?utm_source=moreatbb&amp;amp;utm_medium=nextpost&amp;amp;utm_campaign=nextpostthumbnails&quot; onclick=&quot;clickTrack(this.href, 'Next Post Button', 'Next Post Thumbnails');&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; src=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/media.boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/product_24129_product_shots1_image-1.jpg?fit=600%2C450&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; class=&quot;attachment-medium size-medium wp-post-image&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/media.boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/product_24129_product_shots1_image-1.jpg?w=630&amp;amp;ssl=1 630w, https://i0.wp.com/media.boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/product_24129_product_shots1_image-1.jpg?resize=300%2C225&amp;amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/media.boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/product_24129_product_shots1_image-1.jpg?resize=600%2C450&amp;amp;ssl=1 600w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Virtual Private Networks can make the internet a much safer place, but that’s not all. They can offer freedom from local content restrictions, anonymity and even protection from popup ads – and a really good one will do all that while still keeping you surfing at top speed. Before you go browsing the web, browse […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://boingboing.net/2019/07/25/need-security-as-well-as-speed.html&quot;&gt;READ THE REST&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;nextstory&quot; readability=&quot;31.24644549763&quot;&gt;

&lt;a href=&quot;https://boingboing.net/2019/07/24/rosetta-stone-is-still-the-fas.html?utm_source=moreatbb&amp;amp;utm_medium=nextpost&amp;amp;utm_campaign=nextpostthumbnails&quot; onclick=&quot;clickTrack(this.href, 'Next Post Button', 'Next Post Thumbnails');&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;413&quot; src=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/media.boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/pexels-photo-297642.jpeg?fit=600%2C413&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; class=&quot;attachment-medium size-medium wp-post-image&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/media.boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/pexels-photo-297642.jpeg?w=1880&amp;amp;ssl=1 1880w, https://i1.wp.com/media.boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/pexels-photo-297642.jpeg?resize=300%2C207&amp;amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i1.wp.com/media.boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/pexels-photo-297642.jpeg?resize=600%2C413&amp;amp;ssl=1 600w, https://i1.wp.com/media.boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/pexels-photo-297642.jpeg?resize=768%2C529&amp;amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i1.wp.com/media.boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/pexels-photo-297642.jpeg?resize=930%2C641&amp;amp;ssl=1 930w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every language has its quirks. The gendered pronouns in French and Spanish can raise an eyebrow for some, and the verb placement in Japanese can confound English speakers. But when learning any new language, the brain pretty much works the same way: It needs total immersion. Rosetta Stone understands that better than anyone, and that’s […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://boingboing.net/2019/07/24/rosetta-stone-is-still-the-fas.html&quot;&gt;READ THE REST&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2019 12:47:18 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>based2</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Claiming your $125 from Equifax is a &quot;moral duty&quot;</og:title>
<og:description>Claiming your $125 from Equifax is a &quot;moral duty&quot;</og:description>
<og:url>https://boingboing.net/2019/07/26/soak-em.html</og:url>
<og:image>https://media.boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/39059469075_e80c3e7554_b.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://boingboing.net/2019/07/26/soak-em.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Bedridden for 11 years, he discovered a surgery for his adrenal condition</title>
<link>https://www-m.cnn.com/2019/07/27/health/doug-lindsay-invented-surgery-trnd/index.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www-m.cnn.com/2019/07/27/health/doug-lindsay-invented-surgery-trnd/index.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;27&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong data-type=&quot;sourceText&quot;&gt;(CNN) —&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;span&gt;Doug Lindsay was 21 and starting his senior year at Rockhurst University, a Jesuit college in Kansas City, Missouri, when his world imploded.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After his first day of classes, the biology major collapsed at home on the dining room table, the room spinning around him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was 1999. The symptoms soon became intense and untreatable. His heart would race, he felt weak and he frequently got dizzy. Lindsay could walk only about 50 feet at a time and couldn't stand for more than a few minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Even lying on the floor didn't feel like it was low enough,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The former high school track athlete had dreamed of becoming a biochemistry professor or maybe a writer for &quot;The Simpsons.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2019 11:28:38 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>actraub</dc:creator>
<og:title>This college dropout was bedridden for 11 years. Then he invented a surgery and cured himself</og:title>
<og:description>Doug Lindsay was starting his senior year in college when he was stricken by a mysterious illness. Doctors were baffled. He eventually realized that if he wanted his life back, he'd have to do it himself.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.cnn.com/2019/07/27/health/doug-lindsay-invented-surgery-trnd/index.html</og:url>
<og:image>//cdn.cnn.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/190430194441-02-doug-lindsay-1-super-tease.jpeg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www-m.cnn.com/2019/07/27/health/doug-lindsay-invented-surgery-trnd/index.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why we don&amp;#039;t use Galileo&amp;#039;s last name (2009)</title>
<link>https://slate.com/news-and-politics/2009/08/why-we-don-t-use-galileo-s-last-name.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://slate.com/news-and-politics/2009/08/why-we-don-t-use-galileo-s-last-name.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Galileo Galilei&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;slate-paragraph&quot; data-editable=&quot;text&quot; data-uri=&quot;slate.com/_components/slate-paragraph/instances/cq-article-d58bae527c06fd0b488121e617feea88-component-1@published&quot; data-word-count=&quot;66&quot;&gt;Four hundred years ago this month, Galileo Galilei &lt;a data-linktype=&quot;External&quot; href=&quot;http://www.britannica.com/EBchecked/topic/224058/Galileo/8440/Telescopic-discoveries&quot;&gt;presented his eight-powered telescope&lt;/a&gt; to the Venetian Senate. He was soon working with a 20-powered telescope, and later that year, he proved that the moon’s surface was rough, contrary to the prevailing view. Galileo went on to become one of the most recognized names in scientific history. But why do we call him by his first name only?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;slate-paragraph&quot; data-editable=&quot;text&quot; data-uri=&quot;slate.com/_components/slate-paragraph/instances/cq-article-d58bae527c06fd0b488121e617feea88-component-2@published&quot; data-word-count=&quot;80&quot;&gt;Because that’s how he referred to himself. At the time of Galileo’s birth in 1564, surnames were optional in Italy.  In daily interactions, an Italian would use the name his parents gave him at birth—what we’d now call a first name—and, if further clarification were required, add on his father’s name (like &lt;em&gt;di Antonio&lt;/em&gt;, or “son of Antonio”), his birthplace (&lt;em&gt;Romano&lt;/em&gt;, or “from Rome”), his occupation (&lt;em&gt;Panettiere&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a data-linktype=&quot;Bookmark&quot; href=&quot;http://www.slate.com#correction&quot;&gt;*&lt;/a&gt; meaning “baker”), or a traditional family surname (if one existed, like &lt;em&gt;Galilei&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;slate-paragraph&quot; data-editable=&quot;text&quot; data-uri=&quot;slate.com/_components/slate-paragraph/instances/cq-article-d58bae527c06fd0b488121e617feea88-component-3@published&quot; data-word-count=&quot;63&quot;&gt;The Italian astronomer’s name is unusually confusing because both &lt;em&gt;Galileo&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Galilei&lt;/em&gt; were surnames used by his family for generations. (An equivalent might be “William Williams.”) This was not a particularly common practice at the time. Moreover, the name Galileo itself, although not completely unique, was quite rare. This is part of the reason we continue to use his first name only—it’s unambiguous.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;slate-paragraph&quot; data-editable=&quot;text&quot; data-uri=&quot;slate.com/_components/slate-paragraph/instances/cq-article-d58bae527c06fd0b488121e617feea88-component-4@published&quot; data-word-count=&quot;171&quot;&gt;In Renaissance Italy, individuals didn’t even stick with the same second, or identifying, name throughout their lives. Many used their family surnames one day and place of birth the next, depending on the circumstances. Take Leonardo da Vinci. Because Vinci was a very small town, calling himself Leonardo from the town of Vinci left little room for confusion—unless, of course, he was in Vinci at the time. (Leonardo was a common name.) In that case, the artist would probably have called himself Leonardo di ser Piero da Vinci, making reference to his father. Once he became famous, he often signed his name simply “Leonardo.” Galileo referred to himself sometimes by first name only, sometimes as Galileo Galilei, and sometimes as &lt;a data-linktype=&quot;External&quot; href=&quot;http://www.law.umkc.edu/faculty/projects/ftrials/galileo/dialogue.html&quot;&gt;Galileo Galilei Linceo&lt;/a&gt; (a nod to his alliance with a &lt;a data-linktype=&quot;External&quot; href=&quot;http://www.americanscientist.org/bookshelf/pub/in-galileos-orbit&quot;&gt;progressive group of scientists&lt;/a&gt;, which served, in part, as a kind of honorific). Also, because the convention was so casual, some individuals weren’t consistent with spelling or construction. Negri, Negro, de Negro, or Neri might all refer to the same person.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p class=&quot;slate-paragraph&quot; data-editable=&quot;text&quot; data-uri=&quot;slate.com/_components/slate-paragraph/instances/cq-article-d58bae527c06fd0b488121e617feea88-component-5@published&quot; data-word-count=&quot;173&quot;&gt;The governments of the various Italian city-states eventually grew frustrated by their citizens’ constantly shifting last names—without standardization, it was difficult to levy taxes or enforce military registration requirements. Beginning in Galileo’s lifetime, therefore, laws swept through Italy requiring parents to record both first and last names for their children. If a family had a traditional surname, they usually used that. If not, they resorted to town of origin or occupation, and then these names were passed down through the generations. For the first time, a person named &lt;em&gt;da Vinci&lt;/em&gt; might not actually be from Vinci. A man named &lt;em&gt;&lt;a data-linktype=&quot;External&quot; href=&quot;http://www.babynames.com/name/FERRARI&quot;&gt;Ferrari&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; might not be a blacksmith. Italians also had to record their names upon marriage and death with either church or state authorities, depending on the area. Italy was a bit of a latecomer in this regard. Many nearby countries, like France and Germany, had systematized surnames generations earlier. This is probably why we don’t refer to Johannes Kepler, Galileo’s colleague and regular correspondent, or Nicolaus Copernicus, who pre-dated Galileo, as Johannes and Nicolaus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;slate-paragraph&quot; data-editable=&quot;text&quot; data-uri=&quot;slate.com/_components/slate-paragraph/instances/cq-article-d58bae527c06fd0b488121e617feea88-component-6@published&quot; data-word-count=&quot;9&quot;&gt;Got a question about today’s news? &lt;a data-linktype=&quot;External&quot; href=&quot;mailto:ask_the_explainer@yahoo.com?subject=&quot;&gt;Ask the Explainer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;slate-paragraph&quot; data-editable=&quot;text&quot; data-uri=&quot;slate.com/_components/slate-paragraph/instances/cq-article-d58bae527c06fd0b488121e617feea88-component-7@published&quot; data-word-count=&quot;20&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Explainer thanks Valeria Finucci of Duke University, Meredith Gill of the University of Maryland, and Owen Gingerich of Harvard University.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;slate-paragraph&quot; data-editable=&quot;text&quot; data-uri=&quot;slate.com/_components/slate-paragraph/instances/cq-article-d58bae527c06fd0b488121e617feea88-component-8@published&quot; data-word-count=&quot;22&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Correction,&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Aug. 21, 2009:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The original version of this article misspelled the Italian word for&lt;/em&gt; baker&lt;em&gt;. (&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a data-linktype=&quot;Bookmark&quot; href=&quot;http://www.slate.com#return&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Return&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;to the corrected sentence.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2019 02:16:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>never-the-bride</dc:creator>
<og:title>Why we don't use Galileo's last name.</og:title>
<og:url>https://slate.com/news-and-politics/2009/08/why-we-don-t-use-galileo-s-last-name.html</og:url>
<og:description> Four hundred years ago this month, Galileo Galilei presented his eight-powered telescope to the Venetian Senate. He was soon working with a 20-powered...</og:description>
<og:image>https://compote.slate.com/images/8e8a460d-0f8f-4261-b3e7-7e2e2be7f45f.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://slate.com/news-and-politics/2009/08/why-we-don-t-use-galileo-s-last-name.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Siri records fights, doctor’s appointments, and sex, and contractors hear it</title>
<link>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/07/siri-records-fights-doctors-appointments-and-sex-and-contractors-hear-it/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/07/siri-records-fights-doctors-appointments-and-sex-and-contractors-hear-it/</guid>
<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/siri-logo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&amp;quot;Siri, define the word &amp;quot;surprising.'&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Okay. Ask me to define the word 'mother' twice, then.&amp;quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/siri-logo.jpg&quot; class=&quot;enlarge-link&quot; data-height=&quot;503&quot; data-width=&quot;719&quot;&gt;Enlarge&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;sep&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &quot;Siri, define the word &quot;surprising.'&quot; &quot;Okay. Ask me to define the word 'mother' twice, then.&quot;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;aside id=&quot;social-left&quot; aria-label=&quot;Read the comments or share this article&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;comment-count-before&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;115 posters participating&quot; class=&quot;comment-count icon-comment-bubble-down&quot; href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/07/siri-records-fights-doctors-appointments-and-sex-and-contractors-hear-it/?comments=1&quot;&gt;reader comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;a title=&quot;115 posters participating&quot; class=&quot;comment-count icon-comment-bubble-down&quot; href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/07/siri-records-fights-doctors-appointments-and-sex-and-contractors-hear-it/?comments=1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;comment-count-number&quot;&gt;225&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;with 115 posters participating&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;share-links&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Share this story&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Voice assistants are growing in popularity, but the technology has been experiencing a parallel rise in concerns about privacy and accuracy. Apple’s Siri is the latest to enter this gray space of tech. This week, The Guardian reported that contractors who review Siri recordings for accuracy and to help make improvements may be hearing personal conversations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the contract workers told &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2019/jul/26/apple-contractors-regularly-hear-confidential-details-on-siri-recordings&quot;&gt;The Guardian&lt;/a&gt; that Siri did sometimes record audio after mistaken activations. The wake word is the phrase “hey Siri,” but the anonymous source said that it could be activated by similar-sounding words or with the noise of a zipper. They also said that when an Apple Watch is raised and speech is detected, Siri will automatically activate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“There have been countless instances of recordings featuring private discussions between doctors and patients, business deals, seemingly criminal dealings, sexual encounters and so on,” the source said. “These recordings are accompanied by user data showing location, contact details, and app data.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple has said that it takes steps to protect users from being connected with the recordings sent to contractors. The audio is not linked to an Apple ID and less than 1% of daily Siri activations are reviewed. It also sets confidentiality requirements for those contract workers. We reached out to Apple for further comment and will update the story if we receive it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple, along with Google and Amazon, all have similar policies for the contract workers it hires to review those audio snippets. But all three voice AI makers have also been the subject of similar privacy breaches, either by whistleblowers going to the press or through errors that give users access to incorrect audio files.&lt;/p&gt;

The tech companies have also all been the subject of inquiries around voice platforms recording conversations they weren't supposed to. Amazon recently &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/07/amazon-confirms-it-keeps-your-alexa-recordings-basically-forever/&quot;&gt;outlined its policies&lt;/a&gt; for keeping and reviewing recordings in response to queries from Sen. Chris Coons (D-Delaware). A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vrt.be/vrtnws/en/2019/07/10/google-employees-are-eavesdropping-even-in-flemish-living-rooms/&quot;&gt;whistleblower report&lt;/a&gt; from a Google contractor said that workers had heard conversations between parents and children, private and identifying information, and at least one possible case of sexual assault.
&lt;p&gt;These cases bring up a series of questions. What can Apple and its colleagues do to better protect user privacy as they develop their voice systems? Should users be notified when their recordings are reviewed? What can be done to reduce or eliminate the accidental activations? How should the companies handle the accidental information that its contractors overhear? Who is responsible when dangerous or illegal activity is recorded and discovered, all by accident?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Voice assistants appear to be yet another instance where a technology has been developed and adopted faster than its consequences have been fully thought-out.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2019 00:06:30 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>vatueil</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/07/siri-records-fights-doctors-appointments-and-sex-and-contractors-hear-it/</og:url>
<og:title>Siri records fights, doctor’s appointments, and sex (and contractors hear it)</og:title>
<og:image>https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/siri-logo-719x380.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>In a new report, Apple takes its turn in the crosshairs over how it reviews user recordings.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/07/siri-records-fights-doctors-appointments-and-sex-and-contractors-hear-it/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Wind is outpacing coal as a power source in Texas for the first time</title>
<link>https://edition.cnn.com/2019/07/25/us/texas-wind-energy-trnd/index.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://edition.cnn.com/2019/07/25/us/texas-wind-energy-trnd/index.html</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://edition.cnn.com/2019/07/25/us/texas-wind-energy-trnd/index.html&quot;&gt;https://edition.cnn.com/2019/07/25/us/texas-wind-energy-trnd/index.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20538614&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20538614&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 259&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 133&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 21:43:42 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rchaudhary</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/07/siri-records-fights-doctors-appointments-and-sex-and-contractors-hear-it/</og:url>
<og:title>Siri records fights, doctor’s appointments, and sex (and contractors hear it)</og:title>
<og:image>https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/siri-logo-719x380.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>In a new report, Apple takes its turn in the crosshairs over how it reviews user recordings.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/07/siri-records-fights-doctors-appointments-and-sex-and-contractors-hear-it/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Scientists stunned by ‘city-killer’ asteroid that just missed Earth</title>
<link>https://www.seattletimes.com/nation-world/scientists-stunned-by-city-killer-asteroid-that-just-missed-earth/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.seattletimes.com/nation-world/scientists-stunned-by-city-killer-asteroid-that-just-missed-earth/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Alan Duffy was confused. On Thursday, the astronomer’s phone was suddenly flooded with calls from reporters wanting to know about a large asteroid that had just whizzed past Earth, and he couldn’t figure out “why everyone was so alarmed.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I thought everyone was getting worried about something we knew was coming,” Duffy, who is also lead scientist at the Royal Institution of Australia, told The Washington Post. Forecasts had already predicted that a couple asteroids would be passing relatively close to Earth this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then he looked up the details of the hunk of space rock named Asteroid 2019 OK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I was stunned,” he said. “This was a true shock.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This asteroid wasn’t one that scientists had been tracking and it had seemingly appeared from “out of nowhere,” Michael Brown, a Melbourne-based observational astronomer, told The Post. According to data from NASA, the craggy rock was large, roughly 110 yards wide, and moving quickly along a path that brought it within about 45,360 miles of Earth. That’s about one-fifth of the distance to the moon and what Duffy considers “uncomfortably close.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It snuck up on us pretty quickly,” said Brown, an associate professor with Australia’s Monash University’s School of Physics and Astronomy. “People are only sort of realizing what happened pretty much after it’s already flung past us.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The asteroid’s presence was discovered only earlier this week by separate astronomy teams in Brazil and the United States. Information about its size and path was announced just hours before it rocketed past Earth, Brown said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-container u-ofh u-bg-dark-off-white full-width-inset mb-4 mt-4 pt-0 ad-container-multiple body1&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-label font-micro u-tc u-mid-light-gray u-sans pv-10 u-upper&quot;&gt;Advertising&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It shook me out my morning complacency,” he said. “It’s probably the largest asteroid to pass this close to Earth in quite a number of years.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how did the event almost go unnoticed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, there’s the issue of size, Duffy said. Asteroid 2019 OK is a sizable chunk of rock, but it’s nowhere near as big as the ones capable of causing an event like the dinosaurs’ extinction. More than 90 percent of those asteroids, which are 1 kilometer, 0.62 miles, or larger, have already been identified by NASA and its partners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Nothing this size is easy to detect,” Duffy said of the 110-yard-wide asteroid. ″You’re really relying on reflected sunlight, and even at closest approach it was barely visible with a pair of binoculars.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brown said the asteroid’s “eccentric orbit” and speed were also likely factors in what made spotting it ahead of time challenging. Its “very elliptical orbit” takes it “from beyond Mars to within the orbit of Venus,” which means the amount of time it spends near Earth where it is detectable isn’t long, he said. As it approached Earth, the asteroid was traveling at about 15 miles per second, he said. By contrast, other recent asteroids that flew by Earth clocked in at between 2,5 and 12 miles per second.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s faint for a long time,” Brown said of Asteroid 2019 OK. “With a week or two to go, it’s getting bright enough to detect, but someone needs to look in the right spot. Once it’s finally recognized then things happen quickly, but this thing’s approaching quickly so we only sort of knew about it very soon before the flyby.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last-minute detection is yet another sign of how much still remains unknown about space and a sobering reminder of the very real threat asteroids can pose, Duffy said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-container u-ofh u-bg-dark-off-white full-width-inset mb-4 mt-4 pt-0 ad-container-single&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-label font-micro u-tc u-mid-light-gray u-sans pv-10 u-upper&quot;&gt;Advertising&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It should worry us all quite frankly,” he said. “It’s not a Hollywood movie. It is a clear and present danger.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Duffy said astronomers have a nickname for the kind of space rock that just came so close to Earth: “city-killer asteroids.” If the asteroid had struck Earth, most of it would have likely reached the ground, resulting in devastating damage, Brown said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It would have gone off like a very large nuclear weapon” with enough force to destroy a city, he said. “Many megatons, perhaps in the ballpark of 10 megatons of TNT, so something not to be messed with.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2013 a significantly smaller meteor, about 22 yards across, broke up over the Russian city of Chelyabinsk and unleashed an intense shock wave that collapsed roofs, shattered windows and left about 1,200 people injured. The last space rock to strike Earth similar in size to Asteroid 2019 OK was more than a century ago, Brown said. That asteroid, known as the Tunguska event, caused an explosion that leveled nearly 500,000 square acres of forest land in Siberia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though the chances of a large asteroid landing on a city are “modest,” Brown said it is still worthwhile to devote resources toward detection and prevention. Brown said Asteroid 2019 OK proves there are “still dangerous asteroids out there that we don’t know of” that “can arrive on our doorstep unannounced.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientists are working on developing at least two approaches to deflecting potentially harmful asteroids, Duffy said. One strategy involves gently pushing the asteroid slowly over time off its course and away from Earth, he said. The other, which he called a “very elegant solution,” is the gravity tractor. If an asteroid is detected early enough, it could be possible to divert it using the gravity of a spacecraft, according to NASA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People shouldn’t try to “blast it with a nuke,” Duffy said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It makes for a great Hollywood film,” he said. “The challenge with a nuke is that it may or not work, but it would definitely make the asteroid radioactive.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In light of Asteroid 2019 OK, Duffy stressed the importance of investing in a “global dedicated approach” to detecting asteroids because “sooner or later there will be one with our name on it, it’s just a matter of when not if.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div data-section=&quot;nation-world&quot; class=&quot;most-read-container module most-shared truncate show u-border-t u-border-b u-border-light-gray embed-container mt-40 mb-40&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;most-read-wrapper mb-17&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;mrw-header pt-27&quot;&gt;Most Read Nation &amp;amp; World Stories&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We don’t have to go the way of the dinosaurs,” he said. “We actually have the technology to find and deflect certainly these smaller asteroids if we commit to now.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emily Lakdawalla, senior editor of the Planetary Society, which promotes space exploration, said the recent near miss is a reminder that “it’s an important activity to be watching the skies.” The more that can be learned about an asteroid, the better prepared people can be to prevent potential disasters, she told The Post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, Lakdawalla said that while the asteroid’s close brush with Earth may have sparked some concern, “it is zero percent danger to us.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s the kind of thing where you learn about something that you didn’t know about, like things flying close by us, and your inclination is to be scared,” she said. “But just like sharks in the ocean, they’re really not going to hurt you and they’re really fascinating to look at.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;extended-byline&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;single-byline&quot;&gt;This story was originally published at washingtonpost.com. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/nation/2019/07/26/it-snuck-up-us-city-killer-asteroid-just-missed-earth-scientists-almost-didnt-detect-it-time/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Read it here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 20:05:02 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>swamp40</dc:creator>
<og:title>Scientists stunned by ‘city-killer’ asteroid that just missed Earth</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.seattletimes.com/nation-world/scientists-stunned-by-city-killer-asteroid-that-just-missed-earth/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.seattletimes.com/wp-content/themes/st_refresh/img/st-meta-facebook.png</og:image>
<og:description>The pretty hefty &quot;Asteroid 2019 OK&quot; (its official name) was discovered only this week. One astronomer said it proves there are &quot;still dangerous asteroids out there that we don't know of&quot; that &quot;can arrive on our doorstep unannounced.&quot;</og:description>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.seattletimes.com/nation-world/scientists-stunned-by-city-killer-asteroid-that-just-missed-earth/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How is China able to provide enough food to feed over 1B people?</title>
<link>https://www.quora.com/How-is-China-able-to-provide-enough-food-to-feed-its-population-of-over-1-billion-people-Do-they-import-food-or-are-they-self-sustainable?share=1</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.quora.com/How-is-China-able-to-provide-enough-food-to-feed-its-population-of-over-1-billion-people-Do-they-import-food-or-are-they-self-sustainable?share=1</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ui_qtext_rendered_qtext&quot;&gt;Seeing is believing. Open your Google Earth and have a look at what is really going on in China from above. Western media won’t normally tell you about this.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ui_qtext_rendered_qtext&quot;&gt;I will guide you through and point you where to look at.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ui_qtext_rendered_qtext&quot;&gt;Here are the coordinates:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ui_qtext_rendered_qtext&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location 1&lt;/strong&gt;: Ningde Bay, Fujian, China (26°43'02.8&quot;N 119°57'45.2&quot;E)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ui_qtext_rendered_qtext&quot;&gt;Our first destination is the coastal area in Fujian province.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_outer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ui_qtext_rendered_qtext&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;landscape ui_qtext_image zoomable_in zoomable_in_feed&quot; src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-be7aa640d5467751fe844ba2fee9fa14&quot; master_src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-906d1f90807f60291c1d46bb513c3beb&quot; master_w=&quot;1747&quot; master_h=&quot;1440&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ui_qtext_rendered_qtext&quot;&gt;If we zoom in, we can find millions of floating houses and cages on the sea surface.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_outer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ui_qtext_rendered_qtext&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;landscape ui_qtext_image zoomable_in zoomable_in_feed&quot; src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-639b06d2fcf908ae3bf2042dc62fb366&quot; master_src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-ea4a1d9d501d7519d7459b83113658f7&quot; master_w=&quot;1769&quot; master_h=&quot;1202&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ui_qtext_rendered_qtext&quot;&gt;If you look around the coastline from Zhejiang province to Guangdong province along the 1000 miles, you can see those floating cages are virtually “everywhere”.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_outer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ui_qtext_rendered_qtext&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;landscape ui_qtext_image zoomable_in zoomable_in_feed&quot; src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-264acc950255539ff22ee97c09eb671a&quot; master_src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-1179bd34e115671da0ba177db476df54&quot; master_w=&quot;1050&quot; master_h=&quot;809&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ui_qtext_rendered_qtext&quot;&gt;What are those? They are actually Chinese “seafood farms”.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_outer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ui_qtext_rendered_qtext&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;landscape ui_qtext_image zoomable_in zoomable_in_feed&quot; src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-a8fa05963b4b2c08b930b3e83979d3c3&quot; master_src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-e0d282eb41b66afbd94b03479f6fbb25&quot; master_w=&quot;1080&quot; master_h=&quot;718&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ui_qtext_rendered_qtext&quot;&gt;Instead of going out to the oceans and catching wild seafood, why not stay in the same place and raise your own seafood? And you can actually make more money with much less effort from raising fish, shrimps, crabs, lobsters, clams, etc.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ui_qtext_rendered_qtext&quot;&gt;It is not just sea or ocean waters that are being farmed, Chinese farmers find any possible open water such as reservoirs, rivers, lakes for farming their seafood/freshwater food.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_outer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ui_qtext_rendered_qtext&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;landscape ui_qtext_image zoomable_in zoomable_in_feed&quot; src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-f1209e8e0087db42d7eea7a20d89df2f&quot; master_src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-7b32e87f8b30b0a9abb9f9db07b9eef1&quot; master_w=&quot;1692&quot; master_h=&quot;1358&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ui_qtext_rendered_qtext&quot;&gt;Imagine each of the cages contains tens of fishes and crabs. That’s A LOT of FISH!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ui_qtext_rendered_qtext&quot;&gt;So how much seafood does China consume?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ui_qtext_rendered_qtext&quot;&gt;It is estimated that the global demand for seafood consumption is 143.8 million tonnes per year and China alone has the largest seafood consumption (&lt;strong&gt;65 million&lt;/strong&gt; tonnes, 45% of global consumption), followed by the European Union (13 million tonnes), Japan (7.4 million tonnes), the United States (7.1 million tonnes) and India (4.8 million tonnes). (Source: &lt;span class=&quot;qlink_container&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ec.europa.eu/jrc/en/news/how-much-fish-do-we-consume-first-global-seafood-consumption-footprint-published%20(https://ec.europa.eu/jrc/en/news/how-much-fish-do-we-consume-first-global-seafood-consumption-footprint-published)&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; onclick=&quot;return Q.openUrl(this, 132745322);&quot; class=&quot;external_link&quot; data-qt-tooltip=&quot;europa.eu&quot;&gt;EU SCIENCE HUB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;As we know, both China and India have a similar population but China consumes &lt;strong&gt;12 times&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;more&lt;/strong&gt; seafood than India, despite the fact that India is in a better geographical position surrounded by warmer oceans in a tropical fishing-rich region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;Among the 65 million tonnes of seafood consumed in China, only 15 million tonnes are caught from the wild, the rest of 50 million tonnes are all raised by aquaculture “farming”. In contrast, 90% of Japanese seafood consumption is from wild catch. Thanks to seafood farming, normal Chinese families can afford cheap seafood in their daily meal. This is a typical family get-together dinner settings: You can see lots of them are seafood!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_outer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;landscape ui_qtext_image zoomable_in zoomable_in_feed&quot; src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-76e9773cfa53092332d54b6726d44ef0&quot; master_src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-7a7d950c9cbd2f3c6967a0748e6af605&quot; master_w=&quot;2048&quot; master_h=&quot;1535&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;This vlog shows how a bigger Chinese family enjoys steamed seafood. The whole table only costs around $120 US dollars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location 2&lt;/strong&gt;: Nanxun, Huzhou, Zhejiang, China (30°46'14.5&quot;N 120°09'02.9&quot;E)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;Our next destination is the vast flood plain of between the Yangtze River, Taihu Lake, and Qiantang River. Thanks to the abundance of fresh water carrying nutrients from the river upstream, this area is so productive that it has raised over 100 million people here. And it is one of the most densely populated areas of China. This area is very similar to the flood plains in Bangladesh, West Bengal in India, Saigon in Vietnam etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;What have the Chinese done differently compared to other densely populated flooded plains in India and Bangladesh?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;Instead of growing rice, the Chinese have been growing a variety of “water food” that can sell at higher prices and makes them become richer than if they were growing rice. If you zoom in, you will find millions of fish ponds instead of rice fields. Besides the fish ponds, you might identify lots of green trees grown around them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_outer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;landscape ui_qtext_image zoomable_in zoomable_in_feed&quot; src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-f3f35c642d7992b7845205c7b21124c2&quot; master_src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-47e0346458267251ba0d8a2e4eb8ba4e&quot; master_w=&quot;1072&quot; master_h=&quot;504&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;These trees are mulberry trees used for silkworm farming. Over the past two thousand years, the Chinese have developed many sophisticated and sustainable agriculture ecosystems around these areas. One most famous eco-cycle is the fish-mulberry tree-silk cycle as shown in the following graph:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_outer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;landscape ui_qtext_image zoomable_in zoomable_in_feed&quot; src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-3e762d66c467d3d713170f9f5f76b85b&quot; master_src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-9e37758b136c7e733ce51be2781a61c2&quot; master_w=&quot;1500&quot; master_h=&quot;1210&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;Chinese farmers have been exploiting the ecosystem in fish, silk farming for thousands of years without knowing the concept of “sustainable development”. Nowadays, it is evolved into multiple cycles of “recycling” on the same land:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_outer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;landscape ui_qtext_image zoomable_in_feed&quot; src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-69ced43ae713e5e9e5be04b1f550b352&quot; master_src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-69ced43ae713e5e9e5be04b1f550b352&quot; master_w=&quot;509&quot; master_h=&quot;446&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;However, in order to raise more fish in the ponds, you need an &lt;strong&gt;aerator&lt;/strong&gt; that pumps air into the water, otherwise, the fishes would not have enough oxygen to breathe. In the following picture, the aerator is the white dot in the centre of each pond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_outer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;landscape ui_qtext_image zoomable_in zoomable_in_feed&quot; src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-9607ced180e69204c61de3a01f3a4190&quot; master_src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-4a504cc75c0c47eeeec08e983bbd8163&quot; master_w=&quot;800&quot; master_h=&quot;533&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;Having an aerator requires every fish pond to be connected to electricity. How to generate electricity for the aerators? Yes, you are right: have solar panels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_outer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;landscape ui_qtext_image zoomable_in zoomable_in_feed&quot; src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-fa325b8fcf0bb5195385ac41ea583444&quot; master_src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-5db047fd1cb1678b9cbd80f3204f210e&quot; master_w=&quot;1000&quot; master_h=&quot;600&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;From Google Earth, you can see that solar panel fish ponds are already taking over some of the traditional mulberry fish ponds in China. Some of the areas in Huzhou area have already installed solar panels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_outer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;landscape ui_qtext_image zoomable_in zoomable_in_feed&quot; src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-50c35db88f981ad0ca22b9e54134c8f2&quot; master_src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-a4af1ad0f3257bcbb317ba807026b74d&quot; master_w=&quot;1488&quot; master_h=&quot;944&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Above picture: The left is the traditional mulberry fish ponds. The right is the latest solar power fish ponds.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;Local fishermen and farmers are actually forced to learn the latest solar technology and sustainable techniques provided by professionals from the local Chinese government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;Why are the local Chinese governments so eager to promote high tech to the local farmers? In order for an official to gain promotion to the next rank, he &lt;em&gt;or she&lt;/em&gt; has to demonstrate their “government performance”. Solar panel fish ponds is one of the best indicators for “promotion” as it fits well in the sustainable development initiative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;From this, you might understand why China has dominated the world’s silk production (84%), and freshwater fish production (66%) and solar energy generation (25.8%). In the Zhejiang, Jiangsu area, rural people eat fish almost every day. Some say that’s why people from these regions are more clever than other regions of China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eco-cycle option 2&lt;/strong&gt;: lotus root - fish&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;In some fish ponds, you can also grow other kinds of vegetables while raising fish. One of the most widely grown vegetables is the &lt;strong&gt;lotus root&lt;/strong&gt;. China lotus root production is 11 million tonnes which accounts for 90% of world production and 60% of the world export. Not only Chinese people like to eat them, but most of the lotus root production is exported to Korea, Japan, and Vietnam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_outer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;landscape ui_qtext_image zoomable_in zoomable_in_feed&quot; src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-e6b48c6a6705e4dd22bc8f767f5d70ff&quot; master_src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-e4c505006b12e0819613d0c3dea90dfa&quot; master_w=&quot;900&quot; master_h=&quot;675&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_outer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;landscape ui_qtext_image zoomable_in zoomable_in_feed&quot; src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-3e55b5ff78c7205b2b4f1c82a41e8a85&quot; master_src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-87eaecf62163c466b4a170f19a63b977&quot; master_w=&quot;800&quot; master_h=&quot;533&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;Lotus roots are one of my favourite vegetables too, I hope China can promote this delicious root for the rest of the world to enjoy as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eco-cycle option 3&lt;/strong&gt;: canola oil - bee- fish &amp;amp; crab&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;You can also grow rapeseed using the same principle. Instead of using fertilizers, at each winter, Chinese farmers dig the “nutrient mud” from the bottom of the water and stack on the bank. And then they grow different plants such as rapeseeds or taros on the mud. After thousands of years of continuous cultivation, the field has become something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_outer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;landscape ui_qtext_image zoomable_in zoomable_in_feed&quot; src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-328e11bebd2f548b916ad151828210b7&quot; master_src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-cceb9749b93694e304ba58858d3065c4&quot; master_w=&quot;900&quot; master_h=&quot;600&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;Location: Duotian(垛田镇), Xinghua, Jiangsu, China 32°56'51.9&quot;N 119°51'50.4&quot;E&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;There are no roads. You can only navigate around using boats. Of course, that is why China is also the leading world producer of rapeseed oil (22% of global production).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;Not to mention the massive &lt;strong&gt;beekeeping&lt;/strong&gt; industry that thrived on the rape flowers in China, China takes over 30% of the global honey production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_outer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;landscape ui_qtext_image zoomable_in zoomable_in_feed&quot; src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-6b7a9199782b18b6890a91ddfb7e5d9b&quot; master_src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-4044f820f8799b11ef033bff8e5feb54&quot; master_w=&quot;1024&quot; master_h=&quot;680&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_outer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;portrait ui_qtext_image zoomable_in_feed&quot; src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-cf89d210da9f033ef36bd602e6bd9b21&quot; master_src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-cf89d210da9f033ef36bd602e6bd9b21&quot; master_w=&quot;282&quot; master_h=&quot;348&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;Actually, one-third of the honey consumed in the US are directly or indirectly from China. To avoid tariffs from the US, Chinese honey exporters would first export their honey to India, Philippines and Malaysia. Then they change labels and alter them to domestic production and sell them to the US. I’m sure this happens to other products too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_outer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;landscape ui_qtext_image zoomable_in_feed&quot; src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-819d43d3eb3066f6e729c7497ee628c9&quot; master_src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-819d43d3eb3066f6e729c7497ee628c9&quot; master_w=&quot;450&quot; master_h=&quot;318&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;qlink_container&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.downtoearth.org.in/coverage/chinese-honey-route-1953&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; onclick=&quot;return Q.openUrl(this, 132745322);&quot; class=&quot;external_link&quot; data-qt-tooltip=&quot;downtoearth.org.in&quot;&gt;https://www.downtoearth.org.in/c...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;qlink_container&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/one-third-of-honey-in-the-us-may-be-an-illegal-and-dangerous-import-from-china-2012-2?IR=T&amp;amp;r=US&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; onclick=&quot;return Q.openUrl(this, 132745322);&quot; class=&quot;external_link&quot; data-qt-tooltip=&quot;businessinsider.com&quot;&gt;One Third Of America's Honey May Be A Dangerous And Illegal Import From China&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;Besides honey, this area is also where the most famous Chinese mitten crabs are produced. They can sell at $60 per kilo, therefore only the middle-class Chinese can afford this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_outer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;landscape ui_qtext_image zoomable_in zoomable_in_feed&quot; src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-3bc959765a680c8442df651c1146b8ef&quot; master_src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-f20d3c3672632b711f6243715f41dad7&quot; master_w=&quot;1024&quot; master_h=&quot;680&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location 3&lt;/strong&gt;: Shouguang, Shandong, China (36°44'15.9&quot;N 118°44'14.7&quot;E)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;Our third destination is the great plain area in Shandong province.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_outer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;portrait ui_qtext_image zoomable_in zoomable_in_feed&quot; src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-037f78e2fded3ae320e9d1ff06109085&quot; master_src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-0c104c4effec66a0981c1d2180772e5a&quot; master_w=&quot;988&quot; master_h=&quot;1156&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;If we zoom in, we can find millions of reflecting “shiny” houses on the plain area. Try looking around, it is “everywhere”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_outer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;landscape ui_qtext_image zoomable_in zoomable_in_feed&quot; src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-3b1dbb3f38fec9298be9f06dfc6c5714&quot; master_src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-bc7fa57ac1690489a99d045bfaf57b21&quot; master_w=&quot;1320&quot; master_h=&quot;1319&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;What are those? They are greenhouses designed to provide regulated and controlled conditions such as temperatures and humidity for vegetables and fruits to grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_outer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;landscape ui_qtext_image zoomable_in zoomable_in_feed&quot; src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-7f01cf29d8dac6b9b5b7db310fceb8a6&quot; master_src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-00718bef91109de8b22b4fa0371c323b&quot; master_w=&quot;900&quot; master_h=&quot;675&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;In the greenhouse, you can grow all kinds of different vegetables and fruits &lt;strong&gt;several times per year&lt;/strong&gt; regardless of the time of the year. That means you can get several times more vegetable and fruit yield compared to a normal field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;For example, you need at least &lt;strong&gt;52 days&lt;/strong&gt; to grow lettuce from seeds until you can harvest them in a greenhouse. That means you can grow &lt;strong&gt;7 times&lt;/strong&gt; each year. That is &lt;strong&gt;7x&lt;/strong&gt; efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_outer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;landscape ui_qtext_image zoomable_in zoomable_in_feed&quot; src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-2221325d0af1112c5b76527805b608c3&quot; master_src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-cad925f7295b7c4c3d687f404bb625e2&quot; master_w=&quot;1000&quot; master_h=&quot;666&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;Therefore greenhouses can significantly improve agriculture output in a limited space, which sounds perfect to the Chinese. Eager for promotion, local Chinese government officials in Northern China have therefore forced their constituency —the local farmers to install greenhouses with loans from the “&lt;em&gt;Chinese Rural Cooperative Bank&lt;/em&gt;”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;What’s worse, they also forced them to install IoT based surveillance system in their greenhouses. Farmers are forced to be taught in a “reeducation camp” to use their mobile phones to monitor the status in the greenhouse including CO2, light strength, soil temperature, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_outer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;landscape ui_qtext_image zoomable_in zoomable_in_feed&quot; src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-6e3f1411ba311452e781a735d43cb95d&quot; master_src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-db8c1276834b8ebab916850b7a75652c&quot; master_w=&quot;797&quot; master_h=&quot;493&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;As a result, according to the Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nation, the vegetable and fruit production and consumption of China is around &lt;strong&gt;700 million&lt;/strong&gt; tonnes, which is 40% of the world consumption. Compared to India (180 million), China achieved 3.8x the amount of vegetable and fruit production, despite most of the population in India claim to be vegetarians, and despite the fact that the arable land in China is less than India. &lt;strong&gt;The secret key is the greenhouse.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;qlink_container&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_largest_producing_countries_of_agricultural_commodities&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; onclick=&quot;return Q.openUrl(this, 132745322);&quot; class=&quot;external_link&quot; data-qt-tooltip=&quot;wikipedia.org&quot;&gt;List of largest producing countries of agricultural commodities - Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;Thanks to greenhouses, Chinese people can enjoy cheaper and a bigger variety of vegetables than any other country in the world all year round. You can check Wikipedia, basically, China &lt;strong&gt;tops the chart in almost every kind of non-tropical vegetable production&lt;/strong&gt;, far outpacing second place. There are vegetables that are not ranked because they are only specific to East Asia, such as the “garlic chives” (韭菜).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_outer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;landscape ui_qtext_image zoomable_in zoomable_in_feed&quot; src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-11d571c68b7ac28cb2b02efe6254ea5c&quot; master_src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-564edb5e74c4fe20c64c20c0d86e05c8&quot; master_w=&quot;1200&quot; master_h=&quot;720&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;Similarly, for fruit production, China &lt;strong&gt;tops the global chart in almost every kind of non-tropical fruit production, far outpacing second place as well.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;I was once pranked and called as “racist” when I invited a black friend over for a summer BBQ with lots of watermelons. I proved my innocence by showing him these statistics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_outer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;landscape ui_qtext_image zoomable_in_feed&quot; src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-59d7bbb6a6938a58b4aa77fa31c89683&quot; master_src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-59d7bbb6a6938a58b4aa77fa31c89683&quot; master_w=&quot;287&quot; master_h=&quot;209&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;In Japan, a watermelon typically costs 2000 yen ($18) and in China, you can afford a much larger watermelon just in 10RMB ($1.5). And watermelons in China are sweeter if they’re grown in Xinjiang. If you love watermelons or any other melons, come to China, especially Kumul in Xinjiang.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location 4:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Lhasa, Tibet, China (29°41'52.3&quot;N 91°09'18.6&quot;E)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;Our fourth destination is also about greenhouses but in Tibet. Use your Google Earth and navigate to any town in Tibet. You will always find greenhouses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_outer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;portrait ui_qtext_image zoomable_in zoomable_in_feed&quot; src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-003e2faefc88de8acef92b62f2907fbc&quot; master_src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-e73f3b3f1d923239ecdd763637df37ce&quot; master_w=&quot;1033&quot; master_h=&quot;1239&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;I mean, the Chinese government has also forced Tibetans to build a massive amount of greenhouses on the Tibetan plateau. Those Tibetans have no time to go to temples for worshipping any more, instead, they have to work in the greenhouses taking care of tomatoes. This is why Dalai Lama is not so happy to hear this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_outer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;landscape ui_qtext_image zoomable_in_feed&quot; src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-a319cf29dfe4b021959079f7169e19a4&quot; master_src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-a319cf29dfe4b021959079f7169e19a4&quot; master_w=&quot;530&quot; master_h=&quot;353&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;As a result, the average vegetable price in Tibet has reduced by 90% over the past decade and they don’t have to import vegetables from nearby provinces anymore. Most of the Tibetans can finally afford to eat watermelons. Who doesn’t like eating watermelons?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;You know that most Tibetans historically only eat yak meat, milk, cheese, and bread? They couldn’t grow anything in such a harsh climate. Only monks could have the luxury to eat vegetables. Now it is the solid proof that the Chinese government didn’t just destroy temples in Tibetan culture but helped them eat vegetables and fruits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location 5&lt;/strong&gt;: Kokdala, Ili, Xinjiang, China 43°43'51.2&quot;N 80°35'21.5&quot;E.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;Kokdala is a city in northern Xinjiang, China, bordering Kazakhstan's Almaty Region to the west. And here is the satellite image of the border between China and Kazakhstan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_outer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;landscape ui_qtext_image zoomable_in zoomable_in_feed&quot; src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-654aa92fe79f0315e6a93aeb77699633&quot; master_src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-7d8391d4a46123c33e1ed1165fd9bae6&quot; master_w=&quot;1003&quot; master_h=&quot;811&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;And you can clearly see there are more green farms on the Chinese side. On Kazakhstan's side, there is nothing but barren lands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_outer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;landscape ui_qtext_image zoomable_in zoomable_in_feed&quot; src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-1ce72c9da784dc7b0d66ac9aa3bb7656&quot; master_src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-2c1242774f8a454d9b214831605ef565&quot; master_w=&quot;1126&quot; master_h=&quot;803&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;And actually, these lands are just wasted land as their soils are too acid and there is limited water to grow any food. You can only count on the water from the melting glaciers in the surrounding mountains. &lt;strong&gt;For people in Kazakhstan, it is too expensive to grow and they don’t have a big market to sell their products&lt;/strong&gt;. That’s why those Kazakhs in Kazakhstan decided not to cultivate on those lands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;On the Chinese side, all the barren lands are cultivated by the special division of the Chinese government: XPCC &lt;span class=&quot;qlink_container&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Xinjiang_Production_and_Construction_Corps&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; onclick=&quot;return Q.openUrl(this, 132745322);&quot; class=&quot;external_link&quot; data-qt-tooltip=&quot;wikipedia.org&quot;&gt;Xinjiang Production and Construction Corps - Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. This is a state enterprise with a military background. XPCC has amassed 2.6 million employees and farmers including Uyghurs and Hans and operate as a giant organisation. Therefore due to its scale, the cost of operation can be reduced and their market can be directly connected to the whole Chinese market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;Since the past three decades, XPCC has been sending its agriculture professionals to &lt;strong&gt;Israel&lt;/strong&gt; every year to learn Israeli’s most advanced agriculture technology in a similar desert climate. Those Chinese students then returned to China and started cultivating those lands using the latest technology such as drip irrigation etc. Once they found those technologies can actually mature into profits, they would sell some of the newly cultivated lands to local Uyghur, Han, and Kazakhs families or hire them directly in the cooperations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;Some of these Uyghurs, Kazakhs are sent to the reeducation camps and they are forced to learn Mandarin Chinese and the latest drip irrigation techniques to save water and reduce costs. Moreover, each village is assigned with one or more communist party members to guide them through to make sure that they don’t mess up the newly cultivated land.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_outer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;landscape ui_qtext_image zoomable_in zoomable_in_feed&quot; src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-5529a780340829707db1d19e544314c7&quot; master_src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-c74f00043548770d04f45c395f38e4b7&quot; master_w=&quot;640&quot; master_h=&quot;480&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;Yes, the drip irrigation technique can significantly reduce water usage and cost. Thanks to the Israeli and domestic Chinese technology, they make the barren land in Xinjiang more and more fertile and productive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_outer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;landscape ui_qtext_image zoomable_in zoomable_in_feed&quot; src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-1b22e1fc45074e012cadaa87e65d1dbd&quot; master_src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-83d7e6eb0cfb8aafe431d297a6850213&quot; master_w=&quot;1024&quot; master_h=&quot;680&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;So what are those people growing on the new land?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;Tomatoes, chillies, melons, grapes, and cotton. All of them can sell higher prices than wheat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_outer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;landscape ui_qtext_image zoomable_in_feed&quot; src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-bb30cf1322f4b334da6841181b16507d&quot; master_src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-bb30cf1322f4b334da6841181b16507d&quot; master_w=&quot;550&quot; master_h=&quot;364&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;Thanks to the strong sunlight and cold nights in Xinjiang, those products are normally sweeter and tastier, so that they can sell for higher prices to the markets in China and the world. In China, people prefer to buy fruits from Xinjiang than the rest of China because of its great taste and quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;Actually, agricultural efficiency is so high in Xinjiang that it produces much more than the Chinese market actually needs. Instead of relying on the “free market” causing the prices to drop and hurt those Uyghur farmers, XPCC, as a state enterprise, is pushing to sell those products to the rest of the world at higher prices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;What if the rest of the country doesn’t want to buy the products?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;The communist XPCC is relying on China’s “superpower” to force those customers from the rest of the world to buy using some terms and conditions that you can’t refuse. &lt;strong&gt;This strategy is learned from the U.S. agricultural business model&lt;/strong&gt;. This is exactly what the US has been doing. And this is what “state capitalism” is about. Whenever Xi Jinping is visiting a country, he is also in charge of selling those products to the country by signing “free trade” agreement using carrots and “implicit sticks”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;If you are not convinced, let us move to the next location for more proof:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location 6&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Hejing, Bayingol, Xinjiang, China 42°18'36.1&quot;N 86°36'15.4&quot;E&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_outer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;landscape ui_qtext_image zoomable_in zoomable_in_feed&quot; src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-aa204c0ced8436193329eecd6d6c38c1&quot; master_src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-f161792c46436cbc3ec0878c01b28ef7&quot; master_w=&quot;832&quot; master_h=&quot;802&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;What are those “red” lands in the middle of the desert?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_outer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;landscape ui_qtext_image zoomable_in zoomable_in_feed&quot; src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-6170ec2c7f36f2a3a777028a0940152f&quot; master_src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-94e8c2247bc6cef22467ab52965c1cb0&quot; master_w=&quot;900&quot; master_h=&quot;478&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;If we zoom in, you can see it is actually the land of “tomatoes” — billions of tomatoes. You can imagine the amount by measuring the total area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_outer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;landscape ui_qtext_image zoomable_in zoomable_in_feed&quot; src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-c4999d906a3f969fb0c4ddbb6c992a92&quot; master_src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-ac0dd9112456b1431969ad95e5b76f3a&quot; master_w=&quot;1200&quot; master_h=&quot;868&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_outer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;landscape ui_qtext_image zoomable_in_feed&quot; src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-dee8b2b8674b40e6fcfefc3533111816&quot; master_src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-dee8b2b8674b40e6fcfefc3533111816&quot; master_w=&quot;409&quot; master_h=&quot;271&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;Next time you enjoy Italian spaghetti, Turkish kebab, or spreading Heinz ketchup on your chips, think about that, you might be eat tomatoes from Xinjiang. It might not directly say the tomatoes are from Xinjiang. These tomatoes might be first exported to a third country and get rebranded just like the honey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;qlink_container&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.farwestchina.com/blog/your-ketchup-probably-came-from-xinjiang/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; onclick=&quot;return Q.openUrl(this, 132745322);&quot; class=&quot;external_link&quot; data-qt-tooltip=&quot;farwestchina.com&quot;&gt;Your Ketchup Probably Came from Xinjiang | Xinjiang: Far West China&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;China produces 56.3 million tonnes of tomatoes and dominates the world’s 1/3 tomato exports. Over &lt;strong&gt;14 million&lt;/strong&gt; are from Xinjiang. You can verify this by looking at the global top ten ketchup companies &lt;span class=&quot;qlink_container&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldatlas.com/articles/which-are-the-world-s-leading-tomato-producing-countries.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; onclick=&quot;return Q.openUrl(this, 132745322);&quot; class=&quot;external_link&quot; data-qt-tooltip=&quot;worldatlas.com&quot;&gt;The World's Leading Producers of Tomatoes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;COFCO Group (China) 2nd&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Xinjiang Chalkis Co. Ltd (China) 3rd&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fuyuan Agriculture Products Limited (China) 6th&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Heinz (United States) 7th&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Xinjiang Tianye Co., Ltd. (China) 15th&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;These companies are more or less the redistributors from the XPCC and the Chinese government. These companies can actually return most of the profits back to the Xinjiang farmers. And just recently the Chinese government is trying to sell Xinjiang tomatoes to eastern Europe through the one belt one road initiative. As Xi Jinping just visited Italy this March 2019, I am not sure whether Italy is interested in Xinjiang’s tomatos or not after Xi Jinping’s visit at this time. The western media will never tell you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;Besides tomatoes and chillis, China is also the largest producer of grapes, accounting for 19.1% of global production. And the most and the best of grapes are from Turpan, Xinjiang. However, China really sucks at making wines from grapes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_outer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;landscape ui_qtext_image zoomable_in zoomable_in_feed&quot; src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-e5da19256a0c1744cf19e4c0c67941cb&quot; master_src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-77aeb07860c4216826ead1be716446cc&quot; master_w=&quot;1024&quot; master_h=&quot;683&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;qtext_hr&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;Finally, let’s talk about the main crops such as &lt;strong&gt;rice, wheat,&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;corns&lt;/strong&gt; in China. They are the most important food of all, not only to human beings but also to animals such as pigs, chickens, and cattle that produce meat and milk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;Here is a simple comparison between the top four producers across the world:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;Arable Land: China 1086 India 1579 EU 1091 US 1631 (1000 km2)&lt;br/&gt;Rice: China 208.1 India 169.5 EU 3.1 US 9.2 (million tonnes)&lt;br/&gt;Wheat: China 134.3 India 98.5 EU 150.2 US 47.3 (million tonnes)&lt;br/&gt;Corn: China 257.3 India 26.0 EU 60.9 US 366.2 (million tonnes)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;As you can see, China is an all-around top crop producer compared to the other three regions. However, for a population of 1.4 billion, this is enough to be “filling” but still far from enough if the Chinese want to achieve similar “well-fed” status in per-capita consumption in terms of the developed country standard just like the EU and US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;Currently, there is just not enough arable land for China to produce enough crops to raise 1.4 billion people to the well-fed status. And what’s worse, &lt;strong&gt;the arable land in China is quickly shrinking&lt;/strong&gt; as more and more land has been used for industries and cities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location 7&lt;/strong&gt;: Xingtai, Hebei, China 37°35'54.1&quot;N 114°55'20.8&quot;E&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;To show you how the Chinese were quickly using up their precious land, our next destination is the great northern plain of China. This is where the most crops are grown in China. (Picture scale: top to bottom 1500km)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_outer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;portrait ui_qtext_image zoomable_in zoomable_in_feed&quot; src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-ff37066f9f92ed8da468a249131e5ce2&quot; master_src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-c4335e03539ca9528f39f5ccecd298e4&quot; master_w=&quot;1025&quot; master_h=&quot;1198&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;If we zoom in to any location in the plain, for example, the Xingtai city, a 4th tier city, a “small” city with 7 million people. (Picture scale: top to bottom 60km).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_outer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;landscape ui_qtext_image zoomable_in zoomable_in_feed&quot; src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-014ec48287096a27ffa9823f06d26acd&quot; master_src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-c4e008e3872e74cf35b4114046b9f979&quot; master_w=&quot;1726&quot; master_h=&quot;1305&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;This is actually quite scary to many people. The green fields are the farmlands. These white dots are actually villages. Each “dot” contains around 500 people. The larger white regions are towns with around 10k to 100k people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;As you can see, as more and more people are getting rich and building large houses on the farmlands, those green land would be running out gradually. It is estimated that China is losing around 3,000 km2 area of arable land every year. Those arable land would be turned into “white” and dead concrete land. This is obviously a disaster and the Chinese government has been trying every effort to regulate the land uses. However, you just can’t control the huge momentum of “urbanisation” so easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location 8&lt;/strong&gt;: Qingyang, Gansu, China 35°41'00.7&quot;N 107°40'38.3&quot;E&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;The lack of arable land has been a “top concern” ever since the CCP has governed China. From the era of Mao Zedong, the CCP has been organising massive cultivations on hilly lands on different parts of China. There are countless examples. Here is the most significant one: &lt;strong&gt;Loess Plateau&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_outer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;landscape ui_qtext_image zoomable_in zoomable_in_feed&quot; src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-d574428e76bf8f2f80de4bb117a8532c&quot; master_src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-9856618856ac719d69eb93f96e8df1de&quot; master_w=&quot;1516&quot; master_h=&quot;1390&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;This 640,000 km² plateau is actually not suitable for growing crops. But if you zoom in, you can see all the valleys, all the hills are converted to arable lands. From above, all the cultivated lands appeared like “roots”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_outer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;portrait ui_qtext_image zoomable_in zoomable_in_feed&quot; src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-3cc823826cf68c727544e84a52efdfc0&quot; master_src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-d74d2c60aabf8f5c06c04f63bcd30259&quot; master_w=&quot;1313&quot; master_h=&quot;1331&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;Just zoom in to any place, you would find all the hills are converted to terraces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_outer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;landscape ui_qtext_image zoomable_in zoomable_in_feed&quot; src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-d5236690d8151db5b8c5cd131d955c2f&quot; master_src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-e0609d744a8b2235bc89a242497d6c8f&quot; master_w=&quot;1200&quot; master_h=&quot;616&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;However, people have found that creating too much terraced land would cause land degradation and destructive mudslide during the monsoon season. From year 1999, the CCP realised that its previous massive cultivation campaign does not improve crop production significantly but instead has caused many floods and mudslides, then it halted the cultivation and proposed the “Returning Farmland to Forest Program (退耕还林)” campaign.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;For those lands with low yield, farmers are forced to give up their land and they have to grow trees on them. &lt;strong&gt;And for the farmers who lost the land, the government would compensate the farmers with a fee that is equivalent to the field earnings&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_outer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;portrait ui_qtext_image zoomable_in zoomable_in_feed&quot; src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-96c38a51c7964c2e8543ad52ea8876f7&quot; master_src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-686b98140443e2863c7dec39900e5edd&quot; master_w=&quot;696&quot; master_h=&quot;878&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;The above picture shows the impact of the forestation and afforestation. This is proof that after many lessons, the CCP has gradually grasped the key to sustainable development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;Xi Jinping once said: “China highly values ecological and environmental protection. Guided by the conviction that lucid waters and lush mountains are invaluable assets, the country advocates harmonious coexistence between humans and nature, and sticks to the path of green and sustainable development.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_outer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;landscape ui_qtext_image zoomable_in zoomable_in_feed&quot; src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-5ba288a9e3fdd57a5e7dc79ad64a1b8a&quot; master_src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-c568c1c7036cbaabf4326b47f8f8c8a0&quot; master_w=&quot;1430&quot; master_h=&quot;504&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;These are not empty words. Every “word” is backed by actual actions. Many people outside China may wonder why mainland Chinese still prefer Xi Jinping. One of the reasons is that he restructured the old bureaucracy of China to be more “environment focused”. For example, the local environmental officials now have the authority to impeach local mayors if the region has done badly in sustainable development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;The outcome of “Returning Farmland to Forest Program” is definitely causing the reduction of the arable land in China. However, despite the arable land degradation, thanks to the huge investment in agriculture technology, agriculture efficiency still improves, making its domestic crop production still increase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;One example is the new technology that allows you to grow rice using salty sea water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_outer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;landscape ui_qtext_image zoomable_in_feed&quot; src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-b4b6e98afef978c22e98fae2b8831e85&quot; master_src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-b4b6e98afef978c22e98fae2b8831e85&quot; master_w=&quot;590&quot; master_h=&quot;357&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;qlink_container&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/yuan-longping-chinese-rice-scientist-growing-saltwater-rice-2017-11&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; onclick=&quot;return Q.openUrl(this, 132745322);&quot; class=&quot;external_link&quot; data-qt-tooltip=&quot;businessinsider.com&quot;&gt;An 87-year-old scientist may have just unlocked the secret to growing rice in saltwater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;qlink_container&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.independent.co.uk/news/rice-seawater-chinese-scientists-food-200-million-a8017971.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; onclick=&quot;return Q.openUrl(this, 132745322);&quot; class=&quot;external_link&quot; data-qt-tooltip=&quot;independent.co.uk&quot;&gt;Chinese scientists may have just found a new way to feed 200 million people&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;Despite the domestic crop production increase, China is still not self-sustainable in terms of rice, wheat, and corn. It has to import 10% of its annual consumption from the rest of the world. However, most of them are not directly for human consumption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;Example 1: &lt;strong&gt;Beer and Baijiu production&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_outer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;landscape ui_qtext_image zoomable_in zoomable_in_feed&quot; src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-a02117fd2d57db18e5498bc80a7917b3&quot; master_src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-4efc9f3c2a683bbff27254827f013912&quot; master_w=&quot;750&quot; master_h=&quot;422&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;Since 2006, China has become the world's largest producer of beer with 46.5438 million kiloliters, which is more than double that of the US. It has increased production by 4.9% annually. Besides wheat, China has to import most of the hop plant for beers from Germany and the USA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;And China is also the world’s leading producer of spirit alcohol. Most Chinese people don’t favor Whiskey or Vodka, but prefer drinking Baiju, which is more fragrant and rich in flavour. The Baiju production is around 13.6 million kiloliters, which is much more than western people consume. And the local rice wine made by individual Chinese households is not even counted!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_outer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;landscape ui_qtext_image zoomable_in_feed&quot; src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-97e85c7bab3a814f2be6007e4ba58e81&quot; master_src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-97e85c7bab3a814f2be6007e4ba58e81&quot; master_w=&quot;580&quot; master_h=&quot;403&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;As a result, some parts of China has a much heavier drinking culture that the rest of the world is not even aware of. Let me tell you. It is much heavier than the British and the Russians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;Example 2: &lt;strong&gt;Pig and pork production&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_outer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;landscape ui_qtext_image zoomable_in zoomable_in_feed&quot; src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-2a806b4312b8172290fb7d500975894b&quot; master_src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-1df4ea55eb4281df84b13d4ad6024998&quot; master_w=&quot;668&quot; master_h=&quot;573&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Global pork production&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;The above graph just shows how do the Chinese love pork so much. Some of the pigs raised in China fed on the corns imported from the USA and Brazil. This also applies to the chickens, cattle and other animals raised in China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;China is able to provide enough food more than just plain rice or wheat. The variety of food offered on the Chinese table is much more diverse and cheaper than most developed places in the world. This applies to “poor people” as well. This is based on my personal experiences and observations after traveling from many countries in Europe, the US, and Japan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;For example, in China, a group of eight people can sit at a round table, enjoying 20 different dishes including different meats, vegetables, desserts etc. They don’t have to worry about religious restrictions, allergic concerns, and personal spaces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_outer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;landscape ui_qtext_image zoomable_in zoomable_in_feed&quot; src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-ee1858048772b38ce994d860f532c3ee&quot; master_src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-4dc7ccab217b02a1703d390aaaf70e3f&quot; master_w=&quot;2560&quot; master_h=&quot;1600&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;In Shandong, the total dinner costs around $50. The same set of 20 dishes could cost $150 in Beijing/Shanghai/Taipei or $300 in California/Japan/Hong Kong etc. And we are not counting the beers and drinks. Actually, most people in California/Japan don’t have the luxury to enjoy 20 different dishes at all but it is more than common in China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;After this extremely long post, I hope you learned something new about China and also know how the Chinese can feed themselves more than just “enough”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr u-text-align--start&quot;&gt;Thanks for reading :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 18:59:17 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>carapace</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.quora.com/How-is-China-able-to-provide-enough-food-to-feed-its-population-of-over-1-billion-people-Do-they-import-food-or-are-they-self-sustainable?share=1</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>IRS sends warning letters to more than 10k cryptocurrency holders</title>
<link>https://www.wsj.com/articles/irs-sending-warning-letters-to-more-than-10-000-cryptocurrency-holders-11564159523?mod=rsswn</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.wsj.com/articles/irs-sending-warning-letters-to-more-than-10-000-cryptocurrency-holders-11564159523?mod=rsswn</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;is-lead-inset&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div data-layout=&quot;header&amp;#10;              &quot; data-layout-mobile=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&amp;#10;        media-object&amp;#10;        type-InsetMediaIllustration&amp;#10;          header&amp;#10;  article__inset&amp;#10;        article__inset--type-InsetMediaIllustration&amp;#10;          article__inset--lead&amp;#10;  &quot;&gt;
      
      
          
    &lt;figure class=&quot;media-object-image enlarge-image renoImageFormat- img-header article__inset__image&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot;&gt;&lt;div data-mobile-ratio=&quot;66.66666666666666%&quot; data-layout-ratio=&quot;66.66666666666666%&quot; data-subtype=&quot;photo&quot; class=&quot;image-container  responsive-media article__inset__image__image&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img srcset=&quot;https://images.wsj.net/im-93324?width=140&amp;amp;size=1.5 140w,&amp;#10;https://images.wsj.net/im-93324?width=540&amp;amp;size=1.5 540w,&amp;#10;https://images.wsj.net/im-93324?width=620&amp;amp;size=1.5 620w,&amp;#10;https://images.wsj.net/im-93324?width=700&amp;amp;size=1.5 700w,&amp;#10;https://images.wsj.net/im-93324?width=860&amp;amp;size=1.5 860w,&amp;#10;https://images.wsj.net/im-93324?width=1260&amp;amp;size=1.5 1260w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 140px) 100px,&amp;#10;(max-width: 540px) 500px,&amp;#10;(max-width: 620px) 580px,&amp;#10;(max-width: 700px) 660px,&amp;#10;(max-width: 860px) 820px,&amp;#10;1260px&quot; src=&quot;https://images.wsj.net/im-93324?width=620&amp;amp;size=1.5&quot; data-enlarge=&quot;https://images.wsj.net/im-93324?width=1260&amp;amp;size=1.5&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;In the letters, tax officials warned about penalties for failing to report income and pay...&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
      &lt;figcaption class=&quot;wsj-article-caption article__inset__image__caption&quot; itemprop=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;wsj-article-caption-content&quot;&gt;In the letters, tax officials warned about penalties for failing to report income and pay tax on transactions involving virtual currencies.&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;span class=&quot;wsj-article-credit article__inset__image__caption__credit&quot; itemprop=&quot;creator&quot;&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;wsj-article-credit-tag&quot;&gt;
              Photo: 
            &lt;/span&gt;
        Zach Gibson/Getty Images
          &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt; 
    &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;clearfix byline-wrap&quot;&gt;


      
      &lt;div class=&quot;byline article__byline&quot;&gt;
      
      
          &lt;span&gt;By&lt;/span&gt;
              &lt;div class=&quot;author mobile-scrim hasMenu&quot; data-scrim=&quot;{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;author&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;header&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Laura Saunders&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;subhead&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;The Wall Street Journal&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;list&amp;quot;:[{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;bio&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.wsj.com/news/author/6491&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Biography&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;twitter&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://twitter.com/SaundersWSJ&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;@SaundersWSJ&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;facebook&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://facebook.com/&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;email&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;mailto:Laura.Saunders@wsj.com&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Laura.Saunders@wsj.com&amp;quot;}]}&quot;&gt;
                  &lt;span class=&quot;name&quot; itemprop=&quot;name&quot;&gt;Laura Saunders&lt;/span&gt; and 
                  &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;author  hasMenu&quot; data-scrim=&quot;{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;author&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;header&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Britton O’Daly&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;subhead&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;The Wall Street Journal&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;list&amp;quot;:[]}&quot;&gt;
                  &lt;span itemprop=&quot;name&quot;&gt;Britton O’Daly&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;

      &lt;/div&gt;
      
        &lt;time class=&quot;timestamp article__timestamp flexbox__flex--1&quot;&gt;
          Updated July 26, 2019 6:39 pm ET
        &lt;/time&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  

  &lt;div class=&quot;article-content &quot;&gt;

      &lt;p&gt;The Internal Revenue Service has begun sending letters to more than 10,000 cryptocurrency holders, warning they may have broken federal tax laws.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;The agency wasn’t specific about the possible violations it was reviewing, but those who hold digital currencies could be subject to a variety of taxes, especially on capital gains.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;div class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Taxpayers should take these letters very seriously. The IRS is expanding efforts involving virtual currency,” IRS Commissioner Chuck Rettig said.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;The agency expects its mailing to be completed by the end of August. Three variations of the letter are being sent, depending on the information the IRS has about the recipient.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;The IRS letters come as bitcoin, the world’s most popular cryptocurrency, has ridden a new wave of optimism in recent months. In mid-July, bitcoin topped $12,000, more than three times its value at the end of 2018. Investors, speculators and Facebook Inc. have extolled the potential of digital currencies. &lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;At the same time, use by drug dealers and other nefarious actors has marred its reputation. The IRS has expressed worries about the ability of digital currencies to promote tax evasion.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;An IRS spokesman declined to say how it learned about the targeted cryptocurrency holders and their transactions. &lt;/p&gt;






      &lt;div data-layout=&quot;wrap&amp;#10;              &quot; data-layout-mobile=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&amp;#10;        media-object&amp;#10;        type-InsetRichText&amp;#10;          wrap&amp;#10;    scope-web&amp;#10;  article__inset&amp;#10;        article__inset--type-InsetRichText&amp;#10;            article__inset--wrap&amp;#10;  &quot;&gt;
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
          &lt;div class=&quot;media-object-rich-text&quot;&gt;
    	

&lt;h4&gt;Share Your Thoughts&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;em&gt;Do you think government should tax profits bitcoin trades? Join the conversation below.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      &lt;/div&gt; 




      &lt;p&gt;One possible source is information provided to the agency by cryptocurrency exchange Coinbase. In mid-March of 2018, Coinbase provided data—under a federal-court order—on about 13,000 accounts as requested by the IRS. &lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;Coinbase turned over data on customers who bought, sold, sent or received digital currency worth $20,000 or more between 2013 and 2015. &lt;br/&gt;The data included the customer’s name, taxpayer identification number, birth date and address, plus account statements and the names of counterparties.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;A representative for Coinbase declined to comment.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;“In terms of the actual people who have crypto capital gains, most of them are not prepared because they have not been filing crypto taxes based on conversations with thousands of our users” said Chandan Lodha, chief executive and co-founder of CoinTracker, a digital-currency tax software company.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;Mr. Lodha said that many cryptocurrency exchanges weren’t built to provide users with transaction histories. Without such histories, investors would have had to keep track of their transactions by hand.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;“This is a problem that people should have been paying attention to for a long time,” he said. &lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;The sternest version of the letter, released Friday, asks recipients who believe they have followed the law to sign a statement declaring, under penalty of perjury, that they are in compliance with tax laws.&lt;/p&gt;




      




      &lt;p&gt;It also says the recipient should understand the IRS may be in touch with them.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;The two other versions of the letter are less threatening. The mildest warns that the recipient “may not know the requirements for reporting transactions involving virtual currency” and then details them.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;Tax professionals warned that the letters shouldn’t be ignored.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;They say it is usually far better, and less expensive in the end, to go to the IRS and attempt to rectify past mistakes. By sending the letters, the agency put people on notice that they are already in its sights.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;Jimmy Song, a cryptocurrency investor who teaches a course on bitcoin at the University of Texas at Austin, said he heard rumblings about a potential crackdown on Twitter this week. &lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;The new enforcement “doesn’t feel good,” Mr. Song said. “It seems like an intrusive way to get people to pay and I personally don’t like it because I’m a libertarian and many people who own this are.”&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;According to an IRS spokesman, there is no explicit requirement that many cryptocurrency sales be reported to the agency by third parties. Sales of stock shares must generally be reported on Form 1099-B to the IRS by the brokerage firm.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;Among the possible taxes: If an investor sells a cryptocurrency after holding it longer than a year, the profits are typically long-term capital gains. &lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;The tax rate is 0%, 15%, or 20%, plus a 3.8% surtax in some cases, depending on the owner’s total income.&lt;/p&gt;






      &lt;div data-layout=&quot;header&amp;#10;              &quot; data-layout-mobile=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&amp;#10;        media-object&amp;#10;        type-InsetMediaVideo&amp;#10;          header&amp;#10;    scope-web|mobileapps&amp;#10;  article__inset&amp;#10;        article__inset--type-InsetMediaVideo&amp;#10;            article__inset--header&amp;#10;  &quot;&gt;
      
      
      
          &lt;figure class=&quot;media-object-video article__inset__video media-object-video--standard&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;wsj-article-caption article__inset__video__caption&quot;&gt;
            an original WSJ documentary, markets reporter Steven Russolillo ventures Japan and Hong Kong explore universe His mission: create WSJCoin, virtual token for newspaper industry. Image: Crystal Tai. Video: Clément Bürge
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt; 




      &lt;p&gt;In general, the IRS has until three years after a return’s due date to assess a deficiency, but that limit expands to six years if income is understated by more than 25%.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;There are many exceptions, however. For example, the statute of limitations doesn’t start to run until a tax return is filed, and there is no time limit to bring civil fraud charges.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt; When it comes to preparing tax returns involving cryptocurrencies, Darren Neuschwander, a certified public accountant, said many tax preparers are frustrated because the IRS has long promised new guidance on cryptocurrencies that it hasn’t yet released.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;“It’s ironic that the IRS is issuing these letters because we’re still waiting to know more rules,” he said. &lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Write to &lt;/strong&gt;Laura Saunders at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:laura.saunders@wsj.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;icon &quot;&gt;laura.saunders@wsj.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;/div&gt;



  
  &lt;p&gt;Copyright ©2019 Dow Jones &amp;amp; Company, Inc. All Rights Reserved. 87990cbe856818d5eddac44c7b1cdeb8&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;/div&gt;


    &lt;p class=&quot;printheadline&quot;&gt;
      Appeared in the July 27, 2019, print edition as 'IRS Warns Holders of Digital Currencies.'
    &lt;/p&gt;




</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 17:02:39 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rememberlenny</dc:creator>
<og:title>IRS Sending Warning Letters to More Than 10,000 Cryptocurrency Holders</og:title>
<og:description>The Internal Revenue Service has begun sending letters to more than 10,000 cryptocurrency holders, warning about penalties for failing to report income and pay tax on transactions involving virtual currencies.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.wsj.com/articles/irs-sending-warning-letters-to-more-than-10-000-cryptocurrency-holders-11564159523</og:url>
<og:image>https://images.wsj.net/im-93324/social</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.wsj.com/articles/irs-sending-warning-letters-to-more-than-10-000-cryptocurrency-holders-11564159523?mod=rsswn</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>