<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>U.S. Navy bans TikTok from government-issued mobile devices</title>
<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-tiktok-navy/u-s-navy-bans-tiktok-from-government-issued-mobile-devices-idUSKBN1YO2HU</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-tiktok-navy/u-s-navy-bans-tiktok-from-government-issued-mobile-devices-idUSKBN1YO2HU</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;PrimaryAsset_container&quot; readability=&quot;7.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Image_container&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;LazyImage_container LazyImage_dark&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s2.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;amp;d=20191220&amp;amp;t=2&amp;amp;i=1466648848&amp;amp;r=LYNXMPEFBJ1VF&amp;amp;w=20&quot; aria-label=&quot;FILE PHOTO: TikTok logo is displayed on the smartphone while standing on the U.S. flag in this illustration picture taken, November 8, 2019. REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/File Photo&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;FILE PHOTO: TikTok logo is displayed on the smartphone while standing on the U.S. flag in this illustration picture taken, November 8, 2019. REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/File Photo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Reuters) - Earlier this week the United States Navy banned the social media app TikTok from government-issued mobile devices, saying the popular short video app represented a “cybersecurity threat.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A bulletin issued by the Navy on Tuesday showed up on a Facebook page serving military members, saying users of government issued mobile devices who had TikTok and did not remove the app would be blocked from the Navy Marine Corps Intranet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Navy would not describe in detail what dangers the app presents, but Pentagon spokesman Lieutenant Colonel Uriah Orland said in a statement the order was part of an effort to “address existing and emerging threats”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TikTok did not return a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TikTok is hugely popular with U.S. teenagers, but has come under scrutiny from U.S. regulators and lawmakers in recent months. The U.S. government has opened a national security review of the app’s owner Beijing ByteDance Technology Co’s $1 billion acquisition of U.S. social media app Musical.ly, Reuters first reported last month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last month, U.S army cadets were instructed not to use TikTok, after Senator Chuck Schumer raised security concerns about the army using TikTok in their recruiting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Navy spokesman said Naval and Marine personnel who use government issued smart devices are generally allowed to use popular commercial apps, including common social media apps, but from time to time specific programs that present security threats are banned. He would not give examples of apps that are allowed or those considered unsafe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Pentagon’s Orland said the “Cyber Awareness Message” sent Dec. 16 “identifies the potential risk associated with using the TikTok app and directs appropriate action for employees to take in order to safeguard their personal information.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Attribution_container&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Attribution_attribution&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Attribution_content&quot;&gt;Reporting by Michael M.B. Pell and Echo Wang in New York; editing by Grant McCool&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;StandardArticleBody_trustBadgeContainer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;StandardArticleBody_trustBadgeTitle&quot;&gt;Our Standards:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;trustBadgeUrl&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thomsonreuters.com/en/about-us/trust-principles.html&quot;&gt;The Thomson Reuters Trust Principles.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2019 15:43:36 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>swat535</dc:creator>
<og:title>U.S. Navy bans TikTok from government-issued mobile devices</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-tiktok-navy-idUSKBN1YO2HU</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Earlier this week the United States Navy banned the social media app TikTok from...</og:description>
<og:image>https://s2.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;d=20191220&amp;t=2&amp;i=1466648848&amp;w=1200&amp;r=LYNXMPEFBJ1VF</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-tiktok-navy/u-s-navy-bans-tiktok-from-government-issued-mobile-devices-idUSKBN1YO2HU</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Free and Open-Source Mathematics Textbooks</title>
<link>http://dcernst.github.io/resources/free-and-open-source-textbooks/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://dcernst.github.io/resources/free-and-open-source-textbooks/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;container&quot; readability=&quot;5.0363708504166&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot; readability=&quot;6.1057768924303&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-xs-12 col-sm-12 col-md-8 col-lg-9&quot; readability=&quot;8.8473080317741&quot;&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;breadcrumb&quot;&gt;&lt;li/&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;active&quot;&gt;Textbooks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here is a (partial) list of free and/or open-source textbooks. If you find one of these more helpful than another, please &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:dana.ernst@nau.edu&quot;&gt;let me know&lt;/a&gt;. Also, take a peek at &lt;a href=&quot;http://buzzard.ups.edu&quot;&gt;Rob Beezer’s&lt;/a&gt; selection on &lt;a href=&quot;http://linear.ups.edu/curriculum.html&quot;&gt;this page&lt;/a&gt;. Moreover, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aimath.org&quot;&gt;American Institute of Mathematics&lt;/a&gt; maintains a list of &lt;a href=&quot;http://aimath.org/textbooks/approved-textbooks/&quot;&gt;approved open-source textbooks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;calculus&quot;&gt;Calculus&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apexcalculus.com&quot;&gt;APEX Calclus&lt;/a&gt; is an open-source textbook by a group of faculty from Virginia Military Institute. It has the look and feel of a traditional calculus (e.g., Stewart’s &lt;em&gt;Calculus&lt;/em&gt;). Includes interactive 3D graphics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mooculus.osu.edu/handouts&quot;&gt;MOOCulus Textbook&lt;/a&gt; is a free textbook from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://mooculus.osu.edu/&quot;&gt;MOOCulus&lt;/a&gt; folks at Ohio State University. This text is mostly an adaptation of the Community Calculus text listed below.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://communitycalculus.org&quot;&gt;Community Calculus&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;http://skink.whitman.edu/~guichard/&quot;&gt;David Guichard&lt;/a&gt; (Whitman College). This one is also available as a free PDF. You can also purchase a very inexpensive hardcopy from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lulu.com/spotlight/whitmancalculus&quot;&gt;Lulu&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://faculty.gvsu.edu/boelkinm/Home/Download.html&quot;&gt;Active Calculus&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;http://faculty.gvsu.edu/boelkinm/Home/MB.html&quot;&gt;Matt Boelkins&lt;/a&gt; (Grand Valley State College). This is one of the newer additions to the list of free calculus texts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ocw.mit.edu/resources/res-18-001-calculus-online-textbook-spring-2005/textbook/&quot;&gt;Calculus&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www-math.mit.edu/~gs/&quot;&gt;Gilbert Strang&lt;/a&gt; (MIT). This book is available as a free PDF from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://ocw.mit.edu/index.htm&quot;&gt;MIT Open Courseware Project&lt;/a&gt;. There are also some corresponding videos, which can be found &lt;a href=&quot;http://ocw.mit.edu/high-school/courses/highlights-of-calculus/index.htm&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.math.umn.edu/~garrett/calculus/&quot;&gt;Calculus Refresher&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.math.umn.edu/~garrett/index.shtml&quot;&gt;Paul Garrett&lt;/a&gt; (University of Minnesota). Another free PDF. This short book seems designed for students who have had some experience with calculus and need some review.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.math.upenn.edu/~ghrist/FLCT/index.html&quot;&gt;Funny Little Calculus Text&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.math.upenn.edu/~ghrist/index.html&quot;&gt;Robert Ghrist&lt;/a&gt; (University of Pennsylvania). Currently only first semester calculus, very short, and no exercises, but a free PDF.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://tutorial.math.lamar.edu/&quot;&gt;Paul’s Online Math Notes&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.math.lamar.edu/faculty/dawkins/dawkins.aspx&quot;&gt;Paul Dawkins&lt;/a&gt; (Lamar University). Paul’s notes cover Calculus 1-3, Linear Algebra, and more. The notes are available as free HTML-based material. These notes seem to be popular with students.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://wdjoyner.com/teach/calc1-sage/&quot;&gt;Differential Calculus with Sage&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;http://wdjoyner.com/&quot;&gt;David Joyner&lt;/a&gt; (United States Naval Academy) and Granville. This free book is available as either a PDF or in HTML form. The book covers first semester calculus and incorporates &lt;a href=&quot;http://sagemath.org&quot;&gt;Sage&lt;/a&gt;, which is an open-source mathematics software package.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://boxen.math.washington.edu/home/wdj/teaching/calc2-sage/&quot;&gt;Integral Calculus with Sage&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;http://scidiv.bellevuecollege.edu/dh/&quot;&gt;Dale Hoffman&lt;/a&gt; (Bellevue Community College), &lt;a href=&quot;http://modular.math.washington.edu/&quot;&gt;William Stein&lt;/a&gt; (University of Washington), and &lt;a href=&quot;http://wdjoyner.com/&quot;&gt;David Joyner&lt;/a&gt; (United States Naval Academy). The book picks up where the previous book left off.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://scidiv.bellevuecollege.edu/dh/Calculus_all/Calculus_all.html&quot;&gt;Contemporary Calculus&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;http://scidiv.bellevuecollege.edu/dh/&quot;&gt;Dale Hoffman&lt;/a&gt; (Bellevue Community College). A free online calculus text that is being developed for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://opencourselibrary.org&quot;&gt;Open Course Library Project of the Washington State Colleges&lt;/a&gt;. This book is part of the foundation for the previous book. It covers three semesters of calculus and seems to do a thorough job of it, but the formatting is awful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;differential-equations&quot;&gt;Differential Equations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;discrete-mathematics&quot;&gt;Discrete Mathematics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;introduction-to-proof&quot;&gt;Introduction to Proof&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;linear-algebra&quot;&gt;Linear Algebra&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;combinatorics&quot;&gt;Combinatorics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;abstract-algebra&quot;&gt;Abstract Algebra&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;real-analysis&quot;&gt;Real Analysis&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2019 12:55:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>vo2maxer</dc:creator>
<og:title>Free and Open-Source Textbooks</og:title>
<og:description>Mathematics, Teaching, &amp; Technology</og:description>
<og:url>http://dcernst.github.io/resources/free-and-open-source-textbooks/</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://danaernst.com/resources/free-and-open-source-textbooks/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Deep Sea</title>
<link>https://neal.fun/deep-sea/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://neal.fun/deep-sea/</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://neal.fun/deep-sea/&quot;&gt;https://neal.fun/deep-sea/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=21850527&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=21850527&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 294&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 49&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2019 09:34:57 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Yuval_Halevi</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://neal.fun/deep-sea/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Monica: Open-source personal CRM</title>
<link>https://www.monicahq.com/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.monicahq.com/</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;28.477477477477&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;f2 normal tc-ns&quot;&gt;Monica empowers people who want to be better&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;measure lh-copy center-ns&quot;&gt;Monica is for people who have jobs, a family, and are busy trying to find a good work/life balance. So busy, that they don’t have time anymore to remember to call a friend, say happy birthday to a nephew, or remember to invite someone special for dinner next week. The older we get, the more life gets in the way. It’s sad, but it’s the reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;measure lh-copy center&quot;&gt;I created Monica to help these people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;measure lh-copy center&quot;&gt;Monica is not a social network. It will never be. It's a private place for your eyes only, that you own, without any ads or malicious software that will read your data, where you can safely document what you know about who you love. And if you want another level of security, you can always &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/monicahq/monica#get-started&quot;&gt;install Monica&lt;/a&gt; on a server that you own, for free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;12.297297297297&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Built for people. With people.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;measure lh-copy&quot;&gt;Monica is open source. That means the code is &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/monicahq/monica&quot;&gt;publicly available&lt;/a&gt;, scrutinized by thousands. Dozens of people have already contributed to the project. That level of transparency ensures both the security of the application, and your peace of mind concerning what we do with your data (nothing, in fact).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2019 07:28:16 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jandeboevrie</dc:creator>
<og:title>Monica</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.monicahq.com</og:url>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:description>Monica lets you remember everything about your loved ones.</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.monicahq.com/img/social/site/facebook.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.monicahq.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>ACM signed letter opposing open access</title>
<link>https://newsroom.publishers.org/researchers-and-publishers-oppose-immediate-free-distribution-of-peer-reviewed-journal-articles</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://newsroom.publishers.org/researchers-and-publishers-oppose-immediate-free-distribution-of-peer-reviewed-journal-articles</guid>
<description>&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MORE THAN 135 SCIENTIFIC RESEARCH AND PUBLISHING ORGANIZATIONS JOIN TOGETHER IN OPPOSITION&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;strong&gt;TO PROPOSED ADMINISTRATION POLICY FORCING IMMEDIATE FREE DISTRIBUTION&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;OF PEER-REVIEWED JOURNAL ARTICLES&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Proposed Policy Would Undermine American Science, Research, Intellectual Property,&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;and Global Competitiveness&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;December 18, 2019, Washington, DC – In a new major &lt;a href=&quot;https://presspage-production-content.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/1508/coalitionletteropposinglowerembargoes-864869.pdf?54750&quot;&gt;letter&lt;/a&gt; signaling deep concern, more than 135 organizations – representing publishers in scientific and medical societies, global companies, and the U.S. Chamber of Commerce – have expressed their strong opposition to a proposed Administration policy that would mandate immediate free distribution of peer-reviewed journal articles reporting on federally funded research. Along with the Association of American Publishers (AAP), the American Cancer Society, the American Heart Association, the American Academy of Pediatrics, the American Chemical Society, the American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics, and the New England Journal of Medicine are among the many signatories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peer-reviewed articles are not free to produce. Hundreds of non-profit and commercial publishers across America make significant investments, &lt;u&gt;at no cost to taxpayers&lt;/u&gt;, to finance the peer-review, publication, distribution, and long-term stewardship of these articles. Relying on a highly important and successful marketplace and the bedrock copyright laws that make it possible, publishers disseminate these articles to users in hundreds of foreign markets, supporting billions of dollars in U.S. exports and an extensive network of American businesses and jobs. This network includes American professional societies that invest in educating and nurturing our nation’s scientists, engineers, doctors, and other researchers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The American publishing industry invests billions of dollars financing, organizing, and executing the world’s leading peer-review process in order to ensure the quality, reliability, and integrity of the scientific record,” said Maria A. Pallante, President &amp;amp; CEO of the Association of American Publishers. “The result is a public-private partnership that advances America’s position as the global leader in research, innovation, and scientific discovery. If the proposed policy goes into effect, not only would it wipe out a significant sector of our economy, it would also cost the federal government billions of dollars, undermine our nation’s scientific research and innovation, and significantly weaken America’s trade position. Nationalizing this essential function—that our private, non-profit scientific societies and commercial publishers do exceedingly well—is a costly, ill-advised path.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The letter notes that “publishers both support and enable ‘open access’ business models and ‘open data’ as important options within a larger framework that assumes critical publisher investments remain viable. Under a legacy regulation that is still in force today, proprietary journal articles that report on federally funded research must be made available for free within 12 months of publication. This mandate already amounts to a significant government intervention in the private market. Going below the current 12 month ‘embargo’ would make it very difficult for most American publishers to invest in publishing these articles. As a consequence, it would place increased financial responsibility on the government through diverted federal research grant funds or additional monies to underwrite the important value added by publishing. In the coming years, this cost shift would place billions of dollars of new and additional burden on taxpayers.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read the full coalition letter &lt;a href=&quot;https://presspage-production-content.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/1508/coalitionletteropposinglowerembargoes-864869.pdf?54750&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The letter comes on the heels of another strong letter to the Administration from Senator Thom Tillis (R-NC), Chairman of the Senate Judiciary Intellectual Property Subcommittee, which expresses similar concerns about the proposed policy. That letter is available &lt;a href=&quot;https://copyrightalliance.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Tillis-12.12-Ltr-to-DOC-and-OMB-re-Scientific-Journals.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Media contacts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John McKay / 202-220-4552 / &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:jmckay@publishers.org&quot;&gt;jmckay@publishers.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cara Duckworth / 202-220-4558 / &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:cduckworth@publishers.org&quot;&gt;cduckworth@publishers.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;u&gt;List of Signatories to the Coalition Letter&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AMDA – The Society for Post-Acute and Long-Term Care Medicine&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Academy of Allergy, Asthma &amp;amp; Immunology&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Academy of Child and Adolescent Psychiatry&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Academy of Family Physicians&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Academy of Neurology&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Academy of Ophthalmology&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Academy of Orthopaedic Surgeons&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Academy of Otolaryngology- Head and Neck Surgery&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Academy of Pediatrics&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Academy of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Association for Anatomy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Association for Cancer Research&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Association for Pediatric Ophthalmology and Strabismus&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Association for the Study of Liver Diseases&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Association for the Surgery of Trauma&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Association of Immunologists&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Association of Occupational Health Nurses&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Association of Physicists in Medicine&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Astronomical Society&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Cancer Society&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Ceramic Society&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Chemical Society&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American College of Cardiology&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American College of Emergency Physicians&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American College of Physicians&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American College of Radiology&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American College of Rheumatology&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American College of Surgeons&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Contact Dermatitis Society&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Council on the Teaching of Foreign Languages&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Counseling Association&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Dental Association&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Diabetes Association&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Gastroenterological Association&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Geophysical Union&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Geriatrics Society&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Headache Society&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Heart Association&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Institute of Chemical Engineers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Oil Chemists Society&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Medical Association&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Neurological Association&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Physiological Society&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Psychiatric Association&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Psychological Association&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Sexual Health Association&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Sexually Transmitted Diseases Association&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Society for Clinical Pharmacology &amp;amp; Therapeutics&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Society for Nutrition&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Society for Biochemistry and Molecular Biology&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Society for Bone and Mineral Research&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Society for Clinical Pathology&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Society for Dermatologic Surgery Association&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Society for Investigative Pathology&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Society for Parenteral and Enteral Nutrition&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Society for Pharmacology and Experimental Therapeutics&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Society for Radiation Oncology&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Society for Reproductive Medicine&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Society of Anesthesiologists&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Society of Agricultural and Biological Engineers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Society of Agronomy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Society of Animal Science&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Society of Civil Engineers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Society of Clinical Oncology&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Society of Cytopathology&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Society of Gene &amp;amp; Cell Therapy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Society of Health-System Pharmacists&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Society of Heating, Refrigerating &amp;amp; Air-Conditioning Engineers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Society of Hematology&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Society of Mechanical Engineers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Society of Nephrology&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Society of Neurorehabilitation (ASNR)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Society of Plant Biologists&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Society of Plastic Surgeons&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Society of Transplantation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Society of Transplant Surgeons&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Thoracic Society&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Urological Association&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Water Works Association&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Association for Computing Machinery&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Association for Molecular Pathology&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Association for Psychological Science&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Association for the Sciences of Limnology and Oceanography&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Association of American Publishers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Association of Schools and Programs of Public Health&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Association of Teacher Educators&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Biophysical Society&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Botanical Society of America&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Common Ground Research Networks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Council of Medical Specialty Societies&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Council of Scientific Society Presidents&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crop Science Society of America&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ecological Society of America&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elsevier&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Endocrine Society&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Financial Management Association&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genetics Society of America&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Infectious Diseases Society of America&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Institute for Operations Research and the Management Sciences&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Institute of Food Technologists&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Institute of Industrial and Systems Engineers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;International Anesthesia Research Society&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;International Literacy Association&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;International Society for Sexual Medicine&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Journal of Diabetes Science and Technology, Diabetes Technology Society&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kappa Delta Pi, International Honor Society in Education&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Macmillan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;McGraw-Hill Education&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Milbank Memorial Fund&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;National Council on Family Relations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;National Kidney Foundation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New England Journal of Medicine published by the Massachusetts Medical Society&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Orthopaedic Research Society&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Radiological Society of North America&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seismological Society of America&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shock Society&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Society for Leukocyte Biology&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Society for Research on Adolescence&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Society for the Psychological Study of Social Issues&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Society for Research in Child Development&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Society of General Internal Medicine&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Society of Plastics Engineers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soil Science Society of America&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Software and Information Industry Association&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Heart Rhythm Society&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Histochemical Society&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Journal of Bone &amp;amp; Joint Surgery, Inc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Minerals, Metals &amp;amp; Materials Society&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Optical Society&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Triological Society&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Voice Foundation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;University of Chicago Press&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;U.S. Chamber of Commerce&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wiley&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wolters Kluwer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;# # #&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;About AAP&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;AAP | The Association of American Publishers represents the leading book, journal, and education publishers in the United States on matters of law and policy, advocating for outcomes that incentivize the publication of creative expression, professional content, and learning solutions. As essential participants in local markets and the global economy, our members invest in and inspire the exchange of ideas, transforming the world we live in one word at a time. Find us online at newsroom.publishers.org or on twitter at @AmericanPublish.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;







</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2019 06:21:11 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>beefhash</dc:creator>
<og:title>COALITION OF 135+ SCIENTIFIC RESEARCH AND PUBLISHING ORGANIZATIONS SENDS LETTER TO ADMINISTRATION</og:title>
<og:image>https://content.presspage.com/clients/o_1508.png</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://newsroom.publishers.org/researchers-and-publishers-oppose-immediate-free-distribution-of-peer-reviewed-journal-articles/</og:url>
<og:description>MORE THAN 135 SCIENTIFIC RESEARCH AND PUBLISHING ORGANIZATIONS JOIN TOGETHER IN OPPOSITION  TO PROPOSED ADMINISTRATION POLICY FORCING IMMEDIATE FREE DISTRIBUTION OF PEER-REVIEWED JOURNAL ARTICLES Proposed Policy Would Undermine American Science, Research, Intellectual Property, and Global Competitiveness December 18, 2019, Washington, DC –...</og:description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://newsroom.publishers.org/researchers-and-publishers-oppose-immediate-free-distribution-of-peer-reviewed-journal-articles</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Fast</title>
<link>https://patrickcollison.com/fast</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://patrickcollison.com/fast</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Some examples of people quickly accomplishing ambitious things together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BankAmericard.&lt;/strong&gt; Dee Hock was given 90 days to launch the BankAmericard card (which became the Visa card), starting from scratch. He did. In that period, he signed up more than 100,000 customers. &lt;em&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Electronic-Value-Exchange-Origins-Computing/dp/1849961387&quot;&gt;Electronic Value Exchange&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;P-80 Shooting Star.&lt;/strong&gt; Kelly Johnson and his team designed and delivered the P-80 Shooting Star, the first jet fighter used by the USAF, in 143 days. &lt;em&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Skunk-Works-Personal-Memoir-Lockheed/dp/0316743003&quot;&gt;Skunk Works&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marinship.&lt;/strong&gt; &quot;Shipyard construction was begun promptly after a telegram from the United States Maritime Commission was received by the W. A. Bechtel Company. The telegram was received on 2 March 1942, the Sausalito site selected on 3 March, and a proposal to build the shipyard presented in Washington DC was made on 9 March. Ten minutes into the presentation U. S. Maritime Commission administrators told the W.A. Bechtel Company to build the shipyard. Physical construction began on 28 March. Construction start was delayed two weeks to allow the 42 families living on Pine Point, which was scheduled to be demolished to build the shipyard, to move.&quot; The first ship was completed on September 15 of that year, 197 days after receiving the telegram. &lt;em&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sausalitohistoricalsociety.com/2019-columns/2019/1/23/marinship-on-the-fast-track&quot;&gt;Marinship on the Fast Track&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Spirit of St. Louis.&lt;/strong&gt; In 1927, Donald Hall and Charles Lindbergh designed and built &lt;em&gt;Spirit&lt;/em&gt; in 60 days. &quot;To determine the amount of fuel the plane would need, Lindbergh and Hall drove to the San Diego Public Library at 820 E St. Using a globe and a piece of string, Lindbergh estimated the distance from New York to Paris. It came out to 3,600 statute miles, which Hall calculated would require 400 gallons of gas.&quot; &lt;em&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sandiegoyesterday.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/lindbergh.pdf&quot;&gt;Ryan Airlines gave Lindbergh wings&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Eiffel Tower.&lt;/strong&gt; The Eiffel Tower was built in 2 years and 2 months; that is, in 793 days. When completed in 1889, it became the tallest building in the world, a record it held for more than 40 years. It cost about $40 million in 2019 dollars. &lt;em&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Eiffels-Tower-Thrilling-Extraordinary-Introduced/dp/0143117297/&quot;&gt;Eiffel's Tower&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Treasure Island.&lt;/strong&gt; In 1935, San Francisco decided to commemorate the completion of the Golden Gate and Bay Bridges by building a new island as a home for the Golden Gate International Exposition. Treasure Island, a 400 acre man-made island in the middle of the San Francisco Bay, was the result. Construction started in 1935 and was complete by March 1937. &lt;em&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Francisco-Fair-Treasure-Island-1939-1940/dp/094208702X&quot;&gt;San Francisco Fair: Treasure Island&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apollo 8.&lt;/strong&gt; On August 9 1968, NASA decided that Apollo 8 should go to the moon. It launched on December 21 1968, 134 days later. &lt;em&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hq.nasa.gov/office/pao/History/SP-4009/v4p2n.htm&quot;&gt;Apollo Spacecraft Chronology&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Alaska Highway.&lt;/strong&gt; Starting in 1942, 1,700 miles of military roadway were built over the course of 234 days, connecting eastern British Columbia with Fairbanks, Alaska. &lt;em&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Alaska-Highway-World-War-Occupation/dp/0806151765&quot;&gt;The Alaska Highway&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disneyland.&lt;/strong&gt; Walt Disney's conception of &quot;The Happiest Place on Earth&quot; was brought to life in 366 days. &lt;em&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.itsnicethat.com/features/walt-disney-disneyland-taschen-publication-030918&quot;&gt;Under Construction: A look inside Walt Disney’s Disneyland&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Empire State Building.&lt;/strong&gt; Construction was started and finished in 410 days. &lt;em&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Empire-State-Building-America-Then/dp/1604130458&quot;&gt;Empire State Building&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Berlin Airlift.&lt;/strong&gt; On 24 June 1948, the Soviet Union initiated a blockade of Berlin. Two days later, the Berlin Airlift commenced. Over the following 463 days, the US, the UK, and France flew 277,000 flights with 300 aircraft to deliver the supplies required to support 2.2 million Berlin residents. On average, a supply aircraft landed every 2 minutes for 14 months. &lt;em&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Candy-Bombers-Untold-Airlift-Americas/dp/0425227715/&quot;&gt;The Candy Bombers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Pentagon.&lt;/strong&gt; The construction of the world's largest office building was led by Brehon Somervell. The decision to proceed with the project was made on a Thursday evening. Initial drawings were completed that Sunday. Construction started two months later, on September 11 1941, and was finished on January 15 1943, 491 days later. When asked when something was needed, Somervell's go-to response was &quot;the day before yesterday&quot;. &lt;em&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Pentagon-History-Steve-Vogel/dp/0812973259&quot;&gt;The Pentagon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Boeing 747.&lt;/strong&gt; Boeing decided to start the 747 program in March 1966. The first 747 was completed on September 30 1968, about 930 days later. &lt;em&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Boeing-747-History-Delivering-Dream/dp/1783030399/&quot;&gt;Boeing 747: A History&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The New York Subway.&lt;/strong&gt; The first contract was awarded on February 21 1900. 28 stations opened and general operation commenced on October 27 1904, 4.7 years later. In April 2000, the MTA decided to build the Second Avenue Subway. The first phase, with 3 stations, opened on January 1 2017. &lt;em&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/1904/10/28/archives/our-subway-open-150000-try-it-mayor-mcclellan-runs-the-first.html&amp;amp;legacy=true&quot;&gt;The New York Times&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TGV.&lt;/strong&gt; On April 30 1976, the French government approved a plan to build a high-speed rail link between Paris and Lyon, the first high-speed rail line in Europe. This line was to use completely new electric locomotives, also to be developed in France as part of the project. The ensuing line opened on September 26 1981, 1,975 days later. On September 24 1996, the California High-Speed Rail Authority was formed. The completion of the first phase of California's high-speed rail project, a line connecting San Francisco and Anaheim, is currently estimated to happen in 2033, 37 years (i.e. around 13,000 days) after the authority was formed. &lt;em&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Fast-Track-Railway-Modernization-1944-1983-dp-0275973778/dp/0275973778&quot;&gt;On the Fast Track&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;USS Nautilus.&lt;/strong&gt; The US decided to build the world's first nuclear submarine in July 1951. It entered service on September 30 1954, 1,173 days later. &lt;em&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1574885308&quot;&gt;Cold War Submarines&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JavaScript.&lt;/strong&gt; Brendan Eich implemented the first prototype for JavaScript in 10 days, in May 1995. It shipped in beta in September of that year. &lt;em&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GxouWy-ZE80&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&amp;amp;t=12&quot;&gt;Brendan Eich's history of the language&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unix.&lt;/strong&gt; Ken Thompson wrote the first version in three weeks. &lt;em&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/UNIX-History-Memoir-Brian-Kernighan/dp/1695978552/&quot;&gt;UNIX: A History and a Memoir&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Xerox Alto.&lt;/strong&gt; Work on the Xerox Alto, the first GUI-oriented computer, started in November 1972 because of a bet: &quot;Chuck said that a futuristic computer could be done 'in three months' and a Xerox exec bet him a case of wine that it couldn’t be done&quot;. Building the Alto required extensive hardware, operating system, and application &lt;a href=&quot;https://patrickcollison.com/static/files/alto.pdf&quot;&gt;design&lt;/a&gt; and implementation. The first complete Altos were introduced on March 1 1973. &lt;em&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quora.com/How-was-the-Xerox-Alto-done-in-only-3-months/answer/Alan-Kay-11&quot;&gt;Alan Kay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shenzhen.&lt;/strong&gt; In one year, between 1998 and 1999, Shenzhen added 1 million residents (a 22% increase), growing from 4.4 million to 5.4 million people. &lt;em&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://populationstat.com/china/shenzhen&quot;&gt;PopulationStat&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amazon Prime.&lt;/strong&gt; Amazon started to implement the first version of Amazon Prime in late 2004 and announced it on February 2 2005, six weeks later. &lt;em&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/recode/2019/5/3/18511544/amazon-prime-oral-history-jeff-bezos-one-day-shipping&quot;&gt;The making of Amazon Prime&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Git.&lt;/strong&gt; Linus Torvalds started working on Git on April 3 2005. It was self-hosting 4 days later. On April 20 2005, 17 days after work commenced, Linux 2.6.12-rc3 was publicly released with Git. &lt;em&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://lkml.org/lkml/2005/4/20/159&quot;&gt;LKML&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Luckin Coffee.&lt;/strong&gt; Luckin Coffee was founded in October 2017. Their first stores opened on January 1, 2018. On September 3 2018—245 days later—they passed 1,000 directly-operated stores in China. &lt;em&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.leiphone.com/news/201809/bDWatv0HvmcO6AjX.html&quot;&gt;Why is Luckin Coffee the best experimental field for Tencent Smart Retail?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;San Francisco proposed a new bus lane on Van Ness in 2001. Its opening was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sfexaminer.com/news/two-mile-long-van-ness-bus-lane-project-faces-two-year-delay/&quot;&gt;recently delayed&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sfmta.com/projects/van-ness-improvement-project&quot;&gt;2021&lt;/a&gt;, yielding a project duration of around 7,300 days. “The project has been delayed due to an increase of wet weather since the project started,” said Paul Rose, a San Francisco Municipal Transportation Agency spokesperson. The project will cost $310 million, i.e. $100,000 per meter. The Alaska Highway, mentioned above, constructed across remote tundra, cost $793 per meter in 2019 dollars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:patrick@collison.ie&quot;&gt;send me more entries&lt;/a&gt;! (Preferably with sources.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2019 01:10:27 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>doppp</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://patrickcollison.com/fast</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The modern web is becoming unusable</title>
<link>https://omarabid.com/the-modern-web</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://omarabid.com/the-modern-web</guid>
<description>&lt;time datetime=&quot;2019-12-20&quot; class=&quot;article_time&quot;&gt;December 20, 2019&lt;/time&gt;&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;22&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In one of Gerald Weinberg’s books, probably The Secrets of Consulting, there’s the apocryphal story of the giant multinational hamburger chain where some bright MBA figured out that eliminating just three sesame seeds from a sesame-seed bun would be completely unnoticeable by anyone yet would save the company $126,000 per year. So they do it, and time passes, and another bushy-tailed MBA comes along, and does another study, and concludes that removing another five sesame seeds wouldn’t hurt either, and would save even more money, and so on and so forth, every year or two, the new management trainee looking for ways to save money proposes removing a sesame seed or two, until eventually, they’re shipping hamburger buns with exactly three sesame seeds artfully arranged in a triangle, and nobody buys their hamburgers any more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Joel Spolsky from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.joelonsoftware.com/2007/09/11/theres-no-place-like-127001/&quot;&gt;There’s no place like 127.0.0.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I keep browsing today’s internet, I keep recalling this extract. It’s the same thing happening with the modern web: If you add another advertisement to your pages, you generate more revenue. If you track your users better, now you can deliver tailored ads and your conversion rates are higher. If you restrict users from leaving your walled garden ecosystem, now you get all the juice from whatever attention they have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question is: At which point do we reach the breaking point?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I think the answer is: &lt;em&gt;We are very close&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some of these websites, who have managed over time to turn the user experience almost unusable for anyone who doesn’t have an account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;facebook_2&quot;&gt;Facebook &lt;a class=&quot;head_anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://omarabid.com/the-modern-web#facebook_2&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you try to open a Facebook page without an account, this is what you get.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://svbtleusercontent.com/dJwcwmJQW8QkFHeMQBKnTC0xspap.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://svbtleusercontent.com/dJwcwmJQW8QkFHeMQBKnTC0xspap.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screen Shot 2019-11-11 at 6.34.32 PM.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a blue header at the top that has the login form. But in case you missed it, Facebook has made another big white one at the bottom. Have you signed up yet?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s try to scroll a little bit more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://svbtleusercontent.com/gNR1XozEXRGq8TxxBbtSK60xspap.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://svbtleusercontent.com/gNR1XozEXRGq8TxxBbtSK60xspap.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screen Shot 2019-11-11 at 6.34.55 PM.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wooha! Looks like you didn’t login, or you haven’t signed up yet! But there is a small “Not Now” button; because we know &lt;em&gt;you’ll have to create an account later&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case you think this experience is garbage; wait until you see the mobile version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://svbtleusercontent.com/GkQ5zG4SoV2yZDFPZCn1a0xspap.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://svbtleusercontent.com/GkQ5zG4SoV2yZDFPZCn1a0xspap.png&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_3528.PNG&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not even clear, at this point, what the actual page is about. Let’s try to scroll a bit more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://svbtleusercontent.com/iwrmnvSWCCZ6LWkp1V3SRH0xspap.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://svbtleusercontent.com/iwrmnvSWCCZ6LWkp1V3SRH0xspap.png&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_3530.PNG&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There isn’t even any content in this page. Who designed and approved this mess?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think you are a smart-ass? You can create a fake account. But after a while, Facebook will think you are dodgy and ask for more identifiable information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://svbtleusercontent.com/5xyZiwADWPEziRppRmEvSM0xspap.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://svbtleusercontent.com/5xyZiwADWPEziRppRmEvSM0xspap.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screen Shot 2019-11-20 at 11.58.45 AM.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a solution: To buy a disposable phone number and use it to complete the verification. But this was the breaking point. At this point, I no longer bother.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;twitter_2&quot;&gt;Twitter &lt;a class=&quot;head_anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://omarabid.com/the-modern-web#twitter_2&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is Twitter any better? Well, it looks like they are trying to strike a balance between giving you free data and their craving for your identity. You can still read the president tweets from his main page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://svbtleusercontent.com/vfk2SLog4xoJR693CHSUaX0xspap.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://svbtleusercontent.com/vfk2SLog4xoJR693CHSUaX0xspap.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screen Shot 2019-12-20 at 1.07.06 PM.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trying to read his “Tweets &amp;amp; replies” is less fruitful though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://svbtleusercontent.com/8eBsgGd149ankeY2dh9qj80xspap.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://svbtleusercontent.com/8eBsgGd149ankeY2dh9qj80xspap.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screen Shot 2019-12-20 at 1.07.44 PM.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually, all of these buttons are inaccessible as for right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://svbtleusercontent.com/iN7M3MxngAUo8bX8F2JCA80xspap.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://svbtleusercontent.com/iN7M3MxngAUo8bX8F2JCA80xspap.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screen Shot 2019-12-20 at 1.07.06 PM.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extrapolating on the progress these websites have been making, it’s only a matter of time before &lt;em&gt;nothing&lt;/em&gt; on Twitter is readable without an account. Maybe, you’ll get a spoiler in the future; but that’s it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;medium_2&quot;&gt;Medium &lt;a class=&quot;head_anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://omarabid.com/the-modern-web#medium_2&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone is complaining about these tech-giants these days, but are the new incumbents doing any better? Medium is one these &lt;em&gt;dudes&lt;/em&gt; and they claim to be the good guys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;short&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep it ad-free&lt;br/&gt;Medium doesn’t accept advertising. Please don’t market yourself or other products, feature advertisements, or include requests for claps or donations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://svbtleusercontent.com/9VdU6n8fbQbksQwSnKp6Nx0xspap.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://svbtleusercontent.com/9VdU6n8fbQbksQwSnKp6Nx0xspap.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screen Shot 2019-11-11 at 7.26.25 PM.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No ads? Time to check the terms of service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In consideration for Medium granting you access to and use of the Services, you agree that Medium may enable advertising on the Services, including in connection with the display &lt;em&gt;of your content&lt;/em&gt; or other information. We may also &lt;em&gt;use your content&lt;/em&gt; to promote Medium, including its products and content. We will never sell your content to third parties without your explicit permission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So they are advertising, but &lt;em&gt;you are not&lt;/em&gt;. But hey! at least they are not selling your content without your permission. Don’t hold your breath, though. The terms can change at a moment notice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And in case you wondered what the experience of browsing medium is, here it is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://svbtleusercontent.com/wyvY4QLnCK9RFwxDG7CSDc0xspap.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://svbtleusercontent.com/wyvY4QLnCK9RFwxDG7CSDc0xspap.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screen Shot 2019-11-11 at 7.20.10 PM.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://svbtleusercontent.com/wcxC522McDBrpK98NQyK4f0xspap.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://svbtleusercontent.com/wcxC522McDBrpK98NQyK4f0xspap.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screen Shot 2019-11-11 at 7.22.33 PM.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://svbtleusercontent.com/rFMbk9Nh775qzsV2Lx3FLn0xspap.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://svbtleusercontent.com/rFMbk9Nh775qzsV2Lx3FLn0xspap.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screen Shot 2019-11-11 at 7.23.44 PM.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what if you pay? That is you are not the product like they said. Let’s say you check a supposedly reputable company (i.e. Bloomberg) and think of opting for a digital subscription.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://svbtleusercontent.com/uZ3k94FgmD61DTUb4m1bqd0xspap.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://svbtleusercontent.com/uZ3k94FgmD61DTUb4m1bqd0xspap.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screen Shot 2019-11-23 at 9.33.01 PM.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mean it’s only $2/month. Less than what you’d pay for a cup of coffee. Or $&lt;strong&gt;340&lt;/strong&gt;/year; here hoping you are very bad at math.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a nutshell, if I can describe my browsing experience in 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Websites asking to login, register or enter an email.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Websites asking for your phone number after you gave up your email.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Websites asking to allow HTML5 notifications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Websites downloading 50Mb of data and making hundreds of requests to serve 6Kb worth of text.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Websites that are not functioning because they have too much JavaScript.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Websites that are not functioning because some of the JavaScript was caught by uBlock Origin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Websites asking to turn off the Ad Blocker.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Websites asking to accept the cookies in 41,484 different ways.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Websites asking to download their mobile app which is non-native and requires around 200Mb of storage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Popups to buy a deal or download some random crap.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reCaptcha with random street images; that are sometimes impossible to solve.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CloudFlare DDoS protection thinking I’m a bot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Youtube running a 2:30 minutes ad for a 3:30 minutes music video.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Video or Website not showing up because I’m not in said country.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linkedin that keeps sending dozens of emails despite unsubscribing multiple times; and somehow evades the Spam filter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to have a bank account with a local branch of BNP Paribas. When I signed up, I opted for various services like Online Banking, a “Platinum” debit card and other services. It made sense at the time to pay for online banking since it was long ago, but does it make sense now?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worse, in the last few years, I have seen the bill for these services increase three fold in the last 3 years. And they started charging for small crap: Deposit money? There is a small fee. Deposit a check? There is a small fee. Withdraw from another bank ATM? The fee now is so high I have to think twice. &lt;em&gt;Inconvenient&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Changing banks is annoying but not impossible. It’d be better if I can avoid such a thing but there is a point where the system breaks. And at some point, you look at the bill and decide: That’s the &lt;strong&gt;breaking point&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;2,357&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kudos&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;2,357&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kudos&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 23:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>csomar</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://omarabid.com/the-modern-web</og:url>
<og:title>The modern web is becoming an unusable, user-hostile wasteland • Abid Omar</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>In one of Gerald Weinberg’s books, probably The Secrets of Consulting, there’s the apocryphal story of the giant multinational hamburger chain where some bright MBA figured out that eliminating just three sesame seeds from a sesame-seed bun would... | Abid Omar | Svbtle</og:description>
<og:image>https://svbtleusercontent.com/dJwcwmJQW8QkFHeMQBKnTC0xspap.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://omarabid.com/the-modern-web</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Consumers who sought cash settlement from Equifax probably won&amp;#039;t get full $125</title>
<link>https://www.cnbc.com/2019/12/19/court-awards-80-million-to-consumer-attorneys-in-equifax-case.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.cnbc.com/2019/12/19/court-awards-80-million-to-consumer-attorneys-in-equifax-case.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;group&quot; readability=&quot;87.88083371092&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you filed for a cash payout from Equifax as part of the credit bureau's settlement for its massive 2017 data breach, you're probably not getting anywhere close to $125.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, Dec. 19, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.law.com/dailyreportonline/2019/12/19/judge-oks-77-5-million-in-legals-fees-approves-equifax-data-breach-settlement/?cmp=share_twitter&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot; role=&quot;&quot; tabindex=&quot;&quot; data-type=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot;&gt;Georgia federal judge awarded $77.5 million&lt;/a&gt; to the attorneys representing the class of consumers against Equifax. That's over 20% of the roughly $380 million settlement fund Equifax agreed to set up to directly help consumers affected by the breach, according to the Hamilton Lincoln Law Institute, which house the &lt;a href=&quot;https://hlli.org/class-action-fairness/&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot; role=&quot;&quot; tabindex=&quot;&quot; data-type=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot;&gt;Center for Class Action Fairness&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://hlli.org/equifax/&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot; role=&quot;&quot; tabindex=&quot;&quot; data-type=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot;&gt;opposed the high fee award&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's also one more reason why the consumers who sought a cash settlement from Equifax won't be getting the full $125 as initially expected. In fact, consumers were never going to get $125, says Ted Frank, director of litigation for Hamilton Lincoln. &quot;That's down to $6 or $7 [per consumer] now. Maybe even less than that,&quot; he tells &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/make-it/&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; role=&quot;&quot; tabindex=&quot;&quot; data-type=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot;&gt;CNBC Make It&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In July, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2019/07/22/what-you-need-to-know-equifax-data-breach-700-million-settlement.html&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; role=&quot;&quot; tabindex=&quot;&quot; data-type=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot;&gt;credit bureau Equifax agreed to pay&lt;/a&gt; a total of nearly $700 million for its role in the massive 2017 data breach, which impacted 147 million consumers. The settlement included a $380.5 million restitution fund dedicated to consumer compensation and fees associated with the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ftc.gov/news-events/press-releases/2019/07/equifax-pay-575-million-part-settlement-ftc-cfpb-states-related&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot; role=&quot;&quot; tabindex=&quot;&quot; data-type=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot;&gt;terms of the settlement&lt;/a&gt;, affected consumers could potentially get up to $20,000 in reimbursement for out-of-pocket expenses they incurred because of the data breach. But even if you didn't suffer any direct harm from the breach, you could &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2019/07/29/is-it-better-to-get-125-or-free-credit-monitoring-from-equifax.html&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; role=&quot;&quot; tabindex=&quot;&quot; data-type=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot;&gt;claim free credit monitoring&lt;/a&gt; or a flat cash payout of up to $125 if you already have credit services in place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ftc.gov/news-events/press-releases/2019/07/ftc-encourages-consumers-opt-free-credit-monitoring-part-equifax&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot; role=&quot;&quot; tabindex=&quot;&quot; data-type=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot;&gt;Federal Trade Commission announced in late July&lt;/a&gt; that because of the high interest in the $125 cash compensation option, consumers who picked the payout might end up getting far less than initially expected. It turned out that the money set aside in the roughly $380 million restitution fund specifically for cash compensation was capped at $31 million, so if more than 248,000 consumers picked this option, the total compensation for each person would be less.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.consumer.ftc.gov/blog/2019/07/equifax-data-breach-pick-free-credit-monitoring&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot; role=&quot;&quot; tabindex=&quot;&quot; data-type=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot;&gt;FTC took the unusual step of urging consumers&lt;/a&gt; to pick the free credit monitoring instead of the cash payment, saying the service was worth &quot;hundreds of dollars&quot; and comes with identity theft insurance and restoration services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then in September, consumers who filed for the $125 cash payout were &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2019/09/09/equifax-settlement-you-need-to-update-your-claim-to-get-125.html&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; role=&quot;&quot; tabindex=&quot;&quot; data-type=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot;&gt;sent an email&lt;/a&gt; with the subject line: &quot;Your Equifax Claim: You Must Act by October 15, 2019 or Your Claim for Alternative Compensation Will Be Denied.&quot; Under the new requirements, consumers had two options: verify their claim by providing more information or amend their paperwork to opt for a non-cash settlement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If consumers failed to file the additional information before Oct. 15, 2019, the notice said their claim would be completely rejected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now Thursday's ruling puts that $125 award amount even further out of reach, Frank says. &quot;Class counsel in their briefing said that [consumers] were never going to get $125, and they blamed the media for it. But that's absolutely not what the press releases said, and there was a reason people thought they were getting $125.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet it's worth noting that if you spent money on freezing your credit, buying credit monitoring, or on other expenses because of the beach, you can still be fully reimbursed, says Amy Keller an attorney with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dicellolevitt.com/amy-e-keller-named-co-lead-counsel-in-equifax-security-breach-multidistrict-litigation/&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot; role=&quot;&quot; tabindex=&quot;&quot; data-type=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot;&gt;Chicago-based DiCello Levitt Gutzler&lt;/a&gt; and co-lead counsel for consumers in the case against Equifax. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Unfortunately, we think that the focus on the alternative compensation is preventing consumers from understanding that they can be fully reimbursed for the money that they spent in response to the breach,&quot; she tells CNBC Make It.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Frank says it's still a bad deal. &quot;The FTC let themselves get snookered by the class counsel into believing how good this settlement was. That's why their press release was misleading,&quot; Frank says. &quot;It's unfortunate because they're supposed to looking out for consumers here and instead they signed off on a settlement where the beneficiaries are really the attorneys.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Updated to include comments from an attorney for class counsel. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Like this story?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/c/CNBCMakeIt?sub_confirmation=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot; role=&quot;&quot; tabindex=&quot;&quot; data-type=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subscribe to CNBC Make It on YouTube&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don't miss:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 23:29:20 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rahuldottech</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>If you made a claim for $125 from Equifax, you're not getting it after court awards nearly $80 million to attorneys</og:title>
<og:description>On Thursday, a Georgia federal judge awarded $80 million to attorneys representing consumers against Equifax. That's just one more factor chipping away at the $125 cash payments consumers thought they were getting.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.cnbc.com/2019/12/19/court-awards-80-million-to-consumer-attorneys-in-equifax-case.html</og:url>
<og:image>https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/104702901-RTX3FBVD-equifax.jpg?v=1564335187</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.cnbc.com/2019/12/19/court-awards-80-million-to-consumer-attorneys-in-equifax-case.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>CDC Confirms a THC Additive, Vitamin E Acetate, Is Culprit in Most Vaping Deaths</title>
<link>https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2019/12/20/790154919/cdc-confirms-a-thc-contaminant-vitamin-e-acetate-the-culprit-in-most-vaping-deat</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2019/12/20/790154919/cdc-confirms-a-thc-contaminant-vitamin-e-acetate-the-culprit-in-most-vaping-deat</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;res790212670&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap image large&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imagewrap&quot; data-crop-type=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2019/12/20/gettyimages-954732484-1--1c4428edc6246033ed771d8f9837e2102955715a-s1100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2019/12/20/gettyimages-954732484-1--1c4428edc6246033ed771d8f9837e2102955715a-s1100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-wrap&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image caption&quot; readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CDC is still trying to understand the mechanism by which Vitamin E acetate, an additive in some vapes, injures lung tissue. It may interfere with a natural fluid in the lung called surfactant, which helps make lung tissue stretchy. Or a byproduct may be a toxic chemical. &lt;strong class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Jelacic Valentina/EyeEm/Getty Images&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong class=&quot;hide-caption&quot;&gt;hide caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;strong class=&quot;toggle-caption&quot;&gt;toggle caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Jelacic Valentina/EyeEm/Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_measure&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img_wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2019/12/20/gettyimages-954732484-1--1c4428edc6246033ed771d8f9837e2102955715a-s1200.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_html&quot; readability=&quot;8.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image_data&quot; readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;The CDC is still trying to understand the mechanism by which Vitamin E acetate, an additive in some vapes, injures lung tissue. It may interfere with a natural fluid in the lung called surfactant, which helps make lung tissue stretchy. Or a byproduct may be a toxic chemical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Jelacic Valentina/EyeEm/Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A health-surveillance system put in place after the terrorist attacks of September 2001 has been used to pinpoint the cause of the vaping-related lung injuries that have killed 54 Americans and sent more than 2,500 people to the hospital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using this system, researchers at the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention have found that the lung injuries rose sharply in June of this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cdc.gov/about/leadership/leaders/pdd.html&quot;&gt;Dr. Anne Schuchat&lt;/a&gt;, the CDC's principal deputy director, says this sharp spike strongly points to a single culprit for most of these cases: vitamin E acetate, an additive found in illicit cannabis-containing vapes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res790213398&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap internallink insettwocolumn inset2col&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bucket img&quot;&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;featuredStackSquareImage777646890&quot; href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2019/11/08/777646890/cdc-finds-possible-culprit-in-outbreak-of-vaping-related-lung-injuries&quot; data-metrics=&quot;{&amp;quot;category&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Story to Story&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;action&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Click Internal Link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;label&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https:\/\/www.npr.org\/sections\/health-shots\/2019\/11\/08\/777646890\/cdc-finds-possible-culprit-in-outbreak-of-vaping-related-lung-injuries&amp;quot;}&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2019/11/08/ap_19312637159446_sq-bab094e6db8d6e64925a5ace366a7db695daa7a3-s100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2019/11/08/ap_19312637159446_sq-bab094e6db8d6e64925a5ace366a7db695daa7a3-s100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;CDC Finds Possible Culprit In Outbreak Of Vaping-Related Lung Injuries&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;That doesn't mean that there aren't other chemicals that can or are causing lung injury,&quot; Schuchat said during a telephone news conference. But backed with additional data about vitamin E acetate found in lung samples from people who were injured after vaping, she attributes the bulk of the outbreak to that additive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CDC is still trying to understand the mechanism by which this substance injures lung tissue. It may interfere with a natural fluid in the lung called surfactant, which helps make lung tissue stretchy. Or a byproduct may be a toxic chemical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emergency-room doctors in Wisconsin first noticed an outbreak of these lung injuries in June. They alerted state and federal health officials, who quickly &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/2019/10/22/772368792/cdc-studying-tissue-to-try-and-track-down-root-cause-of-vaping-related-lung-dama&quot;&gt;started investigating&lt;/a&gt; the extent of the outbreak as they looked for what could be causing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investigators homed in on vaping products containing marijuana extracts, specifically those that were purchased online or on the street, rather than through dispensaries. Further research focused on vitamin E acetate, which is used in some of these preparations to dilute the much more expensive THC oil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id=&quot;ad-backstage-wrap&quot; aria-label=&quot;advertisement&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;res790215239&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap internallink insettwocolumn inset2col&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bucket img&quot;&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;featuredStackSquareImage776356212&quot; href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2019/12/11/776356212/he-started-vaping-thc-to-cope-with-chronic-pain-then-he-got-sick&quot; data-metrics=&quot;{&amp;quot;category&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Story to Story&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;action&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Click Internal Link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;label&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https:\/\/www.npr.org\/sections\/health-shots\/2019\/12\/11\/776356212\/he-started-vaping-thc-to-cope-with-chronic-pain-then-he-got-sick&amp;quot;}&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2019/12/09/paul_home0_sq-175f92d49c41335d02c477070062f45768f3fc93-s100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2019/12/09/paul_home0_sq-175f92d49c41335d02c477070062f45768f3fc93-s100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;He Started Vaping THC To Cope With Chronic Pain. Then He Got Sick&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was important to understand the timing of the outbreak as part of this investigation. Health officials wanted to know when exactly the problems first cropped up, and whether they had missed many cases before those initial reports. That's why they turned to the surveillance data, collected from more than 3,200 emergency rooms from most states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They found a gradual increase in emergency-room visits among people who vaped or used e-cigarettes, starting in January of 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Those visits weren't limited to lung injury, so there may be other health effects that people were experiencing,&quot; says Kathleen Hartnett, an epidemiologist at the CDC who is first author of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nejm.org/doi/full/10.1056/NEJMsr1915313&quot;&gt;a study being published&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;em&gt;New England Journal of Medicine&lt;/em&gt;. People may have also been going to the emergency room because of nicotine poisoning, or intoxication from THC, the main psychoactive ingredient in marijuana.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res790213282&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap internallink insettwocolumn inset2col&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bucket img&quot;&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;featuredStackSquareImage788540191&quot; href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2019/12/16/788540191/vaping-nicotine-linked-to-increased-risk-of-chronic-lung-disease&quot; data-metrics=&quot;{&amp;quot;category&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Story to Story&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;action&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Click Internal Link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;label&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https:\/\/www.npr.org\/sections\/health-shots\/2019\/12\/16\/788540191\/vaping-nicotine-linked-to-increased-risk-of-chronic-lung-disease&amp;quot;}&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2019/12/16/ap_19142747642115_sq-16e090975c74944153d0d12defe1ef6ed9b7f4cb-s100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2019/12/16/ap_19142747642115_sq-16e090975c74944153d0d12defe1ef6ed9b7f4cb-s100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;Vaping Nicotine Linked To Increased Risk Of Chronic Lung Disease&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Narrowing their search to people under the age of 35, they detected a sharp spike in June of 2019 — the same time that the doctors in Wisconsin reported their first cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res790213808&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap internallink insettwocolumn inset2col&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bucket img&quot;&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;featuredStackSquareImage776397270&quot; href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2019/11/06/776397270/more-teens-than-ever-are-vaping-heres-what-we-know-about-their-habits&quot; data-metrics=&quot;{&amp;quot;category&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Story to Story&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;action&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Click Internal Link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;label&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https:\/\/www.npr.org\/sections\/health-shots\/2019\/11\/06\/776397270\/more-teens-than-ever-are-vaping-heres-what-we-know-about-their-habits&amp;quot;}&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2019/11/06/promo-juul_sq-ab9ae988d44c7666c327207d2c01bda9b19087a8-s100-c15.png&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2019/11/06/promo-juul_sq-ab9ae988d44c7666c327207d2c01bda9b19087a8-s100.png&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;More Teens Than Ever Are Vaping. Here's What We Know About Their Habits&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The number of cases climbed from June into September, when they peaked. They have since declined, but the CDC still reports about 100 cases a week, and the death toll continues to tick up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The surveillance system doesn't automatically flag health concerns – often scientists dive into the data once their suspicion is raised, as it was in this case. The outbreak only became apparent in the data once researchers defined more closely what they were looking for and focused on one age group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;While electronic health data are increasingly powerful, they really can't yet replace the experience of clinicians like the ones in Wisconsin, who most definitely saved lives when they... reported these first cases,&quot; Hartnett says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The US Food and Drug Administration also announced Friday a crackdown on illicit vaping cartridges. The FDA and the Drug Enforcement Administration seized 44 websites advertising the sale of these products, as part of &quot;Operation Vapor Lock,&quot; its response to the lung injuries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can contact NPR Science Correspondent Richard Harris at&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:rharris@npr.org&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;rharris@npr.org&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 22:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>harmmonica</dc:creator>
<og:title>CDC Confirms A THC Additive, Vitamin E Acetate, Is The Culprit In Most Vaping Deaths</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2019/12/20/790154919/cdc-confirms-a-thc-contaminant-vitamin-e-acetate-the-culprit-in-most-vaping-deat</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>The spate of more than 2,500 acute vaping-related lung injuries tracked by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention is on the decline, epidemiologists say, and the number of deaths has slowed.</og:description>
<og:image>https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2019/12/20/gettyimages-954732484-1-_wide-3617b9f9099b38b2e35d48c274fa08d4dbfe0c65.jpg?s=1400</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2019/12/20/790154919/cdc-confirms-a-thc-contaminant-vitamin-e-acetate-the-culprit-in-most-vaping-deat</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>People Who Do Not Exist Invade Facebook</title>
<link>https://analysis.leadstories.com/3471185-fake-faces-people-Who-Do-Not-Exist-Invade-Facebook-To-Influence-2020-Elections.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://analysis.leadstories.com/3471185-fake-faces-people-Who-Do-Not-Exist-Invade-Facebook-To-Influence-2020-Elections.html</guid>
<description>&lt;header&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;e_category&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://analysis.leadstories.com/&quot;&gt;Analysis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/header&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;ContactSheet-001.jpg&quot; src=&quot;https://leadstories.com/xContactSheet-001.jpg.pagespeed.ic.kxes2t7dtq.jpg&quot; width=&quot;3000&quot; height=&quot;2160&quot; class=&quot;mt-image-none&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;EDITORS NOTE:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;27.684971098266&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Meet Carolina Chaney. Take a good look at &lt;a href=&quot;%20https://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=108299683992750&amp;amp;set=a.108299730659412&amp;amp;type=3&amp;amp;theater&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;her Facebook profile photo.&lt;/a&gt; Maybe she looks like your kid's math teacher or your doctor. Privacy settings block us from seeing anything about her, but we do see she is one of 11 administrators of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/groups/887399568328028/about/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&quot;Trump - 2020 KAG!#&quot; Facebook group.&lt;/a&gt; Carolina started in that role on Monday, December 9, 2019, and posted two stories on her first day. Those posts suggest that Carolina does not like &lt;a href=&quot;https://thebl.com/us-news/ken-starr-says-pelosi-has-arrogance-masquerading-as-patriotism-and-impeachment-is-profoundly-wrong.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;House Speaker Nancy Pelosi&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://thebl.com/politics/if-hunter-biden-has-done-nothing-wrong-then-why-is-joe-biden-so-upset.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;former Vice President Joe Biden.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Don't try to send Carolina a friend request. She is a person who does not exist. In fact, Carolina's profile image was created by the website &lt;a href=&quot;https://thispersondoesnotexist.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ThisPersonDoesNotExist.com.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sarah Thompson, a very real person and the authenticity analyst for Lead Stories, found Carolina Chaney and hundreds of other non-existent people serving as administrators and members of dozens of Facebook groups that solely promote the content of TheBL.com, a major web publisher. Thompson's previous investigation connected TheBL.com to hundreds of fake Facebook accounts using images of real people taken from other websites, but now she's discovered a new, unreal tactic.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The fake profiles help the publisher distort the popularity of its content, which then makes it more likely to show up on someone's timeline. When it is political content - which most often is what TheBL.com publishes - it is especially concerning.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TheBL is an undeclared offshoot of The Epoch Times and NTD media. NBC Tech News reporters Brandy Zadrozny and Ben Collins &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/tech-news/trump-qanon-impending-judgment-day-behind-facebook-fueled-rise-epoch-n1044121&quot;&gt;wrote about the connections&lt;/a&gt; between the Epoch Times and Falun Gong in August 2019. Alex Kasprak and Jordan Liles of Snopes &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.snopes.com/news/2019/10/11/pro-trump-outlet-linked-epoch-times/&quot;&gt;uncovered the links&lt;/a&gt; between The Epoch Times and TheBL. I wrote about my own investigation into TheBL network of Facebook pages, groups and profiles for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.secjuice.com/author/media-literacy-advocate-exposing-deceptive-practices-in-social-media/&quot;&gt;infosec blog SecJuice&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I began investigating TheBL network in October 2019, many of their fake Facebook profiles used images taken from the photo-sharing website &lt;a href=&quot;http://unsplash.com&quot;&gt;UnSplash.com&lt;/a&gt;, where photographers allow publishers to use their work for free as long as they are credited. TheBL ignored the credit requirement. The images were mostly young, good looking people of many races.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They also used repurposed real accounts, sometimes without even changing the name in the link. The URL for the &quot;Kathy Crum&quot; profile (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/thom.cuoi&quot;&gt;https://www.facebook.com/thom.cuoi&lt;/a&gt;) retained the name of &quot;Thom Cuoi&quot; for example, indicating the repurposed account originally belonged to someone in Vietnam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;kathythom.jpg&quot; src=&quot;https://leadstories.com/xkathythom.jpg.pagespeed.ic.qDS3cVIih0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;973&quot; height=&quot;1176&quot; class=&quot;mt-image-none&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Privacy settings often hid the profile history but sometimes not. I could see that just a few weeks earlier the profile had only posted in the Vietnamese language. The fraudulent nature of these profiles is obvious, yet they've been able to game Facebook for months, using false American identities to run more than 200 political pages and groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The profile picture &quot;Kathy&quot; used? An UnSplash stock photo by Allef Vinicius:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;embedly-card&quot; data-card-key=&quot;44ee665819f64c0cae2451b526b9590c&quot; data-card-controls=&quot;0&quot; data-card-image=&quot;http://images.unsplash.com/photo-1545928365-5da111f1bb2d?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;amp;q=80&amp;amp;fm=jpg&amp;amp;crop=entropy&amp;amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;amp;w=1080&amp;amp;fit=max&quot; data-card-type=&quot;article-full&quot; readability=&quot;6.0281690140845&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/0bWUNgYraHA&quot;&gt;Photo by Allef Vinicius on Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download this free HD photo of accessories, sunglasses, accessory and person by Allef Vinicius (@seteales)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In November 2019 I noticed a change in how TheBL network created new fake profiles. No more UnSplash images. The new faces were headshots which I recognized as having been AI generated, sourced from ThisPersonDoesNotExist.com. Production of new profiles also seems to be speeding up. Most of the 336 synthetic face profiles I found (of which 34 have already been deleted) were created since November 19th. Forty three of them were made on one Saturday - December 7, 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Carolina Chaney&quot; was created on Monday morning, December 10, 2019 for example. Just hours later, she was amplifying a link to TheBL.com in one of the network's many groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://leadstories.com/assets_c/2019/12/e18021f3a62b39651de1d2100af02ff3be08b4ca-3061904.html&quot; onclick=&quot;javascript:void(&amp;quot;mce-mt-event-placeholer&amp;quot;);return false&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://leadstories.com/assets_c/2019/12/xe18021f3a62b39651de1d2100af02ff3be08b4ca-thumb-900xauto-3061904.jpg.pagespeed.ic.MBsWy_fgYh.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Carolinagroupscreen.JPG&quot; class=&quot;mt-image-center&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;824&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So what is ThisPersonDoesNotExist.com?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In February 2019 Twitter was buzzing about the new website from Philip Wang, &lt;a href=&quot;https://thispersondoesnotexist.com/&quot;&gt;ThisPersonDoesNotExist.com&lt;/a&gt;. Visitors to the site are greeted by a random face on the screen. There's no article or introduction, just a human face. Refresh the page and a new face appears. You can do this all day and never see the same face twice. If you'd rather see cats, there is also &lt;a href=&quot;http://thiscatdoesnotexist.com&quot;&gt;ThisCatDoesNotExist.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;embedly-card&quot; data-card-key=&quot;44ee665819f64c0cae2451b526b9590c&quot; data-card-controls=&quot;0&quot; data-card-type=&quot;article-full&quot; readability=&quot;9.2518337408313&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2019/2/15/18226005/ai-generated-fake-people-portraits-thispersondoesnotexist-stylegan&quot;&gt;ThisPersonDoesNotExist.com uses AI to generate endless fake faces&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ability of AI to generate fake visuals is not yet mainstream knowledge, but a new website - ThisPersonDoesNotExist.com - offers a quick and persuasive education. The site is the creation of Philip Wang, a software engineer at Uber, and uses research released last year by chip designer Nvidia to create an endless stream of fake portraits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What makes this so compelling is that these people aren't real. The faces were created by an algorithm named StyleGAN developed by NVIDIA. GAN stands for &quot;generative adversarial network.&quot; The adversarial part has to do with two computer systems working together in a competitive way to learn to get better at generating something. In this case, it's making a digital representation of a human face that looks like a photograph. The super-realistic synthetic faces are a high-resolution 1024x1024 pixel square and are copyright free. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.copyright.gov/comp3/chap300/ch300-copyrightable-authorship.pdf&quot; title=&quot;US Copyright Law&quot;&gt;US Copyright law&lt;/a&gt; says that in order to have a copyright, the image must be made by a human.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be decisive, because if you want to save a picture from ThisPersonDoesNotExist, there's no going back. The face disappears when you refresh the page - replaced by a new image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reactions of the real people on Twitter when this came out were wide-ranging, from delight to dread. Many people wondered if they might randomly encounter a computer-generated doppelganger. Others predicted that this would be used by scammers and con artists. Actual artists dreamed of creative things that could be done with such realistic copyright free pictures. Some wondered how long it would take before this delightful innovation was used for some dastardly scheme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In March 2019, Adam Ghahramani wrote an alarmist piece in &lt;a href=&quot;https://venturebeat.com/2019/03/03/why-thispersondoesnotexist-and-its-copycats-need-to-be-restricted/&quot;&gt;VentureBeat&lt;/a&gt; about why this technology should be restricted. I wasn't ready to make up my mind. I wanted to know more. The availability of these faces might broaden a criminal's available choices, but there wasn't anything specific a synthetic face offered that wasn't already available with lower-tech options.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;More alarm bells rang in June when &lt;a href=&quot;https://apnews.com/bc2f19097a4c4fffaa00de6770b8a60d&quot;&gt;Raphael Satter's story&lt;/a&gt; titled &quot;Experts: Spy used AI-generated face to connect with targets&quot; went out on the Associated Press. Some well-connected people in Washington fell for a LinkedIn profile photo of a beautiful woman with auburn hair and a captivating gaze. She was not real, but a real spy was using the GAN image to lure targets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How To Detect A GAN Image?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Training myself, part one&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to see if I could learn to spot fake faces generated using the website so that first week I trained with my kids. It felt like playing, but I was studying. We carefully analyzed each image. In this exercise we had a given that 100-percent of the time we knew this was a fake photo. It was our job to pick out quirky clues that confirmed it. Learning the patterns in the hair and the stubble, counting teeth, incisors, canines. We called those iridescent blotches that would appear in some images &quot;beetles.&quot; We laughed at the funny hats that were sized to fit the entire hairstyle and not just the head. There were some men who seemed to be wearing a needle-felted toupee, and none of the women had a matching pair of earrings. (Kyle McDonald wrote &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@kcimc/how-to-recognize-fake-ai-generated-images-4d1f6f9a2842&quot;&gt;an excellent guide&lt;/a&gt; on these telltale signs.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Training myself, part two&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter Carl Bergstrom and Jevin West of Calling Bullshit with their practice tool, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.whichfaceisreal.com/&quot;&gt;WhichFaceIsReal.com&lt;/a&gt;. It was just what I was hoping for: a game that presented a real and a fake face next to each other. Now we had a different challenge, we know one of the photos is fake, but which one? Test-taking strategies can come in to play now. Just guessing randomly could give us a score of 50-percent, but now we had the advantage of being able to rule out the synthetic one if we could identify something real in the other photo. With this tool we learned a new set of things that only real people can have in their photos that the computer-generated face pictures don't. Things like logos, zippers, printed patterns, hands, watches, identifiable things in the background... and friends. We kept score. Then I tried for speed, I tried to learn to trust my instincts. I wanted it to become second nature. It wasn't easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hunting for synthetic faces in the wild&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was already formulating some ideas about geometry when I came across an image from Conspirator0 and Dr ZQ that provided the key I needed. They shared this haunting ethereal visage on Twitter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; readability=&quot;8.2554517133956&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Roughly a week ago, an AI for generating synthetic faces was made publicly available at thispersondoesnotexist(dot)com. We used it to generate 5000 sample faces. Pictured below is the result of blending all 5000 images.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;cc: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ZellaQuixote?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@ZellaQuixote&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/F2qTqKPSMu&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/F2qTqKPSMu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
-- Conspirador Norteño (@conspirator0) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/conspirator0/status/1096877542521344002?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;February 16, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the comments on this thread misinterpreted what they were seeing. They thought this blur was some sort of an average face. It's not. What this otherwise blurry image is depicting are eyes as anchor points. That no matter which way the faces were looking, left, right or center, the eyes were all rendered in the same position in the square. What an important revelation! The sample set of real human faces that were fed into the StyleGAN program had all been positioned, sized and cropped so that their eyes were a constant given position within the 1024x1024 pixel square. The resulting output reflects that underlying data structure. This geometric &quot;rule&quot; is then carried by the synthetic faces in the bounds of that perfect square -- into the bounds of a circular profile photo on Facebook, automatically snapping into place the way circles in squares do.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The graphic below shows eight synthetic profiles which were made by TheBL in November and all have names beginning with S: Smith, Smith, Smith, Shane, Scott, Susan, Sue and Sammy. Notice how the look of the image changes when it is cropped as a circle, but that at the widest and tallest dimensions -- none of the image has been lost. The large central image was made by layering all eight profiles on top of each other. Not the same process and Conspirador0 and Dr ZQ used -- but enough layers to get the idea across.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://leadstories.com/assets_c/2019/12/BlendedCollage-3061909.html&quot; onclick=&quot;javascript:void(&amp;quot;mce-mt-event-placeholer&amp;quot;);return false&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://leadstories.com/assets_c/2019/12/xBlendedCollage-thumb-900xauto-3061909.jpg.pagespeed.ic.TcZDLsZguQ.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;BlendedCollage.jpg&quot; class=&quot;mt-image-center&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;749&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, this geometry could be defeated by someone who cared to mix it up. There is another &lt;a href=&quot;https://generated.photos/&quot;&gt;website offering stock photo synthetic faces&lt;/a&gt; with a neutral background that can easily be made rectangular, unlike the random assortment offered up by ThisPersonDoesNotExist, their website format allows you to browse through a collection. Whoever is churning out the fake profiles for TheBL (it could be automated) is not even matching the fake names to the apparent gender of the synthetic faces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a sample of four of those, Andy, Kim, Pamela and William.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://leadstories.com/assets_c/2019/12/gridonsquares-3061912.html&quot; onclick=&quot;javascript:void(&amp;quot;mce-mt-event-placeholer&amp;quot;);return false&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://leadstories.com/assets_c/2019/12/xgridonsquares-thumb-900xauto-3061912.jpg.pagespeed.ic.WuN0V5opro.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;gridonsquares.jpg&quot; class=&quot;mt-image-center&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;900&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's look at them as they appear cropped into a Facebook profile. (Note: Garwood Pamela's rectangular profile box has a slightly different dimension because that picture got one like on Facebook.) In the middle row I put the square of the 5,000 face blend behind a slightly transparent layer of the profiles, and in the bottom row we can compare them side by side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://leadstories.com/profileswithblended.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;profileswithblended.jpg&quot; src=&quot;https://leadstories.com/assets_c/2019/12/xprofileswithblended-thumb-900xauto-3061915.jpg.pagespeed.ic.rsSuMy9Utr.jpg&quot; class=&quot;mt-image-center&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;720&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;What does it look like when TheBL installs an entire Facebook group administration team consisting of fake profiles made with synthetic faces?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://leadstories.com/assets_c/2019/12/AllignedAdmins-3061917.html&quot; onclick=&quot;javascript:void(&amp;quot;mce-mt-event-placeholer&amp;quot;);return false&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://leadstories.com/assets_c/2019/12/xAllignedAdmins-thumb-autox1757-3061917.jpg.pagespeed.ic.B-fvq0U3yS.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;AllignedAdmins.jpg&quot; class=&quot;mt-image-center&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;1757&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These synthetic face profiles are just as fake as any of the other BL profiles made with the photos from Unsplash. Inauthentic behavior is inauthentic behavior, no matter how it's dressed up. Some fake profiles never offer a face at all. It could be a bald eagle, a puppy, an American flag, or a bouquet of flowers (they are also doing lots of flowers now.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lead Stories has reported all fake profiles we found to Facebook just before publication of this article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come back next week as we'll take a closer look at what kind of content these fake people are putting out, and we'll also be examining some of the tools their &quot;operators&quot; seem to be using. Also expect some more information on what could be behind those flowers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Additional material&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;footer readability=&quot;2.745867768595&quot;&gt;&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;8.2376033057851&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;About the author:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;SarahThompson_userpic.png&quot; src=&quot;https://leadstories.com/xSarahThompson_userpic.png.pagespeed.ic.s6uaXpc9Ab.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sarah Thompson lives with her family and pets on a small farm in Southeastern Indiana. She founded a Facebook page and a blog called “Exploiting the Niche” in 2017 to help others learn about manipulative tactics and avoid scams on social media. Since then she has collaborated with journalists in the USA, Canada and Australia and &lt;span&gt;since December 2019 &lt;/span&gt;she works as a Social Media Authenticity Analyst at Lead Stories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://leadstories.com/sarah-thompson.html&quot;&gt;Read more about or contact Sarah Thompson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/footer&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 21:37:58 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ericzawo</dc:creator>
<og:title>Fake Faces: People Who Do Not Exist Invade Facebook To Influence 2020 Elections (Part 1) | Lead Stories</og:title>
<og:description>EDITORS NOTE: Meet Carolina Chaney. Take a good look at her Facebook profile photo. Maybe she looks like your kid's math teacher or your doctor. Privacy settings block us</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://analysis.leadstories.com/3471185-fake-faces-people-Who-Do-Not-Exist-Invade-Facebook-To-Influence-2020-Elections.html</og:url>
<og:image>https://leadstories.com/caption_3471201.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://analysis.leadstories.com/3471185-fake-faces-people-Who-Do-Not-Exist-Invade-Facebook-To-Influence-2020-Elections.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>