<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Apple introduces 8-core MacBook Pro</title>
<link>https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2019/05/apple-introduces-first-8-core-macbook-pro-the-fastest-mac-notebook-ever/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2019/05/apple-introduces-first-8-core-macbook-pro-the-fastest-mac-notebook-ever/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Apple updated MacBook Pro with faster 8th- and 9th-generation Intel Core processors, bringing eight cores to MacBook Pro for the first time. MacBook Pro now delivers two times faster performance than a quad-core MacBook Pro and 40 percent more performance than a 6-core MacBook Pro, making it the fastest Mac notebook ever.&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; These new processors, combined with powerful graphics, the brilliant and colorful Retina display, super-fast SSDs, the Apple T2 Security Chip, all-day battery life and macOS, make MacBook Pro the world’s best pro notebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Whether it’s college students mastering a course of study, developers building world-class apps or video editors creating feature films, we’re constantly amazed at what our customers do with their MacBook Pro,” said Tom Boger, Apple’s senior director of Mac Product Marketing. “Now with 8-core processors for an incredible performance boost, along with its stunning Retina display, fast storage, all-day battery life and running macOS, MacBook Pro continues to be the world’s best pro notebook and we can’t wait to get it into our customer’s hands to see what they do next.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 16:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>css</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Apple introduces first 8-core MacBook Pro, the fastest Mac notebook ever</og:title>
<og:description>Apple updated MacBook Pro with faster 8th- and 9th-generation Intel Core processors, bringing eight cores to MacBook Pro for the first time.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2019/05/apple-introduces-first-8-core-macbook-pro-the-fastest-mac-notebook-ever/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/mac/standard/apple_macbookpro-8-core_video-editing_05212019_LP_hero.jpg.og.jpg?201905212030</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2019/05/apple-introduces-first-8-core-macbook-pro-the-fastest-mac-notebook-ever/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Technical Debt</title>
<link>https://martinfowler.com/bliki/TechnicalDebt.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://martinfowler.com/bliki/TechnicalDebt.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;tags&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://martinfowler.com/tags/technical%20debt.html&quot;&gt;technical debt&lt;/a&gt; · &lt;a href=&quot;https://martinfowler.com/tags/clean%20code.html&quot;&gt;clean code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;tagLabel&quot;&gt;tags:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Software systems are prone to the build up of &lt;strong&gt;cruft&lt;/strong&gt; - deficiencies in internal quality that make it harder than it would ideally be to modify and extend the system further. Technical Debt is a metaphor, coined by Ward Cunningham, that frames how to think about dealing with this cruft, thinking of it like a financial debt. The extra effort that it takes to add new features is the interest paid on the debt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fullPhoto&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://martinfowler.com/bliki/images/tech-debt/sketch.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine I have a confusing module structure in my code base. I need to add a new feature. If the module structure was clear, then it would take me four days to add the feature but with this cruft, it takes me six days. The two day difference is the interest on the debt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What most appeals to me about the debt metaphor is how it frames how I think about how to deal with this cruft. I could take five days to clean up the modular structure, removing that cruft, metaphorically paying off the principal. If I only do it for this one feature, that's no gain, as I'd take nine days instead of six. But if I have two more similar features coming up, then I'll end up faster by removing the cruft first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stated like that, this sounds like a simple matter of working the numbers, and any manager with a spreadsheet should figure out the choices. Sadly since we &lt;a href=&quot;https://martinfowler.com/bliki/CannotMeasureProductivity.html&quot;&gt;CannotMeasureProductivity&lt;/a&gt;, none of these costs are objectively measurable. We can &lt;em&gt;estimate&lt;/em&gt; how long it takes to do a feature, &lt;em&gt;estimate&lt;/em&gt; what it might be like if the cruft was removed, and &lt;em&gt;estimate&lt;/em&gt; the cost of removing the cruft. But our accuracy of such estimates is pretty low.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given this, usually the best route is to do what we usually do with financial debts, pay the principal off gradually. On the first feature I'll spend an extra couple of days to remove some of the cruft. That may be enough to reduce the interest rate on future enhancements to a single day. That's still going to take extra time, but by removing the cruft I'm making it cheaper for future changes to this code. The great benefit of gradual improvement like this is that it naturally means we spend more time on removing cruft in those areas that we modify frequently, which are exactly those areas of the code base where we most need the cruft to be removed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thinking of this as paying interest versus paying of principal can help decide which cruft to tackle. If I have a terrible area of the code base, one that's a nightmare to change, it's not a problem if I don't have to modify it. I only trigger an interest payment when I have to work with that part of the software (this is a place where the metaphor breaks down, since financial interest payments are triggered by the passage of time). So crufty but stable areas of code can be left alone. In contrast, areas of high activity need a zero-tolerance attitude to cruft, because the interest payments are cripplingly high. This is especially important since cruft accumulates where developers make changes without paying attention to internal quality - the more changes, the greater risk of cruft building up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The metaphor of debt is sometimes used to justify neglecting internal quality. The argument is that it takes time and effort to stop cruft from building up. If there new features that are needed urgently, then perhaps it's best to take on the debt, accepting that this debt will have to be managed in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The danger here is that most of the time this analysis isn't done well. Cruft has a quick impact, slowing down the very new features that are needed quickly. Teams who do this end up maxing out all their credit cards, but still delivering later than they would have had they put the effort into higher internal quality. Here the metaphor often leads people astray, as the dynamics don't really match those for financial loans. Taking on debt to speed delivery only works if you stay below the design payoff line of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://martinfowler.com/bliki/DesignStaminaHypothesis.html&quot;&gt;DesignStaminaHypothesis&lt;/a&gt;, and teams hit that line is weeks rather than months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are regular debates whether different kinds of cruft should be considered as debt or not. I found it useful to think about whether the debt is acquired deliberately and whether it is prudent or reckless - leading me to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://martinfowler.com/bliki/TechnicalDebtQuadrant.html&quot;&gt;TechnicalDebtQuadrant&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;furtherReading&quot; readability=&quot;35.544609665428&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Further Reading&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as I can tell, Ward first introduced this concept in an experience report for &lt;a href=&quot;http://c2.com/doc/oopsla92.html&quot;&gt;OOPSLA 1992&lt;/a&gt;. It has also been discussed on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.c2.com/cgi/wiki?ComplexityAsDebt&quot;&gt;wiki&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ward Cunningham has a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pqeJFYwnkjE&quot;&gt;video talk&lt;/a&gt; where he discusses this metaphor he created.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dave Nicolette expands on Ward's view of technical debt with a &lt;a href=&quot;http://neopragma.com/index.php/2019/03/30/technical-debt-the-man-the-metaphor-the-message/&quot;&gt;fine case study&lt;/a&gt; of what I refer to as &lt;a href=&quot;https://martinfowler.com/bliki/TechnicalDebtQuadrant.html&quot;&gt;Prudent Intentional debt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple of readers sent in some similarly good names. David Panariti refers to ugly programming as &lt;strong&gt;deficit programming&lt;/strong&gt;. Apparently he originally started using a few years ago when it fitted in with government policy; I suppose it's natural again now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scott Wood suggested &quot;&lt;strong&gt;Technical Inflation&lt;/strong&gt; could be viewed as the ground lost when the current level of technology surpasses that of the foundation of your product to the extent that it begins losing compatibility with the industry. Examples of this would be falling behind in versions of a language to the point where your code is no longer compatible with main stream compilers.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.construx.com/10x_Software_Development/Technical_Debt/&quot;&gt;Steve McConnell&lt;/a&gt; brings out several good points in the metaphor, particularly how keeping your unintended debt down gives you more room to intentionally take on debt when it's useful to do so. I also like his notion of minimum payments (which are very high to fix issues with embedded systems as opposed to web sites).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aaron Erickson talks about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.informit.com/articles/article.aspx?p=1401640&quot;&gt;Enron financing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.crisp.se/2013/10/11/henrikkniberg/good-and-bad-technical-debt&quot;&gt;Henrik Kniberg argues&lt;/a&gt; that it's older technical debt that causes the greatest problem and that it's wise to a qualitative debt ceiling to help manage it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Erik Dietrich discusses the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.daedtech.com/human-cost-tech-debt/&quot;&gt;human cost of technical debt&lt;/a&gt;: team infighting, atrophied skills, and attrition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;revisions&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Revisions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I originally published this post on October 1 2003. I gave it a thorough rewrite in April 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 16:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>BerislavLopac</dc:creator>
<og:title>bliki: TechnicalDebt</og:title>
<og:url>https://martinfowler.com/bliki/TechnicalDebt.html</og:url>
<og:description>Technical Debt is a metaphor for the consequences of cruft. You either have to accept a drag on further features (paying interest) or fix the software (paying the principal)</og:description>
<og:image>https://martinfowler.com/bliki/images/tech-debt/sketch.png</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://martinfowler.com/bliki/TechnicalDebt.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Bullshit I had to go through while organizing a software conference</title>
<link>https://notamonadtutorial.com/the-bullshit-i-had-to-go-through-while-organizing-a-software-conference-4de1225d0acb</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://notamonadtutorial.com/the-bullshit-i-had-to-go-through-while-organizing-a-software-conference-4de1225d0acb</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;uiScale uiScale-ui--regular uiScale-caption--regular u-flexCenter u-marginVertical24 u-fontSize15 js-postMetaLockup&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;u-flex0&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link u-baseColor--link avatar&quot; href=&quot;https://notamonadtutorial.com/@unbalancedparen?source=post_header_lockup&quot; data-action=&quot;show-user-card&quot; data-action-source=&quot;post_header_lockup&quot; data-action-value=&quot;d257e779bd2c&quot; data-action-type=&quot;hover&quot; data-user-id=&quot;d257e779bd2c&quot; data-collection-slug=&quot;this-is-not-a-monad-tutorial&quot; dir=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/fit/c/100/100/1*8CQ8azFtqLAzUYdnx--Vxg.png&quot; class=&quot;avatar-image u-size50x50&quot; alt=&quot;Go to the profile of unbalancedparentheses&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;c382&quot; id=&quot;c382&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;This time I am not writing an interview or a technical post. I am writing about a series of events that took place in the context of the conference organization which exposed me to a situation that is now out of control despite my efforts to avoid conflict. The impact these events are having oblige me to write this article as a tool to clarify what happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;8b2a&quot; id=&quot;8b2a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I expect this specific case illustrates the type of things that might happen to anyone out there trying to create something for the community. I hope the article it is not too boring, I want to give more precise information but I can’t yet. In the end, the truth comes out and people show their true colors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;e75a&quot; id=&quot;e75a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;Reach me via twitter at&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/unbalancedparen&quot; data-href=&quot;https://twitter.com/unbalancedparen&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;@unbalancedparen&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;if you have any comments.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*EuMfVua_a5Ch7RaAbc9gRQ.jpeg&quot; data-width=&quot;3088&quot; data-height=&quot;2320&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*EuMfVua_a5Ch7RaAbc9gRQ.jpeg&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*EuMfVua_a5Ch7RaAbc9gRQ.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Teammates and I in last year’s conference
&lt;p name=&quot;2e59&quot; id=&quot;2e59&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;Why organize a conference?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;20bf&quot; id=&quot;20bf&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Organizing a conference involves a great expenditure of time and money. True, sponsors make up for a big part of financing, and ticket sales help. Still, conferences tend to net to a loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;62f0&quot; id=&quot;62f0&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Then why do we do it? Because they are also an enormous source of satisfaction. For a couple of days, conferences generate a vibrant community, where people have the opportunity to grow and learn together, renew passion for their work and create relationships that will evolve in new projects that will last far beyond the scope of the conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;2d09&quot; id=&quot;2d09&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;What are the usual problems that appear while organizing a conference?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;0693&quot; id=&quot;0693&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Anyone that has organized an event of this scale knows how hard it is to sell tickets, publicise, organize logistics, get sponsors, look for accomodation, buy airfare tickets, coordinate catering, pay for insurance, arrange stands and manage audio and video recording. Also, differences within the organizing team and diverse points of view will most likely appear. Basically, “whatever can go wrong, will go wrong”, and this is quite a challenge during the preproduction and during the conference itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;1bfd&quot; id=&quot;1bfd&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;What has been our experience so far?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;aeda&quot; id=&quot;aeda&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Until now, my team and I have organized several meetups and participated in lots of conferences; but only last year we took the plunge and organized our first software conference, called &lt;a href=&quot;https://buzzconf.org/&quot; data-href=&quot;https://buzzconf.org/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;BuzzConf&lt;/a&gt;. This will be the second time we started a new telecommunication conference called &lt;a href=&quot;https://zruput.org/&quot; data-href=&quot;https://zruput.org/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Zruput&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;2a1e&quot; id=&quot;2a1e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;We learned how to deal with the unexpected: flights were cancelled, the catering messed up the gluten-free food, the cell phone of one of our speakers went missing during the conference, the audio and video recording of the talks failed and some sponsors paid months after the conference. Despite these inconveniences, which are normal, it was an incredible experience and we enjoyed it greatly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;d43b&quot; id=&quot;d43b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;We were able to bring people who develop Linux’s kernel, who are part of the Rust language core team, who make important contributions to distributed systems, people who launch satellites, among other things. The people we met and the things we learned broadened our horizons. This year we are expecting computer scientists that were involved in the design of Haskell, that created an amazing package managers and that implemented Python packages, used by hedge funds, for statistical modeling. We know we are privileged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;89f7&quot; id=&quot;89f7&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;What happened this year?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;b90e&quot; id=&quot;b90e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;My team and I were contacted by different people to warn us that they were uncomfortable with the participation of a speaker and her boyfriend in our conference. Sadly, I can’t go into details until the legal issue is over. This communication took us by surprise since we had performed a basic background check on the chosen speakers to avoid these kinds of issues. Like many of you who are reading this article, I am skeptical of what people I don’t know say over the Internet. I initially hesitated to do something based upon these comments when my team and I discussed the matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;f89a&quot; id=&quot;f89a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;When you are in a difficult situation, the most reasonable thing to do is to search for the help of those who can provide knowledge and experience, so we consulted on what we should do with different people on what to do. Several people who knew both of them confirmed that they had had problems with them in the past. We also talked with the organizers of other conferences and with dev that are part of gender groups focalized in technology and all of them recommended us to take distance from them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;0ce8&quot; id=&quot;0ce8&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;This was how we finally decided that the best thing to do was to inform the speaker she wasn’t going to be a member of the conference. It was a difficult decision in which we prioritized the participation of the public that had reached out to us while also knowing that many people, especially women, wouldn’t come to the conference if we did nothing about this situation. Neither I nor the rest of the organization wanted to create a problematic situation, we were just trying to solve a difficult conflict in the best possible way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;3c3e&quot; id=&quot;3c3e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Therefore, on April 25, 2019, I, along with an employee of my company, communicated to her our decision in a meeting held in a place of her choice. She took it badly. We knew it was hard news to take on. Nevertheless, we didn’t expect a threatening reaction followed by several emails, Twitter DMs, persistent phone calls and Whatsapp messages. She even texted my girlfriend, one of the organizers of the conference, whose telephone number is not public and wasn’t given to her at any moment. At the same time, she started contacting other speakers of the conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;31ae&quot; id=&quot;31ae&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;Problems escalate&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;c4ac&quot; id=&quot;c4ac&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;A few hours later, I was contacted via Whatsapp by a person who told me he needed to meet me to talk about the conference because he had a big problem which could be solved by talking. That person identified himself. I didn’t know who he was and I replied that I had no problem speaking but I didn’t know how I could help him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;fc51&quot; id=&quot;fc51&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;At around the same time I got a message from an employee of my company who told me that the same person had contacted a speaker of our conference and requested a meeting with him. The speaker confirmed this to me and told me he had felt uncomfortable with the way in which this person had written to him. When this happened, I asked around and acquaintances of mine told me that this person was the boyfriend of the speaker we had decided wouldn’t be a part of the conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;34f9&quot; id=&quot;34f9&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;At this point I found out this man is an internationally renowned information security specialist. He found vulnerabilities in known operating systems and privacy-oriented messaging platforms. I was learning all this in the spur of the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;46a1&quot; id=&quot;46a1&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;It was late in the day, but before I went to sleep I found an anonymous threat which stated private information about me would be published. I can’t confirm who the author was, as it was anonymous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;5bd7&quot; id=&quot;5bd7&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;Conference encounter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;99e1&quot; id=&quot;99e1&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Two days later on April 27th, a software conference took place that has no relationship with the conference I am organizing. I went there to meet two acquaintances. After meeting with them I decided to tour around and see the different stands of the conference. At that precise moment I saw the former speaker. She was calling the security of the event and using her cellphone to record me. She yelling that I was at the conference to stalk her, and that I was harassing her and following her. I never thought something like this could ever happen. It is worth noting that, at this point, I had only talked over the phone with her once, met her in person also once and, as I stated before, I had received several persistent communications from her. Now she was accusing me of following her to her work, to a conference and of being a stalker. One of the organizers of this conference intervened and let her yell at me instead of trying to solve the issue. A few days after I learned he was a close friend of her and her partner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;dc66&quot; id=&quot;dc66&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I had to leave the conference, depressed by the whole situation. Luckily, my girlfriend and other friends were there to help me. I was just attending a conference and was subjected, along with my acquaintances, to a very unpleasant moment by being unfairly accused by a person I didn’t know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;0888&quot; id=&quot;0888&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;They went public&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;4a4d&quot; id=&quot;4a4d&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;After this incident, a friend gave me a heads up that the boyfriend of this person had taken to Twitter to post that I was harassing and threatening his girlfriend. He even suggested that I was personally attacking him through his girlfriend. He later deleted this tweet but I managed to save screenshots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;3331&quot; id=&quot;3331&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;After this I felt powerless and despaired. I never imagined that telling someone she would not speak at the conference would expose me and my team to this sort of situation. Several people contacted us to ask what was going on and why I was being accused of harassing a woman. I had to give explanations to our sponsors. Being accused like that caused me harm. He had already gone public with his version, so I decided to tell my side of the story on Twitter too. I needed people to know the facts: we had contacted a speaker to tell her she was no longer a part of the conference, we were harassed and I was the victim of a false accusation that had a commercial impact for me. I had to talk with clients, sponsors and employees to explain what was happening. Due to all of this, I decided to file the corresponding lawsuits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;e3f7&quot; id=&quot;e3f7&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;While I was sleeping, early morning May 4th, my phone began to ring incessantly for minutes with notifications. It was an employee’s phone sending messages via Signal, for several minutes. I called him to ask what was going on. He said he hadn’t touched his phone. I asked him to turn off his phone, but the messages kept coming. At the same time, another employee called me to tell me he was getting those messages too and wanted to know what was happening. To be clear, I don’t think in any way somebody exploited a vulnerability of Signal, but it was used. In the years I have been using Signal, this never happened to me nor do I know of similar cases, but I have talked with security specialists that pointed me to how this might have happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;cb3e&quot; id=&quot;cb3e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;This is just one of many similar issues I had to go through since then, but this article would become long and boring if I listed them all, and I think you already get the idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;28b3&quot; id=&quot;28b3&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;What is the best way to act in these cases?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;f553&quot; id=&quot;f553&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Sometimes, our initial reaction to this type of situation is keeping quiet and hope it goes away. As soon as you start talking you start being judged and getting deep into even a bigger problem. These are the reasons why we hesitated within my team to make this situation public. We didn’t want to waste time, energy and resources on this affair. Generally, the best scenario is to talk with the involved parties, to cooperate and to seek a solution that doesn’t make the problem bigger. This isn’t always possible. In this case they went public and accused me and I had to explain what happened. I had to explain to sponsors, clients, employees and other members of the community what happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;b795&quot; id=&quot;b795&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;What’s the legal status of the conflict?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;1299&quot; id=&quot;1299&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I’m currently analyzing with different attorneys and advisers the steps to take next. One of the pieces of advice they gave me were not to give any names to avoid escalating the situation even further. It pains me to do so, because I feel I need to warn the community so that this doesn’t happen to more people. But I understand this is the way things work and right now I need to trust that the justice system in my country will do its work. Therefore, I will take the necessary legal actions to bring light to this situation, and I will request the legal system to publish all necessary documents to prove I acted with integrity at all times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;063c&quot; id=&quot;063c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;Why is it important to create safe and diverse cooperation spaces?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;ed89&quot; id=&quot;ed89&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Some people consider that software conferences are focusing too much on inclusion and diversity. What they want is for conferences to be exclusively technical. This makes sense only in abstract. The problem with this is that they aren’t taking into account that many people can’t partake in the way they could and would like to. There is no way of making a technical conference if some people feel insecure or uncomfortable. This is why inclusion and diversity are essential in these kinds of events, as well as the participation of the groups that promote these values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;d303&quot; id=&quot;d303&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;We know that hostile environments are often generated where harassment and uncomfortable situations make women and minorities step aside. It is important to generate a space where everybody, no matter what gender, ethnicity, religion or ideology, is able to share knowledge in a friendly, pleasant environment with a collaboration spirit. There are several ways to achieve this. One of them is to work along gender and minority technology groups, which are doing an excellent work in promoting bigger diversity, and cooperate with them. Giving discounts to those minorities that have less resources is another way. It is also necessary to be attentive towards potential conflict situations that may occur so we can solve them by following a code of conduct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;5d63&quot; id=&quot;5d63&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;This year, only 2 of the 9 speakers in our conference will be women. The conference is still really behind its gender equality goals in this sense. We are working with different women’s groups to improve. I am sure that we will do better in the following years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;05e6&quot; id=&quot;05e6&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;How will we move forward?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;cc79&quot; id=&quot;cc79&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Today, we are working to leave all this behind us, but since there are legal complaints, this will probably take more time, more money and more energy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;93e8&quot; id=&quot;93e8&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Being involved in situations like this is part of the risk one takes when organizing a conference and facing a greater deal of public exposure. It was probably naive of me not to consider these kind of things could happen. I actually believed that the hard part of organizing a conference was the logistics, but I learned that sometimes the hardest part is the human factor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;61b8&quot; id=&quot;61b8&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The best way to face this type of situation is to always be faithful to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lambdaclass/buzzconf/blob/master/CODE_OF_CONDUCT.md&quot; data-href=&quot;https://github.com/lambdaclass/buzzconf/blob/master/CODE_OF_CONDUCT.md&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;code of conduct&lt;/a&gt;, not give in to undue pressure and consult groups dedicated to ethics, gender and minorities in technology because they know the most about these issues. Also, to lay things out in the open, speak up and not let there be a taboo is essential to prevent other people to go through the same ordeal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;ab19&quot; id=&quot;ab19&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p graf--trailing&quot;&gt;Finally, I would like to thank everybody that contacted us. In times like these, those gestures are worth a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 16:03:37 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>unbalancedparen</dc:creator>
<og:title>The bullshit I had to go through while organizing a software conference</og:title>
<og:url>https://notamonadtutorial.com/the-bullshit-i-had-to-go-through-while-organizing-a-software-conference-4de1225d0acb</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*EuMfVua_a5Ch7RaAbc9gRQ.jpeg</og:image>
<og:description>This time I am not writing an interview or a technical post. I am writing about a series of events that took place in the context of the…</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://notamonadtutorial.com/the-bullshit-i-had-to-go-through-while-organizing-a-software-conference-4de1225d0acb?gi=dc2d62a5f129</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A Solution for Loneliness: Get out and volunteer, research suggests</title>
<link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/a-solution-for-loneliness/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/a-solution-for-loneliness/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;mura-region mura-region-loose&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;mura-region-local&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was riding a bus recently and noticed an older man sitting outside a coffee shop on a busy sidewalk. He had set up a chessboard on the table in front of him, and he watched as people passed by, mostly engrossed in their phones. His eyes kept jumping from person to person, searching for someone to notice and join him for a game of chess. Right before the traffic cleared and my bus moved on, he reached over to make the first move, and then resumed his searching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Loneliness is rampant, and it’s killing us—&lt;a href=&quot;https://journals.plos.org/plosmedicine/article?id=10.1371/journal.pmed.1000316&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;literally&lt;/a&gt;. Anywhere from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.com/graphic-detail/2018/08/31/loneliness-is-pervasive-and-rising-particularly-among-the-young&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;one quarter&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.multivu.com/players/English/8294451-cigna-us-loneliness-survey/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;one half&lt;/a&gt; of Americans feel lonely a lot of the time, which puts them at risk for developing a range of physical and mental illnesses, including heart disease, cancer, diabetes, and depression. This is a public health problem that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/to-combat-loneliness-promote-social-health1/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;needs to be addressed&lt;/a&gt; on a wide scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But at the individual level, there is much we can do to ward off loneliness. One strategy is to bring a chessboard to a busy street and wait for someone to play with you. For the older man’s sake, I sincerely hope that this is effective, but I can’t be sure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another strategy is to volunteer. In a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncvo.org.uk/images/documents/policy_and_research/volunteering/Volunteer-experience_Full-Report.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;recent survey&lt;/a&gt; of over 10,000 people in the UK, two-thirds reported that volunteering helped them feel less isolated. Similarly, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://academic.oup.com/psychsocgerontology/article/73/3/501/3938841&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;2018 study&lt;/a&gt; of nearly 6,000 people across the US examined widows who, unsurprisingly, felt lonelier than married adults. After starting to volunteer for two or more hours per week, their average level of loneliness subsided to match that of married adults, even after controlling for demographics, baseline health, personality traits, and other social involvement. These benefits may be especially strong the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.royalvoluntaryservice.org.uk/Uploads/Documents/Reports%20and%20Reviews/the_impact_of_volunteering_on_wellbeing_in_later_life.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;older you are&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/12730314&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;more often&lt;/a&gt; you volunteer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participating in volunteer opportunities may help alleviate loneliness and its related health impact for several reasons. The first and most obvious is that it’s a meaningful way to connect with others and make new friends. I experienced this firsthand when I moved to San Francisco and knew almost no one. After joining a young professionals volunteer group, getting involved with a local nonprofit serving seniors and adults with disabilities, and both organizing and assisting with neighborhood events, I felt my own sense of community and social support increase dramatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, volunteering can make up for the loss of meaning that commonly occurs with loneliness. Research using the UCLA Loneliness Scale and Meaning in Life Questionnaire has shown that more loneliness is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2717555/#S16title&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;associated&lt;/a&gt; with less meaning. This makes sense, given our deeply rooted &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Mark_Leary2/publication/15420847_The_Need_to_Belong_Desire_for_Interpersonal_Attachments_as_a_Fundamental_Human_Motivation/links/5b647053aca272e3b6af9211/The-Need-to-Belong-Desire-for-Interpersonal-Attachments-as-a-Fundamental-Human-Motivation.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;need for belonging&lt;/a&gt;. By volunteering for social causes that are important to us, we can gain a sense of purpose, which in turn may shield us from negative health outcomes. For example, purpose in life has been linked to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022399913000391&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;reduced&lt;/a&gt; likelihood of stroke and &lt;a href=&quot;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1111/j.2044-8295.1992.tb02429.x&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;greater&lt;/a&gt; psychological well-being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Third, loneliness and isolation can &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/23362501&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;lead to&lt;/a&gt; cognitive decline, such as memory loss. But &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ted.com/talks/lisa_genova_what_you_can_do_to_prevent_alzheimer_s/transcript&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;according&lt;/a&gt; to the neuroscientist Lisa Genova, people who regularly engage in mentally stimulating activities build up more neural connections and are subsequently more resilient to symptoms of Alzheimer’s. So, volunteering is one way to stay engaged and stimulated, rather than isolated and lonely, and thereby protect against cognitive decline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These insights may be especially relevant for the growing senior population. By 2030, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.census.gov/newsroom/press-releases/2018/cb18-41-population-projections.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;one in five&lt;/a&gt; residents in the US will be of retirement age, may no longer have work to provide purpose and connection, and will be prone to isolation due to increased physical limitations and loved ones passing away. Given that loneliness seems to be &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/22303614&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;most prevalent&lt;/a&gt; among those over 65 and under 25 years old, mentoring across ages could be a powerful way to volunteer and connect. Indeed, I recently experimented with &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/world-economic-forum-global-shapers-san-francisco/bridging-the-intergenerational-divide-5ee500025774&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;hosting&lt;/a&gt; an intergenerational friendship gathering and found that it left baby boomers and millennials—not to mention me—feeling gratified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish I could have stopped my bus and skipped my plans that day to play chess with the older man. He struck me as a symbol of our times: people wanting desperately to connect—not through a screen, but face-to-face, with others from their community. Now more than ever, we have a real need and opportunity to build a culture of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/to-combat-loneliness-promote-social-health1/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;social health&lt;/a&gt;, one interaction at a time. Volunteering is a great way to start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 15:49:18 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>headalgorithm</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>A Solution for Loneliness</og:title>
<og:description>Get out and volunteer, research suggests</og:description>
<og:image>https://static.scientificamerican.com/sciam/cache/file/98EA5202-9A46-4C37-A03304875C5889D8.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/a-solution-for-loneliness/</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/a-solution-for-loneliness/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Free Wolfram Engine for Developers</title>
<link>https://blog.stephenwolfram.com/2019/05/launching-today-free-wolfram-engine-for-developers/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.stephenwolfram.com/2019/05/launching-today-free-wolfram-engine-for-developers/</guid>
<description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-arent-you-using-our-technology&quot;&gt;Why Aren’t You Using Our Technology?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Text&quot;&gt;It happens far too often. I’ll be talking to a software developer, and they’ll be saying how great they think our technology is, and how it helped them so much in school, or in doing R&amp;amp;D. But then I’ll ask them, “So, are you using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolfram.com/language/&quot;&gt;Wolfram Language&lt;/a&gt; and its &lt;a href=&quot;https://reference.wolfram.com/language/&quot;&gt;computational intelligence&lt;/a&gt; in your production software system?” Sometimes the answer is yes. But too often, there’s an awkward silence, and then they’ll say, “Well, no. Could I?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Text&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolfram.com/developer/&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-20690&quot; title=&quot;Free Wolfram Engine for Developers&quot; src=&quot;https://blog.stephenwolfram.com/data/uploads/2019/05/wolfram-engine-for-developers.png&quot; alt=&quot;Free Wolfram Engine for Developers&quot; width=&quot;173&quot; height=&quot;157&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I want to make sure the answer to this can always be: “Yes, it’s easy!” And to help achieve that, we’re releasing today the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolfram.com/developer/&quot;&gt;Free Wolfram Engine for Developers&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a full engine for the Wolfram Language, that can be deployed on any system—and called from programs, languages, web servers, or anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Text&quot;&gt;The Wolfram Engine is the heart of all our products. It’s what implements the Wolfram Language, with all its computational intelligence, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolfram.com/algorithmbase/&quot;&gt;algorithms&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolfram.com/knowledgebase/&quot;&gt;knowledgebase&lt;/a&gt;, and so on. It’s what powers our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolfram.com/wolfram-one&quot;&gt;desktop products&lt;/a&gt; (including &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolfram.com/mathematica&quot;&gt;Mathematica&lt;/a&gt;), as well as our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolframcloud.com/&quot;&gt;cloud platform&lt;/a&gt;. It’s what’s inside &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolframalpha.com&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Wolfram|Alpha&lt;/a&gt;—as well as an increasing number of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolfram.com/enterprise-private-cloud&quot;&gt;major production systems&lt;/a&gt; out in the world. And as of today, we’re making it available for anyone to download, for free, to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolfram.com/engine/&quot;&gt;use in their software development projects&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-wolfram-language&quot;&gt;The Wolfram Language&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Text&quot;&gt;Many people know the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolfram.com/language/&quot;&gt;Wolfram Language&lt;/a&gt; (often in the form of Mathematica) as a powerful system for interactive computing—and for doing R&amp;amp;D, education, data science and “computational X” for many X. But increasingly it’s also being used “behind the scenes” as a key component in building production software systems. And what the Free Wolfram Engine for Developers now does is to package it so it’s convenient to insert into a whole range of software engineering environments and projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Text&quot;&gt;It’s worth explaining a bit about &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.stephenwolfram.com/2019/05/what-weve-built-is-a-computational-language-and-thats-very-important/&quot;&gt;how I see the Wolfram Language these days&lt;/a&gt;. (By the way, you can run it immediately on the web in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.open.wolframcloud.com/view/newNotebook?funnel=OpenCloudWLSandbox#sidebar=sandbox-links&quot;&gt;Wolfram Language Sandbox&lt;/a&gt;.) The most important thing is to realize that the Wolfram Language as it now exists is really a new kind of thing: a &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.stephenwolfram.com/2019/05/what-weve-built-is-a-computational-language-and-thats-very-important/&quot;&gt;full-scale computational language&lt;/a&gt;. Yes, it’s an extremely powerful and productive (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolfram.com/language/for-experts/&quot;&gt;symbolic, functional, …&lt;/a&gt;) programming language. But it’s much more than that. Because it’s got the unique feature of having a huge amount of computational knowledge built right into it: knowledge about algorithms, knowledge about the real world, knowledge about how to automate things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Text&quot;&gt;We’ve been steadily building up what’s now the Wolfram Language for &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.stephenwolfram.com/2018/06/weve-come-a-long-way-in-30-years-but-you-havent-seen-anything-yet/&quot;&gt;more than 30 years&lt;/a&gt;—and one thing I’m particularly proud of (though it’s hard work; e.g. check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.stephenwolfram.com/livestreams/&quot;&gt;livestreams&lt;/a&gt;!) is how &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolfram.com/language/principles/&quot;&gt;uniform, elegant and stable a design&lt;/a&gt; we’ve been able to maintain across the whole language. There are now altogether &lt;a href=&quot;https://reference.wolfram.com/language/&quot;&gt;5000+ functions in the language&lt;/a&gt;, covering everything from &lt;a href=&quot;https://reference.wolfram.com/language/#VisualizationAndGraphics&quot;&gt;visualization&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolfram.com/featureset/machine-learning/&quot;&gt;machine learning&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://reference.wolfram.com/language/#SymbolicAndNumericComputation&quot;&gt;numerics&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://reference.wolfram.com/language/guide/ImageProcessing.html&quot;&gt;image computation&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://reference.wolfram.com/language/guide/GeometricComputation.html&quot;&gt;geometry&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://reference.wolfram.com/language/#HigherMathematicalComputation&quot;&gt;higher math&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolfram.com/natural-language-understanding/&quot;&gt;natural language understanding&lt;/a&gt;—as well as lots of areas of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolfram.com/knowledgebase/&quot;&gt;real-world knowledge&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://reference.wolfram.com/language/#GeographicDataAndComputation&quot;&gt;geo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://reference.wolfram.com/language/#ScientificandMedicalDataAndComputation&quot;&gt;medical&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://reference.wolfram.com/language/#SocialCulturalAndLinguisticData&quot;&gt;cultural&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://reference.wolfram.com/language/#EngineeringDataAndComputation&quot;&gt;engineering&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://reference.wolfram.com/language/#ScientificandMedicalDataAndComputation&quot;&gt;scientific&lt;/a&gt;, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Text&quot;&gt;In recent years, we’ve also introduced lots of hardcore software engineering capabilities—instant &lt;a href=&quot;https://reference.wolfram.com/language/guide/CloudFunctionsAndDeployment.html&quot;&gt;cloud deployment&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://reference.wolfram.com/language/guide/NetworkProgramming.html&quot;&gt;network programming&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://reference.wolfram.com/language/guide/WebOperations.html&quot;&gt;web interaction&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://reference.wolfram.com/language/guide/DatabaseConnectivity.html&quot;&gt;database connectivity&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://reference.wolfram.com/language/guide/ImportingAndExporting.html&quot;&gt;import/export (200+ formats)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://reference.wolfram.com/language/guide/DirectControlOfExternalProcesses.html&quot;&gt;process control&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://reference.wolfram.com/language/guide/SystematicTestingAndVerification.html&quot;&gt;unit testing&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://reference.wolfram.com/language/guide/AutomatedReports.html&quot;&gt;report generation&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://reference.wolfram.com/language/guide/Cryptography.html&quot;&gt;cryptography&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://reference.wolfram.com/language/guide/Blockchain.html&quot;&gt;blockchain&lt;/a&gt;, etc. (The symbolic nature of the language makes these particularly clean and powerful.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Text&quot;&gt;The goal of the Wolfram Language is simple, if ambitious: have everything be right there, in the language, and be as automatic as possible. Need to &lt;a href=&quot;https://reference.wolfram.com/language/guide/ImageProcessing.html&quot;&gt;analyze an image&lt;/a&gt;? Need &lt;a href=&quot;https://reference.wolfram.com/language/guide/GeographicData.html&quot;&gt;geographic data&lt;/a&gt;? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolfram.com/language/12/new-in-audio-processing/&quot;&gt;Audio processing&lt;/a&gt;? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolfram.com/language/12/convex-optimization&quot;&gt;Solve an optimization problem&lt;/a&gt;? &lt;a href=&quot;https://reference.wolfram.com/language/guide/WeatherData.html&quot;&gt;Weather information&lt;/a&gt;? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolfram.com/language/12/core-geometry/&quot;&gt;Generate 3D geometry&lt;/a&gt;? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolfram.com/language/12/biology-and-medical-entities/&quot;&gt;Anatomical data&lt;/a&gt;? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolfram.com/language/12/natural-language-processing/&quot;&gt;NLP entity identification&lt;/a&gt;? &lt;a href=&quot;https://reference.wolfram.com/language/ref/AnomalyDetection.html&quot;&gt;Find anomalies&lt;/a&gt; in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://reference.wolfram.com/language/guide/TimeSeries.html&quot;&gt;time series&lt;/a&gt;? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolfram.com/language/12/mail-and-messaging/&quot;&gt;Send a mail message&lt;/a&gt;? &lt;a href=&quot;https://reference.wolfram.com/language/ref/GenerateDigitalSignature.html&quot;&gt;Get a digital signature&lt;/a&gt;? All these things (and &lt;a href=&quot;https://reference.wolfram.com/language&quot;&gt;many, many more&lt;/a&gt;) are just functions that you can immediately call in any program you write in Wolfram Language. (There are no libraries to hunt down; everything is just integrated into the language.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Text&quot;&gt;Back on the earliest computers, all one had was machine code. But then came simple programming languages. And soon one could also take it for granted that one’s computer would have an operating system. Later also networking, then a user interface, then web connectivity. My goal with the Wolfram Language is to provide a layer of computational intelligence that in effect encapsulates the computational knowledge of our civilization, and lets people take it for granted that their computer will know how to identify objects in an image, or how to solve equations, or what the populations of cities are, or countless other things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Text&quot;&gt;And now, today, what we want to do with the Free Wolfram Engine for Developers is to make this something ubiquitous, and immediately available to any software developer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-wolfram-engine&quot;&gt;The Wolfram Engine&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Text&quot;&gt;The Free Wolfram Engine for Developers implements the full Wolfram Language as a software component that can immediately be plugged into any standard software engineering stack. It runs on any standard platform (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolfram.com/compatibility-and-connectivity/&quot;&gt;Linux, Mac, Windows&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolfram.com/raspberry-pi/&quot;&gt;RasPi&lt;/a&gt;, …; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolfram.com/compatibility-and-connectivity/&quot;&gt;desktop, server, virtualized, distributed, parallelized, embedded&lt;/a&gt;). You can use it directly with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolfram.com/wolframscript/&quot;&gt;a script&lt;/a&gt;, or from a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolfram.com/wolframscript/&quot;&gt;command line&lt;/a&gt;. You can call it from programming languages (&lt;a href=&quot;https://reference.wolfram.com/language/WolframClientForPython/&quot;&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://reference.wolfram.com/language/JLink/tutorial/Overview.html&quot;&gt;Java&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://reference.wolfram.com/language/NETLink/tutorial/Overview.html&quot;&gt;.NET&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolfram.com/wstp/&quot;&gt;C/C++&lt;/a&gt;, …), or from other systems (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolfram.com/cloud-connector-for-excel/&quot;&gt;Excel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/WolframResearch/WolframLanguageForJupyter&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Jupyter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolfram.com/language/12/built-in-interface-to-unity-game-engine&quot;&gt;Unity&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/WolframResearch/RhinoLink&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Rhino&lt;/a&gt;, …). You can call it through &lt;a href=&quot;https://reference.wolfram.com/language/guide/NetworkProgramming.html&quot;&gt;sockets&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolfram.com/language/12/networking-and-system-operations/zeromq-socket-pair.html&quot;&gt;ZeroMQ&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://reference.wolfram.com/language/guide/Channel-BasedCommunication.html&quot;&gt;MQTT&lt;/a&gt; or its own native &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolfram.com/wstp/&quot;&gt;WSTP (Wolfram Symbolic Transfer Protocol)&lt;/a&gt;. It reads and writes &lt;a href=&quot;https://reference.wolfram.com/language/guide/ImportingAndExporting.html&quot;&gt;hundreds of formats&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://reference.wolfram.com/language/ref/format/CSV.html&quot;&gt;CSV&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://reference.wolfram.com/language/ref/format/JSON.html&quot;&gt;JSON&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://reference.wolfram.com/language/ref/format/XML.html&quot;&gt;XML&lt;/a&gt;, …), and connects to databases (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolfram.com/language/12/relational-database-connectivity&quot;&gt;SQL&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolfram.com/language/12/rdf-and-sparql&quot;&gt;RDF/SPARQL&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/WolframResearch/MongoLink&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Mongo&lt;/a&gt;, …), and can call external programs (&lt;a href=&quot;https://reference.wolfram.com/language/guide/CallingExternalPrograms.html&quot;&gt;executables&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://reference.wolfram.com/language/guide/LibraryLink.html&quot;&gt;libraries&lt;/a&gt;, …), &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolfram.com/language/12/external-system-integration&quot;&gt;browsers&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolfram.com/language/12/mail-and-messaging/?product=language&quot;&gt;mail servers&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://reference.wolfram.com/language/guide/ListingOfSupportedExternalServices.html&quot;&gt;APIs&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://reference.wolfram.com/language/guide/UsingConnectedDevices.html&quot;&gt;devices&lt;/a&gt;, and languages (&lt;a href=&quot;https://reference.wolfram.com/language/ref/externalevaluationsystem/Python.html&quot;&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://reference.wolfram.com/language/ref/externalevaluationsystem/NodeJS.html&quot;&gt;NodeJS&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://reference.wolfram.com/language/JLink/tutorial/Overview.html&quot;&gt;Java&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://reference.wolfram.com/language/NETLink/tutorial/Overview.html&quot;&gt;.NET&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://reference.wolfram.com/language/RLink/guide/RLink.html&quot;&gt;R&lt;/a&gt;, …). Soon it’ll also plug directly into web servers (J2EE, aiohttp, Django, …). And you can edit and manage your Wolfram Language code with standard IDEs, editors and tools (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolfram.com/workbench/&quot;&gt;Eclipse&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://wlplugin.halirutan.de/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;IntelliJ IDEA&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://atom.io/packages/language-mathematica&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Atom&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/arnoudbuzing/wolfram-vim&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Vim&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/skidvision/wolfram-language&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Visual Studio Code&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/WolframResearch/GitLink&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt;, …).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Text&quot;&gt;The Free Wolfram Engine for Developers has access to the whole &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolfram.com/knowledgebase/&quot;&gt;Wolfram Knowledgebase&lt;/a&gt;, through a free &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolframcloud.com/&quot;&gt;Basic subscription to the Wolfram Cloud&lt;/a&gt;. (Unless you want real-time data, everything can be cached, so you can run the Wolfram Engine without network connectivity.) The Basic subscription to the Wolfram Cloud also lets you deploy limited &lt;a href=&quot;https://reference.wolfram.com/language/workflowguide/DeployingAndUsingWebAPIs.html&quot;&gt;APIs in the cloud&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Text&quot;&gt;A key feature of the Wolfram Language is that you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolfram.com/universal-deployment-system/&quot;&gt;run the exact same code anywhere&lt;/a&gt;. You can run it interactively using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolfram.com/notebooks/&quot;&gt;Wolfram Notebooks&lt;/a&gt;—on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolfram.com/wolfram-one/&quot;&gt;desktop&lt;/a&gt;, in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolframcloud.com/&quot;&gt;cloud&lt;/a&gt;, and on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolfram.com/cloud-app/&quot;&gt;mobile&lt;/a&gt;. You can run it in a cloud API (or &lt;a href=&quot;https://reference.wolfram.com/language/guide/BackgroundAndScheduledTasks.html&quot;&gt;scheduled task&lt;/a&gt;, etc.), on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolframcloud.com/&quot;&gt;public Wolfram Cloud&lt;/a&gt;, or in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolfram.com/enterprise-private-cloud/&quot;&gt;Wolfram Enterprise Private Cloud&lt;/a&gt;. And now, with the Wolfram Engine, you can also easily run it deep inside any standard software engineering stack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Text&quot;&gt;(Of course, if you want to use our whole hyperarchitecture spanning desktop, server, cloud, parallel, embedded, mobile—and interactive, development and production computing—then a good entry point is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolfram.com/wolfram-one/&quot;&gt;Wolfram|One&lt;/a&gt;, and, yes, there are &lt;a href=&quot;https://account.wolfram.com/access/wolfram-one/trial&quot;&gt;trial versions&lt;/a&gt; available.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;going-into-production&quot;&gt;Going into Production&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Text&quot;&gt;OK, so how does the licensing for Free Wolfram Engine for Developers work? For the past 30+ years, our company has had a very &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.wolfram.com/2019/04/02/why-wolfram-tech-isnt-open-source-a-dozen-reasons/&quot;&gt;straightforward model&lt;/a&gt;: we license our software to generate revenue that allows us to continue our long-term mission of &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.stephenwolfram.com/2019/04/version-12-launches-today-big-jump-for-wolfram-language-and-mathematica/&quot;&gt;continuous, energetic R&amp;amp;D&lt;/a&gt;. We’ve also made many important things available for free—like our main &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolframalpha.com/&quot;&gt;Wolfram|Alpha website&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolfram.com/player/&quot;&gt;Wolfram Player&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolframcloud.com/&quot;&gt;basic access to the Wolfram Cloud&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Text&quot;&gt;The Free Wolfram Engine for Developers is intended for use in pre-production software development. You can use it to develop a product for yourself or your company. You can use it to conduct personal projects at home, at school or at work. And you can use it to explore the Wolfram Language for future production projects. (Here’s the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolfram.com/legal/terms/wolfram-engine.html&quot;&gt;actual license&lt;/a&gt;, if you’re curious.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Text&quot;&gt;When you have a system ready to go into production, then you get a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolfram.com/engine/commercial-options/&quot;&gt;Production License&lt;/a&gt; for the Wolfram Engine. Exactly how that works will depend on what kind of system you’ve built. There are options for local individual or enterprise deployment, for distributing the Wolfram Engine with software or hardware, for deploying in cloud computing platforms—and for deploying in the Wolfram Cloud or Wolfram Enterprise Private Cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Text&quot;&gt;If you’re making a free, open-source system, you can apply for a Free Production License. Also, if you’re part of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolfram.com/group-organization-licensing/&quot;&gt;Wolfram Site License&lt;/a&gt; (of the type that, for example, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wolfram.com/education/&quot;&gt;most universities have&lt;/a&gt;), then you can freely use Free Wolfram Engine for Developers for anything that license permits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Text&quot;&gt;We haven’t worked out all the corners and details of every possible use of the Wolfram Engine. But we are committed to providing predictable and straightforward licensing for the long term (and we’re working to ensure the availability and vitality of the Wolfram Language in perpetuity, independent of our company). We’ve now had consistent pricing for our products for 30+ years, and we want to stay as far away as possible from the many variants of bait-and-switch which have become all too prevalent in modern software licensing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-use-it&quot;&gt;So Use It!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Text&quot;&gt;I’m very proud of what we’ve created with Wolfram Language, and it’s been wonderful to see all the inventions, discoveries and education that have happened with it over decades. But in recent years there’s been a new frontier: the increasingly widespread use of the Wolfram Language inside large-scale software projects. Sometimes the whole project is built in Wolfram Language. Sometimes Wolfram Language is inserted to add some critical computational intelligence, perhaps even just in a corner of the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Text&quot;&gt;The goal of the Free Wolfram Engine for Developers is to make it easy for anyone to use the Wolfram Language in any software development project—and to build systems that take advantage of its computational intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Text&quot;&gt;We’ve worked hard to make the Free Wolfram Engine for Developers as easy to use and deploy as possible. But if there’s something that doesn’t work for you or your project, please &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:s.wolfram@wolfram.com&quot;&gt;send me mail&lt;/a&gt;! Otherwise, please use what we’ve built—and do something great with it!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 14:15:24 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>GWOLF</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.stephenwolfram.com/2019/05/launching-today-free-wolfram-engine-for-developers/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Firefox 67.0 Released</title>
<link>https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/67.0/releasenotes/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/67.0/releasenotes/</guid>
<description>&lt;li id=&quot;note-787991&quot; readability=&quot;0.96352583586626&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firefox 67 demonstrates improved performance thanks to a number of changes such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Lowering priority of &lt;code&gt;setTimeout&lt;/code&gt; during page load&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Delayed component initialization until after start up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Painting sooner during page load but less often&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Suspending unused tabs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Learn more about our approach to performance in 67 in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/blog/2019/05/21/latest-firefox-release-is-faster-than-ever/&quot;&gt;Mozilla blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&quot;note-787992&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users can block known cryptominers and fingerprinters in the Custom settings of their &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.mozilla.org/kb/content-blocking&quot;&gt;Content Blocking preferences&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;note-787993&quot; readability=&quot;4.5192307692308&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keyboard accessibility has improved in the latest version of Firefox. Toolbar and toolbar overflow menu are both &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.mozilla.org/kb/access-toolbar-functions-using-keyboard&quot;&gt;fully keyboard accessible&lt;/a&gt;: keyboard users can now access add-ons, the downloads panel, the overflow, Page actions and Firefox menus, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;note-787994&quot; readability=&quot;-0.67307692307692&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://support.mozilla.org/kb/extensions-private-browsing&quot;&gt;Private Browsing&lt;/a&gt; sees both &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/addons/2019/03/26/extensions-in-firefox-67/&quot;&gt;usability and security improvements&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Save passwords in private browsing mode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choose which extensions to exclude from private tabs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;note-787995&quot; readability=&quot;-0.82787878787879&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A myriad of new features help make Firefox easier to use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;We’ve added a &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.mozilla.org/kb/how-do-i-know-status-my-sync&quot;&gt;toolbar menu&lt;/a&gt; for your Firefox Account to provide more transparency for when you are synced, sharing data across devices and with Firefox. Personalize the appearance of the menu with your own avatar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tabs can now be &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.mozilla.org/kb/pinned-tabs-keep-favorite-websites-open&quot;&gt;pinned&lt;/a&gt; from the Page Actions menu in the address bar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Firefox will highlight useful features (like Pin Tabs) when users are most likely to benefit from them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easier access to your list of saved logins from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://matthew.noorenberghe.com/blog/2019/05/password-manager-improvements-firefox-67&quot;&gt;main menu and login autocomplete&lt;/a&gt;. Learn about all the ways you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.mozilla.org/kb/password-manager-remember-delete-change-and-import&quot;&gt;manage your passwords&lt;/a&gt; in Firefox.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Import Data from Another Browser feature is now also available from the File menu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Users will be able to run different Firefox installs &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.nightly.mozilla.org/2019/01/14/moving-to-a-profile-per-install-architecture/&quot;&gt;side by side by default&lt;/a&gt; so that you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.mozilla.org/kb/dedicated-profiles-firefox-installation&quot;&gt;run the beta and release versions simultaneously&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;note-787996&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firefox will now protect you against running older versions of the browser which can lead to data corruption and stability issues&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;note-787997&quot; readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firefox is upgrading to the newer, higher performance, AV1 decoder known as ‘dav1d’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;note-787998&quot; readability=&quot;-0.81318681318681&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WebRender is &lt;a href=&quot;https://mozillagfx.wordpress.com/2019/05/21/graphics-team-ships-webrender-mvp/&quot;&gt;gradually enabled&lt;/a&gt; by default on Windows 10 desktops with NVIDIA graphics cards&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;note-788020&quot; readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mozilla’s highest performing JavaScript compiler now supports ARM64 Windows devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;note-787953&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/security/2019/04/04/shipping-fido-u2f-api-support-in-firefox/&quot;&gt;Enable FIDO U2F API&lt;/a&gt;, and permit registrations for Google Accounts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;note-787999&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some users will see experiments with an &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.getpocket.com/article/1149-firefox-home-layout-tests-faq&quot;&gt;improved Pocket experience&lt;/a&gt; in Firefox Home with different layouts and more topical content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 12:29:52 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Spydar007</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/67.0/releasenotes/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.mozilla.org/media/img/firefox/template/page-image.4b108ed0b8d8.png</og:image>
<og:title>Firefox 67.0, See All New Features, Updates and Fixes</og:title>
<og:description></og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/67.0/releasenotes/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>I don&amp;#039;t know how CPUs work so I simulated one in code</title>
<link>https://djhworld.github.io/post/2019/05/21/i-dont-know-how-cpus-work-so-i-simulated-one-in-code/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://djhworld.github.io/post/2019/05/21/i-dont-know-how-cpus-work-so-i-simulated-one-in-code/</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;small gray&quot;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&quot;2019-05-21&quot;&gt;Tuesday, May 21, 2019&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://djhworld.github.io/img/simple-computer/text-writer.gif&quot; title=&quot;Hello World&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few months ago it dawned on me that I didn’t really understand how computers work under the hood. I still don’t understand how &lt;em&gt;modern&lt;/em&gt; computers work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, after making my way through &lt;a href=&quot;http://buthowdoitknow.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;But How Do It Know?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by J. Clark Scott, a book which describes the bits of a simple 8-bit computer from the NAND gates, through to the registers, RAM, bits of the CPU, ALU and I/O, I got a hankering to implement it in code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I’m not &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; interested in the physics of the circuitry, the book just about skims the surface of those waters and gives a neat overview of the wiring and how bits move around the system without the requisite electrical engineering knowledge. For me though I can’t get comfortable with book descriptions, I have to see things in action and learn from my inevitable mistakes, which led me to chart a course on the rough seas of writing a circuit in code and getting a bit weepy about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fruits of my voyage can be seen in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/djhworld/simple-computer&quot;&gt;simple-computer&lt;/a&gt;; a simple computer that’s simple and computes things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://djhworld.github.io/img/simple-computer/ascii.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://djhworld.github.io/img/simple-computer/ascii1.png&quot; title=&quot;ASCII&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://djhworld.github.io/img/simple-computer/brush.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://djhworld.github.io/img/simple-computer/brush1.png&quot; title=&quot;brush&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://djhworld.github.io/img/simple-computer/text-writer.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://djhworld.github.io/img/simple-computer/text-writer1.png&quot; title=&quot;doing the typesin'&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Example programs
&lt;p&gt;It is quite a neat little thing, the CPU code is implemented &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/djhworld/simple-computer/blob/master/cpu/cpu.go#L763&quot;&gt;as a horrific splurge of gates turning on and off&lt;/a&gt; but it works, I’ve &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/djhworld/simple-computer/blob/master/cpu/cpu_test.go&quot;&gt;unit tested it&lt;/a&gt;, and we all know unit tests are irrefutable proof that something works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It handles &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/djhworld/simple-computer/blob/master/io/keyboard.go#L20&quot;&gt;keyboard inputs&lt;/a&gt;, and renders text &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/djhworld/simple-computer/blob/master/io/display.go#L13&quot;&gt;to a display&lt;/a&gt; using a painstakingly crafted set of glyphs for a professional font I’ve named “Daniel Code Pro”. The only cheat bit is to get the keyboard input and display output working I had to hook up go channels to speak to the outside world via &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/djhworld/simple-computer/blob/master/cmd/simulator/glfw_io.go&quot;&gt;GLFW&lt;/a&gt;, but the rest of it is a simulated circuit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I even wrote a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/djhworld/simple-computer/blob/master/asm/assembler.go&quot;&gt;crude assembler&lt;/a&gt; which was eye opening to say the least. It’s not perfect. Actually it’s a bit crap, but it highlighted to me the problems that other people have already solved many, many years ago and I think I’m a better person for it. Or worse, depending who you ask.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I’ve seen thirteen year old children do this in Minecraft, come back to me when you’ve built a &lt;u&gt;REAL&lt;/u&gt; CPU out of telegraph relays”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My mental model of computing is stuck in beginner computer science textbooks, and the CPU that powers the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/djhworld/gomeboycolor&quot;&gt;gameboy emulator I wrote back in 2013&lt;/a&gt; is really nothing like the CPUs that are running today. Even saying that, the emulator is just a state machine, it doesn’t describe the stuff at the logic gate level. You can implement most of it using just a &lt;code&gt;switch&lt;/code&gt; statement and storing the state of the registers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I’m trying to get a better understanding of this stuff because I don’t know what L1/L2 caches are, I don’t know what pipelining means, I’m not entirely sure I understand the Meltdown and Spectre vulnerability papers. Someone told me they were optimising their code to make use of CPU caches, I don’t know how to verify that other than taking their word for it. I’m not really sure what all the x86 instructions mean. I don’t understand how people off-load work to a GPU or TPU. I don’t know what a TPU is. I don’t know how to make use of SIMD instructions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But all that is built on a foundation of knowledge you need to earn your stripes for, so I ain’t gonna get there without reading the map first. Which means getting back to basics and getting my hands dirty with something simple. The “Scott Computer” described in the book is simple. That’s the reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Scott computer is an 8-bit processor attached to 256 bytes of RAM, all connected via an 8-bit system bus. It has 4 general purpose registers and can execute &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/djhworld/simple-computer#instructions&quot;&gt;17 machine instructions&lt;/a&gt;. Someone built a visual simulator &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.buthowdoitknow.com/but_how_do_it_know_cpu_model.html&quot;&gt;for the web here&lt;/a&gt;, which is really cool, I dread to think how long it took to track all the wiring states!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://djhworld.github.io/img/simple-computer/scott-cpu.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://djhworld.github.io/img/simple-computer/scott-cpu.png&quot; title=&quot;The Scott CPU&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;A diagram outlining all the components that make up the Scott CPU&lt;br/&gt;Copyright © 2009 - 2016 by Siegbert Filbinger and John Clark Scott.
&lt;p&gt;The book takes you on a journey from the humble NAND gate, onto a Bit of memory, onto a register and then keeps layering on components until you end up with something resembling the above. I really recommend reading it, even if you are already familiar with the concepts because it’s quite a good overview. I don’t recommend the Kindle version though because the diagrams are sometimes hard to zoom in and decipher on a screen. A perennial problem for the Kindle in my experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only thing that’s different about my computer is I upgraded it to 16-bit to have more memory to play with, as storing even just the glyphs for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/djhworld/simple-computer/blob/master/_programs/ascii.asm#L27&quot;&gt;ASCII table&lt;/a&gt; would have dwarfed most of the 8-bit machine described in the book, with not much room left for useful code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During development it really was just a case of reading the text, scouring the diagrams and then attempting to translate that using a general purpose programming language code and definitely &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; using something that’s designed for integrated circuit development. The reason why I wrote it in Go, is well, I know a bit of Go. Naysayers might chime in and say, you blithering idiot! I can’t believe you didn’t spend all your time learning &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/VHDL&quot;&gt;VHDL&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Verilog&quot;&gt;Verilog&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cburch.com/logisim/&quot;&gt;LogSim&lt;/a&gt; or whatever but I’d already written my bits and bytes and NANDs by that point, I was in too deep. Maybe I’ll learn them next and weep about my time wasted, but that’s my cross to bear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the grand scheme of things most of the computer is just passing around a bunch of booleans, so any boolean friendly language will do the job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Applying a schema to those booleans is what helps you (the programmer) derive its meaning, and the biggest decision anyone needs to make is decide what &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Endianness&quot;&gt;endianness&lt;/a&gt; your system is going to use and make sure all the components transfer things to and from the bus in the right order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was an absolute pain in the backside to implement. From the offset I opted for little endian but when testing the ALU my hair took a beating trying to work out why the numbers were coming out wrong. Many, &lt;em&gt;many&lt;/em&gt; print statements took place on this one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Development did take a while, maybe about a month or two during some of my free time, but once the CPU was done and successfully able to execute 2 + 2 = 5, I was happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, until the book discussed the I/O features, with designs for a simple keyboard and display interface so you can get things in and out of the machine. &lt;em&gt;Well I’ve already gotten this far&lt;/em&gt;, no point in leaving it in a half finished state. I set myself a goal of being able to type something on a keyboard and render the letters on a display.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The peripherals use the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adapter_pattern&quot;&gt;adapter pattern&lt;/a&gt; to act as a hardware interface between the CPU and the outside world. It’s probably not a huge leap to guess this was what the software design pattern took inspiration from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://djhworld.github.io/img/simple-computer/io.png&quot; title=&quot;i couldn't be bothered to do the corners around the CPU for the system bus&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;How the I/O adapters connect to a GLFW window
&lt;p&gt;With this separation of concerns it was actually pretty simple to hook the other end of the keyboard and display to a window managed by GLFW. In fact I just pulled most of the code from my &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/djhworld/gomeboycolor-glfw&quot;&gt;emulator&lt;/a&gt; and reshaped it a bit, using go channels to act as the signals in and out of the machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;https://djhworld.github.io/img/simple-computer/brush.gif&quot; title=&quot;brush.bin&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;This was probably the most tricky part, or at least the most cumbersome. Writing assembly with such a limited instruction set sucks. Writing assembly using a crude assembler I wrote sucks even more because you can’t shake your fist at someone other than yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest problem was juggling the 4 registers and keeping track of them, pulling and putting stuff in memory as a temporary store. Whilst doing this I remembered the Gameboy CPU having a stack pointer register so you could push and pop state. Unfortunately this computer doesn’t have such a luxury, so I was mostly moving stuff in and out of memory on a bespoke basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only pseudo instruction I took the time to implement was &lt;code&gt;CALL&lt;/code&gt; to help calling functions, this allows you to run a function and then return to the point after the function was called. Without that stack though you can only call one level deep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also as the machine does not support interrupts, you have to implement awful polling code for functions like getting keyboard state. The book does discuss the steps needed to implement interrupts, but it would involve a lot more wiring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But anyway enough of the moaning, I ended up writing &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/djhworld/simple-computer/blob/master/_programs/README.md&quot;&gt;four programs&lt;/a&gt; and most of them make use of some shared code for drawing fonts, getting keyboard input etc. Not exactly operating system material but it did make me appreciate some of the services a simple operating system might provide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t easy though, the trickiest part of the text-writer program was getting the maths right to work out when to go to a newline, or what happens when you hit the enter key.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-asm&quot; data-lang=&quot;asm&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;main-getInput:&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span&gt;CALL&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;ROUTINE-io-pollKeyboard&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span&gt;CALL&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;ROUTINE-io-drawFontCharacter&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span&gt;JMP&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;main-getInput&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
The main loop for the text-writer program
&lt;p&gt;I didn’t get round to implementing the backspace key either, or any of the modifier keys. Made me appreciate how much work must go in to making text editors and how tedious that probably is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a fun and very rewarding project for me. In the midst of programming in the assembly language I’d largely forgotten about the NAND, AND and OR gates firing underneath. I’d ascended into the layers of abstraction above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the CPU in the is very simple and a long way from what’s sitting in my laptop, I think this project has taught me a lot, namely:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;How bits move around between all components using a bus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How a &lt;em&gt;simple&lt;/em&gt; ALU works&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What a &lt;em&gt;simple&lt;/em&gt; Fetch-Decode-Execute cycle looks like&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That a machine without a stack pointer register + concept of a stack sucks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That a machine without interrupts sucks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What an assembler is and does&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How a peripherals communicate with a simple CPU&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How &lt;em&gt;simple&lt;/em&gt; fonts work and an approach to rendering them on a display&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What a &lt;em&gt;simple&lt;/em&gt; operating system might start to look like&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;So what’s next? The book said that no-one has built a computer like this since 1952, meaning I’ve got 67 years of material to brush up on, so that should keep me occupied for a while. I see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://software.intel.com/sites/default/files/managed/39/c5/325462-sdm-vol-1-2abcd-3abcd.pdf&quot;&gt;x86 manual is 4800 pages long&lt;/a&gt;, enough for some fun, light reading at bedtime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe I’ll have a brief dalliance with operating system stuff, a flirtation with the C language, a regrettable evening attempting to &lt;a href=&quot;https://obsolescence.wixsite.com/obsolescence/pidp-11&quot;&gt;solder up a PiDP-11 kit&lt;/a&gt; then probably call it quits. I dunno, we’ll see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all seriousness though I think I’m going to start looking into RISC based stuff next, maybe RISC-V, but probably start with early RISC processors to get an understanding of the lineage. Modern CPUs have a lot more features like caches and stuff so I want to understand them as well. A lot of stuff out there to learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do I need to know any of this stuff in my day job? Probably helps, but not really, but I’m enjoying it, so whatever, thanks for reading xxxx&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 12:04:11 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>boyter</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-gb</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://djhworld.github.io/post/2019/05/21/i-dont-know-how-cpus-work-so-i-simulated-one-in-code/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Facebook and Google pressured EU experts to soften fake news regulations</title>
<link>https://www.opendemocracy.net/en/facebook-and-google-pressured-eu-experts-soften-fake-news-regulations-say-insiders/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.opendemocracy.net/en/facebook-and-google-pressured-eu-experts-soften-fake-news-regulations-say-insiders/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;When asked about the selection process and potential conflicts of interests within the group, Commissioner Gabriel’s cabinet insisted they had carefully examined applications from organisations that said they had received funding from Google. This was done in order “to exclude situations where applicants would have an interest that could compromise or be reasonably perceived to compromise their capacity to act independently”, a cabinet member states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Divina Frau-Meigs, who teaches media sociology at the Sorbonne Nouvelle University in Paris and was also a member of the expert group, stresses the integrity of the academics in the group, who she believes were working honestly and diligently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, she still found the financial relationship between the platforms and some other group members troublesome: &quot;It’s a very subtle dependency relationship: it is difficult to focus on the platform that supports you, even without strings attached. Having a financial relationship lays you suspect to some kind of bias of self-censorship.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It's been known for some time that Google, Facebook and other tech companies give money to academics and journalists,” said Ska Keller, the German MEP. “There is a problem because they can use the threat of stopping this funding if these academics or journalists criticise them in any reporting they do.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Frau-Meigs, independent funding for academics as well as journalists is extremely important. “Google and Facebook are paying these partnerships from their direct marketing arm, not through more neutral foundations,” she says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fact that platforms support both academics and journalists is in itself not a problem for Frau-Meigs as long as it is transparent, but the lack of clear criteria and a separate funding entity is. This can lead to a complicated and opaque situation, as the expert group’s example demonstrates. Frau-Meigs concludes: “The platforms should not exert influence the way they do now.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A hobbled code&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the ‘high-level group’ on fake news and online disinformation was created it had grand ambitions. Commissioner Gabriel – alarmed by the Brexit vote and Trump’s election – announced in autumn 2017: &quot;The fake news phenomenon is not new, but the reach and speed with which disinformation has spread online is unprecedented.” She said she had decided to call together a group of experts “in order to find a common solution to this growing phenomenon”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The code of practice that the European Commission adopted last September certainly included some valuable guidelines. It acknowledged the need to improve the scrutiny of advertisement placements; to ensure the transparency of political and issue-based advertising; to establish clear labelling and rules for bots so that they would not be confused with human interaction; and to reduce the visibility of disinformation by making trustworthy content easier to find and by ensuring users have access to different news sources with a range of viewpoints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A significant omission, however, was the mechanisms proposed by Goyens and others that would have forced the platforms to be more transparent about their business models and, in turn, would have helped policymakers assess whether these models might enable or promote disinformation. This was something the platforms tried hard to prevent, according to group members who spoke to Investigate Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 10:59:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>okket</dc:creator>
<og:title> Facebook and Google pressured EU experts to soften fake news regulations, say insiders</og:title>
<og:description> On the eve of European elections, the tech giants stand accused of sabotaging the European Union’s fight against disinformation.</og:description>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.opendemocracy.net/en/facebook-and-google-pressured-eu-experts-soften-fake-news-regulations-say-insiders/</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn-prod.opendemocracy.net/media/images/PA-36193000.2e16d0ba.fill-1200x630.jpg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.opendemocracy.net/en/facebook-and-google-pressured-eu-experts-soften-fake-news-regulations-say-insiders/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: Turn an Excel file into a web application</title>
<link>https://keikai.io/blog/p/currency-exchange</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://keikai.io/blog/p/currency-exchange</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The other day a young lady in the administration department looked busy so I asked her what she was up to. She said that she has to visit several websites to check the currency rate, put them down in Excel and send it to her boss. The boss will then tell her to buy a certain currency at a certain amount. Finally, she has to keep the record in another Excel file. And this is one of her daily routines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is the year 2019. I was surprised that she still has to do lots of copy-paste routines and email Excel files around. My pride in being a developer wouldn't allow me, so I offered her that I will write a little program for her. Fortunately, with Keikai, I was able to do it in just 2 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, I asked her to lay out what she wishes to see in Excel. Then, I grabbed currency data from internet and populated it to the desired cells. Next, I implemented page navigation to smoothen the workflow and finally I generated a report. That’s it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me describe in detail about how each step was done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best thing about using Keikai is that it takes your Excel file and renders exactly the same in your browser. This means your Excel file is immediately turned into a web application UI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This enables your business team, like the administrative lady, being able to join the system development easily by creating an Excel file as the UI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the admin lady sent me her Buy-Currency Excel file: on the first screen, she expects to see a selected list of countries and their currency, and the currency data should be populated automatically. On the second screen, she expects to input the buying amount and the exchanged amount, and lastly, she expects to see a report generated automatically containing Dates, Currency, and Amounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://keikai.io/blog/images/2019-05-currency/3ExcelSheets.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All I need to do here is to import the Excel file, and now the Excel template renders in my browser just like what she designed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-java&quot; data-lang=&quot;java&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;public&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;static&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;final&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;String&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;INTERNAL_BOOK_FOLDER&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;/WEB-INF/book/&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;...&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;public&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;static&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;final&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;String&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;BOOK_NAME&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;currencyExchange.xlsx&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;...&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;spreadsheet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;importAndReplace&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;BOOK_NAME&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;File&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Configuration&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;DEFAULT_BOOK_FOLDER&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;BOOK_NAME&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;));&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, I filled in currency exchange rates retrieved from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ecb.europa.eu/stats/policy_and_exchange_rates/euro_reference_exchange_rates/html/index.en.html&quot;&gt;European Central Bank&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;code&gt;setValues()&lt;/code&gt; to the desired cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-java&quot; data-lang=&quot;java&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;String&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;currency&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;CURRENCY_LIST&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;){&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;spreadsheet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;getRange&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;startingRow&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;6&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;setValues&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;currency&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;rates&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;get&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;currency&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;));&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;startingRow&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;++;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the admin lady can see the latest exchange rates being updated without visiting various websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://keikai.io/blog/images/2019-05-currency/listSheet.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Excel file she gave me contained formulas for calculating total exchanged amount according to the buying amount and exchange rate. But nothing to worry, I got formula supported on each cell out-of-the-box. Don't even need to enable it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lady can enter a formula according to her conditions without calculating numbers in her head, e.g. she can calculate how many notes she has in a cell and buys the same amount of USD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://keikai.io/blog/images/2019-05-currency/usingFormula.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I call &lt;code&gt;Range::getValue()&lt;/code&gt;, I can get the calculated result of that formula. No need to parse the formula by myself. Isn't great?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, I will take care of page navigation – once she is done with the current page, take her to the next page. This can be done with &lt;a href=&quot;https://keikai.io/javadoc/latest/io/keikai/client/api/Worksheet.html#activate--&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;activate()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The code below listens to the button clicking event and switches to another sheet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-java&quot; data-lang=&quot;java&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;private&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;void&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;addEventListener&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;...&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;//listen to buy button&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;exchangeSheet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;getButton&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;Buy&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;addAction&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;buttonShapeMouseEvent&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;placeAnOrder&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;listSheet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;activate&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;//listen to &quot;buy another&quot; button&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;listSheet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;getButton&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;BuyAnother&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;addAction&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;buttonShapeMouseEvent&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;selectSheet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;activate&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that the application workflow has been implemented, but we need to implement some “safety” to make sure that she follows the desired path. By default, a user can edit any cell in a typical Excel file or spreadsheet. But when making a Web application, usually we wish users to follow the flow we defined. The following APIs are handy for controlling accessibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;customize-ui&quot;&gt;Customize UI&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I customize UI by hiding the toolbar, context menu and sheet tabs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-java&quot; data-lang=&quot;java&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;private&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;void&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;setupAccessibility&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;spreadsheet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;getUIService&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;().&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;showToolbar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;spreadsheet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;getUIService&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;().&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;showSheetTabs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;spreadsheet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;getUIService&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;().&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;showContextMenu&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;...&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I prevent our administration lady from making undesired changes with these APIs, like deleting a sheet (page) by accident. There is &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.keikai.io/dev-ref/ui-configurations&quot;&gt;another easier way through data attributes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://keikai.io/blog/images/2019-05-currency/uiAccessibility.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;limit-visible-area&quot;&gt;Limit Visible Area&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, to let her concentrate on the application, I decided to show a proper area instead of showing her the whole sheet (16,384 columns and 1,048,576 rows) so the lady won't scroll to the end of the world (sheet):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-java&quot; data-lang=&quot;java&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;private&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;void&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;setupVisibleArea&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;selectSheet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;setVisibleArea&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;A1:O17&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;exchangeSheet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;setVisibleArea&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;A1:L12&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;listSheet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;setVisibleArea&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;A:M&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://keikai.io/blog/images/2019-05-currency/visibleArea.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;protect-a-sheet-to-be-read-only&quot;&gt;Protect a Sheet to be Read-only&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But hiding toolbar and the context menu is not enough because users can still edit cells arbitrarily. Therefore, I enabled sheet protection to make the whole sheet read-only so that she won’t accidentally delete a currency row or change a currency rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-java&quot; data-lang=&quot;java&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;public&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;static&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;final&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;SheetProtection&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;PROTECTION&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;SheetProtection&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;Builder&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;().&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;setPassword&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;setAllowSelectLockedCells&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;setAllowFiltering&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;build&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;...&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;listSheet&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;spreadsheet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;getWorksheet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;list&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;...&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;listSheet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;protect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;PROTECTION&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since there are 17 different permissions of a &lt;code&gt;SheetProtection&lt;/code&gt;, I create a &lt;code&gt;SheetProtection&lt;/code&gt; object with a Builder pattern API, &lt;a href=&quot;https://keikai.io/javadoc/latest/io/keikai/client/api/SheetProtection.Builder.html&quot;&gt;SheetProtection.Builder&lt;/a&gt; which is a more readable code style.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;limit-editable-area&quot;&gt;Limit Editable Area&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I’ve made the whole sheet read-only, she can’t edit anywhere. I need to unlock the cell where she needs to input the buying cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unlock a cell&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-java&quot; data-lang=&quot;java&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;private&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;void&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;unlockCostInput&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Range&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;costCell&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;spreadsheet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;getRangeByName&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;exchangeSheet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;getSheetId&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(),&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;cost&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;CellStyle&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;unlockedStyle&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;costCell&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;createCellStyle&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Protection&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;protection&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;unlockedStyle&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;createProtection&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;protection&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;setLocked&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;unlockedStyle&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;setProtection&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;protection&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;costCell&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;setCellStyle&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;unlockedStyle&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;exchangeSheet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;protect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;PROTECTION&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Line 2: I get a range by a defined name, and it can avoid code change even I move the input cell address. This approach has better code change resistance than getting by a cell address like C5.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;So that cell (D7) becomes the only one editable cell in the read-only sheet:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://keikai.io/blog/images/2019-05-currency/unlocked.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the last page, I will show a list of currency transaction in a table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;19&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-java&quot; data-lang=&quot;java&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;private&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;void&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;placeAnOrder&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;listSheet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;unprotect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Range&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;costCell&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;spreadsheet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;getRangeByName&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;exchangeSheet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;getSheetId&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(),&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;COST_CELL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;costCell&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;toString&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;().&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;isEmpty&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;())&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Double&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;cost&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;costCell&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;getRangeValue&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;().&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;getCellValue&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;().&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;getDoubleValue&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;cost&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Double&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;amount&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;spreadsheet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;getRangeByName&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;exchangeSheet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;getSheetId&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(),&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;amount&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;getRangeValue&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;().&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;getCellValue&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;().&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;getDoubleValue&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Range&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;orderTable1stRow&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;spreadsheet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;getRange&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;BOOK_NAME&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;listSheet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;getSheetId&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(),&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;C6:G6&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;orderTable1stRow&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;getEntireRow&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;().&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;insert&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Range&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;InsertShiftDirection&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;ShiftDown&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Range&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;InsertFormatOrigin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;RightOrBelow&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;orderTable1stRow&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;setValues&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;DateUtil&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;getExcelDate&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;Date&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;()),&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;cost&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;destinationCurrency&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;destinationRate&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;amount&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;listSheet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;protect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;PROTECTION&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Line 2: Since it's a protected sheet, I need to unprotect it before setting cell values.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Line 9-10: insert a new row and set values in a row at once.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Keikai also saves your efforts to maintain a table's style including background color, borders, font, and filters. When inserting and deleting rows. You just need to call &lt;code&gt;insert()&lt;/code&gt;, and Keikai handles all changes on the related styles for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I enable a filter in Excel, Keikai also enables it after importing. After the lady places an order for many times, she may wish to filter some rows according to the criteria, e.g. list only the EUR to USD transactions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://keikai.io/blog/images/2019-05-currency/openFilter.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Filtered Result&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;https://keikai.io/blog/images/2019-05-currency/filteredResult.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if a filter was not enabled in the Excel file, I can enable the filter programmatically through Keikai API: &lt;a href=&quot;https://keikai.io/javadoc/latest/io/keikai/client/api/Range.html#setAutoFilter-int-java.lang.Object-io.keikai.client.api.Range.AutoFilterOperator-java.lang.Object-boolean-&quot;&gt;setAutoFilter()&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole usage is like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://keikai.io/blog/images/2019-05-currency/usageDemo.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope she will appreciate this little arrangement I made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through these steps, I can turn a traditional workflow of sending Excel forms into a web application. Then, those forms immediately become your system UI, and all my colleagues can effortlessly migrate to Keikai-based web system because they can execute workflows with a familiar UI without extra learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you enjoyed reading my article. The complete source code of &quot;buy currency&quot; application mentioned in this article is available at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/keikai/dev-ref&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just run the project and visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:8080/dev-ref/case/exchange&quot;&gt;http://localhost:8080/dev-ref/case/exchange&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 07:45:26 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>visionPASSION</dc:creator>
<og:title>Turn Your Excel File Into a Web Application</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://keikai.io/blog/p/currency-exchange.html</og:url>
<og:image>https://keikai.io/blog2019-05-currency/listSheet.png</og:image>
<og:description>&lt;!--images come from https://drive.google.com/open?id=17EEz_BuTVsTSeAA3a8AakyMspVSd_OEb made with draw.io</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://keikai.io/blog/p/currency-exchange</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Niki Lauda has died</title>
<link>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2019/may/21/niki-lauda-formula-one-legend-dies-aged-70</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2019/may/21/niki-lauda-formula-one-legend-dies-aged-70</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The sport of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/sport/formulaone&quot; data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Formula One&lt;/a&gt; has united to pay tribute to the courage and bravery of its three-times world champion, Niki Lauda, who has died at the age of 70.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Austrian died in Vienna on Monday, his family announced, nine months after receiving a lung transplant. Lauda, who won titles in 1975, 1977 and 1984, was hugely admired, respected and liked within F1 after a remarkable career during which he won two titles for Ferrari and one for McLaren and came back from an horrific accident in 1976.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;element element-rich-link element--thumbnail element-rich-link--not-upgraded&quot; data-component=&quot;rich-link&quot; data-link-name=&quot;rich-link-2 | 1&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;rich-link&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;rich-link__container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;rich-link__header&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;rich-link__title&quot;&gt;Niki Lauda: a single-minded F1 champion who beat the best of his age | Richard Williams&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Trapped in his burning car at the German Grand Prix, he was pulled from the wreckage, but suffered severe burns and damage to his lungs. Despite doubts he would survive or indeed ever race again, Lauda’s determination to do so was extraordinary and just six weeks later he returned for the Italian Grand Prix, still bandaged and in pain after extensive surgery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sir Jackie Stewart, a fellow three-times world champion who raced alongside Lauda in the early 1970s, described him as one of the bravest drivers in the history of the sport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Niki had a degree of bravery that I had never seen the like of before,” Stewart, 79, said. “I remember seeing Niki put his helmet on, and his wounds were still absolutely obvious. To be brave enough to put on the helmet was amazing, but then he went out and qualified fifth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“He will not go down as just one of the best drivers of all time, but one of the most courageous, too. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/sport/niki-lauda&quot; data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Niki Lauda&lt;/a&gt; will be remembered forever.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, Lauda competed in 171 races and won 25. He also actively pursued business interests including his own airline and went on to have senior roles in F1 management, most recently as non-executive chairman at the hugely successful Mercedes team since 2012, where he helped bring the British world champion Lewis Hamilton on board.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details data-snippet-id=&quot;dce171bd-5e21-4e46-9edf-4bb743442640&quot; data-snippet-type=&quot;timeline&quot; class=&quot;atom atom--snippet atom--snippet--timeline&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;atom--snippet__label&quot;&gt;Timeline&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;atom--snippet__headline&quot;&gt;Niki Lauda's career&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;button class=&quot;atom__button atom__button--large atom__button--rounded atom--snippet__handle&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;is-on&quot;&gt; Show&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;is-off&quot;&gt; Hide&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/button&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__body&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__item&quot;&gt;&lt;time class=&quot;atom--snippet__event-date&quot; datetime=&quot;1949-02-22T00:00:00&quot;&gt;22 February 1949&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andreas Nikolaus Lauda is born in Vienna, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/austria&quot; data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Austria&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__item&quot;&gt;&lt;time class=&quot;atom--snippet__event-date&quot; datetime=&quot;1971-08-15T00:00:00&quot;&gt;15 August 1971&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Makes his Formula One debut for March-Ford in his home Austrian Grand Prix&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__item&quot;&gt;&lt;time class=&quot;atom--snippet__event-date&quot; datetime=&quot;1974-04-28T00:00:00&quot;&gt;28 April 1974&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now driving for Ferrari, Lauda wins a Formula One race for the first time at the Spanish Grand Prix &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__item&quot;&gt;&lt;time class=&quot;atom--snippet__event-date&quot; datetime=&quot;1975-09-07T00:00:00&quot;&gt;7 September 1975&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lauda secures his first world title for Ferrari at the Italian Grand Prix, with one race in the season left to go&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__item&quot;&gt;&lt;time class=&quot;atom--snippet__event-date&quot; datetime=&quot;1976-08-01T00:00:00&quot;&gt;1 August 1976&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lauda is burned in a crash on the second lap of the German Grand Prix at the Nürburgring. His injuries are so severe that he is read the last rites, but remarkably, after reconstructive surgery on his face, he returns to racing the same season, only missing two races&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__item&quot;&gt;&lt;time class=&quot;atom--snippet__event-date&quot; datetime=&quot;1977-10-02T00:00:00&quot;&gt;2 October 1977&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lauda takes his second world championship, securing victory with a fourth place finish in the US Grand Prix, with two races to go&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__item&quot;&gt;&lt;time class=&quot;atom--snippet__event-date&quot; datetime=&quot;1979-04-01T00:00:00&quot;&gt;April 1979&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Founds his first airline - Lauda Air&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__item&quot;&gt;&lt;time class=&quot;atom--snippet__event-date&quot; datetime=&quot;1979-09-01T00:00:00&quot;&gt;September 1979&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having left Ferrari for Brabham, Lauda retires from Formula One at the end of the season&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__item&quot;&gt;&lt;time class=&quot;atom--snippet__event-date&quot; datetime=&quot;1982-04-01T00:00:00&quot;&gt;1982&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lauda returns to the sport, this time driving for McLaren &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__item&quot;&gt;&lt;time class=&quot;atom--snippet__event-date&quot; datetime=&quot;1984-10-21T00:00:00&quot;&gt;21 October 1984&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lauda finishes second behind Alain Prost in the final race of the season, but it is enough to give him a narrow half-point victory overall, and he secures his third world title&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__item&quot;&gt;&lt;time class=&quot;atom--snippet__event-date&quot; datetime=&quot;1985-08-25T00:00:00&quot;&gt;25 August 1985&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wins his 25th Formula One race at the Netherlands Grand Prix&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__item&quot;&gt;&lt;time class=&quot;atom--snippet__event-date&quot; datetime=&quot;1985-11-03T00:00:00&quot;&gt;3 November 1985&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Retires from Formula One after competing in the Australia Grand Prix, with an overall record of 3 world championships, 25 wins and 54 podium finishes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__item&quot;&gt;&lt;time class=&quot;atom--snippet__event-date&quot; datetime=&quot;1993-05-21T00:00:00&quot;&gt;1993&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Returns to Formula One in a consultancy role for Ferrari&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__item&quot;&gt;&lt;time class=&quot;atom--snippet__event-date&quot; datetime=&quot;2001-05-21T00:00:00&quot;&gt;2001&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Takes on the role of team principal of the Jaguar Formula One team&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__item&quot;&gt;&lt;time class=&quot;atom--snippet__event-date&quot; datetime=&quot;2012-05-21T00:00:00&quot;&gt;2012&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Becomes non-executive chairman of the Mercedes team, where he helped bring Lewis Hamilton to the team&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__item&quot;&gt;&lt;time class=&quot;atom--snippet__event-date&quot; datetime=&quot;2019-05-20T00:00:00&quot;&gt;20 May 2019&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lauda dies peacefully, eight months after receiving a lung transplant&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;footer class=&quot;atom--snippet__footer&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__feedback&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Was this helpful?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__ack&quot; hidden=&quot;&quot; aria-role=&quot;alert&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot;&gt;Thank you for your feedback.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;/details&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hamilton has paid an emotional tribute to Lauda on Instagram. “My buddy, I am struggling to believe you are gone,” he wrote. “I will miss our conversations, our laughs, the big hugs after winning races together. It’s truly been an honour working alongside you over these past seven years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I wouldn’t have even been in this team if it wasn’t for you. God rest your soul. Thank you for being a bright light in my life. I’ll always be here for your family should they ever need me. Love you man. Your friend always, Lewis.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Toto Wolff, the team principal at Mercedes, said: “Niki will always remain one of the greatest legends of our sport – he combined heroism, humanity and honesty inside and outside the cockpit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“His passing leaves a void in Formula One. We haven’t just lost a hero who staged the most remarkable comeback ever seen, but also a man who brought precious clarity and candour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Our Mercedes team has also lost a guiding light. Niki, you are quite simply irreplaceable, there will never be another like you. It was our honour to call you our chairman – and my privilege to call you my friend.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Everyone who was in Formula One knew Niki’s personality as one of the most potent individuals in the sport,” Damon Hill told Sky Sports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“He was highly intellectual, stoic, someone who didn’t have time for any of the BS in the business at all. He was eminently quotable all the time. It’s very sad to hear that we’ve lost Niki, but so many people have been affected positively by having known him.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chase Carey, chairman and chief executive of the Formula One group, issued a statement: “Formula 1 has lost not only one of the truly great exponents of the sport but also one of its heroes. His love of racing and the courage he demonstrated were simply extraordinary and he inspired so many fans. His passing is a great loss for the entire Formula 1 family and motorsport as a whole. All our thoughts go out to his family.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/nico_rosberg/status/1130723158670041088&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Nico Rosberg, F1’s 2016 world champion&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/nico_rosberg/status/1130723158670041088&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;with Mercedes,&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/nico_rosberg/status/1130723158670041088&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;tweeted&lt;/a&gt;: “Dear Niki. Thank you for everything that you did for me. I learned so much from you. Your passion, your fighting spirit ... myself and all of your fans around the world are thinking of you and your family and wish that you Rest in Peace.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lauda was born in 1949 and pursued a career in racing against the wishes of his family, taking out a personal bank loan to ensure he could enter the sport. He made his debut in 1971 and impressed enough for Enzo Ferrari to offer him a drive with the Scuderia in 1974. Ferrari were rewarded with a podium on his first race and a win three meetings later in Spain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;element element-rich-link element--thumbnail element-rich-link--not-upgraded&quot; data-component=&quot;rich-link&quot; data-link-name=&quot;rich-link-2 | 2&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;rich-link&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;rich-link__container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;rich-link__header&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;rich-link__title&quot;&gt;Niki Lauda: the three-time Formula One world champion's life – in pictures&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next year he took his first title for the team, their first for over a decade.&lt;br/&gt;In 1976, he was in another strong position for the title when he crashed at the Nürburgring. Having made his astonishing return at Monza, Lauda could still have taken the title in Japan but opted to retire from the race, convinced the torrential rain made it unsafe. James Hunt, with whom he enjoyed both respect and friendship, took the championship. The story of the rivalry between the two drivers was turned into the 2013 film, Rush.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lauda went on to take the title a second time in the year following his crash but, after two further seasons with Brabham, retired in 1979. He made a comeback for McLaren in 1982 and went on to win the championship in 1984 after a competitive fight with teammate Alain Prost. The Austrian took the title in the final race by just half a point. He retired from F1 for a second and final time in 1985.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A number of tributes to Lauda are expected to take place at this weekend’s Monaco Grand Prix.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 07:22:18 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>CaliforniaKarl</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://www.theguardian.com/sport/2019/may/21/niki-lauda-formula-one-legend-dies-aged-70</og:url>
<og:description>The great Austrian driver won two F1 titles for Ferrari and one for McLaren and came back from an horrific accident that left him severely burned and injured in 1976</og:description>
<og:image>https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/940a5a163e4f3c741b8d9f06659047aefb8627d8/0_276_5472_3283/master/5472.jpg?width=1200&amp;height=630&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;overlay-align=bottom%2Cleft&amp;overlay-width=100p&amp;overlay-base64=L2ltZy9zdGF0aWMvb3ZlcmxheXMvdGctZGVmYXVsdC5wbmc&amp;s=8b9c14d3bf32a9976ad6697315edef08</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Niki Lauda, three-times Formula One world champion, dies aged 70</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2019/may/21/niki-lauda-formula-one-legend-dies-aged-70</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>