<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Fonts for Complex Data</title>
<link>https://www.typography.com/blog/fonts-for-complex-data</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.typography.com/blog/fonts-for-complex-data</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;small-caps&quot;&gt;Type designers work with a diverse clientele,&lt;/span&gt; and yet common themes always seem to emerge in our conversations. This seems to be the season of complex typography, in which designers everywhere are faced with the challenge of presenting different and competing kinds of information to readers. An agency we’re working with is designing a demanding identity for a fast-moving consumer goods brand; an in-house art department is creating a responsive website for complex financial disclosures; a freelance graphic designer is doing the identity for a local coffeeshop, and discovering the joys and perils of digital menu boards. As always, the wrong fonts can lead designers into sticky dead ends, but the right ones can be immeasurably helpful. Here are some of the things our clients consider when faced with complex typography, and some of the typographic strategies that can be the quickest routes to success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Strategies for Small Sizes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Information can often be divided into data and annotations. A web form needs a way to distinguish entry fields from labels; a graph needs not only labels for its &lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;y&lt;/em&gt; axes, but most crucially a verifiable reference for the source of its data. (#fakenews, I’m looking at you.) The most familiar and obvious way to establish this hierarchy is through type size, using palpably smaller type to distinguish the content from its notes. But at smaller-than-text sizes, even the most lucid typefaces can become difficult to read, their spacing overly tight, their counters congested, and their x-heights measly. Compare the tiny type in these two examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/fonts/whitney/styles/screensmart/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d31td5fkd89rr1.cloudfront.net/assets/images/blog/designing-captions.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;750&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/fonts/whitney/overview/&quot;&gt;Whitney&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/fonts/whitney/styles/screensmart/&quot;&gt;Whitney ScreenSmart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Helpfully, there’s an adaptation designed for the web that proves useful in any medium: a typeface’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/collections/screensmart/&quot;&gt;ScreenSmart&lt;/a&gt; fonts, which are designed to compensate for the effects of scale. Above, two compositions using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/fonts/whitney/overview/&quot;&gt;Whitney&lt;/a&gt; typeface, the one at the right substituting &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/fonts/whitney/styles/screensmart/&quot;&gt;Whitney ScreenSmart&lt;/a&gt; for the tiny annotations below the graph. ScreenSmart fonts always deliver greater clarity and more comfortable reading at smaller-than-text sizes, making them a useful companion to a multipurpose typeface for setting the fine print.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Dealing with Lists&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fine print is the bugbear of typography not only for its tiny size, but often its prodigious length. Disclosures, disclaimers, and lists of ingredients may be the sections that readers most often ignore, yet they’re among the most heavily regulated part of any typographic object, and therefore the content that’s most heavily scrutinized by an alarmingly large portion of an organization. Hands up if you’ve ever received a request from Legal to fit in a few more sentences once a design has been approved. Hands up if this wasn’t exacly a “request.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/fonts/gotham/styles/gothamnarrowbundle&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d31td5fkd89rr1.cloudfront.net/assets/images/blog/designing-ingredients-3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;750&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/fonts/gotham/styles/gothamcondensedbundle&quot;&gt;Gotham Condensed&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/fonts/gotham/styles/gothamnarrowbundle&quot;&gt;Gotham Narrow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A non-designer’s first impulse is often to reach for a condensed typeface, on the principle that narrower letters take up less space. Yet it’s almost always a better option to make the counter-intuitive choice of a &lt;em&gt;wider&lt;/em&gt; typeface, and to set the type in a smaller size with tighter leading. Wider letters have more comfortable proportions, they’re more generously spaced, and they have more ample counters, collectively making them the more legible choice. Above, two ingredient lists in Gotham: at left the passable &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/fonts/gotham/styles/gothamcondensedbundle&quot;&gt;Gotham Condensed&lt;/a&gt;, but at right the far more inviting &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/fonts/gotham/styles/gothamnarrowbundle&quot;&gt;Gotham Narrow&lt;/a&gt;, a family that’s two steps wider. &lt;strong class=&quot;alternate&quot;&gt;TIP:&lt;/strong&gt; Use not only a wider font, but a wider &lt;em&gt;ScreenSmart&lt;/em&gt; font as well, for maximum clarity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Working the Character Set&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The humble &lt;em&gt;annotation&lt;/em&gt; can give designers the chance to flex their creativity, and an excuse to explore the more colorful quarters of the character set. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/blog/house-of-flying-reference-marks&quot;&gt;Reference marks&lt;/a&gt;, starting with the asterisk and dagger, are sometimes a welcome grace note whenever the subject matter becomes dry, but beware their use if there are more than three notes in a document. Readers can be counted upon to recognize the cycle of *, †, and ‡, but probably not the longer series of **, ††, and ‡‡ — or §, || and #, depending on your house style. If there are more than three footnotes, stick with unambiguously numbered &lt;em&gt;superscripts&lt;/em&gt; instead:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/fonts/chronicle-text/overview/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d31td5fkd89rr1.cloudfront.net/assets/images/blog/designing-footnotes.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;750&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/fonts/chronicle-text/overview/&quot;&gt;Chronicle Text Grade 2 Pro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Superscripts are included in every H&amp;amp;Co font that has a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/collections/charts-tables/&quot;&gt;Pro&lt;/a&gt; edition, as well as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/fonts/gotham/features/gotham-numerics&quot;&gt;Gotham&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/fonts/ringside/features/ringside-numerics&quot;&gt;Ringside&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/fonts/inkwell/features/inkwell-numerics&quot;&gt;Inkwell&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strong class=&quot;alternate&quot;&gt;TIP:&lt;/strong&gt; In the text, mark your footnotes with &lt;em&gt;superscripts,&lt;/em&gt; which ascend above the cap height. But in the notes themselves, use &lt;em&gt;numerators&lt;/em&gt; instead, which are lower on the body. This connects them more clearly with the explanations that follow, and gives them greater clearance from the preceding lines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Numerics, Numerics, Numerics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.typography.com/collections/charts-tables/&quot;&gt;Pro&lt;/a&gt; packages that contain superscripts and numerators contain &lt;em&gt;tabular figures,&lt;/em&gt; the most vital part of any composition that includes numbers. Unlike a font’s traditional &lt;em&gt;proportional figures,&lt;/em&gt; whose widths vary with the natural shape of each number — from a narrow &lt;strong class=&quot;alternate&quot;&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt; to a wide &lt;strong class=&quot;alternate&quot;&gt;0&lt;/strong&gt; — tabular figures are all built on the same horizontal measure, ensuring that columns of data always align correctly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/collections/symbols-technical/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d31td5fkd89rr1.cloudfront.net/assets/images/blog/sans-serif-numbers.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;750&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tabular figures have a second and equally important characteristic: they maintain their equal widths across a range of &lt;em&gt;weights. (&lt;/em&gt;This runs counter to the typical behavior in a typeface, in which heavier weights become progressively wider.) Known as “duplexing,” this is one of the essential characteristics of tabular figures, because it allows designers to highlight individual lines in boldface without disrupting the width of the column.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/collections/symbols-technical/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d31td5fkd89rr1.cloudfront.net/assets/images/blog/serif-numbers.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;750&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;alternate&quot;&gt;TIP:&lt;/strong&gt; The word “tabular” may imply the dense tables that are annexed to annual reports and financial disclosures, but don’t forget how often stacks of numbers appear in other contexts. Tabular figures are essential in menus, indexes, and directories, and anywhere that a design includes prices, statistics, account numbers, or scores — or any kind of dynamic data online. Any digital experience that shows changing numbers such as stock prices, sports scores, product &lt;span class=&quot;small-caps&quot;&gt;sku&lt;/span&gt;s, exchange rates, flight numbers, timetables, or membership points will absolutely demand tabular figures. Design your projects with tabular figures from the outset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/fonts/archer/styles/archer3pro&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d31td5fkd89rr1.cloudfront.net/assets/images/blog/designing-menus.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;750&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Making Creative Choices&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advanced numeric characters like tabular figures and superscripts aren’t the exclusive province of workhorse type families, and not every project demands a sober serif or sans. When a project’s complexity requires a hard-working typeface, but its subject matter invites a more individual tone, look for unexpected typefaces that feature extended numerics. The handwritten &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/fonts/inkwell/features/inkwell-numerics&quot;&gt;Inkwell&lt;/a&gt; contains all the features needed to articulate demanding content, but its relaxed demeanor has a natural affinity for entertainment, retail, food services, the arts, hospitality, pediatric care, and even philanthropy:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/fonts/inkwell/styles/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d31td5fkd89rr1.cloudfront.net/assets/images/blog/designing-annual-reports.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;750&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/fonts/inkwell/overview/&quot;&gt;Inkwell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;alternate&quot;&gt;TIP:&lt;/strong&gt; If your tables will use only a single weight, consider a typeface whose numbers have &lt;em&gt;equal widths&lt;/em&gt; without the regular-and-bold &lt;em&gt;duplexing&lt;/em&gt; of true tabular figures. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/fonts/numbers/inside/indicia&quot;&gt;Indicia&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/fonts/numbers/inside/claimcheck&quot;&gt;Claimcheck&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/fonts/numbers/inside/revenue&quot;&gt;Revenue&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/fonts/numbers/inside/greenback&quot;&gt;Greenback&lt;/a&gt; typefaces in our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/fonts/numbers/overview/&quot;&gt;Numbers&lt;/a&gt; collection are designed on a fixed width, as are the cheeky digits in each weight of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/fonts/inkwell/inside/inkwell-blackletter&quot;&gt;Inkwell Blackletter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/collections/symbols-technical/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d31td5fkd89rr1.cloudfront.net/assets/images/blog/decorative-numbers3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;750&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Branding Custom Collateral&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last mile of visual communications are often the things created not by designers, but by software. It’s frequently the operators of word processors, spreadsheets, and presentation packages who need to speak in the organization’s voice, but lack the tools to do so properly. For these projects, we’ve created &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/blog/office-fonts&quot;&gt;Office Fonts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/collections/office/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d31td5fkd89rr1.cloudfront.net/assets/images/blog/designing-statements.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;750&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/fonts/isotope/overview/&quot;&gt;Isotope&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/fonts/whitney/styles/office/&quot;&gt;Whitney Office&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Office Fonts are adaptations of H&amp;amp;Co’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/collections/office/&quot;&gt;hardest-working typefaces&lt;/a&gt;, specifically engineered for use in business packages such as Word, Excel, and PowerPoint. These are the same families whose ScreenSmart fonts invite use at small sizes, and whose Pro character sets can tackle complex data. Reimagined for the non-designer, Office Fonts are limited to a familiar four styles per family (roman, italic, bold, and bold italic), and feature exclusively tabular figures, to avoid typographic mishaps that might go undetected. (And they ship in TrueType format, for maximum backward compatibility with even the most antiquated operating systems.) &lt;strong class=&quot;alternate&quot;&gt;TIP:&lt;/strong&gt; If a brand’s communications will ultimately include custom collateral like reports, proposals, statements, and presentations, design these documents from the outset using Office Fonts, to take advantage of their unique characteristics. —JH&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 02:46:01 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>privong</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.typography.com/blog/fonts-for-complex-data</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Tech watchdogs call on Facebook, Google for transparency around censored content</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2018/05/07/santa-clara-principles-eff-cdt-aclu-facebook-google-twitter/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2018/05/07/santa-clara-principles-eff-cdt-aclu-facebook-google-twitter/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;If a company like &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/facebook/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;facebook&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; can’t even understand why its moderation tools work the way they do, then its users certainly don’t have a fighting shot. Anyway, that’s the idea behind what a coalition of digital rights groups are calling The &lt;a href=&quot;https://cdt.org/files/2018/05/Santa_Clara_Principles.pdf&quot;&gt;Santa Clara Principles&lt;/a&gt; (PDF), “a set of minimum standards” aimed at Facebook, Google, Twitter and other tech companies that moderate the content published on their platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The suggested guidelines grew out of a set of events addressing “&lt;a href=&quot;http://comoatscale.com/&quot;&gt;Content Moderation and Removal at Scale&lt;/a&gt;,” the second of which is taking place &lt;a href=&quot;http://comoatscale.com/video/&quot;&gt;today&lt;/a&gt; in Washington, D.C. The group participating in these conversations shared the goal of coming up with a suggested ruleset for how major tech companies should disclose which content is being censored, why it is being censored and how much speech is censored overall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Users deserve more transparency and greater accountability from platforms that play an outsized role — in Myanmar, Australia, Europe, and China, as well as in marginalized communities in the U.S. and elsewhere — in deciding what can be said on the internet,” Electronic Frontier Foundation (EFF) Director for International Freedom of Expression Jillian C. York said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the Center for Democracy and Technology explains, The &lt;a href=&quot;https://cdt.org/files/2018/05/Santa_Clara_Principles.pdf&quot;&gt;Santa Clara principles&lt;/a&gt; (PDF) ask tech companies to disclose three categories of information:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Numbers (of posts removed, accounts suspended);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notice (to users about content removals and account suspensions); and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Appeals (for users impacted by content removals or account suspensions).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The Santa Clara Principles are the product of years of effort by privacy advocates to push tech companies to provide users with more disclosure and a better understanding of how content policing works,” EFF Senior Staff Attorney Nate Cardozo added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Facebook and &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/google/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;google&quot;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt; have taken some steps recently to improve transparency, and we applaud that. But it’s not enough. We hope to see the companies embrace The Santa Clara Principles and move the bar on transparency and accountability even higher.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participants in drafting The Santa Clara Principles include the ACLU Foundation of Northern California, Center for Democracy and Technology, Electronic Frontier Foundation, New America’s Open Technology Institute and a handful of scholars from departments studying ethics and communications.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 20:10:31 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>cfadvan</dc:creator>
<og:title>Tech watchdogs call on Facebook and Google for transparency around censored content</og:title>
<og:description>If a company like Facebook can’t even understand why its moderation tools work the way they do, then its users certainly don’t have a fighting shot. Anyway, that’s the idea behind what a coalition of digital rights groups are calling The Santa Clara Principles (PDF), “a set …</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/fb-hate-speech-censor1.jpg?w=711</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2018/05/07/santa-clara-principles-eff-cdt-aclu-facebook-google-twitter/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2018/05/07/santa-clara-principles-eff-cdt-aclu-facebook-google-twitter/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Conversations with a six-year-old on functional programming</title>
<link>https://byorgey.wordpress.com/2018/05/06/conversations-with-a-six-year-old-on-functional-programming/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://byorgey.wordpress.com/2018/05/06/conversations-with-a-six-year-old-on-functional-programming/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;My six-year-old son walked up to me yesterday. “What are you reading?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time, I was reading part of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.janis-voigtlaender.eu/papers/TypesForProgrammingAndReasoning.pdf&quot;&gt;Janis Voigtländer’s habilitation thesis&lt;/a&gt;. Unsure where to even start, I decided to just answer straightforwardly: “I’m reading a very long story about free theorems.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He persisted. “What are free theorems?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Never one to shrink from a pedagogical challenge, I thought for a moment, then began: “Do you know what a &lt;em&gt;function&lt;/em&gt; is?” He didn’t. “A function is like a machine where you put something in one end and something comes out the other end. For example, maybe you put a number in, and the number that is one bigger comes out. So if you put in three, four comes out, or if you put in six, seven comes out.” This clearly made sense to him, so I continued, “The &lt;em&gt;type&lt;/em&gt; of a function machine tells you what kinds of things you put in and what kinds of things come out. So maybe you put a number in and get a number out. Or maybe you put in a &lt;em&gt;list&lt;/em&gt; of numbers and get a number out.” He interrupted excitedly, “Or maybe you could put &lt;em&gt;words&lt;/em&gt; in??” “Yes, exactly! Maybe you can put words in and get words out. Or maybe there is a function machine where you put &lt;em&gt;other function machines&lt;/em&gt; in and get function machines out!” He gasped in astonishment at the idea of putting function machines into function machines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“So,” I concluded, “a free theorem is when you can say something that is always true about a function machine if you &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; know its type, but you &lt;em&gt;don’t&lt;/em&gt; know anything about what it does on the inside.” This seemed a bit beyond him (and to be fair, free theorems are only interesting when polymorphism is involved which I definitely didn’t want to go into). But the whole conversation had given me a different idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Hey, I have a good idea for a game,” I said. “It’s called the function machine game. I will think of a function machine. You tell me things to put into the function machine, and I will tell you what comes out. Then you have to guess what the function machine does.” He immediately liked this game and it has been a huge hit; he wants to play it all the time. We played it while driving to a party yesterday, and we played it this morning while I was in the shower. So far, he has correctly guessed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried &lt;img src=&quot;https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=%5Clambda+x.%5C%2C+%5Cmin%28x%2B2%2C10%29&amp;amp;bg=ffffff&amp;amp;fg=333333&amp;amp;s=0&quot; alt=&quot;\lambda x.\, \min(x+2,10)&quot; title=&quot;\lambda x.\, \min(x+2,10)&quot; class=&quot;latex&quot;/&gt; but that was a bit tough for him. I realized that in some cases he may understand intuitively what the function does but have trouble expressing it in words (this was also a problem with &lt;img src=&quot;https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=%5Clambda+x.%5C%2C+10+%5Clfloor+x%2F10+%5Crfloor&amp;amp;bg=ffffff&amp;amp;fg=333333&amp;amp;s=0&quot; alt=&quot;\lambda x.\, 10 \lfloor x/10 \rfloor&quot; title=&quot;\lambda x.\, 10 \lfloor x/10 \rfloor&quot; class=&quot;latex&quot;/&gt;), so we started using the obvious variant where once the guesser thinks they know what the function does, the players switch roles and the person who came up with function specifies some inputs in order to test whether the guesser is able to produce the correct outputs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=%5Clambda+x.%5C%2C+6&amp;amp;bg=ffffff&amp;amp;fg=333333&amp;amp;s=0&quot; alt=&quot;\lambda x.\, 6&quot; title=&quot;\lambda x.\, 6&quot; class=&quot;latex&quot;/&gt; was also surprisingly difficult for him to guess (though he did get it right eventually). I think he was just stuck on the idea of the function doing something arithmetical to the input, and was having trouble coming up with some sort of arithmetic procedure which would result in &lt;img src=&quot;https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=6&amp;amp;bg=ffffff&amp;amp;fg=333333&amp;amp;s=0&quot; alt=&quot;6&quot; title=&quot;6&quot; class=&quot;latex&quot;/&gt; no matter what you put in! It simply hadn’t occurred to him that the machine might &lt;em&gt;not care&lt;/em&gt; about the input. (Interestingly, many students in my functional programming class this semester were also confused by constant functions when we were learning about the lambda calculus; they really wanted to substitute the input &lt;em&gt;somewhere&lt;/em&gt; and were upset/confused by the fact that the bound variable did not occur in the body at all!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a few rounds of guessing my functions, he wanted to come up with his own functions for me to guess (as I knew he would). Sometimes his functions are great and sometimes they don’t make sense (usually because his idea of what the function does changes over time, which of course he, in all sincerity, denies), but it’s fun either way. And after he finally understood &lt;img src=&quot;https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=%5Clambda+x.+%5Cmin%28x%2B2%2C+10%29&amp;amp;bg=ffffff&amp;amp;fg=333333&amp;amp;s=0&quot; alt=&quot;\lambda x. \min(x+2, 10)&quot; title=&quot;\lambda x. \min(x+2, 10)&quot; class=&quot;latex&quot;/&gt;, he came up with his own function which was something like&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=%5Clambda+x%3A%5Cmathbb%7BN%7D.+%5Cbegin%7Bcases%7D+10+-+x+%26+x+%5Cleq+10+%5C%5C+10+%26+%5Ctext%7Botherwise%7D+%5Cend%7Bcases%7D&amp;amp;bg=ffffff&amp;amp;fg=333333&amp;amp;s=0&quot; alt=&quot;\lambda x:\mathbb{N}. \begin{cases} 10 - x &amp;amp; x \leq 10 \\ 10 &amp;amp; \text{otherwise} \end{cases}&quot; title=&quot;\lambda x:\mathbb{N}. \begin{cases} 10 - x &amp;amp; x \leq 10 \\ 10 &amp;amp; \text{otherwise} \end{cases}&quot; class=&quot;latex&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;inspired, I think, by his kindergarten class where they were learning about pairs of numbers that added up to &lt;img src=&quot;https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=10&amp;amp;bg=ffffff&amp;amp;fg=333333&amp;amp;s=0&quot; alt=&quot;10&quot; title=&quot;10&quot; class=&quot;latex&quot;/&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Definitely one of my better parenting days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;wpcnt&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wpa wpmrec&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;wpa-about&quot;&gt;Advertisements&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;jp-post-flair&quot; class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-like-enabled sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;robots-nocontent sd-block sd-social sd-social-icon-text sd-sharing&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Share this:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 19:24:11 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>weatherlight</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Conversations with a six-year-old on functional programming</og:title>
<og:url>https://byorgey.wordpress.com/2018/05/06/conversations-with-a-six-year-old-on-functional-programming/</og:url>
<og:description>My six-year-old son walked up to me yesterday. “What are you reading?” At the time, I was reading part of Janis Voigtländer’s habilitation thesis. Unsure where to even start, I decided to just ans…</og:description>
<og:image>https://s0.wp.com/i/blank.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://byorgey.wordpress.com/2018/05/06/conversations-with-a-six-year-old-on-functional-programming/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Who controls glibc?</title>
<link>https://lwn.net/SubscriberLink/753646/a6ebb50040c5862c/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://lwn.net/SubscriberLink/753646/a6ebb50040c5862c/</guid>
<description>&lt;center&gt;
&lt;table width=&quot;90%&quot; cellspacing=&quot;5&quot; readability=&quot;4.1829745596869&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;11.154598825832&quot;&gt;&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Welcome to LWN.net&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following subscription-only content has been made available to you by an LWN subscriber. Thousands of subscribers depend on LWN for the best news from the Linux and free software communities. If you enjoy this article, please consider accepting the trial offer on the right. Thank you for visiting LWN.net!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;Form&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; readability=&quot;1.2016574585635&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.6049723756906&quot;&gt;&lt;td readability=&quot;4.8066298342541&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Free trial subscription&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try LWN for free for 1 month: no payment or credit card required. &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/Promo/slink-trial2-2/claim&quot;&gt;Activate your trial subscription now&lt;/a&gt; and see why thousands of readers subscribe to LWN.net.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By &lt;strong&gt;Jonathan Corbet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;May 7, 2018&lt;/p&gt;
The removal of an old joke from the GNU C Library manual might not seem like the sort of topic that would inspire a heated debate. At times, though, a small action can serve as an inadvertent proxy for a more significant question, one which is relevant to both the developers and the users of the project. In this case, that question would be: how is the project governed and who makes decisions about which patches are applied?
&lt;p&gt;Toward the end of April, Raymond Nicholson posted &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/Articles/753647/&quot;&gt;a patch to the glibc manual&lt;/a&gt; removing a joke that he didn't think was useful to readers. The joke played on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/libc/manual/html_node/Aborting-a-Program.html&quot;&gt;documentation for &lt;tt&gt;abort()&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to make a statement about US government policy on providing information about abortions. As Nicholson noted: &quot;&lt;span&gt;The joke does not provide any useful information about the abort() function so removing it will not hinder use of glibc&lt;/span&gt;&quot;. On April 30, Zack Weinberg &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/Articles/753649/&quot;&gt;applied the patch&lt;/a&gt; to the glibc repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Richard Stallman, who added the joke sometime in the 1990s, &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/Articles/753651/&quot;&gt;asked&lt;/a&gt; that it not be removed. The resulting discussion touched on a number of issues. Carlos O'Donell, who has been trying hard to resolve the issue with some degree of consensus, &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/Articles/753653/&quot;&gt;suggested&lt;/a&gt; that the joke could hurt people who have had bad experiences associated with abortion. He proposed a couple of possible alternatives, including avoiding jokes entirely or discussing such issues in a different forum. Stallman, however, &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/Articles/753654/&quot;&gt;replied&lt;/a&gt; that &quot;&lt;span&gt;a GNU manual, like a course in history, is not meant to be a 'safe space'&lt;/span&gt;&quot;. He suggested the possibility of adding a trigger warning about functions that create child processes, since childbirth is &quot;&lt;span&gt;far more traumatic than having an abortion&lt;/span&gt;&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether the joke belongs in the glibc manual is an issue for the glibc developers to decide and wouldn't normally be of much interest beyond the project itself. But in this case, it raises the question of how the developers make this decision. &lt;a href=&quot;https://sourceware.org/glibc/wiki/Consensus&quot;&gt;The project's wiki&lt;/a&gt; states that the project &quot;&lt;span&gt;uses a consensus-based community-driven development model&lt;/span&gt;&quot;. In this case, there seems to be a fairly clear consensus among the actual glibc developers that this joke is not appropriate in the project's manual. Weinberg's application of the patch was based on this consensus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stallman, however, has made it clear that there are limits to the extent to which glibc is consensus-based; his &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/Articles/753655/&quot;&gt;response&lt;/a&gt; was: &quot;&lt;span&gt;My decision is to keep the joke&lt;/span&gt;&quot;. Weinberg &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/Articles/753656/&quot;&gt;stated&lt;/a&gt; his refusal to revert the change; Stallman &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/Articles/753657/&quot;&gt;answered&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;&lt;span&gt;I stand by my decision to keep the joke&lt;/span&gt;&quot;. O'Donell &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/Articles/753658/&quot;&gt;apologized&lt;/a&gt; for not contacting Stallman directly about the removal, but also stood by the decision to remove it. He asked:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A large group of developers, serious senior developers, at least 3 project stewards (GNU Developers for the project), are indicating that they do not share your same view on the joke. Please consider their input and work with me to reach a consensus position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weinberg &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/Articles/753688/&quot;&gt;defended&lt;/a&gt; his application of the patch:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't think I did anything wrong procedurally. RMS may be the project leader, but he is not a glibc maintainer. His wishes regarding glibc are perhaps to be given _some_ more weight than those of any other individual, particularly when he is also the author of text under dispute, but we have never, to my knowledge, treated them as mandates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stallman was unimpressed, though, and fell back to a pure authority play, &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/Articles/753660/&quot;&gt;saying&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;&lt;span&gt;As the head of the GNU Project, I am in charge of what we publish in GNU manuals. I decide the criteria to decide by, too&lt;/span&gt;&quot;. He later &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/Articles/753661/&quot;&gt;added&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I exercise my authority over Glibc very rarely -- and when I have done so, I have talked with the official maintainers. So rarely that some of you thought that you are entirely autonomous. But that is not the case. On this particular question, I made a decision long ago and stated it where all of you could see it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O'Donell &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/Articles/753662/&quot;&gt;repeated&lt;/a&gt; that a discussion was underway and that the maintainers did not intend to revert the patch. He also asked whether the change violated any GNU policies — a question that went unanswered as of this writing. He also &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/Articles/753663/&quot;&gt;stated clearly&lt;/a&gt; that the joke would not return in any form until some sort of consensus was reached.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One could argue that the consensus is already there if one looks at the developers who actually work on glibc; it is difficult to find any of them arguing for the joke's return. The number of people arguing for the joke in general is quite small. That did not stop Alexandre Oliva, who evidently &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/Articles/753666/&quot;&gt;has a high opinion&lt;/a&gt; of Stallman's sense of humor, from &lt;a href=&quot;https://sourceware.org/git/?p=glibc.git;a=commitdiff;h=ffa81c22a3ac0fb75ad9bf2b1c3cdbf9eafa0bc9&quot;&gt;reverting&lt;/a&gt; the change early on May 7 — his first glibc change in 2018. He did not post his change to the mailing list (and only &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/Articles/753699/&quot;&gt;explained it&lt;/a&gt; after being asked); his attempt to justify it as a return to consensus &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/Articles/753700/&quot;&gt;did not fly&lt;/a&gt; with O'Donell. This discussion, one suspects, is not done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each project has its own governance model. The &quot;authoritarian leader&quot; model is quite common in this space, with many projects subject to the will of a (hopefully benevolent) dictator who can decide to accept or reject any change. Sometimes that model works better than others; glibc itself improved its processes and inclusiveness considerably when its single leader was replaced by a more consensus-oriented model. Usually, though, such leaders are at least active developers in the projects they manage; that is not the case for the GNU projects. It can be discouraging for a developer to discover that their changes are subject to a veto from on high by somebody who is not otherwise involved with the project's development. The echoes of this action may thus persist in the glibc community for some time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;br clear=&quot;all&quot; /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;Form&quot; readability=&quot;1.2534246575342&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.5068493150685&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Did you like this article?&lt;/strong&gt; Please accept our &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/Promo/slink-trial2-2/claim&quot;&gt;trial subscription offer&lt;/a&gt; to be able to see more content like it and to participate in the discussion.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr width=&quot;60%&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;
(&lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/login?target=/Articles/753646/&quot;&gt;Log in&lt;/a&gt; to post comments)</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 19:22:30 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>CJefferson</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://lwn.net/SubscriberLink/753646/a6ebb50040c5862c/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Cutting Edge Deep Learning for Coders, Part 2</title>
<link>http://course.fast.ai/part2.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://course.fast.ai/part2.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;item&quot; readability=&quot;13.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;I’ve tried (and if I’m honest) failed to scale the steep deep learning curve many times. I realise with hindsight it was the equations that were preventing me from becoming a deep learning practitioner. Jeremy brought me up to speed with the state-of-the-art, and within two weeks I was in the top half of the leaderboard for three Kaggle competitions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;author-avatar&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://course.fast.ai/images/people/chrisk.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;author-name&quot;&gt;- &lt;strong&gt;Christopher Kelly&lt;/strong&gt; , CEO- Nourish, Balance, Thrive&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;item&quot; readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;If you are looking to venture into the Deep learning field, look no further and take this course. It is very hands-on and adopts a top-down approach, which means everyone irrespective of varying knowledge can get started with implementing Deep learning models immediately. Another major factor why this course is very appealing is its emphasis on social relevance. That is, how can we use this awesome technology to serve the world better?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;author-avatar&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://course.fast.ai/images/people/sravya.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;author-name&quot;&gt;- &lt;strong&gt;Sravya Tirukkovalur&lt;/strong&gt; , Vice President, Apache Sentry&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;item&quot; readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;This course filled a gap I couldn't find anywhere else—there really is no other source where I could learn from a 'code first' perspective. This means you can prod, poke, and cajole these networks in different ways, and see how they respond. You can quickly feel an intuitive perspective growing as you explore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;author-avatar&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://course.fast.ai/images/people/mattob.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;author-name&quot;&gt;- &lt;strong&gt;Matt O'Brien&lt;/strong&gt; , Data Scientist, UCSF Neurology&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;item&quot; readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;I teach machine learning in a master’s degree program. After this course, I cannot ignore the new developments in deep learning—I will devote one third of my machine learning course to the subject. Also, I now have the tools to apply deep learning models to real world problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;author-avatar&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://course.fast.ai/images/people/yannet.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;author-name&quot;&gt;- &lt;strong&gt;Yannet Interian&lt;/strong&gt; , Assistant Professor of Analytics, University of San Francisco&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;item&quot; readability=&quot;11.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;It was very empowering to be able to start training a model within minutes downloading the Jupyter notebooks. Jeremy and Rachel were excellent instructors and the content was high quality and enlightening. It was very cool to be able to read blogposts about the latest Deep Learning research and actually be able to understand it. I was surprised to be able to match academic results from just 2 years ago with pretty simple architectures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;author-avatar&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://course.fast.ai/images/people/robink.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;author-name&quot;&gt;- &lt;strong&gt;Robin Kraft (@robinkraft)&lt;/strong&gt; , Product Manager at Planet Labs (Satellites)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;item&quot; readability=&quot;13.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;I'm a CEO, not a coder, so the idea that I'd be able to create a GPU deep learning server in the cloud meant learning a lot of new things—but with all the help on the wiki and from the instructors and community on the forum I did it! Jeremy is an incredible instructor and is able to make what might seem like a difficult subject completely accessible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;author-avatar&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://course.fast.ai/images/people/nichol.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;author-name&quot;&gt;- &lt;strong&gt;Nichol Bradford&lt;/strong&gt; , Executive Director of Transformative Tech Lab at Sofia University&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;item&quot; readability=&quot;13.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;Sometimes I feared whether I would be able to solve any deep learning problems, as all the research papers I read were very mathy beyond reach of simple intuitive terms. But Jeremy and Rachel (Course Professors) believe in the theory of 'Simple is Powerful', by virtue of which anyone who takes this course will be able to confidently understand the simple techniques behind the 'magic' Deep Learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;author-avatar&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://course.fast.ai/images/people/shetty.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;author-name&quot;&gt;- &lt;strong&gt;Janardhan Shetty&lt;/strong&gt; , Senior Big Data Engineer at Salesforce&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;item&quot; readability=&quot;14.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;Running a company is extremely time intensive, so I was a weary of taking on the commitment of the course. It was definitely worth it, though. It smashed my preconceptions about the technological obstructions to doing deep learning, and showed again and again examples where just a small subset of the training data and just a few epochs of training on standard GPU hardware could get most of the way towards a really good model&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;author-avatar&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://course.fast.ai/images/people/dario.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;author-name&quot;&gt;- &lt;strong&gt;Dario Fanucchi&lt;/strong&gt; , Co-founder and CTO at Isazi Consulting&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;item&quot; readability=&quot;13.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;It can take years to develop the necessary skills and knowledge for Deep Learning, especially without the support of mentors and peers. Not only did Jeremy teach us the most valuable methods and practices, he provided us with an invaluable community and environment. The course exceeded my expectations and showed me first hand how both Deep Learning and ourselves could change the world for better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;author-avatar&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://course.fast.ai/images/people/taro.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;author-name&quot;&gt;- &lt;strong&gt;Taro-Shigenori Chiba&lt;/strong&gt; , Organizer of the SF Deep Learning Study Group&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 19:15:16 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mlboss</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://course.fast.ai/part2.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: How to Tune a Guitar</title>
<link>https://mathisonian.github.io/idyll/how-to-tune-a-guitar/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://mathisonian.github.io/idyll/how-to-tune-a-guitar/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;article-header idyll-header&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mathisonian.github.io/idyll/how-to-tune-a-guitar/images/speaker.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fixed&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;guitar-svg&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Loading audio...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;section readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a second and strum the guitar. It doesn’t sound so good, does it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve just taken it out of storage and &lt;em&gt;it’s all out of tune...&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section idyll=&quot;[object Object]&quot; readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tune the guitar using the tuner. Click and drag the tuning knobs on the right to tighten and loosen the strings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section idyll=&quot;[object Object]&quot; readability=&quot;1.5&quot;&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This doesn’t sound in tune quite yet. Scroll back up and try to get all of the tuning knobs to turn green.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section idyll=&quot;[object Object]&quot; readability=&quot;10.9453125&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guitars generate noise through the vibration of their strings. On an electric guitar such as this one, magnetic “pick-ups” convert those vibrations into an electrical signal which can then be sent to a tuner or an amplifier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This signal can be &lt;a href=&quot;https://pudding.cool/2018/02/waveforms/&quot;&gt;visualized as a raw waveform&lt;/a&gt;, but often we want to visualize the frequency instead. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://jackschaedler.github.io/circles-sines-signals/dft_introduction.html&quot;&gt;fourier transform&lt;/a&gt; is a mathematical function that reveals the audio frequencies hidden in that wave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strum the guitar to see the frequency visualized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section idyll=&quot;[object Object]&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we’ve tuned the guitar using a tuner, let’s try to tune the guitar by ear. This is more challenging, and it may take you time to master.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;p&gt;The guitar is out of tune again!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section idyll=&quot;[object Object]&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll start by tuning to a reference note. When you manipulate the tuners on the right the current note will be played, as will a reference note.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;button idyll=&quot;[object Object]&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Turn distortion off.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will be easier with a cleaner sound. Match the two sounds to get the guitar in tune.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section idyll=&quot;[object Object]&quot; readability=&quot;29.44219886823&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Harmonic Intervals.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the strings on a guitar are separated by an interval known as a &lt;em&gt;perfect fourth&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;button class=&quot;interval&quot; idyll=&quot;[object Object]&quot;&gt;♬ E2-A2&lt;/button&gt;&lt;button class=&quot;interval&quot; idyll=&quot;[object Object]&quot;&gt;♬ A2-D3&lt;/button&gt;&lt;button class=&quot;interval&quot; idyll=&quot;[object Object]&quot;&gt;♬ D3-G3&lt;/button&gt;&lt;button class=&quot;interval&quot; idyll=&quot;[object Object]&quot;&gt;♬ B3-E4&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The perfect fourth is beautifully resonant, but there’s one pair of strings on a guitar which are not separated by a perfect fourth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interval between the &lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;GG&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathit&quot;&gt;G&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;BB&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathit&quot;&gt;B&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; strings is a &lt;em&gt;major third&lt;/em&gt;. The major third sounds happy and uplifting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;button class=&quot;interval&quot; idyll=&quot;[object Object]&quot;&gt;♬ G3-B4&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
These intervals show up all the time in music, for example, the major third can be found the first two notes of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/When_the_Saints_Go_Marching_In&quot;&gt;The Saints&lt;/a&gt;. The first two notes of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amazing_Grace&quot;&gt;Amazing Grace&lt;/a&gt; form a perfect fourth.
&lt;p&gt;Learning to hear these intervals will help you tune your guitar without a tuner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Find the beat.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When two strings are played together, they produce a third higher frequency known as an overtone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the two strings are not perfectly in tune, the overtone is inconsistent over time. This produces a wobbling, &lt;em&gt;a beat&lt;/em&gt;, in the overtone which you can hear if you listen carefully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Play notes with a &lt;span class=&quot;idyll-dynamic&quot;&gt;5.00&lt;/span&gt; Hz difference:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;button idyll=&quot;[object Object]&quot;&gt;Listen for the beats!&lt;/button&gt;&lt;button idyll=&quot;[object Object]&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Turn distortion off.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you get a pair of strings closer in tune, the beats will slow down until the overtone is perfecly amplified. Listening for the slowing of these beats is a helpful cue for tuning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try tuning the guitar by listening for the relationships between adjacent strings and the beats in the resultant overtone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;button idyll=&quot;[object Object]&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Show tuner&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;button idyll=&quot;[object Object]&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Remove distortion&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;button class=&quot;tune-action&quot; idyll=&quot;[object Object]&quot;&gt;Tune Guitar&lt;/button&gt;&lt;button class=&quot;tune-action&quot; idyll=&quot;[object Object]&quot;&gt;Detune Guitar&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section readability=&quot;5.9719626168224&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This page was built using &lt;a href=&quot;https://idyll-lang.org&quot;&gt;Idyll&lt;/a&gt;, a markup language for interactive documents. The guitar was created using &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mathisonian/sketch-interactive-export&quot;&gt;Sketch Interactive Export&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://d3js.org/&quot;&gt;D3&lt;/a&gt;, and a modified version of &lt;a href=&quot;https://tonejs.github.io/&quot;&gt;Tone.js&lt;/a&gt;. Audio samples were provided by &lt;a href=&quot;https://freesound.org/people/SpeedY/&quot;&gt;freesound.org user SpeedY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project is from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://idl.cs.washington.edu/&quot;&gt;Interactive Data Lab&lt;/a&gt; at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cs.washington.edu/&quot;&gt;University of Washington&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 18:18:56 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mathisonian</dc:creator>
<og:title>How To: Tune a Guitar</og:title>
<og:image>https://mathisonian.github.io/idyll/how-to-tune-a-guitar/images/share.png</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>An interactive audio guide with guitars and a little music theory.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mathisonian.github.io/idyll/how-to-tune-a-guitar/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ask HN: How do you continuously monitor web logs for hack attempts?</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17014818</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17014818</guid>
<description>&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.55737704918033&quot;&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=&quot;#FF6600&quot;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.9904648390942&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;fatitem&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.7067938021454&quot;&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing&quot; id=&quot;17014818&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;title&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17014818&quot; class=&quot;storylink&quot;&gt;Ask HN: How do you continuously monitor web logs for hack attempts?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.71428571428571&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;subtext&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;score&quot; id=&quot;score_17014818&quot;&gt;356 points&lt;/span&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/user?id=sandGorgon&quot; class=&quot;hnuser&quot;&gt;sandGorgon&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;age&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17014818&quot;&gt;17 hours ago&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span id=&quot;unv_17014818&quot;/&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/hide?id=17014818&amp;amp;goto=item%3Fid%3D17014818&quot;&gt;hide&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://hn.algolia.com/?query=Ask%20HN%3A%20How%20do%20you%20continuously%20monitor%20web%20logs%20for%20hack%20attempts%3F&amp;amp;sort=byDate&amp;amp;dateRange=all&amp;amp;type=story&amp;amp;storyText=false&amp;amp;prefix&amp;amp;page=0&quot; class=&quot;hnpast&quot;&gt;past&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=Ask%20HN%3A%20How%20do%20you%20continuously%20monitor%20web%20logs%20for%20hack%20attempts%3F&quot;&gt;web&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/fave?id=17014818&amp;amp;auth=fda63792fbd494fe93c235b4187cbe82ef1d26b2&quot;&gt;favorite&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17014818&quot;&gt;172 comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;13.5&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;what is the generally accepted best practice to be monitoring web logs for anomalous accesses ?
&lt;p&gt;do you guys just throw cloudflare in front and forget about it ? Or do you have engineers who work like data scientists - eyeball the logs ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have heard suggestions of using a firewall - but I'm genuinely curious on how do security focus companies discover things like &quot;oh, we got attacked by Bitcoin miners from North Korea&quot;. Are there sophisticated tools that do this for you.. or is there a generally accepted practice that has evolved for even regular engineers to do this ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P.S. I'm personally more interested in an API-focused answer, but I guess the same thing applies for websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;yclinks&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsguidelines.html&quot;&gt;Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsfaq.html&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Support&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/HackerNews/API&quot;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/security.html&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/lists&quot;&gt;Lists&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/bookmarklet.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Bookmarklet&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/legal/&quot;&gt;Legal&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Apply to YC&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Contact&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 17:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>sandGorgon</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17014818</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Uber vehicle reportedly saw but ignored woman it struck</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2018/05/07/uber-vehicle-reportedly-saw-but-ignored-woman-it-struck/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2018/05/07/uber-vehicle-reportedly-saw-but-ignored-woman-it-struck/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The cause of the fatal crash of an &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/uber/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;uber&quot;&gt;Uber&lt;/a&gt; self-driving car appears to have been at the software level, specifically a function that determines which objects to ignore and which to attend to, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theinformation.com/articles/uber-finds-deadly-accident-likely-caused-by-software-set-to-ignore-objects-on-road&quot;&gt;The Information reported&lt;/a&gt;. This puts the fault squarely on Uber’s doorstep, though there was never much reason to think it belonged anywhere else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/19/heres-how-ubers-self-driving-cars-are-supposed-to-detect-pedestrians/&quot;&gt;Given the multiplicity of vision systems and backups&lt;/a&gt; on board any given autonomous vehicle, it seemed impossible that any one of them failing could have prevented the car’s systems from perceiving Elaine Herzberg, who was crossing the street directly in front of the lidar and front-facing cameras. Yet the car didn’t even touch the brakes or sound an alarm. Combined with an inattentive safety driver, this failure resulted in Herzberg’s death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only possibilities that made sense were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A:&lt;/strong&gt; Fault in the object recognition system, which may have failed to classify Herzberg and her bike as a pedestrian. This seems unlikely since bikes and people are among the things the system should be most competent at identifying.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B:&lt;/strong&gt; Fault in the car’s higher logic, which makes decisions like which objects to pay attention to and what to do about them. No need to slow down for a parked bike at the side of the road, for instance, but one swerving into the lane in front of the car is cause for immediate action. This mimics human attention and decision making and prevents the car from panicking at every new object detected.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The sources cited by The Information say that Uber has determined B was the problem. Specifically, it was that the system was set up to ignore objects that it should have attended to; Herzberg seems to have been detected but considered a false positive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autonomous vehicles have superhuman senses: lidar that stretches out hundreds of feet in pitch darkness, object recognition that tracks dozens of cars and pedestrians at once, radar and other systems to watch the road around it unblinkingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But all these senses are subordinate, like our own, to a “brain” — a central processing unit that takes the information from the cameras and other sensors and combines it into a meaningful picture of the world around it, then makes decisions based on that picture in real time. This is by far the hardest part of the car to create, as Uber has shown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t matter how good your eyes are if your brain doesn’t know what it’s looking at or how to respond properly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: Uber issued the following statement, but did not comment on the claims above:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re actively cooperating with the NTSB in their investigation. Out of respect for that process and the trust we’ve built with NTSB, we can’t comment on the specifics of the incident. In the meantime, we have initiated a top-to-bottom safety review of our self-driving vehicles program, and we have brought on former NTSB Chair Christopher Hart to advise us on our overall safety culture. Our review is looking at everything from the safety of our system to our training processes for vehicle operators, and we hope to have more to say soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As this is a situation without precedent, the NTSB and other reports may be particularly difficult to create and slow to issue, and it’s not abnormal for a company or individual to hold off from revealing too much information ahead of publication.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 17:52:43 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>runesoerensen</dc:creator>
<og:title>Uber vehicle reportedly saw but ignored woman it struck</og:title>
<og:description>The cause of the fatal crash of an Uber self-driving car appears to have been at the software level, specifically a function that determines which objects to ignore and which to attend to, The Information reported. This puts the fault squarely on Uber's doorstep, though there was never much reason …</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/ubercar-11.jpg?w=600</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2018/05/07/uber-vehicle-reportedly-saw-but-ignored-woman-it-struck/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2018/05/07/uber-vehicle-reportedly-saw-but-ignored-woman-it-struck/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Economics of Writing a Technical Book</title>
<link>https://medium.com/p/the-economics-of-writing-a-technical-book-689d0c12fe39</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://medium.com/p/the-economics-of-writing-a-technical-book-689d0c12fe39</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--insetColumn&quot; readability=&quot;141.11337209302&quot;&gt;

&lt;p name=&quot;9a00&quot; id=&quot;9a00&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;I am not an expert. I have co-authored a single book in 2017 called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cnibook.info&quot; data-href=&quot;http://www.cnibook.info&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;Cloud Native Infrastructure&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for O’Reilly Media. Many people have asked me what it was like so I will attempt to explain the process, time investment, and financial incentive here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;e364&quot; id=&quot;e364&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;This was &lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;my&lt;/strong&gt; experience. If you have written a book, or would like to, I promise your experience will be different. Nonetheless, I hope you can learn something from the things I learned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;65c3&quot; id=&quot;65c3&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Process&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;327c&quot; id=&quot;327c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;The process was about what I expected. I was introduced to Brian, our first of three editors, from someone I knew who was already writing their third book. They thought I might be a good fit for what they were looking for so they made the introduction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*eNnav_Kcf-C_EoLjxARDiQ.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1920&quot; data-height=&quot;1080&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*eNnav_Kcf-C_EoLjxARDiQ.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*eNnav_Kcf-C_EoLjxARDiQ.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;211e&quot; id=&quot;211e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;I thought about it for a couple weeks and then submitted a formal book proposal which entailed filling out a Word document template and emailing it to the editor. I didn’t hear back for about 3 weeks and then, after a follow-up email, heard the proposal was approved. After a kick-off call it was suggested that I find a co-author to help write the book. I had a week to find one and then needed to sign a contract with O’Reilly for dates and deliverables. I interviewed a few people and &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@transplain&quot; data-href=&quot;https://medium.com/@transplain&quot; data-anchor-type=&quot;2&quot; data-user-id=&quot;158602cec861&quot; data-action-value=&quot;158602cec861&quot; data-action=&quot;show-user-card&quot; data-action-type=&quot;hover&quot; class=&quot;markup--user markup--p-user&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Kris Nova&lt;/a&gt; and I complemented each others skills perfectly for the content we wanted to cover in the book. She agreed it sounded like a good topic and she was excited to take on the challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;8bdb&quot; id=&quot;8bdb&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The contract seemed fairly standard and focused around content ownership and royalties split. The default split between authors is 50/50 which we stuck with. The contract stipulated that Kris and I own the copyright for the content, but O’Reilly has exclusive rights to use the content any way they see fit throughout the world now and in the future for the duration of the copyright.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;4d55&quot; id=&quot;4d55&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Once the contract was signed there was a steady pace of work as we both figured out how to lay out content and what we should write about. O’Reilly provides a platform called Atlas for writing which is quite good. You write in plain text &lt;a href=&quot;http://asciidoc.org/&quot; data-href=&quot;http://asciidoc.org/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;AsciiDoc&lt;/a&gt; and then O’Reilly’s Atlas platform can generate a PDF, or other formats, via the web interface or API. We both used &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/odewahn/atlas-cli&quot; data-href=&quot;https://github.com/odewahn/atlas-cli&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;atlas-cli&lt;/a&gt; to generate PDFs as we wrote. Generating the PDFs was a good feedback loop on the content. It helped make sure formatting was right and also allowed us to take a step back to read what we wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;5f56&quot; id=&quot;5f56&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Atlas works as a remote git repo but Kris and I chose to mostly work out of a private GitHub repo. We originally envisioned making pull requests to collaborate on each other's content but that didn’t happen as much as expected. Atlas has editing tools and some additional features available but we mostly just used it as a git remote URL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;6dc9&quot; id=&quot;6dc9&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;On March 1st we were assigned our cover animal which Kris and I named Andy O’Connor the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Andean_condor&quot; data-href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Andean_condor&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Andean Condor&lt;/a&gt;. We were pretty excited to see the cover for the first time even if the subtitle went through multiple revisions. We didn’t get to pick the animal or the picture. We were told up front we wouldn’t get to pick the animal so we knew what to expect. We were also told that Tyrannosaurus Rex and unicorns are not allowed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;0*srZXvqZpo2266zkp.png&quot; data-width=&quot;381&quot; data-height=&quot;500&quot; data-is-featured=&quot;true&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/0*srZXvqZpo2266zkp.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;34ad&quot; id=&quot;34ad&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;We kept writing until the 1/2 draft was due in early June. We turned it in and got less feedback than we expected, but it was still good to have a fresh set of eyes looking at it. We didn’t like what we had created. We had written almost 6 chapters and threw away 3 of them. The first two were heavily edited and the remaining chapter was trimmed down significantly and turned into an appendix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;542b&quot; id=&quot;542b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;We had some more planning meetings and came up with a revised outline that we submitted to our editor for review. By this time we were on our 2nd editor who wasn’t very familiar with the project so we got very little feedback and went with what we had.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;b863&quot; id=&quot;b863&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;We kept writing with minimal interactions with our editor until we were really close to needing the full draft due. I had sent select chapters to friends to look at and tried to incorporate the changes they suggested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;c3b0&quot; id=&quot;c3b0&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The first Tuesday of September the full draft was due and then went into a review process. There were technical reviewers we were able to suggest but mostly O’Reilly pulled from a pool of their trusted reviewers. We got minimal feedback from most of them (a survey form) and one returned notes on the PDF. We had a week to make edits. During this time the draft was made available as a preview on Safari books. In retrospect I wish we had posted preview chapters sooner which was something our first editor suggested, but we were both too embarrassed to follow through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;848e&quot; id=&quot;848e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;It wasn’t enough feedback for me so I reached out to more people and sent them chapters looking for someone to tell me it sucks and why. Luckily, I found someone who would give me the harsh feedback I wanted and I had about 3 days to incorporate their changes into the book before it went off to post production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;2b9a&quot; id=&quot;2b9a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The last push was very difficult and stressful. There were a lot of big changes on the last weekend which was a risk, but I think in the end made the book better. The final weekend we moved some chapters around and wrote a chapter from scratch for content we felt was missing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;7f4c&quot; id=&quot;7f4c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Post production was handled by non-technical, professional editors for grammar, spelling, and general readability. I believe the first PDF came back with more than 1300 edits. Overall there were more than 2000 changes made during post. I later found out this amount of edits is fairly standard for our book length. We had about 3 weeks of emailing large, heavily notated PDFs back and forth which was no fun compared to the plain text git workflow of writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p name=&quot;35c5&quot; id=&quot;35c5&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;Post production took about a month to complete and then the book went off for printing. At the same time it was posted on Safari Books Online and immediately available. We each received 6 copies of the book in the mail shortly after it was available for sale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;36a7&quot; id=&quot;36a7&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;All in all I worked from Feb — Oct for roughly 5 nights a week at 2–3 hours per night. I also worked about 3 weekends non-stop when a draft or final edits were due. Roughly I’d say I worked about 500 hours total. That was only my time and doesn’t include Kris’. I was lucky to have a co-author to share the load.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;d209&quot; id=&quot;d209&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Some people have asked how I found motivation to keep writing. I’m a fairly driven individual and the deadlines in the contract were enough for me to put in time most nights. I wasn’t motivated enough to meet the original 250 page goal, but I was happy with the content we were able to cover and how much we accomplished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*065i2j1xvje7kA7iStSH7Q.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1183&quot; data-height=&quot;601&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*065i2j1xvje7kA7iStSH7Q.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*065i2j1xvje7kA7iStSH7Q.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Not a perfect depiction of work done but shows when activity happened
&lt;p name=&quot;8a31&quot; id=&quot;8a31&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;Kris had a different creative process than I did. She was better at mulling over a topic in her head and putting it all down in one sitting; often the week before one of the deadlines. This made me nervous on multiple occasions and was probably the biggest thing I stressed about. Everything was submitted and completed on time, but I would suggest you have a sense for how you and your co-author work together at the beginning instead of the week before a project deadline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;6650&quot; id=&quot;6650&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Throughout the writing process I felt like I finished writing multiple times. Once when the final draft was due, once when technical reviewer’s feedback was incorporated, and once at the end of the post editing process. In each case it meant we got to take a break from writing while we waited for feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;4e20&quot; id=&quot;4e20&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;At the end of final edits I was done (contractually and mentally). I had read through the entire book at least three times and much of the content was starting to lose meaning. After sending the final edited PDF I wanted to stress about missing an edit before going to bed, but I was too tired to care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;a290&quot; id=&quot;a290&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Marketing and Affiliate Links&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;f436&quot; id=&quot;f436&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;O’Reilly provides an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cj.com/&quot; data-href=&quot;http://www.cj.com/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;affiliate program&lt;/a&gt; which was terrible to set up and in the end hardly worth the time. You get a cut from all sales that go through your link but I have never received any money from affiliate book sales. The only money I got was when someone used my link and then bought a ticket to an O’Reilly conference. To date only one person has done that and I received $200. If anyone is looking to buy tickets to Velocity or OSCON feel free to click the O’Reilly book links at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cnibook.info.&quot; data-href=&quot;http://www.cnibook.info.&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.cnibook.info&lt;/a&gt; and then buy a conference ticket. 😊&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;c2fc&quot; id=&quot;c2fc&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I attempted to set up an affiliate program for Amazon but my application was denied. Amazon offers an author central site to create a 1998 inspired &lt;a href=&quot;https://authorcentral.amazon.com/gp/profile&quot; data-href=&quot;https://authorcentral.amazon.com/gp/profile&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;author profile page&lt;/a&gt; and an out of date book sale statistics and rankings. I’m really not sure the point of creating the Amazon author information outside of claiming the book(s) you author and confirming that you have a terrible book rank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;f760&quot; id=&quot;f760&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;While setting up these accounts is when I created the cnibook.info website and @cnibook twitter handle. Luckily the website is a static page hosted on GitHub so there is no recurring costs. The twitter account I still maintain but has minimal interactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--outsetColumn&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*97sT8vlz-4F6qda920Rltw.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1965&quot; data-height=&quot;626&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*97sT8vlz-4F6qda920Rltw.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*97sT8vlz-4F6qda920Rltw.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Google Analytics for cnibook.info&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--insetColumn&quot; readability=&quot;22&quot;&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;15dc&quot; id=&quot;15dc&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;The landing page was a valuable use of my time as it gave a URL to point people to for anyone searching for the book or wanting more information. I would suggest anyone writing a book spend a night to register a domain and set one up. I launched it on August 31, 2017 and it has over 4,600 visits which is terrible by most website standards but good as a place to funnel users for info.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p name=&quot;8e4e&quot; id=&quot;8e4e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;During AWS Re:Invent I decided it would be fun to try a Twitter campaign to try and get some interest in the book. I set a limit of $50 which bought 7,648 impressions (people saw the tweet). This includes 161 engagements (clicked on the tweet, RT’d, or favorited), and 37 clicks (clicked the link). I promoted the tweet above and I don’t think it was worth the money. I don’t believe it generated any sales and cost $.31 per engagement. After that campaign I had another tweet that was retweeted by a friend (I didn’t ask them to do it) with a lot of followers and it had more engagements than the paid for, promoted tweet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--outsetColumn&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*aUZvopYnNH1bLIjQXObFiw.png&quot; data-width=&quot;2376&quot; data-height=&quot;733&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*aUZvopYnNH1bLIjQXObFiw.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*aUZvopYnNH1bLIjQXObFiw.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Twitter campaign breakdown&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--insetColumn&quot; readability=&quot;95.306064880113&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;5654&quot; id=&quot;5654&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;Sales and Royalties&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;bbca&quot; id=&quot;bbca&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;The book was originally supposed to be 250 pages and would have cost $59.99. Instead it was only 160 pages and cost $39.99. Because we co-authored the book we each got 5% of revenue for physical books and 12.5% for ebooks and digital access (10% and 25% for individual authors).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;1fff&quot; id=&quot;1fff&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;This breaks down to we each get $.99 for a physical book and $.46 for an ebook. Safari Books Online (SBO) pays based on how many pages are viewed and how many people have added the book to their personal bookshelf (I never knew before why that was a thing). So far I have received $539 over 5 months for SBO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;1121&quot; id=&quot;1121&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The payments come on the last day of the month after the month when O’Reilly receives payment for the sale. If you bought a book on February 1st, $.99 was added to the check I received on March 31st.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;e410&quot; id=&quot;e410&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;From December through March the book has sold &lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;1337&lt;/strong&gt; copies. I have no idea how well other books in this category sell. This total also includes 2 book signings at conferences that were sponsored by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://cncf.io&quot; data-href=&quot;https://cncf.io&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CNCF&lt;/a&gt; (Thank you!) which was roughly 150 physical books total. On average, the book has sold 222 copies per month which is greatly skewed by the first month which had 930 sales. The last month (March) had 34 physical book sales. I suspect that number will go down even more over the next few months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;254e&quot; id=&quot;254e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Sponsorships was an unexpected source of income. We have been lucky enough to have 3 sponsors so far. The sponsor pays O’Reilly for exclusive rights to provide a PDF and optional print version of the book. The company gets to put a forward in the book that Kris, me, and an O’Reilly editor approve. Once the sponsor completes their contract with O’Reilly they can do whatever they want with the books. Usually, the PDF gets put behind a web form so you fill out your email address and the company uses it for marketing services and getting customer leads. Physical books are usually given away at conferences where they can scan badges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;b4c5&quot; id=&quot;b4c5&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I have no idea if this model is financially viable for the companies but I would assume so. I’ve asked for download numbers but was never provided any and the sponsors are not contractually obligated to give numbers. I’m not sure how many books get sponsors, but it helps a lot with raising awareness of the book because companies have more of a presence on social media and have budgets for advertising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;0655&quot; id=&quot;0655&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Each full book sponsorship for one month nets me $3,705 and partial sponsorships give an amount based on percentage of the book sponsored (e.g. 5 chapters in a 10 chapter book is 50% sponsored). That’s much better than I expected because a one month full sponsorship is more than all other sales combined. I’m not going to say exactly what percentage I get from the sponsorship simply because I don’t want to disclose how much any of these 3rd parties pay and their finances are not my business to disclose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;3253&quot; id=&quot;3253&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;There are also some other sponsorships that I think count as ebook sales but I never got a clear answer how royalties work for those. Book licensing incurs a small payment but I’m unclear how that is used. From my statements, three people have licensed the book or excerpts from it which has netted me $2.37.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p name=&quot;039a&quot; id=&quot;039a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;My April 2018 statement (sales from December — March) says I’ve made $11,554.15 which roughly breaks down to $23 per hour for the estimated 500 hours of work. Without the three sponsorships that would have been $5.29 per hour. Luckily that number only gets better with time. I’ve heard 2nd editions are a better rate per hour because they have less time investment with similar sales as the original, but I don’t have any experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;5314&quot; id=&quot;5314&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Going into this project I had a rough estimate in my head to make about $2000–3000 so this is much better than I expected. Set your expectations accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;3abb&quot; id=&quot;3abb&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Outcomes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;ba19&quot; id=&quot;ba19&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;I’m extremely happy with the how things have turned out. We’ve got a lot of great feedback and some average reviews on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Cloud-Native-Infrastructure-Applications-Environment/dp/1491984309&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Cloud-Native-Infrastructure-Applications-Environment/dp/1491984309&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; (please leave us a review!). I’m grateful that people are reading it and I hope it’s helping them in some way. We worked hard and wanted to help engineers get better at running infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;b00e&quot; id=&quot;b00e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I learned that you can’t just write a book and expect it to sell. There needs to be a lot of effort (a.k.a. budget and time) in marketing and it takes more than just individuals with twitter accounts to get the word out. It has been humbling to have friends and organizations help us promote the book and even pay to put the book in people’s hands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;4a89&quot; id=&quot;4a89&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;So far I know of only one grammatical mistake, which is a win in my book (pun intended).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p name=&quot;8d9e&quot; id=&quot;8d9e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;The book has provided a few other opportunities that I probably wouldn’t have had. So far I’ve done a couple podcast interviews, spoken at a few events, did one webinar, and have had a few opportunities for more writing projects with O’Reilly (some of which I’ve taken).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;3bbf&quot; id=&quot;3bbf&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Would I write another book? Not for the foreseeable future. I would like to update &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;Cloud Native Infrastructure&lt;/em&gt; to keep it fresh with current industry trends, but another book from scratch is not a year long project I’d be looking forward to at this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;8d67&quot; id=&quot;8d67&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I’m very proud of the work we accomplished and glad we wrote it. I can’t think of anything else I would have done with that time that would have been better spent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;22c5&quot; id=&quot;22c5&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I’d love it if you bought a copy of the book using the affiliate links at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnibook.info/&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.cnibook.info/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.cnibook.info&lt;/a&gt; and if you’ve already read it please let us know what you think. We’re available on twitter &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/rothgar&quot; data-href=&quot;http://twitter.com/rothgar&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;rothgar&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/krisnova&quot; data-href=&quot;http://twitter.com/krisnova&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;krisnova&lt;/a&gt;. We also love pictures of the book with your pets. It makes us smile. 😄&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p name=&quot;ff1d&quot; id=&quot;ff1d&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure graf--trailing&quot;&gt;I hope this has given you some insights into what it takes to write a book and what you can expect if you do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 16:37:22 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>JustinGarrison</dc:creator>
<og:title>The Economics of Writing a Technical Book – Justin Garrison – Medium</og:title>
<og:url>https://medium.com/@rothgar/the-economics-of-writing-a-technical-book-689d0c12fe39</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/0*srZXvqZpo2266zkp.png</og:image>
<og:description>I am not an expert. I have co-authored a single book in 2017 called Cloud Native Infrastructure for O’Reilly Media. Many people have asked…</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://medium.com/@rothgar/the-economics-of-writing-a-technical-book-689d0c12fe39</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Twitter suspended our Open Data project&amp;#039;s account and wiped all our followers</title>
<link>http://www.openbenches.org/blog/2018/05/twitter-suspended-our-account-and-wiped-all-our-followers/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.openbenches.org/blog/2018/05/twitter-suspended-our-account-and-wiped-all-our-followers/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;On Saturday evening, I was disturbed to discover that our &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openbenches&quot;&gt;OpenBenches Twitter Account&lt;/a&gt; had been suspended!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-width=&quot;530&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Well… this is sub-optimal! Twitter have suspended &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openbenches?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@openbenches&lt;/a&gt;. No idea why. No way I can see to appeal. Grrr! &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/rCkHnMTEOM&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/rCkHnMTEOM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— ꧁Terence Eden꧂ ⏻ (@edent) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/edent/status/992803869032927234?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;May 5, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be clear, OpenBenches posts photos of benches. That’s it. No porn, no spam, no encouraging malicious behaviour. It’s just pictures like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-width=&quot;530&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;IN LOVING MEMORY OF&lt;br/&gt;BERYL HOOTON&lt;br/&gt;TO WHOM THE GARDEN MEANT SO MUCH&lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/uIr63hLiQ9&quot;&gt;https://t.co/uIr63hLiQ9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;CC BY-SA 4.0 &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/Gzlit7T4jZ&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/Gzlit7T4jZ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— OpenBenches.org (@openbenches) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openbenches/status/992408273973317637?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;May 4, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went to appeal the suspension, I quickly got back an automated reply denying the appeal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.openbenches.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/suspended.png&quot; alt=&quot;Email from Twitter &amp;quot;Hello, Your account has been suspended due to multiple or repeat violations of the Twitter Rules: https://twitter.com/rules. Please do not respond to this email as replies and new appeals for this account will not be monitored. Thanks, Twitter Support&amp;quot;&quot; width=&quot;454&quot; height=&quot;479&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-93&quot; srcset=&quot;http://www.openbenches.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/suspended.png 454w, http://www.openbenches.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/suspended-284x300.png 284w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 454px) 100vw, 454px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was baffling! The account is connected to a valid email address and working mobile phone number. There were no added apps which could have been used for spamming. Nothing that broke &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/rules&quot;&gt;the rules&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I kicked up a bit of a stink on Twitter – and I’m grateful that &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/katie_fenn/status/993241321371586566&quot;&gt;so&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dug/status/993118329920421888&quot;&gt;many&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/IanYorston/status/993101907337072640&quot;&gt;people&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/billt/status/993097502340648960&quot;&gt;Tweeted&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/PublicChaffinch/status/993091727610253313&quot;&gt;their&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Luehea/status/993067284653662209&quot;&gt;support&lt;/a&gt;. I dropped an email to a few people I know at Twitter, but it is a Bank Holiday weekend, so I didn’t expect any of them to answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I filed &lt;em&gt;another&lt;/em&gt; appeal the next day, which was also swiftly denied. But, hey, it’s still a long weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then, without warning, I got this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.openbenches.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/unsuspended.png&quot; alt=&quot;Hello, We've unsuspended your account; sorry for the inconvenience. Please note that it may take an hour or so for your follower and following numbers to return to normal. Twitter has automated systems that find and remove multiple automated spam accounts in bulk. Unfortunately, it looks like your account got caught up in one of these spam groups by mistake. Please do not respond to this email as replies will not be monitored. Thanks, Twitter Support&quot; width=&quot;454&quot; height=&quot;679&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-94&quot; srcset=&quot;http://www.openbenches.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/unsuspended.png 454w, http://www.openbenches.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/unsuspended-201x300.png 201w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 454px) 100vw, 454px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve no idea whether a human reviewed it. We were now free from Twitter jail! But it came with a cost. Despite the promises, the followers never returned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We only had a few hundred, not bad for a parochial project on the psychogeography of memorials, but now we had zero.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, if you &lt;em&gt;were&lt;/em&gt; following us – please follow us again! If you weren’t, now’s a good time to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openbenches&quot;&gt;follow us on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;! Or, submit a photo of a bench using your mobile phone at &lt;a href=&quot;https://OpenBenches.org&quot;&gt;https://OpenBenches.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yes, I know. We should redecentralize and put our content on Mastodon, or the BlockChain, or some other convoluted platform which has no users. But that’s just not practical for a small project. We have limited technical resources and have to go to where the people are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a website, and lots of &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/edent/openbenches/#open-data-api&quot;&gt;Open Data&lt;/a&gt; – if you want to help syndicate us to multiple platforms, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/edent/openbenches/&quot;&gt;please file a pull request&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 16:34:32 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>edent</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Twitter suspended our account and wiped all our followers!</og:title>
<og:url>http://www.openbenches.org/blog/2018/05/twitter-suspended-our-account-and-wiped-all-our-followers/</og:url>
<og:description>On Saturday evening, I was disturbed to discover that our OpenBenches Twitter Account had been suspended! To be clear, OpenBenches posts photos of benches. That’s it. No porn, no spam, no enc…</og:description>
<og:image>http://www.openbenches.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/suspended.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-GB</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.openbenches.org/blog/2018/05/twitter-suspended-our-account-and-wiped-all-our-followers/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>