<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Ending Bitcoin Support</title>
<link>https://stripe.com/blog/ending-bitcoin-support</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://stripe.com/blog/ending-bitcoin-support</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;At Stripe, we’ve long been excited about the possibilities of cryptocurrencies and the experimentation and innovation that’s come with them. In 2014, we became the first major payments company to support Bitcoin payments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/blog/bitcoin-the-stripe-perspective&quot;&gt;hope&lt;/a&gt; was that Bitcoin could become a universal, decentralized substrate for online transactions and help our customers enable buyers in places that had less credit card penetration or use cases where credit card fees were prohibitive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past year or two, as block size limits have been reached, Bitcoin has evolved to become better-suited to being an asset than being a means of exchange. Given the overall success that the Bitcoin community has achieved, it’s hard to quibble with the decisions that have been made along the way. (And we’re certainly happy to see any novel, ambitious project do so well.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has led to Bitcoin becoming &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bitcoin-dot-org/bitcoin.org/pull/2010/files&quot;&gt;less useful&lt;/a&gt; for payments, however. Transaction confirmation times &lt;a href=&quot;https://blockchain.info/charts/avg-confirmation-time?daysAverageString=7&amp;amp;timespan=2years&quot;&gt;have risen substantially&lt;/a&gt;; this, in turn, has led to an increase in the failure rate of transactions denominated in fiat currencies. (By the time the transaction is confirmed, fluctuations in Bitcoin price mean that it’s for the “wrong” amount.) Furthermore, fees &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitinfocharts.com/comparison/bitcoin-transactionfees.html#1y&quot;&gt;have risen&lt;/a&gt; a great deal. For a regular Bitcoin transaction, a fee of tens of U.S. dollars is common, making Bitcoin transactions &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mybanktracker.com/news/wire-transfer-fee-comparison-top-10-us-banks&quot;&gt;about as expensive&lt;/a&gt; as bank wires.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of this, we’ve seen the desire from our customers to accept Bitcoin decrease. And of the businesses that are accepting Bitcoin on Stripe, we’ve seen their revenues from Bitcoin decline substantially. Empirically, there are fewer and fewer use cases for which accepting or paying with Bitcoin makes sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, starting today, we are winding down support for Bitcoin payments. Over the next three months we will work with affected Stripe users to ensure a smooth transition before we stop processing Bitcoin transactions on April 23, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite this, we remain very optimistic about cryptocurrencies overall. There are a lot of efforts that we view as promising and that we can certainly imagine enabling support for in the future. We’re interested in what’s happening with &lt;a href=&quot;https://lightning.network/&quot;&gt;Lightning&lt;/a&gt; and other proposals to enable faster payments. &lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.omise.co/omg/whitepaper.pdf&quot;&gt;OmiseGO&lt;/a&gt; is an ambitious and clever proposal; more broadly, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ethereum.org/&quot;&gt;Ethereum&lt;/a&gt; continues to spawn many high-potential projects. We may add support for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.stellar.org/&quot;&gt;Stellar&lt;/a&gt; (to which we provided seed funding) if substantive use continues to grow. It’s possible that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bitcoincash.org/&quot;&gt;Bitcoin Cash&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://litecoin.org/&quot;&gt;Litecoin&lt;/a&gt;, or another Bitcoin variant, will find a way to achieve significant popularity while keeping settlement times and transaction fees very low. Bitcoin itself may become viable for payments again in the future. And, of course, there’ll be more ideas and technologies in the years ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, we will continue to pay close attention to the ecosystem and to look for opportunities to help our customers by adding support for cryptocurrencies and new distributed protocols in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 19:02:40 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>uptown</dc:creator>
<og:title>Ending Bitcoin Support</og:title>
<og:url>https://stripe.com/blog/ending-bitcoin-support</og:url>
<og:description>Starting today, we are winding down support for Bitcoin payments. Over the next three months we will work with affected Stripe users to ensure a smooth transition.</og:description>
<og:image>https://stripe.com/img/v3/home/social.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://stripe.com/blog/ending-bitcoin-support</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Firefox 58</title>
<link>https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/58.0/releasenotes/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/58.0/releasenotes/</guid>
<description>&lt;h2&gt;Version 58.0, first offered to Release channel users on January 23, 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this release, we’re building on the great foundation provided by our &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/blog/2017/11/14/introducing-firefox-quantum/&quot;&gt;all-new Firefox Quantum browser&lt;/a&gt;. We're optimizing the performance gains we released in 57 by improving the way we render graphics and cache JavaScript. We also made functional and privacy improvements to Firefox Screenshots. On Firefox for Android, we’ve added support for Progressive Web Apps (PWAs) so you can add websites to your home screen and use them like native apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you to all of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/community/2018/01/17/firefox-58-new-contributors/&quot;&gt;new Mozillians&lt;/a&gt; who contributed to this release of Firefox!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 16:39:32 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ortuman</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/58.0/releasenotes/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.mozilla.org/media/img/firefox/template/page-image.4b108ed0b8d8.png</og:image>
<og:title>Firefox — Notes (58.0)</og:title>
<og:description></og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/58.0/releasenotes/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Amazon Go and the Future</title>
<link>https://stratechery.com/2018/amazons-go-and-the-future</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://stratechery.com/2018/amazons-go-and-the-future</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon Go is the story of technology, and so is this tweet:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;I’m in Seattle and there is currently a line to shop at the grocery store whose entire premise is that you won’t have to wait in line. &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/fWr80A0ZPV&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/fWr80A0ZPV&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Ryan Petersen (@typesfast) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/typesfast/status/955522688268746752?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;January 22, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday the Amazon Go concept store in Seattle opened to the public, filled with sandwiches, salads, snacks, various groceries, and even beer and wine (Recode has a great set of pictures &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.recode.net/2018/1/21/16913984/what-does-photos-amazon-jeff-bezos-seattle-new-no-cashier-line-grocery-story-amazon-go&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). The trick is that you don’t pay, at least in person: a collection of cameras and sensors pair your selection to your Amazon account — registered at the door via smartphone app — which rather redefines the concept of “grab-and-go.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The economics of Amazon Go define the tech industry; the strategy, though, is uniquely Amazon’s. Most of all, the implications of Amazon Go explain both the challenges and opportunities faced by society broadly by the rise of tech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Economics of Tech&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This point is foundational to nearly all of the analysis of Stratechery, which is why it’s worth repeating. To understand the economics of tech companies one must understand the difference between fixed and marginal costs, and for this Amazon Go provides a perfect example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A cashier — and forgive the bloodless language for what is flesh and blood — is a marginal cost. That is, for a convenience store to sell one more item requires some amount of time on the part of a cashier, and that time costs the convenience store operator money. To sell 100 more items requires even more time — costs increase in line with revenue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fixed costs, on the other hand, have no relation to revenue. In the case of convenience stores, rent is a fixed cost; 7-11 has to pay its lease whether it serves 100 customers or serves 1,000 in any given month. Certainly the more it serves the better: that means the store is achieving more “leverage” on its fixed costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the case of Amazon Go specifically, all of those cameras and sensors and smartphone-reading gates are fixed costs as well — two types, in fact. The first is the actual cost of buying and installing the equipment; those costs, like rent, are incurred regardless of how much revenue the store ultimately produces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Far more extensive, though, are the costs of developing the underlying systems that make Amazon Go even possible. These are R&amp;amp;D costs, and they are different enough from fixed costs like rent and equipment that they typically live in another place on the balance sheet entirely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These different types of costs affect management decision-making at different levels (that is, there is a spectrum from purely marginal costs to purely fixed costs; it all depends on your time frame):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;If the marginal cost of selling an individual item is more than the marginal revenue gained from selling the item (i.e. it costs more to pay a cashier to sell an item than the gross profit earned from an item) then the item won’t be sold.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the monthly rent for a convenience store exceeds the monthly gross profit from the store, then the store will be closed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the cost of renovations and equipment (in the case of small businesses, this cost is usually the monthly repayments on a loan) exceeds the net profit ex-financing, then the owner will go bankrupt.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind, most businesses start out in the red: it usually takes financing, often in the form of a loan, to buy everything necessary to even open the business in the first place; a company is not truly profitable until that financing is retired. Of course once everything is paid off a business is not entirely in the clear: physical objects like shelves or refrigeration units or lights break and wear out, and need to be replaced; until that happens, though, money can be made by utilizing what has already been paid for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This, though, is why the activity that is accounted for in R&amp;amp;D is so important to tech company profitability: while digital infrastructure obviously needs to be maintained, by-and-large the investment reaps dividends far longer than the purchase of any physical good. Amazon Go is a perfect example: the massive expense that went into developing the underlying system powering cashier-less purchasing does not need to be spent again; moreover, unlike shelving or refrigerators, the output of that expense can be duplicated infinitely without incurring any additional cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This principle undergirds the fantastic profitability of successful tech companies:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;It was expensive to develop mainframes, but IBM could reuse the expertise to build them and most importantly the software needed to run them; every new mainframe was more profitable than the last.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It was expensive to develop Windows, but Microsoft could reuse the software on all computers; every new computer sold was pure profit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It was expensive to build Google, but search can be extended to anyone with an Internet connection; every new user was an opportunity to show more ads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It was expensive to develop iOS, but the software can be used on billions of iPhones, every one of which generates tremendous profit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It was expensive to build Facebook, but the network can scale to two billion people and counting, all of which can be shown ads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;In every case a huge amount of fixed costs up front is overwhelmed by the ongoing ability to make money at scale; to put it another way, tech company combine fixed costs with marginal revenue opportunities, such that they make more money on additional customers without any corresponding rise in costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is clearly the goal with Amazon Go: to build out such a complex system for a single store would be foolhardy; Amazon expects the technology to be used broadly, unlocking additional revenue opportunities without any corresponding rise in fixed costs — of developing the software, that is; each new store will still require traditional fixed costs like shelving and refrigeration. That, though, is why this idea is so uniquely Amazonian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Strategy of Technology&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most important difference between Amazon and most other tech companies is that the latter generally invest exclusively in research and development — that is, to say, in software. And why not? As I just explained software development has the magical properties of value retention and infinite reproduction. Better to let others handle the less profitable and more risky (at least in the short term) marginal complements. To take the three most prominent examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Microsoft builds the operating system (and eventually, application software) and leaves the building of computers to OEMs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google builds the search engine and leaves the creation of web pages to be searched to the rest of the world&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Facebook builds the infrastructure of the network, and leaves the creation of content to be shared to its users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;All three companies are, at least in terms of their core businesses, pure software companies, which means the economics of their businesses align with the economics of software: massive fixed costs, and effectively zero marginal costs. And while Microsoft’s market, large though it may have been, was limited by the price of a computer, Google and Facebook, by virtue of their advertising model, are &lt;a href=&quot;https://stratechery.com/2017/defining-aggregators/&quot;&gt;super-aggregators&lt;/a&gt; capable of scaling to anyone with an Internet connection. All three also benefit (or benefited) from strong network effects, both on the supply and demand side; these network effects, supercharged by the ability to scale for free, are these companies’ moats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple and IBM, on the other hand, are/were vertical integrators, particularly IBM. In the mainframe era the company built everything from components to operating systems to application software and sold it as a package with a long-term service agreement. By doing so all would-be competitors were foreclosed from IBM’s market; eventually, in a(n unsuccessful) bid to escape antitrust pressure, application software was opened up, but that ended up entrenching IBM further by adding on a network effect. Apple isn’t nearly as integrated as IBM was back in the 60s, but it builds both the software and the finished products on which it runs, foreclosing competitors (while gaining economies of scale from sourcing components and two-sided network effects through the App Store); Apple is also happy to partner with telecoms, which have their own network effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon is doing both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In market after market the company is leveraging software to build horizontal businesses that benefit from network effects: in e-commerce, more buyers lead to more suppliers lead to more buyers. In cloud services, more tenants lead to great economies of scale, not just in terms of servers and data centers but in the leverage gained by adding ever more esoteric features that both meet market needs and create lock-in. &lt;a href=&quot;https://stratechery.com/2017/amazons-new-customer/&quot;&gt;As I wrote last year&lt;/a&gt; the point of buying Whole Foods was to jump start a similar dynamic in groceries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time Amazon continues to vertically integrate. The company is making more and more products under its own private labels on one hand, and building out its fulfillment network on the other. The company is rapidly moving up the stack in cloud services, offering not just virtual servers but microservices that obviate the need for server management entirely. And in logistics the company has its own airplanes, trucks, and courier services, and has promised drones, with the clear goal of allowing the company to deliver products entirely on its own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be both horizontal and vertical is incredibly difficult: horizontal companies often betray their economic model by trying to differentiate their vertical offerings; vertical companies lose their differentiation by trying to reach everyone. That, though, gives a hint as to how Amazon is building out its juggernaut: economic models — that is, the constraint on horizontal companies going vertical — can be overcome if the priority is not short-term profit maximization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Amazon’s Triple Play&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2012 Amazon acquired Kiva Systems for $775 million, then the largest acquisition in company history. Kiva Systems built robots for fulfillment centers, and many analysts were puzzled by the purchase: Kiva Systems already had a plethora of customers, and Amazon was free to buy their robots for a whole lot less than $775 million. Both points argued against a purchase: continuing to sell to other companies removed the only plausible strategic rationale for buying the company instead of simply buying robots, but to stop selling to Kiva Systems’ existing customers would be value-destructive. It’s one thing to pay 8x revenue, as Amazon did; it’s another to cut off that revenue in the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, though, that is exactly what Amazon did. The company had no interest in sharing Kiva Systems’ robots with its competitors, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.therobotreport.com/the-technology-gap-left-by-amazons-acquisition-of-kiva-systems/&quot;&gt;leaving a gap in the market&lt;/a&gt;. At the same time the company ramped up its fulfillment center build-out, gobbling up all of Kiva Systems’ capacity. In other words, Amazon made the “wrong” move in the short-term for a long-term benefit: more and better fulfillment centers than any of its competitors — and spent billions of dollars doing so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This willingness to spend is what truly differentiates Amazon, and the payoffs are tremendous. I mentioned telecom companies in passing above: their economic power flows directly from massive amounts of capital spending; said power is limited by a lack of differentiation. Amazon, though, having started with a software-based horizontal model and network-based differentiation, has not only started to build out its vertical stack but has spent massive amounts of money to do so. That spending is painful in the short-term — which is why most software companies avoid it — but it provides a massive moat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is why, contra most of the analysis I have seen, I don’t think Amazon will license out the Amazon Go technology. Make no mistake, that is exactly what a company like Google would do (and as I expect them to do with Waymo), and for good reason: the best way to get the greatest possible return on software R&amp;amp;D is to spread it as far and wide as possible, which means licensing. The best way to build a moat, though, is to actually put in the effort to dig it, i.e. spend the money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To that end, I suspect that in five to ten years the countries Amazon serves will be blanketed with Amazon Go stores, selling mostly Amazon products, augmented by Amazon fulfillment centers. That is the other point many are missing; yes, the Amazon Go store took pains to show that it still had plenty of workers: shelf stockers, ID checkers, and food preparers, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/AP_18022824846326reduced.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/AP_18022824846326reduced-1024x537.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;336&quot; class=&quot;size-large wp-image-3016&quot; srcset=&quot;https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/AP_18022824846326reduced-1024x537.jpg 1024w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/AP_18022824846326reduced-300x157.jpg 300w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/AP_18022824846326reduced-768x403.jpg 768w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/AP_18022824846326reduced.jpg 1300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Workers as seen from a sidewalk window as they assemble sandwiches in an Amazon Go store Monday, Jan. 22, 2018, in Seattle. More than a year after it introduced the concept, Amazon opened its artificial intelligence-powered Amazon Go store in downtown Seattle on Monday. The store on the bottom floor of the company’s Seattle headquarters allows shoppers to scan their smartphone with the Amazon Go app at a turnstile, pick out the items they want and leave. (AP Photo/Elaine Thompson)
&lt;p&gt;Unlike cashiers, though, none of these jobs have to actually be present in the store most of the time. It seems obvious that Amazon Go stores of the future will rarely have employees in store at all: there will be a centralized location for food preparation and a dedicated fleet of shelf stockers. That’s the thing about Amazon: the company isn’t afraid of old-world scale. No, sandwich preparation doesn’t scale infinitely, but it does scale, particularly if you are willing to spend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Marx Versus Bezos&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The political dilemma embedded in this analysis is hardly new: Karl Marx was born 200 years ago. Technology like Amazon Go is the ultimate expression of capital: invest massive amounts of money up front in order to reap effectively free returns at scale. What has fundamentally changed, though, is the role of labor: Marx saw a world where capital subjugated labor for its own return; technologies like Amazon Go have increasingly no need for labor at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some, certainly, see this as a problem: what about all the cashiers? What about all the truck drivers? What about all of the other jobs that will be &lt;a href=&quot;https://stratechery.com/2017/the-arrival-of-artificial-intelligence/&quot;&gt;displaced by automation&lt;/a&gt;? Well, I would ask, what about the labor of Marx’s day, the factory workers borne of the industrial revolution that he thought should overthrow the bourgeoisie?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, they are all gone, replaced by automation. And, in the meantime, nearly all of humanity has been lifted out of abject poverty. As &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/01/06/opinion/sunday/2017-progress-illiteracy-poverty.html&quot;&gt;Nicholas Kristof wrote in the New York Times&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2017 was probably the very best year in the long history of humanity. A smaller share of the world’s people were hungry, impoverished or illiterate than at any time before. A smaller proportion of children died than ever before. The proportion disfigured by leprosy, blinded by diseases like trachoma or suffering from other ailments also fell…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every day, the number of people around the world living in extreme poverty (less than about $2 a day) goes down by 217,000, according to calculations by Max Roser, an Oxford University economist who runs a website called Our World in Data. Every day, 325,000 more people gain access to electricity. And 300,000 more gain access to clean drinking water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t seek to minimize real struggles, much less the real displacement that will come from technologies like Amazon Go writ large. For decades technology helped the industrial world work better; more and more, technology is replacing that world completely, and there will be pain. That, though, is precisely why it is worth remembering that the world is not static: to replace humans is, in the long run, to free humans to create entirely new needs and means to satisfy those needs. It’s what we do, and the faith to believe it will happen again will be the best guide in figuring out how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for Amazon, &lt;a href=&quot;https://stratechery.com/2016/the-amazon-tax/&quot;&gt;the company’s goal to effectively tax all economic activity&lt;/a&gt; continues apace. Surely the company is grateful about the &lt;a href=&quot;https://stratechery.com/2018/facebooks-motivations/&quot;&gt;attention Facebook is receiving&lt;/a&gt; from the public, even as it builds a monopoly with a triple moat. The lines outside Amazon Go, though, are a reminder of exactly why &lt;a href=&quot;https://stratechery.com/2016/antitrust-and-aggregation/&quot;&gt;aggregator monopolies&lt;/a&gt; are something entirely new: these companies are dominant because people love them. Regulation may be as elusive as Marx’s revolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;robots-nocontent sd-block sd-social sd-social-icon-text sd-sharing&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Share this:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 14:15:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>misiti3780</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Amazon Go and the Future</og:title>
<og:url>https://stratechery.com/2018/amazons-go-and-the-future/</og:url>
<og:description>Amazon Go exemplifies how Amazon is building its monopoly in three ways: horizontally, vertically, and financially. Plus, why automation is worth being optimistic about.</og:description>
<og:image>https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/AP_18022824846326reduced.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://stratechery.com/2018/amazons-go-and-the-future/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>DuckDuckGo moves beyond search to also protect you while browsing</title>
<link>https://spreadprivacy.com/privacy-simplified/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://spreadprivacy.com/privacy-simplified/</guid>
<description>&lt;h2&gt;DuckDuckGo moves beyond search to also protect you while browsing.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the years, DuckDuckGo has offered millions of people a private alternative to Google, serving over &lt;a href=&quot;https://duckduckgo.com/traffic.html&quot;&gt;16 billion anonymous searches&lt;/a&gt;. Today we're excited to launch fully revamped versions of our browser extension and mobile app, extending DuckDuckGo's protection beyond the search box to wherever the Internet takes you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to use the Internet without it feeling a bit creepy – like there’s a nosey neighbor watching everything you do from across the street. Except, instead of a nosey neighbor, it’s a vast array of highly sophisticated tracker networks, run by big companies like Google and Facebook, &lt;a href=&quot;https://myactivity.google.com/myactivity&quot;&gt;recording everything you do online&lt;/a&gt;, often without your knowledge, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2017/10/2/16405974/facebook-russian-election-ads-10-million-viewers&quot;&gt;selling their findings&lt;/a&gt; to the highest bidder via targeted ads. While closing the blinds at home can put a stop to your neighbors, there isn’t something that simple that can work online. Until now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today we’re taking a major step to simplify online privacy with the launch of fully revamped versions of our browser extension and mobile app, now with built-in tracker network blocking, smarter encryption, and, of course, private search – all designed to operate seamlessly together while you search and browse the web. Our updated app and extension are now available across all major platforms – &lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/firefox/addon/duckduckgo-for-firefox/&quot;&gt;Firefox&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://duckduckgo.com&quot;&gt;Safari&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/duckduckgo-for-chrome/bkdgflcldnnnapblkhphbgpggdiikppg&quot;&gt;Chrome&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/app/id663592361?mt=8&quot;&gt;iOS&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.duckduckgo.mobile.android&quot;&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt; – so that you can easily get all the privacy essentials you need on any device with just one download.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The DuckDuckGo browser extension and mobile app will also now show you a Privacy Grade rating (A-F) when you visit a website. This rating lets you see at a glance how protected you are, dig into the details to see who we caught trying to track you, and learn how we enhanced the underlying website's privacy measures. The Privacy Grade is scored automatically based on the prevalence of hidden tracker networks, encryption availability, and website privacy practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://spreadprivacy.com/content/images/2018/01/creepy-site_devices.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of the DuckDuckGo app and extension showing how a site's privacy has been improved.&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To date, cobbling together an effective privacy solution has required researching complicated technologies, installing multiple add-ons and apps on each device, and often worsening your Internet experience. Others have been unfortunately misled by supposed simple solutions. Think “Incognito” mode blocks Google from watching what you’re doing? Think again. Private browsing modes are marketed to make you think that if it's not in your device’s browser history, it never happened. Sadly, that &lt;a href=&quot;https://spreadprivacy.com/is-private-browsing-really-private/&quot;&gt;couldn't be further from the truth&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the new DuckDuckGo browser extension or mobile app, you are now able to seamlessly:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;tracking&quot;&gt;Expose and Block Tracker Networks Watching You&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vast majority of websites across the Internet &lt;a href=&quot;https://spreadprivacy.com/followed-by-ads/&quot;&gt;contain hidden tracker networks&lt;/a&gt;, with Google trackers now lurking behind 76% of pages, Facebook’s trackers on 24% of pages, and countless others soaking up your personal information to follow you with ads around the Web, or worse. Our Privacy Protection will block all the hidden trackers we can find, exposing the major advertising networks tracking you over time, so that you can track who's trying to track you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://spreadprivacy.com/content/images/2018/01/creepy-site_iphone.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of the DuckDuckGo app showing how many trackers have been blocked.&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;https&quot;&gt;Increase Encryption Protection&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While not all sites offer an encrypted version, thankfully &lt;a href=&quot;https://letsencrypt.org/stats/#percent-pageloads&quot;&gt;this has been rapidly changing&lt;/a&gt;. If we discover a site offers an encrypted version but does not send you to it automatically, DuckDuckGo will. This encryption protects you from eavesdroppers, like ISPs, grabbing up your personal information as it travels across the Internet between you and the websites you visit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;tosdr&quot;&gt;Decode a Website’s Privacy Policy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most privacy policies are difficult to understand, and aren’t reviewed closely enough. Even if we block all the tracker networks we find, and even if we upgrade encryption, a website could still be using your data for nefarious purposes, such as selling it to third parties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve partnered with &lt;a href=&quot;https://tosdr.org/&quot;&gt;Terms of Service Didn't Read&lt;/a&gt; (TOSDR) to include their scores of website terms of service and privacy policies, where available. However, because most privacy policies still remain unstudied, we’re working with TOSDR to help them to rate and label as many websites as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;search&quot;&gt;Search Privately&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, our app and extension also include DuckDuckGo private search! You share your most personal information with your search engine, like your financial, medical, and political questions. What you search for is your own business, which is why DuckDuckGo search doesn’t track you. Ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Once you start using the new app and browser extension, you’ll quickly notice something: hardly any website currently gets an &quot;A&quot; on privacy. That’s because hardly any website out there truly prioritizes your privacy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of these widespread poor privacy practices, too many people believe you simply can’t expect privacy on the Internet. We disagree, and have made it our mission to set a new standard of trust online. We want privacy to be the default, not the exception, and this launch is a major step in that direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the last decade, DuckDuckGo has been giving you the ability to search privately, but that privacy was only limited to our search box. Now, when you also use the DuckDuckGo browser extension or mobile app, we will provide you with seamless privacy protection on the websites you visit. Our goal is to expand this privacy protection over time by adding even more privacy features into this single package. While not all privacy protection can be as seamless, the essentials available today and those that we will be adding will go a long way to protecting your privacy online, without compromising your Internet experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As more people start taking their privacy back online, the companies who make money off our personal information will be put on more notice and we’ll collectively raise the Internet’s privacy grade, ending the widespread use of invasive tracking. True to the collective nature of this effort, we’re also building our extension and app in the open with all of the code &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/duckduckgo/&quot;&gt;available on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;, so we invite you to join us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://duckduckgo.com/app&quot;&gt;Install DuckDuckGo on any device to take back your privacy!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For more privacy advice, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/duckduckgo&quot;&gt;follow us on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; get our &lt;a href=&quot;http://duckduckgo.com/about#newsletter&quot;&gt;privacy tips newsletter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 13:11:43 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>brisance</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Privacy, simplified.</og:title>
<og:description>We're excited to launch a new browser extension and mobile app, extending DuckDuckGo's protection beyond the search box to wherever the Internet takes you.</og:description>
<og:url>https://spreadprivacy.com/privacy-simplified/</og:url>
<og:image>https://spreadprivacy.com/content/images/2018/01/Hero_cropped.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://spreadprivacy.com/privacy-simplified/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Hetzner Cloud</title>
<link>https://www.hetzner.com/cloud</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.hetzner.com/cloud</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Yes. All servers that have finished their creation process will be billed until they are deleted, regardless of their state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is because, internally, we allocate full resources to servers regardless of their power state. And it enables rapid startup and boot times for you, the customer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 10:06:29 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>CSDude</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.hetzner.com/cloud</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Tsunami warning ends for B.C. after large earthquake strikes off Alaska</title>
<link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/alaska-earthquake-tsunami-1.4499558</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/alaska-earthquake-tsunami-1.4499558</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;A tsunami warning for coastal British Columbia and parts of Alaska has ended after a powerful earthquake struck about 250 kilometres southeast of Chiniak, Alaska, early today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The quake struck at 1:31 a.m. PT Tuesday and prompted a tsunami warning for the entire B.C. coast and a tsunami watch for the entire U.S. West Coast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.cbc.ca/1.4499635.1516711869!/fileImage/httpImage/image.png_gen/derivatives/original_620/tofino-muster-centre.png&quot; alt=&quot;tofino-muster-centre&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;figure-caption&quot;&gt;People gather at a reception centre in Tofino, B.C. (Catherine Lempke/Twitter)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Port Alberni, a city that was devastated by a tsunami in 1964, Mayor Mike Ruttan activated the four tsunami sirens at around 3 a.m. PT, alerting 17,000 residents to move to higher ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The warning was repeated every 10 minutes for two minutes [in duration]. They're very loud, there's no way you can ignore them. And then in between time, the paper mill was blowing its horns for extended periods of time to let people know there was civic emergency.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hear the sound of the sirens below:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe class=&quot;story-embed-item&quot; type=&quot;text/html&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/6zbZw9wXOdw&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ruttan said although the city could have communicated better on social media, the evacuation was orderly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I am pleased with the response for the most part,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Tofino, on the west coast of Vancouver Island, warning sirens were activated on the two main beaches in town, and hundreds of people evacuated to the emergency reception centres at the community hall and an elementary school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Everything has proceeded in a really orderly fashion,&quot; said Tofino Mayor Josie Osborne. &quot;This is why we train, this is why we do exercises and this is why spend time making emergency plans and then testing them.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot; readability=&quot;5.2322274881517&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/Tsunami?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#Tsunami&lt;/a&gt; Warning previously issued for coastal areas of &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/BC?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#BC&lt;/a&gt; has been CANCELLED. Continue to listen to instructions from local officials until the ALL CLEAR has been issued in your community.&lt;/p&gt;
— &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/EmergencyInfoBC/status/955781136055259136?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@EmergencyInfoBC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The provincial emergency systems worked the way it was supposed to, said B.C.'s public safety minister.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Whether it was in Esquimalt where we saw firefighters and first responders going door to door, or... Queen Charlotte City which was fully evacuated, or the sirens in Tofino and Ucluelet, and people going to their local emergency centres, people responded admirably and I think the emergency services did a remarkable job,&quot; said Mike Farnworth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Geological Survey initially reported the quake's strength at 8.2 early Tuesday and later revised that to 7.9, with a depth of 25 kilometres. At least three aftershocks were reported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot; readability=&quot;8.664406779661&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, most of the displacement on the ocean floor was horizontal, not vertical..one of the reasons we didn't get a large damaging tsunami. But this was the best kind of test for BC emergency officials... and for all of us to know what to do next time. Get your kits/plan ready&lt;/p&gt;
— &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/JWagstaffe/status/955785228789821440?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@JWagstaffe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;This is a place in the world where we see historically a lot of large earthquakes,&quot; said CBC seismologist Johanna Wagstaffe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wagstaffe said early data showed the movement of tectonic plates under the ocean was more of a side-to-side motion than what's known as a mega-thrust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Mega thrusts are the ones we really worry about when it comes to widespread and large tsunamis because there is so much more vertical displacement of the ocean floor,&quot; she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Side-to-side can definitely still generate a tsunami, and again we are seeing a small one, but this motion doesn't generate as large of a tsunami as what we would get with a mega-thrust.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot; readability=&quot;11.003460207612&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/tsunami?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#tsunami&lt;/a&gt; warning area, move out of the water, off the beach &amp;amp; away from harbors, marinas, breakwaters, bays &amp;amp; inlets. Follow instructions from your local emergency officials because they may have more detailed or specific information for your location.&lt;/p&gt;
— &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/EmergencyInfoBC/status/955747994766336001?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@EmergencyInfoBC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.emergencyinfobc.gov.bc.ca/tsunami-warning-coastal-areas-of-bc-jan-23-2018-at-0135am/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Emergency Info BC&lt;/a&gt;, directed by the province's lead agency for disaster management, said the warning did not include Vancouver.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot; readability=&quot;2.8915662650602&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tue Jan 23 09:38:01 UTC 2018 event picture &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/AHbKZ8xPuJ&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/AHbKZ8xPuJ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
— &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/NWS_NTWC/status/955736371607556096?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@NWS_NTWC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emergency Info BC warned people in the affected area to move away from the water, off beaches, and away from harbours, marinas, breakwaters, bays and inlets. Boat operators were advised to move their boats out to sea to a depth of at least 55 metres.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot; readability=&quot;4.5443786982249&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/tsunami?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#tsunami&lt;/a&gt; warning for BC notification zones A, B, C &amp;amp; D. More information from Environment Canada: &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/y28IfBkpdm&quot;&gt;https://t.co/y28IfBkpdm&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/JJrBei92v5&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/JJrBei92v5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
— &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/EmergencyInfoBC/status/955743543582187520?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@EmergencyInfoBC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trevor Jarvis, the emergency co-ordinator for the Village of Masset on the north end of Haida Gwaii, said he sent out an emergency text to residents and set off the tsunami emergency siren just after 2 a.m. on Tuesday. Everyone on the north end of the village was told to get to higher ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot; readability=&quot;3.261744966443&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hundreds gathered on Mt Tolmie after &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/tsunami?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#tsunami&lt;/a&gt; warning head home after &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/environmentca?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@environmentca&lt;/a&gt; lifts alert &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/yyj?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#yyj&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/cTEw0bDUn1&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/cTEw0bDUn1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
— &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/NicoleCrescenzi/status/955781135925235712?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@NicoleCrescenzi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The quake struck 280 kilometres southeast of Kodiak, Alaska. People reported on social media that it was felt hundreds of kilometres away in Anchorage. Some said they saw the water retreating in Kodiak harbour, a possible sign that strong waves could return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, Kodiak police later said the tsunami warning was downgraded to advisory. They also said they received two reports that tide levels in the channel were fluctuating &quot;by six inches to one foot.&quot; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Pacific Tsunami Warning Centre issued a tsunami watch for the state of Hawaii that was soon cancelled.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 10:01:34 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>nergal</dc:creator>
<og:title>Tsunami warning ends for B.C. after large earthquake strikes off Alaska</og:title>
<og:url>http://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/british-columbia/alaska-earthquake-tsunami-1.4499558</og:url>
<og:image>https://i.cbc.ca/1.4499600.1516706727!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/16x9_1180/tsunami-map.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>A tsunami warning for coastal British Columbia and parts of Alaska has ended after a powerful earthquake struck, about 250 kilometres southeast of Chiniak, Alaska, early today.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/alaska-earthquake-tsunami-1.4499558</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: Paper Programs – Run JavaScript on pieces of paper</title>
<link>https://paperprograms.org/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://paperprograms.org/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who created Paper Programs? And why?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Hi, I’m &lt;a href=&quot;http://janpaulposma.nl&quot;&gt;JP&lt;/a&gt;. There are lots of reasons I could list for building Paper Programs, such as having worked on interactive tools for many years, a background in programming education, and having experimented with different representations of program execution. But the truth is, I was just &lt;em&gt;unreasonably excited&lt;/em&gt; after trying &lt;a href=&quot;https://dynamicland.org&quot;&gt;Dynamicland&lt;/a&gt; for the first time, and wanted to explore their interaction model more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much thanks to everyone who helped testing Paper Programs. Special thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://rsnous.com&quot;&gt;Omar Rizwan&lt;/a&gt; for sort-of instigating this project, and offering tons of ideas and feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How is Paper Programs related to &lt;a href=&quot;https://dynamicland.org&quot;&gt;Dynamicland&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Paper Programs is inspired by the projector and camera setup of the 2017 iteration of Dynamicland. I liked how you could &lt;em&gt;physically hold a program in your hands&lt;/em&gt;, and then put on any surface in the building, where it would start executing, as if by magic. And I liked how people &lt;em&gt;naturally started collaborating&lt;/em&gt;, writing programs that interact with each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In contrast, Dynamicland is a community space designed around Realtalk. Realtalk is a research operating system (in development for several years) designed to &lt;em&gt;bring computation into the physical world&lt;/em&gt;. It is more general than papers, projectors, and cameras. Dynamicland is intended as a &lt;em&gt;new medium of human communication&lt;/em&gt;, and is designed to be learned and used by a community of people interacting face-to-face, not over the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paper Programs is not a clone of Dynamicland. To learn more about their system and vision, be sure to visit Dynamicland in Oakland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How does Paper Programs work?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Programs are stored on a server (using &lt;a href=&quot;https://nodejs.org&quot;&gt;Node.js&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.postgresql.org&quot;&gt;PostgreSQL&lt;/a&gt;), hosted on paperprograms.org. Each program has a number, and the dots on the paper encode that number. Currently each corner is uniquely identified with 5 dots of 5 possible colours, which means you can have about 600 unique papers currently (this is a significant limitation).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A camera detects the dots and retrieves the program associated with each paper. This is done in a browser, using &lt;a href=&quot;https://opencv.org&quot;&gt;OpenCV&lt;/a&gt; compiled to &lt;a href=&quot;http://webassembly.org&quot;&gt;WebAssembly&lt;/a&gt;, and some custom Javascript code. Calibration happens manually, using a UI built in &lt;a href=&quot;https://reactjs.org&quot;&gt;React&lt;/a&gt;. Program code and configuration are stored in the browser’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/Window/localStorage&quot;&gt;local storage&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Projection and execution of programs happens in a separate browser window. Each program runs asynchronously in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/Web_Workers_API&quot;&gt;Web Worker&lt;/a&gt;, and can request access to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/Canvas_API&quot;&gt;canvas&lt;/a&gt;, coordinates of other programs, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there is an editor page, which anyone in the space with a laptop or tablet can use to edit programs, using &lt;a href=&quot;https://microsoft.github.io/monaco-editor/&quot;&gt;Monaco&lt;/a&gt;. When having created a new program, you can click a print button to print out a new paper that runs that program. It has the program text printed on the paper itself. Any edited program can be reverted to its original state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How can I help?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;If you’re interested in contributing to Paper Programs, feel free to submit PRs, bugs, and suggestions at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/janpaul123/paperprograms&quot;&gt;Github repo&lt;/a&gt;. And please tag any posts in social media with &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/search?f=tweets&amp;amp;q=%23paperprograms&amp;amp;src=typd&quot;&gt;#paperprograms&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 06:37:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>janpaul123</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:image>https://paperprograms.org/og-image.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Paper Programs</og:title>
<og:description>Run Javascript programs on pieces of paper, using a projector and camera. Physically hold programs in your hand, and see them come to life, as if by magic.</og:description>
<og:url>https://paperprograms.org</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://paperprograms.org/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Facebook open-sources Detectron</title>
<link>https://research.fb.com/facebook-open-sources-detectron/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://research.fb.com/facebook-open-sources-detectron/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Today, Facebook AI Research (FAIR) open sourced &lt;a href=&quot;https://research.fb.com/downloads/detectron/&quot;&gt;Detectron&lt;/a&gt; — our state-of-the-art platform for object detection research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Detectron project was started in July 2016 with the goal of creating a fast and flexible object detection system built on Caffe2, which was then in early alpha development. Over the last year and a half, the codebase has matured and supported a large number of our projects, including &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1703.06870&quot;&gt;Mask R-CNN&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1708.02002&quot;&gt;Focal Loss for Dense Object Detection&lt;/a&gt;, which won the Marr Prize and Best Student Paper awards, respectively, at ICCV 2017. These algorithms, powered by Detectron, provide intuitive models for important computer vision tasks, such as instance segmentation, and have played a key role in the unprecedented advancement of visual perception systems that our community has achieved in recent years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond research, a number of Facebook teams use this platform to train custom models for a variety of applications including augmented reality and community integrity. Once trained, these models can be deployed in the cloud and on mobile devices, powered by the highly efficient Caffe2 runtime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our goal in open sourcing Detectron is to make our research as open as possible and to accelerate research in labs across the world. With its release, the research community will be able to reproduce our results and have access to the same software platform that FAIR uses every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Detectron is available under the Apache 2.0 license at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/facebookresearch/Detectron&quot;&gt;https://github.com/facebookresearch/Detectron&lt;/a&gt;. We’re also releasing extensive performance baselines for more than 70 pre-trained models that are available to download from our model zoo.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 03:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rmason</dc:creator>
<og:description>Today, Facebook AI Research (FAIR) open sourced Detectron — our state-of-the-art platform for object detection research. The Detectron project was started in July 2016 with the goal of creating a fast and flexible object detection system built on Caffe2, which was then in early alpha development. Over the last year and a half, the codebase…</og:description>
<og:title>Facebook open sources Detectron</og:title>
<og:image>https://research.fb.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/mask-detectron-post.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>https://research.fb.com/facebook-open-sources-detectron</og:url>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://research.fb.com/facebook-open-sources-detectron/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Discrete Math Is Important</title>
<link>https://artofproblemsolving.com/articles/discrete-math</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://artofproblemsolving.com/articles/discrete-math</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Why Discrete Math Is Important&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;by David Patrick&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most middle and high school math curricula follow a well-defined path:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pre-algebra → Algebra 1 → Geometry → Algebra 2 → Trig / Precalculus → Calculus&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other middle and high schools prefer an &quot;integrated&quot; curriculum, wherein elements of algebra, geometry, and trigonometry are mixed together over a 3-year or 4-year sequence. However, both of these approaches generally lack a great deal of emphasis on &lt;strong&gt;discrete math&lt;/strong&gt;: topics such as combinatorics, probability, number theory, set theory, logic, algorithms, and graph theory. Because discrete math does not figure prominently in most states' middle or high school &quot;high-stakes&quot; progress exams, and because it also does not figure prominently on college-admissions exams such as the SAT, it is often overlooked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, discrete math has become increasingly important in recent years, for a number of reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Discrete math is essential to college-level mathematics and beyond.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discrete math—together with calculus and abstract algebra—is one of the core components of mathematics at the undergraduate level. Students who learn a significant quantity of discrete math before entering college will be at a significant advantage when taking undergraduate-level math courses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Discrete math is the mathematics of computing.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mathematics of modern computer science is built almost entirely on discrete math, in particular combinatorics and graph theory. This means that in order to learn the fundamental algorithms used by computer programmers, students will need a solid background in these subjects. Indeed, at most universities, a undergraduate-level course in discrete mathematics is a required part of pursuing a computer science degree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Discrete math is very much &quot;real world&quot; mathematics.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many students' complaints about traditional high school math—algebra, geometry, trigonometry, and the like—is &quot;What is this good for?&quot; The somewhat abstract nature of these subjects often turn off students. By contrast, discrete math, in particular counting and probability, allows students—even at the middle school level—to very quickly explore non-trivial &quot;real world&quot; problems that are challenging and interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Discrete math shows up on most middle and high school math contests.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prominent math competitions such as MATHCOUNTS (at the middle school level) and the American Mathematics Competitions (at the high school level) feature discrete math questions as a significant portion of their contests. On harder high school contests, such as the AIME, the quantity of discrete math is even larger. Students that do not have a discrete math background will be at a significant disadvantage in these contests. In fact, one prominent MATHCOUNTS coach tells us that he spends nearly 50% of his preparation time with his students covering counting and probability topics, because of their importance in MATHCOUNTS contests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Discrete math teaches mathematical reasoning and proof techniques.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Algebra is often taught as a series of formulas and algorithms for students to memorize (for example, the quadratic formula, solving systems of linear equations by substitution, etc.), and geometry is often taught as a series of &quot;definition-theorem-proof&quot; exercises that are often done by rote (for example, the infamous &quot;two-column proof&quot;). While undoubtedly the subject matter being taught is important, the material (as least at the introductory level) does not lend itself to a great deal of creative mathematical thinking. By contrast, with discrete mathematics, students will be thinking flexibly and creatively right out of the box. There are relatively few formulas to memorize; rather, there are a number of fundamental &lt;em&gt;concepts&lt;/em&gt; to be mastered and applied in many different ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Discrete math is fun.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many students, especially bright and motivated students, find algebra, geometry, and even calculus dull and uninspiring. Rarely is this the case with most discrete math topics. When we ask students what their favorite topic is, most respond either &quot;combinatorics&quot; or &quot;number theory.&quot; (When we ask them what their least favorite topic is, the overwhelming response is &quot;geometry.&quot;) Simply put, most students find discrete math more fun than algebra or geometry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We strongly recommend that, before students proceed beyond geometry, they invest some time learning elementary discrete math, in particular counting &amp;amp; probability and number theory. Students can start studying discrete math - for example, our books &lt;a href=&quot;https://artofproblemsolving.com/store/item/intro-counting&quot;&gt;Introduction to Counting &amp;amp; Probability&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://artofproblemsolving.com/store/item/intro-number-theory&quot;&gt;Introduction to Number Theory&lt;/a&gt; - with very little algebra background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also see our article &lt;a href=&quot;https://artofproblemsolving.com/articles/calculus-trap&quot;&gt;The Calculus Trap&lt;/a&gt; which discusses the pitfalls of rushing into calculus too quickly and/or with inadequate preparation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 03:35:02 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jaoo</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://artofproblemsolving.com/articles/discrete-math</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>In-N-Out managers earn triple the industry average</title>
<link>https://medium.californiasun.co/in-n-out-store-managers-earn-160000-wages-b08fe6f1706f</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://medium.californiasun.co/in-n-out-store-managers-earn-160000-wages-b08fe6f1706f</guid>
<description>&lt;p name=&quot;c974&quot; id=&quot;c974&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;A typical architect in California earns about $112,000 a year, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.indeed.com/salaries/architect-Salaries,-California&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.indeed.com/salaries/architect-Salaries,-California&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;according to the jobs site Indeed&lt;/a&gt;. For lawyers and software engineers, the average figures are more than $115,000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;130f&quot; id=&quot;130f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;But beating them all — by a lot — is an unlikely job title: In-N-Out Burger store manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;2f4c&quot; id=&quot;2f4c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;According to the latest numbers from the Irvine hamburger chain, the average yearly pay of its restaurant managers is now more than $160,000. That’s roughly triple &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.indeed.com/salaries/Restaurant-Manager-Salaries,-California&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.indeed.com/salaries/Restaurant-Manager-Salaries,-California&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the industry average&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;983a&quot; id=&quot;983a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--p&quot;&gt;“In-N-Out is just eons above everybody else,” said Saru Jayaraman, who leads the &lt;a href=&quot;http://laborcenter.berkeley.edu/topic/food-labor-research-center/&quot; data-href=&quot;http://laborcenter.berkeley.edu/topic/food-labor-research-center/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Food Labor Research Center&lt;/a&gt; at U.C. Berkeley. “On wages and benefits, they really are the best large chain.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p name=&quot;6f43&quot; id=&quot;6f43&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;A family-owned company, In-N-Out is known for treating its employees well. Denny Warnick, vice president of operations, said in an email that the approach was set down with the company’s founding in 1948 by Harry and Esther Snyder, who made quality service a central focus.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;“Paying their associates well was just one way to help maintain that focus, and those beliefs remain firmly in place with us today,” Warnick said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;74da&quot; id=&quot;74da&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;In-N-Out workers get at least $13 an hour to start, and can eventually rise through the ranks to store manager — no college degree necessary. Benefits include 401(k) plans, paid vacation, and health, dental, and vision plans. (California’s minimum wage for large companies &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.latimes.com/business/la-fi-minimum-wage-20171228-story.html&quot; data-href=&quot;http://www.latimes.com/business/la-fi-minimum-wage-20171228-story.html&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;recently bumped up to $11&lt;/a&gt;, and is required by law to hit $15 by 2022.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*xauIQJq-CrmOoBjzAdpLrw.jpeg&quot; data-width=&quot;2040&quot; data-height=&quot;1310&quot; data-is-featured=&quot;true&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*xauIQJq-CrmOoBjzAdpLrw.jpeg&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*xauIQJq-CrmOoBjzAdpLrw.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
In-N-Out employees enjoy some of the highest wages of the fast food industry. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/people/plasticbag/&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/people/plasticbag/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--figure-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;cc:attributionURL noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Tom Coates&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/2.0/&quot; data-href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/2.0/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--figure-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;license noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CC BY-NC 2.0&lt;/a&gt;)
&lt;p name=&quot;8bb0&quot; id=&quot;8bb0&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;Jayaraman said In-N-Out wasn’t performing charity — a loyal workforce means increased productivity, less employee turnover, and in the long run larger profits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;e537&quot; id=&quot;e537&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--p&quot;&gt;“Our research shows that companies that take the high road make a profit not in spite of paying their workers better but because they pay their workers better,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;7c9f&quot; id=&quot;7c9f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;If other fast food establishments have been reluctant to raise wages, Jayaraman added, it’s because pressure from investors has elevated quarterly gains above the potential long-term benefits of happy workers. In-N-Out has no public shareholders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;052d&quot; id=&quot;052d&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;But isn’t the work a grind? To be sure, many of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.glassdoor.com/Reviews/In-N-Out-Burger-Reviews-E14276.htm&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.glassdoor.com/Reviews/In-N-Out-Burger-Reviews-E14276.htm&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;accounts from In-N-Out employees&lt;/a&gt; on the job review website Glassdoor cite hard work and long hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;dc34&quot; id=&quot;dc34&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Even so, more than 90 percent said they’d recommend the workplace to a friend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;26d4&quot; id=&quot;26d4&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;That’s one reason In-N-Out was №4 in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.glassdoor.com/Award/Best-Places-to-Work-LST_KQ0,19.htm&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.glassdoor.com/Award/Best-Places-to-Work-LST_KQ0,19.htm&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Glassdoor’s latest national ranking&lt;/a&gt; of the best places to work — beating out Google, LinkedIn, and Salesforce, among many others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;a233&quot; id=&quot;a233&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p graf--trailing&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;This article is from&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.californiasun.co/&quot; data-href=&quot;http://www.californiasun.co/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;the California Sun&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;, a newsletter that delivers California’s most compelling news to your inbox each morning — for free.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.californiasun.co&quot; data-href=&quot;http://www.californiasun.co&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;Sign up here&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 00:59:08 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ohjeez</dc:creator>
<og:title>In-N-Out managers are earning a lot more than you think</og:title>
<og:url>https://medium.californiasun.co/in-n-out-store-managers-earn-160000-wages-b08fe6f1706f</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*xauIQJq-CrmOoBjzAdpLrw.jpeg</og:image>
<og:description>A typical architect in California earns about $112,000 a year, according to the jobs site Indeed. For lawyers and software engineers, the…</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://medium.californiasun.co/in-n-out-store-managers-earn-160000-wages-b08fe6f1706f?gi=70c88360629d</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>