<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>$35,000 Tesla Model 3 Available Now</title>
<link>https://www.tesla.com/blog/35000-tesla-model-3-available-now</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.tesla.com/blog/35000-tesla-model-3-available-now</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;We are incredibly excited to announce that the standard Model 3, with 220 miles of range, a top speed of 130 mph and 0-60 mph acceleration of 5.6 seconds is now available at $35,000! Although lower in cost, it is built to achieve the same perfect &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tesla.com/blog/model-3-lowest-probability-injury-any-vehicle-ever-tested-nhtsa&quot;&gt;5-star safety rating&lt;/a&gt; as the longer-ranged version, which has the lowest probability of injury of any car ever tested by the U.S. Government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, we are introducing the Model 3 Standard Range Plus, which offers 240 miles of range, a top speed of 140 mph, 0-60 mph acceleration of just 5.3 seconds and most premium interior features at $37,000 before incentives. For 6% more money, you get 9% more range, more power, and an upgraded interior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To achieve these prices while remaining financially sustainable, Tesla is shifting sales worldwide to online only. You can now buy a Tesla in North America via your phone in about 1 minute, and that capability will soon be extended worldwide. We are also making it much easier to try out and return a Tesla, so that a test drive prior to purchase isn’t needed. You can now return a car within 7 days or 1,000 miles for a full refund. Quite literally, you could buy a Tesla, drive several hundred miles for a weekend road trip with friends and then return it for free. With the highest consumer satisfaction score of any car on the road, we are confident you will want to keep your Model 3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shifting all sales online, combined with other ongoing cost efficiencies, will enable us to lower all vehicle prices by about 6% on average, allowing us to achieve the $35,000 Model 3 price point earlier than we expected. Over the next few months, we will be winding down many of our stores, with a small number of stores in high-traffic locations remaining as galleries, showcases and Tesla information centers. The important thing for customers in the United States to understand is that, with online sales, anyone in any state can quickly and easily buy a Tesla.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, we will be increasing our investment in the Tesla service system, with the goal of same-day, if not same-hour service, and with most service done by us coming to you, rather than you coming to us. Moreover, we guarantee service availability anywhere in any country in which we operate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re also excited to announce that we’re implementing a number of firmware upgrades for both new and existing customers. These upgrades will increase the range of the Long Range Rear-Wheel Drive Model 3 to 325 miles, increase the top speed of Model 3 Performance to 162 mph, and add an average of approximately 5% peak power to all Model 3 vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tesla is committed to making not just the best electric cars, but the best cars, period. And our products are the reason we continue to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.consumerreports.org/car-reliability-owner-satisfaction/10-most-satisfying-cars-owner-satisfaction/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;rank #1 in Consumer Reports owner satisfaction survey&lt;/a&gt; and have every single year since Tesla was first eligible to be included in 2013. Both Model 3 Standard and Standard Plus are available starting today at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tesla.com/&quot;&gt;Tesla.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 22:08:57 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>felipemesquita</dc:creator>
<og:title>$35,000 Tesla Model 3 Available Now</og:title>
<og:description>We are incredibly excited to announce that the standard Model 3, with 220 miles of range, a top speed of 130 mph and 0-60 mph acceleration of 5.6 seconds is now available at $35,000! Although lower in cost, it is built to achieve the same perfect</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.tesla.com/sites/default/files/blog_images/tesla_announcement_social.jpg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.tesla.com/blog/35000-tesla-model-3-available-now</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>YouTube bans comments on all videos of children</title>
<link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-47408969</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-47408969</guid>
<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption full-width lead&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                &lt;img class=&quot;js-image-replace&quot; alt=&quot;YouTube logo&quot; src=&quot;https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/320/cpsprodpb/E2D0/production/_105846085_ytkids.png&quot; width=&quot;976&quot; height=&quot;549&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body__introduction&quot;&gt;YouTube says it will switch off comments on almost all videos featuring under-18s, in an attempt to &quot;better protect children and families&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Several brands stopped advertising on YouTube after discovering that paedophiles were leaving predatory comments on videos of children.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;YouTube had originally disabled comments on videos that were attracting predatory and obscene comments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But it will now disable comments on almost all videos of minors by default.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It said the change would take effect over several months.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;What was happening?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-42110068&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;BBC first reported that paedophiles were leaving explicit comments&lt;/a&gt; on YouTube videos back in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As well as leaving obscene or sexual comments, they were also using the comments section to signal content of interest to other paedophiles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the time, YouTube said it was &quot;working urgently&quot; to clean up the site.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, in February this year advertisers including AT&amp;amp;T, Nestle and Hasbro suspended their ads after more predatory activity was found.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;What has YouTube announced?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2019/02/more-updates-on-our-actions-related-to.html&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link-external&quot;&gt;In a blog post&lt;/a&gt;, YouTube said its new policy meant videos of very young children would automatically have the comments section disabled.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The move is likely to include videos of toddlers uploaded by parents, as well as short films featuring children by established YouTube stars.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Videos of older children and teenagers will typically not have the comments disabled, unless a specific video is likely to attract predatory attention. That could include, for example, a video of a teenager doing gymnastics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;YouTube told the BBC it would use algorithms to detect which videos contained children.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Millions of hours of footage are uploaded to YouTube every day.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;When will comments be permitted?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A small number of YouTube content creators will be allowed to enable comments on videos featuring children.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These channels will be trusted partners such as family video-bloggers or known YouTube stars. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, they will be required to actively moderate their comments and demonstrate that their videos carry a low risk of attracting predatory comments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul class=&quot;story-body__unordered-list&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-47325893&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;AT&amp;amp;T and Hasbro pull YouTube ads over abuse claims&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-42110068&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;Predatory comments prompt YouTube ad suspension&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;YouTube said it had developed a system that was better at detecting predatory comments and removing them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Previously, it had said it would stop video-makers earning ad revenue if paedophiles left explicit comments on their videos, but this will no longer be necessary.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;What further action is being taken?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition to updating its comments policy, YouTube said it had terminated several channels that were &quot;endangering&quot; children.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ban included several channels that were adding shocking content in the middle of children's cartoons.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It named FilthyFrankClips as one of the banned channels. It had released a video instructing children how to cut themselves.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Nothing is more important to us than ensuring the safety of young people on the platform,&quot; said YouTube chief executive &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/SusanWojcicki/status/1101182716593135621&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link-external&quot;&gt;Susan Wojcicki on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;YouTube's app for children - YouTube Kids - has been criticised for using algorithms to curate content. Inappropriate videos have repeatedly been discovered on the service.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;How have creators responded?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The comments left by fans on YouTube videos help the platform's algorithms decide which videos to serve up and recommend to viewers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Creators have expressed concern that being forced to disable comments on their videos will affect the growth of their channels.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite the wide-ranging new policy, comments will remain part of the recommendation algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;We understand that comments are an important way creators build and connect with their audiences,&quot; YouTube said in a statement. &quot;We also know that this is the right thing to do to protect the YouTube community.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Andy Burrows from the child protection charity NSPCC said the announcement was an &quot;important step&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;We know that offenders are twisting YouTube videos for their own sexual gratification, using them to contact other predators and using the comments section as shop window to child abuse image sites,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, he called for an &quot;independent statutory regulator&quot; that could &quot;force social networks to follow the rules or face tough consequences&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
            </description>
<pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 19:45:20 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>_wmd</dc:creator>
<og:title>YouTube bans comments on all videos of kids</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>The streaming platform is disabling comments on videos of children after paedophiles left predatory comments.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-47408969</og:url>
<og:image>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/E2D0/production/_105846085_ytkids.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-GB</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-47408969</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>UC terminates subscriptions with Elsevier in push for open access</title>
<link>https://www.universityofcalifornia.edu/press-room/uc-terminates-subscriptions-worlds-largest-scientific-publisher-push-open-access-publicly</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.universityofcalifornia.edu/press-room/uc-terminates-subscriptions-worlds-largest-scientific-publisher-push-open-access-publicly</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;As a leader in the global movement toward open access to publicly funded research, the University of California is taking a firm stand by deciding not to renew its subscriptions with Elsevier. Despite months of contract negotiations, Elsevier was unwilling to meet UC’s key goal: securing universal open access to UC research while containing the rapidly escalating costs associated with for-profit journals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In negotiating with Elsevier, UC aimed to accelerate the pace of scientific discovery by ensuring that research produced by UC’s 10 campuses — which accounts for nearly 10 percent of all U.S. publishing output — would be immediately available to the world, without cost to the reader. Under Elsevier’s proposed terms, the publisher would have charged UC authors large publishing fees on top of the university’s multi-million dollar subscription, resulting in much greater cost to the university and much higher profits for Elsevier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Knowledge should not be accessible only to those who can pay,” said Robert May, chair of UC’s faculty Academic Senate. “The quest for full open access is essential if we are to truly uphold the mission of this university.” The Academic Senate issued a &lt;a href=&quot;https://senate.universityofcalifornia.edu/_files/reports/academic-council-statement-elsevier-feb28.pdf&quot;&gt;statement&lt;/a&gt; today endorsing UC’s position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open access publishing, which makes research freely available to anyone, anywhere in the world, fulfills UC’s mission by transmitting knowledge more broadly and facilitating new discoveries that build on the university’s research and scholarly work. This follows UC’s faculty-driven &lt;a href=&quot;https://senate.universityofcalifornia.edu/_files/committees/ucolasc/scholcommprinciples-20180425.pdf&quot;&gt;principles&lt;/a&gt; on scholarly communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I fully support our faculty, staff and students in breaking down paywalls that hinder the sharing of groundbreaking research,” said UC President Janet Napolitano. “This issue does not just impact UC, but also countless scholars, researchers and scientists across the globe — and we stand with them in their push for full, unfettered access.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elsevier is the largest scholarly publisher in the world, disseminating about 18 percent of journal articles produced by UC faculty. The transformative model that UC faculty and libraries are championing would make it easier and more affordable for UC authors to publish in an open access environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Make no mistake: The prices of scientific journals now are so high that not a single university in the U.S. — not the University of California, not Harvard, no institution — can afford to subscribe to them all,” said Jeffrey MacKie-Mason, university librarian and economics professor at UC Berkeley, and co-chair of UC’s negotiation team. “Publishing our scholarship behind a paywall deprives people of the access to and benefits of publicly funded research. That is terrible for society.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elsevier was unwilling to meet UC’s reasonable contract terms, which would integrate subscription charges and open access publishing fees, making open access the default for any article by a UC scholar and stabilizing journal costs for the university.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The university’s, and the world’s, move toward open access has been a long time in the making. Many institutions and countries agree that the current system is both financially unsustainable and ill-suited to the needs of today’s global research enterprise,” said Ivy Anderson, associate executive director of UC’s California Digital Library and co-chair of UC’s negotiation team. “Open access will spur faster and better research — and greater global equity of access to new knowledge.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn more about UC’s efforts to establish open access, visit the UC Office of Scholarly Communication’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://osc.universityofcalifornia.edu/open-access-at-uc/publisher-negotiations/uc-and-elsevier/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 18:51:11 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tingletech</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>UC terminates subscriptions with world’s largest scientific publisher in push for open access to publicly funded research</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.universityofcalifornia.edu/press-room/uc-terminates-subscriptions-worlds-largest-scientific-publisher-push-open-access-publicly</og:url>
<og:description>As a leader in the global movement toward open access to publicly funded research, the University of California is taking a firm stand by deciding not to renew its subscriptions with Elsevier. Despite months of contract negotiations, Elsevier was unwilling to meet UC’s key goal: securing universal open access to UC research while containing the rapidly escalating costs associated with for-profit journals.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.universityofcalifornia.edu/press-room/uc-terminates-subscriptions-worlds-largest-scientific-publisher-push-open-access-publicly</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Pagedraw is shutting down and going open source</title>
<link>https://pagedraw.io/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://pagedraw.io/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;We want to give one last, big thank you to all our users, supporters, and investors. It’s been An Incredible Journey. We’re moving on, but We’re very proud of the technology we’ve built. We’re releasing it open source both so you can keep using it, and so we can share our ideas about how to build UI tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, we think Pagedraw is the wrong product. We think you can get 90% of the benefits of Pagedraw by just using JSX better. Our findings on this will be controversial, as they go entirely against the current “best practices,” so we’ll save them for a later blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As promised, you can simply stop using Pagedraw— all the generated code already lives in your repo! If you’re using Pagedraw in production, contact us if you’re worried about a more complex migration pathway. You’ll be able to download your &lt;code&gt;.pagedraw.json&lt;/code&gt; files from our servers and use them with the newly released, open source, desktop app. The web version will stay up through April so you can migrate at your convenience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Jared Pochtar and Gabriel Guimaraes&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 18:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jameslk</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://pagedraw.io/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Implications of Rewriting a Browser Component in Rust</title>
<link>https://hacks.mozilla.org/2019/02/rewriting-a-browser-component-in-rust/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://hacks.mozilla.org/2019/02/rewriting-a-browser-component-in-rust/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The previous posts in this &lt;a href=&quot;https://hacks.mozilla.org/category/fearless-security/&quot;&gt;Fearless Security series&lt;/a&gt; examine &lt;a href=&quot;https://hacks.mozilla.org/2019/01/fearless-security-memory-safety/&quot;&gt;memory safety&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://hacks.mozilla.org/2019/02/fearless-security-thread-safety/&quot;&gt;thread safety&lt;/a&gt; in Rust. This closing post uses the &lt;a href=&quot;https://hacks.mozilla.org/2017/08/inside-a-super-fast-css-engine-quantum-css-aka-stylo/&quot;&gt;Quantum CSS project&lt;/a&gt; as a case study to explore the real world impact of rewriting code in Rust.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The style component is the part of a browser that applies CSS rules to a page. This is a top-down process on the DOM tree: given the parent style, the styles of children can be calculated independently—a perfect use-case for parallel computation. By 2017, Mozilla had made two previous attempts to parallelize the style system using C++. Both had failed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Quantum CSS&lt;/em&gt; resulted from a need to improve page performance. Improving security is a happy byproduct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://2r4s9p1yi1fa2jd7j43zph8r-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/files/2019/02/successrust-250x250.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rewrites code to make it faster; also makes it more secure&quot; width=&quot;250&quot; height=&quot;250&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-medium wp-image-33199&quot; srcset=&quot;https://hacks.mozilla.org/files/2019/02/successrust-250x250.jpg 250w, https://hacks.mozilla.org/files/2019/02/successrust.jpg 500w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 250px) 100vw, 250px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a large overlap between memory safety violations and security-related bugs, so we expected this rewrite to reduce the attack surface in Firefox. In this post, I will summarize the potential security vulnerabilities that have appeared in the styling code since &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Firefox_version_history&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Firefox’s initial release in 2002&lt;/a&gt;. Then I’ll look at what could and could not have been prevented by using Rust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the course of its lifetime, there have been 69 security bugs in Firefox’s style component. If we’d had a time machine and could have written this component in Rust from the start, 51 (73.9%) of these bugs would not have been possible. While Rust makes it easier to write better code, it’s not foolproof.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Rust&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rust is a modern systems programming language that is type- and memory-safe. As a side effect of these safety guarantees, Rust programs are also known to be thread-safe at compile time. Thus, Rust can be a particularly good choice when:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;✅ processing untrusted input safely.&lt;br/&gt;✅ introducing parallelism to improve performance.&lt;br/&gt;✅ integrating isolated components into an existing codebase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, there are classes of bugs that Rust explicitly does not address—particularly correctness bugs. In fact, during the Quantum CSS rewrite, engineers accidentally reintroduced a critical security bug that had previously been patched in the C++ code, regressing the fix for &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=641731&quot;&gt;bug 641731&lt;/a&gt;. This allowed global history leakage via SVG image documents, resulting in &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1420001&quot;&gt;bug 1420001&lt;/a&gt;. As a trivial history-stealing bug, this is rated security-high. The original fix was an additional check to see if the SVG document was being used as an image. Unfortunately, this check was overlooked during the rewrite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there were automated tests intended to catch &lt;code&gt;:visited&lt;/code&gt; rule violations like this, in practice, they didn’t detect this bug. To speed up our automated tests, we temporarily turned off the mechanism that tested this feature—tests aren’t particularly useful if they aren’t run. The risk of re-implementing logic errors can be mitigated by good test coverage (and actually running the tests). There’s still a danger of introducing new logic errors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As developer familiarity with the Rust language increases, best practices will improve. Code written in Rust will become even more secure. While it may not prevent all possible vulnerabilities, Rust eliminates an entire class of the most severe bugs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Quantum CSS Security Bugs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, bugs related to memory, bounds, null/uninitialized variables, or integer overflow would be prevented by default in Rust. The miscellaneous bug I referenced above would not have been prevented—it was a crash due to a failed allocation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Security bugs by category&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of the bugs in this analysis are related to security, but only 43 received official security classifications. (These are assigned by Mozilla’s security engineers based on educated “exploitability” guesses.) Normal bugs might indicate missing features or problems like crashes. While undesirable, crashes don’t result in data leakage or behavior modification. Official security bugs can range from low severity (highly limited in scope) to critical vulnerability (might allow an attacker to run arbitrary code on the user’s platform).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a significant overlap between memory vulnerabilities and severe security problems. Of the 34 critical/high bugs, 32 were memory-related.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Security rated bug breakdown&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Comparing Rust and C++ code&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=955913&quot;&gt;Bug 955914&lt;/a&gt; is a heap buffer overflow in the &lt;code&gt;GetCustomPropertyNameAt&lt;/code&gt; function. The code used the wrong variable for indexing, which resulted in interpreting memory past the end of the array. This could either crash while accessing a bad pointer or copy memory to a string that is passed to another component.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ordering of all &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/CSS/CSS_Properties_Reference&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CSS properties&lt;/a&gt; (both longhand and custom) is stored in an array, &lt;code&gt;mOrder&lt;/code&gt;. Each element is either represented by its CSS property value or, in the case of custom properties, by a value that starts at &lt;code&gt;eCSSProperty_COUNT&lt;/code&gt; (the total number of non-custom CSS properties). To retrieve the name of a custom property, first, you have to retrieve the custom property value from &lt;code&gt;mOrder&lt;/code&gt;, then access the name at the corresponding index of the &lt;code&gt;mVariableOrder&lt;/code&gt; array, which stores the custom property names in order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Vulnerable C++ code:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;    void GetCustomPropertyNameAt(uint32_t aIndex, nsAString&amp;amp; aResult) const {
            MOZ_ASSERT(mOrder[aIndex] &amp;gt;= eCSSProperty_COUNT);

            aResult.Truncate();
            aResult.AppendLiteral(&quot;var-&quot;);
            aResult.Append(mVariableOrder[aIndex]);
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem occurs at line 6 when using &lt;code&gt;aIndex&lt;/code&gt; to access an element of the &lt;code&gt;mVariableOrder&lt;/code&gt; array. &lt;code&gt;aIndex&lt;/code&gt; is intended for use with the &lt;code&gt;mOrder&lt;/code&gt; array not the &lt;code&gt;mVariableOrder&lt;/code&gt; array. The corresponding element for the custom property represented by &lt;code&gt;aIndex&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;mOrder&lt;/code&gt; is actually &lt;code&gt;mOrder[aIndex] - eCSSProperty_COUNT&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixed C++ code:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;    void Get CustomPropertyNameAt(uint32_t aIndex, nsAString&amp;amp; aResult) const {
      MOZ_ASSERT(mOrder[aIndex] &amp;gt;= eCSSProperty_COUNT);

      uint32_t variableIndex = mOrder[aIndex] - eCSSProperty_COUNT;
      aResult.Truncate();
      aResult.AppendLiteral(&quot;var-&quot;);
      aResult.Append(mVariableOrder[variableIndex]);
    }
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Equivalent Rust code&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Rust is similar to C++ in some ways, idiomatic Rust uses different abstractions and data structures. Rust code will look very different from C++ (see below for details). First, let’s consider what would happen if we translated the vulnerable code as literally as possible:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;    fn GetCustomPropertyNameAt(&amp;amp;self, aIndex: usize) -&amp;gt; String {
        assert!(self.mOrder[aIndex] &amp;gt;= self.eCSSProperty_COUNT);

        let mut result = &quot;var-&quot;.to_string();
        result += &amp;amp;self.mVariableOrder[aIndex];
        result
    }
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Rust compiler would accept the code, since there is no way to determine the length of vectors before runtime. Unlike arrays, whose length must be known, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.rust-lang.org/std/vec/struct.Vec.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Vec&lt;/code&gt; type&lt;/a&gt; in Rust is dynamically sized. However, the standard library vector implementation has built-in bounds checking. When an invalid index is used, the program immediately terminates in a controlled fashion, preventing any illegal access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://dxr.mozilla.org/mozilla-central/source/servo/ports/geckolib/glue.rs#5735&quot;&gt;actual code&lt;/a&gt; in Quantum CSS uses very different data structures, so there’s no exact equivalent. For example, we use Rust’s powerful built-in data structures to unify the ordering and property name data. This allows us to avoid having to maintain two independent arrays. Rust data structures also improve data encapsulation and reduce the likelihood of these kinds of logic errors. Because the code needs to interact with C++ code in other parts of the browser engine, the new &lt;code&gt;GetCustomPropertyNameAt&lt;/code&gt; function doesn’t look like idiomatic Rust code. It still offers all of the safety guarantees while providing a more understandable abstraction of the underlying data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;tl;dr;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the overlap between memory safety violations and security-related bugs, we can say that Rust code should result in fewer critical &lt;a href=&quot;https://cve.mitre.org/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CVEs&lt;/a&gt; (Common Vulnerabilities and Exposures). However, even Rust is not foolproof. Developers still need to be aware of correctness bugs and data leakage attacks. Code review, testing, and fuzzing still remain essential for maintaining secure libraries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compilers can’t catch every mistake that programmers can make. However, Rust has been designed to remove the burden of memory safety from our shoulders, allowing us to focus on logical correctness and soundness instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;about&quot; readability=&quot;0.042553191489362&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;url&quot; href=&quot;https://hacks.mozilla.org/author/dhosfeltmozilla-com/&quot;&gt;More articles by Diane Hosfelt…&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 14:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>zwliew</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://hacks.mozilla.org/2019/02/rewriting-a-browser-component-in-rust</og:url>
<og:title>Implications of Rewriting a Browser Component in Rust – Mozilla Hacks - the Web developer blog</og:title>
<og:description>Since our first release in 2002, there have been 69 security bugs in Firefox’s style component. If we'd had a time machine and could have written this component in Rust from the start, 51% wouldn't have happened. That said, Rust is not foolproof. Developers still need to be aware of correctness bugs and data leakage attacks.</og:description>
<og:image>https://hacks.mozilla.org/files/2019/02/fearless.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://hacks.mozilla.org/2019/02/rewriting-a-browser-component-in-rust/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Liberapay – A recurrent donations platform</title>
<link>https://liberapay.com/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://liberapay.com/</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;15.820463320463&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-6&quot; readability=&quot;17.495689655172&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;Donate&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People who contribute to the commons need you to support their work. Building free software, spreading free knowledge, these things take time and cost money, not only to do the initial work, but also to maintain it over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liberapay's recurrent donations system is designed to provide a stable crowdfunded basic income to creators, enabling them to keep doing great work that benefits everyone. Ready to contribute? Then let's get started:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-6&quot; readability=&quot;14.086538461538&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-success&quot;&gt;Receive&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you a creator of commons? Do you make free art, spread free knowledge, write free software? Or something else that can be funded by recurrent donations?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes? Then Liberapay is for you! Create your account, fill your profile, and ask your audience to financially support your work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Thanks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liberapay benefits from sponsored accounts on the following open source services:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sentry.io/&quot; class=&quot;s-logo&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Sentry&quot; src=&quot;https://liberapay.com/assets/sponsors/sentry.png?etag=.Ex6avTRrUwll0vBy0PglIQ~~&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://weblate.org/&quot; class=&quot;s-logo&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Weblate&quot; src=&quot;https://liberapay.com/assets/sponsors/weblate.png?etag=.Nli2mp9eFGagwRNxpesTmg~~&quot; height=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bitwarden.com/&quot; class=&quot;s-logo&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Bitwarden&quot; src=&quot;https://liberapay.com/assets/sponsors/bitwarden.png?etag=.Mb55KkXyGZIptuqJn_6hNA~~&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;18.158854166667&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Recent Activity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;839 user accounts have been created in the past month. The most recent was 12 minutes ago.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;219 new donations have been started in the past month, increasing total weekly funding by €235.38.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;31 new &lt;a href=&quot;https://liberapay.com/explore/pledges&quot;&gt;pledges&lt;/a&gt; have been made in the past month, adding €3.57 of weekly donations waiting to be claimed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;€1,589.34 was transferred last week between 1,554 users.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://liberapay.com/about/stats&quot; class=&quot;btn btn-info&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;More stats&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 12:10:14 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>NicoJuicy</dc:creator>
<og:description>We help you fund the creators and projects you appreciate.</og:description>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://liberapay.com/</og:url>
<og:title>Liberapay</og:title>
<og:image>https://liberapay.com/assets/liberapay/icon-v2_yellow-r.200.png?etag=.tHETOTVJLK08nI5l9FUnuA~~</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://liberapay.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Mozilla releases the largest to-date public domain transcribed voice dataset</title>
<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/blog/2019/02/28/sharing-our-common-voices-mozilla-releases-the-largest-to-date-public-domain-transcribed-voice-dataset/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.mozilla.org/blog/2019/02/28/sharing-our-common-voices-mozilla-releases-the-largest-to-date-public-domain-transcribed-voice-dataset/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mozilla crowdsources the largest dataset of human voices available for use, including 18 different languages, adding up to almost 1,400 hours of recorded voice data from more than 42,000 contributors.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the onset, our vision for &lt;a href=&quot;https://voice.mozilla.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Common Voice&lt;/a&gt; has been to build the world’s most diverse voice dataset, optimized for building voice technologies. We also made a promise of openness: we would make the high quality, transcribed voice data that was collected publicly available to startups, researchers, and anyone interested in voice-enabled technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, we’re excited to share our first multi-language dataset with 18 languages represented, including English, French, German and Mandarin Chinese (Traditional), but also for example Welsh and Kabyle. Altogether, the new dataset includes approximately 1,400 hours of voice clips from more than 42,000 people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this release, the continuously growing Common Voice dataset is now the largest ever of its kind, with tens of thousands of people contributing their voices and original written sentences to the public domain (&lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/share-your-work/public-domain/cc0/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;CC0&lt;/a&gt;). Moving forward, the full dataset will be available for download on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://voice.mozilla.org/data&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Common Voice site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-12018&quot; src=&quot;https://ffp4g1ylyit3jdyti1hqcvtb-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/CV-Datasets-animated-graphic.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1440&quot; height=&quot;850&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dat&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;a Qualities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Common Voice dataset is unique not only in its &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/JRMeyer/open-speech-corpora&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;size and licence model&lt;/a&gt; but also in its diversity, representing a global community of voice contributors. Contributors can opt-in to provide metadata like their age, sex, and accent so that their voice clips are tagged with information useful in training speech engines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a different approach than for other publicly available datasets, which are either hand-crafted to be diverse (i.e. equal number of men and women) or the corpus is as diverse as the “found” data (e.g. the TEDLIUM corpus from TED talks is ~3x men to women).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More Common Voices: from 3 to 22 languages in 8 months&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we enabled multi-language support in June 2018, Common Voice has grown to be more global and more inclusive. This has surpassed our expectations: Over the last eight months, communities have enthusiastically rallied around the project, launching data collection efforts in 22 languages with an incredible 70 more in progress on the Common Voice site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a community-driven project, people around the world who care about having a voice dataset in their language have been responsible for each new launch — some are passionate volunteers, some are doing this as part of their day jobs as linguists or technologists. Each of these efforts require translating the website to allow contributions and adding sentences to be read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our latest additions include Dutch, Hakha-Chin, Esperanto, Farsi, Basque, and Spanish. In some cases, a new language launch on Common Voice is the beginning of that language’s internet presence. These community efforts are proof that all languages—not just ones that can generate high revenue for technology companies—are worthy of representation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll continue working with these communities to ensure their voices are represented and even help make voice technology for themselves. In this spirit, we recently joined forces with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.giz.de/en/html/index.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Deutsche Gesellschaft für Internationale Zusammenarbeit (GIZ)&lt;/a&gt; and co-hosted an &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/mozilla-open-innovation/sustainable-tech-development-needs-local-solutions-voice-tech-ideation-in-kigali-ec8dd33e0823&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;ideation hackathon in Kigali&lt;/a&gt; to create a speech corpus for Kinyarwanda, laying the foundation for local technologists in Rwanda to develop open source voice technologies in their own language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improvements in the contribution experience, including optional profiles&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Common Voice Website is one of our main vehicles for building voice data sets that are useful for voice-interaction technology. The way it looks today is the result of an ongoing &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/mozilla-open-innovation/prototyping-with-intention-33d15fb147c2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;process of iteration&lt;/a&gt;. We listened to community feedback about the pain points of contributing while also conducting usability research to make contribution easier, more engaging, and fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People who contribute not only see progress per language in recording and validation, but also have improved prompts that vary from clip to clip; new functionality to review, re-record, and skip clips as an integrated part of the experience; the ability to move quickly between speak and listen; as well as a function to opt-out of speaking for a session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also added the option to create a saved profile, which allows contributors to keep track of their progress and metrics across multiple languages. Providing some optional demographic profile information also improves the audio data used in training speech recognition accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_12017&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-12017 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://ffp4g1ylyit3jdyti1hqcvtb-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/CV-homepage-default.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1550&quot; height=&quot;1089&quot; srcset=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/CV-homepage-default.png 1550w, https://blog.mozilla.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/CV-homepage-default-300x211.png 300w, https://blog.mozilla.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/CV-homepage-default-768x540.png 768w, https://blog.mozilla.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/CV-homepage-default-600x422.png 600w, https://blog.mozilla.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/CV-homepage-default-1000x703.png 1000w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1550px) 100vw, 1550px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Common Voice started as a proof of concept prototype and has been collaboratively iterated over the past year&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Empower decentralized product innovation: a marathon rather than a sprint&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mozilla aims to contribute to a more diverse and innovative voice technology ecosystem. Our goal is to both release voice-enabled products ourselves, while also supporting researchers and smaller players. Providing data through Common Voice is one part of this, as are the open source Speech-to-Text and Text-to-Speech engines and trained models through &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mozilla/deepspeech&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;project DeepSpeech&lt;/a&gt;, driven by our Machine Learning Group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We know this will take time, and we believe releasing early and working in the open can attract the involvement and feedback of technologists, organisations, and companies that will make these projects more relevant and robust. The current reality for both projects is that they are still in their research phase, with DeepSpeech making strong progress toward productization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To date, with data from Common Voice and other sources, DeepSpeech is technically capable to convert &lt;a href=&quot;https://hacks.mozilla.org/2018/09/speech-recognition-deepspeech/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;speech to text with human accuracy and “live”&lt;/a&gt;, i.e. in realtime as the audio is being streamed. This allows transcription of lectures, phone conversations, television programs, radio shows, and and other live streams all as they are happening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The DeepSpeech engine is already being used by a variety of non-Mozilla projects: For example in &lt;a href=&quot;https://mycroft.ai/blog/deepspeech-update/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Mycroft&lt;/a&gt;, an open source voice based assistant; in &lt;a href=&quot;https://getleon.ai/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Leon&lt;/a&gt;, an open-source personal assistant; in FusionPBX, a telephone switching system installed at and serving a private organization to transcribe phone messages. In the future Deep Speech will target smaller platform devices, such as smartphones and in-car systems, unlocking product innovation in and outside of Mozilla.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Common Voice, our focus in 2018 was to build out the concept, make it a tool for any language community to use, optimise the website, and build a robust backend (for example, the accounts system). Over the coming months we will focus efforts on experimenting with different approaches to increase the quantity and quality of data we are able to collect, both through community efforts as well as new partnerships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our overall aim remains: Providing more and better data to everyone in the world who seeks to build and use voice technology. Because competition and openness are healthy for innovation. Because smaller languages are an issue of access and equity. Because privacy and control matters, especially over your voice.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 11:38:16 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Vinnl</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://blog.mozilla.org/blog/2019/02/28/sharing-our-common-voices-mozilla-releases-the-largest-to-date-public-domain-transcribed-voice-dataset</og:url>
<og:title>Sharing our Common Voices – Mozilla releases the largest to-date public domain transcribed voice dataset – The Mozilla Blog</og:title>
<og:description>Mozilla Common Voice releases the largest to-date public domain voice dataset, including 18 languages, almost 1,400 hours of data from 42,000 contributors.</og:description>
<og:image>https://blog.mozilla.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/CV-Dataset-static-graphic-2x-1200x770.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.mozilla.org/blog/2019/02/28/sharing-our-common-voices-mozilla-releases-the-largest-to-date-public-domain-transcribed-voice-dataset/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: Expensive Chat – Pay one cent per letter</title>
<link>https://expensive.chat</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://expensive.chat</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;www.coindex.de [The cdx further acts as the industry standard and benchmark, in the domain of crypto assets, for both (semi-) professional and retail investors alike. Thus it likewise serves as as a tool for enabling passive investors to participate in this new asset class. The cdx family - which consists of multiple members ranging from cdx01, cdx03 and cdx05 over cdx10 to cdx50 - is designed to objectively measure the overall, daily and long-term growth of the cryptocurrency market. It tracks up to 50 crypto assets and has been designed for diversification, transparency, replicability, coverage and risk-adjusted performance. The calculation of the cdx index family dates back to January 1st, 2014 with a starting value of 1.000.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$6.23&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;time datetime=&quot;2019-02-28T13:18:08Z&quot; data-local=&quot;time&quot; data-format=&quot;%H:%M&quot;&gt;13:18&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 08:38:08 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>keesj</dc:creator>
<og:title>Expensive Chat – Pay one cent per letter</og:title>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>http://expensive.chat/</og:url>
<og:image>http://expensive.chat/assets/og-fbd08525844e415bfedf88efae791ca31ab1117faa54eecc3e03c26385895ea3.png</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://expensive.chat/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Red Flags in Software Developer Job Descriptions</title>
<link>https://joecmarshall.com/posts/job-description-red-flags/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://joecmarshall.com/posts/job-description-red-flags/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;For &lt;a href=&quot;https://jobletter.io&quot;&gt;some reason&lt;/a&gt; I’ve been reading a lot of job descriptions for junior devs lately and that has naturally left me with an inordinate number of opinions. I have, with great effort, condensed them here for you, dear reader.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following aren’t pulled from any specific listings because these types of awfulness transcend the individual - and because that would be dickish. But their spirit should ring true to anyone in the trenches of the job search process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;wordpress-developer-degree-10-years-experience-required&quot;&gt;“Wordpress Developer - Degree + 10 years experience required”&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not to dunk on Wordpress but - it is not the LHC. There’s a certain amount of inflation to be expected when it comes to job requirements (you should always cut the number of years asked for in half when considering applying somewhere) but people get ridiculous. Rigorous compiler work is not a prerequisite for building a shopify theme. In addition to being a potential tell for a demanding workplace culture in general - or a complete lack of technical understanding on the part of leadership - inflated expectations can set you up for failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those the gods wish to destroy they first call promising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;php-contractor-2-months&quot;&gt;“PHP Contractor - 2 Months”&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Short, time-bound, contracts can be a great stepping stone for a young developer, or a good stint for a freelancer looking to focus on one project for a while, but they can also be sources of ennervating, aggravating legacy work. And the presence of a lot of contractors employed on short terms can also be indicative of a short-termist culture: There’s a natural inclination to burn through people that way, because of the financial and organizational incentives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;early-stage-emmployee-technical-co-founder-person-to-make-my-thing&quot;&gt;“Early Stage Emmployee / Technical Co-founder / Person to Make My Thing”&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being a technical co-founder or “First Engineer” often means that someone has a brilliant, unicorn-level idea and they just need that tiny part of the entire product / platform / paradigm-shifting technology to be built by someone technical (like you). Ideas are incredibly cheap. Don’t invest significant effort unless there’s compelling market validation, great compensation, or both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;technologies-coldfusion-jquery&quot;&gt;“Technologies: Coldfusion + jQuery”&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your job search shouldn’t be driven by what’s fashionable in tech, but popularity and the market for a skill &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; important factors, since they influence a career track’s employability and profitability. The market for Coldfusion devs isn’t too hot (or even a thing) and jQuery simply doesn’t have the complexity or potential power of a full JS MVC. Companies advertising outdated stacks open you up to the risk of building the wrong sorts of skills, which can have far-reaching effects on your career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These have just been a few of the red flags that I’ve encountered, but there are many and more every day. Just like in any relationship, one red flag might be offset by a redeeming trait or focus (maybe?) but in a certain variety, or combination, it becomes too much to ignore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And you deserve better!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 04:40:02 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>webappsecperson</dc:creator>
<og:title>Red Flags in Software Developer Job Descriptions</og:title>
<og:description>Developer and Author from Austin, TX.</og:description>
<og:url>https://joecmarshall.com/posts/job-description-red-flags/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://joecmarshall.com/posts/job-description-red-flags/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Facebook wants up to 30% of fan subscriptions vs Patreon’s 5%</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/26/facebook-vs-patreon/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/26/facebook-vs-patreon/</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/facebook&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;facebook&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; will drive a hard bargain with influencers and artists judging by the terms of service for the social network’s Patreon-like Fan Subscriptions feature that lets people pay a monthly fee for access to a creator’s exclusive content. The policy document attained by TechCrunch shows Facebook plans to take up to a 30 percent cut of subscription revenue minus fees, compared to 5 percent by &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/patreon&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;patreon&quot;&gt;Patreon,&lt;/a&gt; 30 percent by YouTube, which covers fees and 50 percent by Twitch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook also reserves the right to offer free trials to subscriptions that won’t compensate creators. And Facebook demands a “non-exclusive, transferable, sub-licensable, royalty-free, worldwide license to use” creators’ content and “This license survives even if you stop using Fan Subscriptions.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Distrust of Facebook could scare creators away from the platform when combined with its significant revenue share and ability to give away or repurpose creators’ content. Facebook has consistently shown that it puts what it thinks users want and its own interests above those of partners. It cut off game developers from viral channels, inadequately warned Page owners their reach would drop over time, decimated referral traffic to news publishers and, most recently, banished video makers from the feed. If Facebook wants to win creators’ trust and the engagement of their biggest fans, it may need a more competitive offering with larger limits on its power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;breakout aligncenter wp-image-1789315&quot; src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Facebook-Fan-Subscriptions.png?w=680&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;584&quot; srcset=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Facebook-Fan-Subscriptions.png 1694w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Facebook-Fan-Subscriptions.png?resize=150,97 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Facebook-Fan-Subscriptions.png?resize=300,195 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Facebook-Fan-Subscriptions.png?resize=768,499 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Facebook-Fan-Subscriptions.png?resize=680,442 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Facebook-Fan-Subscriptions.png?resize=50,32 50w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 900px) 100vw, 900px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Facebook reached out to offer Hard Drive early access to a ‘fan subscription’ product” &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MattSaincome/status/1100216609564549120&quot;&gt;tweeted Matt Saincome&lt;/a&gt;, who also runs satirical news site &lt;a href=&quot;https://thehardtimes.net/&quot;&gt;The Hard Times&lt;/a&gt;. “I asked my editors about it and the complete distrust amongst our team was kinda funny. We read through the terms and found a couple things that were hilarious when compared to Patreon’s 5% . . . Up to 30% and the rights to all our stuff? From the people who let us build an audience on their platform before pulling it out from under our feet? Hilarious. Here’s a crazy alternative: let people who signed up to see our content see it and then we can monetize that hahah.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/ec-1/patreon/&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignright&quot; src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/ec-1-patreon-read-more1.png?w=400&quot; alt=&quot;Read a deep dive of Patreon on Extra Crunch&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;215&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instagram is refocusing on creators too. Instagram’s Android app reveals the prototype of a feature that lets users switch their profile into a Creator Account, similar to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2016/05/31/instagram-officially-announces-its-new-business-tools/&quot;&gt;Business Profiles&lt;/a&gt; it launched in 2016. Instagram first told &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/news/instagram-testing-creator-accounts-direct-message-filters-growth-insights-1168167?utm_source=twitter&quot;&gt;The Hollywood Reporter&lt;/a&gt; about Creator Accounts in December, but now it’s showing up in the code. Reverse-engineering specialist &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/wongmjane&quot;&gt;Jane Manchun Wong&lt;/a&gt; generated this screenshot showing the option for Creator Accounts to hide their contact info or profile category.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fellow code digger &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ishanagarwal24&quot;&gt;Ishan Agarwal&lt;/a&gt; gave TechCrunch an exclusive look at the Instagram code that shows the Creator Accounts are “Best for public figures, content producers, artists, and influencers.” Creator Accounts give users “more advanced insights and reach more people with promotions,” “more growth tools” and “a new inbox that makes it easier to manage message requests and connect with fans.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-1789318 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Instagram-Creator-Account-Best-For.jpg?w=680&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;680&quot; height=&quot;163&quot; srcset=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Instagram-Creator-Account-Best-For.jpg 1350w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Instagram-Creator-Account-Best-For.jpg?resize=150,36 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Instagram-Creator-Account-Best-For.jpg?resize=300,72 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Instagram-Creator-Account-Best-For.jpg?resize=768,184 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Instagram-Creator-Account-Best-For.jpg?resize=680,163 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Instagram-Creator-Account-Best-For.jpg?resize=50,12 50w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-1789321 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Instagram-Creator-Profile-Hide-Contact-Info.jpg?w=680&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;680&quot; height=&quot;643&quot; srcset=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Instagram-Creator-Profile-Hide-Contact-Info.jpg 1080w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Instagram-Creator-Profile-Hide-Contact-Info.jpg?resize=150,142 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Instagram-Creator-Profile-Hide-Contact-Info.jpg?resize=300,284 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Instagram-Creator-Profile-Hide-Contact-Info.jpg?resize=768,727 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Instagram-Creator-Profile-Hide-Contact-Info.jpg?resize=680,643 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Instagram-Creator-Profile-Hide-Contact-Info.jpg?resize=50,47 50w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Trading control for subscribers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook began testing &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/19/facebook-creator-monetization/&quot;&gt;Fan Subscriptions&lt;/a&gt; a year ago to give creators a financial alternative to maximizing ad views after watching the rise of Patreon, which now has 3 million patrons who’ll pay 100,000 artists, comedians, models and makers more than $500 million this year. This month Facebook expanded the test to the U.K., Spain, Germany and Portugal to allow users to pay $4.99 per month to a creator for exclusive content, live videos and a profile badge that highlights them as a subscriber. While Twitch owns gamers, YouTube rules amongst videographers and Patreon is a favorite with odd-ball creators, Facebook may see an opportunity to popularize Fan Subscriptions internationally and turn mainstream consumers into paid supporters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The terms for Fan Subscriptions are not publicly available, and only visible on Facebook’s site to Pages it’s invited to test the feature. But TechCrunch has published the full policy document below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-1789350 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/facebook-patreon-clone.png?w=680&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;680&quot; height=&quot;361&quot; srcset=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/facebook-patreon-clone.png 3200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/facebook-patreon-clone.png?resize=150,80 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/facebook-patreon-clone.png?resize=300,159 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/facebook-patreon-clone.png?resize=768,408 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/facebook-patreon-clone.png?resize=680,361 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/facebook-patreon-clone.png?resize=50,27 50w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, Facebook isn’t taking a cut of Fan Subscription revenue during the test phase, and creators get to keep 100 percent of the money paid by any patrons it signs up before the official launch. Facebook tells me that it hasn’t finalized its percentage cut, though the terms permit it to take as much as 30 percent. That would qualify, given Facebook tells me its rake will be in line with industry standards and creators will retain the majority of their earnings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;vertical alignright size-large wp-image-1789346&quot; src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Facebook-Subscribe-Become-A-Supporter-Button1.png?w=380&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;380&quot; height=&quot;680&quot; srcset=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Facebook-Subscribe-Become-A-Supporter-Button1.png 456w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Facebook-Subscribe-Become-A-Supporter-Button1.png?resize=84,150 84w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Facebook-Subscribe-Become-A-Supporter-Button1.png?resize=167,300 167w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Facebook-Subscribe-Become-A-Supporter-Button1.png?resize=380,680 380w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Facebook-Subscribe-Become-A-Supporter-Button1.png?resize=28,50 28w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 380px) 100vw, 380px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But whatever cut it takes will be after processing fees and the 15 to 30 percent tax Apple and Google levy on iOS and Android in-app purchases. We’ll see if Facebook tries a workaround that pushes users to their mobile browser where it can take their subscription money tax-free. And if Facebook decides it want to give users a free one-month trial or discount to any creator, they can’t stop it even if that lets people download all their exclusive content and then cancel without ever paying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what’s sure to raise the most hairs is the clause about “Supplemental Data” that gives Facebook a license to display a creator’s content as they might expect, but also a royalty-free license to use it however they want, even after a creator abandons Facebook Fan Subscriptions. A Facebook spokesperson confirmed that Supplemental Data does in fact cover all content provided by the creator. They claim it’s so if a creator made a custom fan sticker, a subscriber could use it in their own Facebook post, but the rule gives Facebook vast power beyond that. Patreon has a similar clause, but gets the benefit of the doubt in a way Facebook doesn’t after so many scandals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook’s spokesperson claimed that the Supplemental Data terms were similar to Facebook’s standard terms, but the normal Facebook terms say “You can end this license any time by deleting your content or account.” Not so with Fan Subscriptions. I don’t expect Facebook is going to try to outright steal and resell creators’ content, but it will have jurisdiction to use their art however it wants to fuel its war with Patreon, &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/twitch&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;twitch&quot;&gt;Twitch&lt;/a&gt; and YouTube.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creators will have to decide whether access to Facebook’s 2.3 billion users is worth the platform risk of building a following somewhere they don’t control and that has other business priorities. If Facebook’s strategy suddenly veers away from Fan Subscriptions, it could be hard for creators to score new signups or retain their old ones. At least with a dedicated site like Patreon, creators know the platform can’t abuse them without the threaten of ruin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here’s the full Terms of Service for Facebook’s Patreon competitor Fan Subscriptions:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fan Subscriptions creator terms&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fan funding feature (“&lt;strong&gt;Fan Subscriptions&lt;/strong&gt;”) allows Facebook users to support their favorite pages, creators, group administrators, gamers, or others (“&lt;strong&gt;Pages&lt;/strong&gt;”) through a monthly subscription with Facebook (“&lt;strong&gt;Subscription&lt;/strong&gt;”) that gives those people (“&lt;strong&gt;fans&lt;/strong&gt;”) access to digital content offered by Pages, such as exclusive digital content, fan recognition, and merchandise discounts. These Terms (“&lt;strong&gt;Terms&lt;/strong&gt;”) govern how Pages use Fan Subscriptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With regard to your use of Fan Subscriptions, you agree to the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Your use of the Platform with respect to Fan Subscriptions is subject to, and you agree to comply with, the Platform Policy currently available at &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.facebook.com/policy/&quot; data-saferedirecturl=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?q=https://developers.facebook.com/policy/&amp;amp;source=gmail&amp;amp;ust=1551288789493000&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNGbb_VxN1FT_22MFatR1o1pJrmpzQ&quot;&gt;https://developers.facebook.com/policy/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your use of Fan Subscriptions to offer digital content and/or services to Facebook fans is subject to, and you agree to comply with the (a) Monetization Eligibility Standards currently available at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/help/publisher/169845596919485?ref=ffterms&quot; data-saferedirecturl=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.facebook.com/help/publisher/169845596919485?ref%3Dffterms&amp;amp;source=gmail&amp;amp;ust=1551288789493000&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNEHaGDNqrmWhco34S6KYPNGI09h5w&quot;&gt;https://www.facebook.com/help/publisher/169845596919485&lt;/a&gt;, and (b) Content Guidelines for Monetization currently available at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/facebookmedia/get-started/monetization_contentguidelines&quot; data-saferedirecturl=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.facebook.com/facebookmedia/get-started/monetization_contentguidelines&amp;amp;source=gmail&amp;amp;ust=1551288789493000&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNGRqvd6N-zSTfdGuXsTLI5dJTHTyw&quot;&gt;https://www.facebook.com/facebookmedia/get-started/monetization_contentguidelines&lt;/a&gt;. You agree to follow any additional instructions and/or technical documentation we provide to you for Fan Subscriptions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will provide accurate information to fans in connection with your use of Fan Subscriptions, including but not limited as part of any digital content or services you choose to offer to them. You must clearly and conspicuously disclose all material terms regarding your offer and the nature of content or services you will provide to fans once they choose to subscribe. You agree to comply with all laws applicable to your use of Fan Subscriptions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You confirm that the content you offer via Subscription does not infringe upon the intellectual property rights of any third party and that you have secured all rights necessary to distribute, copy, display, publicly perform, or otherwise use the content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will not use, incorporate, or provide any music or physical goods in connection with your use of Fan Subscriptions without FB’s prior written approval (email is sufficient).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will not offer discounts on physical goods that exceed 80 percent of the offered goods’ retail value.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your fans’ Subscriptions may be processed as payments to Facebook via Apple’s In-App Purchase or Google’s In-App Billing services, which are subject to Apple’s and Google’s separate payment terms and conditions. Apple and Google may charge Facebook a revenue share and/or other fees for such payment services according to their respective terms and conditions. FB will pay you a revenue share calculated as a percentage (“Your Share”) of what’s left after deduction of those fees/charges and of any other fees or taxes incurred by Facebook. As a the date of these Terms, Your Share of that net revenue is 100%. However, Facebook may in the future change these Terms such that Facebook keeps a revenue share of up to 30%. We will give 30 days’ notice of any such change.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Facebook reserves the right to offer discounted and free trials for fans from time to time in our discretion, whether to incentivize Subscription sign-ups or otherwise. Where we do so in relation to your Fan Subscriptions, your revenue share will be reduced accordingly: we only pay you a revenue share based on the amounts fans actually pay (less fees and taxes we incur).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you have accurately completed and timely provided to FB any forms or documentation that FB reasonably determines are required to set up payment to you, and subject to and only in the event that you are in compliance in all respects with these Terms, payment of any net amounts FB receives from Apple and Google for Subscriptions made by your fans during your use of Fan Subscriptions will be on a monthly basis, within approximately 60 days after the end of the applicable month. Facebook will not be responsible for any subsequent fees applied by your financial institution to complete payment of the Monthly Fee to you. Furthermore, in the event the payment due to you would be less than One Hundred U.S. Dollars ($100.00), Facebook reserves the right to roll such payment over month to month until such payment threshold is met, at which time Facebook will make the applicable payment to you. Facebook also reserves the right to set off and/or withhold any amounts that Facebook reasonably considers are or are likely to be payable by you to Facebook under these Terms (including under any indemnities).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;.If you are providing (or allowing us to access) any data, content, or other information in connection with your use of Fan Subscriptions (collectively, “&lt;strong&gt;Supplemental Data&lt;/strong&gt;”), then you grant us (and our affiliates) a non-exclusive, transferable, sub-licensable, royalty-free, worldwide license to use such Supplemental Data. This license survives even if you stop using Fan Subscriptions. You are responsible for obtaining the necessary rights from all applicable rights holders to grant this license.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are responsible for paying any applicable taxes owed with respect to any amounts you receive through your use of Fan Subscriptions. Facebook will charge you taxes with respect to such amounts if it is required to do so under applicable law.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;.Facebook can terminate or suspend your use of Fan Subscriptions at any time in our sole discretion, and we may change or stop offering Fan Subscriptions at any time in our sole discretion. In no event will we be liable in any way for terminating or suspending your use of Fan Subscriptions, for the discontinuation of Fan Subscriptions, for the removal of or disabling of access to content, or for the withdrawal of the content or Fan Subscriptions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;.If you change what’s included in a Subscription in a way that could be considered material, you must give fans reasonable prior notice such that they have a reasonable opportunity to cancel their Subscriptions if they so choose, with the change only taking effect after their next Subscription fee payment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;.If you are using Fan Subscription on behalf of a third party (including, but not limited to, as an agent or representative of a Creator), you represent and warrant that you have the authority as agent of such party to use such features on their behalf, agree to these Terms, and hereby bind such party to these Terms. You agree to indemnify and hold Facebook harmless from any claims, suits, losses, liabilities, damages, costs, and expenses resulting from your breach of the Terms. If you are accepting these Terms as admin of Facebook Business Manager for your business, these Terms shall apply to Content on all Facebook Pages and profiles owned or operated by your business at the time of acceptance and thereafter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;.By using the Fan Subscriptions feature, you agree that we may communicate with you electronically any important information regarding your use of Fan Subscriptions, including without limitation as to Your Share and any payments. We may also provide notices to you by posting them on our website, or by sending them to an email address or street address that you previously provided to us. Website and email notices shall be considered received by you within 24 hours of the time posted or sent; notices by postal mail shall be considered received within three (3) business days of the time sent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;.Facebook reserves the right to update these Terms from time to time. If any change to these Terms will materially disadvantage you, or materially affect the availability of the Subscription, we will provide you with notice before the changes become effective and you can choose to cancel your Subscription. Your continued use of this feature constitutes acceptance of those changes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;.Fan Subscriptions is part of the “&lt;strong&gt;Facebook Products&lt;/strong&gt;” under Facebook’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/legal/terms/&quot; data-saferedirecturl=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.facebook.com/legal/terms/&amp;amp;source=gmail&amp;amp;ust=1551288789493000&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNHox0JjQc-dLrjyBZO5kRmW6T7liQ&quot;&gt;Terms of Service&lt;/a&gt; (“&lt;strong&gt;Facebook Terms&lt;/strong&gt;”), and your use of Fan Subscriptions is deemed part of your use of Facebook Products. In the event of any express conflict between these Terms and the Facebook Terms, these Terms will govern solely with respect to your use of Fan Subscriptions and solely to the extent of the conflict. These Terms do not alter in any way the terms or conditions of any other agreement you may have with Facebook. Facebook reserves the right to monitor or audit your compliance with these Terms and to update these terms from time to time, and your continued use of Fan Subscriptions constitutes acceptance of those changes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 04:36:19 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>doppp</dc:creator>
<og:title>Facebook wants up to 30% of fan subscriptions vs Patreon’s 5%</og:title>
<og:description>Facebook will drive a hard bargain with influencers and artists judging by the terms of service for the social network’s Patreon-like Fan Subscriptions feature that lets people pay a monthly fee for access to a creator’s exclusive content. The policy document attained by TechCrunch show…</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/fb-dollar-sign-mobile-alt1-2.png?w=711</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2019/02/26/facebook-vs-patreon/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/26/facebook-vs-patreon/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>