<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>European parliament committee approves vote on ‘disastrous’ copyright bill</title>
<link>https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-44546620</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-44546620</guid>
<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape has-caption full-width lead&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                &lt;img class=&quot;js-image-replace&quot; alt=&quot;People looking at a screen&quot; src=&quot;https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/320/cpsprodpb/130E4/production/_102125087_gettyimages-857906012.jpg&quot; width=&quot;976&quot; height=&quot;549&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    The changes could put an end to user-generated content, warn critics
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body__introduction&quot;&gt;A committee of MEPs has voted to accept major changes to European copyright law, which experts say could change the nature of the internet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They voted to approve the controversial Article 13, which critics warn could put an end to memes, remixes and other user-generated content.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Article 11, requiring online platforms to pay publishers a fee if they link to their news content, was also approved.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One organisation opposed to the changes called it a &quot;dark day&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The European Parliament's Committee on Legal Affairs voted by 15 votes to 10 to adopt Article 13 and by 13 votes to 12 to adopt Article 11.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It will now go to the wider European Parliament to vote on in July.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;'Censorship'&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last week, 70 influential tech leaders, including Vint Cerf and Tim Berners-Lee, signed &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/files/2018/06/12/article13letter.pdf&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link-external&quot;&gt;a letter&lt;/a&gt; opposing Article 13, which they called &quot;an imminent threat to the future&quot; of the internet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Article 13 puts more onus on websites to enforce copyright and could mean that every online platform that allows users to post text, sounds, code or images will need some form of content-recognition system to review all material that users upload.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Activist Cory Doctorow has called it a &quot;foolish, terrible idea&quot;.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Writing on online news website &lt;a href=&quot;https://boingboing.net/2018/06/14/six-days-left.html&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link-external&quot;&gt;BoingBoing&lt;/a&gt;, he said: &quot;No filter exists that can even approximate this. And the closest equivalents are mostly run by American companies, meaning that US big tech is going to get to spy on everything Europeans post and decide what gets censored and what doesn't.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Article 11 has been called the &quot;link tax&quot; by opponents. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Designed to limit the power over news publishers that tech giants such as Facebook and Google have, it requires online platforms to pay publishers a fee if they link to their news content.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The theory is that this would help support smaller news publishers and drive users to their homepages rather than directly to their news stories.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But critics say it fails to clearly define what constitutes a link and could be manipulated by governments to curb freedom of speech.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the vote, US not-for-profit organisation Creative Commons, which aims to make more content free for others to share, called it a &quot;dark day for the open web&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another Twitter user tweeted: &quot;15 MEPs voted for upload filtering. They understand the internet better than the people who invented it, apparently.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open Rights executive director Jim Killock told the BBC: &quot;Article 13 must go. The EU parliament will have another chance to remove this dreadful law.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;The EU parliament's duty is to defend citizens from unfair and unjust laws. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;MEPs must reject this law, which would create a robo-copyright regime intended to zap any image, text, meme or video that appears to include copyright material, even when it is entirely legal material.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But publishers, including the Independent Music Companies Association (Impala) welcomed the vote.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;This is a strong and unambiguous message sent by the European Parliament,&quot; said executive chair Helen Smith.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;It clarifies what the music sector has been saying for years: if you are in the business of distributing music or other creative works, you need a licence, clear and simple. It's time for the digital market to catch up with progress.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
            </description>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 11:49:57 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>sebst</dc:creator>
<og:title>'Disastrous' copyright bill vote approved</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Critics call it a &quot;dark day&quot; as an EU committee adopts two controversial changes to copyright law.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-44546620</og:url>
<og:image>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/130E4/production/_102125087_gettyimages-857906012.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-44546620</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Canada legalises recreational cannabis use</title>
<link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-44543286</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-44543286</guid>
<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape has-caption full-width lead&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                &lt;img class=&quot;js-image-replace&quot; alt=&quot;Canadian flying a national flag with a marijuana leaf instead of a maple leaf&quot; src=&quot;https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/320/cpsprodpb/F2FA/production/_102120226_aa038ab5-e73f-400f-ae7e-f024eff17c6f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;976&quot; height=&quot;549&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;AFP/Getty&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    The Senate passed the bill, with 52 votes in favour and 29 against
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body__introduction&quot;&gt;Canada's parliament has passed a law legalising the recreational use of marijuana nationwide.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Cannabis Act passed its final hurdle on Tuesday in a 52-29 vote in the Senate. The bill controls and regulates how the drug can be grown, distributed, and sold. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Canadians will be able to buy and consume cannabis legally as early as this September. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The country is the second worldwide to legalise the drug's recreational use.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul class=&quot;story-body__unordered-list&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-44531112&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;Legalising cannabis: What you need to know&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-latin-america-39522345&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;Uruguay became the first country to legalise the sale of cannabis for recreational use&lt;/a&gt; in December 2013, while a number of US states have also voted to permit it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cannabis possession first became a crime in Canada in 1923 but medical use has been legal since 2001. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul class=&quot;story-body__unordered-list&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-38083738&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;Pot advocates concerned about legalisation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/av/world-us-canada-38500023/marijuana-brands-aim-for-high-end-retail-in-canada&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;Marijuana brands aim for high-end retail in Canada&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The bill will likely receive Royal Assent this week, and the government will then choose an official date when the law will come into force.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Prime Minister Justin Trudeau tweeted that until now, &quot;it's been too easy for our kids to get marijuana - and for criminals to reap the profits&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;social-embed&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;social-embed-post social-embed-twitter&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;embed embed-twitter&quot; readability=&quot;4.7739938080495&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;embed-region&quot; role=&quot;region&quot; aria-label=&quot;Twitter post by @JustinTrudeau&quot; readability=&quot;5.5696594427245&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a class=&quot;off-screen jump-link&quot; href=&quot;#jump-linkhttps://twitter.com/JustinTrudeau/status/1009227308216045568&quot;&gt;Skip Twitter post  by @JustinTrudeau&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;twitter-wrap&quot; readability=&quot;6.1285140562249&quot;&gt;
                &lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot; readability=&quot;6.2768595041322&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;It’s been too easy for our kids to get marijuana - and for criminals to reap the profits. Today, we change that. Our plan to legalize &amp;amp; regulate marijuana just passed the Senate. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/PromiseKept?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#PromiseKept&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Justin Trudeau (@JustinTrudeau) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/JustinTrudeau/status/1009227308216045568?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 20, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

            
            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;p class=&quot;off-screen&quot; id=&quot;jump-linkhttps://twitter.com/JustinTrudeau/status/1009227308216045568&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;End of Twitter post  by @JustinTrudeau&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;But some groups objected to the new law, with opposition Conservative politicians and indigenous groups among those voicing concerns.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The government is expected to give the provinces and territories, as well as municipalities, eight to 12 weeks to set up the new marijuana marketplace.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This timeframe will also allow industry and police forces to prepare for the new legal framework.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2015, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-42416763&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;Canadians were estimated to have spent about C$6bn ($4.5bn, £3.4bn) on cannabis&lt;/a&gt; - almost as much as they did on wine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;How will legal marijuana in Canada work? &lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is likely that by mid-September, Canadians will be able to buy cannabis and cannabis oil grown by licensed producers at various retail locations. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Canadians across the country will also be able to order the drug online from federally licensed producers, and grow up to four plants at home.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-with-caption&quot; readability=&quot;-24&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;player-with-placeholder&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img class=&quot;media-placeholder player-with-placeholder__image narrative-video-placeholder&quot; src=&quot;https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/images/ic/720x405/p06blz34.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Media playback is unsupported on your device&lt;/p&gt;
      
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-with-caption__caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Media caption&lt;/span&gt;Take a look inside the world's largest legal cannabis farm&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Adults will be able to possess up to 30 grams (one ounce) of dried cannabis in public. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Edibles, or cannabis-infused foods, will not be immediately available for purchase but will be within a year of the bill coming into force. The delay is meant to give the government time to set out regulations specific to those products. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The minimum legal age to buy and consume marijuana has been set federally at 18 but some provinces have chosen to set it at 19. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul class=&quot;story-body__unordered-list&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-42285744&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;Canada, provinces reach pot tax deal &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-28767270&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;Cannabis and Canada: Why has drug policy changed?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Provinces are in charge of how it is sold and have the power to set various other limits on its use within their jurisdiction - like where it can be smoked. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But the federal government has set guidelines for plain packaging with little branding and strict health warnings. It will also impose restrictions on promotions targeting young people, promotion through sponsorships, or depictions of celebrities, characters or animals in advertisements.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;What will remain illegal?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It will be illegal to possess more than 30 grams of cannabis in public, grow more than four plants per household and to buy from an unlicensed dealer. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape has-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
                 &lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;Press Association&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    There will still be some restrictions on cannabis use in Canada
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Penalties will be severe. Someone caught selling the drug to a minor could be jailed for up to 14 years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some critics say the penalties are too harsh and not proportional to similar laws like those around selling alcohol to minors. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;What are the rules around the world?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cannabis is banned in most countries but a number of places have decriminalised its use in recent years. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-44536978&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;The UK government said recently it would review the use of medicinal cannabis.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is legal for medicinal purposes in 14 European countries, Israel, Argentina, Puerto Rico, Panama, Mexico, Turkey, Zambia and Zimbabwe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the US, medicinal use is allowed in 29 states and the District of Columbia, Nine of the states have legalised both medical and personal cannabis use.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Spain, the Netherlands, Portugal, Slovenia, Jamaica, Chile, Peru, Colombia, Ecuador and Luxembourg are among countries that have relaxed legislation regarding personal use.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;Did anyone object?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new law has not been met with universal praise.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Conservative Party leader Andrew Scheer has previously said he was apprehensive it would normalise cannabis use and make it more accessible. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Leo Housakos, a Conservative senator from Quebec, tweeted to say that he thought the law would be &quot;catastrophic for Canadian generations to come&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One specific concern being raised is the legal minimum age being set at 18 instead of 25, as was recommended by multiple experts. However, the government's own task force recommended 18, warning that setting the age limit too high could continue to encourage youth to buy marijuana on the illegal market. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Opponents also question the potential public health impact of legalisation. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, indigenous groups and politicians have voiced fears that their communities were not adequately consulted in the run-up to the vote.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indigenous services minister Jane Philpott and health minister Ginette Petitpas Taylor had to write a letter to the chair and deputy chair of the Senate's Committee on Aboriginal Peoples earlier in June promising a full report to parliament addressing their concerns, narrowly averting a delay to the law's passage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;Why is Canada doing this now? &lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This legislation fulfils a 2015 campaign promise by Mr Trudeau, the leader of the Liberal Party.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The prime minister has argued that Canada's nearly century-old laws criminalising use of the drug have been ineffective, given that Canadians are still among the world's heaviest users.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Polls have repeatedly indicated that a solid majority of Canadians are supportive of the move. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The decision to legalise recreational use of marijuana in Canada comes as global trends shift away from criminal prohibition of the widely used drug. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-with-caption&quot; readability=&quot;-24&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;player-with-placeholder&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img class=&quot;media-placeholder player-with-placeholder__image narrative-video-placeholder&quot; src=&quot;https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/images/ic/720x405/p05jldgm.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Media playback is unsupported on your device&lt;/p&gt;
      
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-with-caption__caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Media caption&lt;/span&gt;UK Labour backbencher Paul Flynn said the tide of world opinion is moving to legalisation of cannabis&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 01:06:59 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pmoriarty</dc:creator>
<og:title>Canada legalises recreational cannabis use</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>It becomes the second country in the world to allow recreational use of the drug nationwide.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-44543286</og:url>
<og:image>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/F2FA/production/_102120226_aa038ab5-e73f-400f-ae7e-f024eff17c6f.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-GB</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-44543286</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Microsoft Employees Pressure Leadership to Cancel ICE Contract</title>
<link>https://gizmodo.com/microsoft-employees-pressure-leadership-to-cancel-ice-c-1826965297</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://gizmodo.com/microsoft-employees-pressure-leadership-to-cancel-ice-c-1826965297</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrapper lazy-image&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-permalink-sub-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;js_lightbox-wrapper lightbox-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.kinja-img.com/gawker-media/image/upload/s--mndKSxdx--/c_scale,f_auto,fl_progressive,q_80,w_800/oq3ebqwe1ap5r8pwzxbe.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lazyload ls-lazy-image-tag&quot; data-sizes=&quot;auto&quot; data-width=&quot;2880&quot; data-chomp-id=&quot;oq3ebqwe1ap5r8pwzxbe&quot; data-format=&quot;jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Illustration: Bryan Menegus (Gizmodo)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft employees are putting pressure on their management to cancel a contract with U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, part of a backlash against the agency’s policy of separating children from their families at the U.S. border.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an open letter to Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella sent today, employees demanded that the company cancel its $19.4 million contract with ICE and instate a policy against working with clients who violate international human rights law. The text of the employee letter was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/06/19/technology/tech-companies-immigration-border.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; onclick=&quot;window.ga('send', 'event', 'Embedded Url', 'External link', 'https://www.nytimes.com/2018/06/19/technology/tech-companies-immigration-border.html', {metric25:1})&quot;&gt;first reported by the New York Times&lt;/a&gt; and confirmed by Gizmodo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We believe that Microsoft must take an ethical stand, and put children and families above profits,” the letter, signed by Microsoft employees, states. “We request that Microsoft cancel its contracts with ICE, and with other clients who directly enable ICE. As the people who build the technologies that Microsoft profits from, we refuse to be complicit. We are part of a growing movement, comprised of many across the industry who recognize the grave responsibility that those creating powerful technology have to ensure what they build is used for good, and not for harm.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, as word of the contract between ICE and Microsoft’s Azure cloud platform spread within Microsoft’s ranks, some &lt;a href=&quot;https://gizmodo.com/microsoft-employees-up-in-arms-over-cloud-contract-with-1826927803&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; onclick=&quot;window.ga('send', 'event', 'Embedded Url', 'Internal link', 'https://gizmodo.com/microsoft-employees-up-in-arms-over-cloud-contract-with-1826927803', {metric25:1})&quot;&gt;employees were incensed&lt;/a&gt;—and considering quitting. Now, Gizmodo has learned, those outside the company are having second thoughts about working with a tech giant that’s a “&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/azuregov/2018/01/24/federal-agencies-continue-to-advance-capabilities-with-azure-government/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; onclick=&quot;window.ga('send', 'event', 'Embedded Url', 'External link', 'https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/azuregov/2018/01/24/federal-agencies-continue-to-advance-capabilities-with-azure-government/', {metric25:1})&quot;&gt;proud&lt;/a&gt;” and willing collaborator with ICE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;inset--story js_inset branded-item branded-item--gizmodo&quot; onclick=&quot;window.ga('send', 'event', 'Embedded Url', 'Internal inset', 'https:\/\/gizmodo.com\/microsoft-employees-up-in-arms-over-cloud-contract-with-1826927803', {metric25:1})&quot; readability=&quot;16.05&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gizmodo.com/microsoft-employees-up-in-arms-over-cloud-contract-with-1826927803&quot; class=&quot;inset--story__thumb&quot; onclick=&quot;window.ga('send', 'event', 'Permalink page click', 'Permalink page click - inset photo');&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazyload&quot; data-sizes=&quot;auto&quot; src=&quot;https://i.kinja-img.com/gawker-media/image/upload/s--ZNz2ikEq--/c_fill,fl_progressive,g_north,h_77,q_80,w_137/hmxy23igudxwrkw0lsje.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Article preview thumbnail&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;inset--story__content&quot; readability=&quot;20.211111111111&quot;&gt;
&lt;h6 class=&quot;inset--story__headline&quot; onclick=&quot;window.ga('send', 'event', 'Permalink page click', 'Permalink page click - inset headline');&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gizmodo.com/microsoft-employees-up-in-arms-over-cloud-contract-with-1826927803&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Microsoft Employees Up in Arms Over Cloud Contract With ICE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tensions are high within Microsoft, as new scrutiny is given to a partnership between the company’s …&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://gizmodo.com/microsoft-employees-up-in-arms-over-cloud-contract-with-1826927803&quot; class=&quot;js_readmore inset--story__readmore&quot; onclick=&quot;window.ga('send', 'event', 'Permalink page click', 'Permalink page click - inset read more link');&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Read more &lt;span class=&quot;js_external-text hide&quot;&gt;Read&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;js_ad-mobile-dynamic js_ad-dynamic ad-mobile-dynamic&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-unit js_ad-unit hide-contents ad-mobile js_ad-mobile&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-mobile-inner&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ad-label proxima&quot;&gt;&lt;small class=&quot;proxima&quot;&gt;Advertisement&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mat Marquis, a writer and developer, announced on Twitter that he was canceling his contract with Microsoft in protest against its ICE contract.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It would be easy to think of coding as neutral—we solve puzzles,” Marquis told Gizmodo. “Put a semicolon in the right place and an error goes away, make the website a little faster than it was yesterday; in a vacuum, it’s innocuous work. It’s important, though, to consider the bigger picture for the things we help to build—how can it be misused, who am I supporting with it, who benefits from it and who bears the costs? I didn’t work with the Azure team; I would never have ended up there, considering my skillset. But the decision to work with an organization is a decision to help them achieve their goals, and Microsoft has shown that they’re willing to lend their name to ICE’s goals. I will not.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result of its ongoing relationship with ICE, Jer Thorp—a deeply-credentialed artist who is currently the Library of Congress’s Innovator-in-Residence—also chose to sever ties with Microsoft. He was scheduled to speak at New York’s Civic Hall on Friday as part of the company’s Machine Eatable conference series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;js_ad-mobile-dynamic js_ad-dynamic ad-mobile-dynamic&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-unit js_ad-unit hide-contents ad-mobile js_ad-mobile&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-mobile-inner&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ad-label proxima&quot;&gt;&lt;small class=&quot;proxima&quot;&gt;Advertisement&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I think that what we’re seeing right now with ICE is deeply immoral. It’s a violation of human rights on all kinds of levels. As builders and programmers, one our primary concerns has to be the safety of the people who are living in the data systems we create,” he told Gizmodo over Twitter DM. “By doing business with ICE, [Microsoft] is turning tools towards very different purposes than the developers who worked on the tools might have imagined. It’s up to those workers, really, to speak up and take action and refuse to let the fruits of their labors be used to put kids in cages.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to course-correct, Thorp suggested the company state plainly whether or not it had allowed extant facial recognition tools be used by ICE and/or if it had developed custom artificial intelligence tools for the agency. “Following that, he has to state clearly [whether] MSFT will be continuing their contract with ICE into the future,” he wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gizmodo asked Microsoft those exact questions yesterday. The company instead provided a &lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.microsoft.com/on-the-issues/2018/06/18/microsoft-statement-on-separating-families-at-the-southern-border/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; onclick=&quot;window.ga('send', 'event', 'Embedded Url', 'External link', 'https://blogs.microsoft.com/on-the-issues/2018/06/18/microsoft-statement-on-separating-families-at-the-southern-border/', {metric25:1})&quot;&gt;statement&lt;/a&gt; which addressed neither issue. In a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/fathers-day-families-together-brad-smith/?published=t&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; onclick=&quot;window.ga('send', 'event', 'Embedded Url', 'External link', 'https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/fathers-day-families-together-brad-smith/?published=t', {metric25:1})&quot;&gt;LinkedIn post&lt;/a&gt; on Sunday, Microsoft president and chief legal officer Brad Smith highlighted the company’s work reuniting refugee families in Bosnia and its contributions to Kids in Need of Defense, an organization that provides legal representation to immigrant children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;js_ad-mobile-dynamic js_ad-dynamic ad-mobile-dynamic&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-unit js_ad-unit hide-contents ad-mobile js_ad-mobile&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-mobile-inner&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ad-label proxima&quot;&gt;&lt;small class=&quot;proxima&quot;&gt;Advertisement&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“When we keep children with their parents, we not only follow in the footsteps of one of the world’s oldest and most important humanitarian traditions, we help build a stronger country,” Smith wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The outcry from Microsoft’s rank-and-file is the latest in a series of well-founded objections by tech workers against the tools they help to build falling into the hands of law enforcement and government agencies. After Google’s collaboration with the Pentagon was made public by Gizmodo, Google employees raised alerts internally, culminating in a similar letter being sent to leadership. Shortly after Trump’s election, tech workers across multiple companies signed the “Never Again” pledge to refuse collaboration on tools that “target individuals based on race, religion, or national origin.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The open letter by Microsoft employees echoes one sent by Google employees to their CEO earlier this year, which also called on the company to cancel a controversial government contract. Google employees objected to their company’s involvement in Project Maven, a Defense Department pilot program that uses artificial intelligence to assess drone footage. Facing employee pressure, &lt;a href=&quot;https://gizmodo.com/google-plans-not-to-renew-its-contract-for-project-mave-1826488620&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; onclick=&quot;window.ga('send', 'event', 'Embedded Url', 'Internal link', 'https://gizmodo.com/google-plans-not-to-renew-its-contract-for-project-mave-1826488620', {metric25:1})&quot;&gt;Google announced it would not renew its Project Maven contract&lt;/a&gt;. The search giant also unveiled new ethical principles for its use of AI, although some &lt;a href=&quot;https://gizmodo.com/in-reversal-google-says-its-ai-will-not-be-used-for-we-1826649327&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; onclick=&quot;window.ga('send', 'event', 'Embedded Url', 'Internal link', 'https://gizmodo.com/in-reversal-google-says-its-ai-will-not-be-used-for-we-1826649327', {metric25:1})&quot;&gt;employees questioned&lt;/a&gt; whether the principles included a firm commitment to following international human rights law.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;js_ad-mobile-dynamic js_ad-dynamic ad-mobile-dynamic&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-unit js_ad-unit hide-contents ad-mobile js_ad-mobile&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-mobile-inner&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ad-label proxima&quot;&gt;&lt;small class=&quot;proxima&quot;&gt;Advertisement&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft did not immediately respond to our request for comment on the letter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update 6/19/18 8:05pm ET:&lt;/strong&gt; Less than an hour ago, Jason Zander, Vice President of Azure, posted a response to employees in an internal Yammer thread in which he claimed the scope of ICE’s use of Microsoft tools was far less sinister than what had been assumed. “I’ve heard from many employees over the last two days with questions on the work we are doing with US Immigration &amp;amp; Customs Enforcement,” Zander wrote, “Our current engagement with ICE is focused on moving legacy infrastructure such as mail, calendar, messaging and document management to the cloud using Azure. This means we are not doing anything with AI, Cognitive Services, or facial recognition. I know this is a complicated issue. I hope having the facts helps.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The January &lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/azuregov/2018/01/24/federal-agencies-continue-to-advance-capabilities-with-azure-government/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; onclick=&quot;window.ga('send', 'event', 'Embedded Url', 'External link', 'https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/azuregov/2018/01/24/federal-agencies-continue-to-advance-capabilities-with-azure-government/', {metric25:1})&quot;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; where Microsoft announced the partnership, however, explicitly makes mention of Azure’s facial recognition capabilities—hailing them as a boon to the agency. “This can help employees make more informed decisions faster, with Azure Government enabling them to process data on edge devices or utilize deep learning capabilities to accelerate facial recognition and identification,” it states. We’ve reached out to Microsoft about this apparent inconsistency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;js_ad-mobile-dynamic js_ad-dynamic ad-mobile-dynamic&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-unit js_ad-unit hide-contents ad-mobile js_ad-mobile&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-mobile-inner&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ad-label proxima&quot;&gt;&lt;small class=&quot;proxima&quot;&gt;Advertisement&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read the full letter below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;52&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Satya,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe that Microsoft must take an ethical stand, putting children and families above profits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, we ask that Microsoft cancel its contracts with US Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) immediately, including contracts with clients who support ICE. We also call on Microsoft to draft, publicize and enforce a clear policy stating that neither Microsoft nor its contractors will work with clients who violate international human rights law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were dismayed to learn that Microsoft has a standing $19.4M contract with ICE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a clear abdication of ethical responsibility, Microsoft went as far as boasting that its services “support the core [ICE] agency functions” and enable ICE agents to “process data on edge devices” and “utilize deep learning capabilities to accelerate facial recognition and identification.” These are powerful capabilities, in the hands of an agency that has shown repeated willingness to enact inhumane and cruel policies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In response to questions, Brad Smith published a statement saying that Microsoft is “not aware of Azure products or services being used for the purpose of separating families.” This does not go far enough. We are providing the technical undergirding in support of an agency that is actively enforcing this inhumane policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We request that Microsoft cancel its contracts with ICE, and with other clients who directly enable ICE. As the people who build the technologies that Microsoft profits from, we refuse to be complicit. We are part of a growing movement, comprised of many across the industry who recognize the grave responsibility that those creating powerful technology have to ensure what they build is used for good, and not for harm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acknowledging this responsibility, we request that you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. Cancel the existing Azure Government contract with ICE immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. Draft, publicize, and enforce a clear policy stating that neither Microsoft nor its contractors will work with clients who violate international human rights law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3. Commit to transparency and review regarding contracts between Microsoft and government agencies, in the US and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft workers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;js_ad-mobile-dynamic js_ad-dynamic ad-mobile-dynamic&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-unit js_ad-unit hide-contents ad-mobile js_ad-mobile&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-mobile-inner&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ad-label proxima&quot;&gt;&lt;small class=&quot;proxima&quot;&gt;Advertisement&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 23:55:55 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rumcajz</dc:creator>
<og:title>Microsoft Employees Pressure Leadership to Cancel ICE Contract</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://i.kinja-img.com/gawker-media/image/upload/s--qqcCFisV--/c_fill,fl_progressive,g_center,h_900,q_80,w_1600/oq3ebqwe1ap5r8pwzxbe.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>https://gizmodo.com/microsoft-employees-pressure-leadership-to-cancel-ice-c-1826965297</og:url>
<og:description>Microsoft employees are putting pressure on their management to cancel a contract with U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, part of a backlash against the agency’s policy of separating children from their families at the U.S. border.</og:description>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://gizmodo.com/microsoft-employees-pressure-leadership-to-cancel-ice-c-1826965297</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Machine Fired Me</title>
<link>https://idiallo.com/blog/when-a-machine-fired-me</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://idiallo.com/blog/when-a-machine-fired-me</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;It was 7am when my phone rang. Instead of an alarm, it was my recruiter disturbing me from a pleasant dream. It was too early for a phone call or to be caught off guard, so I did not answer. I went to take a shower and get ready for the day. On my way to work, I listened to the voice mail she had left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Oh my God, are you OK!&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the company's directory, there are several people that shared the same first and last name as me. I was OK. So she must have dialed the wrong phone number. I assumed somewhere, an employee named Ibrahim Diallo, was in trouble. But not me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At work, when I scanned my key card at the turnstile, it flashed red, made a grumpy beep, and refused to disengage. I tried it a few more times, it kept flashing red and grumping. I threw a glance at Jose and made sure to make eye contact. He shrugged. A moment later he laughed then pressed a button under his desk and the turnstile turned open. Jose was one of the security guards in the LA-1 skyscraper I worked in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I immediately called the recruiter back and it went something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recruiter: Did you have a talk with your manager yesterday?&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;Me: Yes I did.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;R: Is everything OK?&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;M: Yes, everything is OK. Is there a problem?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;R: I'm not sure, I received an email about you this morning... I guess it must have been a mistake. Did they let you in the building?&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;M: I don't understand. Yes, they let me in the building. What is happening?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;R: I think there is a confusion. I'll ask my manager then I will call you back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jose has seen me come to work everyday through those doors for more than half a year. I believe this was his idea of a joke. He must have disabled the turnstile right before I was to scan my key card. I went straight to my manager to see &quot;If everything was OK.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Me: Hi!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Sam (manager): Hi Ibrahim, how are you?&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;Me: I'm fine. I received a call from my recruiter. Did you want to talk to me?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Sam: No, I don't think so. Did she tell you what the problem was?&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;Me: No. She said she will call me back. I'll wait for her call, I guess.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did not receive a call from her. Nothing interesting happened on that day, &lt;a href=&quot;https://idiallo.com/blog/hiring-angular-experts-not&quot;&gt;just good Ol' work routine&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day I drove my car to the parking structure and heard the same grumpy beep when I scanned my card. There was a long line of cars forming behind me, the drivers were getting impatient and some had started to honk at me already. It's a long one way corridor where getting out of the lane was not an option. I silently panicked. A security guard appeared, gave me a look, shook his head disappointed, then used his own card to let me in. I embarrassingly drove all the way to the 8th floor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inside the building, my card failed again, and the loud grumpy beep made sure everyone was aware of it. Jose let me in once more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It wasn't the first time my key card failed, I assumed it was time to replace it. As soon as I got to my floor, I went to see my manager to let her know. She promised to order me a new one right away. In the meanwhile, every morning the security guard would have to print a temporary badge for me that would expire by 7pm. Small price to pay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went to my desk and worked for a few hours on hardware. When I was done, I logged into my Windows machine to mark my Jira ticket as completed, that's when I noticed that I had been logged out of Jira. I tried my jira credentials multiple times and they did not work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On my floor, there was a poster at the very entrance. An employee made a New Yorker style comic with two employees talking from across their cubicles. These were the words:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is JIRA down?&lt;br/&gt;Yes, JIRA is down!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jira is always down. So I asked my coworker in the next cubicle if JIRA was working for him. He answered Yes. Then I asked him to look for my ticket number. He opened it. Right next to my name on this ticket, it had the word &lt;strong&gt;(Inactive)&lt;/strong&gt; and my name was grayed out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's something the manager could sort out, but it was lunch time. I went down to the cafeteria and ordered a nice black bean burger, a healthy diet is important if your work consists off sitting down all day. I went for my usual after-lunch one mile walk, again this counters sitting down all day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, when I come back, I take the stairs up to the 11th floor. Very hard, but you know, sitting down all day is not good. The only problem was that I forgot that when I reached the 11th floor, I would have to scan my key card to leave the stairs. That card reader reminded me with the slowest, meanest, and grumpiest beep an 8 bit machine could make. I was stuck on the stairs. I sat there for 10 minutes until a fellow stair taker opened the door for me. I sneaked into the floor like a common thief.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's when my recruiter called me in panic apologizing again and asking &lt;em&gt;if everything was OK&lt;/em&gt;. She told me she had received an email saying I was terminated. I told my manager right away, and she was surprised because she received no such information. She couldn't understand why my JIRA was disabled but the system wouldn't allow her to enable my account. She created a JIRA ticket for the support team to re-enable my account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back at my desk, there was a big scary (and threatening) error message on my screen. It asked me to restart my computer immediately. I did not comply. Well, I had a few hundred windows open and multiple programming environments running. I just dismissed the box. I knew that if I restarted that computer, I wouldn't be able to log back in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, I logged into Confluence to document my work for the rest of the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day, I took Uber to work, I didn't want to deal with the parking again. Jose couldn't print a temporary badge for me because my name appeared in RED and flagged in the system. My manager had to come down to escort me into the building. The recruiter sent me a message telling me not to go to work. She had just received a message that my badge had been used while I had been terminated. I was already in the building. We got the &lt;em&gt;Director&lt;/em&gt; involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What the Hell is happening? Am I fired or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The director laughed. She was a tall elegant woman with the confidence of a countess. She stretched her arm, unhooked the phone and dialed the number for support with the one same hand. With her might and title, she ordered them to immediately restore everything back to normal and hung up. She assured me that everything will be alright, to get back to work and this would be solved by the end of the day. I was still there in her office and saw her face when she got this email:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.idiallo.com/images/assets/353/email.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;You are fired&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was successfully terminated. Case closed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meanwhile, there was an emergency on the multimillion dollar tool I was working on. Hundred of thousands of records were missing and the web interface was not responding. I went to my desk only to see that my Windows machine had been automatically restarted (Damn you Microsoft) and my account had been disabled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank God I had my CentOS machine. The regular tools I use for development were no longer accessible. I had to hack my way into the server to restart it, debug it, reactivate all the services, and reprocess the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I left the building I went to see the director that was still on the phone with support. She gave me the green light to come to work the next day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day, I had been locked out off every single system except my Linux machine. Even the service we used to log our hours to get paid had been deactivated. I spent the first half of the day documenting my work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After lunch, two people appeared at my desk. One was a familiar long face that seemed to avoid making direct eye contact. It was Jose and his fellow security guard. He cordially informed me that he was to escort me out of the building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The director was furious. They had received a very threatening email to escort me out of the building and were just doing their job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Who the hell is sending those emails!?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was fired. There was nothing my manager could do about it. There was nothing the director could do about it. They stood powerless as I packed my stuff and left the building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the next 3 weeks, I was CCed on the emails about my case. I watched it be escalated to bigger and more powerful titles over and over, yet no one could do anything about it. From time to time, they would attach a system email. It was soulless and written in red as it gave orders that dictated my fate. Disable this, disable that, revoke access here, revoke access there, escort out of premises, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The system was out for blood and I was its very first victim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had worked there for more than 8 months and my work spoke for itself. I was receiving constant praises, people were fascinated by my work. I was getting along super well with every one. I like to believe that I never did anything wrong to anyone... This was a great reminder of the frailty of &lt;a href=&quot;https://idiallo.com/blog/job-security&quot;&gt;job security&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually the problem was solved. My recruiter called me one morning and told me that I can come back to work. I had missed 3 weeks of work by that time, and pay. Once on site, I got an explanation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the order for employee termination is put in, the system takes over. All the necessary orders are sent automatically and each order completion triggers another order. For example, when the order for disabling my key card is sent, there is no way of it to be re-enabled. Once it is disabled, an email is sent to security about recently dismissed employees. Scanning the key card is a red flag. The order to disable my Windows account is also sent. There is also one for my JIRA account. And on and on. There is no way to stop the multi-day long process. I had to be rehired as a new employee. Meaning I had to fill up paperwork, set up direct deposit, wait for Fedex to ship a new key card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But at the end of the day the question is still, why was I terminated in the first place?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was on a 3 years contract and had only worked for 8 months. Just before I was hired, this company was acquired by a much larger company and I joined during the transition. My manager at the time was from the previous administration. One morning I came to work to see that his desk had been wiped clean, as if he was disappeared. As a full time employee, he had been laid off. He was to work from home as a contractor for the duration of a transition. I imagine due to the shock and frustration, he decided not to do much work after that. Some of that work included renewing my contract in the new system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was very comfortable at the job. I had learned the in-and-out of all the systems I worked on. I had made friends at work. I had created a routine around the job. I became the go-to guy. I was comfortable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When my contract expired, the machine took over and fired me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A simple automation mistake(feature) caused everything to collapse. I was escorted out of the building like a thief, I had to explain to people why I am not at work, my coworkers became distant (except my manager who was exceptionally supportive). Despite the great opportunity it was for me to work at such a big company, I decided to take the next opportunity that presented itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I called job security was only an illusion. I couldn't help but imagine what would have happened if I had actually made a mistake in this company. Automation can be an asset to a company, but there needs to be a way for humans to take over if the machine makes a mistake. I missed 3 weeks of pay because no one could stop the machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At least a year later, I can sit here and write about it without feeling too embarrassed. So that's the story about the machine that fired me and no human could do anything about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PS:&lt;/strong&gt; I am willing to bet the recent issue with &lt;a href=&quot;https://torrentfreak.com/youtubes-piracy-filter-blocks-mit-courses-blender-videos-and-more-180618/&quot;&gt;YouTube Piracy filter blocking MIT courses and the Blender Foundation&lt;/a&gt; are the result of &lt;strong&gt;The Machine&lt;/strong&gt; being the ultimate decider. Even though YouTube's support team clearly knows that these don't violate terms and conditions, the &lt;strong&gt;Machine&lt;/strong&gt; decided otherwise. And they will have to fight it to death to bring the videos back online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ottomon.net?rel=id&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.ottomon.net/images/logo-b-bg.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out my new Startup &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ottomon.net?rel=id&quot;&gt;Ottomon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contact the owner of any car with the click of a button.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;article__end&quot;/&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;prev-next&quot;&gt;

&lt;/aside&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 22:02:51 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>foxfired</dc:creator>
<og:type>blog</og:type>
<og:title>The Machine Fired Me</og:title>
<og:image>https://cdn.idiallo.com/images/assets/353/thumb.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>It was 7am when my phone rang. Instead of an alarm, it was my recruiter disturbing me from a pleasant dream. It was too early for a phone call or to be caught off guard, so I did not answer. I went to</og:description>
<og:url>https://idiallo.com/blog/when-a-machine-fired-me</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://idiallo.com/blog/when-a-machine-fired-me</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>OpenBSD disables Intel&amp;#039;s hyperthreading due to security concerns</title>
<link>https://www.mail-archive.com/source-changes@openbsd.org/msg99141.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.mail-archive.com/source-changes@openbsd.org/msg99141.html</guid>
<description>&lt;pre&gt;
CVSROOT:        /cvs
Module name:    src
Changes by:     kette...@cvs.openbsd.org        2018/06/19 13:29:52
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;margintop marginbottom&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;hidden&quot;&gt;Advertising&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-7266757337600734&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;9759909619&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;

Modified files:
        sys/arch/amd64/amd64: cpu.c 
        sys/arch/amd64/include: cpu.h 
        sys/kern       : kern_sched.c kern_sysctl.c 
        sys/sys        : sched.h sysctl.h 

Log message:
SMT (Simultanious Multi Threading) implementations typically share
TLBs and L1 caches between threads.  This can make cache timing
attacks a lot easier and we strongly suspect that this will make
several spectre-class bugs exploitable.  Especially on Intel's SMT
implementation which is better known as Hypter-threading.  We really
should not run different security domains on different processor
threads of the same core.  Unfortunately changing our scheduler to
take this into account is far from trivial.  Since many modern
machines no longer provide the ability to disable Hyper-threading in
the BIOS setup, provide a way to disable the use of additional
processor threads in our scheduler.  And since we suspect there are
serious risks, we disable them by default.  This can be controlled
through a new hw.smt sysctl.  For now this only works on Intel CPUs
when running OpenBSD/amd64.  But we're planning to extend this feature
to CPUs from other vendors and other hardware architectures.

Note that SMT doesn't necessarily have a posive effect on performance;
it highly depends on the workload.  In all likelyhood it will actually
slow down most workloads if you have a CPU with more than two cores.

ok deraadt@

&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 21:04:59 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mereel</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.mail-archive.com/source-changes@openbsd.org/msg99141.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Microsoft ports Windows 10, Linux to homegrown “E2” CPU design</title>
<link>https://www.theregister.co.uk/2018/06/18/microsoft_e2_edge_windows_10/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theregister.co.uk/2018/06/18/microsoft_e2_edge_windows_10/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;trailer&quot;&gt;Updated&lt;/strong&gt; Microsoft has ported Windows 10 and Linux to E2, its homegrown processor architecture it has spent years working on mostly in secret.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as the two operating systems, the US giant's researchers say they have also ported Busybox and FreeRTOS, plus a collection of toolkits for developing and building applications for the processor: the standard C/C++ and .NET Core runtime libraries, the Windows kernel debugger, Visual C++ 2017's command line tools, and .NET's just-in-time compiler RyuJIT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has also ported the widely used LLVM C/C++ compiler and debugger, and related C/C++ runtime libraries. The team wanted to demonstrate that programmers do not need to rewrite their software for the experimental chipset, and that instead programs just need to be recompiled – then they are ready to roll on the new technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The design of E2 is a radical departure from the computer chips designed by Intel, Arm, AMD, and others. It uses an instruction set architecture known as explicit data graph execution, aka EDGE which isn't to be confused with Microsoft's Edge browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Register&lt;/em&gt; understands from people familiar with its development that prototype E2 processors exist in the form of FPGAs – chips with reprogrammable circuitry that are typically used during the development of chips. For example, a dual-core implementation on Xilinx FPGAs exists, clocked at 50MHz. The team has also developed a cycle-accurate simulator capable of booting Windows and Linux, and running applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Qualcomm researchers were evaluating two EDGE chip designs with Microsoft: a small R0 core, and an R1 core running up to 2GHz fabricated using a 10nm process. The project, we must stress, is very much a work in progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;crosshead&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Join the queue&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the outside, a typical mainstream processor appears to operate like, let's say, a garbage recycling machine with a single conveyor belt going into it: trash is fed, piece by piece, into the jaws of the iron beast to consume. Inside, there is a robot that sorts the waste into groups and sends them down their own separate conveyor belts to be processed by different parts of the machine. One belt will take plastics, another glass, another food, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today's computer, server, and smartphone processors do the same but with software instructions. Take, for example, the &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theregister.co.uk/2018/05/31/arm_cortex_a76/&quot;&gt;Arm Cortex-A76&lt;/a&gt;, which splits fetched instructions into eight conveyor belts that go into the rest of the core: four for integer math operations, two for floating point math, and two for accessing data in memory. The frontend of the core tries to place instructions on the belts so there's always something being processed along each of these lanes, even if it means executing the code out of order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You want to avoid situations where, for example, one of the integer math units is sitting there without anything to do while work is queuing in other lanes: it's a waste of resources. And if an instruction in one lane relies on the output of an instruction behind it in another lane, then processing will be held up. All these logistics are scheduled and resolved a billion times a second. The processors get the job done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, there may be a better way: the EDGE way, as used in the E2. It works by breaking up programs into blocks of simple instructions that can be safely executed together as atomic transactions without data dependencies holding up processing. Within the block, the code uses its own private registers, avoiding having to access a global core-wide register file. The code is also annotated by the compiler to describe the flow of data through the program, allowing the CPU to schedule instruction blocks accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, crucially, with many small execution units within a core processing these blocks, many instructions can be executed at once. Rather than eight conveyor belts as in the Cortex-A76, imagine 32 or more, as is the case with the aforementioned Qualcomm R1 design. The R1 is a 32-instruction-wide out-of-order processor blueprint, and the R0 is eight-wide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the aim of this super-RISC approach is to run software faster than rival architectures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;crosshead&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;History&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has been quietly working on EDGE processors since roughly 2010 in its research labs. The technology started life, though, in the early 2000s at the University of Texas at Austin, in the US, as TRIPS – the Tera-op, Reliable, Intelligently adaptive Processing System. The Tera-Op refers to the goal of producing a 1 TFLOPS processor, one that could achieve one trillion floating-point math operations per second. Back then, that was a lot of speed, however, today's graphics processors and specialist hardware accelerators can run faster than that. Only now are top-end general purpose CPUs for your computer approaching or exceeding the TFLOPS barrier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The TRIPS project managed to produce and demonstrate an &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.cs.utexas.edu/~trips/prototype.html&quot;&gt;ambitious prototype chip&lt;/a&gt; before the research effort wound down by the end of the decade. Knowhow, experience, and architectural ideas from TRIPS made their way into Microsoft's R&amp;amp;D labs, and were distilled into what is now the E2 project, which aims to outpace today's Intel and Arm cores using its novel design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;crosshead&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;And now&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although E2 development has been ongoing for several years, three things happened this month that are significant. First, the team revealed Windows 10 has been ported to the architecture along with a hefty amount of support materials for application developers, allowing them to build apps for the platform. In October 2017, the researchers said they were able to get Linux booting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, it emerged that US chip design giant Qualcomm was collaborating with Microsoft. Third, Microsoft's website doesn't have a lot of information about E2 – and what was online now isn't. Last week, it curiously &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20160428161757/http://research.microsoft.com:80/en-us/projects/e2&quot;&gt;removed this page&lt;/a&gt; about the work, leaving the URL to redirect to an unrelated project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this year's International Symposium on Computer Architecture, held this month in California, Microsoft researchers Doug Burger and Aaron Smith, and Greg Wright, Qualcomm's senior director of engineering in its processor research division, went on stage to talk about their EDGE work, and demonstrate Windows running on an E2 simulator. Burger co-led the TRIPS project, and supervised Smith in his PhD work on building software for the CPU design, at the University of Texas in Austin. Now both are at Microsoft Research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet tw-align-center&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot; readability=&quot;4.1506849315068&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Aaron Smith demonstrates Linux and Windows running on an EDGE architecture. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/isca18?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#isca18&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/65DuhdhTgQ&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/65DuhdhTgQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
— SIGARCH (@sigarch) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/sigarch/status/1004395534281396225?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 6, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smith, on his LinkedIn page, noted, as a principal research manager, the extent of his E2 efforts: &quot;I started and lead the E2 project at Microsoft Research which is investigating next-generation EDGE architectures. I grew the project from a one person team to dozens of engineers spanning multiple divisions, companies and countries.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The instruction set for E2 was finalized a couple of years ago, we're told, and is mostly secret for now. However, we do know that each block of code starts with reading in data from the global registers to temporary private registers, then processes that data, and finally writes the result back to the global registers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has form in designing chips: for example, the &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theregister.co.uk/2016/08/22/microsoft_hololens_hpu/&quot;&gt;math accelerator&lt;/a&gt; in its HoloLens virtual reality goggles. It also works on an awful lot of private research, with some projects making their way into commercial products – such as &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theregister.co.uk/2016/11/18/microsoft_running_windows_apps_on_linux/&quot;&gt;Drawbridge&lt;/a&gt; into SQL Server on Linux – whereas some forever remain lab experiments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is speculated this E2 design may be best suited for implementing &quot;soft&quot; processors in FPGAs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spokespeople for Microsoft and Qualcomm declined to comment. ®&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;crosshead&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Updated to add&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After publication, a spokeswoman for Microsoft got back to us with some extra details. &quot;E2 is currently a research project, and there are currently no plans to productize it,&quot; she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;E2 has been a research project where we did a bunch of engineering to understand whether this type of architecture could actually run a real stack, and we have wound down the Qualcomm partnership since the research questions have been answered.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the missing webpage, she added: &quot;Given much of the research work has wound down, we decided to take down the web page to minimize assumptions that this research would be in conflict with our existing silicon partners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;We expect to be able to incorporate learnings from the work into our ongoing research.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;boxout&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;crosshead&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Further reading and references&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wptl btm&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Sponsored:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://go.theregister.co.uk/tl/1757/shttp://www.mcubed.london/&quot;&gt;Minds Mastering Machines - Call for papers now open&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 19:49:48 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>cpeterso</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://regmedia.co.uk/2018/06/18/shutterstock_circuit_board.jpg?x=1200&amp;y=794</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.theregister.co.uk/2018/06/18/microsoft_e2_edge_windows_10/</og:url>
<og:title>Now Microsoft ports Windows 10, Linux to homegrown CPU design</og:title>
<og:description>MSR's E2 processor EDGEs into public view... with a little help from Qualcomm, too</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theregister.co.uk/2018/06/18/microsoft_e2_edge_windows_10/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Facebook ordered to explain deleted profile</title>
<link>https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-44537048</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-44537048</guid>
<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption full-width lead&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                &lt;img class=&quot;js-image-replace&quot; alt=&quot;Azra Sabados and Mirza Krupalija&quot; src=&quot;https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/320/cpsprodpb/C699/production/_102114805_627b101f-dbab-4b4a-b1f2-df245674f9c9.jpg&quot; width=&quot;976&quot; height=&quot;549&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;Azra Sabados&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body__introduction&quot;&gt;Facebook has been ordered by a UK high court judge to reveal who told it to delete the profile of a jazz musician and his band, six months after he died.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Times reports that the firm said it had acted on a request but had declined to reveal to the family who had instructed it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mirza Krupalija's partner Azra Sabados says she is certain that it was not a family member or friend.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She said losing his posts and messages felt like losing him &quot;a second time&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr Krupalija, who lived in Sarajevo, suffered a fatal heart attack just after his 57th birthday in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;It's that feeling, you lose someone you love and you try to hang onto everything, and then something happens and you can't explain that either and nobody knows, none of the friends, none of the family,&quot; Ms Sabados told the BBC.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Lots of Mirza's profile included me and our travels, our photos, music he shared, some for me, some for friends, his profile stated that he was in a relationship with me - they could have dropped me an email to check [before deleting it].&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ms Sabados said she spent a year talking to Facebook before pursuing legal action.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Facebook declined to comment. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ms Sabados' lawyer Greg Callus from the law firm 5BR confirmed to the BBC that Facebook is now required to provide the details under what is legally known as a Norwich Pharmacal Order - where Facebook is innocent but may have information about a third party who could be involved in wrongdoing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The firm will have 21 days to respond.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;The judgement was amazing,&quot; Ms Sabados said. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;It meant so much to me that in court the judge agreed that what was done was wrongdoing, it wasn't right, it wasn't fair, it caused a lot of distress.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;We want Facebook to say exactly what their process is when they receive such a request - behind that profile was a human being and there are lots of people affected, a circle of friends who love that person.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ms Sabados and her friend Ognjen Savija launched &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.change.org/p/facebook-save-mirza-krupalija-facebook-profile-right-to-remember&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link-external&quot;&gt;an online petition&lt;/a&gt; two years ago calling on the firm to restore Mr Krupalija's profile and private messages. It has had over 850 signatures.&lt;/p&gt;
            </description>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 19:17:29 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mikece</dc:creator>
<og:title>Facebook ordered to explain deleted profile</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>The social network has been ordered by a UK judge to reveal who told it to delete the profile of a jazz musician</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-44537048</og:url>
<og:image>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/C699/production/_102114805_627b101f-dbab-4b4a-b1f2-df245674f9c9.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-44537048</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Qt for WebAssembly</title>
<link>http://blog.qt.io/blog/2018/05/22/qt-for-webassembly/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://blog.qt.io/blog/2018/05/22/qt-for-webassembly/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;You may have seen the news that Qt Project released&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.qt.io/blog/2018/04/23/beta-qt-webassembly-technology-preview/&quot;&gt;Qt for WebAssembly tech preview&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We use&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://kripken.github.io/emscripten-site/docs/introducing_emscripten/index.html&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Emscripten&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;to compile Qt into something that runs in a web browser from a web&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;server. Instead of compiling and deploying for multiple platforms, the idea is to compile and &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;deploy on a web server for any platform that has a browser that supports WebAssembly. If&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;you are an enterprise and have multiple clients that have various platforms in use, you could use Qt for WebAssembly to compile your Qt or Quick app and deploy once.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Qt for WebAssembly build instructions are listed on&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.qt.io/Qt_for_WebAssembly&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Qt for WebAssembly wiki&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;You will first need to download and setup the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://kripken.github.io/emscripten-site/docs/getting_started/downloads.html&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;emsdk compiler&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. It’s fairly trivial to do. We use this as the cross-compiler.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Developing/Debugging&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Debugging is a bit arcane as there is no gdb, but there are output statements (&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;std::cout, qDebug and printf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;) as well as the debugger console in the browser.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;You might also have to increase the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;Web console log limit with (Firefox) “devtools.hud.loglimit.console” from about:config.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To set a breakpoint, add&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;EM_ASM({ debugger });  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;into your code to popup the browser debugger. (Don’t forget to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;#include&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&amp;amp;lt;emscripten.h&amp;amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;The downside is that you need to recompile.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Screenshots&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Not everything works perfectly, but here are some screenshots of a few working examples:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;collidingmice:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone wp-image-51054&quot; src=&quot;https://qt-blog-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/collidingmice-Qt-for-WebAssembly-example.png&quot; alt=&quot;collidingmice-qt-for-webassembly-example&quot; width=&quot;374&quot; height=&quot;266&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Standarddialogs: showing multiple windows&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone wp-image-51055&quot; src=&quot;https://qt-blog-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Standarddialogs-Qt-for-WebAssembly-example.png&quot; alt=&quot;standarddialogs-qt-for-webassembly-example&quot; width=&quot;365&quot; height=&quot;350&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;QOpenGLWindow works and seems to get near 60 fps. Although they are ‘full screen’ windows currently, which means they will take up the full browser window. QOpenGLWidget still has some issues. Some shaders seem to have some issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emscripten translates OpenGL calls in WegGL, so there are limitations from the desktop and embedded versions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Openglwindow:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone wp-image-51056&quot; src=&quot;https://qt-blog-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Openglwindow-Qt-for-WebAssembly-example.png&quot; alt=&quot;openglwindow-qt-for-webassembly-example&quot; width=&quot;433&quot; height=&quot;368&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides QtBase and QtDeclarative that use the ‘wip/webassembly’ branch, Qt modules &lt;span&gt;known to work are:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;QtCharts&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;QtGraphicalEffects&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;QtQuickControls&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;QtQuickControls2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;QtWebSockets&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;QtMqtt (using WebSocketIODevice from the websockets example)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;To use QtMqtt, you will need to integrate the WebSocketIODevice class from the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;websocketsubscription example in QtMqtt into your app.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;There is also a WIP MR for a backend to QtSensors for orientation changes on &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;mobiles (including laptops) that I have thrown together which compiles, but hasn’t been tested.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Qml clocks:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-51061 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://qt-blog-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Screen-Shot-2018-05-18-at-15.50.05.png&quot; alt=&quot;screen-shot-2018-05-18-at-15-50-05&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;600&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Since javascript and webassembly have only one thread, QtDeclarative was made &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;to work with only one thread.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;textinsgnode:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-51063 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://qt-blog-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Screen-Shot-2018-05-18-at-15.53.30-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;screen-shot-2018-05-18-at-15-53-30&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;600&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;QtCharts, QtGraphicalEffects, QtQuickcontrols, QtQuickControls2 all work without changes.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;QtCharts oscilloscope:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-51064 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://qt-blog-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Screen-Shot-2018-05-18-at-15.55.45.png&quot; alt=&quot;screen-shot-2018-05-18-at-15-55-45&quot; width=&quot;601&quot; height=&quot;601&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;IoT sensor demo showing demo data&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-51065 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://qt-blog-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Screen-Shot-2018-05-18-at-15.56.05.png&quot; alt=&quot;screen-shot-2018-05-18-at-15-56-05&quot; width=&quot;602&quot; height=&quot;441&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;There is a WIP merge request for clipboard support, but it is unfinished at this time. It is working&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;for simple text.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Things that don’t work&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugreports.qt.io/browse/QTBUG-63917&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QTBUG-63917&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Multithreading&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugreports.qt.io/browse/QTBUG-64700&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;QTBUG-64700&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;there is a stub QThread&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;disabled in the browsers due to the Spectre vulnerability&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Most QNetwork&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugreports.qt.io/browse/QTBUG-63920&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;QTBUG-63920&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;no DNS lookups due to javascript sandbox&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;simple QNAM requests should work.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Local Filesystem access&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugreports.qt.io/browse/QTBUG-67834&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;QTBUG-67834&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;persistent QSettings, it syncs the config rather slow and asynchronously&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugreports.qt.io/browse/QTBUG-63923&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;QTBUG-63923&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;QOpenGLWIdget&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugreports.qt.io/browse/QTBUG-66944&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;QTBUG-66944&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Opengl only works fullscreen&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugreports.qt.io/browse/QTBUG-67717&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;QTBUG-67717&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;some shaders&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugreports.qt.io/browse/QTBUG-67338&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;QTBUG-67338&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;QResource fails to find shaders built-in to Qt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;The exec loop does not function like other platforms&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugreports.qt.io/browse/QTBUG-64020&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;QTBUG-64020&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;exec() event loop will not return where you expect it to&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Returning values from modal dialogs are known not to work but can be worked around by using non-modal signals and show(). Although modal dialogs/windows will still open.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;toUpperCase&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugreports.qt.io/browse/QTBUG-66621&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;QTBUG-66621&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;QClipboard&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bugreports.qt.io/browse/QTBUG-64638&quot;&gt;QTBUG-64638&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Examples&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;ssba ssba-wrap&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;Do you like this? Share it&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a data-site=&quot;linkedin&quot; class=&quot;ssba_linkedin_share ssba_share_link&quot; href=&quot;http://www.linkedin.com/shareArticle?mini=true&amp;amp;url=http://blog.qt.io/blog/2018/05/22/qt-for-webassembly/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://qt-blog-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/qt_linkedin.png&quot; alt=&quot;Share on LinkedIn&quot; title=&quot;LinkedIn&quot; class=&quot;ssba ssba-img&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a data-site=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;ssba_google_share&quot; href=&quot;https://plus.google.com/share?url=http://blog.qt.io/blog/2018/05/22/qt-for-webassembly/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://qt-blog-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/qt_googleplus.png&quot; title=&quot;Share on Google+&quot; class=&quot;ssba ssba-img&quot; alt=&quot;Google+&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a data-site=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;ssba_facebook_share&quot; href=&quot;http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://blog.qt.io/blog/2018/05/22/qt-for-webassembly/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://qt-blog-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/qt_facebook.png&quot; title=&quot;Facebook&quot; class=&quot;ssba ssba-img&quot; alt=&quot;Share on Facebook&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a data-site=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;ssba_twitter_share&quot; href=&quot;http://twitter.com/share?url=http://blog.qt.io/blog/2018/05/22/qt-for-webassembly/&amp;amp;text=Qt+for+WebAssembly+&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://qt-blog-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/qt_twitter.png&quot; title=&quot;Twitter&quot; class=&quot;ssba ssba-img&quot; alt=&quot;Tweet about this on Twitter&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 18:33:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>anhack</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Qt for WebAssembly - Qt Blog</og:title>
<og:description>You may have seen the news that Qt Project released Qt for WebAssembly tech preview. We use Emscripten to compile Qt into something that runs in a web browser from a web server. Instead of compiling and deploying for multiple platforms, the idea is to compile and deploy on a web server for any platform that has …</og:description>
<og:url>http://blog.qt.io/blog/2018/05/22/qt-for-webassembly/</og:url>
<og:image>https://qt-blog-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/collidingmice-Qt-for-WebAssembly-example.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://blog.qt.io/blog/2018/05/22/qt-for-webassembly/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Behind the Tech with John Carmack: 5k Immersive Video</title>
<link>https://developer.oculus.com/blog/behind-the-tech-with-john-carmack-5k-immersive-video/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://developer.oculus.com/blog/behind-the-tech-with-john-carmack-5k-immersive-video/</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;_p-7 _p-9 _p-b&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Today, video decoders are constrained by a number of limitations, including display resolution, FOV, and compression. In an effort to bring full 360 degree, 60 fps stereo to immersive video, Oculus CTO John Carmack has implemented a new technique for video encoding that can unlock a greater level of quality and visual clarity from existing high quality 360 captures. The following post from John provides more information on this technology and the making of its sample video: a 5k re-release of the award-winning&lt;/em&gt; Henry&lt;em&gt;, from Oculus Story Studio for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oculus.com/experiences/go/2084588764916379/&quot;&gt;Oculus Go&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oculus.com/experiences/gear-vr/2084588764916379/&quot;&gt;Gear VR&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_p-7 _p-9 _p-b&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Developers interested in testing this experimental tool and source player with their existing 360 content can visit the Oculus Developer Center to &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.oculus.com/downloads/package/vr5kplayer/&quot;&gt;download the SDK sample.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;_3fwr _4tae&quot;/&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;_2e90 _2e92 _2e95&quot;&gt;Video Limits&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_p-7 _p-9 _p-b&quot;&gt;Playing traditional “flat” video in VR is generally limited by the resolution of the display — a 1280x720 video is already slightly beyond the resolution of the display, at least at the edges, unless you have an enormous curved virtual screen. We need higher resolution screens to get any advantage from 1080 HD content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_p-7 _p-9 _p-b&quot;&gt;Immersive video is another matter. To play a 360 degree, 60 frames per second, stereo video, you need much more resolution than the video decoders can currently provide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_p-7 _p-9 _p-b&quot;&gt;There isn’t a precise number for the angular resolution of the displays because the viewing optics make it non-uniform, but 5120 pixels across 360 degrees is a good approximation. Anyone over this on current VR headsets is simply wasting resources and inviting aliasing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_p-7 _p-9 _p-b&quot;&gt;The most common representation for immersive videos is the “equirectangular” or “equirect” projection, where a sphere is mapped onto a rectangle twice as wide as it is high. This is an inefficient use of pixels at the poles, and other projections like barrels or inflated cubes can provide some savings, but they are in the tens of percents, not integral factors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_p-7 _p-9 _p-b&quot;&gt;For stereo, you want this for each eye, so the total desired video is 5120 x 5120 at 60 fps, or 1500 M pixels per second.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_p-7 _p-9 _p-b&quot;&gt;When Gear VR debuted on the Note 4, you could decode 3840x2160 video at 30 fps, or 240 Mpps. If you stretched that around a full 360 the resolution looked decent, but motion wasn’t smooth, and it didn’t have any depth. If you wanted 60 fps and stereo, you got one quarter the resolution, which was objectionably blurry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_p-7 _p-9 _p-b&quot;&gt;With the Galaxy S7 generation, video decoders doubled in performance to 4k60, or 480 Mpps, which is where we still are on Oculus Go and the latest Samsung phones. This is still only 1/3 of what we would like&lt;del&gt;.&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_p-7 _p-9 _p-b&quot;&gt;If you are willing to sacrifice on any one of the axes — be 180 degrees instead of 360, be 30 fps instead of 60 fps, or be mono instead of stereo, then you are only off by 50%, which really isn’t too bad. If you sacrifice on two axes, you can achieve the peak display quality with margin to spare — 180 degree, 30 fps stereo video is the most straightforward way to do that. Most cameras and workflows will still not be delivering optimal quality pixels, but it is possible with care, or with computer-generated imagery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_p-7 _p-9 _p-b&quot;&gt;If you want to achieve full stereo, you need to somehow only decode the parts of the video that are important to the current view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;_2e90 _2e92 _2e95&quot;&gt;View-Dependent Videos&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_p-7 _p-9 _p-b&quot;&gt;Today’s VR headsets have roughly a 90-degree field of view, so your view is only about one-sixth if the entire sphere. if you were at the center of a cube, looking exactly at the middle of a face, the other five faces would not be visible at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_p-7 _p-9 _p-b&quot;&gt;Our video decoder can decode 1/3 of the world, and we only actually need 1/6 of it, so that should be plenty of margin to work with, but there are still a lot of challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_p-7 _p-9 _p-b&quot;&gt;Because of the way video compression works, you can’t just decode arbitrary little pieces of it. Sequences of video are broken up into “groups of pictures” or “gops”, and you can only start decoding at those boundaries, where the complete picture, or “key frame,” is present. The remaining frames are predicted from earlier frames, which lets them be much, much smaller. Most video-on-demand systems use gops of three to five seconds to get a good compression ratio. With one second gops, the key frames will take up about 25% of the file size. With half second gops, basically, half the file is key frames.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_p-7 _p-9 _p-b&quot;&gt;Because you can’t instantly change what you are decoding, you need to have some lower fidelity encoding of the entire 360-degree view always available, because you can easily flip your head 90 degrees to the side in a couple hundred milliseconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_p-7 _p-9 _p-b&quot;&gt;Our earliest view dependent approach was to make twenty separate versions of the video, each one focusing on the detail in a different place. Initially a “pyramid projection” was used, then it migrated to an “offset cube map”. All these versions were stored on the servers, and the VR client switched between them as you looked around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_p-7 _p-9 _p-b&quot;&gt;The gops were one second, but the additional overhead of going through the internet to traditional web servers made the switching delay even longer, and pretty much everyone noticed it — you would look to the side and everything would be blurry for sometimes two seconds or more before getting sharp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_p-7 _p-9 _p-b&quot;&gt;Building 20 different versions of each video was problematic, and it was impractical to have them all on a device so that you could play locally instead of streaming from a server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_p-7 _p-9 _p-b&quot;&gt;Something that was also not appreciated was that any resampling inevitably degrades the image quality. If you get a master video delivered as an equirect, turning it into a cube map lowered the quality even if it theoretically had the exact same pixel density.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;_2e90 _2e92 _2e95&quot;&gt;The New Scheme&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;_3zn8&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img&quot; src=&quot;https://scontent.fphx1-2.fna.fbcdn.net/v/t39.2365-6/35366195_844539999090227_3942804437566750720_n.png?_nc_cat=0&amp;amp;oh=fe0b8dfefbb44daa8ce4d25a4b384727&amp;amp;oe=5BAC82F6&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Left: 5k x 5k Master, Top Right: 2k x 2k Base, Bottom Right: 10 x 2k x 512 Strips&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_p-7 _p-9 _p-b&quot;&gt;The key compromise in the current scheme is to accept lower resolution at the top and bottom of the sphere. I justify this in several ways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;_3e2_ _1ewa _1g4e&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Most people don’t look very far up or down when watching 360 video. Of course, you can follow this a little farther and say they don’t look left and right all that much either, and you wind up with the strong argument for 180 video, but 360 is still an incremental value.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The down direction is often blacked out to hide the camera rig.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For 3D 360 videos, directors are strongly urged to keep people from looking up or down, because the stereo 3D effect has to be ramped down before you can see the poles and have your eyes try to go backward.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The uneven equirect projection at the poles can still give you some “extra” resolution, at least in one axis, so the bug becomes sort of a feature.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;_p-7 _p-9 _p-b&quot;&gt;Still, it is a compromise, and some videos won’t work well in this format. An obvious example would be putting crisp text on the ceiling or floor. In exchange, we get a situation where view dependency in just the yaw angle is sufficient, which allows a system with minimal data duplication, so it can work on local devices instead of just massive servers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_p-7 _p-9 _p-b&quot;&gt;As a base layer, the entire 5k master is resampled to a 2k x 2k version that is always available, so even if you spin around 180 degrees in a split second, there will always be something sensible to see. If you look at the ceiling or floor, this version is all that you will see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_p-7 _p-9 _p-b&quot;&gt;The key center regions are cropped directly out of the 5k x 5k master, pixel for pixel with no resampling. These are split into ten independent video files, a 512 x 1024 pixel column from each eye, stacked and transposed to make 2048 x 512 video strips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_p-7 _p-9 _p-b&quot;&gt;The total file size is roughly what a traditional 5k x 5k encoding would be because skipping the poles balances out the extra gop keyframes and extra low detail copy of the middle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_p-7 _p-9 _p-b&quot;&gt;The playback engine simultaneously decodes four video streams – the background and the three strips centered in your current view. As you look around, the three strips switch sources at each gop transition point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_p-7 _p-9 _p-b&quot;&gt;We know users don’t like to download huge apps, so there is a strong tension between quality and size. Henry is encoded with H264 at a CRF 22 quality level with half-second gops. If I were making an encoding to be preloaded onto a headset for a film festival or location-based platform where I didn’t care about download size, I would use CRF 18 and possibly quarter second gops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_p-7 _p-9 _p-b&quot;&gt;The current implementation is codec-agnostic, and each of the eleven videos are completely independent. You can use h264, h265, VP9, or probably even MPEG-2 if you felt like it (the current tool only supports h264 and h265). Ideally, I would be decoding four strips at a time instead of three, but there is a painful amount of system software overhead with the video decoders, so this is all I feel comfortable with right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_p-7 _p-9 _p-b&quot;&gt;That leads to the reason the videos are transposed sideways. My as-yet unrealized crafty plan is to do enough bitstream hacking to paste the samples for all the strips together as h264/h265 “slices” in a larger frame, so the video decoder is decoding just one larger video instead of three or four smaller ones. This would be a drastic reduction in overhead, and the strips could then be narrower if desired since I could paste ten+ slices together pretty easily. I haven’t gotten it to work yet, though…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_p-7 _p-9 _p-b&quot;&gt;Henry works out quite well as a demo for this technology, with almost all of the action staying in the high detail band. It still doesn’t represent the absolute quality limit, though – Henry was built within the limitations of real-time rendering a few years ago, and while the capture for 360 video was done at a non-real-time pace, a similar short designed for and rendered with state of the art offline tools could be higher quality (but matching the charm will be tough!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;_p-7 _p-9 _p-b&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: While many multi-camera rigs for capturing live footage may be able to spit out very high-resolution masters, the multiple levels of processing between the sensor and the stitched stereo master may mean that they don’t really produce much value over 4k.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_p-7 _p-9 _p-b&quot;&gt;The “Wow, not blurry!” first impression is the most obvious effect of the new technology, but there are some other subtle things going on that contribute to the presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_p-7 _p-9 _p-b&quot;&gt;To get the resolution to all the right places on the screen, the video pieces are put on VrApi layers, rather than drawn to conventional eye buffers. No matter what resolution you would use, the extra filtering step through eye buffers always has a cost in quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_p-7 _p-9 _p-b&quot;&gt;Directly texture mapping a video in VR gives you linear filtering, not the sRGB filtering you want. With a low-resolution video it doesn’t matter much, but when you have high resolution and high contrast elements like credits text, it makes a big difference – the text shimmers at the edges instead of feeling really solid. Since I have to copy the strips to assemble them into a contiguous range, I take the opportunity to use an sRGB texture as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_p-7 _p-9 _p-b&quot;&gt;Almost all video players let the video frame rate vary to match the time sync on the audio, which results in stutters in the video playback that are especially noticeable at 60 fps. Here, I insist on releasing exactly one video frame for each display frame, and I subtly resample the audio to stay in sync. Henry isn’t the most dramatic demonstration of this, but anything with continuous movement benefits from it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_p-7 _p-9 _p-b&quot;&gt;The Audio 360 spatialized audio is done on-demand in the low latency audio fast path, so it responds much faster than the default implementation, giving no perceptible lag to the audio positioning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_p-7 _p-9 _p-b&quot;&gt;I am very excited at the prospect of unlocking quality that has laid dormant in so many high-end 360 productions made over the last several years that have only been seen at terribly degraded quality – dust off those old studio masters!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 16:57:37 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ot</dc:creator>
<og:title>Behind the Tech with John Carmack: 5k Immersive Video</og:title>
<og:description>The following post from John provides more information on this technology and the making of its sample video: a 5k re-release of the award-winning Henry, from Oculus Story Studios for Oculus Go and Gear Vr.</og:description>
<og:image>https://scontent.fphx1-2.fna.fbcdn.net/v/t39.2365-6/35240271_447596755705542_7385625818036174848_n.png?_nc_cat=0&amp;oh=b207c9fa8cc835bcd8d25e6952122941&amp;oe=5BA6C9A0</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://developer.oculus.com/blog/behind-the-tech-with-john-carmack-5k-immersive-video</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://developer.oculus.com/blog/behind-the-tech-with-john-carmack-5k-immersive-video/?_fb_noscript=1</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>React Native at Airbnb</title>
<link>https://medium.com/airbnb-engineering/react-native-at-airbnb-f95aa460be1c</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://medium.com/airbnb-engineering/react-native-at-airbnb-f95aa460be1c</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;

&lt;h2 name=&quot;4315&quot; id=&quot;4315&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h4 graf-after--h3 graf--subtitle&quot;&gt;In 2016, we took a big bet on React Native. Two years later, we’re ready to share our experience with the world and show what’s next.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;80.695253505933&quot;&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;4c87&quot; id=&quot;4c87&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;This is the first in a series of blog posts in which we outline our experience with React Native and what is next for mobile at Airbnb.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;bfdf&quot; id=&quot;bfdf&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;When Airbnb launched 10 years ago, smartphones were in their infancy. Since then, smartphones have become an essential tool to navigate our everyday lives, especially as more and more people travel around the globe. As a community that enables new forms of travel for millions of people, having a world-class app is crucial. Mobile devices are oftentimes their primary or only form of communication while away from home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;448c&quot; id=&quot;448c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Since our first three guests stayed in Rausch Street in 2008, mobile usage has increased from zero to millions of bookings per year. Our apps give hosts the ability to manage their listings on the go and provide travelers with inspiration to discover new places and experiences right at their fingertips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;60c9&quot; id=&quot;60c9&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;To keep up with the accelerated pace of mobile usage, we’ve grown our team to more than 100 mobile engineers to enable new experiences and improve existing ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;a0ce&quot; id=&quot;a0ce&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Placing a Bet on React Native&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;6f5a&quot; id=&quot;6f5a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;We are continually evaluating new technologies to enable us to improve the experience of using Airbnb for guests and hosts, move quickly, and maintain a great developer experience. In 2016, one of those technologies was React Native. Back then, we recognized how important mobile was becoming to our business but simply didn’t have enough mobile engineers to reach our goals. As a result, we began to explore alternative options. Our website is built primarily with React. It has been a highly effective and universally liked web framework within Airbnb. Because of this, we saw React Native as an opportunity to open up mobile development to more engineers as well as ship code more quickly by leveraging its cross-platform nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;7c50&quot; id=&quot;7c50&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;When we began investing in React Native, we knew that there were risks. We were adding a new, fast-moving and unproven platform to our codebase that had the potential to fragment it instead of unifying it. We also knew that if we were going to invest in React Native, we wanted to do it right. Our goals with React Native were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;postList&quot;&gt;&lt;li name=&quot;032f&quot; id=&quot;032f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Allow us to &lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--li-strong&quot;&gt;move faster&lt;/strong&gt; as an organization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;1304&quot; id=&quot;1304&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;Maintain the &lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--li-strong&quot;&gt;quality bar&lt;/strong&gt; set by native.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;85bd&quot; id=&quot;85bd&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;Write product code &lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--li-strong&quot;&gt;once&lt;/strong&gt; for mobile instead of &lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--li-strong&quot;&gt;twice&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;417a&quot; id=&quot;417a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;Improve upon the &lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--li-strong&quot;&gt;developer experience&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h3 name=&quot;f15c&quot; id=&quot;f15c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--li&quot;&gt;Our Experience&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;0b26&quot; id=&quot;0b26&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;Over the past two years, that experiment turned into a serious effort. We have built an incredibly strong integration into our apps to enable complex native features such as shared element transitions, parallax, and geofencing as well as bridges to our existing native infrastructure such as networking, experimentation, and internationalization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;98c1&quot; id=&quot;98c1&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;We have launched a number of critical products for Airbnb using React Native. React Native enabled us to launch &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.airbnb.com/s/experiences&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.airbnb.com/s/experiences&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Experiences&lt;/a&gt;, an entirely new business for Airbnb, as well as dozens of other features from reviews to gift cards. Many of these features were built at a time where we simply did not have enough native engineers to achieve our goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;be64&quot; id=&quot;be64&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Different teams had a wide range of experiences with React Native. React Native proved to be an incredible tool at times while posing technical and organizational challenges in others. In this series, we provide a detailed account of our experiences with it and what we’re doing next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;adcf&quot; id=&quot;adcf&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/airbnb-engineering/react-native-at-airbnb-the-technology-dafd0b43838&quot; data-href=&quot;https://medium.com/airbnb-engineering/react-native-at-airbnb-the-technology-dafd0b43838&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;In part two&lt;/a&gt;, we enumerate what worked and what didn’t with React Native as a technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;1004&quot; id=&quot;1004&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/airbnb-engineering/building-a-cross-platform-mobile-team-3e1837b40a88&quot; data-href=&quot;https://medium.com/airbnb-engineering/building-a-cross-platform-mobile-team-3e1837b40a88&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;In part three&lt;/a&gt;, we enumerate some of the organizational challenges associated with building a cross-platform mobile team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;2797&quot; id=&quot;2797&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/airbnb-engineering/sunsetting-react-native-1868ba28e30a&quot; data-href=&quot;https://medium.com/airbnb-engineering/sunsetting-react-native-1868ba28e30a&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;In part four&lt;/a&gt;, we highlight where we stand with React Native today and what its future at Airbnb looks like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;3564&quot; id=&quot;3564&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p graf--trailing&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/airbnb-engineering/whats-next-for-mobile-at-airbnb-5e71618576ab&quot; data-href=&quot;https://medium.com/airbnb-engineering/whats-next-for-mobile-at-airbnb-5e71618576ab&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;In part five&lt;/a&gt;, we take our top learnings from React Native and use them to make native even better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 16:44:11 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>msoad</dc:creator>
<og:title>React Native at Airbnb – Airbnb Engineering &amp; Data Science – Medium</og:title>
<og:url>https://medium.com/airbnb-engineering/react-native-at-airbnb-f95aa460be1c</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*P9Kc_EWojKpqfc1-_AhnSg.jpeg</og:image>
<og:description>In 2016, we took a big bet on React Native. Two years later, we’re ready to share our experience with the world and show what’s next.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://medium.com/airbnb-engineering/react-native-at-airbnb-f95aa460be1c</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>