<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Teenager facing prison for downloading unsecured files from government website</title>
<link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/nova-scotia/freedom-of-information-request-privacy-breach-teen-speaks-out-1.4621970</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/nova-scotia/freedom-of-information-request-privacy-breach-teen-speaks-out-1.4621970</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The 19-year-old facing a criminal charge for downloading files from Nova Scotia's freedom-of-information portal sits in a sofa in his parent's living room in Halifax.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;His bedroom is upstairs. That's where police found him sleeping when 15 officers raided the family home last Wednesday morning.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;His demeanour is polite, almost meek. When he speaks, his voice is quiet. He could easily pass for younger than 19.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;Computers have been a part of me for a very long time,&quot; he said.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The teen has been charged with &quot;unauthorized use of a computer,&quot; which carries a possible 10-year prison sentence, for downloading approximately 7,000 freedom-of-information releases.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The provincial government says about 250 of those contain Nova Scotians' sensitive personal information.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;placeholder&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;64.03&quot; class=&quot;imageEl storyImage loaded lazyImage smallImage&quot; src=&quot;https://i.cbc.ca/1.4619266.1523654694!/cpImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_1180/ns-infrastructure-funding-20180410.jpg?imwidth=100&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;leadimage-caption&quot;&gt;On Friday, Nova Scotia Premier Stephen McNeil said the person who downloaded the documents 'stole' the information. (Canadian Press)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The government has faced continued questions since it announced the privacy breach last week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Friday, the premier accused the teenager of &quot;stealing&quot; the information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in an interview with CBC News, the 19-year-old says he thought he was downloading an archive of public information that was supposed to be freely available on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Anonymity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The teenager has not been formally arraigned on the single charge, so his name is not yet public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the family's request, CBC News is granting him anonymity because of his hope the charge will be dropped and his reputation preserved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I don't know if I'll be able to get a job if this gets on my record.… I don't know what my future will be like,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Early talent&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the teenager's earliest memories involve playing with MS Paint on the family computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When he was around eight, he remembered playing around with the HTML of the Google search page, making the coloured letters spell out his name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;6.5193370165746&quot;&gt;Around the same time, his Grade 3 class adopted an animal at a shelter, receiving an electronic adoption certificate.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That lead to a discovery on the classroom computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The website had a number at the end, and I was able to change the last digit of the number to a different number and was able to see a certificate for someone else's animal that they adopted,&quot; he said. &quot;I thought that was interesting.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Researching teachers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The teenager's current troubles arose because he used the same trick on Nova Scotia's freedom-of-information portal, downloading about 7,000 freedom-of-information requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He says his interest stemmed from the government's recent labour troubles with teachers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I wanted more transparency on the teachers' dispute,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a few searches for teacher-related releases on the provincial freedom-of-information portal, he didn't find what he was looking for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;A lot of them were just simple questions that people were asking. Like some were information about Syrian refugees. Others were about student grades and stuff like that,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;placeholder&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;56.29&quot; class=&quot;imageEl storyImage loaded lazyImage smallImage&quot; src=&quot;https://i.cbc.ca/1.3521317.1459867899!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_1180/computer-code.jpg?imwidth=100&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;leadimage-caption&quot;&gt;The teen said a single line of code was all it took to get the information. (CBC)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So instead, he decided to download all the files to search later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I decided these are all transparency documents that the government is displaying. I decided to download all of them just to save,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He says it took a single line of code and a few hours of computer time to copy 7,000 freedom-of-information requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I didn't do anything to try to hide myself. I didn't think any of this would be wrong if it's all public information. Since it was public, I thought it was free to just download, to save,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Passion for archiving&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It wasn't the first website the 19-year-old had saved for general interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He estimates he has around 30 terabytes of online data on hard drives in his home, the equivalent of &quot;millions&quot; of web pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;5.4&quot;&gt;He usually copies online forums such as 4chan and Reddit, where posts are either quickly erased or can become difficult to locate.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I preserve things, I archive the internet. I have history on my computer, and all of that should be saved and preserved,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His mother vouches for her son's passion for organizing, even cataloguing his late grandfather's VHS collection of home video and recordings off the television.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I don't think he did anything wrong. He's a good boy and he saved stuff.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Police raid&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The family was going through its morning routine last Wednesday when the police banged on the front door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mother says she, her husband, and two of her kids were corralled in the living room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;They read us our rights and told us not to talk,&quot; she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Our daughter, she was really traumatized, really bad — brought her to tears, the way they conducted this,&quot; said the father.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She says at one point there were 15 officers in the home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;People were going into the kitchen, were going into the dining room, going upstairs. They went into the basement. They were [traipsing] through the house, everywhere,&quot; the mother said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;placeholder&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;56.29&quot; class=&quot;imageEl storyImage loaded lazyImage smallImage&quot; src=&quot;https://i.cbc.ca/1.4615046.1523475512!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_1180/supt-jim-perrin-said-police-rarely-charge-people-with-unauthorized-use-of-a-computer.jpg?imwidth=100&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;leadimage-caption&quot;&gt;Supt. Jim Perrin said last week police rarely charge people with unauthorized use of a computer, but that it was the right offence in this case. (CBC)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She says the family is still working through the mess they left behind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;They rifled through everything. They turned over mattresses, they took drawers and emptied out drawers, they went through personal papers, pictures,&quot; she said. &quot;It was totally devastating and traumatic.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She says police seized her son's computers, plus her husband's cellphone and work computers, which has left him unable to do his job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They also seized her younger son's desktop computer, after he was arrested on the street walking to high school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officers took her 13-year-old daughter to question her in a police car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;My little ones are asking, 'Will I be able to get a job because we were arrested?'&quot; she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Next steps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 19-year-old accused says he's been passing his time watching TV and doing paper crosswords because he's not allowed to access the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He's worried he'll lose his academic year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I've been feeling kind of sick the whole past week. Haven't been eating much. Haven't been doing much at all,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;3.4041095890411&quot;&gt;He says this is his first time he's ever been in this kind of trouble.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I have never been in the legal system ever in my life.… This is the first time for me. All this is first, and it's all new, and I don't know what to do.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The teenager says since he was downloading public records off a public website, it all feels unfair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I just had no malicious intent and I shouldn't be charged for this,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 21:56:38 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>eigenvector</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/nova-scotia/freedom-of-information-request-privacy-breach-teen-speaks-out-1.4621970</og:url>
<og:title>Teen charged in Nova Scotia government breach says he had 'no malicious intent' | CBC News</og:title>
<og:image>https://i.cbc.ca/1.2660358.1485899977!/cpImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/16x9_620/privacy-watchdog-20130213.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>The 19-year-old says he believed the documents he plucked from Nova Scotia's Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act web portal were &quot;free to just download.&quot;</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/nova-scotia/freedom-of-information-request-privacy-breach-teen-speaks-out-1.4621970</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>NirSoft Freeware</title>
<link>https://www.nirsoft.net/about_nirsoft_freeware.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nirsoft.net/about_nirsoft_freeware.html</guid>
<description>&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; readability=&quot;52.04381443299&quot;&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;misccaption&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Introduction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;table readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;18&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.nirsoft.net/nir.jpg&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;/&gt; My name is Nir Sofer, and I'm experienced developer with extensive knowledge in C++, .NET Framework, Windows API, and Reverse Engineering of undocumented binary formats and encryption algorithms.&lt;br/&gt;NirSoft is a Web site of one man. In NirSoft, there is no CTO or CEO, there is no secretary, there is no development team, and there are no rented offices. The entire Web site and all the utilities that you can find here were developed by me, and only by me. NirSoft is not a full-time job, but I use all my free time to maintain and develop this Web site. My time for maintaining this Web site is used for adding new tools, adding features to existing utilities, fixing bugs, and answering to emails that I receive (well... at least for some of them).&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;misccaption&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Web Site Name&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
As you probably guessed, the name 'NirSoft' is the combination of my given name - 'Nir' and the prefix of the word 'Software'. However, there is another reason for choosing this name: My full name is 'Nir Sofer', so removing the 'er' letters and adding the 't' letter instead, also gives the same result - NirSoft.
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;misccaption&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;A Little History...&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
NirSoft Web site was originally in created in 2001 as a personal Web site which provided a few utilities that I developed for my own use. In the beginning, NirSoft was hosted in some &quot;free&quot; Web hosting services like Tripod and multiservers.com&lt;br/&gt;Unfortunately, these &quot;free&quot; Web sites produced a fair amount of annoying popup ads and some of them even tried to install unwanted Spywares on the computer of the site visitors. Also, after my site became pretty popular, they disabled my hosting account because I used too much resources on their server.
&lt;p&gt;In August 2004, after suffering from all these free services, I decided to purchase a domain for my site (nirsoft.net) and host it in a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.webhostingsearch.com/&quot; target=&quot;webhostingsearch&quot;&gt;non-free hosting service&lt;/a&gt;, in order make my Web site more reliable, friendly and secured. In the days that I started with nirsoft.net domain, my site was already popular more than an average Web site, with more than 90,000 unique visitors and 1.5 million hits in a month. The most popular utilities in these days were &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nirsoft.net/utils/ipnetinfo.html&quot;&gt;IPNetInfo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nirsoft.net/utils/volumouse.html&quot;&gt;Volumouse&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nirsoft.net/utils/mspass.html&quot;&gt;MessenPass&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nirsoft.net/utils/pspv.html&quot;&gt;Protected Storage PassView&lt;/a&gt;. All these utilities are still very popular even today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the last 4 years, I added more and more utilities to my Web site, and today it contains more than 100 utilities. As I added more utilities, the Web site traffic was also gradually increased, and today (May 2008) NirSoft Web site have more than 850,000 unique visitors and 13.5 million hits in a month.&lt;br/&gt;During these years, I also made some changes in the utilities according the users requests. For example - In the beginning, all utilities saved the settings into a Registry key under HKEY_CURRENT_USER\Software\NirSoft. But after many users complained about the keys that I added to the Registry, I decided to save the settings into a file, and today most of the utilities save the settings into a .cfg file located in the same folder of the .exe file. This means that my utilities can be used directly from a USB Flash Drive, without leaving any traces in the computer itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During these years, I also developed a unique translation system that automatically allows any simple user to easily translate my tools to another language. Today, the most popular utilities have translations to more than 20 languages, all of them were created by volunteers from around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the last year, I also added a 64-bit (x64) build for some of my utilities, and for some other utilities I added separated Unicode download (For good multilingual support) and Non-Unicode download (for Windows 98/ME users). I also fixed most of my utilities to work properly under Windows Vista.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;misccaption&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&quot;False Positive&quot; Issues&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
As my Web site became more popular, a very annoying problem started to appear frequently: &quot;False Positive&quot; alerts in AntiVirus software. This means that AntiVirus/AntiSpyware programs detect my utilities as infected with Virus/Trojan/Spyware while my utilities are clean from any malicious code. Each time that a popular AntiVirus software begins to detect one of my utilities as Virus or Trojan, my email is flooded with messages from worried people that think my Web site is infected with Viruses. Some of them even blame me that I spread Viruses through my Web site. But the truth is that I have never had any Virus/Trojan/Spyware in my tools. All the alerts and warnings displayed by the AntiVirus programs regarding my utilities are simply wrong, and cause a widespread panic without a reason.
&lt;p&gt;Due to the large amount of &quot;False Positive&quot; alerts, I created a special Web page that displays the major &quot;False Positive&quot; problems with NirSoft utilities: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nirsoft.net/false_positive_report.html&quot;&gt;False Positive Reports&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Web page is also message to all Antivirus companies that they must improve the quality and the reliability of their Virus detection mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;misccaption&quot; readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Advantages of NirSoft utilities&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
For almost every utility that you can find here, there is probably others alternative tools with similar functionality. However, NirSoft utilities have some unique advantages over many other freeware and commercial products:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Most of the utilities in this site were developed in C++, which make them fast, small and effective.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My utilities are portable and mostly don't require any installation. While many software companies create a bloated installation package with size of 1 - 3 MB, the size of single utility in NirSoft is usually less than 100KB.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All my utilities (except of a few very old tools) don't write anything to the Registry or to your profile folder. This means that you can use them from a USB Flash drive, without leaving traces in the computer that you use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most of my utilities can be used from command-line, without displaying any user interface.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You don't have to register or give your email in order to download from NirSoft.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My utilities are completely freeware, without any catch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;misccaption&quot; readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Privacy Policy of NirSoft Web site&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;special2&quot;&gt;Personal Information Collected on this Website:&lt;/span&gt; No personally-identifiable information is collected on this website from persons that browse this Web site or from persons that run and use my utilities. The only personally-identifiable information collected on this website is gathered on my &quot;Contact NirSoft&quot; page, where fields are provided so that you can provide your name and email address contact information. This information is sent directly to my email and it only used to respond your comments. You user name/email information is not saved in any database.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;special2&quot;&gt;Anonymous Information Collected on this Website:&lt;/span&gt; Anonymous data is recorded on this Web site. Most of the information collected from this website is anonymous information, such as the pages you visit. Other anonymous data I may collect might include the name of your internet service provider, the website that you used to link to my site, the websites that you visit from our site, and your IP address. The data is only used for statistical purposes, but you, as the individual user, remain anonymous.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;special2&quot;&gt;Cookies:&lt;/span&gt; Cookies are used on this website by Google and other third party advertising companies. Google uses a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/faq.aspx&quot; target=&quot;doubleclick&quot;&gt;DoubleClick DART cookie&lt;/a&gt; to serve ads to you based on visit to this sites and other sites on the Internet. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these Google, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html&quot; target=&quot;privacy_ads&quot;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td width=&quot;10&quot;&gt;  &lt;/td&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 17:44:02 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>valgaze</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nirsoft.net/about_nirsoft_freeware.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Coinbase acquires Earn.com</title>
<link>https://news.earn.com/earn-com-joins-coinbase-a282a36411d2</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.earn.com/earn-com-joins-coinbase-a282a36411d2</guid>
<description>&lt;p name=&quot;a43b&quot; id=&quot;a43b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;Paid email is already one of the first truly useful applications of the blockchain. With Coinbase, we think we can prove that at scale.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*cw-BdhvEfMUjE_FbdNITHA.png&quot; data-width=&quot;800&quot; data-height=&quot;400&quot; data-is-featured=&quot;true&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*cw-BdhvEfMUjE_FbdNITHA.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*cw-BdhvEfMUjE_FbdNITHA.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;e249&quot; id=&quot;e249&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;As of today, Earn.com is being acquired by Coinbase! The Earn.com product is going to get bigger and better as a consequence of this deal. You can read more about the acquisition &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.coinbase.com/welcome-balaji-srinivasan-coinbases-new-chief-technology-officer-e746503d7ab6&quot; data-href=&quot;https://blog.coinbase.com/welcome-balaji-srinivasan-coinbases-new-chief-technology-officer-e746503d7ab6&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and the history of the company &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@balajis/the-turnaround-2d145589d814&quot; data-href=&quot;https://medium.com/@balajis/the-turnaround-2d145589d814&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. In this post, we want to first briefly introduce Earn.com for new audiences and then explain what this means for our existing users and senders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;d83c&quot; id=&quot;d83c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Earn.com at a glance&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;11c0&quot; id=&quot;11c0&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;Earn.com allows senders to pay users in digital currency for replying to emails and completing tasks. Relative to the status quo, the introduction of payments benefits both normal email users and large-scale senders of commercial emails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*-9BWSCcg6jZ6_81B_wHhIQ.gif&quot; data-width=&quot;350&quot; data-height=&quot;560&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*-9BWSCcg6jZ6_81B_wHhIQ.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Earn.com users complete tasks on web and mobile to earn crypto.
&lt;p name=&quot;f878&quot; id=&quot;f878&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;If you’re a normal email user, you can now earn money in your free time simply by replying to emails. You can keep the money you earn, or donate it to &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.earn.com/profiles/why-should-i-create-an-earncom-profile&quot; data-href=&quot;https://support.earn.com/profiles/why-should-i-create-an-earncom-profile&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;charity&lt;/a&gt; with one click. You can also use the prices of inbound emails as a signal to rank them by importance. And you know immediately what the sender wants from you in a reply, as they’ve made their payment conditional on the completion of a very specific task. Hundreds of thousands of users have earned digital currency with Earn.com so far, earning millions of dollars in their free time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*f59-ApwmRc2QFoIO8ZL7uw.gif&quot; data-width=&quot;375&quot; data-height=&quot;401&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*f59-ApwmRc2QFoIO8ZL7uw.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Senders use Earn.com to create paid email campaigns and surveys.
&lt;p name=&quot;35cb&quot; id=&quot;35cb&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;Conversely, if you’re a sender of commercial email, you can use Earn.com to pay one user or one hundred thousand to get them to quickly reply to important messages. Thousands of senders have sent millions of dollars worth of paid messages through Earn.com for recruiting, fundraising, and marketing their products. Empirically, we find that Earn.com senders get 30–70% response rates within 24 hours for $1–10 incentives, even for messages with many thousands of recipients. This is extraordinarily high relative to the typical &lt;a href=&quot;http://fastcompany.com/3036672/what-we-learned-from-sending-1000-cold-emails&quot; data-href=&quot;http://fastcompany.com/3036672/what-we-learned-from-sending-1000-cold-emails&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;1.7%&lt;/a&gt; response rates for cold emails. As such, any business that sends cold email or conducts surveys can benefit from Earn.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;a02e&quot; id=&quot;a02e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The blockchain is a fundamental enabling technology for Earn.com, because it allows us to accommodate senders and users anywhere in the world. In particular, we can effectively compensate a user in any country with a small amount of money for replying to an email or completing a simple task, even if they lack a bank account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;b8ac&quot; id=&quot;b8ac&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Earn also has many other features, like a &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.earn.com/search-for-users-and-pay-them-to-reply-with-the-new-earn-com-search-8a2ff6fb9b72&quot; data-href=&quot;https://news.earn.com/search-for-users-and-pay-them-to-reply-with-the-new-earn-com-search-8a2ff6fb9b72&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;search engine&lt;/a&gt; where you can find users through their &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.earn.com/get-paid-to-read-email-from-outside-your-network-with-a-21-profile-8a388548a9ef&quot; data-href=&quot;https://news.earn.com/get-paid-to-read-email-from-outside-your-network-with-a-21-profile-8a388548a9ef&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;public profiles&lt;/a&gt; and pay them to reply, &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.earn.com/make-money-online-by-joining-21-co-lists-b90e6d119ab7&quot; data-href=&quot;https://news.earn.com/make-money-online-by-joining-21-co-lists-b90e6d119ab7&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;lists&lt;/a&gt; that users can join to make more money, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.earn.com/monetize-your-gmail-inbox-with-21-co-ec1f9687956d&quot; data-href=&quot;https://news.earn.com/monetize-your-gmail-inbox-with-21-co-ec1f9687956d&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Gmail integration&lt;/a&gt; which allows you to bounce commercial emails sent to your address, and a &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.earn.com/organize-paid-crowdsourcing-with-social-tasks-98fb0713af6c&quot; data-href=&quot;https://news.earn.com/organize-paid-crowdsourcing-with-social-tasks-98fb0713af6c&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;shareable task&lt;/a&gt; feature which allows you to outsource work to your business’s Twitter and Facebook followers. And Earn.com also extends beyond simply replying to emails, because we also allow senders to create surveys, tasks, and multi-stage pipelines that combine more than one digital task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;4e36&quot; id=&quot;4e36&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;For existing Earn.com users and senders&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;4e6e&quot; id=&quot;4e6e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;If you’re an existing Earn.com user or sender, everything will continue as before in the short term, with one exception: we’ve put our token launch on the back burner and will instead focus on integrating with Coinbase’s infrastructure and scaling up our service. You might be able to guess what this will enable, but stay tuned anyway as you might be surprised! Over the next few weeks, as we integrate and ship new features, we will make announcements as we do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;c105&quot; id=&quot;c105&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Buy crypto. And now earn crypto.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;e587&quot; id=&quot;e587&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;Over the last several years, the primary way most people have obtained cryptocurrency is through buying it, with many of these transactions facilitated by Coinbase. With this acquisition, we allow users to also &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;earn&lt;/em&gt; crypto by doing things they already know how to do — like replying to emails and filling out surveys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;b68a&quot; id=&quot;b68a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p graf--trailing&quot;&gt;If we’re successful in our long-term goals, we will be able to turn the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2017/01/17/6-billion-smartphones-will-be-in-circulation-in-2020-ihs-report.html&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2017/01/17/6-billion-smartphones-will-be-in-circulation-in-2020-ihs-report.html&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;billions of smartphones&lt;/a&gt; worldwide into a new source of work. Open the Earn.com app in any country — and receive a personalized, targeted list of paid microtasks and emails just for you. Thanks to the blockchain, anywhere there’s a phone, there’s a job. We think that’s an exciting vision and we’re going to work hard on achieving that at Coinbase!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 16:13:37 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ammaristotle</dc:creator>
<og:title>Earn.com joins Coinbase – news.earn.com</og:title>
<og:url>https://news.earn.com/earn-com-joins-coinbase-a282a36411d2</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*cw-BdhvEfMUjE_FbdNITHA.png</og:image>
<og:description>Paid email is already one of the first truly useful applications of the blockchain. With Coinbase, we think we can prove that at scale.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.earn.com/earn-com-joins-coinbase-a282a36411d2?gi=2cf0be3a2d16</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Amazon warehouse workers &amp;#039;peed in bottles&amp;#039; fearing punishment for taking breaks</title>
<link>http://www.pulse.ng/bi/tech/undercover-author-finds-amazon-warehouse-workers-in-uk-peed-in-bottles-over-fears-of-being-punished-for-taking-a-break-amzn-id8258070.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.pulse.ng/bi/tech/undercover-author-finds-amazon-warehouse-workers-in-uk-peed-in-bottles-over-fears-of-being-punished-for-taking-a-break-amzn-id8258070.html</guid>
<description>&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An undercover author told The Sun that workers at an Amazon warehouse in the UK &quot;peed in bottles&quot; because they were scared walking to a bathroom would cause them to miss targets.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The author, James Bloodworth, found that staff members feared being disciplined for &quot;idle time.&quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A separate survey of Amazon workers released Monday found that some workers who reported feeling sick — even through pregnancy — said they were penalized for not turning up or taking breaks.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amazon said it didn't recognize the allegations as an accurate portrayal of its warehouse working conditions.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The company disputed the survey findings and said it didn't time toilet breaks.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Amazon founder Jeff Bezos may be the world's richest person, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/billionaires/list/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;with a net worth of about $112 billion (£78 billion)&lt;/a&gt;, but at least some of those working on his warehouse floors are apparently so desperate to keep their jobs that they don't even take time to use a restroom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The author James Bloodworth went undercover at an Amazon warehouse in Staffordshire, UK, for a book on low wages in Britain. He found that the warehouse's fulfillment workers, who run around Amazon's massive warehouses gathering products for delivery, had a &quot;toilet bottle&quot; system in place because the bathrooms were too sparse to get to quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;For those of us who worked on the top floor, the closest toilets were down four flights of stairs,&quot; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thesun.co.uk/news/6055021/rushed-amazon-warehouse-staff-time-wasting/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Bloodworth told The Sun&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;People just peed in bottles because they lived in fear of being ­disciplined over 'idle time' and ­losing their jobs just because they needed the loo.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon is known to track how fast its warehouse workers can pick and package items from its shelves, imposing strictly timed breaks and targets. It issues warning points for those who don't meet its goals or who take extended breaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.organise.org.uk/blog/2018/2/9/whats-it-like-working-in-an-amazon-warehouse-the-results&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;separate survey&lt;/a&gt; found almost three-quarters of UK fulfillment-center staff members were afraid of using the toilet because of time concerns. A report released Monday with the survey's findings said 241 Amazon warehouse employees in England were interviewed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The survey anonymously quoted one person as saying targets had &quot;increased dramatically&quot; and &quot;I do not drink water because I do not have time to go to the toilet.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another said: &quot;The target grows every year. I do not have two more legs yet to make the 100% to pick, where you actually need to run and go to the toilet just during the break. Packing 120 products per hour is terribly heavy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;You have to pack two products per minute. You do not have time to drink water because you go to the toilet after every evening sends messages to the scanner with the target and tells you to hurry.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The survey, compiled by the worker campaign platform Organise, also found that respondents said they felt considerably more anxious after joining Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Workers say they have been punished for being sick&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another employee said she was ill while pregnant and was still given a warning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet another said: &quot;I turned up for my shift even though I felt like s---, managed 2 hours then I just could not do anymore. Told my supervisor and was signed off sick, I had a gastric bug (sickness and diarrhoea, very bad) saw my doc. Got a sick note with an explanation, but still got a strike.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon disputed the allegations. The company said in a statement to Business Insider:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Amazon provides a safe and positive workplace for thousands of people across the UK with competitive pay and benefits from day one. We have not been provided with confirmation that the people who completed the survey worked at Amazon and we don't recognize these allegations as an accurate portrayal of activities in our buildings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;We have a focus on ensuring we provide a great environment for all our employees and last month Amazon was named by LinkedIn as the 7th most sought after place to work in the UK and ranked first place in the US. Amazon also offers public tours of its fulfillment centres so customers can see first-hand what happens after they click 'buy' on Amazon.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon said it didn't time workers' toilet breaks and set its performance targets based on previous worker performance. The company said it provided coaching to help people improve and used &quot;proper discretion&quot; when it came to sick leave and absences from work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company also said it provided on-site occupational health and physiotherapy support as well as legal, financial, and workplace guidance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you worked in an Amazon warehouse and would like to share your horror stories, email in confidence to &lt;strong&gt;sghosh@businessinsider.com.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 15:15:09 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>vezycash</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://www.pulse.ng/bi/tech/undercover-author-finds-amazon-warehouse-workers-in-uk-peed-in-bottles-over-fears-of-being-punished-for-taking-a-break-amzn-id8258070.html</og:url>
<og:title>Undercover author finds Amazon warehouse workers in UK &quot;peed in bottles&quot; over fears of being punished for taking a break (AMZN)</og:title>
<og:description>An undercover author and an anonymous survey found that workers believed taking a long break could lead to warnings at an Amazon warehouse.</og:description>
<og:image>https://static.pulse.ng/img/tech/crop8258068/3134672191-chorizontal-w1200-h630/5a2b12b7a3b474c12a8b4bcf-1778jpg.png</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.pulse.ng/bi/tech/undercover-author-finds-amazon-warehouse-workers-in-uk-peed-in-bottles-over-fears-of-being-punished-for-taking-a-break-amzn-id8258070.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>I submitted a PWA to 3 app stores. Here&amp;#039;s what I learned</title>
<link>http://debuggerdotbreak.judahgabriel.com/2018/04/13/i-built-a-pwa-and-published-it-in-3-app-stores-heres-what-i-learned/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://debuggerdotbreak.judahgabriel.com/2018/04/13/i-built-a-pwa-and-published-it-in-3-app-stores-heres-what-i-learned/</guid>
<description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Summary&lt;/span&gt;: Turning a web app into a Progressive Web App (PWA) and submitting it to 3 app stores requires about a month of work, a few hundred dollars, and lots of red tape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently published &lt;a href=&quot;https://messianicradio.com&quot;&gt;Chavah Messianic Radio&lt;/a&gt;, a Pandora-like music player, as a Progressive Web App and submitted it to the 3 app stores (Google Play, iOS App Store, Windows Store).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/chavah-messianic-radio/id1361894819?platform=ipad&amp;amp;preserveScrollPosition=true#platform/ipad&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;717&quot; height=&quot;478&quot; title=&quot;image&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;http://debuggerdotbreak.judahgabriel.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/image.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.messianicradio&amp;amp;hl=en&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;1099&quot; height=&quot;405&quot; title=&quot;image&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;http://debuggerdotbreak.judahgabriel.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/image-1.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/store/p/chavah/9nhkjb6lpptv&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;593&quot; height=&quot;171&quot; title=&quot;image&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;http://debuggerdotbreak.judahgabriel.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/image-4.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process was both painful and enlightening. Here’s what I learned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Why?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, you might wonder, “Why even put your app in the app stores? Just live on the opened web!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer, in a nutshell, is because &lt;strong&gt;that’s where the users are&lt;/strong&gt;. We’ve trained a generation of users to find apps in proprietary app stores, not on the free and open web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my web app, there were 2 big reasons to get in the app store:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;User demand&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Web app restrictions by &lt;strike&gt;Apple&lt;/strike&gt; hostile mobile platforms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;User demand: My users have been asking me for years, “Is there an app for Chavah? I don’t see it in the store.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They ask that because we’ve trained users to look for apps in proprietary app stores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My response to my users has up until now been,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Aww, you don’t need an app – just go to the website on your phone! It works!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I was kind of lying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Real web apps only kinda-sorta work on mobile. Which brings me to the 2nd reason: web app restrictions by &lt;strike&gt;Apple&lt;/strike&gt; hostile mobile platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mobile platform vendors, like Apple, are &lt;em&gt;totally cool&lt;/em&gt; with apps that use your phone to its fullest. Access your location, play background audio, get your GPS coordinates, read all your contacts, play videos or audio without app interaction, read your email, intercept your typing, play more than one thing at a time, use your microphone and camera, access your pictures, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple’s totally cool with that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But only if you pay Apple $99/year for the privilege.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to do any of those things in a regular old web app, well, goshdarnit, Apple won’t just deny you these things, it &lt;em&gt;prevents you from even asking permission&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my Pandora-like music player app, this &lt;a href=&quot;http://debuggerdotbreak.judahgabriel.com/2016/12/13/its-almost-2017-and-html5-audio-is-still-broken-on-ios/&quot;&gt;horrible brokenness showed up in numerous ways&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From minor things like “iOS Safari won’t let you play audio without first interacting with the page” to major, show-stopping things like, “iOS Safari won’t let you play the next song if your app is in the background or if your screen is off.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, plus weird visual anomalies like &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/46339063/ios-11-safari-bootstrap-modal-text-area-outside-of-cursor&quot;&gt;typing in a textbox and seeing your text appear elsewhere on screen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, to make my HTML5 music app actually functional and working on people’s mobile devices, it was necessary to turn my PWA into an app in app store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Barriers to entry&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the ideal world, publishing your web app to the app stores would look like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your Web/Cloud Host or CI Provider&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ve published a Progressive Web App. Publish to app stores?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☑ iOS App Store&lt;br/&gt;☑ Google Play&lt;br/&gt;☑ Windows Store&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Or alternately, as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.windowscentral.com/first-batch-windows-10-progressive-web-apps-here&quot;&gt;Microsoft is experimenting with&lt;/a&gt;, your PWA will just automatically appear in the app store as Bing crawls it.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But alas, we don’t live in this ideal world. Instead, we have to deal with all kinds of proprietary native BS to get our web apps in the stores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each of the app stores has a barrier to entry: how difficult it is to take an existing web app and it in the app store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I list some of the barriers below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Cost&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apple&lt;/strong&gt;: $99/year to have your app listed in the iOS app store.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google:&lt;/strong&gt; One-time $25 fee to list your app in the Google Play Store.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Microsoft:&lt;/strong&gt; Free!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Don’t make me pay you to make my app available to your users. My app enriches your platform. Without good apps, your platform will be abandoned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple used to understand this. When it first introduced the iPhone, Steve Jobs was adamant that HTML5 was the future and that apps will simply just be web apps. &lt;a href=&quot;https://9to5mac.com/2011/10/21/jobs-original-vision-for-the-iphone-no-third-party-native-apps/&quot;&gt;There was no native iPhone SDK&lt;/a&gt; for 3rd parties. Apple has since abandoned this vision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google asked for a token $25 one-time fee. Probably to avoid spammers and decrease truly junk apps from entering the store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft seems determined to just increase the total number of apps in their app store, regardless of quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Winner:&lt;/strong&gt; Microsoft. It’s hard to beat free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Adding native capabilities&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an ideal world, I wouldn’t have to write a single extra line of code for my web app to integrate into the OS. Or, as Steve Jobs &lt;a href=&quot;https://9to5mac.com/2011/10/21/jobs-original-vision-for-the-iphone-no-third-party-native-apps/&quot;&gt;said back in 2007&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The full Safari engine is inside of iPhone. And so, you can write amazing Web 2.0 and Ajax apps that look exactly and behave exactly like apps on the iPhone. And these apps can integrate perfectly with iPhone services. They can make a call, they can send an email, they can look up a location on Google Maps.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-Steve Jobs, 2007&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, that means my web app plays background audio using standard HTML5 audio; that works just fine on all OSes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My web app declares what audio is playing, and the OSes pick up on that, show currently playing song info on the lock screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My app controls audio using standard HTML5 audio API; the OS picks up on that and provides play/pause/next/volume/trackbar controls on the lock screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But sadly, we don’t live in this ideal world. All the things listed above don’t actually work out of the box on all 3 platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My web app needs to play audio in the background. And load URLs from my CDN. Sounds reasonable, right? And bonus, how about showing currently playing song info on the lock screen? And controlling the audio (play/pause/next, etc.) from the lock screen? How hard is this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three very different approaches taken here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apple&lt;/strong&gt;: We don’t give web apps a way to declare such capabilities; you’ll need to write a native wrapper (e.g. with Cordova) to interact with the OS.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google&lt;/strong&gt;: Web FTW! Let’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/web/updates/2017/02/media-session&quot;&gt;create a new web standard&lt;/a&gt; that shows audio &amp;amp; controls from the lock screen. Background audio? Sure, go ahead!&lt;br/&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Microsoft:&lt;/strong&gt; We’ll inject our proprietary API, window.Windows.*, into your JavaScript global namespace and you can use that to do the things you want to do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Going into more details here for each store:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For iOS app store, does your web app need to play background audio? &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/danielsogl/cordova-plugin-background-audio&quot;&gt;Use a Cordova plugin&lt;/a&gt;. Need to show currently playing song on the lock screen? &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leon/cordova-plugin-nowplaying&quot;&gt;Use a Cordova plugin&lt;/a&gt;. Need to control the currently playing song from the lock screen? &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leon/cordova-plugin-remotecommand&quot;&gt;Use a Cordova plugin&lt;/a&gt;. You get the idea. Basically, Cordova tricks Apple into thinking you’re a native app. And since you’re not a yucky web app, Apple lets you do all the things native apps can do. You just need native tricks – Cordova plugins – to let you do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Google Play, it’s nice that I can just write JS code to make this work; no Cordova plugins required here. Of course, that JS won’t work anywhere except Chrome on Android…but hey, maybe one day (in an ideal world!) all the mobile browsers will implement these web APIs…and the world will live as one. I’m almost ready to bust out some John Lennon hippie utopia tunes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Windows Store, do you want to play background audio? Sorry! That is, unless you declare your intentions in our proprietary capabilities manifest file (easy) &lt;em&gt;AND&lt;/em&gt; you implement this proprietary media interface using &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/49240479/enabling-background-audio-in-my-windows-store-html5-app?rq=1&quot;&gt;window.Windows.SystemMediaTransportControls&lt;/a&gt; (not so easy). Otherwise we’ll mute you when your app goes to the background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Winner&lt;/strong&gt;: Google. I want to be able to just write JavaScript, and let the OS pick up cues from my app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Runner-up&lt;/strong&gt;: Windows. I can still write plain old JavaScript, but I need to talk to a proprietary Windows JS API that was injected into my process when running on Windows. Not terrible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loser&lt;/strong&gt;: Apple. They don’t care about web apps. Actually, it’s worse than that. It feels like they are actually &lt;em&gt;hostile&lt;/em&gt; to web apps. iOS Safari is the new Internet Explorer 6. It has lagged behind in nearly every web standard, especially around Progressive Web Apps. This is probably for business reasons: web apps disrupt their $99/year + 33% in-app purchases racket. So to make my web app work on their platform, I have to basically pretend I’m a native app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;App Store Registration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Submitting your PWA to the app store requires registration, business verification, and more red tape. Here’s how the 3 app stores fared:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apple&lt;/strong&gt;: You must prove that you’re a legal, registered business. This verification isn’t done by us – but &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dnb.com/&quot;&gt;by a 3rd party&lt;/a&gt;, which may or may not know about your business.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google&lt;/strong&gt;: You want your app in our store? Cool by us.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Microsoft&lt;/strong&gt;: You want your app in our store? Cool by us.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The biggest pain point for me was getting verified as a legal business by Apple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, I went to the site and registered for Apple’s Developer Program. I filled out my name and company information. (Aside: I guess Apple won’t let you submit an app unless you have a registered, legal company?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I click next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The information you entered did not match your D&amp;amp;B profile.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My…what?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A bit of Googling showed that “D&amp;amp;B profile” is Dun and Bradstreet. I’ve never heard of this group before, but I find out that Apple is using them to verify you legal corporation details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And apparently, my D&amp;amp;B profile didn’t match what I put in my Apple Dev registration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I google some more and find the Apple dev forums littered with similar posts. Nobody had a good answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I contact Apple Dev support. 24 hours later, I’m contacted by email saying that I should contact D&amp;amp;B.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://debuggerdotbreak.judahgabriel.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/image-3.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;663&quot; height=&quot;771&quot; title=&quot;image&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;http://debuggerdotbreak.judahgabriel.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/image_thumb-1.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decide to contact them…but Apple says it will take up to a few days for them to respond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, I’m thinking of abandoning the whole idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While waiting for D&amp;amp;B support to get back to me, I decide to go to the D&amp;amp;B site, verify my identity, and update my company information which, I assume, they had taken from government registration records.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did I mention how sucky this is? I just want to list my existing web app in the store. Plz help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I go to D&amp;amp;B to update my business profile. Surprise! They have a JavaScript bug in their validation logic that prevents me from updating my profile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, I’m a proficient developer. I click put a breakpoint in their JavaScript, click submit, change the isValid flag to true, and voila! I’ve updated my D&amp;amp;B profile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back to Apple Dev –&amp;gt; let’s try this again. Register my company…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Error: The information you entered did not match your D&amp;amp;B profile.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AREYOUFREAKINKIDDINGME.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talk to Apple again. “Oh, it may take 24-48 hours for the updated D&amp;amp;B information to get into our system.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know, because digital information can take 2 days to travel from server A to server B. Sigh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two days later, I try to register…finally it works! Now I’m in the Apple Developer program and can submit apps for review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Winner&lt;/strong&gt;: Google and Microsoft; both took all of 5 minutes to register.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loser&lt;/strong&gt;: The Apple Developer registration was slow and painful. It took about a week to actually get registered with their developer program. It required me contacting support from 2 different freaking companies. And it required me to &lt;em&gt;runtime debug the JavaScript code on a 3rd party website&lt;/em&gt; just so that I can get past their buggy client-side validation, so that my info will flow to Apple, so that I can submit my app to the store. Wow, just…wow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there is any saving grace here for Apple, it’s that they have a 501c3 non-profit program, where non-profits can have their $99 annual fee waived. I took advantage of that. And perhaps this extra step complicated matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;App Packaging, Building, Submitting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you have a web app, you have to run some magic on it to turn it into something you can submit for App Store review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apple&lt;/strong&gt;: First, buy a Mac; you can’t build an iOS app without a Mac. Install XCode and these build tools and frameworks, acquire a certificate from our developer program, create a profile on a separate website called iTunes Connect, link it up with the certificate you generated on the Apple Dev center, then submit using XCode. Easy as one, two, three…thirty-seven…&lt;br/&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google&lt;/strong&gt;: Download Android Studio, generate a security certificate through it, then package it using the Studio. Upload the package to Android Developer website.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Microsoft&lt;/strong&gt;: Generate an .appx package using these free command line tools, or Visual Studio. Upload to the Microsoft Dev Center website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The good news is, &lt;strong&gt;there’s a free tool to do the magic of turning your web app into app packages&lt;/strong&gt;. That awesome free tool is called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pwabuilder.com&quot;&gt;PWABuilder&lt;/a&gt;. It analyzes a URL, tells you what you need to do (e.g. maybe add some home screen icons to your PWA web manifest). And in a 3 step wizard, it lets you download packages that contain all the magic:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;For Windows, it actually generates the .appx package. You can literally take that and submit it on the Windows Dev Center site.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For Google, it generates a wrapper Java app that contains your PWA web app. From Android Studio, you build this project, which generates the Android package that can be uploaded to the Android Dev Center site.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For Apple, it generates an XCode project which can be built with XCode. Which requires a Mac.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once again, Apple was the most painful of all of these. I don’t have a Mac. But you cannot build the XCode project for your PWA without a Mac.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t want to pay several thousand dollars to publish my free app in Apple’s app store. I don’t want to pay for the privilege of enriching Apple’s iOS platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, &lt;a href=&quot;http://macincloud.com&quot;&gt;MacInCloud&lt;/a&gt; costs about $25/month, and they give you a Mac machine with XCode already installed. You can remote into it using Windows Remote Desktop, or even via a web interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t enough to just build the XCode project and submit. I had to generate a security certificate on the Apple Developer site, then create a new app profile in a separate site, iTunes Connect, where you actually submit the package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that wasn’t all: since Apple is hostile to web apps, I had to install some special frameworks and add Cordova plugins that allow my app to do things like to play audio in the background, add the current song to the lock screen, control the song volume and play status from the lock screen, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This took at least a week of finagling to get my app into a working state before I could submit it to the app store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Winner&lt;/strong&gt;: Microsoft. Imagine this: you can go to a website that generates an app package for your web app. And if that’s not your thing, you can download command line tools that will do the job. GUI person? The free Visual Studio will work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Runner-up&lt;/strong&gt;: Google. Requires Android Studio, but it’s free, runs everyone, and was simple enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loser&lt;/strong&gt;: Apple. I shouldn’t have to buy a proprietary computer – a several thousand dollar Mac – in order to build my app. The Apple Dev Center –&amp;gt; iTunes Connect tangling seems like an out-of-touch manager’s attempt to push iTunes onto developers. It should simply be part of Apple Developer Center site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;App Testing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you finally did all the magic incantations to turn your existing web app into a mobile app package, you probably want to send it out to testers before releasing your app on the unwashed masses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apple&lt;/strong&gt;: For testing, you have your testers install Test Flight on their iOS device. Then you add the tester’s email in iTunes Connect. The tester will get a notification and can test your app before it’s available in the app store.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google&lt;/strong&gt;: In Android Dev Center, you add email addresses of testers. Once added, they can see your alpha/beta version in the App Store.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Microsoft&lt;/strong&gt;: I didn’t actually use this, so I won’t comment on it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Winner&lt;/strong&gt;: Toss up. Apple’s Test Flight app is simple and streamlined. You can control alpha/beta expiration simply on the admin side. Google wasn’t far behind; it was quite painless, not even requiring a separate app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;App Review&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once your app is ready for prime time, you submit your app for review. The review is done using both a programmatic checklist (e.g. do you have a launch icon?) and by real people (“your app is a clone of X, we reject it”)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apple&lt;/strong&gt;: Prior to submission, XCode warns you about potential problems during build. The human app review takes about 24-48 hours.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google&lt;/strong&gt;: Anybody home? Android Studio didn’t tell me about any potential problems, and my app was approved within minutes of submission. I don’t think a real human being looked at my app.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Microsoft&lt;/strong&gt;: Upon submission, a fast programmatic review caught an issue pertaining to wrong icon formats. After passing, a human reviewed my app within 4 days.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Winner&lt;/strong&gt;: Apple.
&lt;p&gt;Sure, as a developer, I like the fact that my app was instantly in the Google Play store. But that’s only because, I suspect, it wasn’t actually reviewed by a human.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple had the quickest turnaround time for actual human review. Updates also passed review within 24 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft was hit or miss here. The initial review took 3 or 4 days. An later update took 24 hours. Then another update, where I added XBox platform, took another 3-4 days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s painful, and costs money, to take an existing PWA and get them functional on mobile platforms and listed in the App Store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Winner&lt;/strong&gt;: Google. They made it the easiest to get into the app store. The made it the easiest to integrate into the native platform, by attempting to standardize web APIs that OS platforms can pick up on (hello, lovely navigator.mediaSession)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Runner-up&lt;/strong&gt;: Microsoft. They made it the easiest to sprinkle your web app with magic, turning it into a package that can be submitted to their store. (Can be done for free using the &lt;a href=&quot;http://pwabuilder.com&quot;&gt;PWABuilder&lt;/a&gt; site!) Integrating with their platform means using the auto-injected window.Windows.* JavaScript namespace. Not bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loser&lt;/strong&gt;: Apple. Don’t require me to buy a Mac to build an iOS app. Don’t force me to use native wrappers to integrate with your platform. Don’t require me to screw around with security certificates; let your build tools make them for me, and store them automatically in my Dev Center account. Don’t make me use 2 different sites: Apple Dev Center and iTunes Connect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Final thoughts: The web always wins. It defeated Flash. It killed Silverlight. It destroyed native apps on desktop. The browser is the rich client platform. The OS is merely a browser-launcher and hardware-communicator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The web will win, too, on mobile. Developers don’t want to build 3 separate apps for the major platforms. Companies don’t want to pay for development of 3 apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer to all this is the web. We can build rich web apps – Progressive Web Apps – and package them for all the app stores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple in particular has a perverse incentive to stop the progress of the web. It’s the same incentive that Microsoft had in the late ‘90s and early 2000s: it wants to be &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; platform for good apps. PWAs undermine that; they run everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My software wisdom is this: PWAs will eventually win and overtake native mobile apps. In 5-10 years, native iOS apps will be as common as Win32 C apps. Apple will go kicking and screaming, keeping iOS Safari behind the curve, blocking PWA progress where they can. (Even their recent “support” for PWAs in iOS Safari 11.1 &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16826852&quot;&gt;actually cripple PWAs&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My suggestion to mobile app platforms is embrace the inevitable and either automatically add quality PWAs to your app store, or allow developers to easily (e.g. free, and with 3 clicks or less) submit a PWA to your store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Readers, I hope this has been helpful glance at PWAs in App Stores in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you submitted a PWA to an app store? I’d love to hear your experience in the comments.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 14:18:49 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>judah</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://debuggerdotbreak.judahgabriel.com/2018/04/13/i-built-a-pwa-and-published-it-in-3-app-stores-heres-what-i-learned/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Time to rebuild the web?</title>
<link>https://www.oreilly.com/ideas/its-time-to-rebuild-the-web</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.oreilly.com/ideas/its-time-to-rebuild-the-web</guid>
<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://d3tdunqjn7n0wj.cloudfront.net/360x240/wall-2997629_1920_crop-f1d80cccf2838b3d222e6e7ad3a6d59e.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Stone wall&quot; srcset=&quot;https://d3tdunqjn7n0wj.cloudfront.net/360x240/wall-2997629_1920_crop-f1d80cccf2838b3d222e6e7ad3a6d59e.jpg 360w, https://d3tdunqjn7n0wj.cloudfront.net/720x480/wall-2997629_1920_crop-f1d80cccf2838b3d222e6e7ad3a6d59e.jpg 720w, https://d3tdunqjn7n0wj.cloudfront.net/1440x960/wall-2997629_1920_crop-f1d80cccf2838b3d222e6e7ad3a6d59e.jpg 1440w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 1390px) 420px, (min-width: 600px) 45vw, 100vw&quot; class=&quot;&quot;/&gt; Stone wall &lt;span class=&quot;source-name&quot;&gt;(source: &lt;a class=&quot;secondary&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/wall-fixing-city-wall-protection-2997629/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;aside data-type=&quot;note&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://conferences.oreilly.com/fluent/fl-ca?intcmp=il-web-confreg-lp-flca18_new_site_rebuild_the_web_top_cta&quot;&gt;O'Reilly Fluent Conference&lt;/a&gt; will be in San Jose, CA, June 11-14, 2018. &lt;a href=&quot;https://conferences.oreilly.com/fluent/fl-ca/public/schedule/grid/public/2018-06-12?intcmp=il-web-confreg-lp-flca18_new_site_rebuild_the_web_top_cta&quot;&gt;Check out the full schedule here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anil Dash's &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@anildash/the-missing-building-blocks-of-the-web-3fa490ae5cbc&quot;&gt;&quot;The Missing Building Blocks of the Web&quot;&lt;/a&gt; is an excellent article about the web as it was supposed to be, using technologies that exist but have been neglected or abandoned. It's not his first take on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://anildash.com/2012/12/the-web-we-lost.html&quot;&gt;technologies the web has lost&lt;/a&gt;, or on the possibility of &lt;a href=&quot;http://anildash.com/2012/12/rebuilding-the-web-we-lost.html&quot;&gt;rebuilding the web&lt;/a&gt;, and I hope it's not his last. And we have to ask ourselves what would happen if we brought back those technologies: would we have a web that's more humane and better suited to the future we want to build?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've written several times (and will no doubt write more) about rebuilding the internet, but I've generally assumed the rebuild will need peer-to-peer technologies. Those technologies are inherently much more complex than anything Dash proposes. While many of the technologies I'd use already exist, rebuilding the web around &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blockchain&quot;&gt;blockchains&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Onion_routing&quot;&gt;onion routing&lt;/a&gt; would require a revolution in user interface design to have a chance; otherwise it will be a playground for the technology elite. In contrast, Dash's &quot;missing building blocks&quot; are fundamentally simple. They can easily be used by people who don't have a unicorn's worth of experience as web developers and security administrators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dash writes about the demise of the View Source browser feature, which dispays the HTML from which the web page is built. View Source isn't dead, but it's sick. He's right that the web succeeded, in part, because people with little background could look at the source for the pages they liked, copy the code they wanted, and end up with something that looks pretty good. Today, you can no longer learn by copying; while View Source still exists on most browsers, the complexity of modern web pages have made it next to useless. The bits you want are wrapped in megabytes (literally) of JavaScript and CSS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that doesn't have to be the end of the story. HTML can be functional without being complex. Most of what I write (including this piece) goes into a first draft as very simple HTML, using only a half-dozen tags. Simple editors for basic web content still exist. Dash points out that Netscape Gold (the paid version of Netscape) had one, back in the day, and that there are many free editors for basic HTML. We'd have to talk ourselves out of the very complex formatting and layout that, after all, just gets in the way. Ask (almost) any designer: simplicity wins, not a drop-dead gorgeous page. We may have made View Source useless, but we haven't lost simplicity. And if we make enough simple sites, sites from which viewers can effectively copy useful code, View Source will become useful again, too. You can't become a web developer by viewing Facebook's source; but you might by looking at a new site that isn't weighed down by all that CSS and JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The web was never supposed to be a few walled gardens of concentrated content owned by Facebook, YouTube, Twitter, and a few other major publishers. It was supposed to be a cacophony of different sites and voices. And it would be easy to rebuild this cacophony—indeed, it never really died. There are plenty of individual sites out there still, and they provide some (should I say most?) of the really valuable content on the web. The problem with the megasites is that they select and present &quot;relevant&quot; content to us. Much as we may complain about Facebook, selecting relevant content from an ocean of random sites is an important service. It's easy for me to imagine relatives and friends building their own sites for baby pictures, announcements, and general talk. That's what we did in the 90s. But would we go to the trouble of reading those all those sites? Probably not. I didn't in the 90s, and neither did you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We already have a tool for solving this problem. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RSS&quot;&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt; lets websites provide &quot;feeds&quot; of news and new items. Applications like &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedly.com/&quot;&gt;Feedly&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://reederapp.com/&quot;&gt;Reeder&lt;/a&gt; let you build a collection of sites that interest you, and show you what's changed since the last time you visited. While I'd never check a dozen sites each day, I use Feedly to monitor hundreds of websites. I would never check those sites by hand, but I scan Feedly every morning. And, unlike Facebook, Feedly doesn't know anything about its users except for the sites they read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feedly has a decent user interface, though it could be a improved; it would have to be better to become popular with people who aren't technically literate. (Sorry.) Still, though, the UI gap for RSS is much smaller than for technologies like &lt;a href=&quot;https://tor.eff.org/&quot;&gt;TOR&lt;/a&gt;. And if we're going to rebuild the net, we'll probably be better off choosing simple rather than bright, shiny, and complex technologies. Could someone build an RSS reader that made the web of independent sites as approachable as Facebook? I don't see why not—and users would have complete control over what they see. That's important; in a recent &lt;a href=&quot;http://anildash.com/2012/12/the-web-we-lost.html&quot;&gt;tweet&lt;/a&gt;, Dash says:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google’s decision to kill Google Reader [their RSS client] was a turning point in enabling media to be manipulated by misinformation campaigns. The difference between individuals choosing the feeds they read and companies doing it for you affects all other forms of media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, there would still be plenty of sites for every conspiracy theory and propaganda project around; but in a world where you choose what you see rather than letting a third party decide for you, these sites would have trouble gaining momentum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't want to underestimate the difficulty of this project, or overestimate its chances of success. We'd certainly have to get used to sites that aren't as glossy or complex as the ones we have now. We might have to revisit some of the most hideous bits of the first-generation web, including those awful &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yahoo!_GeoCities&quot;&gt;GeoCities&lt;/a&gt; pages. We would probably need to avoid fancy, dynamic websites; and, before you think this will be easy, remember that one of the first extensions to the static web was CGI Perl. We would be taking the risk that we'd re-invent the same mistakes that brought us to our current mess. Simplicity is a discipline, and not an easy one. However, by losing tons of bloat, we'd end up with a web that is much faster and more responsive than what we have now. And maybe we'd learn to prize that speed and that responsiveness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'd also need to avoid many of the privacy and security flaws that were rampant in the early internet, and for which we're still paying. That technical debt came due a long time ago. Paying off that debt may require some complex technology, and some significant UI engineering. All too often, solutions to security problems make things more difficult for both users and attackers. &lt;a href=&quot;https://shift.newco.co/sure-the-internet-is-broken-so-lets-go-fix-it-shall-we-5c27e294c25c&quot;&gt;Crowdflare's new 1.1.1.1 service&lt;/a&gt; addresses some basic problems with our DNS infrastructure and privacy, and their CEO proposes some more basic changes, like DNS over HTTPS. But even simple changes like this require non-technical users to change configuration settings that they don't understand. This is where we really need the help of UX designers. We can't afford to make &quot;safe&quot; difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we'd have to admit that our current web, with all its flaws, evolved from these simple building blocks. To some extent, then, it's what we wanted—or, perhaps, what we deserved. It's certainly what we accepted, and begs the question: &quot;why wouldn't we accept the same thing again?&quot; Starting over means little if we're destined to repeat the mistakes we've already made. So, we would need to develop and incorporate technology for preventing abuse; we would need to build a public space that really is a public space, not someone else's private property; and above all, we would need to divest ourselves of the arrogance that assumes &quot;because we've built it, it is good.&quot; As Dash said six years ago, well before Facebook's Very Bad Month, we would need to &quot;take responsibility and accept blame.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless of how it happens, it's time to start thinking about rebuilding the web. That project is only likely to succeed if the rebuilt web is compatible with what we have today, including Facebook and YouTube. And it's only likely to succeed if it's simple enough for anyone to use. Anil Dash has outlined a way forward. It's not what I would have suggested, but it has a much higher chance of succeeding. Time to (re)build it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-credit&quot;&gt;Article image: Stone wall &lt;span class=&quot;source-name&quot;&gt;(source: &lt;a class=&quot;secondary&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/wall-fixing-city-wall-protection-2997629/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 09:48:38 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>BerislavLopac</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>It's time to rebuild the web</og:title>
<og:description>The web was never supposed to be a few walled gardens of concentrated content owned by a few major publishers; it was supposed to be a cacophony of different sites and voices.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.oreilly.com/ideas/its-time-to-rebuild-the-web</og:url>
<og:image>https://d3tdunqjn7n0wj.cloudfront.net/1400x933/wall-2997629_1920_crop-f1d80cccf2838b3d222e6e7ad3a6d59e.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.oreilly.com/ideas/its-time-to-rebuild-the-web</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Linux 4.17-rc1: “We removed more lines than we added”</title>
<link>http://lkml.iu.edu/hypermail/linux/kernel/1804.1/06654.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://lkml.iu.edu/hypermail/linux/kernel/1804.1/06654.html</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;Content-Type&quot; content=&quot;text/html; charset=utf-8&quot; /&gt;&lt;title&gt;Linux-Kernel Archive: Linux 4.17-rc1&lt;/title&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;Author&quot; content=&quot;Linus Torvalds &amp;lt;torvalds@xxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxx&amp;gt;&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;Subject&quot; content=&quot;Linux 4.17-rc1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body bgcolor=&quot;#FFFFFF&quot; text=&quot;#000000&quot; id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;264.95156228681&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From:&lt;/strong&gt; Linus Torvalds&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; Sun Apr 15 2018 - 21:55:49 EST&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr noshade=&quot;noshade&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;So two weeks have passed, and the merge window was pretty normal and&lt;br /&gt;is now closed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This does not seem to be shaping up to be a particularly big release,&lt;br /&gt;and there seems to be nothing particularly special about it. The most&lt;br /&gt;special thing that happened is purely numerology: we've passed the six&lt;br /&gt;million git objects mark, and that is reason enough to call the next&lt;br /&gt;kernel 5.0. Except I probably won't, because I don't want to be too&lt;br /&gt;predictable. The version numbers are meaningless, which should mean&lt;br /&gt;that they don't even follow silly numerological rules - even if v3.0&lt;br /&gt;and v4.0 happened to be at the 2M and 4M mark respectively.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But v5.0 will happen some day. And it should be meaningless. You have&lt;br /&gt;been warned.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyway, we do have a *few* other things that happened, like Arnd&lt;br /&gt;getting rid of a number of architectures that seem to simply not&lt;br /&gt;matter any more. If it turns out that somebody wants to resurrect any&lt;br /&gt;of them, the code is all there in the git history, but you'll have to&lt;br /&gt;do the work and show that you'll maintain it and have a few users.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And just to not make it *all* about removing old architectures,&lt;br /&gt;there's a new one in there too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The architectures that are gone are blackfin, cris, frv, m32r, metag,&lt;br /&gt;mn10300, score, and tile. And the new architecture is the nds32&lt;br /&gt;(Andes Technology 32-0bit RISC architecture).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We actually have a fair amount of other removal and cleanups too. I&lt;br /&gt;was somewhat pleasantly surprised by the number of pull requests that&lt;br /&gt;actually ended up removing a lot of lines. Some of it was staging&lt;br /&gt;drivers that finally gave up the ghost (like irda), but we also got&lt;br /&gt;rid of some copyright language boiler-plate in favor of just the spdx&lt;br /&gt;lines. And some pre-shipped lexer/parser files are no more, we're&lt;br /&gt;better off just generating them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;End result: we actually removed more lines than we added:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;13538 files changed, 627723 insertions(+), 818855 deletions(-)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;which is probably a first. Ever. In the history of the universe. Or at&lt;br /&gt;least kernel releases.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'd call it momentous, but I think the arch removal was most of it,&lt;br /&gt;and I'm sure people will quickly rectify that momentary glitch of&lt;br /&gt;actually shrinking the kernel source code.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Go out and test,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Linus&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;---&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Al Viro (7):&lt;br /&gt;vfs dcache updates&lt;br /&gt;misc vfs updates&lt;br /&gt;sparc syscall cleanups&lt;br /&gt;alpha syscall cleanups&lt;br /&gt;vfs namei updates&lt;br /&gt;AFS updates&lt;br /&gt;vfs thaw updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alex Williamson (1):&lt;br /&gt;VFIO updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alexandre Belloni (1):&lt;br /&gt;RTC updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Andrew Morton (3):&lt;br /&gt;updates&lt;br /&gt;more updates&lt;br /&gt;yet more updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Andy Shevchenko (1):&lt;br /&gt;x86 platform driver updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anna Schumaker (1):&lt;br /&gt;NFS client updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Arnd Bergmann (5):&lt;br /&gt;ARM SoC device tree updates&lt;br /&gt;ARM SoC platform updates&lt;br /&gt;ARM SoC driver updates&lt;br /&gt;ARM SoC fixes&lt;br /&gt;asm-generic fixes&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bartlomiej Zolnierkiewicz (1):&lt;br /&gt;fbdev updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Benson Leung (1):&lt;br /&gt;chrome platform updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bjorn Andersson (2):&lt;br /&gt;rpmsg updates&lt;br /&gt;remoteproc updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bjorn Helgaas (2):&lt;br /&gt;PCI updates&lt;br /&gt;PCI fixes&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bob Peterson (2):&lt;br /&gt;gfs2 updates&lt;br /&gt;more gfs2 updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Boris Brezillon (1):&lt;br /&gt;MTD updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Borislav Petkov (1):&lt;br /&gt;EDAC updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bruce Fields (1):&lt;br /&gt;nfsd updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Christoph Hellwig (2):&lt;br /&gt;dma-mapping updates&lt;br /&gt;dma-mapping fix&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Corey Minyard (1):&lt;br /&gt;IPMI updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dan Williams (1):&lt;br /&gt;libnvdimm updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Darrick Wong (2):&lt;br /&gt;xfs updates&lt;br /&gt;more xfs updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dave Airlie (2):&lt;br /&gt;drm updates&lt;br /&gt;drm fixes&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;David Howells (1):&lt;br /&gt;fscache updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;David Miller (5):&lt;br /&gt;networking updates&lt;br /&gt;sparc updates&lt;br /&gt;networking fixes&lt;br /&gt;networking fixes&lt;br /&gt;networking fixes&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;David Sterba (2):&lt;br /&gt;btrfs updates&lt;br /&gt;more btrfs updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dmitry Torokhov (1):&lt;br /&gt;input updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dominik Brodowski (1):&lt;br /&gt;removal of in-kernel calls to syscalls&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Eric Biederman (2):&lt;br /&gt;namespace updates&lt;br /&gt;siginfo updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Geert Uytterhoeven (1):&lt;br /&gt;m68k updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Greentime Hu (1):&lt;br /&gt;nds32 architecture support&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Greg KH (5):&lt;br /&gt;USB/PHY updates&lt;br /&gt;tty/serial driver updates&lt;br /&gt;staging/IIO updates&lt;br /&gt;driver core updates&lt;br /&gt;char/misc updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Greg Ungerer (1):&lt;br /&gt;m68knommu update&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Guenter Roeck (1):&lt;br /&gt;hwmon updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Helge Deller (2):&lt;br /&gt;parisc updates&lt;br /&gt;parisc updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Herbert Xu (1):&lt;br /&gt;crypto updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ilya Dryomov (1):&lt;br /&gt;ceph updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ingo Molnar (19):&lt;br /&gt;misc core updates&lt;br /&gt;debugobjects updates&lt;br /&gt;header file cleanup&lt;br /&gt;RCU updates&lt;br /&gt;locking updates&lt;br /&gt;perf updates&lt;br /&gt;x86 RAS updates&lt;br /&gt;scheduler updates&lt;br /&gt;SMP hotplug updates&lt;br /&gt;x86 apic updates&lt;br /&gt;x86 asm fixlets&lt;br /&gt;x86 build updates&lt;br /&gt;x86 cleanups and msr updates&lt;br /&gt;x86 mm updates&lt;br /&gt;x86 platform updates&lt;br /&gt;x86 timer updates&lt;br /&gt;wait_var_event updates&lt;br /&gt;x86 dma mapping updates&lt;br /&gt;EFI updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jacek Anaszewski (1):&lt;br /&gt;LED updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jaegeuk Kim (1):&lt;br /&gt;f2fs update&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;James Bottomley (2):&lt;br /&gt;SCSI updates&lt;br /&gt;SCSI fixes&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;James Hogan (1):&lt;br /&gt;MIPS updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;James Morris (4):&lt;br /&gt;general security layer updates&lt;br /&gt;smack update&lt;br /&gt;TPM updates&lt;br /&gt;integrity updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jan Kara (1):&lt;br /&gt;misc filesystem updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jason Gunthorpe (1):&lt;br /&gt;rdma updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jason Wessel (1):&lt;br /&gt;kdb updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jassi Brar (1):&lt;br /&gt;mailbox updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jean Delvare (1):&lt;br /&gt;dmi updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jens Axboe (2):&lt;br /&gt;block layer updates&lt;br /&gt;block fixes&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jiri Kosina (2):&lt;br /&gt;HID updates&lt;br /&gt;trivial tree updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Joerg Roedel (1):&lt;br /&gt;IOMMU updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;John Johansen (1):&lt;br /&gt;apparmor updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jonathan Corbet (1):&lt;br /&gt;documentation updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Juergen Gross (1):&lt;br /&gt;xen fixes&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kees Cook (2):&lt;br /&gt;pstore updates&lt;br /&gt;pstore fix&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ley Foon Tan (1):&lt;br /&gt;nios2 update&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Linus Walleij (2):&lt;br /&gt;pin control bulk updates&lt;br /&gt;GPIO updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mark Brown (3):&lt;br /&gt;regmap updates&lt;br /&gt;regulator updates&lt;br /&gt;SPI updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mark Salter (1):&lt;br /&gt;c6x updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Martin Schwidefsky (2):&lt;br /&gt;s390 updates&lt;br /&gt;more s390 updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Masahiro Yamada (3):&lt;br /&gt;Kbuild updates&lt;br /&gt;Kconfig updates&lt;br /&gt;more Kbuild updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Matt Turner (1):&lt;br /&gt;alpha updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mauro Carvalho Chehab (2):&lt;br /&gt;media updates&lt;br /&gt;media fixes&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Michael Ellerman (2):&lt;br /&gt;powerpc updates&lt;br /&gt;powerpc fixes&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Michael Tsirkin (2):&lt;br /&gt;fw_cfg, vhost updates&lt;br /&gt;virtio update&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Michal Simek (1):&lt;br /&gt;microblaze updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mike Marshall (1):&lt;br /&gt;orangefs updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mike Snitzer (1):&lt;br /&gt;device mapper updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Miklos Szeredi (1):&lt;br /&gt;overlayfs updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Palmer Dabbelt (1):&lt;br /&gt;RISC-V updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Paolo Bonzini (1):&lt;br /&gt;kvm updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Paul Moore (2):&lt;br /&gt;audit updates&lt;br /&gt;SELinux updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Petr Mladek (1):&lt;br /&gt;printk updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rafael Wysocki (3):&lt;br /&gt;ACPI updates&lt;br /&gt;power management updates&lt;br /&gt;more power management updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rich Felker (1):&lt;br /&gt;arch/sh updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Richard Weinberger (2):&lt;br /&gt;UML updates&lt;br /&gt;UBI and UBIFS updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rob Herring (1):&lt;br /&gt;DeviceTree updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Russell King (2):&lt;br /&gt;ARM updates&lt;br /&gt;ARM SA1100 updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sebastian Reichel (2):&lt;br /&gt;power supply and reset updates&lt;br /&gt;HSI updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shuah Khan (1):&lt;br /&gt;kselftest update&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stafford Horne (1):&lt;br /&gt;OpenRISC fixlet&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stephen Boyd (1):&lt;br /&gt;clk updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Steve French (2):&lt;br /&gt;cifs updates&lt;br /&gt;cifs fixes&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Steven Rostedt (3):&lt;br /&gt;tracing updates&lt;br /&gt;ktest updates&lt;br /&gt;tracing fixes&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Takashi Iwai (2):&lt;br /&gt;sound updates&lt;br /&gt;sound fixes&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ted Ts'o (2):&lt;br /&gt;ext4 updates&lt;br /&gt;/dev/random updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tejun Heo (2):&lt;br /&gt;libata updates&lt;br /&gt;workqueue updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thierry Reding (1):&lt;br /&gt;pwm updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thomas Gleixner (8):&lt;br /&gt;time(r) updates&lt;br /&gt;irq updates&lt;br /&gt;irq affinity fixes&lt;br /&gt;x86 EFI bootup fixlet&lt;br /&gt;more perf updates&lt;br /&gt;scheduler fixes&lt;br /&gt;x86 pti updates&lt;br /&gt;x86 fixes&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tobin Harding (1):&lt;br /&gt;leaking-addresses updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ulf Hansson (2):&lt;br /&gt;MMC updates&lt;br /&gt;MMC fixes&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Vinod Koul (1):&lt;br /&gt;dmaengine updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Will Deacon (2):&lt;br /&gt;arm64 updates&lt;br /&gt;more arm64 updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wim Van Sebroeck (1):&lt;br /&gt;watchdog updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wolfram Sang (2):&lt;br /&gt;i2c updates&lt;br /&gt;more i2c updates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Zhang Rui (1):&lt;br /&gt;thermal management update&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr noshade=&quot;noshade&quot; /&gt;&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 08:52:44 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rbanffy</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://lkml.iu.edu/hypermail/linux/kernel/1804.1/06654.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ketamine has &amp;#039;fast-acting benefits&amp;#039; for depression</title>
<link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/health-43753073</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/health-43753073</guid>
<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption full-width lead&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                &lt;img class=&quot;js-image-replace&quot; alt=&quot;Ketamine&quot; src=&quot;https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/320/cpsprodpb/18492/production/_100847499_c0341336-hospital_staff_at_work-spl-1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;976&quot; height=&quot;549&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;Science Photo Library&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body__introduction&quot;&gt;Ketamine has &quot;shown promise&quot; in the rapid treatment of major depression and suicidal thoughts, a US study says. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ketamine has a reputation as a party drug but is licensed as an anaesthetic. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The study found use of the drug via a nasal spray led to &quot;significant&quot; improvements in depressive symptoms in the first 24 hours. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Royal College of Psychiatrists said it was a &quot;significant&quot; study that brought the drug &quot;a step closer to being prescribed on the NHS&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The report by researchers from Janssen Research and Development, a Johnson and Johnson company, and Yale School of Medicine, is the first study into ketamine as a treatment for depression that has been done by a drug company. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is being published in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ajp.psychiatryonline.org/&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link-external&quot;&gt;American Journal of Psychiatry&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The trial looked at 68 people at imminent risk of suicide. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All patients were treated with a stay in hospital and anti-depressants. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition, half were given ketamine in the form of esketamine (part of the ketamine molecule) in a nasal spray and half were given a placebo. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The study found those using esketamine had a much greater improvement in depression symptoms at all points over the first four weeks of treatment. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, at 25 days the effects had levelled out. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The study's authors suggest it could offer an effective rapid treatment for people severely depressed and at imminent risk of suicide and could help in the initial stages of treatment, as most anti-depressants take four to six weeks to become fully effective.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The nasal spray is now undergoing phase three trials before it can be licensed for treatment. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;Potential for abuse&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;There were no reports of esketamine dependence or misuse in the trial but the authors warn that more research is needed on the potential for abuse of ketamine and say these should be looked at during subsequent trials. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scientists in the UK are also studying ketamine as a treatment for depression taken intravenously. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dr James Stone, from the Royal College of Psychiatrists, told the BBC the &quot;interesting&quot; US study confirmed the findings from successful studies into intravenous ketamine. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;The main reason for its significance is because this is being developed by a drug company and it's potentially quite likely that this medication might become available as a treatment available on the NHS for depression.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;'Severe depression'&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;He said because it was being given as a nasal spray it was &quot;much easier to administer&quot; than intravenous ketamine and was &quot;potentially quicker to give, so it means more people can be dosed at the same time&quot; and you need less equipment. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dr Stone said if it did go on to be prescribed on the NHS it would be aimed at people with severe depression as a second or third line of treatment if other drugs haven't worked and could be used for people instead of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mind.org.uk/information-support/drugs-and-treatments/electroconvulsive-therapy-ect/#.WtDdSfldWIg&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link-external&quot;&gt;electroconvulsive therapy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Prof Mitul Mehta from King's College told the BBC it was an &quot;exciting&quot; study.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;All the studies to date have been looking at intravenous use - there are some people who have explored oral ketamine but that doesn't appear to be as successful as intravenous so intranasal seems to be a really good halfway-house.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;It enters the body relatively quickly - it's not as fast as going straight into your bloodstream but not as slow as via the stomach and it's reasonably easy to control how much you give to a person. In that respect this is a really important study.&quot; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But he said far bigger studies are needed to look out for any rare side-effects. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption body-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;You may also like:&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;Prescribed off licence&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Because ketamine is licensed to be used by doctors as an aneasthetic it can be prescribed off licence for depression. This is happening in private clinics in the US and the UK. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But to be prescribed on the NHS, it would need to be licensed to be used as a treatment for depression.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the UK, doctors have been trialling ketamine to treat depression since 2011.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dr Rupert McShane, who has led a trial in Oxford, says ketamine &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/health-26647738&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;can work on patients with depression &quot;where nothing has helped before&quot;.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last year &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/health-39501566&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;he called for the use of ketamine to treat depression to be rolled out.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, he called for a national registry to monitor its use.&lt;/p&gt;
    </description>
<pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 05:11:16 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pmoriarty</dc:creator>
<og:title>Ketamine's 'rapid help' for depression</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>A study treating depressed patients with the drug via a nasal spray saw &quot;significant improvements&quot;.</og:description>
<og:url>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/health-43753073</og:url>
<og:image>https://ichef-1.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/18492/production/_100847499_c0341336-hospital_staff_at_work-spl-1.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-GB</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/health-43753073</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>You Can’t Do Data Science in a GUI</title>
<link>https://blog.dominodatalab.com/data-scientist-programmer-mutually-exclusive/?r=1</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.dominodatalab.com/data-scientist-programmer-mutually-exclusive/?r=1</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;story-top&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;story-right&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;a2a_kit a2a_kit_size_0 addtoany_list&quot; data-a2a-url=&quot;https://blog.dominodatalab.com/data-scientist-programmer-mutually-exclusive/&quot; data-a2a-title=&quot;Data Scientist? Programmer? Are They Mutually Exclusive?&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;a2a_dd addtoany_share_save addtoany_share&quot; href=&quot;https://www.addtoany.com/share&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.dominodatalab.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/share.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Share&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This Domino Data Science Field Note blog post provides highlights of &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hadleywickham&quot;&gt;Hadley Wickham&lt;/a&gt;’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chicagoacm.org/meeting-topics/2018-03-07-hadley-wickham---you-can-t-do-data-science-in-a-gui&quot;&gt;ACM Chicago&lt;/a&gt; talk, “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PURtmHwk_-0&quot;&gt;You Can’t Do Data Science in a GUI&lt;/a&gt;”. In his talk, Wickham advocates that, unlike a GUI, using code provides reproducibility, data provenance, and the ability to track changes so that data scientists have the ability to see how the data analysis has evolved. As the creator of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ggplot2&quot;&gt;ggplot2&lt;/a&gt;, it is not a surprise that Wickham also advocates the use of visualizations and models together to help data scientists find the real signals within their data. This blog post also provides clips from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PURtmHwk_-0&quot;&gt;original video&lt;/a&gt; and follows the &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/&quot;&gt;Creative Commons license&lt;/a&gt; affiliated with the original video recording.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignleft wp-image-5672 size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://blog.dominodatalab.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Definition-of-Data-Science-300x168.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;168&quot; srcset=&quot;https://blog.dominodatalab.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Definition-of-Data-Science-300x168.jpg 300w, https://blog.dominodatalab.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Definition-of-Data-Science-768x430.jpg 768w, https://blog.dominodatalab.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Definition-of-Data-Science-1024x574.jpg 1024w, https://blog.dominodatalab.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Definition-of-Data-Science.jpg 1048w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hadley Wickham, Chief Scientist at RStudio, presented an ACM Chicago talk, “You Can’t Do Data Science in a GUI”, that covered data science work flows and tools. For example, Wickham advocates the use of visualizations and models to support data scientists find the real signals within their data. He also suggests leveraging a programming language for benefits that include reproducibility, data provenance, and the ability to see how data analysis has evolved over time. He also touches upon what he favors about the R programming language. From his perspective, using a GUI does not allow for these benefits. Benefits that are particularly important as he defines data science, according to the slide from this talk, as “the process by which data becomes understanding, knowledge, and insight”. GUIs deliberately obfuscate the process as you can only do what the GUI inventors want you to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before diving into answering the question, “why program?” portion of his talk, Wickham discusses two “main engines” that help data scientists understand what is going on within a data set: &lt;a href=&quot;http://r4ds.had.co.nz/data-visualisation.html&quot;&gt;visualization&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://r4ds.had.co.nz/model-intro.html&quot;&gt;models&lt;/a&gt;. Visualization is a tool that enables a data scientist to iterate on a “vague question” and help them refine it. Or taking the question and “trying to make it sufficiently precise so that you can answer it quantitatively.” Wickham also advocates the use of visualization because it may surprise a data scientist or lead them to see something they didn’t expect to see. During the talk, Wickham indicates “that the first visualization you look at will always reveal a data quality error, and if it doesn’t not reveal a data quality error, that just mans you haven’t found one yet.” Yet, he also indicates that visualizations do not scale particularly well and suggests using models to complement visualizations. Models are used when data scientists are able to make their questions precise enough to use an algorithm or summary statistic. Models are more scalable than visualizations because “it is way easier to throw more computers at the problem then it is to throw more brains at it.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Wickham advocates using a programming language, rather than a GUI, to do data science as it provides the opportunity to reproduce work, understand the data provenance (which is also linked to reproducibility), and the ability to see how the data analysis has evolved over time. Two workflows that Wickham points out, in particular, that are useful include cut-and-paste and using &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/&quot;&gt;stack overflow&lt;/a&gt;. While these tools were mentioned in humor, code is text and it is easy to cut-and-paste text, including error messages into stack overflow to find a solution. Also, understanding data provenance enables reproducibility because it enables the data scientist to “rerun that code with a new data later on, and get updated results you can use”. Working with code also enables data scientists share their work via open ways such as GitHub. In this portion of his talk, Wickham references a project on GitHub where people can see the series of commits, drill down on the commits, and see “where data analysis is now but you can see how it evolved over time.” He contrasts this with Excel which provides the opportunity for people to accidentally randomize their data without knowing the provenance or having a rollback option.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As Wickham is the Chief Scientist at RStudio, he indicates while he thinks “Python is great too”, he “particularly loves &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.r-project.org/about.html&quot;&gt;R&lt;/a&gt;”. A few of R features that appeal to Wickham include&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;It is a functional programing language which allows you to “solve problems by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.stat.berkeley.edu/~statcur/Workshop2/Presentations/functions.pdf&quot;&gt;composing functions&lt;/a&gt; in various ways”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://statistics.berkeley.edu/computing/r-vectors-matrices&quot;&gt;R vectors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how R provides the ability to look at the structure of the code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how R “gives us this incredible power to create little domain specific languages that are tailored to certain parts of data science process”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;This also leads to the potential to build &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.mit.edu/insong/www/pdf/rpackage_instructions.pdf&quot;&gt;R packages&lt;/a&gt;. Wickham indicates that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tidyverse.org/packages/&quot;&gt;packages&lt;/a&gt; allow people to solve complex problems by breaking them down into smaller pieces, smaller pieces that can be taken from one project and then “recombined in different ways” (reproducibility), to solve a new problem.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As Wickham defines data science as “the process by which data becomes understanding, knowledge, and insight”, he advocates using data science tools where value is gained from iteration, surprise, reproducibility, and scalability. In particular, he argues that being a data scientist and being programmer are not mutually exclusive and that using a programming language helps data scientists towards understanding the real signal within their data. While this blog post only covers some of the key highlights from Wickham’s ACM Chicago talk, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PURtmHwk_-0&quot;&gt;full video is available for viewing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;sup&gt;Domino Data Science Field Notes provides highlights of data science research, trends, techniques, and more, that support data scientists and data science leaders accelerate their work or careers. If you are interested in your data science work being covered in this blog series, please send us an email at writeforus(at)dominodatalab(dot)com.&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;jp-relatedposts-headline&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Related&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;signup-callout margin-verticals-medium&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;signup-headline&quot;&gt;Don't miss future data science articles&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2018 23:36:30 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>gk1</dc:creator>
<og:type>video.other</og:type>
<og:image>https://blog.dominodatalab.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/unnamed-file-1.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Data Scientist? Programmer? Are They Mutually Exclusive?</og:title>
<og:description>This Domino Data Science Field Note blog post provides highlights of Hadley Wickham’s ACM Chicago talk, “You Can’t Do Data Science in a GUI”. In his talk,</og:description>
<og:url>https://blog.dominodatalab.com/data-scientist-programmer-mutually-exclusive/</og:url>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.dominodatalab.com/data-scientist-programmer-mutually-exclusive/?r=1</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>ReactOS releases 0.4.8 with experimental Vista/7/10 software compatibility</title>
<link>https://reactos.org/project-news/reactos-048-released</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://reactos.org/project-news/reactos-048-released</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The ReactOS Project is pleased to announce the release of version 0.4.8 as we continue to work on releasing every three months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you may know, our previous 0.4.7 version was the first one developed in our &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.github.com/reactos&quot;&gt;Git/GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt;. 0.4.8 is the nice sequel and a good way to measure the GitHub impact on the ReactOS project. Since ReactOS reached GitHub, it has been forked &lt;strong&gt;248&lt;/strong&gt; times. A nice amount understanding ReactOS is not a framework or a library, but a final product. These forks represent a nice amount of newcomers: translators, designers, coders and testers. Thanks to all of them, and the ReactOS regular devs, &lt;strong&gt;209 new Pull Requests&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;1094 commits&lt;/strong&gt; have made it through to this 0.4.8 version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;User Experience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ReactOS keeps pushing to bring the best possible user experience. Therefore the ReactOS User Interface in 0.4.8 has received extra care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taskbar&lt;/strong&gt; settings and dialogs have been rewritten by Giannis so now the auto-hide, toggle lock and always on top options work. These settings were visible before but as you might have noticed they've never been working at all. Meanwhile, David fixed several bugs and glitches of the notification area. Thanks to him, Giannis and Hermès, now &lt;strong&gt;balloon notifications&lt;/strong&gt; are properly supported, queued and shown while a range of tooltip problems have been solved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talking about the &lt;strong&gt;notification tray&lt;/strong&gt;, due to Ged’s work, icons of killed and finished process are now automatically removed, even when apps crash. This is something that Windows doesn't even provide with Win10, and many Windows users may have noticed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://reactos.org/sites/default/files/imagepicker/14095/balloon.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; class=&quot;imgp_img&quot; width=&quot;90%&quot; height=&quot;768&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the bottom right you can see the Notifications working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Selecting multiple desktop icons was impossible prior 0.4.8. Enjoy it now thanks to Giannis’ work. His amazing work doesn't stop there, bugs related to property dialogs have been squashed, like the one preventing drive and folders capacity from being shown. &lt;strong&gt;Deletion and renaming&lt;/strong&gt; of folders and files should work reliably after Pierre fixed a major leak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additional new features included in this release should also boost the user experience, such as the &lt;strong&gt;shell autocompletion&lt;/strong&gt; brought to you by Mark, a nice bonus on top of the improved relative path handling done by Stanislav. Also, now &lt;strong&gt;Network drives&lt;/strong&gt; can be dismounted directly from explorer due to Pierre’s work, and &lt;strong&gt;Eject and Disconnect&lt;/strong&gt; menu items are now implemented thanks to Katayama.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the visual point of view, several glitches related to the redrawing of static text elements, scrollbars, button captions, fonts and text background colors were fixed in this version. As a bonus, now ReactOS also detects more themes and is much faster when rendering big amounts of text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://reactos.org/sites/default/files/imagepicker/14095/autohide.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; class=&quot;imgp_img&quot; width=&quot;90%&quot; height=&quot;768&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new settings and autohide working!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding internationalization, now when changing the language in ReactOS, the font substitution settings are properly overwritten thanks to Katayama, and time is now correctly set due to Doug’s work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Combine all these features with the Kernel and Filesystem fixes that 0.4.8 is bringing and you'll understand why the ReactOS team is so excited regarding this new release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;NT6+ Software support and Games&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With software specifically leaving NT5 behind, ReactOS is &lt;strong&gt;expanding&lt;/strong&gt; its target to &lt;strong&gt;support NT6+ (Vista, Windows 8, Windows 10) software&lt;/strong&gt;. Colin, Giannis and Mark are creating the needed logic in NTDLL and LDR for this purpose. Giannis has finished the side-by-side support and the implicit activation context, Colin has changed Kernel32 to accept software made for NT6+, and Mark keeps working on the shim compatibility layer. Although in a &lt;strong&gt;really greenish and experimental state&lt;/strong&gt;, the new additions in 0.4.8 should start helping several software pieces created for Vista and upwards to start working in ReactOS. Microsoft coined the term backwards compatibility, ReactOS the forward compatibility one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://reactos.org/sites/default/files/imagepicker/14095/quicktime.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; class=&quot;imgp_img&quot; width=&quot;90%&quot; height=&quot;768&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quicktime for Vista and 7 working in ReactOS!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new tool, a &lt;strong&gt;DrWatson32 alike&lt;/strong&gt;, has been created by Mark and added to 0.4.8, so now any application crashing will create a log file on the desktop. This crash dump details the list of modules and threads loaded, stack traces, hexdumps, and register state. Therefore, this new tool should help us understand what went wrong when the software crashed. Adding these reports, plus the debug logs, will provide ReactOS developers a good amount of information to understand what went wrong and how to create the needed fixes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://reactos.org/sites/default/files/imagepicker/14095/drwatson.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; class=&quot;imgp_img&quot; width=&quot;90%&quot; height=&quot;768&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;DrWatson-alike in action!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 0.4.7, several games were having trouble initializing properly when using &lt;strong&gt;native graphics drivers&lt;/strong&gt;. Jérome has not just fixed this issue but also a palette regression in DirectX which was garbling colors when playing games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Kernel Stability and new features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kernel stability in this version comes from the Memory Manager, File system and Cache Manager fixes. The latest Coverity scan, which tracks old and detects new issues, shows a great evolution since 0.4.7.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several bugs have been squashed in the ReactOS CC and Freeloader, allowing it to &lt;strong&gt;boot in 96MB&lt;/strong&gt; hardware (smaller RAM need than our 0.4.7 release). Talking about hardware, Pierre has fixed several bugs when writing the bootloader to disk and Serge has updated ACPI with extended features, that should bring some extra compatibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://reactos.org/sites/default/files/imagepicker/14095/ram.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; class=&quot;imgp_img&quot; width=&quot;90%&quot; height=&quot;768&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;ReactOS in 96MB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 0.4.7 the initial Cache Manager bugfixing was a great step forward in terms of stability. From 0.4.7 to 0.4.8, &lt;strong&gt;Cache Manager&lt;/strong&gt; has gone under a massive review lead by Thomas and Pierre. This work revealed several bugs thanks to the tests specifically created to ensure this review doesn't introduce new regressions. Among others, a 17-year-old bug which was introducing corruption in the file system and which is now finally fixed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the Cache Manager work hasn't just been focused on bug-hunting, but also adding new and needed features. Now the ReactOS 0.4.8 Common Cache supports &lt;strong&gt;Lazy Writing and Read Ahead&lt;/strong&gt;, which are major steps toward a performant operating system by reducing file access latencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other major component, the ReactOS &lt;strong&gt;Memory Manager&lt;/strong&gt;, has also received many fixes thanks to Timo, some revealed by Coverity and others due his work on the x64 ReactOS port which enforces a pointer-size agnostic Memory Manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Hardware support, NTFS and other drivers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the main objectives of each new ReactOS version is to improve the compatibility with hardware. In case you find any issues running ReactOS in your real hardware, please don't hesitate to file a bug report at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jira.reactos.org&quot;&gt;ReactOS bugtracker.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to these logs, we've discovered that old hardware and some virtual machines were &lt;strong&gt;failing to boot when an empty floppy drive was detected&lt;/strong&gt;. This bug has now been fixed and these hardware rigs are now enjoying ReactOS. Also these logs helped to detect several issues in &lt;strong&gt;PNP IRP handling&lt;/strong&gt; which has been fixed by Thomas for this new version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from fixing bugs in drivers, ReactOS includes some new ones in this version, such as a virtual floppy driver and a &lt;strong&gt;virtual CD-ROM driver&lt;/strong&gt;. Also the &lt;strong&gt;CDFS driver&lt;/strong&gt; has been replaced with the MSPL’ed original one after a full review. This review, as a curiosity, has revealed at least one bug, which has been sent upstream to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Microsoft/Windows-driver-samples/commit/f73e552f14ef61756b5fd1ebf8b5e98d8c6ca33b&quot;&gt;Microsoft GitHub&lt;/a&gt; with its proper fix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;NTFS driver&lt;/strong&gt; coded by Trevor, during GSOC 2016/2017, has been finally added. The NTFS driver has been an ongoing effort started by Hervé and Pierre, and which needed 2 different Google Summer Of Code to reach its current state. Under the mentoring of Pierre, Trevor Thomson has been coding and documenting his titanic NTFS coding efforts. If you're interested in file systems or how NTFS works and the tools needed to understand its behavior, &lt;a href=&quot;https://reactos.org/blogs/codertrevor&quot;&gt;you shouldn't miss the blog posts of Trevor&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks to these efforts ReactOS is able to read NTFS partitions in a more robust way, covering NTFS specific cases, and since 0.4.8, ReactOS introduces initial NTFS writing support. The NTFS writing feature is disabled but can be enabled through registry to test its experimental support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Third Parties&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ReactOS, as part of the open source ecosystem, also uses bits of several projects. 0.4.8 has been synced with Wine 3.0, Freetype 2.9 and Ext2 0.69, among other projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://reactos.org/wiki/0.4.8&quot;&gt;General notes&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://reactos.org/wiki/Tests_for_0.4.8&quot;&gt;tests&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://reactos.org/wiki/ChangeLog-0.4.8&quot;&gt;changelog&lt;/a&gt; for the release can be found at their respective links. A less technical &lt;a href=&quot;https://reactos.org/wiki/Community_Changelog-0.4.8&quot;&gt;community changelog&lt;/a&gt; for ReactOS 0.4.8 is also available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ISO images are ready on the ReactOS &lt;a href=&quot;https://reactos.org/download&quot;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Some statistics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;oldest bug&lt;/strong&gt; reported in Jira and fixed was &lt;a href=&quot;https://jira.reactos.org/browse/CORE-5127&quot;&gt;CORE-5127&lt;/a&gt; (advapi32: OpenTraceA (Sysinternals DiskMon2.01 dies with unhandled exception upon startup).&lt;br/&gt;Since 0.4.7, &lt;strong&gt;340 bugs have been resolved&lt;/strong&gt;: 211 marked as fixed, 37 as duplicates, 42 as won't fix, 21 as incomplete, 29 as cannot reproduce.&lt;br/&gt;320 bugs fixed were directly related with the operating system, 10 from ReactOS online services, 5 from ReactOS test suite and 5 from ReactOS Build Environment.&lt;br/&gt;Pull Requests committed: 209&lt;br/&gt;Forks: 248&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2018 20:29:27 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>bratao</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://reactos.org/project-news/reactos-048-released</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>