<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>When in doubt: hang up, look up, and call back</title>
<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2020/04/when-in-doubt-hang-up-look-up-call-back/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://krebsonsecurity.com/2020/04/when-in-doubt-hang-up-look-up-call-back/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Many security-conscious people probably think they’d never fall for a phone-based phishing scam. But if your response to such a scam involves anything other than hanging up and calling back the entity that claims to be calling, you may be in for a rude awakening. Here’s how one security and tech-savvy reader got taken for more than $10,000 in an elaborate, weeks-long ruse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-45224&quot; src=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/phonescam.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;598&quot; height=&quot;377&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today’s lesson in how not to get scammed comes from “Mitch,” the pseudonym I picked for a reader in California who shared his harrowing tale on condition of anonymity. Mitch is a veteran of the tech industry — having worked in security for several years at a fairly major cloud-based service — so he’s understandably embarrassed that he got taken in by this confidence scheme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Friday, April 17, Mitch received a call from what he thought was his financial institution, warning him that fraud had been detected on his account. Mitch said the caller ID for that incoming call displayed the same phone number that was printed on the back of his debit card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Mitch knew enough of scams to understand that fraudsters can and often do spoof phone numbers. So while still on the phone with the caller, he quickly logged into his account and saw that there were indeed multiple unauthorized transactions going back several weeks. Most were relatively small charges — under $100 apiece — but there were also two very recent $800 ATM withdrawals from cash machines in Florida.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the caller had been a fraudster, he reasoned at the time, they would have asked for personal information. But the nice lady on the phone didn’t ask Mitch for any personal details. Instead, she calmly assured him the bank would reverse the fraudulent charges and said they’d be sending him a new debit card via express mail. After making sure the representative knew which transactions were not his, Mitch thanked the woman for notifying him, and hung up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following day, Mitch received another call about suspected fraud on his bank account. Something about that conversation didn’t seem right, and so Mitch decided to use another phone to place a call to his bank’s customer service department — while keeping the first caller on hold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“When the representative finally answered my call, I asked them to confirm that I was on the phone with them on the other line in the call they initiated toward me, and so the rep somehow checked and saw that there was another active call with Mitch,” he said. “But as it turned out, that other call was the attackers also talking to my bank pretending to be me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mitch said his financial institution has in the past verified his identity over the phone by sending him a one-time code to the cell phone number on file for his account, and then asking him to read back that code. After he hung up with the customer service rep he’d phoned, the person on the original call said the bank would be sending him a one-time code to validate his identity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now confident he was speaking with a representative from his bank and not some fraudster, Mitch read back the code that appeared via text message shortly thereafter. After more assurances that any additional phony charges would be credited to his account and that he’d be receiving a new card soon, Mitch was annoyed but otherwise satisfied. He said he checked his account online several times over the weekend, but saw no further signs of unauthorized activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-45226&quot; src=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/cell8.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;598&quot; height=&quot;688&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is, until the following Monday, when Mitch once again logged in and saw that a $9,800 outgoing wire transfer had been posted to his account. At that point, it dawned on Mitch that both the Friday and Saturday calls he received had likely been from scammers — not from his bank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another call to his financial institution and some escalation to its fraud department confirmed that suspicion: The investigator said another man had called in on Saturday posing as Mitch, had provided a one-time code the bank texted to the phone number on file for Mitch’s account — the same code the real Mitch had been tricked into giving up — and then initiated an outgoing wire transfer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It appears the initial call on Friday was to make him think his bank was aware of and responding to active fraud against his account, when in actuality the bank was not at that time. Also, the Friday call helped to set up the bigger heist the following day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mitch said he and his bank now believe that at some point his debit card and PIN were stolen, most likely by a skimming device planted at a compromised point-of-sale terminal, gas pump or ATM he’d used in the past few weeks. Armed with a counterfeit copy of his debit card and PIN, the fraudsters could pull money out of his account at ATMs and go shopping in big box stores for various items. But to move lots of money out of his account all at once, they needed Mitch’s help.&lt;span id=&quot;more-51346&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make matters worse, the fraud investigator said the $9,800 wire transfer had been sent to an account at an online-only bank that also was in Mitch’s name. Mitch said he didn’t open that account, but that this may have helped the fraudsters sidestep any fraud flags for the unauthorized wire transfer, since from the bank’s perspective Mitch was merely wiring money to another one of his accounts. Now, he’s facing the arduous task of getting identity theft (new account fraud) cleaned up at the online-only bank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mitch said that in retrospect, there were several oddities that should have been additional red flags. For one thing, on his outbound call to the bank on Saturday while he had the fraudsters on hold, the customer service rep asked if he was visiting family in Florida.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mitch replied that no, he didn’t have any family members living there. But when he spoke with the bank’s fraud department the following Monday, the investigator said the fraudsters posing as Mitch had succeeded in adding a phony “travel notice” to his account — essentially notifying the bank that he was traveling to Florida and that it should disregard any geographic-based fraud alerts created by card-present transactions in that region. That would explain why his bank didn’t see anything strange about their California customer suddenly using his card in Florida.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, when the fake customer support rep called him, she stumbled a bit when Mitch turned the tables on her. As part of her phony customer verification script, she asked Mitch to state his physical address.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I told her, ‘You tell me,’ and she read me the address of the house I grew up in,” Mitch recalled. “So she was going through some public records she’d found, apparently, because they knew my previous employers and addresses. And she said, ‘Sir, I’m in a call center and there’s cameras over my head. I’m just doing my job.’ I just figured she was just new or shitty at her job, but who knows maybe she was telling the truth. Anyway, the whole time my girlfriend is sitting next to me listening to this conversation and she’s like, ‘This sounds like bullshit.'”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-40414&quot; src=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/phonefraud-580x580.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;580&quot; height=&quot;580&quot; srcset=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/phonefraud-580x580.jpg 580w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/phonefraud-580x580-150x150.jpg 150w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 580px) 100vw, 580px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mitch’s bank managed to reverse the unauthorized wire transfer before it could complete, and they’ve since put all the stolen funds back into his account and issued a new card. But he said he still feels like a chump for not observing the golden rule: If someone calls saying they’re from your bank, just hang up and call them back — ideally using a phone number that came from the bank’s Web site or from the back of your payment card. As it happened, Mitch only followed half of that advice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What else could have made it more difficult for fraudsters to get one over on Mitch? He could have enabled mobile alerts to receive text messages anytime a new transaction posts to his account. Barring that, he could have kept a closer eye on his bank account balance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If Mitch had previously &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/2018/09/credit-freezes-are-free-let-the-ice-age-begin/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;placed a security freeze on his credit file with the three major consumer credit bureaus&lt;/a&gt;, the fraudsters likely would not have been able to open a new online checking account in his name with which to receive the $9,800 wire transfer (although they might have still been able to wire the money to another account they controlled).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Mitch’s experience shows, many security-conscious people tend to focus on protecting their online selves, while perhaps discounting the threat from less technically sophisticated phone-based scams. In this case, Mitch and his bank determined that his assailants never once tried to log in to his account online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What’s interesting here is the entirety of the fraud was completed over the phone, and at no time did the scammers compromise my account online,” Mitch said. “I absolutely should have hung up and initiated the call myself. And as a security professional, that’s part of the shame that I will bear for a long time.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further reading:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/2018/10/voice-phishing-scams-are-getting-more-clever/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Voice Phishing Scams are Getting More Clever&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/2019/03/why-phone-numbers-stink-as-identity-proof/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Why Phone Numbers Stink as Identity Proof&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/2019/01/apple-phone-phishing-scams-getting-better/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Apple Phone Phishing Scams Getting Better&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/2018/11/sms-phishing-cardless-atm-profit/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;SMS Phishing + Cardless ATM = Profit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;mid-banner&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.akamai.com/us/en/campaign/edge-live.jsp?utm_source=krebsonsecurity&amp;amp;utm_medium=display&amp;amp;utm_id=F-MC-49935&amp;amp;utm_campaign=2020_Global_Display&amp;amp;utm_content=Edge_Live&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/b-akamai/52.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;postmetadata alt&quot;&gt;&lt;small&gt;This entry was posted on Thursday, April 23rd, 2020 at 1:27 pm and is filed under &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/category/sunshine/&quot; rel=&quot;category tag&quot;&gt;A Little Sunshine&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/category/latest-warnings/&quot; rel=&quot;category tag&quot;&gt;Latest Warnings&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/category/comingstorm/&quot; rel=&quot;category tag&quot;&gt;The Coming Storm&lt;/a&gt;. You can follow any comments to this entry through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/2020/04/when-in-doubt-hang-up-look-up-call-back/feed/&quot;&gt;RSS 2.0&lt;/a&gt; feed. You can skip to the end and leave a comment. Pinging is currently not allowed.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 17:32:59 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>todsacerdoti</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2020/04/when-in-doubt-hang-up-look-up-call-back/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Preliminary test results suggest 21% of NYC residents have Covid antibodies</title>
<link>https://www.6sqft.com/new-york-covid-antibody-test-preliminary-results/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.6sqft.com/new-york-covid-antibody-test-preliminary-results/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;small&gt;Image by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scientificanimations.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Scientific Animations&lt;/a&gt; via &lt;a href=&quot;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:3D_medical_animation_coronavirus_structure.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Wikimedia Commons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his press conference today, Governor Cuomo revealed the preliminary results of a first-phase antibody test that surveyed 3,000 New Yorkers over two days in 19 counties at 40 locations that included grocery and big-box stores. The sample suggests that &lt;strong&gt;13.9%&lt;/strong&gt; of New York State residents have the antibodies, meaning they had the virus at one point and recovered. Of the regions tested–Long Island, NYC, Westchester/Rockland, and the rest of the State–New York City had the highest positive rate at &lt;strong&gt;21.2%&lt;/strong&gt;. The potential good news to come to light is that the death rate may be far lower than some estimates, at 0.5%.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The reason the tests were randomly taken from those at grocery and big-box stores is that these were people not isolating in their homes and presumably not at work and therefore not essential workers. Though the governor didn’t mention it, this could also point to a truer representation of how many people are asymptomatic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-197822 pib-hover-img&quot; src=&quot;https://imgs.6sqft.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/23121131/NY-antibody-test-phase-1-region.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1154&quot; height=&quot;644&quot; srcset=&quot;https://imgs.6sqft.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/23121131/NY-antibody-test-phase-1-region.png 1154w, https://imgs.6sqft.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/23121131/NY-antibody-test-phase-1-region-300x167.png 300w, https://imgs.6sqft.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/23121131/NY-antibody-test-phase-1-region-768x429.png 768w, https://imgs.6sqft.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/23121131/NY-antibody-test-phase-1-region-1024x571.png 1024w, https://imgs.6sqft.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/23121131/NY-antibody-test-phase-1-region-440x246.png 440w, https://imgs.6sqft.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/23121131/NY-antibody-test-phase-1-region-90x50.png 90w, https://imgs.6sqft.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/23121131/NY-antibody-test-phase-1-region-280x156.png 280w, https://imgs.6sqft.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/23121131/NY-antibody-test-phase-1-region-679x380.png 679w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1154px) 100vw, 1154px&quot; data-pin-url=&quot;https://www.6sqft.com/new-york-covid-antibody-test-preliminary-results/&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;small&gt;Powerpoint slide from Governor Cuomo’s 4/23/20 press briefing&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The regional breakdown suggests that about 1/5 of NYC residents have had the virus, which is roughly 1.68 million people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-197823 pib-hover-img&quot; src=&quot;https://imgs.6sqft.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/23121137/NY-antibody-test-phase-1-sex.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1158&quot; height=&quot;542&quot; srcset=&quot;https://imgs.6sqft.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/23121137/NY-antibody-test-phase-1-sex.png 1158w, https://imgs.6sqft.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/23121137/NY-antibody-test-phase-1-sex-300x140.png 300w, https://imgs.6sqft.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/23121137/NY-antibody-test-phase-1-sex-768x359.png 768w, https://imgs.6sqft.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/23121137/NY-antibody-test-phase-1-sex-1024x479.png 1024w, https://imgs.6sqft.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/23121137/NY-antibody-test-phase-1-sex-440x206.png 440w, https://imgs.6sqft.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/23121137/NY-antibody-test-phase-1-sex-90x42.png 90w, https://imgs.6sqft.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/23121137/NY-antibody-test-phase-1-sex-280x131.png 280w, https://imgs.6sqft.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/23121137/NY-antibody-test-phase-1-sex-679x318.png 679w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1158px) 100vw, 1158px&quot; data-pin-url=&quot;https://www.6sqft.com/new-york-covid-antibody-test-preliminary-results/&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-197821 pib-hover-img&quot; src=&quot;https://imgs.6sqft.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/23121125/NY-antibody-test-phase-1-race.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1148&quot; height=&quot;646&quot; srcset=&quot;https://imgs.6sqft.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/23121125/NY-antibody-test-phase-1-race.png 1148w, https://imgs.6sqft.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/23121125/NY-antibody-test-phase-1-race-300x169.png 300w, https://imgs.6sqft.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/23121125/NY-antibody-test-phase-1-race-768x432.png 768w, https://imgs.6sqft.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/23121125/NY-antibody-test-phase-1-race-1024x576.png 1024w, https://imgs.6sqft.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/23121125/NY-antibody-test-phase-1-race-440x248.png 440w, https://imgs.6sqft.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/23121125/NY-antibody-test-phase-1-race-90x51.png 90w, https://imgs.6sqft.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/23121125/NY-antibody-test-phase-1-race-280x158.png 280w, https://imgs.6sqft.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/23121125/NY-antibody-test-phase-1-race-679x382.png 679w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1148px) 100vw, 1148px&quot; data-pin-url=&quot;https://www.6sqft.com/new-york-covid-antibody-test-preliminary-results/&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-197820 pib-hover-img&quot; src=&quot;https://imgs.6sqft.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/23121119/NY-antibody-test-phase-1-age.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1152&quot; height=&quot;644&quot; srcset=&quot;https://imgs.6sqft.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/23121119/NY-antibody-test-phase-1-age.png 1152w, https://imgs.6sqft.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/23121119/NY-antibody-test-phase-1-age-300x168.png 300w, https://imgs.6sqft.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/23121119/NY-antibody-test-phase-1-age-768x429.png 768w, https://imgs.6sqft.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/23121119/NY-antibody-test-phase-1-age-1024x572.png 1024w, https://imgs.6sqft.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/23121119/NY-antibody-test-phase-1-age-440x246.png 440w, https://imgs.6sqft.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/23121119/NY-antibody-test-phase-1-age-90x50.png 90w, https://imgs.6sqft.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/23121119/NY-antibody-test-phase-1-age-280x157.png 280w, https://imgs.6sqft.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/23121119/NY-antibody-test-phase-1-age-679x380.png 679w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1152px) 100vw, 1152px&quot; data-pin-url=&quot;https://www.6sqft.com/new-york-covid-antibody-test-preliminary-results/&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;small&gt;Powerpoint slides from Governor Cuomo’s 4/23/20 press briefing&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The demographic breakdowns have a few more caveats. For example, the African American and Latino persons were disproportionately in NYC, and the white persons were more upstate. With age, the assumption is that most persons 75+ are isolating and therefore aren’t out and about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What the 13.9% infection rate suggests is that the death rate is far lower than originally thought. This suggests that 2.7 million have been infected. With approximately 15,500 total fatalities, the death rate would be 0.5%. However, this is only preliminary data and does not include in-home deaths (it only includes those reported from hospitals and nursing homes).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The state will continue its antibody testing on a rolling basis to increase the sample, though no specifics were given on a second phase. The governor said that this will provide snapshots as to how the rate is changing over time, which will help inform &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.6sqft.com/new-york-lays-out-phased-reopening-blueprint-will-begin-state-wide-antibody-testing/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;reopening decisions&lt;/a&gt;. He also noted that the results support the theory that reopening should be done on a regional basis as not every part of the state has the same infection rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RELATED:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p class=&quot;single-tag&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tags :&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.6sqft.com/tag/antibody-testing/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;antibody testing&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.6sqft.com/tag/coronavirus/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;coronavirus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 17:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kgwgk</dc:creator>
<og:title>Preliminary test results suggest 21.2% of NYC residents have COVID antibodies | 6sqft</og:title>
<og:type>blog</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.6sqft.com/new-york-covid-antibody-test-preliminary-results/</og:url>
<og:image>https://imgs.6sqft.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/23120533/coronavirus-1024x576.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Governor Cuomo revealed the preliminary results of a first-phase antibody test that surveyed 3,000 New Yorkers over two days in 19 counties at 40 locations.</og:description>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.6sqft.com/new-york-covid-antibody-test-preliminary-results/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Instagram no longer allows people without an account to view photos on computers</title>
<link>https://manualdousuario.net/instagram-photos-videos-unlogged-on-computers/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://manualdousuario.net/instagram-photos-videos-unlogged-on-computers/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Instagram raised the wall that separates people who do not have an account from those who do. Since at least April 21st, Instagram doesn’t allow unregistered people to view photos and videos from public profiles on computers and tablets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Public profiles, those that don’t have the padlock that restricts content to registered followers, have always been accessible regardless of login. Not anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-21783&quot;/&gt;Several tests made by &lt;strong&gt;Manual do Usuário&lt;/strong&gt; showed that access to photos and videos by unlogged people is only working on mobile phones. When trying to see something from a public profile on a computer or tablet, they are presented with a login and registration form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-21773&quot; src=&quot;https://manualdousuario.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/print-instagram-chrome-windows-960x513.png&quot; alt=&quot;Print do Instagram pedindo login no navegador Chrome no Windows.&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;513&quot; srcset=&quot;https://manualdousuario.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/print-instagram-chrome-windows-960x513.png 960w, https://manualdousuario.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/print-instagram-chrome-windows-768x410.png 768w, https://manualdousuario.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/print-instagram-chrome-windows.png 1366w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px&quot;/&gt;In Chrome, on a Windows computer, the error occurs.
&lt;p&gt;Tests were conducted on Windows and macOS computers, in different Brazilian cities, with mobile and domestic internet connections, in multiple browsers, and with ad-blocking extensions disabled. In all cases, the blockage persisted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Changing the browser’s “user-agent”, a kind of public identifier that informs sites the type of device that is accessing them, changes Instagram’s behavior. When a computer browser is identified as a mobile phone (Android or iPhone), photos and videos open normally. The following video demonstrates this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/411067800?title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; fullscreen&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, photos and videos published on Instagram’s feed now work as stories, which have always been restricted to people logged into Instagram.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many small businesses and professionals use Instagram as their only point of contact with customers, a fact that makes this change troublesome for those who, for whatever reason, do not have and do not intend to have an account there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strike&gt;I have contacted Instagram asking about this change. Until this publication, there had been no answer. If that changes, I will update this post.&lt;/strike&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ctx-atualizacao&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Updated:&lt;/strong&gt; Instagram answered my request. “If you are not logged in Instagram, you may only see a certain amount of posts on public profiles before being asked to login”, they said. “This is to help people view photos in Instagram and understand how to have the best experience on the platform, be part of the community, connecting and interacting with people and the things they love”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a different issue. Since at least November 2019, viewing of public post is limited when a person not logged scrolls the page a bit — see &lt;a href=&quot;https://thenextweb.com/socialmedia/2019/10/28/instagram-now-forces-people-to-sign-in-to-view-public-profiles/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;this report from &lt;em&gt;The Next Web&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. What is new is a much more restrict limit, which doesn’t allow unlogged people to see even one photo or video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Manual do Usuário&lt;/strong&gt; is a Brazilian independent tech blog that only publishes original reporting, mostly in Portuguese, but once in a while in English as well. If you want to be notified about future posts in English, please subscribe to our free newsletter. Your email address will never be transferred, shared or sold:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 16:48:37 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rpgbr</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Instagram no longer allows people without an account to view photos and videos on computers</og:title>
<og:description>Instagram now limits displaying photos and videos from public profiles to unlogged people who try to view them on computers or tablets.</og:description>
<og:url>https://manualdousuario.net/instagram-photos-videos-unlogged-on-computers/</og:url>
<og:image>https://manualdousuario.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/instagram-bloqueando-deslogados-1440x877.png</og:image>
<dc:language>pt-BR</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://manualdousuario.net/instagram-photos-videos-unlogged-on-computers/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>If a MacBook Pro runs hot or shows high kernel CPU, try charging it on the right</title>
<link>https://apple.stackexchange.com/a/363933/182292</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://apple.stackexchange.com/a/363933/182292</guid>
<description>&lt;h3&gt;TLDR; If your MacBook Pro runs hot or shows a high % CPU for the kernel task, try charging on the right and not on the left.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;High &lt;code&gt;kernel_task&lt;/code&gt; CPU Usage is due to &lt;strong&gt;high chassis temperature caused by charging&lt;/strong&gt;. In particular &lt;strong&gt;Left&lt;/strong&gt; Thunderbolt port usage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solutions include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Move charging from the left to the right side. If you have a second charger then plug it in on the right side. Avoid plugging everything on the right side (see last paragraph below).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unplug something from the left side. Either power or another accessory until the battery is full.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Force fans to max before plugging in. iStatMenus has an easy Sensors -&amp;gt; Fans menu item to do so. This only helps in marginal conditions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Move to a cooler room.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Proof:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actual CPU temperature or application CPU usage is uncorrelated with &lt;code&gt;kernel_task&lt;/code&gt;. A hot CPU is throttled by reducing its clock speed, not by scheduling fake no-op load.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The graphs below are from iStatMenus. The machine had been used on battery then plugged in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;State A&lt;/em&gt; a USB-C hub (a mouse and keyboard, plus power) and a USB-C HDMI 2.0 adapter, both on the left side. You can see the &lt;em&gt;Thunderbolt Left Proximity&lt;/em&gt; temperature sensor rise quickly. About 3-4 minutes later the dreaded &lt;code&gt;kernel_task&lt;/code&gt; high CPU usage starts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;State B&lt;/em&gt; cures the &lt;code&gt;kernel_task&lt;/code&gt; problem by moving power from the left ports to the right. The left side temperature drops and the &lt;code&gt;kernel_task&lt;/code&gt; goes away within about 15 seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is causal. Moving power back to the left side, restoring &lt;em&gt;State A&lt;/em&gt;, quickly restores the temperatures and &lt;code&gt;kernel_task&lt;/code&gt; again comes back after 3-4 minutes. Again moving power back to the right side, restoring &lt;em&gt;State B&lt;/em&gt;, resolves the problem immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;State C&lt;/em&gt; shows that simply having stuff plugged in to TB ports raises their temperature significantly. Both the hub (mouse and keyboard ONLY) and HDMI adapter individually raise the temperature about 10 degrees, and 15 degrees together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/eRNpK.png&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/eRNpK.png&quot; alt=&quot;CPU usage and temperature graphs&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(all other temperatures were both low and flat. Under 55 degrees.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that high temperature on the right side appears to be ignored by the OS. Plugging everything into the two right ports instead of the left raised the Right temperatures to over 100 degrees, without the fans coming on. No &lt;code&gt;kernel_task&lt;/code&gt; either, but the machine becomes unusable from &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; throttling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ergo, &lt;strong&gt;high CPU usage by &lt;code&gt;kernel_task&lt;/code&gt; is caused by high &lt;em&gt;Thunderbolt Left Proximity&lt;/em&gt; temperature, which is caused by charging and having normal peripherals plugged in at the same time.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2017 15&quot; Macbook Pro, MacOS 10.14.5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;To actually answer the question:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I find out what this process is doing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only way to actually ask the kernel what it's doing is to attach a kernel debugger. That means getting a debug kernel from Apple, rebooting, then using &lt;em&gt;a second Mac&lt;/em&gt; to attach to the debugged machine. You can then examine stack traces and guess what they mean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Otherwise guessing and testing is the only way. Of course that leads to false conclusions more often than not.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 16:17:34 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>gkop</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://apple.stackexchange.com/questions/363337/how-to-find-cause-of-high-kernel-task-cpu-usage</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn.sstatic.net/Sites/apple/img/apple-touch-icon@2.png?v=b514451ec60c</og:image>
<og:title>How to find cause of high kernel_task cpu usage?</og:title>
<og:description>Occasionally my machine will have a kernel_task instance max out the CPU: This can last from minutes to sometimes hours. The machine is effectively unusable in this state. Restarting doesn't help;...</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://apple.stackexchange.com/questions/363337/how-to-find-cause-of-high-kernel-task-cpu-usage/363933</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Medical staffing companies cut doctors’ pay while spending millions on ads</title>
<link>https://www.propublica.org/article/medical-staffing-companies-cut-doctors-pay-while-spending-millions-on-political-ads</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.propublica.org/article/medical-staffing-companies-cut-doctors-pay-while-spending-millions-on-political-ads</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;
A medical worker at a coronavirus drive-thru testing site in Washington, D.C., on April 2. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;168.04366812227&quot;&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;promo x-small left&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;series-entry&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;lead-art&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;aspect-3-2&quot; href=&quot;https://www.propublica.org/series/coronavirus&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;267&quot; src=&quot;https://assets-c3.propublica.org/images/series/_threeTwo400w/20200326-coronavirus-3x2.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://assets-c3.propublica.org/images/series/_threeTwo400w/20200326-coronavirus-3x2.jpg 400w, https://assets-c3.propublica.org/images/series/_threeTwo800w/20200326-coronavirus-3x2.jpg 800w, https://assets-c3.propublica.org/images/series/_threeTwo1200w/20200326-coronavirus-3x2.jpg 1200w&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;top-notes&quot; readability=&quot;5.6178571428571&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;note&quot; id=&quot;newsletter-txt-note&quot; readability=&quot;6.9142857142857&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ProPublica is a nonprofit newsroom that investigates abuses of power. Sign up to receive &lt;a href=&quot;https://go.propublica.org/big-story-2019&quot;&gt;our biggest stories&lt;/a&gt; as soon as they’re published.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;1.0&quot;&gt;Private equity-backed medical staffing companies that have cut doctors’ pay are continuing to spend millions on political ads, according to Federal Communications Commission &lt;a href=&quot;https://publicfiles.fcc.gov/&quot;&gt;disclosures&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;1.1&quot;&gt;The ads amount to $2.2 million since Health and Human Services Secretary Alex Azar declared a public health emergency on Jan. 31. About $1.2 million has been spent since President Donald Trump’s national emergency declaration on March 13, the disclosures show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;1.2&quot;&gt;The companies behind the ads, TeamHealth and Envision Healthcare, are among the staffing firms that have &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.propublica.org/article/overwhelmed-hospitals-face-a-new-crisis-staffing-firms-are-cutting-their-doctors-hours-and-pay&quot;&gt;cut pay and benefits&lt;/a&gt; for emergency room doctors and other medical workers. The companies say the cuts are needed to cope with falling income because non-coronavirus patients are avoiding hospitals. Executives at TeamHealth and Envision also took pay cuts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;1.3&quot;&gt;“Our attention will be focused on our clinicians so they can provide care for patients who need it,” Envision CEO Jim Rechtin said in a statement this month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;1.4&quot;&gt;But Envision and TeamHealth have continued to pour money into a joint political ad campaign. Their TV and radio spots are aimed at pressuring lawmakers working to address “surprise billing,” where patients get stuck with huge medical costs from out-of-network providers they had no say in choosing. The ads oppose capping out-of-network costs based on median prices in the area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside data-pp-blocktype=&quot;canned-promo&quot; class=&quot;canned-promo special-coronavirus large left&quot; readability=&quot;-9.3333333333333&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;icon&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.propublica.org/static/v4/images/callout.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;h3 class=&quot;aside-head&quot;&gt;Help Us Report on Coronavirus&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;aside-dek&quot;&gt;Are you a public health worker, medical provider, elected official, patient or other COVID-19 expert? &lt;a href=&quot;https:///www.propublica.org/getinvolved/we-want-to-talk-to-people-working-or-living-on-the-front-lines-of-coronavirus-help-us-report&quot;&gt;Help make sure our journalism is responsible and focused on the right issues.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;aside-note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; If you develop emergency warning signs for COVID-19, such as difficulty breathing or bluish lips, get medical attention immediately. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/if-you-are-sick/steps-when-sick.html&quot;&gt;The CDC has more information on what to do if you are sick.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;3.0&quot;&gt;The air time was bought through Doctor Patient Unity, an advocacy group &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/09/13/upshot/surprise-billing-laws-ad-spending-doctor-patient-unity.html&quot;&gt;funded&lt;/a&gt; by staffing firms TeamHealth and Envision. TeamHealth, which has more than 16,000 clinicians, is owned by Blackstone, and KKR owns Envision, with more than 25,000 medical providers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;3.1&quot;&gt;Doctor Patient Unity has spent $57 million on ads since its campaign started last June, making it the largest political advertiser other than presidential campaigns, according to Advertising Analytics, an ad-tracking firm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;3.2&quot;&gt;Doctor Patient Unity stood by its campaign and vowed to continue fighting against legislation that the group says would hurt doctors. “It was a misguided proposal before COVID-19 – it’s reckless in this current environment,” spokesman Greg Blair said in a statement. “While the big insurance companies continue to report massive earnings amid an unprecedented economic downturn, we remain committed to defending our doctors and clinicians as they fight COVID-19 on the frontlines.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;3.3&quot;&gt;TeamHealth and Envision declined to comment beyond Blair’s statement. Blackstone and KKR didn’t respond to requests for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;3.4&quot;&gt;The spending totals don’t include digital ads, which aren’t reported to the FCC. Facebook’s own &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/ads/library/?active_status=all&amp;amp;ad_type=all&amp;amp;country=US&amp;amp;impression_search_field=has_impressions_lifetime&amp;amp;view_all_page_id=2267405033373814&quot;&gt;disclosures&lt;/a&gt; show several thousand dollars more on recent ads invoking the coronavirus pandemic to make their case. Some of the ads name individual lawmakers and target their constituents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;3.5&quot;&gt;“Doctors are stepping up to face the coronavirus crisis,” an ad from April said. “During this crisis, Congress needs to ensure they have the resources they need to continue saving lives.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://assets-c3.propublica.org/images/articles/_threeTwo400w/20200420-fb-ad-shadow-b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;697&quot; srcset=&quot;https://assets-c3.propublica.org/images/articles/_threeTwo400w/20200420-fb-ad-shadow-b.jpg 400w, https://assets-c3.propublica.org/images/articles/_threeTwo800w/20200420-fb-ad-shadow-b.jpg 800w, https://assets-c3.propublica.org/images/articles/_threeTwo1600w/20200420-fb-ad-shadow-b.jpg 1600w, https://assets-c3.propublica.org/images/articles/_threeTwo2000w/20200420-fb-ad-shadow-b.jpg 2000w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 1720px) 826px, (min-width: 780px) calc(46.09vw + 43px), (min-width: 600px) 59.38vw, 93.21vw&quot;/&gt; A Facebook ad paid for by Doctor Patient Unity, an advocacy group funded by staffing firms TeamHealth and Envision Healthcare. &lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;(Screenshot obtained by ProPublica)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;5.0&quot;&gt;A professional group representing ER doctors &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.propublica.org/article/medical-staffing-companies-owned-by-rich-investors-cut-doctor-pay-and-now-want-bailout-money&quot;&gt;asked Azar&lt;/a&gt; to provide $3.6 billion of aid to emergency physician practices. The professional group’s president who signed the request is an executive at Envision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;5.1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://projects.propublica.org/represent/members/W000817-elizabeth-warren&quot;&gt;Sen. Elizabeth Warren, D-Mass.&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://projects.propublica.org/represent/members/P000618-katie-porter&quot;&gt;Rep. Katie Porter, D-Calif.&lt;/a&gt;, called on the companies’ private equity backers to reverse the pay cuts, citing ProPublica’s earlier reporting. “As business leaders who direct and manage billions of dollars, you should be stepping up to protect the financial security of frontline essential workers,” Porter and Warren said in an April 15 &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/RepKatiePorter/status/1250524828274249728?s=20&quot;&gt;letter&lt;/a&gt;. “They are putting themselves at risk every single day to provide for those fighting COVID-19, and to put them at risk of financial harm during this time is unacceptable.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;5.2&quot;&gt;Lawmakers have spent months hammering out a deal on surprise billing that balances the interests of patients, doctors and insurers. House and Senate committee chairs and ranking members struck a bipartisan compromise but weren’t able to get it included in the December spending deal or the March coronavirus stimulus package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;5.3&quot;&gt;The ads from Doctor Patient Unity oppose that bill because it would settle out-of-network bills according to median costs in the area, an approach that the ads attack as “government rate setting.” The ads urge viewers to call their representatives to thank them for opposing the proposal or urge them to oppose it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside data-pp-id=&quot;6&quot; data-pp-blocktype=&quot;promo&quot; class=&quot;promo small right&quot;&gt;&lt;h3 class=&quot;aside-head&quot;&gt;Read More&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;story-entry section-articles&quot; readability=&quot;23.8&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;lead-art&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;aspect-3-2&quot; href=&quot;https://www.propublica.org/article/medical-staffing-companies-owned-by-rich-investors-cut-doctor-pay-and-now-want-bailout-money&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://assets-c3.propublica.org/images/articles/_threeTwo400w/20200410-medical-staffing-3x2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;267&quot; srcset=&quot;https://assets-c3.propublica.org/images/articles/_threeTwo400w/20200410-medical-staffing-3x2.jpg 400w, https://assets-c3.propublica.org/images/articles/_threeTwo800w/20200410-medical-staffing-3x2.jpg 800w, https://assets-c3.propublica.org/images/articles/_threeTwo1200w/20200410-medical-staffing-3x2.jpg 1200w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 1720px) 335px, (min-width: 960px) calc(18.38vw + 23px), (min-width: 780px) 18.75vw, (min-width: 600px) 27.5vw, 43.21vw&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;7.0&quot;&gt;Blair, the group’s spokesman, said the legislation would “impose a 20% pay cut on our medical professionals, risking hospital closures and making it harder for patients to get the critical care they need.” The 20% figure, Blair said, is based on a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbo.gov/system/files/2019-07/s1895_0.pdf&quot;&gt;Congressional Budget Office report&lt;/a&gt; from July. But the CBO report does not predict a 20% drop across to board; rather, it says the proposal to pay out-of-network bills based on local median rates would push the average (mean) rate to converge on the median, a difference of 15% to 20% nationwide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;7.1&quot;&gt;“Under current law, the distribution of payment rates across all providers is highly skewed — some command rates that are well above the median,” the CBO analysts wrote. “Although the national average rate may drop by such an amount, the effects within a given market for any particular insurer and for specific providers will be quite different, with payment rates rising in some cases and falling in others.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;7.2&quot;&gt;An advocacy group representing health insurers, who are at odds with the staffing firms over the proposed legislation, called Doctor Patient Unity’s ads misleading. “At a time when they are cutting back benefits and pay for their own employees, they prefer to invest more resources in running a disingenuous ad campaign about their support for doctors,” the Coalition Against Surprise Medical Billing said in a statement to ProPublica. “Give us a break. Millions of patients are at risk of receiving a bankrupting surprise medical bill because these companies and out-of-network providers continue to exploit the market.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;7.3&quot;&gt;Envision has said it won’t send surprise bills to COVID-19 patients, so patients will be responsible only for in-network copays. TeamHealth &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.teamhealth.com/news-and-resources/featured-article/as-coronavirus-unfolds-teamhealth-upholds-commitment-to-patients-no-balance-billing/&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; it won’t bill patients above what insurers pay (known as “balance billing”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;7.4&quot;&gt;“They’ve always just been worried more about the bottom line than being appreciative of their people,” said an Envision doctor whose pay was cut and who spoke on the condition of anonymity because the company has prohibited employees from speaking publicly. “Physicians don’t feel like they’re being heard and respected for what they do, but we still show up and take care of patients. This is part of what’s breaking the system down.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr id=&quot;jump-to-coronavirus-callout&quot;/&gt;&lt;aside data-pp-blocktype=&quot;canned-promo&quot; class=&quot;canned-promo special-coronavirus-callout large left&quot; readability=&quot;-17.347826086957&quot;&gt;&lt;h3 class=&quot;aside-head&quot;&gt;Tell Us More About Coronavirus&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;dek&quot;&gt;Are you a public health worker, medical provider, elected official, patient or other COVID-19 expert? Help make sure our journalism is responsible and focused on the right issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;small&gt;Powered by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dobt.co/screendoor/&quot;&gt;Screendoor&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/small&gt; &lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;topics-list&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Filed under:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 15:55:57 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>hhs</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.propublica.org/article/medical-staffing-companies-cut-doctors-pay-while-spending-millions-on-political-ads</og:url>
<og:title>Medical Staffing Companies Cut Doctors’ Pay While Spending Millions…</og:title>
<og:description>While cutting benefits for emergency room doctors and other medical workers, TeamHealth and Envision have spent millions on ads meant to pressure politicians working on legislation to cap out-of-network costs for Americans.</og:description>
<og:image>https://assets-c3.propublica.org/images/articles/_1200x630_crop_center-center_82_none/20200420-PE-staffing-ads-OG.jpg?mtime=1587403284</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.propublica.org/article/medical-staffing-companies-cut-doctors-pay-while-spending-millions-on-political-ads</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Rust 1.43</title>
<link>https://blog.rust-lang.org/2020/04/23/Rust-1.43.0.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.rust-lang.org/2020/04/23/Rust-1.43.0.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Apr. 23, 2020 · The Rust Release Team&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;93.655778894472&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Rust team is happy to announce a new version of Rust, 1.43.0. Rust is a programming language that is empowering everyone to build reliable and efficient software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have a previous version of Rust installed via rustup, getting Rust 1.43.0 is as easy as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-console&quot;&gt;rustup update stable
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don't have it already, you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rust-lang.org/install.html&quot;&gt;get &lt;code&gt;rustup&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; from the appropriate page on our website, and check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/blob/master/RELEASES.md#version-1430-2020-04-23&quot;&gt;detailed release notes for 1.43.0&lt;/a&gt; on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What's in 1.43.0 stable&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This release is fairly minor. There are no new major features. We have some new stabilized APIs, some compiler performance improvements, and a small macro-related feature. See the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/blob/master/RELEASES.md#version-1430-2020-04-23&quot;&gt;detailed release notes&lt;/a&gt; to learn about other changes not covered by this post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;code&gt;item&lt;/code&gt; fragments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In macros, you can use &lt;code&gt;item&lt;/code&gt; fragments to interpolate items into the body of traits, impls, and extern blocks. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-rust&quot;&gt;macro_rules! mac_trait {
    ($i:item) =&amp;gt; {
        trait T { $i }
    }
}
mac_trait! {
    fn foo() {}
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will generate:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-rust&quot;&gt;trait T {
    fn foo() {}
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Type inference around primitives&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The type inference around primitives, references, and binary operations was improved. A code sample makes this easier to understand: this code fails to compile on Rust 1.42, but compiles in Rust 1.43.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-rust&quot;&gt;let n: f32 = 0.0 + &amp;amp;0.0;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Rust 1.42, you would get an error that would say &quot;hey, I don't know how to add an &lt;code&gt;f64&lt;/code&gt; and an &lt;code&gt;&amp;amp;f64&lt;/code&gt; with a result of &lt;code&gt;f32&lt;/code&gt;.&quot; The algorithm now correctly decides that both &lt;code&gt;0.0&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;&amp;amp;0.0&lt;/code&gt; should be &lt;code&gt;f32&lt;/code&gt;s instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;New Cargo environment variable for tests&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a move to help integration testing, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/cargo/pull/7697&quot;&gt;Cargo will set some new environment variables&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is easiest to explain by example: let's say we're working on a command line project, simply named &quot;cli&quot;. If we're writing an integration test, we want to invoke that &lt;code&gt;cli&lt;/code&gt; binary and see what it does. When running tests and benchmarks, Cargo will set an environment variable named &lt;code&gt;CARGO_BIN_EXE_cli&lt;/code&gt;, and I can use it inside my test:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-rust&quot;&gt;let exe = env!(&quot;CARGO_BIN_EXE_cli&quot;);
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This makes it easier to invoke &lt;code&gt;cli&lt;/code&gt;, as we now have a path to it directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Library changes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/68952/&quot;&gt;You can now use associated constants on floats and integers directly&lt;/a&gt;, rather than having to import the module. That is, you can now write &lt;code&gt;u32::MAX&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;f32::NAN&lt;/code&gt; with no &lt;code&gt;use std::u32;&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;use std::f32;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/67637/&quot;&gt;new &lt;code&gt;primitive&lt;/code&gt; module&lt;/a&gt; that re-exports Rust's primitive types. This can be useful when you're writing a macro and want to make sure that the types aren't shadowed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, we stabilized six new APIs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Other changes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are other changes in the Rust 1.43.0 release: check out what changed in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/blob/master/RELEASES.md#version-1430-2020-04-23&quot;&gt;Rust&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/cargo/blob/master/CHANGELOG.md#cargo-143-2020-04-23&quot;&gt;Cargo&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust-clippy/blob/master/CHANGELOG.md#rust-143&quot;&gt;Clippy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Contributors to 1.43.0&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people came together to create Rust 1.43.0. We couldn't have done it without all of you. &lt;a href=&quot;https://thanks.rust-lang.org/rust/1.43.0/&quot;&gt;Thanks!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 15:18:40 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>steveklabnik</dc:creator>
<og:title>Announcing Rust 1.43.0 | Rust Blog</og:title>
<og:description>Empowering everyone to build reliable and efficient software.</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.rust-lang.org/static/images/rust-social-wide.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.rust-lang.org/2020/04/23/Rust-1.43.0.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The ProtonMail Android app is now open source</title>
<link>https://protonmail.com/blog/android-open-source/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://protonmail.com/blog/android-open-source/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Starting today, every app you use to access your ProtonMail inbox is open source and has passed an independent security audit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of our guiding principles is transparency. You deserve to know &lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; aria-label=&quot; (opens in a new tab)&quot; href=&quot;https://protonmail.com/about&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;who we are&lt;/a&gt;, how our products &lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; aria-label=&quot; (opens in a new tab)&quot; href=&quot;https://protonmail.com/blog/protonmail-threat-model/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;can and cannot protect you&lt;/a&gt;, and how we &lt;a href=&quot;https://protonmail.com/privacy-policy&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; aria-label=&quot;keep your data private (opens in a new tab)&quot;&gt;keep your data private&lt;/a&gt;. We believe this level of transparency is the only way to earn the trust of our community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To that end, open source has long been a priority at Proton. Our &lt;a href=&quot;https://protonmail.com/blog/protonmail-open-source/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; aria-label=&quot; (opens in a new tab)&quot;&gt;web app has been open source&lt;/a&gt; since 2015, our &lt;a href=&quot;https://protonmail.com/blog/ios-open-source/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; aria-label=&quot; (opens in a new tab)&quot;&gt;iOS app is open source&lt;/a&gt;, our desktop &lt;a href=&quot;https://protonmail.com/blog/bridge-open-source/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; aria-label=&quot; (opens in a new tab)&quot;&gt;Bridge app is open source&lt;/a&gt;, and all &lt;a href=&quot;https://protonvpn.com/blog/open-source/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; aria-label=&quot; (opens in a new tab)&quot;&gt;ProtonVPN apps are open source&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This means that all Proton apps that are out of beta are open source.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today we add the ProtonMail Android app to this list. The code is available on our &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ProtonMail/proton-mail-android&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; aria-label=&quot;GitHub page (opens in a new tab)&quot;&gt;GitHub page&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of making our Android app open source, we commissioned an independent security audit from &lt;a href=&quot;https://sec-consult.com/en/&quot;&gt;SEC Consult&lt;/a&gt;. Their audit found that our app has no outstanding vulnerabilities. We have also published the &lt;a href=&quot;https://protonmail.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Report_1907974_Proton_Technologies_AG_Source_Code_Review_-_ProtonMail_Android_1.2_public.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; aria-label=&quot;full audit report (opens in a new tab)&quot;&gt;full audit report&lt;/a&gt; on our website. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Open source at Proton&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your safety is our number one priority. &lt;strong&gt;Open sourcing our code increases the security of our apps&lt;/strong&gt; because it allows us to leverage the entire IT security community to search for vulnerabilities. Those who discover vulnerabilities may be eligible for our &lt;a href=&quot;https://protonmail.com/blog/protonmail-bug-bounty-program/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; aria-label=&quot; (opens in a new tab)&quot;&gt;bug bounty program&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means that the &lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; aria-label=&quot; (opens in a new tab)&quot; href=&quot;https://protonmail.com/blog/protesters-free-speech/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;activists&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; aria-label=&quot; (opens in a new tab)&quot; href=&quot;https://protonmail.com/blog/bellingcat-cyberattack-phishing/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;journalists&lt;/a&gt; who rely on our service can be confident their communications will remain private.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Open source code contributes to a free Internet&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our goal is to bring security, privacy, and freedom to the Internet. That is why we are strong supporters of the open source community. We maintain two open source cryptographic libraries, &lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; aria-label=&quot; (opens in a new tab)&quot; href=&quot;https://openpgpjs.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;OpenPGPjs&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; aria-label=&quot; (opens in a new tab)&quot; href=&quot;https://gopenpgp.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;GopenPGP&lt;/a&gt;, to make it easier for developers to encrypt their apps and thus protect more data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This cooperation among open source developers is how we create and sustain the privacy tech ecosystem that is necessary to create a safer Internet. Thank you to our community for supporting these efforts, and we look forward to your feedback on GitHub or directly via email at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:contact@protonmail.com&quot;&gt;contact@protonmail.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can get a&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://protonmail.com/signup&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;free secure email account from ProtonMail here&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;We also provide a&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://protonvpn.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;free VPN service&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;to protect your privacy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;ProtonMail and ProtonVPN are funded by community contributions. If you would like to support our development efforts, you can upgrade to a&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://protonmail.com/support/knowledge-base/paid-plans/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;paid plan&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;or&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://protonmail.com/donate&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;donate&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Thank you for your support.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 14:28:10 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kobylisak</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>The ProtonMail Android app is open source</og:title>
<og:description>Our ProtonMail Android app is open source. This is part of our commitment to transparency and to contributing to the open source and privacy tech community.</og:description>
<og:url>https://protonmail.com/blog/android-open-source/</og:url>
<og:image>https://protonmail.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/protonmail-android-open-source-IM-1024x512.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://protonmail.com/blog/android-open-source/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Amazon scooped up data from its own sellers to launch competing products</title>
<link>https://www.wsj.com/articles/amazon-scooped-up-data-from-its-own-sellers-to-launch-competing-products-11587650015</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.wsj.com/articles/amazon-scooped-up-data-from-its-own-sellers-to-launch-competing-products-11587650015</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt; Amazon.com Inc. employees have used data about independent sellers on the company’s platform to develop competing products, a practice at odds with the company’s stated policies.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The online retailing giant has long asserted, including to Congress, that when it makes and sells its own products, it doesn’t use information it collects from the site’s individual third-party sellers—data those sellers view as proprietary.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Yet...
  &lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 14:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>benryon</dc:creator>
<og:title>Amazon Scooped Up Data From Its Own Sellers to Launch Competing Products</og:title>
<og:description>Contrary to assertions to Congress, employees often consulted sales information on third-party vendors when developing private-label merchandise. “We knew we shouldn’t,” said one former employee who accessed such data.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.wsj.com/articles/amazon-scooped-up-data-from-its-own-sellers-to-launch-competing-products-11587650015</og:url>
<og:image>https://images.wsj.net/im-178751/social</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.wsj.com/articles/amazon-scooped-up-data-from-its-own-sellers-to-launch-competing-products-11587650015</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Covid-19 Superspreader Events in 28 Countries: Critical Patterns and Lessons</title>
<link>https://quillette.com/2020/04/23/covid-19-superspreader-events-in-28-countries-critical-patterns-and-lessons/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://quillette.com/2020/04/23/covid-19-superspreader-events-in-28-countries-critical-patterns-and-lessons/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;In 1899, a German bacteriologist named Carl Flügge proved that microbes can be transmitted ballistically through large droplets that emit at high velocity from the mouth and nose. His method for proving the existence of these “Flügge droplets” (as they came to be known) was to painstakingly count the microbe colonies growing on culture plates hit with the expelled secretions of infected lab subjects. It couldn’t have been pleasant work. But his discoveries saved countless lives. And more than 12 decades later, these large respiratory droplets have been identified as a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.who.int/news-room/commentaries/detail/modes-of-transmission-of-virus-causing-covid-19-implications-for-ipc-precaution-recommendations&quot;&gt;transmission mode for COVID-19&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flügge’s graduate students continued his work into the 20&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; century, experimenting with different subjects expelling mucosalivary droplets in different ways. Eventually they determined, as a 1964 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC1897886/pdf/procrsmed00210-0097.pdf&quot;&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Royal Society of Medicine&lt;/em&gt; put it, that the quantity of expelled Flügge droplets varies markedly based on the manner of respiration: “Very few, if any… droplets are produced during quiet breathing, but [instead, they] are expelled during activities such as talking, coughing, blowing and sneezing.” A single heavy cough, it is now known, can expel as much as a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2020/04/14/science/coronavirus-transmission-cough-6-feet-ar-ul.html&quot;&gt;quarter teaspoon of fluid&lt;/a&gt; in the form of Flügge droplets. And the higher the exit velocity of the cough, the larger the globules that can be expelled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_98978&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img aria-describedby=&quot;caption-attachment-98978&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-98978 size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/d24fkeqntp1r7r.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/22134418/Carl_Flu%CC%88gge_c1906-232x300.jpg?resize=232%2C300&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;232&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; srcset=&quot;https://d24fkeqntp1r7r.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/22134418/Carl_Flu%CC%88gge_c1906.jpg 232w, https://d24fkeqntp1r7r.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/22134418/Carl_Flu%CC%88gge_c1906.jpg 400w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 232px) 100vw, 232px&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;caption-attachment-98978&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Carl Flügge&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet if Flügge were with us today, he might be surprised by how little his science has been usefully advanced over the last few generations. As Lydia Bourouiba of the MIT Fluid Dynamics of Disease Transmission Laboratory recently &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jama/fullarticle/2763852&quot;&gt;noted&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;JAMA Insights&lt;/em&gt;, the basic framework used to represent human-to-human transmission of respiratory diseases such as COVID-19 remain rooted in the tuberculosis era. According to the binary model established in the 1930s, droplets typically are classified as either (1) large globules of the Flüggian variety—arcing through the air like a tennis ball until gravity brings them down to Earth; or (2) smaller particles, less than five to 10 micrometers in diameter (roughly a 10th the width of a human hair), which drift lazily through the air as fine aerosols.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a fascinating paper published on March 26th, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jama/fullarticle/2763852&quot;&gt;Turbulent Gas Clouds and Respiratory Pathogen Emissions: Potential Implications for Reducing Transmission of COVID-19&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; Bourouiba shows that analyzing a human sneeze is unusually difficult, even by the standards of fluid dynamics (whose mathematics I once &lt;a href=&quot;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1002/srin.199501763&quot;&gt;modeled&lt;/a&gt; in my former capacity as an engineer and computer programmer). That’s because those mucosalivary droplets we emit are cocooned within a warm, moist enveloping gas cloud—Bourouiba calls it a “puff”—that protects the droplets from evaporation and allows even small globules to travel much farther than one might otherwise predict. The binary distinction between large and small droplets remains fundamental: Eventually, the big particles fall while the smaller ones don’t. But during those first fractions of a second when a sneeze (or cough, or shout) is expelled, Bourouiba shows, the enveloping gas sheath allows smaller particles to act, ballistically speaking, as if they were larger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/9qqHOKUXY5U&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The science here is mind-bogglingly complex, because modeling the puff’s behaviour requires that Bourouiba and her team model not only the dynamics of the puff as it travels and dissipates, but also the biophysical and thermodynamic processes unfolding &lt;em&gt;within&lt;/em&gt; the gas cloud. But the overall upshot is that such a puff “and its payload of pathogen-bearing droplets of all sizes” can travel seven to eight meters—about four times the length of the six-foot social-distancing buffer zone we’ve all been taught to enforce since mid-March.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bourouiba’s research hits squarely on a blind spot in our knowledge of COVID-19. On one hand, scientists have an intimate molecule-by-molecule knowledge of the virus’s structure, its full genome having been &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC7045880/&quot;&gt;sequenced&lt;/a&gt; months ago. On the other hand, the scientific and lay literature is bursting with epidemiological reports from just about every corner of the planet. But the actual nitty-gritty mechanics of actual disease transmission doesn’t take place on the microscopic scale of nucleic acids or on the gargantuan scale of whole nations. It takes place on the everyday face-to-face scale of inches and feet, as Flügge showed 121 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it is on this crucial scale that our knowledge is thinnest. Despite the passage of four months since the first known human cases of COVID-19, our public-health officials remain committed to policies that reflect no clear understanding as to whether it is one-off ballistic droplet payloads or clouds of fine aerosols that pose the greatest risk—or even how these two modes compare to the possibility of indirect infection through contaminated surfaces (known as “fomites”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gaining such an understanding is absolutely critical to the task of tailoring emerging public-health measures and workplace policies, because the process of policy optimization depends entirely on which mechanism (if any) is dominant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;If large droplets are found to be a dominant mode of transmission, then the expanded use of masks and social distancing is critical, because the threat will be understood as emerging from the &lt;em&gt;ballistic&lt;/em&gt; droplet flight connected to sneezing, coughing, and laboured breathing. We would also be urged to speak softly, avoid “coughing, blowing and sneezing,” or exhibiting any kind of agitated respiratory state in public, and angle their mouths downward when speaking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If lingering clouds of tiny aerosol droplets are found to be a dominant mode of transmission, on the other hand, then the focus on sneeze ballistics and the precise geometric delineation of social distancing protocols become somewhat less important—since particles that remain indefinitely suspended in an airborne state can travel over large distances through the normal processes of natural convection and gas diffusion. In this case, we would need to prioritize the use of outdoor spaces (where aerosols are more quickly swept away) and improve the ventilation of indoor spaces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If contaminated surfaces are found to be a dominant mode of transmission, then we would need to continue, and even expand, our current practice of fastidiously washing hands following contact with store-bought items and other outside surfaces; as well as wiping down delivered items with bleach solution or other disinfectants.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the available international data hasn’t been particularly helpful in addressing this inquiry. Every nation is reporting its data in a different way. And to my knowledge, no one has produced a comprehensive international database of large COVID-19 infection clusters—or “superspreading events” (SSEs), as they are sometimes referred to in &lt;a href=&quot;https://wwwnc.cdc.gov/eid/article/26/6/20-0495_article&quot;&gt;the scientific literature&lt;/a&gt;—which would facilitate a systematic study of the forms of behaviour that spread the disease most rapidly. As SSE expert Richard Stein &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1201971211000245&quot;&gt;put it&lt;/a&gt; in a definitive 2011 article&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; roughly “20% of the individuals within any given population are thought to contribute at least 80% to the transmission potential” of typical pathogens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the absence of any comprehensive database of COVID-19 superspreading events, I built my own, cataloguing 58 SSEs in 28 different countries (plus ships at sea). As there is no formal scientific definition of SSE at play, nor any World Health Organization-established protocol for cataloguing them, I simply spent several weeks scanning the scientific and lay press for any information I could find, using search terms such as “superspreader,” “cluster,” “hot spot”; or non-English variants, such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com/mundo/noticias-51452499&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;superpropagadore&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; I also made abundant inquiries to personal and professional contacts through email and social media, seeking to unearth examples that hadn’t been reported in the mass media or scientific journals. That process will continue, and I am appreciative of readers who send me information I may have missed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not an epidemiologist, let alone a virologist. And the data I am working with is substandard anyway, as there are all sorts of obvious selection biases at play, including the editorial biases of the journalists on whom I rely for local reports. In some countries, such as South Korea, COVID-19 contact tracing is meticulous. In other places, it’s virtually non-existent. Some relatively small SSEs—such as the Chicago cluster surrounding the superspreader designated by the US Centers for Disease Control as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cdc.gov/mmwr/volumes/69/wr/mm6915e1.htm&quot;&gt;A1.1&lt;/a&gt;—are documented by dozens of different sources. Yet many much larger SSEs, which have infected hundreds or even thousands of people, remain only vaguely described in the literature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some cases, I found it hard to get even the most basic information—such as the number of individuals believed to have been infected or killed by an SSE. This is one reason why I didn’t impose a hard cut-off in regard to either index, and instead based my inclusion on whether credible local sources presented the cluster as epidemiologically noteworthy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are no doubt hundreds, or even thousands, of SSEs that simply have never been reported, and never will be. And so it is impossible to determine what overall share of global COVID-19 cases are attributable to SSEs. To cite one example: Was Liverpool’s March 11 football match against Atletico Madrid an SSE, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dailymail.co.uk/sport/football/article-8238595/Liverpools-clash-against-Atletico-Madrid-helped-spread-coronavirus-interesting-hypothesis.html&quot;&gt;as many believe&lt;/a&gt;? Possibly. But no one knows, because the study of COVID-19 SSEs is bedevilled by the same sloppy contact-tracing practices and inadequate testing resources as has hampered the public-health response to the disease more generally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another research frustration lies with the fact that even countries that employ competent contact-tracing methods—such as Australia and New Zealand—withhold important information from publication for privacy reasons. (There is a “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.msn.com/en-au/news/coronavirus/hospitality-worker-identified-as-covid-19-super-spreader/ar-BB12s7ZN&quot;&gt;hospitality worker&lt;/a&gt;” in Victoria, for instance, whose case seems particularly interesting. But I have been unable to find detailed information about the events and venues at which he infected others.) In other cases, I’ve received private correspondence whose contents I’ve chosen to exclude from my database—involving Purim parties in Israel, for instance, and a Swedish party at which a whistle apparently was passed around—because the information can’t be corroborated through public sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also chose to exclude examples from some countries that have blocked or distorted information about SSEs. It is widely known, for instance, that large officially-sanctioned religious gatherings in the Iranian city of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/our-columnists/how-iran-became-a-new-epicenter-of-the-coronavirus-outbreak&quot;&gt;Qom&lt;/a&gt; led to massive outbreaks in February. But no adequately reliable data or public reporting exists as to the extent. The same is true of the outbreaks that reportedly have broken out amongst the political leadership in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/04/19/world/asia/coronavirus-afghanistan-president-palace.html&quot;&gt;Afghanistan&lt;/a&gt;. The Chinese literature is full of fascinating examples (including one from &lt;a href=&quot;https://wwwnc.cdc.gov/eid/article/26/7/20-0764_article#suggestedcitation&quot;&gt;a restaurant in Guangdong Province&lt;/a&gt; that I discuss in some detail later on). But China’s policy of selective disclosure and, in some cases, outright dishonesty, has made me skeptical of many reported details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I have chosen to exclude SSEs that center on hospitals and old-age homes, despite the fact that in many countries (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theglobeandmail.com/canada/article-outbreaks-at-seniors-homes-linked-to-almost-half-of-covid-19-deaths/&quot;&gt;including Canada&lt;/a&gt;, where I live), these comprise the main spawning ground for COVID-19. This is because the purpose of this exercise is to gain information about the relative effects of three broad modes of COVID-19 transmission—large droplets transmitted ballistically, persistent concentrations of tiny airborne droplets, and contaminated surfaces. In hospitals and old-age homes, all three of these mechanisms are almost invariably at play—as these tend to be shared spaces full of commonly touched surfaces and close interpersonal contact among residents and staff. And so such SSEs serve to inflate the size of the database without providing assistance in isolating variables. The same principle is true of COVID-19 transmission within households, which is why I have excluded intra-household clusters as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* * *&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only 38 of the 58 SSEs that I recorded were documented in a way that permitted me to determine their date with any specificity. (And even in these cases, I sometimes had to make educated estimates because of the vague nature of the reporting.) In the case of multi-day SSEs, such as religious festivals, I picked a day corresponding to the middle of the event. Unfortunately, some of the largest SSEs, such as those at North American meat processing plants, can’t be usefully pinpointed at all because the infections span multiple weeks (or even months), and the employers haven’t released detailed date-tagged data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignleft wp-image-98988 size-full jetpack-lazy-image&quot; src=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/d24fkeqntp1r7r.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/22204722/Picture1.png?resize=368%2C472&amp;amp;is-pending-load=1#038;ssl=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;368&quot; height=&quot;472&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot; data-lazy-srcset=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/d24fkeqntp1r7r.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/22204722/Picture1.png?resize=368%2C472&amp;amp;ssl=1 368w, https://i1.wp.com/d24fkeqntp1r7r.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/22204722/Picture1.png?resize=368%2C472&amp;amp;ssl=1 234w&quot; data-lazy-sizes=&quot;(max-width: 368px) 100vw, 368px&quot; srcset=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignleft wp-image-98988 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/d24fkeqntp1r7r.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/22204722/Picture1.png?resize=368%2C472&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;368&quot; height=&quot;472&quot; srcset=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/d24fkeqntp1r7r.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/22204722/Picture1.png?resize=368%2C472&amp;amp;ssl=1 368w, https://i1.wp.com/d24fkeqntp1r7r.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/22204722/Picture1.png?resize=368%2C472&amp;amp;ssl=1 234w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 368px) 100vw, 368px&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;Of the 38 SSEs for which dates could be usefully identified, about 75 percent (29/38) took place in the 26-day span between February 25th and March 21st, roughly corresponding to the period when thousands of infected COVID-19 individuals were already traveling around the world, but before social distancing and event-cancelation policies had been uniformly implemented in many of the affected countries. (A notable early outlier is &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.sky.com/story/coronavirus-superspreader-steve-walsh-discharged-from-hospital-11932275&quot;&gt;Steve Walsh&lt;/a&gt;, who spread COVID-19 from a Singapore corporate meeting to a French ski resort to his native UK in late January and early February.) No doubt, a vast number of SSEs occurred in January and February without being reported as such, because public-health officials and journalists weren’t alive to the nature or scale of the coming pandemic. But it is reassuring that, so far, April has been almost entirely bereft of publicly reported SSEs.
&lt;p&gt;I was struck by how few of the SSEs originated in conditions stereotypically associated with the underclass (though a March &lt;a href=&quot;https://foreignpolicy.com/2020/04/08/qatar-south-asian-migrant-workers-cant-afford-coronavirus-lockdown-world-cup-2022/&quot;&gt;outbreak at a Qatari migrant workers camp&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ucluamnestysoc.wordpress.com/2014/02/04/slavery-and-splendour-the-underbelly-of-modern-qatar/&quot;&gt;industrial area&lt;/a&gt; north of Doha offers one such example). Many of the early SSEs, in fact, centered on weddings, birthday parties, and other events that were described in local media as glamorous or populated by “socialites.” Examples here include a March 7th &lt;a href=&quot;https://epoca.globo.com/sociedade/coronavirus-se-alastra-entre-convidados-de-noivado-na-alta-sociedade-carioca-24324313&quot;&gt;engagement party&lt;/a&gt; at a Rio de Janeiro “mansion” that attracted “high society” fly-ins from around the world, and a similarly described &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/03/23/us/coronavirus-westport-connecticut-party-zero.html&quot;&gt;birthday party&lt;/a&gt; in Westport, CT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is theoretically possible that socioeconomically privileged individuals really do lack some immune-response mechanism that protects individuals who have been exposed to a wider array of infectious pathogens. (A recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.medrxiv.org/content/10.1101/2020.04.12.20059618v1&quot;&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; on COVID-19 surveillance testing at a Boston homeless shelter contained the stunning disclosure that 36 percent of 408 screened individuals tested positive for COVID-19. Yet the vast majority were asymptomatic, and even the few who were symptomatic did not diverge statistically from the 64 percent of tested individuals who were COVID-19-negative.) But absent more data, the more obvious explanation is that these early SSEs are linked to the intercontinental travel practices of the guests. (In the case of the Connecticut event, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/03/23/us/coronavirus-westport-connecticut-party-zero.html&quot;&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt; the &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt;, “a visitor from Johannesburg—a 43-year-old businessman—fell ill on his flight home&lt;em&gt;.”&lt;/em&gt; And the Rio party was attended by guests who’d traveled recently from, or through New York, Belgium and Italy.) Moreover, COVID-19 outbreaks in poor communities are simply less likely to be reported, because the victims have less access to testing, high-end medical care, or media contacts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, the truly remarkable trend that jumped off my spreadsheet has nothing to do with the sort of people involved in these SSEs, but rather the extraordinarily narrow range of underlying &lt;em&gt;activities&lt;/em&gt;. And I believe it is on this point that a close study of SSEs, even one based on such a biased and incomplete data set as the one I’ve assembled in my lay capacity, can help us:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Of the 54 SSEs on my list for which the underlying activities were identified, no fewer than nine were linked to religious services or missionary work. This includes massive gatherings such as February’s weeklong Christian Open Door prayer &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/article/us-health-coronavirus-france-church-spec/special-report-five-days-of-worship-that-set-a-virus-time-bomb-in-france-idUSKBN21H0Q2&quot;&gt;meeting&lt;/a&gt; in Mulhouse, France, which has been linked to an astounding 2,500 cases; and a massive &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geo.tv/latest/278852-gazas-two-confirmed-coronavirus-patients-attended-tablighi-ijtema-in-pakistan&quot;&gt;Tablighi Jamaat&lt;/a&gt; Islamic event in Lahore that attracted a quarter-million people. But it also includes much smaller-scale religious activities, such as proselytizing in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2020/03/india-quarantines-15000-virus-kills-super-spreader-guru-200328092832309.html&quot;&gt;rural Punjabi villages&lt;/a&gt; and a religious meeting in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://calgaryherald.com/news/local-news/calgary-man-fights-for-his-life-as-family-quarantined-with-covid-19/&quot;&gt;Calgary home&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nineteen of the SSEs—about one-third—involved parties or liquor-fueled mass attendance festivals of one kind or another, including (as with the examples cited above) celebrations of weddings, engagements and birthdays.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Five of the SSEs involved funerals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Six of the SSEs involved face-to-face business networking. This includes large-scale events such as Biogen’s notorious Boston &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bostonglobe.com/2020/03/11/nation/how-biogen-leadership-conference-boston-spread-coronavirus/&quot;&gt;leadership meeting&lt;/a&gt; in February, as well as one-on-one business meetings—from the unidentified “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bostonglobe.com/2020/03/11/nation/how-biogen-leadership-conference-boston-spread-coronavirus/&quot;&gt;traveling salesperson&lt;/a&gt;” who spread COVID-19 in Maine to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/health-environment/article/3073991/im-not-patient-zero-malaysias-26th-coronavirus-patient&quot;&gt;Hisham Hamdan&lt;/a&gt;, a powerful sovereign-wealth fund official who spread the disease in Malaysia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;All told, 38 of the 54 SSEs for which activities were known involved one or more of these four activities—about 70 percent. Indeed, the categories sometimes overlap, as with patient A1.1 in Chicago, who attended both a party and a funeral in the space of a few days; or the New Rochelle, NY man who covered the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2020/03/10/us/new-rochelle-coronavirus/index.html&quot;&gt;SSE trifecta&lt;/a&gt; of Bar Mitzvah party, synagogue services, and local funeral, all the while going to his day job as a lawyer in New York City.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But even that 70 percent figure underestimates the prevalence of these activities in COVID-19 SSEs, because my database also includes five SSEs involving two warships and three cruise ships—the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-52272249&quot;&gt;USS Roosevelt&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-52308073&quot;&gt;Charles de Gaulle&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cdc.gov/mmwr/volumes/69/wr/mm6912e3.htm&quot;&gt;Diamond Princess&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cdc.gov/mmwr/volumes/69/wr/mm6912e3.htm&quot;&gt;Grand Princess&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.abc.net.au/news/2020-04-20/ruby-princess-passengers-says-overseas-ignored-after-coronavirus/12162942&quot;&gt;Ruby Princess&lt;/a&gt;—at least three of which (and probably all five) featured onboard parties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/eVybeQGVOsY&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These parties, funerals, religious meet-ups and business networking sessions all seem to have involved the same type of behaviour: extended, close-range, face-to-face conversation—typically in crowded, socially animated spaces. This includes the many people infected by a &lt;a href=&quot;https://jcm.asm.org/content/jcm/early/2020/04/03/JCM.00588-20.full.pdf&quot;&gt;bartender&lt;/a&gt; while being served at a raucous après ski venue in Austria, and party guests in Brazil greeting “each other with two kisses on the cheek [a local custom], hugs and handshakes.” The funerals in question are generally described as highly intimate and congested scenes of grieving among close friends and relatives. In the case of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/03/30/us/coronavirus-funeral-albany-georgia.html&quot;&gt;the SSE funeral in Albany, Georgia&lt;/a&gt; that devastated the local population, “people wiped tears away, and embraced, and blew their noses, and belted out hymns. They laughed, remembering. It was a big gathering, with upward of 200 mourners overflowing the memorial chapel, so people had to stand outside.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With few exceptions, almost all of the SSEs took place indoors, where people tend to pack closer together in social situations, and where ventilation is poorer. (It is notable, for instance, that the notorious &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/europe/coronavirus-austria-ski-resorts-quarantine-lifted-ischgl-lockdown-a9479731.html&quot;&gt;outbreak&lt;/a&gt; at an Austrian ski resort is connected to a bartender and not, say, a lift operator.) But generalizations in this area are complicated by the fact that some of the religious festivals described herein were mixed indoor/outdoor affairs. Moreover, the February 19 SSE at San Siro stadium in Milan is also ambiguous, since that stadium has &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.worldstadiums.com/stadium_menu/architecture/stadium_design/milano_meazza.shtml&quot;&gt;a roof over the seating area, but not over the field&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The media accounts of these SSEs are full of descriptions in this vein. At a February 15 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2020/apr/09/the-cluster-effect-how-social-gatherings-were-rocket-fuel-for-coronavirus&quot;&gt;festival&lt;/a&gt; in Gangelt, a town in Germany’s tiny Heinsberg district, “beer and wine flowed aplenty as approximately 350 adults in fancy dress locked arms on long wooden benches and swayed to the rhythm of music provided by a live band. During an interval in the programme, guests got up to mingle with friends and relatives at other tables, greeting each other as Rhineland tradition commands, with a &lt;em&gt;bützchen&lt;/em&gt;, or peck on the cheek.” Since that time, more than 40 Germans from the Heinsberg district have died. It’s been called “Germany’s Wuhan.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the case of religious SSEs, Sikhs, Christians, Jews and Muslims are all represented in the database. The virus makes no distinction according to creed, but does seem to prey on physically intimate congregations that feature some combination of mass participation, folk proselytizing and spontaneous, emotionally charged expressions of devotion. In the case of Islam, it is notable that the same movement, Tablighi Jamaat, has been responsible for massive outbreaks at completely separate events in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2020/04/pakistan-quarantines-20000-tabligh-gathering-lahore-200406075221220.html&quot;&gt;Lahore&lt;/a&gt; (noted above), &lt;a href=&quot;https://quillette.com/2020/04/23/covid-19-superspreader-events-in-28-countries-critical-patterns-and-lessons/Tablighi%20Jamaat&quot;&gt;Delhi&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2020/03/malaysia-mosque-event-virus-hotspot-se-asia-200318021302367.html&quot;&gt;Kuala Lampur&lt;/a&gt;. At Mulhouse, the week’s schedule &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-8168819/French-megachurch-meeting-blamed-sparking-countrys-biggest-cluster-Covid-19-cases.html&quot;&gt;included&lt;/a&gt; Christian “choir performances, collective prayer, singing, sermons from preachers, workshops, and testimony from people who said God had cured their illnesses… Many people came day after day, and spent hours there.” And in Punjab, dozens of Sikhs died thanks to the itinerant rural &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-india-52061915&quot;&gt;preaching&lt;/a&gt; of a single (now deceased) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Y1zS4BApoHY&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&quot;&gt;infamous&lt;/a&gt; septuagenarian named Baldev Singh (whose deadly travels inspired a hit Punjabi song by Sidhu Moose Wala, linked immediately below).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Y1zS4BApoHY&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of the 54 SSEs for which underlying activities could be identified, only 11 did not involve either religious activity, a party, a funeral, a cruise or extended face-to-face professional networking. But even in this minority of cases, one can observe almost identical interpersonal dynamics. Three of the SSEs—in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/03/26/world/asia/japan-coronavirus.html&quot;&gt;Japan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.latimes.com/world-nation/story/2020-03-29/coronavirus-choir-outbreak&quot;&gt;Skagit County, WA&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.straitstimes.com/singapore/health/patients-in-safra-jurong-cluster-had-more-than-just-a-dinner-in-common&quot;&gt;Singapore&lt;/a&gt;—involved concert-goers and singing groups belting out tunes together over a period of hours. (The Skagit example is particularly interesting, because the organizers were aware of the COVID-19 risk beforehand, and took the precaution of spacing out the participants by several feet. If they had been merely chatting, instead of singing, no one might have gotten sick.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another SSE &lt;a href=&quot;https://nationalpost.com/news/how-an-edmonton-curling-tournament-became-a-hotspot-for-the-covid-19-outbreak-in-canada&quot;&gt;involved&lt;/a&gt; a group of Canadian doctors engaged in a day of recreational curling. This is a sport that involves hyperventilating participants frenetically sweeping the ice with brooms while their faces are positioned inches apart, sometimes changing partners—an ideal climate for Flüggian infection. Indeed, this partner-swapping aspect of the activity seems to be a common feature of many suspected SSEs, such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.heraldnet.com/news/a-wholesome-activity-leads-to-infection-square-dancing/&quot;&gt;square-dancing parties&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/-xFxC-JgWtk&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Four of the SSEs were outbreaks at meat-processing plants, in which “gut snatchers” and other &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/04/18/business/coronavirus-meat-slaughterhouses.html&quot;&gt;densely packed workers&lt;/a&gt; must communicate with one another amidst the &lt;a href=&quot;https://asa.scitation.org/doi/10.1121/1.3438003&quot;&gt;ear-piercing shriek of industrial machinery&lt;/a&gt;. I lack the expertise to determine how the refrigerated nature of some meat-processing facilities may affect the dynamics of droplet transmission—though I would also note that at least four of the SSEs on my list unfolded at European ski resorts. But high levels of &lt;em&gt;noise&lt;/em&gt; do seem to be a common feature of SSEs, as such environments force conversationalists to speak at extremely close range. (Related factors may be at play in old-age homes. These tend to be quiet places. But the reduced speaking volume and hearing functions of some elderly residents lend themselves to conversations held at much closer range than is socially typical in the general population.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, three of the SSEs involved mass sports spectacles, during which fans regularly rain saliva in all directions as they communally celebrate or commiserate in response to each turn of fortune. (Advance to the 8:30 mark of &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/eixbo8KaG_U?t=517&quot;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt;, showing euphoric hometown fan reaction during the infamous February 19th football match between Atlanata and Valencia, and you will see exactly what I mean.) As we now know, the danger starts even before the action begins: One of the most dangerous things you can do at a sports event in the COVID-19 era is sing the national anthem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/eixbo8KaG_U&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* * *&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When do COVID-19 SSEs happen? Based on the list I’ve assembled, the short answer is: Wherever and whenever people are up in each other’s faces, laughing, shouting, cheering, sobbing, singing, greeting, and praying. You don’t have to be a 19&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;-century German bacteriologist or MIT expert in mucosalivary ballistics to understand what this tells us about the most likely mode of transmission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s worth scanning all the myriad forms of common human activity that &lt;em&gt;aren’t&lt;/em&gt; represented among these listed SSEs: watching movies in a theater, being on a train or bus, attending theater, opera, or symphony (these latter activities may seem like rarified examples, but they are important once you take stock of all those wealthy infectees who got sick in March, and consider that New York City is a major COVID-19 hot spot). These are activities where people often find themselves surrounded by strangers in densely packed rooms—as with all those above-described SSEs—but, crucially, where attendees also are expected to sit still and talk in hushed tones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world’s untold thousands of white-collar cubicle farms don’t seem to be generating abundant COVID-19 SSEs—despite the uneven quality of ventilation one finds in global workplaces. This category includes call centers (many of which are still operating), places where millions of people around the world literally talk for a living. (&lt;em&gt;Addendum&lt;/em&gt;: there are at least two examples of call-centre-based clusters, both of which were indicated to me by readers after the original version of this article appeared—one in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3074781/coronavirus-new-clusters-emerge-south-korea-cases-reach-7869&quot;&gt;South Korea&lt;/a&gt;, which overlaps with the massive Shincheonji Church of Jesus &lt;a href=&quot;https://graphics.reuters.com/CHINA-HEALTH-SOUTHKOREA-CLUSTERS/0100B5G33SB/index.html&quot;&gt;cluster;&lt;/a&gt; and the other in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.loopjamaica.com/content/police-health-authorities-investigate-alorica&quot;&gt;Jamaica&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In New Zealand, one SSE centered on students at a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newshub.co.nz/home/new-zealand/2020/04/coronavirus-marist-girls-college-principal-on-being-in-charge-of-a-school-while-having-covid-19.html&quot;&gt;girls’ school&lt;/a&gt;. Given the exuberant and socially intimate way in which children laugh, argue and gossip, I am surprised there are not more schools on my list. Moreover, I had trouble finding any SSEs that originated in university classrooms, which one would expect to be massive engines of infection if COVID-19 could be transmitted easily through airborne small-droplet diffusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the United States, the two university-based examples that have received the most media attention are Liberty University in Lynchburg, Va. and the University of Texas. But in neither case was there any apparent connection to classroom activity. At Liberty, where several employees got sick, the one student known to be infected &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/04/16/us/politics/jerry-falwell-liberty-university-coronavirus.html&quot;&gt;isn’t even currently enrolled in classes&lt;/a&gt;. And the UT outbreak, which has caused &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/travel/article/austin-spring-breakers-coronavirus-trnd/index.html&quot;&gt;more than 40 students to be infected&lt;/a&gt;, actually took place on a Spring Break trip to Mexico. It’s possible, I suppose, that these students spent the week holed up in a conference room with a stack of books. But my instincts indicate otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s similarly notable that airplanes don’t seem to be common sites for known SSEs, notwithstanding the sardine-like manner in which airlines transport us and the ample opportunity that the industry’s bureaucracy offers for contact tracing. Yes, New Zealand has one cluster that’s based around an infected but asymptomatic flight attendant. But the many known infections he caused took place &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nzherald.co.nz/nz/news/article.cfm?c_id=1&amp;amp;objectid=12325198&quot;&gt;at a wedding reception&lt;/a&gt;, not in an airplane. This flight attendant was running what was, in effect, an unintended experiment, with the passengers on board his aircraft playing the role of control group. And the results offer a microcosm of the nature of SSEs as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* * *&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve already cataloged the limitations of my approach at some length. And I will emphasize again that I am not an epidemiologist, virologist, or infectious-diseases expert (though I like to think I’ve made myself a somewhat educated reader of the most recently published scientific literature in these fields). But even a layperson can see that there is a fairly clear pattern in the most notorious, destructive, and widely reported cases of mass COVID-19 infection—virtually all of which feature forms of human behaviour that permit the direct ballistic delivery of a large-droplet Flüggian payload from face A to face B. If fomites were a major pathway for COVID-19 infection outside of hospitals, old-age residences, and homes, one would expect restaurant cooks, mass-transit ticket handlers, and FedEx delivery workers to be at the center of major clusters. They’re not. If small-droplet airborne concentrations in unventilated spaces were a common vector for COVID-19 transmission (as with measles, for instance), one would expect whole office buildings to become mass-infection hot spots. That doesn’t seem to have happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One critical factor in all this is that we still have no idea what the &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s12560-011-9056-7&quot;&gt;minimal infectious dose&lt;/a&gt; (MID) is for COVID-19—the number of viral particles required “&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@Cancerwarrior/covid-19-why-we-should-all-wear-masks-there-is-new-scientific-rationale-280e08ceee71&quot;&gt;to start the pathogenesis cascade that causes a clinical disease&lt;/a&gt;”—even if we do have some idea about what regions of our respiratory system the virus &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/ftp/arxiv/papers/2003/2003.06122.pdf&quot;&gt;can use as a point of entry&lt;/a&gt;. Knowing the &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s12560-011-9056-7&quot;&gt;MID&lt;/a&gt; for COVID-19 would be invaluable, because it may well turn out that it is significantly higher than the viral load capacity of small droplets, not to mention the even smaller viral load typically delivered by glancing contact with an infected surface. This would mean that many of our current COVID-19-avoidance protocols, however well-intentioned, would be guarding against modes of transmission that aren’t really significant contributors to the overall pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some cases, public-health rules that guard against non-existent threats may actually make the problem &lt;em&gt;worse&lt;/em&gt;. Consider, for instance, the spread of COVID-19 among diners at a Guangzhou restaurant on January 24th, an episode that I have not included in my database, but which has become the subject of a fascinating &lt;a href=&quot;https://wwwnc.cdc.gov/eid/article/26/7/20-0764_article&quot;&gt;forthcoming article&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Emerging Infectious Diseases.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the authors note, the restaurant in question was air-conditioned on the date in question. Using video footage, they were able to chart the position of every diner in the restaurant, and then map their subsequent infection status in relation to both the single infected individual known to be present at the time and the air conditioning system’s outgoing and intake streams. If the primary transmission mode of COVID-19 were by small, sub-Flüggian airborne particles, the presence of the forced air convection might have made the environment safer (especially since “smear samples from the air conditioner [itself] were all [COVID-19] nucleotide negative”). But the researchers instead found evidence for the opposite: “The key factor for infection was the direction of the airflow,” with downstream individuals being most at risk—a result consistent with the thesis that COVID-19 is transmitted primarily through the ballistic transmission of large respiratory droplets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None of the suggested causality patterns I have described have been proven definitively, of course—let alone by any layperson’s journalistic analysis of a few dozen SSEs. But if the principal modes of COVID-19 transmission can be narrowed down in this way, it would provide an enormous boon to the policymakers who are now starting to think about restarting our economies. Fighting this disease will always be hard. But it will be harder still if we fail to develop a proper understanding of the precise way it attacks us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jonathan Kay is Canadian Editor of&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://quillette.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Quillette&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;. He tweets at&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jonkay&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;@jonkay&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Featured image: Sketch showing arrangement of restaurant tables and air conditioning airflow at a restaurant in Guangzhou, as contained in the article “&lt;a href=&quot;https://wwwnc.cdc.gov/eid/article/26/7/20-0764_article#suggestedcitation&quot;&gt;COVID-19 Outbreak Associated with Air Conditioning in Restaurant, Guangzhou, China, 2020&lt;/a&gt;,” by Jianyun Lu, Jieni Gu, Kuibiao Li, Conghui Xu, Wenzhe Su, Zhisheng Lai, Deqian Zhou, Chao Yu, Bin Xu, and Zhicong Yang.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Correction:&lt;/strong&gt; The original version of this article incorrectly suggested that no SSEs have been found at corporate call centres. This version has been corrected in response to reader-supplied information. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;robots-nocontent sd-block sd-social sd-social-official sd-sharing&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Share this:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 13:35:07 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Symmetry</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>COVID-19 Superspreader Events in 28 Countries: Critical Patterns and Lessons - Quillette</og:title>
<og:description>In 1899, a German bacteriologist named Carl Flügge proved that microbes can be transmitted ballistically through large droplets that emit at high velocity from the mouth and nose. His method for proving the existence of these “Flügge droplets” (as they came to be known) was to painstakingly count the microbe colonies growing on culture plates hit with the expelled secretions of infected lab subjects. It couldn’t have been pleasant work. But his discoveries saved countless lives. And more than 12 decades later, these large respiratory droplets have been identified as a transmission mode for COVID-19. Flügge’s graduate students continued his work into the 20th century, experimenting with different subjects expelling mucosalivary droplets in different ways. Eventually they determined, as a 1964 report in the Proceedings of the Royal Society of Medicine put it, that the quantity of expelled Flügge droplets varies markedly based on the manner of respiration: “Very few, if any… droplets are produced during quiet breathing, but [instead, they] are expelled during activities such as talking, coughing, blowing and sneezing.” A single heavy …</og:description>
<og:url>https://quillette.com/2020/04/23/covid-19-superspreader-events-in-28-countries-critical-patterns-and-lessons/</og:url>
<og:image>https://i1.wp.com/d24fkeqntp1r7r.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/22143232/sd.png?fit=1200%2C800&amp;ssl=1</og:image>
<dc:language>en-AU</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://quillette.com/2020/04/23/covid-19-superspreader-events-in-28-countries-critical-patterns-and-lessons/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>YouTube bans coronavirus-related content that directly contradicts WHO advice</title>
<link>https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-52388586</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-52388586</guid>
<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape has-caption full-width lead&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                &lt;img class=&quot;js-image-replace&quot; alt=&quot;YouTube has banned coronavirus-related content that doesn't follow the World Health Organisation's guidelines&quot; src=&quot;https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/320/cpsprodpb/139F0/production/_111886308_whatsubject.jpg&quot; width=&quot;976&quot; height=&quot;549&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;Getty&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    YouTube has banned coronavirus-related content that does not follow the World Health Organization's guidelines
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body__introduction&quot;&gt;YouTube has banned any coronavirus-related content that directly contradicts World Health Organization (WHO) advice. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Google-owned service says it will remove anything it deems &quot;medically unsubstantiated&quot;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chief executive Susan Wojcicki said the media giant wanted to stamp out &quot;misinformation on the platform&quot;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The move follows YouTube banning &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-52198946&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;conspiracy theories falsely linking Covid-19 to 5G networks&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul class=&quot;story-body__unordered-list&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-52084700?intlink_from_url=https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/topics/c77jz3mdmjxt/youtube&amp;amp;amp;link_location=live-reporting-story&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;YouTube stars urge fans to stay at home&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-52373986&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;Coronavirus: Facebook launches UK Covid-19 symptom survey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mrs Wojcicki made the remarks on Wednesday during her first interview since the global coronavirus lockdown began. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;So people saying, ‘Take vitamin C, take turmeric, we’ll cure you,’ those are the examples of things that would be a violation of our policy,” she told CNN.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Anything that would go against World Health Organization recommendations would be a violation of our policy.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mrs Wojcicki added YouTube had seen a 75% increase in demand for news from &quot;authoritative&quot; sources. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last week, Facebook announced users who had read, watched or shared false Covid-19 information would receive a pop-up alert urging them to visit the WHO's website. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Facebook-owned &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/newsround/52185443&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;messaging service WhatsApp, meanwhile,&lt;/a&gt; stopped users forwarding messages already shared more than four times by the wider community to more than one chat at a time. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;The culture secretary praised the response from social media and technology companies in banning misinformation about coronavirus. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;I pay tribute to the work they have done,&quot; Oliver Dowden told the Digital, Culture, Media and Sport Select Committee on Wednesday. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But he urged them to take down inaccurate information faster during &quot;out of hours&quot; periods such as evenings and weekends. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;Human interest&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It comes as some of the UK's largest news publishers, including Daily Telegraph and the Guardian, criticised Google for failing to be transparent about its approach to filtering adverts alongside coronavirus-related content, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ft.com/content/672911e1-de6a-444b-a5f0-09df9cc06460&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link-external&quot;&gt;according to the Financial Times&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Brands are using blacklist filters to prevent their ads running alongside stories including keywords such as &quot;coronavirus&quot; and &quot;pandemic&quot;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Such filters are already widely used, to avoid car manufacturers' ads appearing next to stories about road accidents, for example. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But now some media outlets are reportedly frustrated content they deem &quot;inoffensive,&quot; such as uplifting human interest stories, are also being prevented from running these adverts. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is estimated keyword ad-blocking could cost the UK newspaper industry $50m (£40m) over the next year.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And Digital Minister John Whittingdale discussed the issue with publishers and advertising agencies earlier this month. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Google told the Financial Times it was &quot;in constant discussions regarding how it can help the industry during this difficult time&quot;. &lt;/p&gt;
            </description>
<pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 11:20:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>topoftheforts</dc:creator>
<og:title>YouTube bans 'medically unsubstantiated' content</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>The Google-owned platform's chief executive says the company is determined to &quot;stamp out&quot; misinformation.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-52388586</og:url>
<og:image>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/139F0/production/_111886308_whatsubject.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-52388586</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>