<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>MoviePass will shut down for good on Sept. 14</title>
<link>https://www.cnbc.com/2019/09/13/moviepass-will-shut-down-for-good-on-sept-14.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.cnbc.com/2019/09/13/moviepass-will-shut-down-for-good-on-sept-14.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;group&quot; readability=&quot;48.417480719794&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MoviePass &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20190913005496/en/Board-Directors-Helios-Matheson-Analytics-Forms-Strategic&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; role=&quot;&quot; tabindex=&quot;&quot; data-type=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot;&gt;announced on Friday&lt;/a&gt; it's shutting down the discount ticketing service on Sept. 14. Shares of MoviePass parent company &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/quotes/?symbol=HMNY&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; role=&quot;&quot; tabindex=&quot;&quot; data-type=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot;&gt;Helios and Matheson Analytics&lt;/a&gt; dropped 10% Friday afternoon, though the stock trades for a fraction of a penny.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MoviePass notified subscribers that it plans to close down the service because its &quot;efforts to recapitalize MoviePass have not been successful to date.&quot; It has formed a strategic review committee, made up of the company's independent directors, to explore &quot;strategic and financial alternatives&quot; for the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among the options it's considering are a sale of the company in its entirety, a sale of the company's assets, including MoviePass, Moviefone and MoviePass Films, as well as the possibility of a reorganization of the company. Helios and Matheson Analytics noted that any transaction would include the &quot;assumption or settlement&quot; of any of its liabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to the service's closure, MoviePass had been struggling for more than a year. Last March, MoviePass &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hmny.com/press-release/2019/3/19/moviepass-launches-new-uncapped-plan-and-reintroduces-revolutionary-995-price-for-a-limited-time&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; role=&quot;&quot; tabindex=&quot;&quot; data-type=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot;&gt;launched&lt;/a&gt; a revamped version of its unlimited plan, which let users watch one movie per day for $9.95 per month, as part of an eleventh-hour attempt to revive the subscription service. However, the service &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2019/07/05/moviepass-app-temporarily-down-while-theater-loyalty-programs-launch.html&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; role=&quot;&quot; tabindex=&quot;&quot; data-type=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot;&gt;saw its subscriber base plummet&lt;/a&gt; from more than 3 million members to about 225,000 as of April 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, MoviePass last month laid off at least seven of its employees, bringing the total staff down to about 12 people, according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/moviepass-lays-off-exhibitor-relations-team-2019-8&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; role=&quot;&quot; tabindex=&quot;&quot; data-type=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot;&gt;Business Insider&lt;/a&gt;. That's after the company was forced to add restrictions to the app in an effort to slow its cash burn, including limiting users to four movies per month, instead of being able to watch one movie per day. Helios and Matheson also took out sizable loans to cover its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2018/08/15/moviepass-parent-lost-100-million-in-the-second-quarter.html&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; role=&quot;&quot; tabindex=&quot;&quot; data-type=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot;&gt;ballooning losses&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last October, then-New York Attorney General Barbara Underwood &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2018/10/17/new-york-ag-launches-probe-into-moviepass-parent-company-for-allegedly-misleading-investors-source.html&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; role=&quot;&quot; tabindex=&quot;&quot; data-type=&quot;&quot; aria-label=&quot;&quot;&gt;opened a probe&lt;/a&gt; into Helios and Matheson's business dealings, alleging the company misled investors regarding its financials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 20:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jameslk</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>MoviePass will shut down for good on Sept. 14</og:title>
<og:description>The company informed subscribers that it was ending the service because its &quot;efforts to recapitalize MoviePass have not been successful to date.&quot;</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.cnbc.com/2019/09/13/moviepass-will-shut-down-for-good-on-sept-14.html</og:url>
<og:image>https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/105660295-1546619880102mitchloweandtedfarnsworthcrop.jpg?v=1568404499</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.cnbc.com/2019/09/13/moviepass-will-shut-down-for-good-on-sept-14.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>When a hospital sling costs 900% more than at Amazon, something is very wrong</title>
<link>https://www.latimes.com/business/story/2019-09-12/medical-equipment-pricing</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.latimes.com/business/story/2019-09-12/medical-equipment-pricing</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Cathy Birker-Hake tripped over a hose in her Valley Village backyard not long ago, dislocated her shoulder and made a beeline for the emergency room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It was one of those really stupid accidents,” she told me, still embarrassed to have needed urgent medical care for such a trivial mishap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Birker-Hake, 63, said her shoulder was put back in place at Providence St. Joseph Medical Center in Burbank and she was given a sling to keep her arm immobile while it healed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hospital charged $6,223 for two ER visits. Birker-Hake said her insurer, Oscar Health, paid nearly $4,400 of that amount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Enhancement&quot; data-align-center=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;GoogleDfpAd-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advertisement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, a few weeks ago, a bill arrived from a Carlsbad company called &lt;a class=&quot;Link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.breg.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Breg&lt;/a&gt;, which describes itself as “the second-largest U.S. provider of orthopedic bracing.” (The largest appears to be &lt;a class=&quot;Link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.djoglobal.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;DJO Global&lt;/a&gt;, formerly of Carlsbad, now based in Texas.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Birker-Hake may have settled accounts with Providence, but Breg wanted an additional $200 for the cloth sling she’d been given — or as the bill more grandly named it, the DLX Shoulder Immobilizer L.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her experience is yet another example of in-your-face medical pricing that often reflects not what things really cost but what healthcare businesses think they can get away with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From hospital stays and prescription drugs to medical equipment and related supplies, Americans spend about $3.5 trillion annually on healthcare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;Enhancement&quot; data-align-center=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;GoogleDfpAd-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advertisement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The average American faces more than $10,000 a year in medical costs, according to the Organization for Economic Development and Cooperation. Out-of-pocket costs are often lower because of insurance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Per-person healthcare spending in this country is about twice the average amount for all comparable countries, the organization found. France, Canada, Japan, Britain, Australia — their citizens pay less than half of what we pay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not laying this disparity at the feet of a single maker of orthopedic gear. But what Birker-Hake is going through helps underline how goofy our system is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Multiply her $200 sling by all those stories of $50 Tylenols and &lt;a class=&quot;Link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.latimes.com/business/la-xpm-2013-apr-18-la-fi-lazarus-20130419-story.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;$3,000 MRIs&lt;/a&gt;, and you quickly understand how our healthcare spending obscenely surpasses that of other developed countries that long ago decided gouging the sick is not an acceptable business practice — and took regulatory steps to prevent it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“In general, we pay higher prices for everything — drugs, supplies, hospital services, physician services,” said Lawrence Casalino, a professor of healthcare policy and research at Weill Cornell Medical College.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He told me the higher prices “often result from market power” — that is, a lack of competition and transparency — and “the ability to surprise bill.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surprise billing is exactly what it sounds like: Hitting patients with unexpected charges after treatment has been administered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most other businesses disclose their prices up front, which is only fair and is crucial to a competitive market. Healthcare is one of the few industries that tells you what things cost after the fact, when you have little recourse but to pay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Enhancement&quot; data-align-center=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;GoogleDfpAd-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advertisement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Birker-Hake was surprised, to say the least, that the sling she’d been given at the hospital would carry a $200 price tag — especially after she’d already coughed up about $1,800 of her own money to add to the $4,400 paid by her insurer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that doesn’t include the nearly $1,500 she pays in annual insurance premiums.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Birker-Hake showed me some pictures of the Breg sling. It’s not a particularly complicated contraption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your arm rests against your body in a horizontal pouch. One strap goes over your shoulder. Another strap goes around your waist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The DLX Shoulder Immobilizer L is presumably the large-size &lt;span class=&quot;Link&quot;&gt;Deluxe Shoulder Immobilizer&lt;/span&gt;, which Breg’s website says “is made from soft, breathable cotton material. It can be used for left or right applications. Plush, full-foam straps provide added patient comfort.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Birker-Hake pointed me toward several similar if not identical slings on Amazon. They range in price from &lt;span class=&quot;Link&quot;&gt;$12.99&lt;/span&gt; to &lt;span class=&quot;Link&quot;&gt;$16.99&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Breg version is nice-looking, as slings go. I’m not sure if those plush, full-foam straps justify a roughly 900% markup over similar products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Birker-Hake complained to her insurance company, which looked into the matter. In a letter dated Aug. 15, the insurer admitted that the Breg charge “qualifies as a surprise bill.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Enhancement&quot; data-align-center=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;GoogleDfpAd-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advertisement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As such, Oscar Health agreed to cover $5.86 of the $200 cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Six bucks?” Birker-Hake told me. “I mean, really?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now she’s wondering what to do. “It’s a piece of fabric with a shoulder strap and a belt,” she said. “Two hundred dollars seems pretty unreasonable.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hillary Schuler-Jones, a Breg spokeswoman, declined to answer questions about the price of the Deluxe Shoulder Immobilizer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It is important to note,” she said, “that Breg’s customer is not the patient, but the healthcare provider.” In most cases, “we don’t sell our products directly to patients, and we therefore don’t have a patient price list.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hospitals or clinics can buy Breg’s products at a discount and then apply whatever markup they please. Or, as in Birker-Hake’s case, they dispense the product on Breg’s behalf and Breg follows up with its own bill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company is aware that its gear can be a lot more expensive than similar goods online. It has &lt;a class=&quot;Link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.breg.com/customer-care/online-pricing/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a web page&lt;/a&gt; devoted to the topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, what the page says is that receiving a sling directly from a doctor or hospital takes all the guesswork out of the equation, so that counts for something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This immediate availability of product is a benefit that is not offered by purchasing the item online and then waiting to receive it,” it says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does that justify a 900% higher price? Breg’s position is that you get what you pay for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But you don’t. The healthcare market isn’t like other markets. Its customers generally have no choice when seeking goods or services — they need immediate attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, most people probably would decline a sling from a doctor if they knew up front that it cost $200 extra and they could get something almost identical for a fraction of the cost, including whatever charge may be required for expedited delivery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My advice to Birker-Hake is that she pay the bill. She doesn’t want to add insult to injury by having debt collectors come after her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But this is yet another illustration of a healthcare system that’s focused more on profit than on patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do we spend so much more than other countries on healthcare? It’s not because of a single company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s all of them — and a government that, unlike the governments of other developed countries, refuses to do anything about the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 19:54:21 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ilamont</dc:creator>
<og:title>Column: When a hospital sling costs 900% more than Amazon's price, something is very wrong</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.latimes.com/business/story/2019-09-12/medical-equipment-pricing</og:url>
<og:image>https://ca-times.brightspotcdn.com/dims4/default/1239f79/2147483647/strip/true/crop/2500x1313+0+177/resize/1200x630!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fca-times.brightspotcdn.com%2Ffd%2F19%2F5f2366d14d3fadd06eff26812f7a%2Fgettyimages-1164203064a.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>This is yet another example of in-your-face medical pricing that often reflects not what things really cost but what healthcare businesses think they can get away with.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.latimes.com/business/story/2019-09-12/medical-equipment-pricing</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The mineral content of vegetables has plummeted</title>
<link>https://www.linkedin.com/posts/leedryburgh_longevity-activity-6568809083200159744-XAqi</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.linkedin.com/posts/leedryburgh_longevity-activity-6568809083200159744-XAqi</guid>
<description>&lt;header class=&quot;share-update-card__header public-post__header&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/leedryburgh?trk=public-post_share-update_actor-image&quot; data-tracking-control-name=&quot;public-post_share-update_actor-image&quot; data-tracking-will-navigate=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy-load share-update-card__actor-image public-post__actor-image share-update-card__actor-image--person public-post__actor-image--person&quot; data-delayed-url=&quot;https://media.licdn.com/dms/image/C4E03AQHS3_k629z3YQ/profile-displayphoto-shrink_100_100/0?e=1573689600&amp;amp;v=beta&amp;amp;t=bKJpyL_2g3nwXAFNrrLSbnmQXjAV9IfL3bcVMrFhh-8&quot; alt=&quot;Lee S Dryburgh&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;share-update-card__actor-info public-post__actor-info&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;share-update-card__actor-text public-post__actor-text&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;share-update-card__actor-text-link public-post__actor-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/leedryburgh?trk=public-post_share-update_actor-text&quot; data-tracking-control-name=&quot;public-post_share-update_actor-text&quot; data-tracking-will-navigate=&quot;&quot;&gt;Lee S Dryburgh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;share-update-card__actor-headline public-post__actor-headline&quot;&gt;Finding clients innovation spaces as devices, AI, apps and mobile converge with biology, health and wellness.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;time class=&quot;share-update-card__post-date public-post__post-date&quot;&gt;4w · Edited&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/header&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;share-update-card__update-text public-post__update-text&quot;&gt;The average mineral content of calcium, magnesium, and iron in cabbage, lettuce, tomatoes, and spinach has dropped 80–90% between 1914 and 2018. [1] 1) https://lnkd.in/ePhAz9C &lt;a class=&quot;share-update-card__update-text-link public-post__update-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/start/join?session_redirect=https%3A%2F%2Fwww%2Elinkedin%2Ecom%2Ffeed%2Fhashtag%2Flongevity&amp;amp;trk=public-post_share-update_update-text&quot; data-tracking-control-name=&quot;public-post_share-update_update-text&quot; data-tracking-will-navigate=&quot;&quot;&gt;#longevity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;share-update-card__social-counts public-post__social-counts share-update-card__social-counts--isReaction public-post__social-counts--isReaction&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;social-counts-reactions__social-counts-item public-post__social-counts-item&quot; href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/uas/login?session_redirect=https%3A%2F%2Fwww%2Elinkedin%2Ecom%2Fposts%2Fleedryburgh_longevity-activity-6568809083200159744-XAqi&amp;amp;trk=_likes-text&quot; data-tracking-control-name=&quot;_likes-text&quot; data-tracking-will-navigate=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;social-counts-reactions__reaction-icon public-post__reaction-icon lazy-load&quot; data-delayed-url=&quot;https://static-exp1.licdn.com/sc/h/247adekfybujlsfvtiolky3ki&quot; alt=&quot;reaction like&quot;/&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;social-counts-reactions__reaction-icon public-post__reaction-icon lazy-load&quot; data-delayed-url=&quot;https://static-exp1.licdn.com/sc/h/d64hskb0a8tuvxyguu57xi4sf&quot; alt=&quot;reaction thinking&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;social-counts-reactions__social-counts-numRections public-post__social-counts-numRections&quot;&gt;76&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;share-update-card__social-counts-item public-post__social-counts-item&quot; href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/uas/login?session_redirect=https%3A%2F%2Fwww%2Elinkedin%2Ecom%2Fposts%2Fleedryburgh_longevity-activity-6568809083200159744-XAqi&amp;amp;trk=public-post_share-update_comments-text&quot; data-tracking-control-name=&quot;public-post_share-update_comments-text&quot; data-tracking-will-navigate=&quot;&quot;&gt;16 Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 19:51:52 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>hispanic</dc:creator>
<og:description>August 18, 2019: Lee S Dryburgh posted images on LinkedIn</og:description>
<og:title>Lee S Dryburgh on LinkedIn: &quot;The average mineral content of calcium, magnesium, and iron in cabbage, lettuce, tomatoes, and spinach has dropped 80–90% between 1914 and 2018. [1] 1) https://lnkd.in/ePhAz9C #longevity&quot;</og:title>
<og:image>https://media.licdn.com/dms/image/C4E22AQFUQ5UcRVFLGA/feedshare-shrink_1280/0?e=1571270400&amp;v=beta&amp;t=J9Jkk-0snAdOqWRm-NbrQJHWcZDaNWCKK1tT2f8Q8f0</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.linkedin.com/posts/leedryburgh_longevity-activity-6568809083200159744-XAqi</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.linkedin.com/posts/leedryburgh_longevity-activity-6568809083200159744-XAqi</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The grandmaster diet: How to lose weight while barely moving</title>
<link>https://www.espn.com/espn/story/_/id/27593253/why-grandmasters-magnus-carlsen-fabiano-caruana-lose-weight-playing-chess</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.espn.com/espn/story/_/id/27593253/why-grandmasters-magnus-carlsen-fabiano-caruana-lose-weight-playing-chess</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;article-meta&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;timestamp&quot; data-behavior=&quot;date_time&quot; data-date=&quot;2019-09-13T10:27:00Z&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;time&quot; data-dateformat=&quot;time1&quot; data-showtimezone=&quot;true&quot;&gt;6:27 AM ET&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ONE WEEK IN&lt;/strong&gt; early March, on a blustery, windswept day, Fabiano Caruana decides to get away. He drives three hours west from his St. Louis apartment over winding gravel roads to reach his destination, a 2,000-acre compound in rural Missouri owned by a wealthy friend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;inline editorial float-r&quot; data-behavior=&quot;article_related&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 Related&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;At 7:30 the next morning, he pulls on gray Mizzou sweats and matching running shorts, rubs the sleep from his eyes and heads out for his hourlong run with his training partner, Cristian Chirila. They jog up and down the hills around the farmland, whispering during water breaks about openings and effective chess permutations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At 5-foot-6, Caruana has a lean frame, his legs angular and toned. He also has a packed schedule for the day: a 5-mile run, an hour of tennis, half an hour of basketball and at least an hour of swimming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As he's jogging, it's easy to mistake him for a soccer player. But he is not. This body he has put together is not an accident. Caruana is, in fact, an American grandmaster in chess, the No. 2 player in the world. His training partner, Chirila? A Romanian grandmaster. And they're doing it all to prepare for the physical demands of ... chess? Yes, chess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;inline inline-photo full&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot; lazyload lazyload&quot; data-image-container=&quot;.inline-photo&quot;/&gt;Caruana, left, retreats to a 2,000-acre compound in rural Missouri ahead of major tournaments to prepare his body as well as his mind. &lt;cite&gt;Neeta Satam for ESPN&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IT SEEMS ABSURD.&lt;/strong&gt; How could two humans -- seated for hours, exerting themselves in no greater manner than intermittently extending their arms a foot at a time -- face physical demands?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, the evidence overwhelms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 1984 World Chess Championship was called off after five months and 48 games because defending champion Anatoly Karpov had lost 22 pounds. &quot;He looked like death,&quot; grandmaster and commentator Maurice Ashley recalls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2004, winner Rustam Kasimdzhanov walked away from the six-game world championship having lost 17 pounds. In October 2018, Polar, a U.S.-based company that tracks heart rates, monitored chess players during a tournament and found that 21-year-old Russian grandmaster Mikhail Antipov had burned 560 calories in two hours of sitting and playing chess -- or roughly what Roger Federer would burn in an hour of singles tennis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robert Sapolsky, who studies stress in primates at Stanford University, says a chess player can burn up to 6,000 calories a day while playing in a tournament, three times what an average person consumes in a day. Based on breathing rates (which triple during competition), blood pressure (which elevates) and muscle contractions before, during and after major tournaments, Sapolsky suggests that grandmasters' stress responses to chess are on par with what elite athletes experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Grandmasters sustain elevated blood pressure for hours in the range found in competitive marathon runners,&quot; Sapolsky says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It all combines to produce an average weight loss of 2 pounds a day, or about 10-12 pounds over the course of a 10-day tournament in which each grandmaster might play five or six times. The effect can be off-putting to the players themselves, even if it's expected. Caruana, whose base weight is 135 pounds, drops to 120 to 125 pounds. &quot;Sometimes I've weighed myself after tournaments and I've seen the scale drop below 120,&quot; he says, &quot;and that's when I get mildly scared.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;inline inline-photo full&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot; lazyload lazyload&quot; data-image-container=&quot;.inline-photo&quot;/&gt;Caruana makes sure to eat a balanced breakfast each morning: two eggs, cured fish, oatmeal and fruit. &lt;cite&gt;Neeta Satam for ESPN&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;But there is literally nothing for Caruana to fear but fear itself. Stress and anxiety, in fact, are the greatest drivers of the phenomenon. Here's how it works:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grandmasters in competition are subjected to a constant torrent of mental stress. That stress, in turn, causes their heart rates to increase, which, in turn, forces their bodies to produce more energy to, in turn, produce more oxygen. It is, according to Marcus Raichle, a neurologist at Washington University in St. Louis, and Philip Cryer, a metabolism expert at the school, a vicious, destructive cycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, players also eat less during tournaments, simply because they don't have the time or the appetite. &quot;The simple explanation is when they're thinking about chess, they're not thinking about food,&quot; says Ewan C. McNay, assistant professor of psychology in the behavioral neuroscience program at the University of Albany.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stress also leads to altered -- and disturbed -- sleep patterns, which in turn cause more fatigue -- and can lead to more weight loss. A brain operating on less sleep, even by just one hour, Kasimdzhanov notes, requires more energy to stay awake during the chess game. Some grandmasters report dreaming about chess, agonizing over what they could have done differently for hours in their sleep, and waking up exhausted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To combat it all, today's players have begun to incorporate strict food and fitness regimens to increase oxygen supply to the brain during tournaments, prevent sugar-related crashes and sustain their energy. In the 1980s and '90s, smoking, drinking and late-night parties were common on the chess circuit -- that's right, chess had a &quot;Boogie Nights&quot; phase -- but that scene has all but disappeared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Physical fitness and brain performance are tied together, and it shouldn't be a surprise that grandmasters are out there trying to look like soccer players,&quot; Ashley says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Ashley, India's first grandmaster, Viswanathan Anand, does two hours of cardio each night to tire himself out so he doesn't dream about chess; Kasimdzhanov drinks tea only during tournaments and plays tennis and basketball every day. Chirila does at least an hour of cardio and an hour of weights to build muscle mass before tournaments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But not one of these grandmasters has perfected his fitness routine like the current world champion, Magnus Carlsen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;inline inline-photo full&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot; lazyload lazyload&quot; data-image-container=&quot;.inline-photo&quot;/&gt;Tennis and other workouts help Caruana stay in shape -- and control the amount of weight he loses during a chess tournament. On average, he says, he drops from about 135 pounds to around 120 over a 10-day tournament. &lt;cite&gt;Neeta Satam for ESPN&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IN 2017, MAGNUS CARLSEN&lt;/strong&gt; realized he had a problem. The reigning world No. 1 for four years felt his grasp on the title loosening. He was still winning most tournaments, but his matches were lasting longer, the victories seemingly less assured. He was beginning to wane in the last hour of games. He noticed younger players catching up to him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it was that Carlsen visited the Olympic training center in Oslo, Norway, with his father, Henrik, seeking advice from performance specialists. Their suggestion was deceptively simple: &quot;You need to cut back on the orange juice you drink during tournaments.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carlsen had relied on a mix of half orange juice, half water for an energy boost since he was a child. But now, in his late 20s, his body was no longer breaking down the sugar as quickly, leading to sugar crashes. The nutritionists suggested that he instead drink a mixture of chocolate milk and plain milk, which contained far lower levels of sugar but would also supplement his body with calcium, potassium and protein.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;It kept his blood sugar at a reasonable level without too big a variation, and he felt less tired during key moments in tournaments that followed the change,&quot; Henrik said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;pull-quote&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;It shouldn't be a surprise that grandmasters are out there trying to look like soccer players.&quot; &lt;cite&gt;Maurice Ashley&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that was merely the beginning of Carlsen's makeover: Since then he has trained his body for chess, down to the very last detail. Before tournaments, he works out for hours -- running on the treadmill, perfecting asanas on his yoga mat, playing soccer with his friends. Before the world championship last year, he went skiing every day and tweeted that it strengthened his legs and his willpower to get to the finish line. He hired a personal chef, Magnus Forssell, who travels with him to ensure he's eating the right combination of proteins, carbs and calcium. (Says Forssell: &quot;Before tournaments, you need a lot of energy, so I am trying to trick him to eat some pasta so he gets some reserve energy.&quot;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These days, during tournaments, Carlsen focuses on relaxing and conserving energy instead of training. Caruana spends at least three hours before a match prepping his moves, but Carlsen does only 15 to 30 minutes of prep. His reasoning: Last-minute preparations are an unnecessary use of energy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;When you allow your body to relax more during a tournament, it means that it will ask for more food, it means you can eat normally, you're not stressed, so your appetite is normal -- that's what happens with Magnus,&quot; Carlsen's father says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's more: Carlsen chews gum during games to try to increase brain function without losing energy; he taps his legs rhythmically to keep his brain and body alert between moves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;inline inline-photo full&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot; lazyload lazyload&quot; data-image-container=&quot;.inline-photo&quot;/&gt;Anatoly Karpov, left, lost so much weight during the 1984 World Chess Championship that the tournament was ultimately called off. &lt;cite&gt;AP Photo&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;He has even managed to optimize ... sitting. That's right. Carlsen claims that many chess players crane their necks too far forward, which can lead to a 30 percent loss of lung capacity, according to studies in the Journal of Physical Therapy Science. And, according to Keith Overland, former president of the American Chiropractic Association, leaning 30 degrees forward increases stress on the neck by nearly 60 pounds, which in turn requires the back and neck muscles to work harder, ultimately resulting in headaches, irregular breathing and reduced oxygen to the brain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;A chess player can develop chronic neck and upper back pain, as well as sore shoulders and backaches,&quot; says Overland, who has worked with the New York Mets and the U.S. Olympic Training Center. &quot;This is particularly concerning considering how much energy they are exerting on playing a competitive game of chess at the highest level.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not Carlsen. The Norwegian rests his lower back against the chair so it retains a natural curve, his knees slightly apart at the edge of the seat, feet firmly on the ground, and leans forward at about a 75-degree angle. In this position, which he arrived at through reading studies and trial and error, he's not too far forward to lose alertness and not too far back to use extra energy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;A lot of times you see Magnus winning games in the fifth hour of play,&quot; says Ashley, who has commentated on most of Carlsen's games in the past decade. &quot;He looks like he's just starting out while his opponents are burning out.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since he became a world champion in 2013, Carlsen has even practiced a strategy familiar to fans of Kawhi Leonard or LeBron James: load management. Although the average elite player will play 12 to 14 events a year to maintain his ranking and earn money, Carlsen has typically reduced his schedule to six to eight tournaments, taking months off to recuperate after each one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Even if he doesn't lose substantial weight like his peers, Magnus understood early on that his nervous system is stressed after every tournament and takes weeks at a time regaining that balance,&quot; Henrik says. &quot;He understands his body well enough to know when he's achieved equilibrium before he goes out to play for another title.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;inline inline-photo full&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot; lazyload lazyload&quot; data-image-container=&quot;.inline-photo&quot;/&gt;No grandmaster has trained his body for chess more diligently than Norway's Magnus Carlsen. He has even discovered an optimal way to sit during competitions. &lt;cite&gt;TOLGA AKMEN/AFP/Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BACK IN MISSOURI,&lt;/strong&gt; Caruana and Chirila hole up in the dining room for six hours of chess, the room soundproofed for secrecy. Caruana is especially careful after screenshots of openings he'd planned to use against Carlsen leaked before last year's world championship. (It's only paranoia if they're &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; out to get you.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afterward, he looks exhausted, his glasses askew. Still, he grabs a handful of nuts and heads out for a final hour of tennis before dinner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kasimdzhanov and Chirila, after a dinner of salad, boiled shrimp, beef stew and mashed potatoes, walk into the kitchen for a serving of chocolate pudding pie. Caruana does not join them. &quot;No dessert for me today,&quot; he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;ad-300&quot;&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before big tournaments, Caruana usually goes into detox mode. Last year he gave up alcohol for three months before the world championship. This time, he has chosen sugar. It's a habit he picked up from Carlsen, who is showing signs, at long last, of possibly being mortal. After a run of eight consecutive tournament victories, the Norwegian dropped 10 games at a competition in August and confessed to &quot;constantly doubting&quot; himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carlsen's wobble on the eve of the Chess World Cup, however slight, is the opening Caruana has been waiting for. In his mind, Caruana knows what he has to do; like all grandmasters, he just needs his body to hold up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Sometimes you have to shock your body into listening to you,&quot; he says.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 15:05:54 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>chris_overseas</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.espn.com/espn/story/_/id/27593253/why-grandmasters-magnus-carlsen-fabiano-caruana-lose-weight-playing-chess</og:url>
<og:title>The grandmaster diet: How to lose weight while barely moving</og:title>
<og:description>You wouldn't think that chess players, who sit for hours on end and only extend their arms from time to time, would struggle with weight loss. But they do. Inside the very real, very bizarre metabolic phenomenon gripping chess.</og:description>
<og:image>https://a3.espncdn.com/combiner/i?img=%2Fphoto%2F2019%2F0913%2Fr596605_2_1296x729_16%2D9.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.espn.com/espn/story/_/id/27593253/why-grandmasters-magnus-carlsen-fabiano-caruana-lose-weight-playing-chess</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Hundreds of dogs in Norway hit by mystery illness</title>
<link>https://www.mattilsynet.no/language/english/serious_illness_in_dogs.36035</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.mattilsynet.no/language/english/serious_illness_in_dogs.36035</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The cause of the cases is not known, but the Norwegian Food Safety Authority recommends that dog owners restrict the close contact between dogs and keep dogs on a lead so that they are under control.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Updated Friday, 13th September:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autopsy of dogs has so far not provided an answer to the reason for the death of these, but the Norwegian Veterinary Institute reports that all had similar signs of serious bowel disease, with bloody content in the small intestines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some of the sampled dogs there has been found a mixed culture of &lt;em&gt;Providencia alcalifaciens&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Clostridium perfringens&lt;/em&gt; in the gut. But we can’t conclude that these are the cause of the symptoms we see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Food Safety Authority is still looking widely for possible causes, such as viruses, bacteria, fungi, and parasites. So far, there are no signs that the animals have been poisoned by known substances, and Salmonella sp. and Campylobacter sp. has not been identified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Norwegian Food Safety Authority, together with the Norwegian Veterinary Institute, will continue to work on mapping the disease outbreak with information from autopsies, samples from sick dogs and obtaining in-depth information from relevant dog owners. An online questionnaire has been established and all Norwegian veterinarians may use this to register the information they gather. Preliminary assessment of the responses received so far in the survey, doesn’t show any correlation between the cases that give a clear trace to follow in the investigation. In most cases where several dogs live in the same animal care, only one dog has become ill. This may indicate that the possible disease is not so contagious from dog to dog. For the time being, the Norwegian Food Safety Authority's advice on restricting close contact between dogs remains valid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Norwegian Food Safety Authority first received information about the disease cases from veterinarians in Oslo and the surrounding area and has since also received information on dogs with similar symptoms in other parts of the country. At present there is no basis to say whether the cases are related.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Norwegian Food Safety Authority now generally recommends that dog owners restrict the close contact between dogs and keep dogs on a lead so that they are under control. When dogs are walked, they should not greet the dogs they meet for as long as the situation is unclear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dogs showing signs of disease should be brought to the veterinarian as soon as possible. Dog owners should follow the vaccination routines recommended by veterinarians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The recommendation to avoid close contact with other dogs means that dog owners should make an independent assessment of whether they should attend dressage courses, exhibitions, hunting trials and the like, which entails closer gatherings of dogs until this matter is solved or new information has been published.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dog owners who are going to the veterinarian should also avoid close contact with other dogs, and in case of suspicion of serious illness, pet owners should contact the clinic before taking the dog in so that infection-reducing measures can be implemented by the clinic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Norwegian Food Safety Authority has not been notified of cases of disease with similar symptoms in other animal species, and so far, there are no indications that this is something that can infect humans.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 13:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kristofferR</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.mattilsynet.no/language/english/serious_illness_in_dogs.36035</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Algorithm No One Knows About (2016)</title>
<link>https://getkerf.wordpress.com/2016/03/30/the-best-algorithm-no-one-knows-about/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://getkerf.wordpress.com/2016/03/30/the-best-algorithm-no-one-knows-about/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Here’s a program roughly 0% of programmers know how to write: generate a list of random tweets, without duplication. You may think you know how to do this, but you almost assuredly don’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Say you work at Twitter and have to select just one tweet at random. This is an easy problem. Generate a random number less than the total number of tweets, and draw the tweet that corresponds somehow to your number. If you have to make a list of tweets, then, provided you don’t mind duplicates, you can repeat this same process over and over. We get a list of tweets drawn at random, possibly with some duplication. Any programmer could write this program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The catch comes when you add the requirement that the selected tweets be unique. The whole problem changes. Once uniqueness is required, you get trapped by another, implicit, requirement, which is that we expect every tweet to be equally likely to appear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Stated more formally: given non-negative integers &lt;em&gt;k&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; with &lt;em&gt;k&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt;= &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt;, generate a list of &lt;em&gt;k&lt;/em&gt; distinct random numbers, each less than &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt;. We reasonably ask that this be done in O(&lt;em&gt;k&lt;/em&gt;) time and O(1) additional space. Finally, the distribution must be uniform.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We started with the language of tweets, but it’s also possible to use the language of cards: deal k cards from a deck of size n, without replacement. So a poker hand like A2345 of clubs is valid for &lt;em&gt;k&lt;/em&gt;=5 and &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt;=52, but a hand containing AAAAA of clubs is not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The misleading part in using the language of cards is that you don’t often consider a deck of size 2&lt;sup&gt;64&lt;/sup&gt;. What’s nice about the card formulation though is that it conveys how simple the problem statement really is. This is a fundamental problem that was open for a long time. Nobody knew how to deal cards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first obstacle that makes the “dealing” (without replacement) hard is that the “draw” method doesn’t work. If you draw (with replacement) over and over again, ignoring cards you’ve already picked, you can simulate a deal, but you run into problems. The main one is that eventually you’re ignoring too many cards and the algorithm doesn’t finish on time (this is the coupon collector’s problem).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several things to try next and none of them work. You can’t generate a random number for every card in the deck (too many cards). You can’t rearrange the deck (too much space). Once you get the basic complexity requirements down, what makes the problem slippery is keeping the balance in the distribution. You can try to play with “resizing the window” you’re looking at, but most of these methods add bias (usually, you undersample early items and oversample later ones).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Card dealing was unsolved for a long time. Finally, Jeffrey Vitter published the solution in 1984. A cleaned-up version appeared in 1987. To put this in context, public-key cryptography algorithms appeared about a decade earlier in the 1970s. Basically all other fundamental problems that sound like this were solved in the 1960s and 1950s, so we might have expected to have a solution from then. But in the 1980s, dealing cards was a research-level problem in Knuth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The algorithm is still relatively unknown. When I came across a need for the algorithm in my work, it took a lot of detective work to even find it. There was no source code online. The algorithm is not referenced often, and when it is, it is in a highly obscure fashion. After reaching Vitter’s papers it again takes a concentrated effort to figure out what you need. This was a big surprise to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the explanation for this is that the method was originally presented as a capstone effort in the area of “reservoirs” and “tape sampling”. These days, while it’s possible you’ve worked at a place that uses tape drives for backup, chances are you’ve never programmed for a tape drive. I certainly haven’t. Based on my reading of the research, by the mid-80s subjects like tape drive sampling were considered antique. The most important algorithm appeared after people had stopped looking at that field. The only reason I know the field exists is it’s a giant section in Knuth that I’ve flipped past many times. Earlier algorithms for “card dealing” or “urn sampling” are hidden in there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today tape drive algorithms seem pointless, but there’s a good reason for approaching the problem from this perspective. Random access is costly on a tape drive. &lt;em&gt;Regular&lt;/em&gt; access is costly on a tape drive. Tape drives are much less nimble than disk drives, and this enforces a strongly sequential read mentality. A sequential, long-duration read pattern is a useful way to frame the problem, as it results in a solution which is both sorted and “online”. Sorted means the dealt cards are in order, and online means you can do them one at a time, perhaps while you wait for a spindle to turn. This completist approach may be how you need to think about the problem in order to solve it in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason it’s nice for an algorithm to produce results in sorted order is because it’s easy to randomize the order after the fact. The reverse is not true. Sorting algorithms are linear only in restricted cases, and so the addition of an O(&lt;em&gt;k*&lt;/em&gt;log(&lt;em&gt;k)&lt;/em&gt;) sort will forfeit our original O(&lt;em&gt;k&lt;/em&gt;) runtime. List shuffling algorithms are O(&lt;em&gt;k&lt;/em&gt;) and easy to implement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That it’s so easy to shuffle a small list is probably why the algorithm is overlooked. When most people need to deal cards they shuffle the entire deck. This works as long as the size of the deck is within reason. What happens is that once the deck is over a certain size, people resort to simple drawing algorithms, and nobody looks too closely at bias or inefficiency in the randomized application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is unfortunate. If you’ve ever sat through a statistics or combinatorics class, you know drawing balls from urns without replacement is a fundamental sampling application. In array languages like APL, sampling with and without replacement are implemented as first-class primitives “deal” and “draw”. It’s nice in theory to have sampling as a primitive since then you don’t have to worry about screwing it up. You do have to worry about the language implementors getting it wrong, though. I’ve talked with several people who’ve implemented deal-like primitives in the past, and Vitter’s name only comes up when I bring it up, so I assume many existing deal implementations either use slower methods, or, I guess, some kind of ad hoc method with an incorrect distribution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use Vitter’s algorithm in &lt;a href=&quot;http://kerfsoftware.com&quot;&gt;Kerf&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;deal()&lt;/em&gt; is a first-class primitive. Kerf’s &lt;em&gt;deal()&lt;/em&gt; is great for when banks need to sample a random collection of stock tickers, or a random collection of trades from throughout the day. Uses appear all the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve cleaned up an older version of the C source code we use and made it available below. This source first appeared in a previous project &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kevinlawler/kona/blob/master/src/r.c#L335&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. A description of the algorithm and pseudocode can be found &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ittc.ku.edu/~jsv/Papers/Vit87.RandomSampling.pdf&quot;&gt;here in Vitter’s paper&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;brush: cpp; title: ; notranslate&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;

//Copyright Kevin Lawler, released under ISC License

double random_double()  //your random double function
{
  //[0,1) uniformly random double, mt19937-64.c source is fine
  //keep in mind most double-based implementations drop randomness to 52-bits
  return genrand64_real2();
}

//POTENTIAL_OPTIMIZATION_POINT: Christian Neukirchen points out we can replace exp(log(x)*y) by pow(x,y)
//POTENTIAL_OPTIMIZATION_POINT: Vitter paper points out an exponentially distributed random var can provide speed ups
//Vitter, J.S. - An Efficient Algorithm for Sequential Random Sampling - ACM Trans. Math. Software 11 (1985), 37-57.
//'a' is space allocated for the hand
//'n' is the size of the hand
//'N' is the upper bound on the random card values
void vitter(int64_t *a, int64_t n, int64_t N) //Method D
{
 

  int64_t i = 0;
  int64_t j = -1;
  int64_t t; 
  int64_t qu1 = -n + 1 + N; 
  int64_t S; 
  int64_t negalphainv = -13;
  int64_t threshold = -negalphainv*n;
  int64_t limit;

  double nreal = n;
  double Nreal = N;
  double ninv = 1.0/n;
  double nmin1inv = 1.0/(n-1);
  double Vprime = exp(log(random_double())*ninv);

  double qu1real = -nreal + 1.0 + Nreal;
  double negSreal;
  double U; 
  double X; 
  double y1; 
  double y2; 
  double top; 
  double bottom;
  

  while(n &amp;gt; 1 &amp;amp;&amp;amp; threshold &amp;lt; N)
  {
    nmin1inv=1.0/(-1.0+nreal);

    while(1)
    {
      while(1)
      {
        X = Nreal * (-Vprime + 1.0);
        S = floor(X);

        if(S &amp;lt; qu1)
        {
          break;
        }

        Vprime = exp(log(random_double()) * ninv);
      }

      U = random_double();
      
      negSreal = -S;
      
      y1 = exp(log(U*Nreal/qu1real) * nmin1inv);
      
      Vprime = y1 * (-X / Nreal+1.0) * (qu1real / (negSreal + qu1real));
      
      if(Vprime &amp;lt;= 1.0)
      {
        break;
      }
      
      y2 = 1.0; 
      
      top = -1.0 + Nreal;       
      
      if(-1+n &amp;gt; S)
      {
        bottom = -nreal + Nreal;
        limit = -S + N;
      }
      else
      {
        bottom = -1.0 + negSreal + Nreal; 
        limit = qu1;
      }
      
      for(t = N-1; t &amp;gt;= limit; t--)
      {
        y2=(y2 * top) / bottom;
        top--; 
        bottom--;
      }
      
      if(Nreal / (-X + Nreal) &amp;gt;= y1 * exp(log(y2) * nmin1inv))
      {
        Vprime = exp(log(random_double()) * nmin1inv);
        break;
      }

      Vprime = exp(log(random_double()) * ninv);
    }

    j += S + 1;

    a[i++] = j;

    N = -S + (-1 + N); 

    Nreal = negSreal + (-1.0 + Nreal);

    n--;
    nreal--;
    ninv = nmin1inv;

    qu1 = -S + qu1;
    qu1real = negSreal + qu1real;

    threshold += negalphainv;
  }

  if(n&amp;gt;1)
  {
    vitter_a(a+i,n,N,j); // if i&amp;gt;0 then n has been decremented
  }
  else
  {
    S = floor(N * Vprime);

    j += S + 1;

    a[i++] = j;
  }

}

void vitter_a(int64_t *a, int64_t n, int64_t N, int64_t j) //Method A
{
  int64_t S, i = 0;
  double top = N - n, Nreal = N, V, quot;

  while(n &amp;gt;= 2)
  {
    V = random_double(); 
    S=0;
    quot=top/Nreal;

    while (quot&amp;gt;V)
    {
      S++; top--; Nreal--;
      quot = (quot * top)/Nreal;
    }

    j+=S+1;

    a[i++]=j;

    Nreal--;

    n--;
  }

  S = floor(round(Nreal) * random_double());

  j+=S+1;

  a[i++]=j;

}

&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;wpcnt&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wpa wpmrec&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;wpa-about&quot;&gt;Advertisements&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ColinWright</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>The Best Algorithm No One Knows About</og:title>
<og:url>https://getkerf.wordpress.com/2016/03/30/the-best-algorithm-no-one-knows-about/</og:url>
<og:description>Here’s a program roughly 0% of programmers know how to write: generate a list of random tweets, without duplication. You may think you know how to do this, but you almost assuredly don’…</og:description>
<og:image>https://s0.wp.com/i/blank.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://getkerf.wordpress.com/2016/03/30/the-best-algorithm-no-one-knows-about/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Color Emulation</title>
<link>https://byuu.net/video/color-emulation</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://byuu.net/video/color-emulation</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Nearly all retro game systems generate colors in some variant of RGB encoding. But the raw pixel colors are often designed for very different screens than those that emulators typically run on. In this article, I'll walk through the importance of color emulation, and provide some example code and screenshots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most common target display type these days are LCD panels. These are known for having very poor black levels. The distinction between TN, PVA, and IPS does not factor too much into this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes CRTs are used by enthusiasts, and OLED screens, especially on phones and tablets, are slowly becoming a thing. But for this article, the focus will be primarily on LCDs, though this technique is important for all display types.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;419436592&quot;&gt;Color precision&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first detail is that most computer monitors run in 24-bit color mode, which provides 8-bits of color detail for the red, green, and blue channels. But most older game systems do not specify colors in that precision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, the Sega Genesis encodes 9-bit colors, giving 3-bits per channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most naive emulator might simply place the 3-bits into the highest 3-bits of the output, leaving the low 5-bits clear, but this would cause whites to become slightly gray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
000 000 000 -&amp;gt; 000'00000 000'00000 000'00000
111 111 111 -&amp;gt; 111'00000 111'00000 111'00000
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If ones were instead filled in, then blacks would become too light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
000 000 000 -&amp;gt; 000'11111 000'11111 000'11111
111 111 111 -&amp;gt; 111'11111 111'11111 111'11111
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The solution to this is that the source bits should repeat to fill in all of the target bits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
000 -&amp;gt; 000 000 00...
010 -&amp;gt; 010 010 01...
011 -&amp;gt; 011 011 01...
111 -&amp;gt; 111 111 11...
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In code form:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
uint8 red = r &amp;lt;&amp;lt; 5 | r &amp;lt;&amp;lt; 2 | r &amp;gt;&amp;gt; 1
//rrr00000 | 000rrr00 | 000000rr -&amp;gt; rrrrrrrr
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;1752322835&quot;&gt;Screen emulation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Retro game systems weren't designed to run on modern PC LCD monitors. Typically home consoles were designed for CRTs, and portable consoles using much older, much less precise LCD panels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emulating specific screen artifacts such as screen curvature, scanlines, color bleed, interframe blending, aperture grilles, etc are beyond the scope of this article: we are focusing only on the individual pixel colors for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;931236051&quot;&gt;PC monitors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's a fairly wide range of colors on existing monitors, as few are professionally calibrated to any kind of standard like SRGB, but in general the best we can do is to attempt to emulate colors as if one were using a properly calibrated SRGB monitor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;1472442628&quot;&gt;CRT emulation: Super Nintendo&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main difference between CRTs and PC LCD monitors is the substantially reduced black levels, which can only be compensated for slightly through the use of a gamma curve:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
//SNES colors are in RGB555 format, so there are 32 levels for each channel
static const uint8 gammaRamp[32] = {
  0x00, 0x01, 0x03, 0x06, 0x0a, 0x0f, 0x15, 0x1c,
  0x24, 0x2d, 0x37, 0x42, 0x4e, 0x5b, 0x69, 0x78,
  0x88, 0x90, 0x98, 0xa0, 0xa8, 0xb0, 0xb8, 0xc0,
  0xc8, 0xd0, 0xd8, 0xe0, 0xe8, 0xf0, 0xf8, 0xff,
};
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Originally, this table comes from Overload of Super Sleuth / Kindred fame. What it does is darken the lower half of the color palette, while leaving the upper half of the palette alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The effect on the image output from emulation is striking: the left is the original, and the right is with the gamma ramp applied:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;////byuu.net/images/color-emulation-1.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;////byuu.net/images/color-emulation-2.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;////byuu.net/images/color-emulation-3.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;////byuu.net/images/color-emulation-4.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;2762090966&quot;&gt;LCD emulation: Game Boy Advance&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Game Boy Advance has one of the worst LCD screens, with colors that are completely washed out. Clever developers found that by greatly exaggerating the colors, they could produce better results on the real hardware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, if you use those colors on a standard PC monitor, the result is a technicolor nightmare. Thankfully, we can compensate for this as well to produce rather natural colors:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
double lcdGamma = 4.0, outGamma = 2.2;
double lb = pow(B / 31.0, lcdGamma);
double lg = pow(G / 31.0, lcdGamma);
double lr = pow(R / 31.0, lcdGamma);
r = pow((  0 * lb +  50 * lg + 255 * lr) / 255, 1 / outGamma) * (0xffff * 255 / 280);
g = pow(( 30 * lb + 230 * lg +  10 * lr) / 255, 1 / outGamma) * (0xffff * 255 / 280);
b = pow((220 * lb +  10 * lg +  50 * lr) / 255, 1 / outGamma) * (0xffff * 255 / 280);
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This bit of code is courtesy of Talarubi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Far more dramatic than the CRT example, the left is the original, and the right is the color-corrected version:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;////byuu.net/images/color-emulation-5.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;////byuu.net/images/color-emulation-6.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;715205027&quot;&gt;LCD emulation: Game Boy Color&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Game Boy Color's screen was surprisingly better at color reproduction, and the result was only a slight bit of washing out of the colors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An algorithm that is quite popular with Game Boy Color emulators is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
R = (r * 26 + g *  4 + b *  2);
G = (         g * 24 + b *  8);
B = (r *  6 + g *  4 + b * 22);
R = min(960, R) &amp;gt;&amp;gt; 2;
G = min(960, G) &amp;gt;&amp;gt; 2;
B = min(960, B) &amp;gt;&amp;gt; 2;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regrettably, I do not know who devised this algorithm. If you know, please contact me so that I can add proper accreditation here!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As before, the original is on the left, and the color-corrected version is on the right:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;////byuu.net/images/color-emulation-7.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;////byuu.net/images/color-emulation-8.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This example was chosen specifically because even though the former looks more vibrant and preferrable, if you look closely, you can see a checkerboard pattern around the character sprite that is brighter than the background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was likely an oversight on the part of the developers, as on a real Game Boy Color, whites are washed out and the two differing color shades blur together almost seamlessly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;759440532&quot;&gt;Closing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many more systems that currently lack good color emulation filters. They're very difficult to fine-tune. Most notably, we don't have good filters for approximating the colors of the WonderSwan and Neo Geo Pocket at the time of writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Handhelds are even trickier on account of often missing backlighting (or even frontlighting in some cases!), and system controls for adjusting the contrast ratio resulting in there not being any one true &quot;color&quot; value for any given RGB value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A particularly interesting corner case is the WonderSwan Color, which has a software-assignable flag to provide a stronger contrast on the image output. It's currently not known how to emulate that precisely, or if we even really can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Color emulation is definitely an area that could use more attention, so if you're an expert with math and analyzing colors, it would be a great place to get involved in the emulation scene with!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 06:57:08 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>bane</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://byuu.net/video/color-emulation</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The SR-71&amp;#039;s predecessor used cesium-laced fuel to create radar-absorbing exhaust</title>
<link>https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone/29787/the-sr-71-blackbirds-predecessor-created-plasma-stealth-by-burning-cesium-laced-fuel</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone/29787/the-sr-71-blackbirds-predecessor-created-plasma-stealth-by-burning-cesium-laced-fuel</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;article-head&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.thedrive.com/images/warzone-logo_high-contrast_dark-bg.png&quot; class=&quot;channel-logo&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;dek&quot;&gt;Skunk Works needed a way to hide the A-12's radar reflecting behind, so they dumped cesium into its fuel to create a radar-absorbing exhaust plume.&lt;/h2&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;hero-image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;image-fade-in&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://the-drive-3.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Fapi.thedrive.com%2Fwp-content%2Fuploads%2F2019%2F09%2Fa-12-top.jpg%3Fquality%3D85?w=1440&amp;amp;auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;ixlib=js-1.4.1&amp;amp;s=de071a2fb95a639d2d7070e8b3e09f28&quot; srcset=&quot;https://the-drive-3.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Fapi.thedrive.com%2Fwp-content%2Fuploads%2F2019%2F09%2Fa-12-top.jpg%3Fquality%3D85?w=1440&amp;amp;auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;ixlib=js-1.4.1&amp;amp;s=de071a2fb95a639d2d7070e8b3e09f28 1x,https://the-drive-3.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Fapi.thedrive.com%2Fwp-content%2Fuploads%2F2019%2F09%2Fa-12-top.jpg%3Fquality%3D85?w=1920&amp;amp;auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;ixlib=js-1.4.1&amp;amp;s=bbe17a97cf0734830152d40ff4fe20ea 1.5x&quot; onload=&quot;this.style.opacity=1&quot;/&gt;CIA/USAF&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;has-ad-column&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;articleFragment paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lockheed's &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone/26251/cia-and-skunk-works-secretly-planned-to-turn-the-a-12-spy-plane-into-a-space-launch-mothership&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A-12 Oxcart&lt;/a&gt; spy plane, which the company developed for the Central Intelligence Agency, was a direct response to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone/8395/the-pentagon-thought-it-could-retire-the-u-2-in-1969&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the growing vulnerability&lt;/a&gt; of its earlier &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone/19462/lockheed-is-proposing-a-major-triple-intelligence-upgrade-for-the-u-2-spy-plane&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;U-2 Dragon Lady&lt;/a&gt; to hostile air defense networks. As such, the plane – the predecessor to the U.S. Air Force's iconic &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone/16243/this-sr-71-blackbird-cockpit-tour-is-the-most-fascinating-thing-youll-see-all-week&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;SR-71 Blackbird&lt;/a&gt; – was extremely high- and fast-flying, but also incorporated then-state-of-the-art features to reduce its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone/15746/lockheeds-helendale-radar-signature-test-range-looks-right-out-of-science-fiction&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;radar cross-section&lt;/a&gt;. These included a combination of a stealthy overall shape and radar-evading structures, as well as the use of composites in its construction, and the incorporation of radar absorbing materials on its skin. A far less known, but still a key component of the Skunk Works plan to make the A-12 harder to spot on radar involved a cesium-laced fuel additive to dramatically reduce the radar signature of the plane's massive engine exhausts and afterburner plumes by creating an ionizing cloud behind the aircraft to help conceal its entire rear aspect from radar waves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even before the U-2 had become operational in 1956, the Central Intelligence Agency (CIA) had begun &lt;a href=&quot;https://nsarchive2.gwu.edu/NSAEBB/NSAEBB434/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;exploring potential successor designs&lt;/a&gt;. The next year, Scientific Engineering Institute (SEI), a CIA front, began laying out requirements for the new spy plane, including a need for a reduced radar signature. By 1958, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lockheed_A-12&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;proposals from Lockheed&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Convair_Kingfish&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Convair&lt;/a&gt; had emerged as the most feasible and the former firm's concept showed more promise when it came to what we would consider today to be stealthy features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;articleFragment paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“From this period [the late 1950s], our studies regarding radar cross-section showed that any flyable aircraft to be operational in the period after 1963 could not avoid radar detection,” Clarence &quot;Kelly&quot; Johnson, famed Lockheed engineer and head of the company's Advanced Development Programs (ADP) division, or Skunk Works, wrote in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cia.gov/library/readingroom/docs/DOC_0001458639.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;now-declassified official internal history&lt;/a&gt; of the A-12 program in 1968. “This did not mean that we had not gone all out on the reduction of radar cross section, as we made many very important contributions, including those of basic shape, to the whole problem on the A-12.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img itemprop=&quot;associatedMedia&quot; class=&quot;figure-image&quot; src=&quot;https://the-drive-3.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Fs3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2Fthe-drive-cms-content-staging%2Fmessage-editor%252F1568309404886-a-12.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;ixlib=js-1.4.1&amp;amp;s=de3aefd16c9bcaca12496fe7d7381a1d&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An early A-12 Oxcart during flight testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;articleFragment paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the CIA chose Lockheed to develop what would become the A-12 in 1959, the company continued to refine its radar-defeating features. The overall planform was designed to deflect radar waves, but there were a number of other physical additions to help improve its radar signature. These included spiked cones to shield the face of the inlets for the plane's two massive &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pratt_%26_Whitney_J58&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Pratt and Whitney J58&lt;/a&gt; engines, chines on the outside of the engine nacelles and engine ducts, curved extensions on the leading edges of the wings, and specially canted rear vertical stabilizers. Below the surface of its chined leading edges, radar defeating saw-tooth baffles also helped deaden the aircraft's radar returns. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nsarchive2.gwu.edu/NSAEBB/NSAEBB434/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img itemprop=&quot;associatedMedia&quot; class=&quot;figure-image-link&quot; src=&quot;https://the-drive.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Fs3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2Fthe-drive-cms-content-staging%2Fmessage-editor%252F1568299257457-anti-radar.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;ixlib=js-1.4.1&amp;amp;s=8becdb1d2e8bf3477fb3fde653f1bd82&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;caption-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A look at the various physical &quot;anti-radar&quot; features found the A-12 from the CIA's &lt;a href=&quot;https://nsarchive2.gwu.edu/NSAEBB/NSAEBB434/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;own now-declassified history&lt;/a&gt; of the U-2 and Oxcart programs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;articleFragment paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the exception of the inlet spikes, these added features made heavy use of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciradioactive.com/blackbird&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;composite, radar-absorbing materials&lt;/a&gt;. Lockheed also developed a special &quot;iron paint,&quot; sometimes referred to as the &quot;iron ball paint&quot; because the mixture contained tiny iron balls, to help absorb radar waves. The special blend, which was also applied to the SR-71, reportedly &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sr71.us/sr_construction.htm&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;cost $400 &lt;em&gt;per quart&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in the 1960s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These features all had a notable impact on reducing the aircraft's radar cross-section. However, there was one aspect of the plane's radar signature that still proved difficult to manage, the exhaust outlets for the J58s and the giant plume from the engines at full afterburner, which was necessary to propel the A-12 to its blistering top speed of well over Mach 3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“To overcome the afterburner problem of a large radar cross section return from the aft quadrant, we proposed the use of [a] cesium additive to the fuel,” Kelly Johnson wrote in his A-12 history. “This was first brought up by Mr. Ed Lovick of ADP and its final development was passed over to P&amp;amp;W. It was eventually a basic part of our cross section reduction methods.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The exhaust pipes were sixty inches in diameter, so they returned large amounts of energy at all frequencies of interest and over large angles to the rear,” Lovick, who also worked on the SR-71 and the F-117 Nighthawk stealth combat aircraft, wrote in his own book, &lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.com/books?id=a-sarv0vc0wC&amp;amp;printsec=frontcover#v=onepage&amp;amp;q&amp;amp;f=false&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Radar Man&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;: A Personal History of Stealth&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. “We knew that the only way to prevent such echoes was, in effect, to close the apertures.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img itemprop=&quot;associatedMedia&quot; class=&quot;figure-image&quot; src=&quot;https://the-drive.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Fs3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2Fthe-drive-cms-content-staging%2Fmessage-editor%252F1568323093706-ground-test.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;ixlib=js-1.4.1&amp;amp;s=54a8afb794711dac3dbf4c0651184b3f&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A J58 during a ground test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img itemprop=&quot;associatedMedia&quot; class=&quot;figure-image&quot; src=&quot;https://the-drive-2.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Fs3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2Fthe-drive-cms-content-staging%2Fmessage-editor%252F1568309548258-j58-2.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;ixlib=js-1.4.1&amp;amp;s=85149f7ad3664e0ee7c067c7b825d48c&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another J58 engine running on a test stand with its afterburner engaged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;articleFragment paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lockheed initially experimented with various metallic mesh screens, but quickly abandoned those efforts, according to Lovick. He says that Dr. Richard Bissell, the CIA’s Special Assistant for Planning and Coordination, who was managing the program, was so worried about this particular issue, he had considered calling for the scrapping of the entire development of a U-2 successor. That’s where the cesium additive, which eventually became known as A-50, came in an idea that Lovick claims saved the A-12 program. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The basic principle behind this is a concept known as “&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Plasma_stealth&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;plasma stealth&lt;/a&gt;.” In the simplest terms, this involves creating a cloud of plasma, or ionized gas, around some or all of an object. The plasma then absorbs electromagnetic radiation, such as radar waves, preventing them from reflecting back. There are multiple ways to generate the required plasma Lovick’s idea was to inject an alkali metal, via a fuel additive, into the extremely hot exhaust streams, where the heat would turn it into an ionized gas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nsarchive2.gwu.edu/NSAEBB/NSAEBB443/docs/area51_11.PDF&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img itemprop=&quot;associatedMedia&quot; class=&quot;figure-image-link&quot; src=&quot;https://the-drive-2.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Fs3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2Fthe-drive-cms-content-staging%2Fmessage-editor%252F1568299965318-rcs.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;ixlib=js-1.4.1&amp;amp;s=3c4720b0d3d23c7708194a985e8b0810&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;Lockheed via USAF&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A breakdown of the radar cross-section reducing goals and the efforts Lockheed was undertaking to meet them with regards to the A-12 from a &lt;a href=&quot;https://nsarchive2.gwu.edu/NSAEBB/NSAEBB443/docs/area51_11.PDF&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;now-declassified company report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;articleFragment paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lockheed tested mixtures using sodium, potassium, and cesium. “Cesium seemed to be the material of choice because in the gaseous state it is the most easily ionized,” Lovick wrote in his book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final additive mix was 30 percent cesium metal and 60 percent dialkyl phosphate, according to Lovick. However, he says in his book that the testing of the additives, which included flight tests at Area 51, was finished by 1965, but it’s unclear if this only refers to Lockheed’s portion of the work before the project passed to Pratt &amp;amp; Whitney. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1965, Pratt &amp;amp; Whitney &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cia.gov/library/readingroom/document/cia-rdp71b00399r000600120025-4&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;had informed the CIA&lt;/a&gt; that it was looking into a new &quot;carrier fluid&quot; for the cesium in A-50, assumed to be dialkyl phosphate, because of a supply chain problem. The company had been purchasing the base solution from sources in the detergent industry, which were generating it as a byproduct of their own production processes. New U.S. government regulations had subsequently forced changes in detergent production that eliminated this byproduct. So, it's unclear if the composition of A-50 subsequently changed or if Pratt &amp;amp; Whitney just identified a new source of dialkyl phosphate in the end. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img itemprop=&quot;associatedMedia&quot; class=&quot;figure-image&quot; src=&quot;https://the-drive.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Fs3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2Fthe-drive-cms-content-staging%2Fmessage-editor%252F1568300826703-memo.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;ixlib=js-1.4.1&amp;amp;s=26eebb1b5f35830dea8c66de56fe0305&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A note about A-50 production from a 1965 CIA memo regarding the A-12.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;articleFragment paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This raises separate questions about the toxicity of the A-50 additive. Though there is no indication that A-50 used a radioactive cesium isotope, the compound is toxic and it's unclear how hazardous the complete mixture may have been, before or after being burned up in the J58s, especially given that its primary component was a detergent byproduct. At the same time, jet fuels are themselves generally toxic, to begin with, and the special fuel that the A-12s ran on was certainly no exception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s also not clear from the available records how much A-50 was necessary per gallon of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/JP-7&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;JP-7 jet fuel&lt;/a&gt; to create the desired effect. The J58s on the A-12s, as well as the SR-71s, needed JP-7, which has a very low volatility and high flash point, because of the unusual combination of extremely high internal temperatures and very low external temperatures the planes experienced during high-altitude supersonic flight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The development of the A-12, in general, where almost every step was a cutting-edge engineering feat, suffered numerous delays and, despite a first flight in 1962, it did not fly an operational mission until 1967. Between 1967 and 1968, A-12s flew 26 sorties over North Vietnam and an additional three over North Korea as part of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.airspacemag.com/military-aviation/operation-black-shield-180964751/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Operation Black Shield&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's hard to tell definitively whether or not A-12s used JP-7 mixed with A-50 on any of those flights. The CIA &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cia.gov/library/readingroom/docs/CIA-RDP69B00041R000800010041-5.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;wanted to use it&lt;/a&gt; on at least one Black Shield mission, referred to as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cia.gov/library/readingroom/docs/DOC_0000615703.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;BX6725&lt;/a&gt;, on Oct. 4, 1967, which included grabbing imagery of Chinese military facilities on Hainan Island as the aircraft exited North Vietnam into the South China Sea. At least one other mission, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cia.gov/library/readingroom/docs/CIA-RDP69B00041R000900030026-9.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;BX6727&lt;/a&gt;, followed similar tracks that offered an opportunity to collect imagery on Chinese targets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img itemprop=&quot;associatedMedia&quot; class=&quot;figure-image&quot; src=&quot;https://the-drive.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Fs3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2Fthe-drive-cms-content-staging%2Fmessage-editor%252F1568302706006-hainan.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;ixlib=js-1.4.1&amp;amp;s=5b9ca2a477de6d5302c2319801bb5667&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A low-quality scan of the map of the approximate tracks for Black Shield mission BX 6725. Hainan Island is not visible, except for the name, but lies just to the northeast of where the routes began and ended in the South China Sea, to the right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;articleFragment paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, none of the post-mission reports clearly state that the A-12s on either of these missions, or any others, used A-50. Available records also make clear that standard JP-7 did not have the cesium mixture and that personnel would only have added it when authorized to do so for a specific mission. It’s not entirely clear why, with the reported effectiveness of the mixture, the CIA would have declined to actually employ operationally in the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;North Vietnamese air defenses, some of the densest in the world at the time, attempted to engage the A-12s during each sortie. On one flight on Oct. 30, 1967, they fired at least six Soviet-made &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/S-75_Dvina&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;SA-2 Guideline&lt;/a&gt; surface-to-air missiles—the same missiles that had shot down Gary Powers' U-2 over the Soviet Union in 1960—at an Oxcart with CIA pilot Dennis Sullivan at the controls. The pictures he took during that flight caught the contrails of the missiles heading toward his aircraft, according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://nsarchive2.gwu.edu/NSAEBB/NSAEBB434/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;an official CIA history&lt;/a&gt;. He saw at least three of them detonate near him and a post-flight inspection found a fragment of one of the missiles embedded in the A-12's fuselage. So, there was certainly a threat. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Years before Black Shield, the CIA had also worked to assess the capabilities of advanced Soviet radars as part of programs codenamed &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cia.gov/library/readingroom/docs/stealth_%20count.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Melody and Palladium&lt;/a&gt;. These projects &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone/28640/could-some-of-the-ufos-navy-pilots-are-encountering-be-airborne-radar-reflectors&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;involved complex efforts&lt;/a&gt; to generate false radar returns and then monitor Soviet reactions, thereby gauging what they could and could not &quot;see&quot; on their radar screens. As such, the Agency would have had at least some sense of how vulnerable the A-12s would be to detection in spite of their stealthy features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img itemprop=&quot;associatedMedia&quot; class=&quot;figure-image&quot; src=&quot;https://the-drive.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Fs3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2Fthe-drive-cms-content-staging%2Fmessage-editor%252F1568310103872-p-14.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;ixlib=js-1.4.1&amp;amp;s=4751c5bed5acca59bb9fe365fdbcf93d&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;ShinePhantom via Wikimedia&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Soviet P-14 Tall King radar, the appearance of which had prompted the CIA to begin looking into reducing the radar cross-section of the U-2, as well as its successor, in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;articleFragment paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given that the A-12’s speed and its electronic warfare package seemed sufficient to protect it over North Vietnam, the CIA may have continued to withhold use of A-50 for operational security reasons. Using it could have exposed its existence and given the Soviets and their allies time to develop countermeasures, rendering it less effective when it might have been absolutely necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not using it outside of an emergency situation where planners deemed to be absolutely critical to a mission’s success may have also been a product of the additive's impacts on the J58 engines. Typically, jet aircraft try to avoid ingesting particulate matter, especially alkali metals that could melt and fuze to internal components, which generally lead to extensive maintenance or potentially catastrophic accidents in flight. Beyond that, adding additional chemical components to the already highly sensitive JP-7 mixture could have had impacts on the fuel’s performance. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A CIA memorandum from 1964 offers evidence of some of these issues in noting that A-12s required a modification to their fuel systems so that pilots could increase the flow when using fuel mixed with A-50. A separate message regarding BX 6725 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cia.gov/library/readingroom/docs/CIA-RDP69B00041R000800010041-5.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;also specifically notes concerns&lt;/a&gt; about degraded engine life due to protracted use of A-50-laced JP-7, saying that &quot;all operational considerations have been applied to reduce additive burning to a minimum.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bigger issue at the end of the day may simply have been the Air Force's concerns about flying KC-135A tankers with loads of JP-7 mixed with A-50. Standard Black Shield missions involved A-12s launching from Kadena Air Base in Japan, then immediately linking up with one of the tankers. The spy planes would then fly their mission and link up with a tanker again, typically over Thailand, before heading back to base. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img itemprop=&quot;associatedMedia&quot; class=&quot;figure-image&quot; src=&quot;https://the-drive-2.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Fs3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2Fthe-drive-cms-content-staging%2Fmessage-editor%252F1568315719503-refuel.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;ixlib=js-1.4.1&amp;amp;s=60bf6cdfbf76d59d59e7075561892ef9&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A KC-135Q refuels an SR-71, the successor to the A-12.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;articleFragment paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the A-12 arrived at the refueling point late, or there was some other issue with the rendezvous, the KC-135As ran the risk of having to burn the JP-7 in order to stay aloft or make it back to base themselves. The tankers could have used the JP-7 in an emergency, but doing so required a complete purge of the tanker's fuel system and J57 engines afterward. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Concerns about JP-7 mixing with the conventional jet fuel the KC-135s use to power their own engines during missions eventually led the Air Force to convert 56 of the aircraft in into &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.habu.org/kc-135q/kc135q.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the KC-135Q configuration&lt;/a&gt; between 1966 and 1968. These aircraft were specifically set aside to support SR-71 operations and featured body tanks that were completely isolated from the rest of the plane's fuel system to ensure everything stayed separate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The A-50 additive would have only compounded these issues, though Lockheed's Lovick said in his book that the company actually conducted the initial tests of the additive effects using a J57. The pre-planning message regarding BX 6725 also suggests that, somewhere along the line, studies had shown tankers could safely burn A-50 in emergencies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img itemprop=&quot;associatedMedia&quot; class=&quot;figure-image&quot; src=&quot;https://the-drive-3.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Fs3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2Fthe-drive-cms-content-staging%2Fmessage-editor%252F1568314672906-bx6725.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;ixlib=js-1.4.1&amp;amp;s=e2558639ac55bcd994f8aaa6f4770f91&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An excerpt from the BX 6725 mission planning message talking about issues relating to A-50.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;articleFragment paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Air Force seems to have been unconvinced. “Tankers almost forced to burn A-50 if there is a delay by receiver,” a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cia.gov/library/readingroom/docs/CIA-RDP69B00041R000800010035-2.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;message dated September 1967&lt;/a&gt; concerning Black Shield operations states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;A-50 still a major logistical problem but understand the reasoning behind at least giving it a try,” the missive continued. “SAC [Strategic Air Command] still not authorizing use except in emergency.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img itemprop=&quot;associatedMedia&quot; class=&quot;figure-image&quot; src=&quot;https://the-drive.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Fs3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2Fthe-drive-cms-content-staging%2Fmessage-editor%252F1568308108132-a-50-note.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;ixlib=js-1.4.1&amp;amp;s=5a227915f850d8eb2c5ae837c792a2d9&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A mention of issues related to A-50 use from a September 1967 CIA message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;articleFragment paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever the case, A-50 appears to have at least remained available for use throughout Operation Black Shield. What happened to any remaining stockpiles of the additive after the A-12 program came to a close in 1968 is unclear. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though there’s no evidence they ever did, there’s no reason the SR-71 would not have been able to use it, if necessary, with the same potential impacts on engine life and performance. The segregated fuel system on the KC-135Q tankers, which the Air Force eventually re-engined with CFM56s to create the KC-135T variant, would have largely eliminated the concerns about the additive finding its way into the tanker's engines for any reason. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone/20379/f-15e-crew-and-kc-135-boom-operator-talk-the-merits-of-coffee-while-refueling&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;KC-10 Extenders&lt;/a&gt;, which also supported the Blackbirds later in their service life, also had the ability to keep the JP-7 separated from the aircraft's own fuel load.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img itemprop=&quot;associatedMedia&quot; class=&quot;figure-image&quot; src=&quot;https://the-drive-3.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Fs3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2Fthe-drive-cms-content-staging%2Fmessage-editor%252F1568326010503-kc-10.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;ixlib=js-1.4.1&amp;amp;s=1a6b8d2c2aa6a4a132501d3dc34be061&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A KC-10 refuels an SR-71.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;articleFragment paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, even though the SR-71 featured improved electronic warfare capabilities and never overflew the Soviet Union, it still operated in areas where there were very real threats from enemy air defenses. Blackbirds also flew over North Vietnam, for instance, and certainly flew missions around the Soviet Union and its Warsaw Pact allies, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone/25205/declassified-us-honors-swedish-pilots-for-escorting-stricken-sr-71-to-safety-during-cold-war&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;which carried distinct risks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img itemprop=&quot;associatedMedia&quot; class=&quot;figure-image&quot; src=&quot;https://the-drive-3.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Fs3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2Fthe-drive-cms-content-staging%2Fmessage-editor%252F1568308280584-sweden.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;ixlib=js-1.4.1&amp;amp;s=14524ed491c7d5c4cb0170ae8bfad148&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;Forsvarsmakten&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A recently declassified picture of an SR-71 experiencing an in-flight emergency in Swedish airspace during a mission near the Soviet Union in 1987.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;articleFragment paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SR-71s also &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/war-is-boring/when-mach-3-spy-planes-dueled-over-the-middle-east-462912095ed&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;flew missions over&lt;/a&gt; Egypt, Israel, Lebanon, and Syria around &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yom_Kippur_War&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the Yom Kippur War&lt;/a&gt; in 1973, areas again with heavy, potentially hostile air defenses. Flights around North Korea, including near the Demilitarized Zone that bisects the Korean Peninsula, were risky, too, with the North Koreans attempting to shoot down one of the Blackbirds on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/1981/08/27/world/missile-is-fired-by-north-koreans-at-us-spy-plane-near-the-dmz.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;at least one occasion&lt;/a&gt; in 1981. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the Blackbirds also flew a mission over Libya to &lt;a href=&quot;https://gizmodo.com/how-a-pilot-risked-his-life-to-spy-on-libya-5768790&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;conduct bomb damage assessments&lt;/a&gt; following U.S. airstrikes on that country in 1986 during &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/1986_United_States_bombing_of_Libya&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Operation El Dorado Canyon&lt;/a&gt;. There were also flights in the Persian Gulf targeting Iran &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.si.edu/object/nasm_A19920072000&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;during the 1980s&lt;/a&gt;, as well as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cia.gov/library/readingroom/docs/CIA-RDP79M00467A000100120005-3.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;routine flights over Cuba&lt;/a&gt;. Additional missions reportedly occured over or near &lt;a href=&quot;https://gizmodo.com/the-thrill-of-flying-the-sr-71-blackbird-5511236&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Falklands&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.upi.com/Archives/1984/11/11/Nicaragua-said-US-spy-planes-Sunday-broke-the-sound/1338468997200/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Nicaragua&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.popularmechanics.com/flight/a14491/story-of-sr-71-blackbird/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;South Africa&lt;/a&gt;. The aircraft could have been called upon to conduct other riskier missions if an actual large-scale conflict had broken out between the United States and a major adversary, such as the Soviet Union.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div itemprop=&quot;associatedMedia&quot; class=&quot;video-youtube&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe class=&quot;video-youtube__video&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/dlSVWo7__-k?rel=0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;has-ad-column&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;articleFragment paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Work related to plasma stealth, as a general concept, certainly continued in the decades after A-12 operations ceased, both in the United States and the Soviet Union. The extent to which this included research and development on creating these ionized clouds via chemical additives in an engine's exhaust stream is less clear. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are reports that Russia may be continuing to investigate the possible value of plasma stealth, especially as it related to the development of hypersonic vehicles. There &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.1tv.ru/news/2017-05-21/325643-v_rossii_uspeshno_proveli_ispytaniya_novoy_giperzvukovoy_rakety_tsirkon_ne_imeyuschey_analogov_v_mire&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;are unconfirmed reports&lt;/a&gt; that the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/3M22_Zircon&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;3M22 Zircon&lt;/a&gt; hypersonic cruise missile &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.trud.ru/article/17-03-2016/1335410_opasnee_kalibra_rossija_nachala_ispytanie_giperzvukovoj_rakety_tsirkon.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;may have some capabilities&lt;/a&gt; in this regard, though the exact method of generating the ionization is unclear. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless, ensuring adequate radar-evading effects in the rear aspect &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone/29734/the-f-35a-will-finally-get-chaff-countermeasures-to-confuse-enemy-radars-next-year&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;remains one of&lt;/a&gt; the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone/27185/f-35s-most-sinister-capability-are-towed-decoys-that-unreel-from-inside-its-stealthy-skin&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;more challenging elements&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone/29559/russias-sukhoi-shows-off-stealthier-vision-for-its-hunter-unmanned-combat-air-vehicle&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;designing stealthy aircraft&lt;/a&gt; and missiles. So, plasma stealth would certainly continue to be one possible method going about this. Concerns about impacts on the engine from using chemical additives would be largely moot in a one-time-use system, such as a cruise missile. Impacts on actual flight performance from using fuel additives would still be an issue, especially &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone/29598/russia-claims-a-grabber-arm-equipped-il-76-will-launch-and-recover-hypersonic-vehicles&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;with flight vehicles&lt;/a&gt; that need to be flying at extreme speeds to remain stable. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plasma stealth could also be a valuable option for quickly improving the stealthy &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone/20434/no-the-su-57-isnt-junk-six-features-we-like-on-russias-new-fighter&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;qualities of existing designs&lt;/a&gt;. As was the case with A-50, fuel additives, specifically, could provide a way of rapidly adding in this kind of capability, but only as necessary and with minimal modifications to the aircraft itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If nothing else, though, the development of the A-50 additive is another intriguing and very obscure part of the story of the A-12, as well as its successor, the SR-71, much of which &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone/26251/cia-and-skunk-works-secretly-planned-to-turn-the-a-12-spy-plane-into-a-space-launch-mothership&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;still remains unknown&lt;/a&gt; to this day, and it also offers intriguing insights into the dawn of stealth technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Contact the author: joe@thedrive.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;articleFragment&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;newsletter-signup the-warzone-wire&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;blurb&quot;&gt;Don't forget to sign up&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;email-blurb&quot;&gt;Your Email Address&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;related-content related-content--rich&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;title-message&quot;&gt;MORE TO READ&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;related-article&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;CIA And Skunk Works Secretly Planned To Turn The A-12 Spy Plane Into A Space Launch Mothership&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dek&quot;&gt;The proposal sheds more light on decades of secretive U.S. work to realize air-launched space access capabilities.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;related-article&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Air Force Wanted To Turn Skunk Works' Mach 3 Capable Recon Drone Into A Nuclear Bomber&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dek&quot;&gt;The concept would have given the service a penetrating high-speed strike asset, something it is still interested in to this day.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;related-article&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Declassified: US Honors Swedish Pilots For Escorting Stricken SR-71 To Safety During Cold War&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dek&quot;&gt;The Blackbird had suffered an engine failure during a mission over the Baltic Sea and its crew feared that Soviet jets might be hunting for them.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;related-article&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;This SR-71 Blackbird Cockpit Tour Is The Most Fascinating Thing You'll See All Week&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dek&quot;&gt;Veteran SR-71 pilot gives a highly detailed tour of both cockpits and shares incredible recollections from his time flying the legendary jet.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;related-article&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;This Overview Of NASA's SR-71 Blackbird Is A Must Watch&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dek&quot;&gt;Even the tiniest details about the SR-71 tend to be fascinating, but a good overview of the jet and its operations is also very intriguing.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;nativo-related-ad&quot;&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;nativo-related-ad&quot;&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/section&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 01:47:52 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ivanech</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>The SR-71 Blackbird's Predecessor Created &quot;Plasma Stealth&quot; By Burning Cesium-Laced Fuel</og:title>
<og:description>Skunk Works needed a way to hide the A-12's radar reflecting behind, so they dumped cesium into its fuel to create a radar-absorbing exhaust plume.</og:description>
<og:image>https://api.thedrive.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/a-12-top.jpg?quality=85</og:image>
<og:url>https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone/29787/the-sr-71-blackbirds-predecessor-created-plasma-stealth-by-burning-cesium-laced-fuel</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone/29787/the-sr-71-blackbirds-predecessor-created-plasma-stealth-by-burning-cesium-laced-fuel</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Toyota is trying to put solar panels on a Prius to charge battery during the day</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-09-12/a-car-running-on-empty-isn-t-impossible-if-toyota-gets-its-way</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-09-12/a-car-running-on-empty-isn-t-impossible-if-toyota-gets-its-way</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-09-12/a-car-running-on-empty-isn-t-impossible-if-toyota-gets-its-way&quot;&gt;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-09-12/a-car-running-on-empty-isn-t-impossible-if-toyota-gets-its-way&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20957946&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20957946&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 263&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 325&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 00:32:29 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>hhs</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/tosv2.html?vid=&amp;uuid=2eac6900-d68b-11e9-8a9e-4552c5fdfcbf&amp;url=L25ld3MvYXJ0aWNsZXMvMjAxOS0wOS0xMi9hLWNhci1ydW5uaW5nLW9uLWVtcHR5LWlzbi10LWltcG9zc2libGUtaWYtdG95b3RhLWdldHMtaXRzLXdheQ==</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>French city of Dunkirk tests out free transport</title>
<link>https://www.france24.com/en/20190831-france-dunkirk-free-transportation-bus-success-climate-cities</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.france24.com/en/20190831-france-dunkirk-free-transportation-bus-success-climate-cities</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The city of Dunkirk in northern France launched a revamped bus system last year with a twist – it’s completely free. A new study shows that the programme is not only revitalising the city center but also helping the environment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;234.39705882353&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;m-interstitial&quot;&gt;
&lt;div data-readmore-target=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;m-interstitial__ad&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;m-block-ad&quot; data-tms-ad-type=&quot;box&quot; data-tms-ad-status=&quot;idle&quot; data-tms-ad-pos=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advertising&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;button data-readmore-unlocker=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;m-interstitial__unlock-btn&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;m-interstitial__unlock-btn__text&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/button&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dunkirk, which sits on the “Opal Coast” at the northernmost tip of &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.france24.com/en/tag/france/&quot;&gt;France&lt;/a&gt;, is best known for the battle and evacuation of hundreds of thousands of Allied soldiers to Britain during the Second World War. After the war, the port city was rebuilt as an industrial hub, with oil refineries and a major steel mill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the city (population 90,000) seeks to become a beacon of a greener economy, by building infrastructure such as a &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.latribune.fr/entreprises-finance/industrie/energie-environnement/parc-eolien-offshore-de-dunkerque-le-groupement-edf-remporte-l-appel-d-offres-820483.html&quot;&gt;large-scale wind farm&lt;/a&gt; off the coast and transforming its city center to be more pedestrian-friendly. Key to this effort is its free bus system, inaugurated on 1 September, 2018. The network connects Dunkirk to a cluster of neighbouring towns, with five express lines running &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.dkbus.com/ftp/documents/Plan-verso-2020-BAT1.pdf&quot;&gt;every ten minutes&lt;/a&gt; throughout the day, and a dozen other lines serving less dense areas. Altogether, it serves some 200,000 residents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many, the effect has been nothing short of liberating, says Vanessa Delevoye, editor of &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.urbislemag.fr/dunkerque-le-bus-gratuit-seduit-les-automobilistes-billet-545-urbis-le-mag.html&quot;&gt;Urbis&lt;/a&gt;, a magazine of urban politics published by the local government. To get around town, you no longer need to look at the schedules, buy tickets or worry about parking, she says. You just hop on the bus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s become a synonym of freedom,” she says, attracting those who might not otherwise have used public transport. In this largely working-class city, “people of limited means say they’ve rediscovered transport” – a prerequisite to finding a job, maintaining friendships or participating in local arts and culture. But it’s not only disadvantaged or working-class people who take the bus. It is also attracting white-collar workers, students and pensioners, according to Delevoye.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;m-figure__img-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;m-figure__img&quot; data-lazyloaded=&quot;image-formats&quot; data-image-dataset=&quot;[{&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https:\/\/s.france24.com\/media\/display\/63759f78-cc98-11e9-8543-005056a98db9\/dunkirk-lighthouse-etienne-m.jpg&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;width&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;height&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;name&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;original&amp;quot;}]&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s.france24.com/media/display/63759f78-cc98-11e9-8543-005056a98db9/dunkirk-lighthouse-etienne-m.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;m-figure__img&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;m-figure__caption__credits&quot;&gt;Etienne, Flickr Creative Commons | A postwar industrial hub, Dunkirk now seeks to become a beacon of a greener economy.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accessibility has been “one of the keys of Dunkirk’s success” with free transport, says Maxime Huré, a political scientist at the University of Perpignan and president of the think tank &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://vigs-conseil.com/&quot;&gt;VIGS&lt;/a&gt;, which specialises in urban development and transport issues. Over the past year, Huré has led an in-depth study of Dunkirk’s free bus experiment, commissioned by the city and carried out by an independent team of social science researchers. The study will officially be released on 11 September, but some of its &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://vigs-conseil.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/VIGS-Note-premiers-re%CC%81sultats-03.06-V7.pdf&quot;&gt;initial findings&lt;/a&gt; have already been published. They show that ridership has spiked over the last year, more than doubling on weekends and increasing by around 60 percent during the week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Going car-free&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More revealing than the simple increase is the way that the free buses are changing residents’ habits. In a town where a large majority of residents (about two-thirds) have typically depended on their cars to get around, half of the 2,000 passengers surveyed by researchers said they take the bus more or much more than before. Of those new users, 48 percent say they regularly use it &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.urbislemag.fr/dunkerque-le-bus-gratuit-seduit-les-automobilistes-billet-545-urbis-le-mag.html&quot;&gt;instead of their cars&lt;/a&gt;. Some (approximately 5 percent of the total respondents) even said that they sold their car or decided against buying a second one because of the free buses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;m-figure__img-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;m-figure__img&quot; data-lazyloaded=&quot;image-formats&quot; data-image-dataset=&quot;[{&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https:\/\/s.france24.com\/media\/display\/4c70649c-cc0d-11e9-a75f-005056bf87d6\/dunkirk-vigs-infographic-2.jpg&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;width&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;height&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;name&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;original&amp;quot;}]&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s.france24.com/media/display/4c70649c-cc0d-11e9-a75f-005056bf87d6/dunkirk-vigs-infographic-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;m-figure__img&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;m-figure__caption__credits&quot;&gt;Source: VIGS. Infographic by AGUR, courtesy of Urbis magazine. Adapted by France 24.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“My car was getting old, it needed major repairs, so I gave it up and I told myself, the new bus network is coming, I’ll see how it goes,” one retiree, Philippe, told the VIGS researchers. “In the end, I don’t need it – I do everything by bus and on foot.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For some young people, the reliable bus service means they may not need to start driving at all. “My cousin started taking lessons to get her driver’s license, she failed, and she dropped it because she found a job and the bus takes her straight there from her house,” said Laure, another passenger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the clear implications for reducing pollution, fighting climate change was not the main goal of Dunkirk’s free bus campaign, says Delevoye. If nothing else, though, it’s a welcome side effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The free buses are a step in overhauling the car-centered model that has shaped European and North American cities since the Second World War. That model has shown itself not only to be environmentally unsustainable, but “disastrous” for urban life, argues Delevoye.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Could the Dunkirk model catch on?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Styling itself as a “&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.urbislemag.fr/les-billets-urbis-du-genre-le-labo-du-bus-gratuit-30.html&quot;&gt;laboratory&lt;/a&gt;” of free transport, Dunkirk has attracted an “incessant” stream of visitors intrigued at whether it could work in their cities, says Delevoye. Among them was Paris Mayor Anne Hidalgo, who &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.liberation.fr/france/2018/10/30/dunkerque-anne-hidalgo-teste-le-bus-gratis_1688890&quot;&gt;took a ride&lt;/a&gt; on Dunkirk’s buses last October. A few months later, she announced that Paris would &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.cnews.fr/france/2019-08-15/paris-qui-est-concerne-par-la-gratuite-dans-les-transports-en-commun-des-septembre&quot;&gt;extend free transit passes&lt;/a&gt; to children under 11 and young people under the age of 20 with a handicap, taking effect this Sunday, 1 September. That’s in addition to senior citizens earning less than €2,000 a month, who already benefited from free ‘Navigo’ passes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such measures remain a far cry from Dunkirk’s model, whose appeal rests in part on there being no forms to fill in or criteria to meet. Expanding free public transport to the level of a major city like Paris poses a completely different set of challenges, says Huré. Before the network was revamped in Dunkirk, buses were often almost empty – a problem common to many small and medium-sized cities. Major metropolises tend to face the opposite problem: a public transport system that is saturated, especially at peak hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Historically, the lack of travelers on Dunkirk’s buses also meant that ticket sales contributed only a small amount – about 10 percent – of the system’s funding. The rest was publicly subsidised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;m-figure__img-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;m-figure__img&quot; data-lazyloaded=&quot;image-formats&quot; data-image-dataset=&quot;[{&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https:\/\/s.france24.com\/media\/display\/2b3543e2-cc99-11e9-adb3-005056bf87d6\/dunkirk-carnaval-etienne-m.jpg&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;width&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;height&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;name&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;original&amp;quot;}]&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s.france24.com/media/display/2b3543e2-cc99-11e9-adb3-005056bf87d6/dunkirk-carnaval-etienne-m.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;m-figure__img&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;m-figure__caption__credits&quot;&gt;Etienne, Flickr Creative Commons | Dunkirk is known for its colourful annual carnival. This year, the carnival period saw a spike in bus ridership.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Dunkirk’s left-wing Mayor Patrice Vergriete, who took office in 2014 after campaigning in large part on the free bus pledge, the small share of ticket revenue was &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.liberation.fr/france/2019/08/30/pionnier-des-bus-gratuits-dunkerque-suscite-l-interet-de-nombreuses-villes_1748292&quot;&gt;less a problem than an opportunity&lt;/a&gt;. It meant that the city could get rid of fares without a major impact on its budget.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, finding the resources to make buses free came down to a “political choice”, says Delevoye. Even in Paris, which is on the high end of funding from customers at &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.iledefrance-mobilites.fr/le-financement-des-transports-publics/&quot;&gt;28 percent&lt;/a&gt;, the transport system is paid for largely by taxation. In other words, the obstacles are less financial than political.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A “figurehead” for post-industrial urban transition&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, several cities closer to Dunkirk’s size are testing out their own versions. Among them is Calais, less than 50 kilometers down the coast. Mayor Natacha Bouchart, of the right-wing Républicains party, presented the measure as a &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.20minutes.fr/societe/2382027-20181127-calais-agglomeration-approuve-gratuite-bus-partir-2020&quot;&gt;response to the Yellow Vest movement’s&lt;/a&gt; demands for greater purchasing power and better public services. It was voted for unanimously by the local government and will take effect in 2020, affecting 100,000 residents. As well as Calais, &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.banquedesterritoires.fr/chateauroux-metropole-des-bus-gratuits-pour-un-service-plus-efficace-36&quot;&gt;Chateauroux&lt;/a&gt; (population 44,000) and &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://france3-regions.francetvinfo.fr/nouvelle-aquitaine/deux-sevres/niort/bus-gratuits-niort-an-apres-mise-place-quel-bilan-1584421.html&quot;&gt;Niort&lt;/a&gt; (population 59,000) in central-western France have also made their buses free in recent years, although without necessarily improving the service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Valenciennes, another city in France’s industrial north, is taking a step in the same direction. Starting this Sunday, residents under the age of 25 can sign up for a pass that will allow them to travel around for free, after a €20 registration fee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Vincent Jarousseau, a photojournalist who spent two years documenting life in neighbouring Denain for his book &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.arenes.fr/livre/les-racines-de-la-colere/&quot;&gt;Les racines de la colère&lt;/a&gt; (The Roots of Anger), the interest of Valenciennes’s approach is mostly “symbolic”. For one thing, students, who are among the main users of public transit in the area, already benefit from steeply discounted passes. And those who wish to take advantage of the new policy face an initial bureaucratic hurdle – they can’t just step on the tram.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, Jarousseau says the push toward free transport could help relieve the pressure on some young residents, who risk confronting ticket controllers when they can’t pay the fare. Denain, which is part of the Valenciennois transport network, is one of the &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.la-croix.com/Culture/Livres-et-idees/Denain-roman-vrai-classes-populaires-2019-03-14-1201008657&quot;&gt;poorest cities in France&lt;/a&gt;, its economy decimated by the closure of an iconic steel plant in the late 1970s as well as surrounding coal mines. It was an early base of support for the &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.france24.com/en/tag/yellow-vest-protests/&quot;&gt;Yellow Vest movement&lt;/a&gt; last fall and winter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;m-figure__img-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;m-figure__img&quot; data-lazyloaded=&quot;image-formats&quot; data-image-dataset=&quot;[{&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https:\/\/s.france24.com\/media\/display\/9beac25c-cc98-11e9-89a3-005056bff430\/dunkirk-harbor-etienne-m.jpg&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;width&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;height&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;name&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;original&amp;quot;}]&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s.france24.com/media/display/9beac25c-cc98-11e9-89a3-005056bff430/dunkirk-harbor-etienne-m.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;m-figure__img&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;m-figure__caption__credits&quot;&gt;Etienne, Flickr Creative Commons | Dunkirk remains a heavily industrial, working-class city with an active harbor.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Damien Carême, the mayor of Grande-Synthe (which neighbors Dunkirk), improving the lives of working-class residents, revitalising small cities and fighting climate change &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2019/07/25/world/europe/france-greens-social-policy.html&quot;&gt;go hand in hand&lt;/a&gt;. Speaking in 2016, Carême (of the Green party, Europe Ecologie les Verts), &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.metropolitiques.eu/spip.php?page=print&amp;amp;id_article=1262&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; he hoped Dunkirk’s fare-free model could “make the urban area a figurehead for industrial territories undergoing environmental transition.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, it’s been a “winning bet”, says Huré. He adds that, despite the different challenges they face, larger cities should not rule out going fare-free. In the interim, Dunkirk’s example is winning over skeptics. Even for supporters like Delevoye, the policy has revealed unexpected benefits. One year in, free transit is increasingly looking like an idea whose time has come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 22:50:45 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>UglyToad</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://s.france24.com/media/display/a9d8335a-cc10-11e9-a893-005056bff430/w:1024/p:16x9/dunkirk-bus-gratuit-m.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>French city of Dunkirk tests out free transport – and it works</og:title>
<og:description>The city of Dunkirk in northern France launched a revamped bus system last year with a twist – it’s completely free. A new study shows that the programme is not only revitalising the city center but …</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.france24.com/en/20190831-france-dunkirk-free-transportation-bus-success-climate-cities</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.france24.com/en/20190831-france-dunkirk-free-transportation-bus-success-climate-cities</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>