<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Close to 735k Fraudulently Obtained IP Addresses Uncovered and Revoked</title>
<link>http://www.circleid.com/posts/20190514_735k_fraudulently_obtained_ip_addresses_have_been_revoked/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.circleid.com/posts/20190514_735k_fraudulently_obtained_ip_addresses_have_been_revoked/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.circleid.com/images/uploads/11888.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.circleid.com/images/uploads/11888.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The American Registry for Internet Numbers, Ltd. (ARIN) has won a legal case&lt;/strong&gt; against an elaborate multi-year scheme to defraud the Internet community of approximately 735,000 IPv4 addresses, the organization has revealed. While the specifics of the findings are not released, John Curran, ARIN President and CEO said the fraud was detected as a result of an internal due diligence process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ARIN is a nonprofit member-based organization responsible for distributing Internet number resources in the US, Canada, and parts of the Caribbean. The emerging IPv4 address transfer market and increasing demand have resulted in more attempts to obtain IPv4 addresses fraudulently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— &lt;strong&gt;This is the first arbitration ever&lt;/strong&gt; brought under an ARIN Registration Services Agreement, and related proceedings in the U.S. District Court for the Eastern District of Virginia. ARIN was able to prove an intricate scheme to fraudulently obtained resources that included many falsely notarized officer attestations sent to ARIN. &quot;A company in South Carolina obtained and utilized 11 shelf companies across the United States, and intentionally created false aliases purporting to be officers of those companies, to induce ARIN into issuing the fraudulently sought IPv4 resources and approving related transfers and reassignments of these addresses. The defrauding party was monetizing the assets obtained in the transfer market, and obtained resources under ARIN's waiting list process.&quot; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://teamarin.net/2019/05/13/taking-a-hard-line-on-fraud/&quot;&gt;ARIN Press Release&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— &lt;strong&gt;The defrauding entity adopted an aggressive posture&lt;/strong&gt; after ARIN requested that it produce certain documents and explain its conduct. The suspected party filed a motion for a Temporary Restraining Order and Preliminary Injunction against ARIN in U.S. District Court, and demanded a hearing the following morning (the Friday just before Christmas). &quot;The aggressive posture was taken after ARIN indicated its intent to revoke addresses, while permitting defrauding entity to renumber to allow existing bona fide customers not to have service interrupted,&quot; ARIN’s General Counsel told CircleID. &quot;The litigation was filed against ARIN to seek an injunction to stop ARIN from revoking and enter arbitration. Some addresses were transferred for money prior to that demand, others were pending transfer and were never transferred due to ARIN investigation.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— &lt;strong&gt;Some fraudulently obtained addresses were transferred to third parties;&lt;/strong&gt; however ARIN made no effort to pursue the parties that received the completed transfer, ARIN’s General Counsel told CircleID. The reason being: &quot;(a) addressed were in another RIR service region (e.g. RIPE NCC and APNIC) and (b) ARIN did not see any evidence they knew of or participated in the fraud. In other words, they appeared to be bona fide 3rd parties.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— &lt;strong&gt;ARIN obtained the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.arin.net/vault/about_us/corp_docs/20190506_arbitration_award_and_order.pdf&quot;&gt;arbitration award&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; on May 1, 2019, which included revocation of all resources issued pursuant to fraud and $350,000 to ARIN for its legal fees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— &lt;strong&gt;UPDATE May 15, 2019:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&quot;Charleston Man and Business Indicted in Federal Court in Over $9M Fraud&quot;&lt;/strong&gt; – United States Department of Justice issues a statement annoucing Amir Golestan, 36, of Charleston, and Micfo, LLC, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.circleid.com/pdf/golstan_indict_filed_20190515.pdf&quot;&gt;were charged in federal court&lt;/a&gt; in a twenty-count indictment. The indictment charges twenty counts of wire fraud, with each count punishable by up to 20 years imprisonment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;21.912698412698&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&quot;The indictment alleges that since February 2014, Golestan and Micfo created and utilized 'Channel Partners,' which purported to consist of several individual businesses, all of whom acquired the right to IP addresses from the American Registry of Internet Numbers (ARIN). The indictment alleges that Golestan and Micfo fabricated the true nature of the Channel Partners, including creating false officers and deceptive websites for the businesses, which were in turn used to deceive ARIN and to fraudulently obtain IP address rights from ARIN. The indictment charges that, through this scheme, Golestan and Micfo obtained the rights to approximately 757,760 IP addresses, with a market value between $9,850,880.00 and $14,397,440.00.&quot;&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.justice.gov/usao-sc/pr/charleston-man-and-business-indicted-federal-court-over-9m-fraud&quot;&gt;DOJ&lt;/a&gt; / May 15, 2019)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 19:54:21 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pencilingin</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Close to 735K Fraudulently Obtained IP Addresses Have Been Uncovered and Revoked, ARIN Reveals</og:title>
<og:image>http://www.circleid.com/images/member_photos/</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.circleid.com/posts/20190514_735k_fraudulently_obtained_ip_addresses_have_been_revoked/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>My Budget – free, open-source offline cross-platform budgeting</title>
<link>https://github.com/reZach/my-budget</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/reZach/my-budget</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;Box-body&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content p-5&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take control of your budget, download it today. It is free - forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/reZach/my-budget/blob/master/images/readme.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/reZach/my-budget/raw/master/images/readme.png&quot; alt=&quot;MyBudget&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Completely offline - we are not saving any information of yours, it remains on your computer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple - only contains what you need to budget.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Passphrase protected - protect your data by providing a passphrase to encrypt your data (this is optional).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Limited* support to sync transactions with your bank. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/reZach/my-budget/wiki/Creating-a-new-connector&quot;&gt;See here&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Built with &lt;a href=&quot;https://electronjs.org/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Electron&lt;/a&gt; - supported on Linux, MacOS and Windows.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can download the application &lt;a href=&quot;https://rezach.github.io/my-budget/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. The application is still in beta, so please be aware there may be breaking changes until we have stabilized for the first major release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join us on &lt;a href=&quot;https://join.slack.com/t/my-budget/shared_invite/enQtNjA0NDg1MTI2MzI2LTkxZmI0M2YzMGQ2YzlkMDc1YzkxMjU1M2EyZmI4MjlkYTY3MzgwNzVhMmY2MzJhNmM4OGE0Njc0NDZiMDVkY2U&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;slack&lt;/a&gt; if you have concerns or questions. For bugs, please go to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/reZach/my-budget/issues&quot;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt; and submit an issue, thanks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New users should check out our &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/reZach/my-budget/wiki/New-user's-guide&quot;&gt;new user's guide&lt;/a&gt;! Have a question how to use My Budget? All of it is available on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/reZach/my-budget/wiki&quot;&gt;wiki&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 18:46:51 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>vitro</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://repository-images.githubusercontent.com/173851397/59ff8d00-6816-11e9-8819-368b1d861e3a</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>reZach/my-budget</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/reZach/my-budget</og:url>
<og:description>Free, open source offline cross-platform budgeting solution built with Electron. - reZach/my-budget</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/reZach/my-budget</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Falsehoods programmers believe about Unix time</title>
<link>https://alexwlchan.net/2019/05/falsehoods-programmers-believe-about-unix-time/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://alexwlchan.net/2019/05/falsehoods-programmers-believe-about-unix-time/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;With apologies to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kalzumeus.com/2010/06/17/falsehoods-programmers-believe-about-names/&quot;&gt;Patrick McKenzie&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dannybirchall&quot;&gt;Danny&lt;/a&gt; was asking us about our favourite facts about &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unix_time&quot;&gt;Unix time&lt;/a&gt; in the Wellcome Slack yesterday, and I was reminded of the way that it behaves in some completely counter-intuitive ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These three facts all seem eminently sensible and reasonable, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Unix time is the number of seconds since 1 January 1970 00:00:00 UTC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If I wait exactly one second, Unix time advances by exactly one second&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unix time can never go backwards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;False, false, false.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it’s unsatisfying to say “this is false” without explaining &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt;, so I’ll explain that below. If you’d like to think about it first and make your own guess, don’t scroll past the picture of the clock!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://alexwlchan.net/images/2019/L0072180.jpg&quot;/&gt; A bracket clock. Construction and assembly by John Leroux. Credit: &lt;a href=&quot;https://wellcomecollection.org/works/t8v9t648&quot;&gt;Wellcome Collection&lt;/a&gt;. Used under &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&quot;&gt;CC BY&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;All three of these falsehoods have the same underlying cause: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leap_second&quot;&gt;leap seconds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. If you’re unfamiliar with leap seconds, here’s a brief primer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two factors that make up UTC:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;1.7771428571429&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;2.6861924686192&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/International_Atomic_Time&quot;&gt;International Atomic Time&lt;/a&gt;, which is an average of hundreds of atomic clocks spread around the globe. We can measure a second from the electromagnetic properties of an atom, and it’s the most accurate measurement of time known to science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;0.87272727272727&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Universal_Time&quot;&gt;Universal Time&lt;/a&gt;, which is based on the Earth’s rotation about its own axis. One complete rotation is one day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Problem is, these two numbers don’t always match. The Earth’s rotation isn’t consistent – it’s gradually slowing down, so days in Universal Time are getting longer. Atomic clocks, on the other hand, are fiendishly accurate, and consistent for millions of years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the two times drift apart, a leap second is added or removed to UTC to bring them back together. Since 1972, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/International_Earth_Rotation_and_Reference_Systems_Service&quot;&gt;the IERS&lt;/a&gt; (who manage this stuff) have inserted an extra 27 leap seconds. The result is a UTC day with 86,401 seconds (one extra), or 86,399 (one missing) – both of which mess with a fundamental assumption of Unix time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unix time assumes that each day is exactly 86,400 seconds long (60 × 60 × 24 = 86,400), leap seconds be damned. If there’s a leap second in a day, Unix time either repeats or omits a second as appropriate to make them match. As of 2019, the extra 27 leap seconds are missing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so our falsehoods go as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;19&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unix time is the number of seconds since 1 January 1970 00:00:00 UTC, &lt;em&gt;minus leap seconds&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;21&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I wait exactly one second, Unix time advances by exactly one second, &lt;em&gt;unless a leap second has been removed&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, there’s never been a leap second removed in practice (and the Earth’s slowing rotation means it’s unlikely), but if it ever happened, it would mean the UTC day is one second shorter. The last UTC second (23:59:59) is dropped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each Unix day has the same number of seconds, so when the next day starts, it skips ahead by one. The final Unix second of the shorter day never gets allocated to a UTC timestamp. Here’s what that would look like, in quarter-second increments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://alexwlchan.net/images/2019/unix_time_skips_forwards.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you start at 23:59:58:00 UTC and wait one second, the Unix time advances by &lt;em&gt;two&lt;/em&gt; seconds, and the Unix timestamp 101 never gets assigned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unix time can never go backwards, &lt;em&gt;unless a leap second has been added&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one has happened in practice – 27 times at time of writing. The UTC day gets an extra second added to the end, 23:59:60. Each Unix day has the same number of seconds, so it can’t just add an extra second – instead, it repeats the Unix timestamps for the last second of the day. Here’s what that would look like, in quarter-second increments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://alexwlchan.net/images/2019/unix_time_goes_backwards.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you start at 23:59:60.50 and wait half a second, the Unix time goes &lt;em&gt;back&lt;/em&gt; by half a second, and the Unix timestamp 101 matches two UTC seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;And these probably aren’t even the only weirdnesses of Unix time – they’re just the ones I half-remembered yesterday, enough to check a few details and write a blog post about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time is &lt;em&gt;straaaaaange&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 18:04:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pplonski86</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://alexwlchan.net/2019/05/falsehoods-programmers-believe-about-unix-time/</og:url>
<og:title>Falsehoods programmers believe about Unix time</og:title>
<og:image>https://alexwlchan.net/theme/apple-touch-icon.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://alexwlchan.net/2019/05/falsehoods-programmers-believe-about-unix-time/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>I Charged $18k for a Static HTML Page</title>
<link>https://idiallo.com/blog/18000-dollars-static-web-page</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://idiallo.com/blog/18000-dollars-static-web-page</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Not too long ago, I made a living working as a contractor where I would hop from project to project. Some were short term where I would work for a week and quickly deliver my service. Others lasted a couple months where I would make enough money to take some time off. I preferred the short ones because they allowed me to charge a much higher rate for a quick job. Not only I felt like my own boss, but I also felt like I didn't have to work too hard to make a decent living. My highest rates were still reasonable, and I always delivered high quality service. That was until I landed a gig with a large company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This company contacted me in urgency and the manager told me they needed someone right away. Someone who required &lt;strong&gt;minimum training for maximum performance&lt;/strong&gt;. For better or worse, that was my motto. This project was exactly the type of work I liked. It was short, fast, and it paid well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After negotiating a decent rate, I received an email with the instructions. They gave me more context for the urgency. Their developer left without prior warning and never updated anyone on the status of his project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need your full undivided attention to complete this project. For the duration of the contract, you will work exclusively with us to deliver result in a timely manner. We plan to compensate you for the trouble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The instructions were simple: Read the requirements then come up with an estimate of how long it would take to complete the project. This was one of the easier projects I have encountered in my career. It was an HTML page with some minor animations and a few embedded videos. I spent the evening studying the requirements and simulating the implementation in my head. Over the years, I've learned not to write any code for a client until I have a guarantee of pay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I determined that this project would be a day's worth of work. But to be cautious, I quoted 20 hours with a rough total of $1500. It was a single HTML page after all, and I can only charge them so much. They asked me to come on site to their satellite office 25 miles away. I would have to drive there for the 3 days I would be working for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day, I arrived at the satellite office. It was in a shopping center where a secret door led to a secret world where a few workers where churning quietly in their cubicles. The receptionist presented me with a brand new MacBook Pro that I had to set up from scratch. I do prefer using a company's laptop because they often require contractors to install suspicious software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent the day downloading my toolkit, setting up email, ssh keys, and requesting invites to services. In other words, I got nothing done. This is why I quoted 20 hours, I lost 8 hours of my estimated time doing busy work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day, I was ready to get down to business. Armed with the MacBook Pro, I sent an email to the manager. I told him that I was ready to work and that I was waiting for the aforementioned assets. That day, I stayed in my cubicle under a softly buzzing light, twiddling my fingers until the sun went down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did the math again. According to my estimate, I had 4 hours left to do the job, which was not so unrealistic for a single HTML page. But needless to say, the next day, I spent those remaining 4 hours in a company sponsored lunch where I ate very well and mingled with other employees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the time expired, I made sure to send the manager another email, to let him know that I had been present in the company only I had not received the assets I needed to do the job. That email, of course, was ignored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following Monday, I hesitantly drove the 25 miles. To my surprise, the manager had come down to the satellite office where he enthusiastically greeted me. He was a nice easy-going guy in his mid thirties. I was confused. He didn't have the urgency tone he had on the phone when he hired me. We had a friendly conversation where no work was mentioned. Later, we went down to lunch where he paid for my meal. It was a good day. No work was done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Call me a creature of habit, but if you feed me and pamper me everyday, I get used to it. It turned into a routine. I'd come to work, spend some time online reading and watching videos. I'd send one email a day, so they know I am around. Then I'd go get lunch and hangout with whomever had an interesting story to share. At the end of the day, I'd stand up, stretch, let out a well deserved yawn, then drive home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got used to it. In fact, I was expecting it. It was a little disappointing when I finally got an email with a link that pointed to the assets I needed for the job. I came back down to earth, and put on my working face. Only, after spending a few minutes looking through the zip file, I noticed that it was missing the bulk of what I needed. The designer had sent me some Adobe Illustrator files, and I couldn't open it on the MacBook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I replied to the email explaining my concerns and bundled a few other questions to save time. At that point, my quoted 20 hours time had long expired. I wanted to get this job over with already. Shortly after I clicked on send, I received an email. All it said was: &quot;Adding Alex to the thread,&quot; and Alex was CC'd to the email. Then Alex replied where he added Steve to the thread. Steve replied saying that Michelle was a designer and she would know more about this. Michelle auto responded saying that she was on vacation and that all inquiries should be directed to her manager. Her manager replied asking &quot;Who is Ibrahim?&quot; My manager replied excusing himself for not introducing me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a contractor, I am usually in and out of a company before people notice that I work there. Here, I received a flood of emails welcoming me aboard. The chain of emails continued for a while and I was forced to answer to those awfully nice messages. Some people were eager to meet me in person. They got a little disappointed when I said that I was all the way down in California. And jealous, they said they were jealous of the beautiful weather.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They used courtesy to ignore my emails. They used CC to deflect my questions. They used spam to dismiss anything I asked. I spent my days like an archaeologist digging through the deep trenches of emails, hoping to find answers to my questions. You can imagine the level of impostor syndrome I felt every time I remembered that my only task was to build a single static HTML page. The overestimated 20 hours project turned into a 7 weeks adventure where I enjoyed free lunches, drove 50 miles everyday, and dug through emails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I finally completed the project, I sent it to the team on github. All great adventures must come to an end. But shortly after, I received an invitation to have my code reviewed by the whole team on Google Hangout. I had spent more than a month building a single static HTML page and now the entire team would have to critique my work? In my defense, there was also some JavaScript interactions, and it was responsive, and it also had CSS animations... Impostor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, the video meeting was rescheduled a few times. When it finally happened, my work and I were not the subject of the meeting. They were all sitting in the same room somewhere in New York and talked for a while like a tight knit group. In fact, all they ever said about the project was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Person 1:&lt;/em&gt; Hey is anyone working on that sponsored page?&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Person 2:&lt;/em&gt; Yeah, I think it's done.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Person 1:&lt;/em&gt; Great, I'll merge it tonight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I went home that night, I realized that I was facing another challenge. I had been working at this company for 7 weeks, and my original quote was for $1,500. That's roughly the equivalent of $11,100 a year or $214 a week. Or even better, it was $5.35 an hour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This barely covered my transportation. So, I sent them an invoice where I quoted them for 7 weeks of work at the original hourly rate. The total amounted to $18,000. I was ashamed of course, but what else was I supposed to do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like I expected, I got no reply. If there is something that all large companies have in common, it's that they are not very eager to pay their bills on time. I felt like a cheat charging so much for such a simple job, but this was not a charity. I had been driving 50 miles everyday to do the job, if the job was not getting done it was not for my lack of trying. It was for their slow responses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got an answer the following week. It was a cold email from the manager where he broke down every day I worked into hourly blocks. Then he highlighted those I worked on and marked a one hour lunch break each day. At the end he made some calculations with our agreed upon hourly rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently, I was wrong. I had miscalculated the total. After adjustment, the total amount they owed me was $21,000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please confirm the readjusted hours so accounting can write you a check.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I quickly confirmed these hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;article__end&quot;/&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;prev-next&quot;&gt;

&lt;/aside&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 16:59:14 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>firefoxd</dc:creator>
<og:type>blog</og:type>
<og:title>I charged $18,000 for a Static HTML Page</og:title>
<og:image>https://cdn.idiallo.com/images/assets/375/thumb.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Not too long ago, I made a living working as a contractor where I would hop from project to project. Some were short term where I would work for a week and quickly deliver my service. Others lasted a</og:description>
<og:url>https://idiallo.com/blog/18000-dollars-static-web-page</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://idiallo.com/blog/18000-dollars-static-web-page</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>TaiChi: Open-source computer graphics library</title>
<link>http://taichi.graphics/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://taichi.graphics/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;fl-builder-content fl-builder-content-156 fl-builder-content-primary&quot; data-post-id=&quot;156&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fl-row fl-row-fixed-width fl-row-bg-none fl-node-58563bd870884&quot; data-node=&quot;58563bd870884&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fl-row-content-wrap&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fl-row-content fl-row-fixed-width fl-node-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fl-col-group fl-node-58563bd87e449&quot; data-node=&quot;58563bd87e449&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fl-col fl-node-58563bd87e824&quot; data-node=&quot;58563bd87e824&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fl-col-content fl-node-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fl-module fl-module-photo fl-node-58563bd8702d6&quot; data-node=&quot;58563bd8702d6&quot; data-animation-delay=&quot;0.0&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fl-module-content fl-node-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fl-photo fl-photo-align-center&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fl-photo-content fl-photo-img-png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;fl-photo-img wp-image-492 size-full&quot; src=&quot;http://taichi.graphics/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/0001000-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;0001000&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; srcset=&quot;http://taichi.graphics/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/0001000-1.png 960w, http://taichi.graphics/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/0001000-1-300x169.png 300w, http://taichi.graphics/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/0001000-1-768x432.png 768w, http://taichi.graphics/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/0001000-1-800x450.png 800w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fl-row fl-row-fixed-width fl-row-bg-none fl-node-58351865dd439&quot; data-node=&quot;58351865dd439&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fl-row-content-wrap&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fl-row-content fl-row-fixed-width fl-node-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fl-col-group fl-node-58351865e3fa5&quot; data-node=&quot;58351865e3fa5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fl-col fl-node-58351865e432f&quot; data-node=&quot;58351865e432f&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fl-col-content fl-node-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fl-module fl-module-video fl-node-584e5e53d9723&quot; data-node=&quot;584e5e53d9723&quot; data-animation-delay=&quot;0.0&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fl-module-content fl-node-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fl-video fl-embed-video&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/VideoObject&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/V5SWjg2hw9Y?loop=1&amp;amp;rel=0&amp;amp;autoplay=1&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fl-module fl-module-photo fl-node-5835180745738&quot; data-node=&quot;5835180745738&quot; data-animation-delay=&quot;0.0&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fl-module-content fl-node-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fl-photo fl-photo-align-center&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fl-photo-content fl-photo-img-jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;fl-photo-img wp-image-333 size-full&quot; src=&quot;http://taichi.graphics/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/volumetric.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;volumetric&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; srcset=&quot;http://taichi.graphics/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/volumetric.jpg 1674w, http://taichi.graphics/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/volumetric-300x184.jpg 300w, http://taichi.graphics/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/volumetric-768x471.jpg 768w, http://taichi.graphics/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/volumetric-1024x628.jpg 1024w, http://taichi.graphics/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/volumetric-800x490.jpg 800w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1674px) 100vw, 1674px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;expect&quot; class=&quot;fl-row fl-row-full-width fl-row-bg-none fl-node-57571353380c6&quot; data-node=&quot;57571353380c6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fl-row-content-wrap&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fl-row-content fl-row-fixed-width fl-node-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fl-col-group fl-node-5a578f42e1f09&quot; data-node=&quot;5a578f42e1f09&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fl-col fl-node-5a578f42e22a0 fl-col-small&quot; data-node=&quot;5a578f42e22a0&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fl-col-content fl-node-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fl-module fl-module-callout fl-node-5758c173f3e5a&quot; data-node=&quot;5758c173f3e5a&quot; data-animation-delay=&quot;0.0&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fl-module-content fl-node-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fl-callout fl-callout-left&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fl-callout-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;fl-callout-title&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/yuanming-hu/taichi&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;fl-callout-title-link&quot;&gt;Open-source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fl-callout-text-wrap&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fl-callout-text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taichi&lt;/strong&gt; is an open-source computer graphics library that aims to provide infrastructures for computer graphics R&amp;amp;D.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/yuanming-hu/taichi&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;fl-callout-cta-link&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fl-col fl-node-5a578f42e22e1 fl-col-small&quot; data-node=&quot;5a578f42e22e1&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fl-col-content fl-node-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fl-module fl-module-callout fl-node-5758c16fcc295&quot; data-node=&quot;5758c16fcc295&quot; data-animation-delay=&quot;0.0&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fl-module-content fl-node-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fl-callout fl-callout-left&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fl-callout-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;fl-callout-title&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/yuanming-hu/taichi/tree/master/projects/examples&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot; class=&quot;fl-callout-title-link&quot;&gt;Easy-to-use&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fl-callout-text-wrap&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fl-callout-text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taichi provides both a C++14 kernel for high-performance computation and Python 3 bindings for flexible scripting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/yuanming-hu/taichi/tree/master/projects/examples&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot; class=&quot;fl-callout-cta-link&quot;&gt;Examples&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fl-row fl-row-fixed-width fl-row-bg-none fl-node-584e8f6b172a4&quot; data-node=&quot;584e8f6b172a4&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fl-row-content-wrap&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fl-row-content fl-row-fixed-width fl-node-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fl-col-group fl-node-584e8f6b2347d&quot; data-node=&quot;584e8f6b2347d&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fl-col fl-node-584e8f6b23808&quot; data-node=&quot;584e8f6b23808&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fl-col-content fl-node-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fl-module fl-module-photo fl-node-584e8f6b16d5f&quot; data-node=&quot;584e8f6b16d5f&quot; data-animation-delay=&quot;0.0&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fl-module-content fl-node-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fl-photo fl-photo-align-center&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fl-photo-content fl-photo-img-png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;fl-photo-img wp-image-469 size-full&quot; src=&quot;http://taichi.graphics/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/0001320.png&quot; alt=&quot;0001320&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; srcset=&quot;http://taichi.graphics/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/0001320.png 960w, http://taichi.graphics/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/0001320-300x169.png 300w, http://taichi.graphics/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/0001320-768x432.png 768w, http://taichi.graphics/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/0001320-800x450.png 800w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 15:46:51 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>adamnemecek</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://taichi.graphics/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>FCC Chairman Proposes Robocall Blocking by Default</title>
<link>https://www.fcc.gov/document/chairman-pai-proposes-robocall-blocking-default</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.fcc.gov/document/chairman-pai-proposes-robocall-blocking-default</guid>
<description>&lt;ul class=&quot;edocs&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Title:&lt;/strong&gt; FCC Chairman Proposes Call Blocking By Default To Help Combat The Scourge Of Robocalls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Document Type(s):&lt;/strong&gt; News Release&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bureau(s):&lt;/strong&gt; Media Relations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;FCC Chairman Ajit Pai is proposing bold action to help consumers block unwanted robocalls. He expects providers to offer consumers robust, free call blocking tools based on analytics &amp;amp; consumer contact lists.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 15:45:26 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>daegloe</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.fcc.gov/document/chairman-pai-proposes-robocall-blocking-default</og:url>
<og:title>Chairman Pai Proposes Robocall Blocking by Default</og:title>
<og:description>FCC Chairman Ajit Pai is proposing bold action to help consumers block unwanted robocalls. He expects providers to offer consumers robust, free call blocking tools based on analytics &amp; consumer contact lists.</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.fcc.gov/sites/default/files/social-media-sharing-fcc-logo.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.fcc.gov/document/chairman-pai-proposes-robocall-blocking-default</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>WhatsApp security breach may have targeted human rights groups</title>
<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-facebook-cyber-whatsapp/whatsapp-security-breach-may-have-targeted-human-rights-groups-idUSKCN1SK0SM</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.reuters.com/article/us-facebook-cyber-whatsapp/whatsapp-security-breach-may-have-targeted-human-rights-groups-idUSKCN1SK0SM</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;WASHINGTON (Reuters) - WhatsApp said on Tuesday that a security breach on its messaging app had signs of coming from a government using surveillance technology developed by a private company, and it may have targeted human rights groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WhatsApp, a unit of Facebook, said it had notified the U.S. Department of Justice to help with an investigation, and it encouraged all WhatsApp users to update to the latest version of the app, where the breach had been fixed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WhatsApp, one of the world’s most popular messaging tools, is used by 1.5 billion people monthly. It has touted its high level of security and privacy, with messages on its platform being encrypted end-to-end so that WhatsApp and third parties cannot read or listen to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company said it was still investigating the breach but believed only a “select number of users were targeted through this vulnerability by an advanced cyber actor.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WhatsApp said its advice to all users to update came “out of an abundance of caution” and a recommendation by Citizen Lab, a research group at the University of Toronto that it notified about the vulnerability before the announcement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It did not disclose how many users were affected. A technical advisory published on Facebook’s security website said the vulnerability affected both Android and iPhones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A WhatsApp spokesman said the attack was sophisticated and had all the hallmarks of a “private company working with governments on surveillance.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The FBI and Justice Department declined to comment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;HUMAN RIGHTS LAWYER A TARGET&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Financial Times initially reported on the WhatsApp vulnerability that allowed attackers to inject spyware on phones via the app’s voice-calling function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WhatsApp told human rights groups it believed the spyware was developed by Israeli cyber surveillance company NSO Group, best known for its mobile hacking tools, said Eva Galperin, the director of cybersecurity at the Electronic Frontier Foundation, a San Francisco-based nonprofit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“They said they believed it was NSO Group, but they also couched it in very careful terms with many caveats, because attribution is hard,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like Citizen Lab, EFF was among the groups WhatsApp notified several days ago about the vulnerability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A second person familiar with the matter also identified NSO Group as the suspected culprit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NSO did not comment on the specific attacks. In a statement sent to Reuters, NSO said it would investigate any “credible allegations of misuse” of its technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company said it never picks or identifies targets of its technology, “which is solely operated by intelligence and law enforcement agencies. NSO would not or could not use its technology in its own right to target any person or organization, including this individual.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Image_container&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;LazyImage_container LazyImage_dark&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;amp;d=20190515&amp;amp;t=2&amp;amp;i=1387249523&amp;amp;r=LYNXNPEF4D0G7&amp;amp;w=20&quot; aria-label=&quot;FILE PHOTO: A logo of WhatsApp is pictured on a T-shirt worn by a WhatsApp-Reliance Jio representative during a drive by the two companies to educate users, on the outskirts of Kolkata, India, October 9, 2018. REUTERS/Rupak De Chowdhuri -&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;Image_caption&quot;&gt;

&lt;span&gt;FILE PHOTO: A logo of WhatsApp is pictured on a T-shirt worn by a WhatsApp-Reliance Jio representative during a drive by the two companies to educate users, on the outskirts of Kolkata, India, October 9, 2018. REUTERS/Rupak De Chowdhuri -&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One target of the new WhatsApp exploit was a United Kingdom-based human rights lawyer who spoke on condition of anonymity. He said an attack against him took place on Sunday after WhatsApp issued its update and was not successful. The lawyer had contacted Citizen Lab after receiving previous suspicious WhatsApp calls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lawyer is helping a Saudi dissident and several Mexican journalists mount civil cases against NSO Group for its alleged role in selling hacking tools to the Saudi and Mexican governments, which they allege were used to hack into their phones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are currently four known legal cases against NSO Group, including three in Israel and one based in Cyprus. NSO is being sued for damages allegedly caused by the sale of its tools, which the company says it sells only to law enforcement and intelligence agencies pursuing legitimate targets, such as terrorists and criminals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;HUMAN RIGHTS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WhatsApp said it was “deeply concerned about the abuse” of such surveillance technologies and that it believed human rights activists may have been the targets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We’re working with human rights groups on learning as much as we can about who may have been impacted from their community. That’s really where our highest concern is,” the spokesman said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Citizen Lab tweeted on Monday: “We believe an attacker tried (and was blocked by WhatsApp) to exploit it as recently as yesterday to target a human rights lawyer.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Citizen Lab told Reuters that the person was the UK lawyer, who had approached Citizen Lab after receiving multiple WhatsApp calls from unknown numbers at strange hours, making him suspicious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ireland’s Data Protection Commission (DPC), WhatsApp’s lead regulator in the European Union, said WhatsApp had notified the agency late on Monday of a “serious security vulnerability” on its platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Slideshow_container Slideshow_small Slideshow_standard&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Slideshow_preview-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;LazyImage_container LazyImage_dark&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s1.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;amp;d=20190515&amp;amp;t=2&amp;amp;i=1387249522&amp;amp;r=LYNXNPEF4D0GA&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

Slideshow &lt;span class=&quot;Slideshow_count&quot;&gt;(3 Images)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The DPC understands that the vulnerability may have enabled a malicious actor to install unauthorized software and gain access to personal data on devices which have WhatsApp installed,” the regulator said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cyber security experts said the vast majority of WhatsApp users were unlikely to have been affected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Attribution_container&quot; readability=&quot;7.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Attribution_attribution&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Attribution_content&quot;&gt;Additional reporting by Steven Scheer and Ari Rabinovitch, Tamara Mathias and Padraic Halpin; Editing by Keith Weir, Jane Merriman and Leslie Adler&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;StandardArticleBody_trustBadgeContainer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;StandardArticleBody_trustBadgeTitle&quot;&gt;Our Standards:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;trustBadgeUrl&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thomsonreuters.com/en/about-us/trust-principles.html&quot;&gt;The Thomson Reuters Trust Principles.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 15:10:27 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>okket</dc:creator>
<og:title>WhatsApp security breach may have targeted human rights groups</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-facebook-cyber-whatsapp-idUSKCN1SK0SM</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>WhatsApp said on Tuesday that a security breach on its messaging app had signs o...</og:description>
<og:image>https://s3.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;d=20190515&amp;t=2&amp;i=1387249523&amp;w=1200&amp;r=LYNXNPEF4D0G7</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-facebook-cyber-whatsapp/whatsapp-security-breach-may-have-targeted-human-rights-groups-idUSKCN1SK0SM</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Four Years of Rust</title>
<link>https://blog.rust-lang.org/2019/05/15/4-Years-Of-Rust.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.rust-lang.org/2019/05/15/4-Years-Of-Rust.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;On May 15th, 2015, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.rust-lang.org/2015/05/15/Rust-1.0.html&quot;&gt;Rust&lt;/a&gt; was released to the world! After 5 years of open development (and a couple of years of sketching before that), we finally hit the button on making the attempt to create a new systems programming language a serious effort!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to look back on the pre-1.0 times and cherish them for being the wild times of language development and fun research. Features were added and cut, syntax and keywords were tried, and before 1.0, there was a big clean-up that removed a lot of the standard library. For fun, you can check Niko’s blog post on &lt;a href=&quot;https://smallcultfollowing.com/babysteps/blog/2012/04/09/rusts-object-system/&quot;&gt;how Rust's object system works&lt;/a&gt;, Marijn Haverbeke’s talk on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=olbTX95hdbg&quot;&gt;features that never made it close to 1.0&lt;/a&gt; or even the &lt;a href=&quot;http://venge.net/graydon/talks/intro-talk-2.pdf&quot;&gt;introductory slides about Servo&lt;/a&gt;, which present a language looking very different from today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Releasing Rust with stability guarantees also meant putting a stop to large visible changes. The face of Rust is still very similar to Rust 1.0. Even with the changes from last year’s 2018 Edition, Rust is still very recognizable as what it was in 2015. That steadiness hides that the time of Rust’s fastest development and growth is &lt;em&gt;now&lt;/em&gt;. With the stability of the language and easy upgrades as a base, a ton of new features have been built. We’ve seen a bunch of achievements in the last year:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This list could go on and on. While the time before and after release was a time where language changes had huge impact how Rust is perceived, it's becoming more and more important what people start building in and around it. This includes projects like whole game engines, but also many small, helpful libraries, meetup formats, tutorials other educational material. Birthdays are a great time to take a look back over the last year and see the happy parts!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rust would be nothing, and especially not winning prizes, without its community. Community happens everywhere! We would like to thank everyone for being along on this ride, from team members to small scale contributors to people just checking the language out and finding interest in it. Your interest and curiosity is what makes the Rust community an enjoyable place to be. Some meetups &lt;a href=&quot;https://calendar.google.com/calendar/embed?showTitle=0&amp;amp;showPrint=0&amp;amp;showTabs=0&amp;amp;showCalendars=0&amp;amp;mode=AGENDA&amp;amp;height=400&amp;amp;wkst=1&amp;amp;bgcolor=%23FFFFFF&amp;amp;src=apd9vmbc22egenmtu5l6c5jbfc%40group.calendar.google.com&amp;amp;color=%23691426&amp;amp;ctz=Europe%2FMadrid&quot;&gt;are running birthday parties&lt;/a&gt; today to which everyone is invited. If you are not attending one, you can take the chance to celebrate in any other fashion: maybe show us a picture of what you are currently working on or talk about what excites you. If you want to take it to social media, consider tagging our &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/rustlang&quot;&gt;Twitter account&lt;/a&gt; or using the hashtag #rustbirthday.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 14:14:44 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>steveklabnik</dc:creator>
<og:title>4 years of Rust | Rust Blog</og:title>
<og:description>Empowering everyone to build reliable and efficient software.</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.rust-lang.org/static/images/rust-social-wide.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.rust-lang.org/2019/05/15/4-Years-Of-Rust.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>LED light can damage eyes, French health authority warns</title>
<link>https://news.yahoo.com/led-light-damage-eyes-health-authority-warns-002221659.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.yahoo.com/led-light-damage-eyes-health-authority-warns-002221659.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;canvas-body Wow(bw) Cl(start) Mb(20px) Lh(30px) Fz(18px) Ff(s) C(#000) D(i)&quot; data-reactid=&quot;14&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;canvas-atom canvas-text Mb(1.0em) Mb(0)--sm Mt(0.8em)--sm&quot; type=&quot;text&quot; content=&quot;Maisons-Alfort (France) (AFP) - The &amp;quot;blue light&amp;quot; in LED lighting can damage the eye's retina and disturb natural sleep rhythms, France's government-run health watchdog said this week.&quot; data-reactid=&quot;15&quot;&gt;Maisons-Alfort (France) (AFP) - The &quot;blue light&quot; in LED lighting can damage the eye's retina and disturb natural sleep rhythms, France's government-run health watchdog said this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;canvas-atom canvas-text Mb(1.0em) Mb(0)--sm Mt(0.8em)--sm&quot; type=&quot;text&quot; content=&quot;New findings confirm earlier concerns that &amp;quot;exposure to an intense and powerful [LED] light is 'photo-toxic' and can lead to irreversible loss of retinal cells and diminished sharpness of vision,&amp;quot; the French Agency for Food, Environmental and Occupational Health &amp;amp;amp; Safety (ANSES) warned in a statement.&quot; data-reactid=&quot;16&quot;&gt;New findings confirm earlier concerns that &quot;exposure to an intense and powerful [LED] light is 'photo-toxic' and can lead to irreversible loss of retinal cells and diminished sharpness of vision,&quot; the French Agency for Food, Environmental and Occupational Health &amp;amp; Safety (ANSES) warned in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;canvas-atom canvas-text Mb(1.0em) Mb(0)--sm Mt(0.8em)--sm&quot; type=&quot;text&quot; content=&quot;The agency recommended in a 400-page report that the maximum limit for acute exposure be revised, even if such levels are rarely met in home or work environments.&quot; data-reactid=&quot;17&quot;&gt;The agency recommended in a 400-page report that the maximum limit for acute exposure be revised, even if such levels are rarely met in home or work environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;canvas-atom canvas-text Mb(1.0em) Mb(0)--sm Mt(0.8em)--sm&quot; type=&quot;text&quot; content=&quot;The report distinguished between acute exposure of high-intensity LED light, and &amp;quot;chronic exposure&amp;quot; to lower intensity sources.&quot; data-reactid=&quot;18&quot;&gt;The report distinguished between acute exposure of high-intensity LED light, and &quot;chronic exposure&quot; to lower intensity sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;canvas-atom canvas-text Mb(1.0em) Mb(0)--sm Mt(0.8em)--sm&quot; type=&quot;text&quot; content=&quot;While less dangerous, even chronic exposure can &amp;quot;accelerate the ageing of retinal tissue, contributing to a decline in visual acuity and certain degenerative diseases such as age-related macular degeneration,&amp;quot; the agency concluded.&quot; data-reactid=&quot;19&quot;&gt;While less dangerous, even chronic exposure can &quot;accelerate the ageing of retinal tissue, contributing to a decline in visual acuity and certain degenerative diseases such as age-related macular degeneration,&quot; the agency concluded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;canvas-atom canvas-text Mb(1.0em) Mb(0)--sm Mt(0.8em)--sm&quot; type=&quot;text&quot; content=&quot;Long-lasting, energy efficient and inexpensive, light-emitting diode (LED) technology has gobbled up half of the general lighting market in a decade, and will top 60 percent by the end of next year, according to industry projections.&quot; data-reactid=&quot;20&quot;&gt;Long-lasting, energy efficient and inexpensive, light-emitting diode (LED) technology has gobbled up half of the general lighting market in a decade, and will top 60 percent by the end of next year, according to industry projections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;canvas-atom canvas-text Mb(1.0em) Mb(0)--sm Mt(0.8em)--sm&quot; type=&quot;text&quot; content=&quot;LED uses only a fifth of the electricity needed for an incandescent bulb of comparable brightness.&quot; data-reactid=&quot;21&quot;&gt;LED uses only a fifth of the electricity needed for an incandescent bulb of comparable brightness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;canvas-atom canvas-text Mb(1.0em) Mb(0)--sm Mt(0.8em)--sm&quot; type=&quot;text&quot; content=&quot;The world's leading LED light-bulb makers are GE Lighting, Osram and Philips.&quot; data-reactid=&quot;22&quot;&gt;The world's leading LED light-bulb makers are GE Lighting, Osram and Philips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;canvas-atom canvas-text Mb(1.0em) Mb(0)--sm Mt(0.8em)--sm&quot; type=&quot;text&quot; content=&quot;The basic technology for producing a white light combines a short wavelength LED such as blue or ultraviolet with a yellow phosphor coating. The whiter or &amp;quot;colder&amp;quot; the light, the greater the proportion of blue in the spectrum.&quot; data-reactid=&quot;23&quot;&gt;The basic technology for producing a white light combines a short wavelength LED such as blue or ultraviolet with a yellow phosphor coating. The whiter or &quot;colder&quot; the light, the greater the proportion of blue in the spectrum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;canvas-atom canvas-text Mb(1.0em) Mb(0)--sm Mt(0.8em)--sm&quot; type=&quot;text&quot; content=&quot;- Circadian rhythm -&quot; data-reactid=&quot;24&quot;&gt;- Circadian rhythm -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;canvas-atom canvas-text Mb(1.0em) Mb(0)--sm Mt(0.8em)--sm&quot; type=&quot;text&quot; content=&quot;LEDs are used for home and street lighting, as well as in offices and industry.&quot; data-reactid=&quot;25&quot;&gt;LEDs are used for home and street lighting, as well as in offices and industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;canvas-atom canvas-text Mb(1.0em) Mb(0)--sm Mt(0.8em)--sm&quot; type=&quot;text&quot; content=&quot;That are also increasingly found in auto headlights, torches (flashlights) and some toys.&quot; data-reactid=&quot;26&quot;&gt;That are also increasingly found in auto headlights, torches (flashlights) and some toys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;canvas-atom canvas-text Mb(1.0em) Mb(0)--sm Mt(0.8em)--sm&quot; type=&quot;text&quot; content=&quot;LED cellphone, tablet and laptop screens do not pose a risk of eye damage because their luminosity is very low compared to other types of lighting, Francine Behar-Cohen, an ophthalmologist and head of the expert group that conducted the review, told journalists.&quot; data-reactid=&quot;27&quot;&gt;LED cellphone, tablet and laptop screens do not pose a risk of eye damage because their luminosity is very low compared to other types of lighting, Francine Behar-Cohen, an ophthalmologist and head of the expert group that conducted the review, told journalists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;canvas-atom canvas-text Mb(1.0em) Mb(0)--sm Mt(0.8em)--sm&quot; type=&quot;text&quot; content=&quot;But these back-lit devices -- especially when they are used at night or in a dark setting -- can &amp;quot;disturb biological rhythms, and thus sleep patterns,&amp;quot; the agency cautioned.&quot; data-reactid=&quot;28&quot;&gt;But these back-lit devices -- especially when they are used at night or in a dark setting -- can &quot;disturb biological rhythms, and thus sleep patterns,&quot; the agency cautioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;canvas-atom canvas-text Mb(1.0em) Mb(0)--sm Mt(0.8em)--sm&quot; type=&quot;text&quot; content=&quot;Because the crystalline lens in their eyes are not fully formed, children and adolescents are particularly susceptible to such disruptions, the ANSES reports noted.&quot; data-reactid=&quot;29&quot;&gt;Because the crystalline lens in their eyes are not fully formed, children and adolescents are particularly susceptible to such disruptions, the ANSES reports noted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;canvas-atom canvas-text Mb(1.0em) Mb(0)--sm Mt(0.8em)--sm&quot; type=&quot;text&quot; content=&quot;Interfering with the body's circadian rhythm is also known to aggravate metabolic disorders such a diabetes, as well as cardiovascular disease and some forms of cancer, noted Dina Attia, a researcher and project manager at ANSES.&quot; data-reactid=&quot;30&quot;&gt;Interfering with the body's circadian rhythm is also known to aggravate metabolic disorders such a diabetes, as well as cardiovascular disease and some forms of cancer, noted Dina Attia, a researcher and project manager at ANSES.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;canvas-atom canvas-text Mb(1.0em) Mb(0)--sm Mt(0.8em)--sm&quot; type=&quot;text&quot; content=&quot;In addition, a stroboscopic affect in some LED lights -- provoked by tiny fluctuations in electric current -- can induce &amp;quot;headaches, visual fatigue and a higher risk of accidents,&amp;quot; the report said.&quot; data-reactid=&quot;31&quot;&gt;In addition, a stroboscopic affect in some LED lights -- provoked by tiny fluctuations in electric current -- can induce &quot;headaches, visual fatigue and a higher risk of accidents,&quot; the report said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;canvas-atom canvas-text Mb(1.0em) Mb(0)--sm Mt(0.8em)--sm&quot; type=&quot;text&quot; content=&quot;For domestic lighting, ANSES recommended buying &amp;quot;warm white&amp;quot; LED lighting, limiting exposure to LED sources with a high concentration of blue light, and avoiding LED screens before bedtime.&quot; data-reactid=&quot;32&quot;&gt;For domestic lighting, ANSES recommended buying &quot;warm white&quot; LED lighting, limiting exposure to LED sources with a high concentration of blue light, and avoiding LED screens before bedtime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;canvas-atom canvas-text Mb(1.0em) Mb(0)--sm Mt(0.8em)--sm&quot; type=&quot;text&quot; content=&quot;ANSES also said that manufacturers should &amp;quot;limit the luminous intensity of vehicle headlights,&amp;quot; some of which are too bright.&quot; data-reactid=&quot;33&quot;&gt;ANSES also said that manufacturers should &quot;limit the luminous intensity of vehicle headlights,&quot; some of which are too bright.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;canvas-atom canvas-text Mb(1.0em) Mb(0)--sm Mt(0.8em)--sm&quot; type=&quot;text&quot; content=&quot;Finally, the agency cast doubt on the efficacy of some &amp;quot;anti-blue light&amp;quot; filters and sunglasses.&quot; data-reactid=&quot;34&quot;&gt;Finally, the agency cast doubt on the efficacy of some &quot;anti-blue light&quot; filters and sunglasses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 13:40:31 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Vaslo</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Maisons-Alfort (France) (AFP) - The &quot;blue light&quot; in LED lighting can damage the eye's retina and disturb natural sleep rhythms, France's government-run health watchdog said this week. New findings confirm earlier concerns that &quot;exposure to an intense and powerful [LED] light is</og:description>
<og:image>https://s.yimg.com/uu/api/res/1.2/Vxou0rB6CdAUaTcpcEervw--~B/aD02MzQ7dz0xMDI0O3NtPTE7YXBwaWQ9eXRhY2h5b24-/http://media.zenfs.com/en_us/News/afp.com/Part-GTY-503675554-1-1-2.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>LED light can damage eyes, health authority warns</og:title>
<og:url>https://news.yahoo.com/led-light-damage-eyes-health-authority-warns-002221659.html</og:url>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.yahoo.com/led-light-damage-eyes-health-authority-warns-002221659.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Senior Developers Are Getting Rejected for Jobs</title>
<link>https://glenmccallum.com/2019/05/14/senior-developers-rejected-jobs/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://glenmccallum.com/2019/05/14/senior-developers-rejected-jobs/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;About how 5 months ago I went through a screening for a job. It was a referral from a friend and it had been a while since I responded to a recruiter. I was surprised how the process has changed in the past 5 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the initial phone screen they sent me to a 3rd party site (HackerRank) to solve three programming puzzles in a one hour time box. It was my first attempt at this. The first two were easy but the last one was trickier. My solution didn’t pass all the unit tests. It passed something like 8/10 tests and there was no time left to debug it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point I was filtered out of the company’s selection process. It turned out to be a mixed blessing due to some &lt;a href=&quot;https://glenmccallum.com/2019/03/02/my-diabetes-diagnosis-story/&quot;&gt;health issues&lt;/a&gt; that came up (I could not have made the trips to HQ to get oriented). However, the whole experience planted a seed in my mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since then I’ve been familiarizing myself with this type of problem solving. I work through &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/glenmccallumcan/HackerRank-Solutions&quot;&gt;one every week&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;It’s happening all over the place&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a good friend looking for his next job, a PhD in Comp Sci with over 10 years experience. Almost every option he explores has some type of programming challenge gate either on a 3rd party site or in person. He bought a copy of Cracking the Coding Interview to get up to speed but it takes time to develop that skill. He’s been passed over by some great companies in the meantime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The issue came up in the Megamaker Group and one person shared this very personal response:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;wp-block-quote&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m approaching my mid 40s and left my last startup (founding CTO role) in December. I have failed at least 10 programming tests and developer interviews since then. I have been developing technology for nearly 20 years including electronics and firmware (I’m an electronic engineering technologist by training) and full-blown distributed web applications with IoT integration. I’ve created software that powers full product traceability in high volume specialized manufacturing facilities around the world. Yet, I can’t get a job as a developer because I always fail these programming test gates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tweet from Max Howell went viral a couple of years ago. It’s funny, sad, and true all at the same time&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://glenmccallum.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/mxcl-tweet-1024x648.png&quot; alt=&quot;Creater of homebrew rejected by google&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-444&quot; srcset=&quot;https://glenmccallum.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/mxcl-tweet-1024x648.png 1024w, https://glenmccallum.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/mxcl-tweet-300x190.png 300w, https://glenmccallum.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/mxcl-tweet-768x486.png 768w, https://glenmccallum.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/mxcl-tweet.png 1141w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mxcl/status/608682016205344768?lang=en&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/mxcl/status/608682016205344768?lang=en&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fact. There are a lot of senior developers out there that are in for a wake-up call when they try to find their next position at a different company.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator&quot;/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Developers Hate Them&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When this topic comes up some developers say …&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;wp-block-quote&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I’ll typically end an interview if this type of stuff shows up”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;or&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;wp-block-quote&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Being able to solve a puzzle like that means nothing, can you talk to clients? Can you actually build a functioning webapp? Can you Google stuff when needed? Can you learn what ever is thrown at you? Not can you find the most efficient way to order this weird data”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The counter argument is that poor software developers dislike being tested and they are the ones that the company is trying to weed out. However, it’s also possible that some strong, independent-minded, senior developers opt-out of the process because they have other options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I agree these challenges are not representative of day-to-day tasks for a professional software developer. The wording is not always the best and I’m not sure the information is always complete (or at least I don’t always infer the completeness of the information from the problem description). Often they are math word problems. Having a formal education is an advantage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hiring company is guaranteed to screen out candidates that would have made amazing team members. For example, when Daniel Buchmueller was turned down at Netflix…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://glenmccallum.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/rrubyist-tweet-1024x903.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tweet about Netflix passing over rockstar developer&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-446&quot; srcset=&quot;https://glenmccallum.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/rrubyist-tweet-1024x903.png 1024w, https://glenmccallum.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/rrubyist-tweet-300x265.png 300w, https://glenmccallum.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/rrubyist-tweet-768x677.png 768w, https://glenmccallum.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/rrubyist-tweet.png 1143w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/rrubyist/status/1124448304555798529&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/rrubyist/status/1124448304555798529&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Companies Love Them&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of programming challenges for hiring we need to realize the the world has changed. Remote work is becoming widely accepted in the software industry. International teams are increasingly common.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You now have a larger pool of great developers you can add to your team but, on the downside, this has &lt;em&gt;drastically increased&lt;/em&gt; the number of applications you have to sort through in order to find the right candidate. Could you imagine sifting through 500 applications for a single position?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://glenmccallum.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/jamie-tweet-1024x764.png&quot; alt=&quot;Companies Easily get 500 applications&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-449&quot; srcset=&quot;https://glenmccallum.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/jamie-tweet-1024x764.png 1024w, https://glenmccallum.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/jamie-tweet-300x224.png 300w, https://glenmccallum.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/jamie-tweet-768x573.png 768w, https://glenmccallum.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/jamie-tweet.png 1150w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ideasasylum/status/1126500299470807046&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/ideasasylum/status/1126500299470807046&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, I’ve heard of getting into an interview where the candidate was way under qualified (couldn’t write a hello world type program). That would be extremely frustrating. Personally, I’d be looking for the nearest exit while offering the candidate some encouragement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programming puzzles as a hiring gate solve both these problems. To a company it is worth skipping over a few great candidates in order to simplify the review and selection process. With a now unlimited pool of applicants they can afford to do that. The numbers suggest that there will always be more good developers in the pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this reason I believe that Programming challenge hiring gates are here to stay and will become even more common in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is true that everyone is hiring and senior developers have never been in more demand. But don’t think that you can walk into another job based on market demand and the number of years on your resume. Prepare for the programming test gates now while you have the luxury of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator&quot;/&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 12:56:26 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>voltrone</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Senior Developers are Getting Rejected for Jobs</og:title>
<og:description>There are a lot of senior developers out there that are in for a wake-up call when they try to find their next position at a different company.</og:description>
<og:url>https://glenmccallum.com/2019/05/14/senior-developers-rejected-jobs/</og:url>
<og:image>https://glenmccallum.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/bruno-cervera-973688-unsplash-1024x683.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://glenmccallum.com/2019/05/14/senior-developers-rejected-jobs/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>