<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Apple Says Apps Must Now Disclose Odds for Loot Boxes</title>
<link>https://kotaku.com/apple-says-itunes-apps-must-now-disclose-odds-for-loot-1821497923</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://kotaku.com/apple-says-itunes-apps-must-now-disclose-odds-for-loot-1821497923</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrapper lazy-image&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-permalink-sub-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;js_lightbox-wrapper lightbox-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.kinja-img.com/gawker-media/image/upload/s--fbrCY5ix--/c_scale,fl_progressive,q_80,w_800/nrx5hz31v79uumuvu7yi.png&quot; class=&quot;lazyload ls-lazy-image-tag&quot; data-sizes=&quot;auto&quot; data-width=&quot;951&quot; data-chomp-id=&quot;nrx5hz31v79uumuvu7yi&quot; data-format=&quot;png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
The Simpsons Tapped Out is one of many iOS games to include loot boxes.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple announced &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/news/?id=12202017a&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; onclick=&quot;window.ga('send', 'event', 'Embedded Url', 'External link', 'https://developer.apple.com/news/?id=12202017a', {metric25:1})&quot;&gt;a sweeping revision to the guidelines for its App Store yesterday&lt;/a&gt;, which now includes a provision that loot boxes must be transparent about their odds.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Apps offering ‘loot boxes’ or other mechanisms that provide randomized virtual items for purchase must disclose the odds of receiving each type of item to customers prior to purchase,” reads the new rule, which will affect the most popular games on iOS, including &lt;em&gt;Hearthstone&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The Simpsons Tapped Out&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Clash Royale&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Loot boxes, which have always been common in the world of iOS gaming, are virtual grab bags that can give players a host of items ranging from common to rare. Most of the time, you can buy these loot boxes not just for in-game currency but for real money, which has led some players to classify them as gambling—a label that &lt;a href=&quot;https://kotaku.com/esrb-says-it-doesnt-see-loot-boxes-as-gambling-1819363091&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; onclick=&quot;window.ga('send', 'event', 'Embedded Url', 'Internal link', 'https://kotaku.com/esrb-says-it-doesnt-see-loot-boxes-as-gambling-1819363091', {metric25:1})&quot;&gt;the Entertainment Software Rating Board doesn’t acknowledge&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This news comes after a year full of controversy over loot boxes, which many players see as manipulative, predatory methods to get them to spend more money on games. Although many mobile games have always had them, loot boxes received renewed attention this year thanks to their inclusion in console games like &lt;em&gt;Shadow of War&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Star Wars Battlefront II&lt;/em&gt;. Rage over the latter game dominated its launch to the point where its publisher, EA, announced the day before release that &lt;a href=&quot;https://kotaku.com/ea-temporarily-removes-microtransactions-from-star-wars-1820528445&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; onclick=&quot;window.ga('send', 'event', 'Embedded Url', 'Internal link', 'https://kotaku.com/ea-temporarily-removes-microtransactions-from-star-wars-1820528445', {metric25:1})&quot;&gt;it was temporarily removing all of &lt;em&gt;Battlefront II&lt;/em&gt;’s microtransactions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As rage over these practices gets louder and louder, Apple’s move is the first of what may be many steps that game publishers and distributors voluntarily take in an attempt to avoid regulation from outside bodies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 17:35:27 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kelukelugames</dc:creator>
<og:title>Apple Says Apps Must Now Disclose Odds For Loot Boxes</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://i.kinja-img.com/gawker-media/image/upload/s--i05n2NU---/c_fill,fl_progressive,g_center,h_450,q_80,w_800/nrx5hz31v79uumuvu7yi.png</og:image>
<og:url>https://kotaku.com/apple-says-itunes-apps-must-now-disclose-odds-for-loot-1821497923</og:url>
<og:description>Apple announced a sweeping revision to the guidelines for its App Store yesterday, which now includes a provision that loot boxes must be transparent about their odds.</og:description>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://kotaku.com/apple-says-itunes-apps-must-now-disclose-odds-for-loot-1821497923</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Chrome is Not the Standard</title>
<link>http://www.chriskrycho.com/2017/chrome-is-not-the-standard.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.chriskrycho.com/2017/chrome-is-not-the-standard.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past few years, I’ve increasingly seen articles with headlines that run something like, “New Feature Coming To the Web”—followed by content which described how Chrome had implemented an experimental new feature. “You’ll be able to use this soon!” has been the promise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reality is a bit more complicated. Sometimes, ideas the Chrome team pioneers make their way out to the rest of the browsers and become tools we can all use. Sometimes… they get shelved because none of the other browsers decide to implement them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many times, when this latter tack happens, developers grouse about the other browser makers who are “holding the web back.” But there is a fundamental problem in this way of looking at things: &lt;em&gt;Chrome isn’t the standard.&lt;/em&gt; The fact that Chrome proposes something, and even the fact that a bunch of developers like it, does not a standard make. Nor does it impose an obligation to other browsers to prioritize it, or even to ship it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As web developers, it can be easy to become focused on interesting new features for the platform we work on. That’s no different than the excitement Android and iOS developers have when Google and Apple release new SDKs for developing on their platforms. It’s healthy to be excited about possible new features, things that might make our jobs easier or enable us to do things we couldn’t do before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; an important difference between those platforms and the web. Those platforms are the domain of a single vendor. The web is a shared platform. This is its unique benefit, and its unique cost. It uniquely allows us to write software that can actually run, and run reasonably well, &lt;em&gt;everywhere&lt;/em&gt;. But it also means that a minimum of four companies—the major browser vendors—get a say in whether a feature is a &lt;em&gt;feature&lt;/em&gt; or whether it’s just an interesting idea one of the teams had.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s get concrete about an example that’s been extremely high-profile for the last couple years—and, to be clear, one I think is a &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt; idea from Google: &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/web/progressive-web-apps/&quot; title=&quot;Google’s PWA page&quot;&gt;progressive web apps&lt;/a&gt; (hereafter &lt;abbr title=&quot;Progressive Web App&quot;&gt;PWA&lt;/abbr&gt;). They have been pitched by Google and other supporters as an unambiguous win for the user experience of complex web applications. And, as a web developer myself, I’m actually inclined to agree with that assessment! However, I have fairly regularly seen people getting angry at especially Apple for not prioritizing support for &lt;abbr title=&quot;Progressive Web App&quot;&gt;PWA&lt;/abbr&gt;s in (especially iOS) Safari—Apple is, in this view, “holding back the future of the web.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well… no. For any given idea Google pitches, Apple may or may not be sold on Google’s vision of the web, or they may even think it’s a good idea but not &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; important than other things they’re working on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this is what it &lt;em&gt;means&lt;/em&gt; to be part of the web platform. No single company gets to dominate the others in terms of setting the agenda for the web. Not Firefox, with its development and advocacy of &lt;a href=&quot;http://webassembly.org/&quot;&gt;WebAssembly&lt;/a&gt;, dear to my heart though that is. Not Microsoft and the IE/Edge team, with its proposal of the CSS grid spec in &lt;em&gt;2011&lt;/em&gt;, sad though I am that it languished for as long as it did. Not Apple, with its pitch for &lt;a href=&quot;https://webkit.org/blog/7846/concurrent-javascript-it-can-work/&quot; title=&quot;“Concurrent JavaScript: it can work!”&quot;&gt;concurrent JavaScript&lt;/a&gt;. And not—however good its developer relations team is—Chrome, with any of the many ideas it’s constantly trying out, including &lt;abbr title=&quot;Progressive Web App&quot;&gt;PWA&lt;/abbr&gt;s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s also worth recognizing how these decisions aren’t, in almost any case, unalloyed pushes for “the future of the web.” They reflect &lt;em&gt;business&lt;/em&gt; priorities, just like any other technical prioritization. Google cares about &lt;abbr title=&quot;Progressive Web App&quot;&gt;PWA&lt;/abbr&gt;s because Google makes its money from the web and wants people to spend more of their time on the web. Apple cares about things like the battery life implications and the sheer speed of its iOS JavaScript engine because it makes money from hardware and it wants people to be happy with their iPhones and iPads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does any one of those browser’s commitments map cleanly to &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; users’ (or even all &lt;em&gt;developers’&lt;/em&gt;) priorities? Of course not! This is and always has been the beauty of a competitive browser landscape. I’m a web developer who wants &lt;abbr title=&quot;Progressive Web App&quot;&gt;PWA&lt;/abbr&gt; support everywhere—so I want Apple supporting it. But I’m also a smartphone user who wants those applications to &lt;em&gt;scream&lt;/em&gt; on my device—not to crawl, like they do on Chrome on Android, which is still years behind iOS in performance. As an end user, not just a developer, it matters to me that running Safari on my laptop instead of Chrome can dramatically increase my battery life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are tradeoffs, plain and simple. Chrome ships new features fast, but they’re not always stable and they often have performance costs. Safari ships new features on a much slower cadence, but they’re usually solid and always perform incredibly well. These are both engineering and business tradeoffs, and the companies behind the browsers are making because of their own business and engineering priorities. Don’t valorize any of the browser vendors, and don’t act as if &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; of them is the standard, or a reliable predictor of the future. Instead, value what each brings to the table, but also value the interplay &lt;em&gt;at&lt;/em&gt; the table, and the ways each of these vendors pushes the others and challenges the others’ assumptions of what is most important. That’s what makes the web so great, even when it makes things move more slowly. Sometimes—often, even!—moving more slowly not in the &lt;em&gt;experimental&lt;/em&gt; phase but in the &lt;em&gt;finalizing&lt;/em&gt; phase makes for a much better outcome overall.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 17:14:37 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>chriskrycho</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://www.chriskrycho.com/2017/chrome-is-not-the-standard.html</og:url>
<og:title>Chrome is Not the Standard</og:title>
<og:description>No single browser vendor represents ”the future of the web.” Each ships in line with its own business priorities. And that's a good thing.</og:description>
<og:image>http://www.chriskrycho.com//assets/images/ck.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.chriskrycho.com/2017/chrome-is-not-the-standard.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Rust in 2017: what we achieved</title>
<link>https://blog.rust-lang.org/2017/12/21/rust-in-2017.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.rust-lang.org/2017/12/21/rust-in-2017.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Rust’s development in 2017 fit into a single overarching theme: &lt;strong&gt;increasing productivity, especially for newcomers to Rust&lt;/strong&gt;. From tooling to libraries to documentation to the core language, we wanted to make it easier to get things done with Rust. That desire led to &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.rust-lang.org/2017/02/06/roadmap.html&quot;&gt;a roadmap&lt;/a&gt; for the year, setting out 8 high-level objectives that would guide the work of the team.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;How’d we do? &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Really, really well&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s not room in a single post to cover everything that happened, but we’ll cover some of the highlights below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;rust-should-have-a-lower-learning-curve&quot;&gt;Rust should have a lower learning curve&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Books&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RustBridge curriculum&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://rustbridge.github.io/&quot;&gt;RustBridge workshops&lt;/a&gt; are focused on getting underrepresented people into Rust. Ashley Williams has vastly improved &lt;a href=&quot;https://rustbridge.github.io/a-very-brief-intro-to-rust/#1&quot;&gt;the workshop curriculum&lt;/a&gt; this year, and we’re planning on having a teacher training in early 2018. The curriculum is available for anyone to use, as long as events are only called RustBridge if they focus on underrepresented folks. See more about RustBridge in 2017 under the Mentorship goal!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Language improvements&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;rust-should-have-a-pleasant-edit-compile-debug-cycle&quot;&gt;Rust should have a pleasant edit-compile-debug cycle&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;cargo check&lt;/code&gt; workflow&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Cargo &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.rust-lang.org/2017/03/16/Rust-1.16.html&quot;&gt;now offers&lt;/a&gt; a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;check&lt;/code&gt; subcommand which can be used to speed up the edit-compile cycle when you’re working on getting your code to pass the compiler’s checks. This mode, in particular, skips producing executable artifacts for crates in the dependency tree, instead doing just enough work to be able to type check the current crate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incremental recompilation&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The cornerstone of our approach to improving compilation times is incremental recompilation, allowing rebuilds to reuse significant pieces of work from prior compilations. Over the course of the year we have put a lot of work into making this happen and now we are happy to announce that incremental compilation will &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.rust-lang.org/2014/10/30/Stability.html&quot;&gt;start riding the trains&lt;/a&gt; with the next beta version of the compiler in January and become available on the stable channel with Rust 1.24 in February!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can see how incremental recompilation performs in practice on some of our key benchmarks below. Note that &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;-opt&lt;/code&gt; refers to optimized builds, “best case” refers to a recompilation with no changes, and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;println&lt;/code&gt; refers to a recompilation with a small change, like adding a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;println&lt;/code&gt; call to a function body. We expect the 50+% speedups we’re seeing now to continue to grow next year as we push incremental recompilation more deeply through the compiler.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Together with the changes in the compiler we will also update Cargo to use incremental recompilation by default for select use cases, so you can take advantage of improved compile times without the need for additional configuration. Of course you will also be able to opt into and out of the feature on a case by case basis as you see fit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.rust-lang.org/images/2017-12-Retro/incr-bench.png&quot; alt=&quot;Incremental recompilation benchmarks&quot; class=&quot;center&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;rust-should-provide-a-solid-but-basic-ide-experience&quot;&gt;Rust should provide a solid, but basic IDE experience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Rust now has solid IDE support in IntelliJ and via the Rust Language Server (RLS). Whether you prefer a fully-featured IDE or a more lightweight editor with IDE features, you can boost your productivity by taking advantage of great Rust integration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IntelliJ&lt;/strong&gt;. Rust has official support in &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2017/08/04/official-support-for-open-source-rust-plugin-for-intellij-idea-clion-and-other-jetbrains-ides/&quot;&gt;JetBrains’ IDEs&lt;/a&gt; (IntelliJ IDEA, CLion, WebStorm, etc.), which includes:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Finding types, functions and traits across the whole project, its dependencies and the standard library.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hierarchical overview of the symbols defined in the current file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Search for all implementations of a given trait.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to definition of symbol at cursor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Navigation to the parent module.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refactoring and code generation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RLS&lt;/strong&gt;. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang-nursery/rls&quot;&gt;RLS&lt;/a&gt; is an editor-independent source of intelligence about Rust programs. It is used to power Rust support in many editors including &lt;a href=&quot;https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=rust-lang.rust&quot;&gt;Visual Studio Code&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=DanielGriffen.Rust&quot;&gt;Visual Studio&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://atom.io/packages/ide-rust&quot;&gt;Atom&lt;/a&gt;, with more in the pipeline. It is on schedule for a 1.0 release in early 2018, but is currently &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.rust-lang.org/2017/10/12/Rust-1.21.html&quot;&gt;available in preview form&lt;/a&gt; for all channels (nightly, beta, and stable). It supports:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Code completion (using Racer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to definition (and peek definition if the editor supports it)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find all references&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find impls for a type or trait&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Symbol search (current file and project)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reformatting using rustfmt, renaming&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apply error suggestions (e.g., to add missing imports)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docs and types on hover&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Code generation using snippets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo tasks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Installation and update of the RLS (via rustup)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;rust-should-integrate-easily-into-large-build-systems&quot;&gt;Rust should integrate easily into large build systems&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alternative registries.&lt;/strong&gt; Cargo now has unstable support for &lt;a href=&quot;http://rust-lang.github.io/rfcs/2141-alternative-registries.html&quot;&gt;installing crates from registries other than crates.io&lt;/a&gt;. This will enable companies to manage and use internal crates as easily as open source crates. Work is underway developing crate servers that are more tailored for private use than the crates.io server is.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cargo as a component&lt;/strong&gt;. A lot of work this year went into gathering constraints from stakeholders who want to integrate Rust crates into a large existing build system (like &lt;a href=&quot;https://bazel.build/&quot;&gt;Bazel&lt;/a&gt;). The Cargo team has &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rfcs/pull/2136&quot;&gt;formulated a vision&lt;/a&gt; of Cargo as a suite of components that can be customized or swapped out, making it easy for an external build system to manage the work it is built to do, while still integrating with crates.io and with Cargo workflows. While we did not get as far as we hoped in terms of implementing this vision, there is ongoing work spiking out “build plan generation” to a sufficient degree that it can support the Firefox build system and &lt;a href=&quot;http://gittup.org/tup/&quot;&gt;Tup&lt;/a&gt;. This initial spike should provide a good strawman for further iteration in early 2018.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;rust-should-provide-easy-access-to-high-quality-crates&quot;&gt;Rust should provide easy access to high quality crates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;rust-should-be-well-equipped-for-writing-robust-servers&quot;&gt;Rust should be well-equipped for writing robust servers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Futures and Tokio&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Much of the story for Rust on the server has revolved around its async I/O story. The futures crate &lt;a href=&quot;http://aturon.github.io/blog/2016/08/11/futures/&quot;&gt;was introduced&lt;/a&gt; in late 2016, and the Tokio project (which provides a networking-focused event loop for use with futures) &lt;a href=&quot;https://tokio.rs/blog/tokio-0-1/&quot;&gt;published its 0.1&lt;/a&gt; early in 2017. Since then, there’s been significant work building out the “Tokio ecosystem”, and a lot of feedback about the core primitives. Late in the year, the Tokio team proposed a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tokio-rs/tokio-rfcs/pull/3&quot;&gt;significant API revamp&lt;/a&gt; to streamline and clarify the crate’s API, and work is underway on a book dedicated to asynchronous programming in Rust. This latest round of work is expected to land very early in 2018.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Async ecosystem&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;There’s been huge growth in the ecosystem around Tokio, including support for &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tokio-rs/tokio-curl&quot;&gt;curl&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/alexcrichton/tokio-openssl&quot;&gt;openssl&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dermesser/tokio-inotify&quot;&gt;inotify&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/alexcrichton/tokio-signal&quot;&gt;unix signals&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dwrensha/capnproto-rust&quot;&gt;cap’n proto&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://crates.io/crates/tk-sendfile&quot;&gt;sendfile&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://crates.io/crates/tokio-postgres&quot;&gt;postgres&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://crates.io/crates/couchbase&quot;&gt;couchbase&lt;/a&gt;, and more. In addition, Rust has async server libraries for both &lt;a href=&quot;http://hyper.rs/&quot;&gt;HTTP1&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/carllerche/h2&quot;&gt;HTTP2.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Generators&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Thanks to a heroic community effort, Rust also saw &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rfcs/pull/2033&quot;&gt;experimental generator support&lt;/a&gt; land in 2017! That support provides the ingredients necessary for &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;async&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;await&lt;/code&gt; notation, which is &lt;a href=&quot;https://internals.rust-lang.org/t/help-test-async-await-generators-coroutines/5835&quot;&gt;usable today&lt;/a&gt; on nightly. Further work in this area is expected to be a high priority in early 2018.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Web frameworks&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Finally, sophisticated web frameworks like &lt;a href=&quot;https://rocket.rs/&quot;&gt;Rocket&lt;/a&gt; (sync) and &lt;a href=&quot;http://gotham.rs/&quot;&gt;Gotham&lt;/a&gt; (async) have continued to evolve this year, and take advantage of Rust’s expressivity to provide a robust but productive style of programming.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;rust-should-have-10-level-crates-for-essential-tasks&quot;&gt;Rust should have 1.0-level crates for essential tasks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Libz Blitz&lt;/strong&gt;. The library team launched the &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.rust-lang.org/2017/05/05/libz-blitz.html&quot;&gt;Libz Blitz&lt;/a&gt; this year, a major effort to vet and improve a large number of foundational crates and push them toward 1.0 releases. It was a massive community effort: we performed a crowd-sourced “crate evaluation” every two weeks, fully vetting a crate against a clear set of guidelines, assessing the issue tracker, and sussing out any remaining design questions. While not all of the assessed crates have published a 1.0 yet, they are all very close to doing so. The full list includes: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang-nursery/log/issues?q=is%3Aissue+is%3Aopen+label%3A%22help+wanted%22&quot;&gt;log&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sebasmagri/env_logger/issues?q=is%3Aissue+is%3Aopen+label%3A%22help+wanted%22&quot;&gt;env_logger&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nikomatsakis/rayon/issues?q=is%3Aissue+is%3Aopen+label%3A%22help+wanted%22&quot;&gt;rayon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/carllerche/mio/issues?utf8=%E2%9C%93&amp;amp;q=is%3Aissue%20is%3Aopen%20label%3A%22help%20wanted%22%20&quot;&gt;mio&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/servo/rust-url/issues/319&quot;&gt;url&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/seanmonstar/num_cpus/issues/55&quot;&gt;num_cpus&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/steveklabnik/semver/issues/139&quot;&gt;semver&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/hyperium/mime/labels/help%20wanted&quot;&gt;mime&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/seanmonstar/reqwest/issues?q=is%3Aissue+is%3Aopen+label%3Aeasy&quot;&gt;reqwest&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang-nursery/tempdir/issues?q=is%3Aissue+is%3Aopen+label%3A%22help+wanted%22&quot;&gt;tempdir&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-threadpool/rust-threadpool/issues/86&quot;&gt;threadpool&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BurntSushi/byteorder/issues?utf8=%E2%9C%93&amp;amp;q=is%3Aissue%20is%3Aopen%20label%3A%22help%20wanted%22%20&quot;&gt;byteorder&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang-nursery/bitflags/issues?utf8=%E2%9C%93&amp;amp;q=is%3Aissue%20is%3Aopen%20label%3A%22help%20wanted%22%20&quot;&gt;bitflags&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/alexcrichton/cc-rs&quot;&gt;cc-rs&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BurntSushi/walkdir/issues/47&quot;&gt;walkdir&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://crates.io/crates/same-file&quot;&gt;same-file&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://crates.io/crates/memmap&quot;&gt;memmap&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang-nursery/lazy-static.rs/issues?utf8=%E2%9C%93&amp;amp;q=is%3Aopen%20is%3Aissue%20label%3A%22help%20wanted%22%20&quot;&gt;lazy_static&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/alexcrichton/flate2-rs/issues?q=is%3Aissue+is%3Aopen+label%3A%22help+wanted%22&quot;&gt;flate2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;API Guidelines&lt;/strong&gt;. A great by-product of the Libz Blitz is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://rust-lang-nursery.github.io/api-guidelines/&quot;&gt;API Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; book, which consolidates the official library team API guidance as informed by the standard library and the Libz Blitz process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;We ran 5 &lt;a href=&quot;https://rustbridge.github.io/&quot;&gt;RustBridge Workshops&lt;/a&gt; in 2017, in Kyiv, Ukraine; Mexico City, Mexico; Portland, OR, USA; Zurich, Switzerland; and Columbus, OH, USA! RustBridge workshops aim to get underrepresented folks started in Rust. Attendees get an introduction to syntax and concepts, work on some &lt;a href=&quot;http://exercism.io/&quot;&gt;exercism&lt;/a&gt; exercises, and build a web application that delivers emergency compliments and crab pictures. We hope to scale this program and help more folks run more workshops in 2018!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.rust-lang.org/2017/06/27/Increasing-Rusts-Reach.html&quot;&gt;Increasing Rust’s Reach program&lt;/a&gt; brought people with skills from other areas (such as teaching) and with different experiences into Rust so that we can improve in areas where the community is missing these skills and experiences. The participants have helped immensely, and many are planning to continue helping in the Rust community going forward. We’re glad they’re here! Here are some blog posts about the experience:
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Last but not least, we also launched the first Rust &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.rust-lang.org/2017/09/18/impl-future-for-rust.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;impl Period&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. This was an ambitious effort to simultaneously help get a lot of new people contributing to the Rust ecosystem while also getting a lot of things done. To that end, we created 40+ working groups, each with their own focus area, leaders, and chat channel. These groups identified good “entry points” for people who wanted to contribute, and helped mentor them through the changes needed. This event was a wild success and resulted in changes and contributions to all areas of Rust, ranging from the compiler internals to documentation to the ecosystem at large. To those of you who participated, a great big thank you — and please keep contributing! To those of you who didn’t get a chance, don’t worry: we hope to make this a regular tradition.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll be spinning up the 2018 roadmap process in the very near future; watch this space!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got a staggering amount of work done this year — and the “we” here includes an equally staggering number of people. Because the work has been spread out over so many facets of the project, it’s hard to provide a single list of people who contributed. For the impl period specifically, you can see detailed contribution lists in the newsletters:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;but of course, there have been contributions of all kinds during the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this post, I’d like to specifically call out the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;leaders&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;mentors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; who have helped orchestrate our 2017 work. Leadership of this kind — where you are working to enable others — is hard work and not recognized enough. So let’s hand it to these folks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cargo&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/carols10cents&quot;&gt;carols10cents&lt;/a&gt;, for sustained leadership and mentoring work throughout the year on crates.io.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Community&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compiler&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nikomatsakis/&quot;&gt;nikomatsakis&lt;/a&gt;, for an incredible amount of leadership, organization, and mentoring work, &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; for a lot of high-value hacking on NLL in particular.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/arielb1/&quot;&gt;arielb1&lt;/a&gt;, likewise for mentoring &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; hacking work, spanning both NLL and the rest of the compiler.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/michaelwoerister/&quot;&gt;michaelwoerister&lt;/a&gt;, for pushing continuously on delivering incremental recompilation, and creating opportunities for others to join in throughout the year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/eddyb&quot;&gt;eddyb&lt;/a&gt;, for continuing to act as a general compiler guru, and for tackling some truly heavy lifts around const generics this year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dev tools&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nrc/&quot;&gt;nrc&lt;/a&gt;, for overseeing the dev tools group as a whole, and for steady work toward shipping the RLS and rustfmt, despite many thorny infrastructure problems to get there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/matklad&quot;&gt;matklad&lt;/a&gt;, for the incredible work on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/intellij-rust/intellij-rust/blob/master/CONTRIBUTORS.txt&quot;&gt;IntelliJ Rust&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/intellij-rust/intellij-rust/blob/master/CONTRIBUTORS.txt&quot;&gt;.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/xanewok&quot;&gt;xanewok&lt;/a&gt;, for &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang-nursery/rls/graphs/contributors&quot;&gt;enormous efforts&lt;/a&gt; making the RLS a reality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/fitzgen&quot;&gt;fitzgen&lt;/a&gt;, for happily corralling a huge contributor base around &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang-nursery/rust-bindgen&quot;&gt;bindgen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Docs&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/steveklabnik/&quot;&gt;steveklabnik&lt;/a&gt;, for launching and overseeing a hugely exciting revamp of rustdoc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/QuietMisdreavus&quot;&gt;quietmisdreavus&lt;/a&gt;, for overseeing tons of activity in the docs world, but most especially for helping the community significantly improve rustdoc this year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Infrastructure&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Mark-Simulacrum&quot;&gt;mark-simulacrum&lt;/a&gt;, for getting the &lt;a href=&quot;https://perf.rust-lang.org/&quot;&gt;perf&lt;/a&gt; website to a highly useful state, and for overhauling rustbuild to better support contribution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/aidanhs/&quot;&gt;aidanhs&lt;/a&gt;, for coordinating maintenance of crater.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Language&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/withoutboats/&quot;&gt;withoutboats&lt;/a&gt;, for keeping us focused on the programmer experience and for helping the community navigate discussion around very thorny language design issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cramertj/&quot;&gt;cramertj&lt;/a&gt;, for keeping us focused on &lt;em&gt;shipping&lt;/em&gt;, and in particular building consensus around some of the topics where that’s been hardest to find: impl Trait, and module system changes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nikomatsakis/&quot;&gt;nikomatsakis&lt;/a&gt;, for making the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rfcs/pull/2094&quot;&gt;NLL RFC&lt;/a&gt; so accessible, and pioneering the idea of using a separate repo for it to allow for greater participation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Libraries&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/brson/&quot;&gt;brson&lt;/a&gt;, for envisioning and largely overseeing the Libz Blitz initiative.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kodraus&quot;&gt;kodraus&lt;/a&gt;, for gracefully taking over the Libz Blitz and seeing it to a successful conclusion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dtolnay&quot;&gt;dtolnay&lt;/a&gt;, for taking on the API guidelines work and getting it to a coherent and polished state.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/budziq&quot;&gt;budziq&lt;/a&gt;, for a ton of work coordinating and editing contributions to the cookbook.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dhardy&quot;&gt;dhardy&lt;/a&gt;, for leading a heroic effort to revamp the rand crate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Technical leaders are an essential ingredient for our success, and I hope in 2018 we can continue to grow our leadership pool, and get even more done — together.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 16:47:09 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>steveklabnik</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.rust-lang.org/2017/12/21/rust-in-2017.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Facebook’s Political Unit Enables Propaganda</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2017-12-21/inside-the-facebook-team-helping-regimes-that-reach-out-and-crack-down</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2017-12-21/inside-the-facebook-team-helping-regimes-that-reach-out-and-crack-down</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;section-break&quot;&gt;Under fire for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/FB:US&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Facebook Inc.&lt;/a&gt;’s role as a platform for political propaganda, co-founder Mark Zuckerberg has punched back, saying his mission is above partisanship. “We hope to give all people a voice and create a platform for all ideas,” Zuckerberg &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/zuck/posts/10104067130714241&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;wrote in September&lt;/a&gt; after President Donald Trump accused Facebook of bias.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Zuckerberg’s social network is a politically agnostic tool for its more than 2 billion users, he has said. But Facebook, it turns out, is no bystander in global politics. What he hasn’t said is that his company actively works with political parties and leaders including those who use the platform to stifle opposition—sometimes with the aid of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2017-12-07/how-rodrigo-duterte-turned-facebook-into-a-weapon-with-a-little-help-from-facebook&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;“troll armies”&lt;/a&gt; that spread misinformation and extremist ideologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The initiative is run by a little-known Facebook global government and politics team that’s neutral in that it works with nearly anyone seeking or securing power. The unit is led from Washington by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.msnbc.com/msnbc/women-bridging-tech-and-politics-the-2016-election-katie-harbath&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Katie Harbath&lt;/a&gt;, a former Republican digital strategist who worked on former New York Mayor Rudy Giuliani’s 2008 presidential campaign. Since Facebook hired Harbath three years later, her team has traveled the globe helping political clients use the company’s powerful digital tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;lazy-img-321843651&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/i4NdQZAdI9dA/v16/60x-1.jpg&quot; data-native-src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/i4NdQZAdI9dA/v16/-1x-1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img__image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Katie Harbath.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photographer: Kirk Irwin/Getty Images for Glamour&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some of the world’s biggest democracies—from India and Brazil to Germany and the U.K.—the unit’s employees have become de facto campaign workers. And once a candidate is elected, the company in some instances goes on to train government employees or provide technical assistance for live streams at official state events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;section-break&quot;&gt;Even before Facebook was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-11-01/social-media-companies-get-unaccustomed-grilling-on-russia-ads&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;forced to explain&lt;/a&gt; its role in U.S. election meddling—portrayed by its executives as a largely passive affair involving Russian-funded ads—the company’s direct and growing role &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/business/success/categories/government-politics&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;catering to political campaigns&lt;/a&gt; raised concerns inside the social media giant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s not Facebook’s job, in my opinion, to be so close to any election campaign,” said Elizabeth Linder, who started and ran the Facebook politics unit’s Europe, Middle East and Africa efforts until 2016. Linder had originally been excited about the company’s potential to be “extraordinarily useful for the world’s leaders—but also the global citizenry.” She said she decided to leave the company in part because she grew uncomfortable with what she saw as increased emphasis on electioneering and campaigns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the U.S., the unit &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2016-10-27/inside-the-trump-bunker-with-12-days-to-go&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;embedded employees&lt;/a&gt; in Trump’s campaign. (Hillary Clinton’s camp declined a similar offer.) In India, the company helped develop the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/narendramodi/&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;online presence&lt;/a&gt; of Prime Minister Narendra Modi, who now has more Facebook followers than any other world leader. In the Philippines, it trained the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/rodyduterte/&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;campaign&lt;/a&gt; of Rodrigo Duterte, known for encouraging extrajudicial killings, in how to most effectively use the platform. And in Germany it helped the anti-immigrant &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-09-29/the-german-far-right-finds-friends-through-facebook&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Alternative for Germany party (AfD)&lt;/a&gt; win its first Bundestag seats, according to campaign staff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;lazy-img-321843984&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iVo3TbMrXFdg/v1/60x-1.jpg&quot; data-native-src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iVo3TbMrXFdg/v1/-1x-1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img__image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supporters of the Alternative for Germany (AfD) party dressed in blue tights attend a campaign rally ahead of European parliamentary elections on May 23, 2014, in Berlin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photographer: Sean Gallup/Getty Images&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By all accounts, Facebook has been an indispensable &lt;a href=&quot;https://fr.newsroom.fb.com/news/2017/04/facebook-lance-un-outil-pour-faciliter-lacces-aux-programmes-des-candidats-a-la-presidentielle/&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;tool of civic engagement&lt;/a&gt;, with candidates and elected officials from mayor to prime minister using the platform to communicate directly with their constituents, and with grassroots groups like Black Lives Matter relying on it to organize. The company says it offers the same tools and services to all candidates and governments regardless of political affiliation, and even to civil society groups that may have a lesser voice. Facebook says it provides advice on how best to use its tools, not strategic advice about what to say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We’re proud to work with the thousands of elected officials around the world who use Facebook as a way to communicate directly with their constituents, interact with voters, and hear about the issues important in their community,” Harbath said in an emailed statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She said the company is investing in artificial intelligence and other ways to better police hate speech and threats. “We take our responsibility to prevent abuse of our platform extremely seriously,” Harbath said. “We know there are ways we can do better, and are constantly working to improve.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Power and social media converge by design at Facebook. The company has long worked to crush its smaller rival, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-05-02/twitter-says-it-would-love-world-leaders-to-use-it-like-trump&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, in a race to be the platform of choice for the world’s so-called influencers, whether politicians, cricket stars or Kardashians. Their posts will, in theory, draw followers to Facebook more frequently, resulting in higher traffic for advertisers and better data about what attracts users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Politicians running for office can be lucrative ad buyers. For those who spend enough, Facebook offers customized services to help them build effective campaigns, the same way it would &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/UNA:NA&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Unilever NV&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/KO:US&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Coca-Cola Co.&lt;/a&gt; ahead of a product launch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Facebook declined to give the size of its politics unit, one executive said it can expand to include hundreds during the peak of an election, drawing in people from the company’s legal, information security and policy teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;section-break&quot;&gt;At meetings with political campaigns, members of Harbath’s team sit alongside Facebook advertising sales staff who help monetize the often viral attention stirred up by elections and politics. They train politicians and leaders how to set up a campaign page and get it authenticated with a blue verification check mark, how to best use video to engage viewers and how to target ads to critical voting blocs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;lazy-img-321843735&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iQAR8coRuoHo/v16/60x-1.jpg&quot; data-native-src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iQAR8coRuoHo/v16/-1x-1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img__image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rodrigo Duterte.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photographer: Mark R. Cristino/AFP/Getty Images&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once those candidates are elected, their relationship with Facebook can help extend the company’s reach into government in meaningful ways, such as being well positioned to push against regulations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the very least, the optics of directly aiding campaigns or those in power may create the impression among users that Facebook is taking sides. Its effort effectively helping the Scottish National Party to victory in 2015 is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/business/success/snp&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;recounted as a “success story”&lt;/a&gt; on Facebook’s corporate website that lists business case studies, even though those who favor staying in the U.K. might see it otherwise. In April, Vietnamese officials bragged that Facebook would build a dedicated channel to prioritize takedown requests for content that offended authorities. The company generally routes requests from governments through a separate channel, and takes the content down if it violates community standards. If it violates local law, it’ll only be unavailable in the relevant country.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“They’re too cozy with power,” said &lt;a href=&quot;https://steinhardt.nyu.edu/faculty/Mark_Crispin_Miller&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Mark Crispin Miller&lt;/a&gt;, a media and culture professor at New York University.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That problem is exacerbated when Facebook’s engine of democracy is deployed in an undemocratic fashion. A November &lt;a href=&quot;https://freedomhouse.org/article/new-report-freedom-net-2017-manipulating-social-media-undermine-democracy&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;report by Freedom House&lt;/a&gt;, a U.S.-based nonprofit that advocates for political and human rights, found that a growing number of countries are “manipulating social media to undermine democracy.” One aspect of that involves “patriotic trolling,” or the use of government-backed harassment and propaganda meant to control the narrative, silence dissidents and consolidate power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;section-break&quot;&gt;Internally, Facebook executives are grappling with how to distinguish between what constitutes trolling harassment and protected political speech. Zuckerberg has long maintained the company doesn’t want to play censor, but Facebook has drawn some lines—banning Greece’s Golden Dawn, the ultranationalist party, for example. The company also often removes the &lt;a href=&quot;https://newsroom.fb.com/news/2017/06/how-we-counter-terrorism/&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;most extreme content&lt;/a&gt;, from white nationalists in the U.S. and from the Islamic State, as well as content it catches violating its “community standards” on hate speech and violence. Not all such content gets caught.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In retrospect, the nexus of power and data at Facebook seems inevitable. In 2007, Facebook opened its first office in Washington. The presidential election the following year saw the rise of the world’s first “Facebook President” in Barack Obama, who with the platform’s help was able to reach millions of voters in the weeks before the election. The number of Facebook users surged around the Arab Spring uprisings in the Middle East around 2010 and 2011, demonstrating the broad power of the platform to influence democracy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;lazy-img-321844100&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iWSQ3CmHdr1g/v1/60x-1.jpg&quot; data-native-src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iWSQ3CmHdr1g/v1/-1x-1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img__image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scottish National Party leader Nicola Sturgeon at a rally in Glasgow in April 2015. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photographer: Jeff J Mitchell/Getty Images&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the time Facebook named Harbath, the former Giuliani aide, to lead its global politics and government unit, elections were becoming major social-media attractions. They now rank alongside the Super Bowl and the Olympics in terms of events that draw blockbuster ad dollars and boost engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook began getting involved in electoral hotspots around the world. They went to Argentina in 2015, where now-President Mauricio Macri streamed campaign rallies live on Facebook and, once elected, announced his entire cabinet on the site, complete with emojis. The same year, Poland’s nationalist president, Andrzej Duda, became one of the first world leaders to livestream his inauguration on the social network. Even as Duda has overseen a crackdown on press freedom in the country, Facebook’s corporate website says the company was “integral” to his electoral success and that his page is “one of his office’s main communication channels.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook has embedded itself in some of the globe’s most controversial political movements while resisting transparency. Since 2011, it has asked the U.S. Federal Election Commission for blanket exemptions from political advertising disclosure rules that could have helped it avoid the current crisis over Russian ad spending ahead of the 2016 election, Bloomberg reported in October. After a Congressional inquiry into Russian election meddling, Facebook has pledged to be more transparent about ad buyers and said it’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-10-04/facebook-fought-for-years-to-avoid-political-ad-disclosure-rules&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;open to regulation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;section-break&quot;&gt;The company’s relationship with governments remains complicated. Facebook has come under fire in the European Union, including for the spread of Islamic extremism on its network. The company just issued its &lt;a href=&quot;https://transparency.facebook.com/&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;annual transparency report&lt;/a&gt; explaining that it will only provide user data to governments if that request is legally sufficient, and will push back in court if it’s not. Despite Facebook’s desire to eventually operate in China and Zuckerberg’s flirtation with the country’s leaders, it’s still unwilling to compromise as much as the government wants it to in order to enter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;lazy-img-321843682&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/i71U2.abwTlg/v16/60x-1.jpg&quot; data-native-src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/i71U2.abwTlg/v16/-1x-1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img__image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Narendra Modi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photographer: Rob Stothard/Getty Images&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;India is arguably Facebook’s most important market, with the nation recently edging out the U.S. as the company’s biggest. The number of users there is growing twice as fast as in the U.S. And that doesn’t even count the 200 million people who use the company’s WhatsApp messaging service in India, more than anywhere else on the globe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the time of India’s 2014 elections, Facebook had for months been working with several campaigns. Modi, who belongs to the nationalist Bharatiya Janata Party, relied heavily on Facebook and WhatsApp to recruit volunteers who in turn spread his message on social media. Since his election, Modi’s Facebook followers have risen to 43 million, almost twice Trump’s count.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within weeks of Modi’s election, Zuckerberg and Chief Operating Officer Sheryl Sandberg both visited the nation as it was rolling out a critical free internet service that the government later curbed. Harbath and her team have also traveled there, offering a series of workshops and sessions that have trained more than 6,000 government officials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Modi’s social media reach grew, his followers increasingly turned to Facebook and WhatsApp to target harassment campaigns against his political rivals. India has become a hotbed for fake news, with one hoax story this year that circulated on WhatsApp leading to two separate mob beatings resulting in seven deaths. The nation has also become an increasingly dangerous place for opposition parties and reporters. In the past year, several journalists critical of the ruling party have been killed. Hindu extremists who back Modi’s party have used social media to issue death threats against Muslims or critics of the government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the night of Sept. 5, a Honda motorcycle pulled in front of the Bengaluru home of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloombergquint.com/politics/2017/09/06/dissent-journalist-gauri-lankesh-who-stood-for-free-speech-killed&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Gauri Lankesh&lt;/a&gt;, an outspoken critic of Modi who had been targeted by patriotic trolls on Facebook and other social media. As the Indian journalist was unlocking her gate, three bullets struck her in the head and chest, killing her. No arrests have been made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://thewire.in/175643/gauri-lankesh-final-editorial-fake-news/&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;final editorial&lt;/a&gt; Lankesh had written for her newspaper was titled “In the Age of False News.” In it, she lamented how misinformation and propaganda on social media were poisoning the political environment.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;— With assistance by Benjamin Elgin&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 15:59:49 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ucaetano</dc:creator>
<og:description>Some of the unit’s clients stifle opposition and stoke extremism.</og:description>
<og:image>https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/ihMXZRVm.Ag0/v0/1200x630.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>The Facebook Team Helping Regimes That Fight Their Opposition</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2017-12-21/inside-the-facebook-team-helping-regimes-that-reach-out-and-crack-down</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2017-12-21/inside-the-facebook-team-helping-regimes-that-reach-out-and-crack-down</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Apple Says It Slows Older iPhones to Save Their Battery Life</title>
<link>http://text.npr.org/s.php?sId=572538593</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://text.npr.org/s.php?sId=572538593</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;Content-Type&quot; content=&quot;text/html; charset=UTF-8&quot; /&gt;&lt;title&gt;Text-Only NPR.org : Apple Says It Slows Older iPhones To Save Their Battery Life&lt;/title&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;robots&quot; content=&quot;noindex, nofollow&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;viewport&quot; content=&quot;width=device-width, initial-scale=1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;126.58561020036&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Text-Only NPR.org (go to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org&quot;&gt;full version&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://text.npr.org/&quot;&gt;Home&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple Says It Slows Older iPhones To Save Their Battery Life&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Bill Chappell&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NPR.org, December 21, 2017 · Confirming iPhone owners' suspicions that Apple purposefully slows the operation of older phones, Apple says that it does just that — and that slowing down processors makes it easier for old batteries to perform after they've begun to lose capacity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple is responding to owners of older phones who have increasingly said they notice slower performance after they upgrade their devices' software. The difference was highlighted in a recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/iphone/comments/7inu45/psa_iphone_slow_try_replacing_your_battery/&quot;&gt;Reddit post&lt;/a&gt; — and it was quantified in a blog post at Geekbench, the processor bench-marking company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Older phones operate more quickly if they're using older versions of Apple's iOS operating system, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geekbench.com/blog/2017/12/iphone-performance-and-battery-age/&quot;&gt;Geekbench found&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The slowdown affects a range of Apple phones, including the iPhone 7 and iPhone 6S, models that came out in 2016 and 2015, respectively. The company says it plans to apply the same strategy to &quot;other products in the future.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smartphones' lithium-ion batteries lose their pep as they age, but processors remain hungry for quick bursts of power. So, Apple used software to throttle the demand — effectively governing the speed at which the phones can operate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The situation is prickly: More than 10 years after Apple introduced its first iPhone, the company says it's trying to deliver the &quot;best experience&quot; to customers by preventing unexpected power-related shutdowns. In addition to addressing aging batteries, the company said it tries to &quot;smooth out&quot; power demand in phones that are operating in cold conditions or that have a low battery charge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But some customers say the company's strategy of dealing with the power demand pushes them to replace their older iPhones with newer models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Reddit post that generated intense interest in Apple's battery strategy earlier this month, a user named &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/user/TeckFire&quot;&gt;TeckFire&lt;/a&gt; reported that after noticing that different versions of the iPhone 6 series were running at vastly different speeds, they saw speeds pick up again once the battery on an iPhone 6S was replaced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That post triggered responses in which other Apple customers wondered whether the battery ploy was also to blame for their older Macbook laptops not working as well as they once had.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explaining how Apple's approach could feed suspicions of &quot;planned obsolescence,&quot; John Poole, founder of Geekbench parent Primate Labs, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geekbench.com/blog/2017/12/iphone-performance-and-battery-age/&quot;&gt;writes&lt;/a&gt;, &quot;users may believe that the slow down is due to [central processing unit] performance, instead of battery performance.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the battery being the reason that Apple is slowing the phones, Poole adds, &quot;This fix will also cause users to think, 'My phone is slow so I should replace it' not, 'My phone is slow so I should replace its battery.' &quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The discrepancy between processors and batteries runs deep — and it's increasingly being highlighted, as lithium-ion batteries are recognized as not having much room for improvement. As Kristin Persson, a professor of materials and engineering at University of California, Berkeley, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.marketplace.org/2017/12/07/tech/lithium-ion-batteries-are-about-good-they-can-get&quot;&gt;told Marketplace on Thursday morning&lt;/a&gt;, lithium-ion batteries are &quot;highly optimized,&quot; and researchers have been working on creating a better battery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Persson told Marketplace's Molly Wood:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;So if you compare batteries to, for example, computers, the difference is really that in batteries you have to invent new materials to make them better, whereas in semiconductors, you're inherently, most of the time, using the same materials and you're just making them smaller, which is easier.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is Apple's statement on the battery/CPU issue:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Our goal is to deliver the best experience for customers, which includes overall performance and prolonging the life of their devices. Lithium-ion batteries become less capable of supplying peak current demands when in cold conditions, have a low battery charge or as they age over time, which can result in the device unexpectedly shutting down to protect its electronic components.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Last year we released a feature for iPhone 6, iPhone 6s and iPhone SE to smooth out the instantaneous peaks only when needed to prevent the device from unexpectedly shutting down during these conditions. We've now extended that feature to iPhone 7 with iOS 11.2, and plan to add support for other products in the future.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;© NPR&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 15:09:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>lyk</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://text.npr.org/s.php?sId=572538593</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Long Island Iced Tea Soars 500% After Changing Its Name to Long Blockchain</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-12-21/crypto-craze-sees-long-island-iced-tea-rename-as-long-blockchain</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-12-21/crypto-craze-sees-long-island-iced-tea-rename-as-long-blockchain</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;There’s a new leader in the &lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-12-20/juices-bras-and-e-cigs-no-past-too-weird-for-new-crypto-firms&quot; title=&quot;Juices, Bras and E-Cigs: No Past Too Weird for New Crypto Firms&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;sweepstakes&lt;/a&gt; for the zaniest name change in the crypto craze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Long Island Iced Tea Corp. shares rose as much as 289 percent after the unprofitable Hicksville, New York-based company rebranded itself Long Blockchain Corp. It’s the latest in a near-daily phenomenon sweeping the stock market, where obscure microcap companies reorient to focus on some aspect of the mania sparked by bitcoin’s 1,500 percent rally this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Long Blockchain, whose business has been selling non-alcoholic beverages, says it will now seek to partner with or invest in companies that develop the decentralized ledgers known as blockchain, the technology that underpins bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;lazy-img-321894490&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iTdaApO9LjpM/v2/60x-1.png&quot; data-native-src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iTdaApO9LjpM/v2/-1x-1.png&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img__image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The re-named firm joins the ranks of recently christened crypto companies -- a list that includes former makers of juice, sports bras and sofas -- whose share prices have all rocketed after their respective announcements. Some are likening the mania to the dot-com boom, and ultimate bust, two decades ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s so reminiscent of what happened in the late 1990s,” Scott Nations, author of ‘A History of the United States in Five Crashes,’ said by phone. “A company that had nothing to do with the internet would put out a press release that they were going to become an internet company now, and the same sort of thing would happen.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The shares surged to as high as $9.49 before closing at $6.91 in New York trading, compared with $2.44 Wednesday. More 15 million shares changed hands, compared with average daily volume of about 170,00 shares over the prior three months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long Blockchain’s shares may be benefiting from the announcement, but so far the company has little to show for its aspirations. It has no agreements with any blockchain firms, and says “there is no assurance that a definitive agreement with these, or any other entity, will be entered into or ultimately consummated.” A request for comment from Chief Executive Officer Philip Thomas wasn’t immediately returned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;inline-newsletter&quot; data-state=&quot;ready&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Eric J. Watson is the largest shareholder of Long Island Iced Tea Corp. with more than 13 percent of outstanding shares, according to U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission filings. Watson, a resident of the U.K., is the founder and executive chairman of Cullen Investments, which the firm says on its &lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;http://www.culleninvestments.com/key-executives.php&quot; title=&quot;Cullen Investments&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; has holdings in fashion retail, financial services, agriculture, real estate and sports and entertainment in the U.S., Britain, New Zealand and Australia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conjunction with the change in focus, the company canceled a planned share sale. Long Island Iced Tea, the product of a 2015 merger with Cullen Agricultural Holding Corp., has been funding operations through a combination of equity and debt sales. It has a market value of about $67 million in after the surge in the stock price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/terminal/OZDNV23PR6RM&quot; title=&quot;Long Island Iced Tea Corp.: 10-Q 2017/09/30&quot; class=&quot;terminal-news-story&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Long Island Iced Tea&lt;/a&gt; had a net loss of $3.9 million on sales of $1.6 million in the three months ended Sept. 30. The company has lost $11.6 million on sales of $3.9 million in the first nine months of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company has reserved the web domain name &lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;http://www.longblockchain.com&quot; title=&quot;Click to view webpage.&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;www.longblockchain.com&lt;/a&gt; and will still operate a ready-to-drink beverage subsidiary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These “sorts of companies that go up the course of five or 10 times in one day just because they say that they’re a blockchain company now,” Nations said. “To me, that just confirms that we’re in a bubble.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Related News and Information:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-12-20/juices-bras-and-e-cigs-no-past-too-weird-for-new-crypto-firms&quot; title=&quot;Juices, Bras and E-Cigs: No Past Too Weird for New Crypto Firms&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Juices, Bras and E-Cigs: No Past Too Weird for New Crypto Firms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-12-19/crypto-mania-rages-with-bankruptcy-stock-suspension-etf-plan&quot; title=&quot;Crypto Mania Rages as Pioneer Sells Out, Coinbase Stumbles (2)&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Crypto Mania Rages as Pioneer Sells Out, Coinbase Stumbles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/terminal/P1BCUOSYF01S&quot; title=&quot;Crypto-Slash-Sofa High Flyer Nova Says Will Now Accept Bitcoin&quot; class=&quot;terminal-news-story&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Crypto-Slash-Sofa High Flyer Nova Says Will Now Accept Bitcoin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;— With assistance by Richard Trueman, Julie Verhage, and Randall Jensen&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 14:45:33 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dkyc</dc:creator>
<og:description>There’s a new leader in the sweepstakes for the zaniest name change in the crypto craze.</og:description>
<og:image>https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iRZZtDup244E/v2/1200x675.png</og:image>
<og:title>Long Island Iced Tea Soars After Changing Its Name to Long Blockchain</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-12-21/crypto-craze-sees-long-island-iced-tea-rename-as-long-blockchain</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-12-21/crypto-craze-sees-long-island-iced-tea-rename-as-long-blockchain</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Tax-Free Bitcoin-To-Ether Trading in US to End Under GOP Plan</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-12-21/tax-free-bitcoin-to-ether-trading-in-u-s-to-end-under-gop-plan</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-12-21/tax-free-bitcoin-to-ether-trading-in-u-s-to-end-under-gop-plan</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Investors in bitcoin and other virtual currencies would lose a lucrative tax break under the Republican tax bill that’s on its way to President Donald Trump’s desk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New limits in the bill would bar cryptocurrency owners from deferring capital gains taxes when trading one type of virtual currency for another -- effectively closing a gray area in the tax code, experts say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those gains can be considerable. Bitcoin, which had an initial price of less than 1 cent when it first traded in 2010, was around $1,000 as 2017 began and surpassed $19,000 this week, at least briefly, before paring some of the gains. Many enthusiasts jump between bitcoin and a long list of similarly volatile competitors, such as ether.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;For investors who hold the virtual currencies, “the bill is bad news,” said Kelsey Lemaster, a tax attorney with Goodwin Procter LLP. “Every time you trade one digital currency for another, one token for another, it’s going to be a taxable event.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The change might not deter traders, who have been leaping into cryptocurrencies without researching what they are -- let alone their tax implications, said Brian Kristiansen, a partner in the digital currency services practice at Friedman LLP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/gadfly/articles/2017-12-21/bitcoin-whales-are-cutting-back&quot; title=&quot;Bitcoin Whales Are Cutting Back as Eager Minnows Dive In: Gadfly&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Bitcoin Whales Are Cutting Back as Eager Minnows Dive In: Gadfly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under current law, such trades have been protected under a provision that allows investors to defer capital gains taxes on so-called “like-kind exchanges” -- trades that traditionally have been staples for investors in real estate, art, racehorses and aircraft. The deferral applies when owners of such property swap it for other property of a similar kind, typically within a 180-day period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;‘Unreal’ Property&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Increasingly, traders concerned about increased government oversight have sought to move between virtual currencies to take advantage of the like-kind deferral. Now, though, the GOP tax bill would restrict the break to trades of domestic real estate only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s only for real property now, and ‘crypto’ is about as not real as you can get,” said Friedman’s Kristiansen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That change goes into effect on Jan. 1. After that, exchanges of cryptocurrencies “would be subject to tax at the time of the exchange,” said Lisa Zarlenga, a tax attorney with Steptoe &amp;amp; Johnson LLP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investors typically have to pay taxes on their short-term capital gains at their individual income rates, which will top out at 37 percent next year. The preferential long-term capital gains rate -- which tops out at 23.8 percent -- is owed when such assets are sold after a year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;inline-newsletter&quot; data-state=&quot;ready&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;With its new limits, Congress addressed a quirky section of the tax code. The rules for like-kind exchanges, first enshrined in the code in 1921, have never applied to stocks, bonds or other securities, and they contain some fine distinctions about what constitutes “similar” property. For example, a beef cow cannot be swapped for a dairy cow. Paintings can generally be swapped, but it’s not clear that a Rembrandt could be swapped for a Jackson Pollock, according to a 2012 article in an American Bar Association trade publication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Virtual Variety&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sheer variety of virtual currencies -- all running on different blockchains, the encrypted networks that record transactions -- has always made them somewhat awkward candidates for the like-kind exchange deferral, Lemaster said. A so-called utility token, like Filecoin, is very different from “true cryptocurrencies like bitcoin and ether,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In March 2014, the I.R.S. declared virtual currency to be property, like gold or real estate, and not currency, for tax purposes. That distinction makes it subject to capital gains taxes. Despite the definition, the tax-collecting agency hadn’t fully defined how -- or whether -- cryptocurrencies could be used in like-kind exchanges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;There’s always been a question under current law as to what types of currencies can be exchanged and qualify,&quot; Lemaster said. &quot;The conservative view is that it doesn’t qualify.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most cryptocurrency investors have ignored that legal fuzziness, and taken the approach that trading a stash of, say, bitcoins for litecoins, qualifies as swapping one form of property for a similar one. “People have probably foot-faulted all over the place,” Lemaster said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once a swapped asset is actually sold, the seller would owe capital gains taxes, at a tax rate that depends on whether it was held for more than a year. While that may take a bite out of some investors’ gains, it’s good for cryptocurrencies in the long run, said Ryan Losi, who leads the international tax practice at accounting firm PIASCIK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More defined regulation will mean that digital assets are more easily accepted in the mainstream, Losi said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“As this fledgling type of payment gets older and more adopted, more scaled, eventually it will get regulated,” Losi said in a telephone interview. “More and more people will come to accept it and agree with it, even if early on it is very speculative.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Likewise, the new law is unlikely to damp interest in listing &lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-12-19/the-next-bitcoin-etfs-are-testing-luck-with-skeptical-regulator&quot; title=&quot;More Bitcoin ETFs Test Their Luck With Skeptical Regulator (1)&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;exchange-traded funds&lt;/a&gt; related to virtual currency, said William Rhind, the chief executive officer of GraniteShares, an investment company that filed forms last week seeking permission to list two bitcoin ETFs. More than 15 bitcoin-related ETFs have been proposed since 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rhind said existing rules already prohibit securities from being used in like-kind exchanges. “I don’t think it’s relevant,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 13:03:07 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jeffwass</dc:creator>
<og:description>Investors in bitcoin and other virtual currencies would lose a lucrative tax break under the Republican tax bill that’s on its way to President Donald Trump’s desk.</og:description>
<og:image>https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iy12CPriyW8I/v0/1200x825.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Tax-Free Bitcoin-to-Ether Trading in U.S. to End Under GOP Plan</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-12-21/tax-free-bitcoin-to-ether-trading-in-u-s-to-end-under-gop-plan</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-12-21/tax-free-bitcoin-to-ether-trading-in-u-s-to-end-under-gop-plan</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Libdill: Structured Concurrency for C (2016)</title>
<link>http://libdill.org/index.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://libdill.org/index.html</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;meta charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;/&gt;&lt;title&gt;libdill&lt;/title&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot; href=&quot;http://libdill.org/main.css&quot;/&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;40.532019704433&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Libdill is a C library that makes writing &lt;a href=&quot;http://libdill.org/structured-concurrency.html&quot;&gt;structured concurrent programs&lt;/a&gt; easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following example launches two concurrent worker functions that print &quot;Hello!&quot; or &quot;World!&quot;, respectively, at random intervals. The program runs for five seconds and then it shuts down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;sourceCode c&quot;&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;sourceCode c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ot&quot;&gt;#include &amp;lt;libdill.h&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;ot&quot;&gt;#include &amp;lt;stdio.h&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;ot&quot;&gt;#include &amp;lt;stdlib.h&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;

coroutine &lt;span class=&quot;dt&quot;&gt;void&lt;/span&gt; worker(&lt;span class=&quot;dt&quot;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;dt&quot;&gt;char&lt;/span&gt; *text) {
    &lt;span class=&quot;kw&quot;&gt;while&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;dv&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;) {
        printf(&lt;span class=&quot;st&quot;&gt;&quot;%s&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ch&quot;&gt;\n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;st&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;, text);
        msleep(now() + random() % &lt;span class=&quot;dv&quot;&gt;500&lt;/span&gt;);
    }
}

&lt;span class=&quot;dt&quot;&gt;int&lt;/span&gt; main() {
    go(worker(&lt;span class=&quot;st&quot;&gt;&quot;Hello!&quot;&lt;/span&gt;));
    go(worker(&lt;span class=&quot;st&quot;&gt;&quot;World!&quot;&lt;/span&gt;));
    msleep(now() + &lt;span class=&quot;dv&quot;&gt;5000&lt;/span&gt;);
    &lt;span class=&quot;kw&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;dv&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;;
}&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Code dependent on libdill is compiled like any other C code. The only extra requirement is that it be linked with libdill library:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;$ cc -ldill -o hello hello.c&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Libdill is licensed under the MIT/X11 license.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 11:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jgrahamc</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://libdill.org/index.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A Letter from the Publisher of Nautilus</title>
<link>http://m.nautil.us/blog/a-letter-from-the-publisher-of-nautilus</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://m.nautil.us/blog/a-letter-from-the-publisher-of-nautilus</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://static.nautil.us/13891_bb83b72bf545e376f3ff9443bda39421.png&quot; width=&quot;733&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap mqw&quot;&gt;M&lt;/span&gt;y name is John Steele. I am the publisher and editorial director of Nautilus. Yesterday an open letter was posted on the National Writers Union website, signed by 19 freelance writers. It stated some writers and editors are “awaiting payment from Nautilus magazine for a collective debt totaling $50,000. Some of us have been waiting to be paid for more than a year.” It’s true that Nautilus has a large, outstanding debt to our contributors. I want to explain how Nautilus got into this situation, and how we plan to get out of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nautilus was started and published with institutional and philanthropic financial support from the John Templeton Foundation and several other science institutions and philanthropies. In the fall of 2016, it became clear that at least some of those grants would not renew, and that our revenue base would not be able to support the magazine at its then level of activity. I determined that our best option was to find an institutional home for Nautilus with the resources that could ensure its editorial mission and growth. It was later that year that we started talks with a number of institutions, including the American Association for the Advancement of Science, or AAAS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Early in 2017, I was confident that a merger of Nautilus into AAAS, supported by philanthropic foundations, was imminent, and reflected that confidence to our staff and contributors. I delayed some payments to writers and artists, but told our editors that our financial course was steady and that we needed to continue putting out the best magazine we could to continue to attract the interest of our suitors. As a result, editorial staff continued to commission work in good faith, based on the information I gave them. The open letter remarks that I instructed the staff to commission articles that I “knew that Nautilus could not pay for.” That is not accurate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By March of 2017, Nautilus’ finances had become critical. We missed payrolls and lost staff, and it became clear to me we could not operate at the levels of the previous three years. We stopped commissioning new market-rate work, shifting to book excerpts, free content, and tiny honoraria. Our sales revenue was growing and there were donations coming in from our supporters. Salaries and expenses were deeply cut. When revenue, donations or small grants came in, we sent out checks to reduce the outstanding debt to contributors, which at the beginning of the year was in the hundreds of thousands of dollars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, my over-confidence that a merger was around the corner prompted me to over-promise, continually, when payments would be made. It was a big mistake on my part for which I sincerely apologize. I OK’d the hiring of interns that I thought could fit into our existing cash flow. I explained the financial challenges and assured them payment that, unfortunately, didn’t materialize. I sent a letter to our readers on September 3, explaining that we were facing challenges as we sought funding, and was deeply encouraged to receive an outpouring of support, much of it financial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We kept publishing. If we didn’t, Nautilus’ value to a potential partner would disappear, leaving shutdown the only option, which would mean that nobody would get paid. As long as the merger talks continued, Nautilus had a way forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The merger talks continued through the summer but abruptly ended in September. I scrambled to find other potential partners or buyers for Nautilus, and many of those talks continue today. Though a positive outcome for Nautilus is not certain, the magazine is a tremendous asset with a large, loyal audience that appreciates the style, imagination, and rigor of our exploration of science. It’s a challenging time for media and magazines in particular. Everyone at Nautilus is invested, both emotionally and financially, in what we have created.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since April of this year, we have paid over $130,000 to writers and artists’ for past-due invoices. Recently we received two small grants. We have used those grants, combined with our revenue, to pay in full two of the authors who signed the open letter. We will be sending out partial payments to another two of them today. By the end of the year, we will pay in full another three of the 19 writers. We are putting a significant percent of our monthly revenue—everything that does not go toward our overhead—to meeting our debt to writers. I continue to work as hard as ever to find an institutional home for Nautilus. I will aggressively pursue debt repayment into 2018 for all of the authors and illustrators we owe, as we have been doing in 2017. We are committed to pay every dollar we owe to contributors, vendors, and staff&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to again make clear that nobody on the Nautilus staff commissioned any work that they knowingly thought wouldn’t be paid for. The staff operated from my instructions and my expectations of resources available. I take full responsibility and am upset by accusations that the staff deceived contributors or interns. Since we began, our editors have worked to nurture great working relationships with writers, artists, and interns. All of them have been working on fractional salaries, despite doing a greater workload due to the departures of their colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ability to pay our debts depends on our continued operations, and our continued status as one of today’s premier outlets for science writing. We understand that we need to maintain a good relationship with our talented contributors. In our four years of publishing, we are proud to have paid out over $2 million to writers, artists, web and graphic designers, and animators. The story of Nautilus has not unfolded as we had hoped, but it’s not over either.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 07:50:03 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>juretriglav</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>http://nautil.us/blog/a-letter-from-the-publisher-of-nautilus</og:url>
<og:title>A Letter from the Publisher of Nautilus - Facts So Romantic - Nautilus</og:title>
<og:description>My name is John Steele. I am the publisher and editorial director of Nautilus. Yesterday an open letter was posted on the National&amp;#8230;</og:description>
<og:image>http://static.nautil.us/13891_bb83b72bf545e376f3ff9443bda39421.png</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://nautil.us/blog/a-letter-from-the-publisher-of-nautilus</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Racing for Realism</title>
<link>https://renderman.pixar.com/stories/cars-3</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://renderman.pixar.com/stories/cars-3</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Written by Harsh Agrawal and Leif Pedersen.&lt;br/&gt;Based on developments by Christophe Hery, Michael Kass, Junyi Ling, and Ryusuke Villemin&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-content-container medium&quot; readability=&quot;48&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Photorealism has been the holy grail for computer graphics, especially in the visual effects world, where recreating digital humans or matching live action film plates is paramount. In recent years, stylized feature film animation has also shifted towards the same need, with an ever-increasing demand for shading and lighting realism. This has pushed the animation industry into physically-based rendering in order to push the visual complexity.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To create such realistic images, attention to detail plays an important role, because when it comes down to judging reality, humans are capable of subconsciously catching the most subtle anomalies. This minute attention to detail is otherwise trivial in our daily life, but recreating it can be a challenging task. Pixar technical artists took on this challenge in order to bring the &lt;em&gt;Cars&lt;/em&gt; universe into a new standard of realism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;mb-5&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-container mb-5&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;parallax-window&quot; data-parallax=&quot;scroll&quot; data-image-src=&quot;https://pixar-community-production.s3-us-west-1.amazonaws.com/Cars_3/cars3-04.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;hero-caption dark text-center feature-copyright with-dropdown&quot;&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;hero-caption-copywrite&quot;&gt;Cars 3 ©Disney/Pixar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Realism and stylization happily coexist in the Cars 3 aesthetic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article-content-container medium&quot; readability=&quot;94.384187408492&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Current state-of-the-art images are a result of various leaps we have taken, like switching to physically-based rendering systems and improving on shading algorithms, for example, Marschner for hair illumination, or fully path traced subsurface scattering. Each of these steps improves upon the problem of bringing us within the grasp of photorealism, w&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;hich brings us to the new steps at Pixar, and a particularly important one for car rendering: &lt;strong&gt;keeping minute detail&lt;/strong&gt;, such as scratches, paint flakes, and other subtle effects, especially when an object is far away from the camera. This is exemplified in two of the latest research papers at Pixar: &lt;a href=&quot;http://graphics.pixar.com/library/PxrMaterialsCourse2017/paper.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Pixar's Foundation for Materials&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://graphics.pixar.com/library/BumpRoughness/paper.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Geometry into Shading&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most materials on a microscopic scale contain an incredible amount of surface variation and undulations. Even a smooth looking Hard Disk platter, one of the most reflective surfaces, second only to a mirror, contains a lot of variation when inspected in detail. It might not be visible in the image below...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Hard disk platters are some of the smoothest surfaces in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...but micro-detail on the surface of the platter is clear when using a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Magnetic_force_microscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;magnetic force microscope&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even though presenting microscopic closeups was not a part of the cinematic goals of &lt;em&gt;Cars 3&lt;/em&gt;, determining how they affect the overall look of surfaces was crucial to realism. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-container mb-5&quot; readability=&quot;5.8&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;expanded&quot; src=&quot;https://pixar-community-production.s3-us-west-1.amazonaws.com/Cars_3/hdd-magnetic-microscope.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;hero-caption text-center&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;hero-caption-copywrite&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/deed.en&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;CC BY-SA 3.0&lt;/a&gt; - Author: Januszartur&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Hard disk platters at micron scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such minute details were not taken into account until Cook and Torrance [1982] introduced the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.graphics.cornell.edu/~westin/consortium-home/cook-tog.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;microfacet shading model&lt;/a&gt;. The idea of the microfacet approach is to characterize the portion of a surface visible at a sample by a distribution of surface orientations, and use the distribution to calculate an appropriate specular reflectance. Meaning, thanks to the work by Cook and Torrance, the surface itself communicates minute changes in shading to the renderer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-container mb-5&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;expanded&quot; src=&quot;https://pixar-community-production.s3-us-west-1.amazonaws.com/Cars_3/macro-surface-vs-microfacet.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, problem solved, right? Not entirely. &lt;span&gt;Though these microfacet approaches take surface orientation into account and give us realistic results while shading,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;the problem is that they don’t take into account the geometric microfacet details contributed by&lt;span&gt; B&lt;/span&gt;ump&lt;span&gt; or Displacement mapping &lt;/span&gt;which can end up inside a single pixel and get filtered out.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-container mb-5&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;expanded&quot; src=&quot;https://pixar-community-production.s3-us-west-1.amazonaws.com/Cars_3/microfacet-surface-with-bump.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In practical terms, the relationship between the texel (texture pixel) and pixel is always changing, so filtering becomes an issue. Objects can have surface details through Displacements and Bump maps, but even with a microfacet shading model, when the object is zoomed far away a lot of these geometric details can end up inside a single pixel and thus the renderer discards this detail as meaningless. This is where Bump-Roughness steps in...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-container mb-5&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;expanded&quot; src=&quot;https://pixar-community-production.s3-us-west-1.amazonaws.com/Cars_3/macro-surface-with-bump-roughness.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, these geometries are acting as microfacets themselves and thus should be contributing to microfacet calculation. &lt;strong&gt;Bump-Roughness is a way to take these geometric details and convert them to roughness when filtering&lt;/strong&gt;. This avoids the dependence of brute force sampling to find these micro details, such as the example below. In this example, we're simulating a pathtracing sampling pattern with some red and green dots; as you can see, when we zoom out, it is possible that a scratch will not be sampled, forcing the user to increase sampling so that the renderer can find these small details. This can have a prohibitively long impact on render times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;columns&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-container mb-5&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;expanded&quot; src=&quot;https://pixar-community-production.s3-us-west-1.amazonaws.com/Cars_3/hdd-closeup-scratch-sampling.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;hero-caption text-center&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;hero-caption-copywrite&quot;&gt;© Disney/Pixar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article-content-container medium&quot; readability=&quot;76&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's look again at our hard disk platter example. As we can see from these two renders, Bumps are visible with traditional methods, but they're not acting like microfacets and contributing to the overall roughness of the hard disk platter. Bump-Roughness makes all this possible while improving the accuracy of the specular anisotropy, which leads to further realism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-container mb-5&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;product-card blog-post light with-toggle&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;blog-post-image-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;blog-post-image-container-inner&quot; data-twentytwenty=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://pixar-community-production.s3-us-west-1.amazonaws.com/Cars_3/hdd-bump-rough-off.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://pixar-community-production.s3-us-west-1.amazonaws.com/Cars_3/hdd-bump-rough-on.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Bump affects the anisotropy and roughness which leads to greater detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what does Bump-Roughness do from a practical standpoint?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hero characters in &lt;em&gt;Cars 3&lt;/em&gt;, such as Louise Nash (shaded by Yeon Kang), have an extensive wear of the clear coat layer across their paint job, this wear can create interesting patterns which break up the specular in interesting ways. Bump-Roughness helps us keep these micro details in medium and wide shots, as shown in this closeup example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only is this an improvement on technology, but it is a storytelling tool to communicate wear and aging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-container mb-5&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;product-card blog-post light with-toggle&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;blog-post-image-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;blog-post-image-container-inner&quot; data-twentytwenty=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://pixar-community-production.s3-us-west-1.amazonaws.com/Cars_3/louise-nash-micro-vs-wide.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://pixar-community-production.s3-us-west-1.amazonaws.com/Cars_3/louise-nash-micro-vs-closeup.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;No detail is lost with Bump Roughness. Check out the micro scratches!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Storytelling is always the focus at Pixar, so we sometimes needed to dial the effect down...&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;-Junyi Ling, Character Co-Supervisor Cars 3&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another great example is this work-in-progress test. The clear coat scratches are a bit more exaggerated than the film's final frames, in order to showcase the effect. In previous films, such micro detail would be lost at this distance or it would be expensive to render due to increased sampling or small shading rates necessary to find such details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Storytelling is always the focus at Pixar, so we sometimes needed to dial the effect down to make sure our focus was on the characters, not the technology,” says Junyi Ling, character co-supervisor on &lt;em&gt;Cars 3&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;parallax-window&quot; data-parallax=&quot;scroll&quot; data-image-src=&quot;https://pixar-community-production.s3-us-west-1.amazonaws.com/Cars_3/louise-nash-render-01.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;copyright&quot;&gt;© Disney/ Pixar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Louise Nash work-in-progress render.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article-content-container medium&quot; readability=&quot;41&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;mb-5&quot;&gt;Another great feature about Bump Roughness is its built-in LOD (Level of Detail), which gives artists the right amount of detail at every distance. &quot;The automatic LOD trickles down to other departments, for example, the lighting department no longer had to spend lots of time finding paint flakes with the right lighting angle,&quot; said George Nguyen, Character Shading Lead on &lt;em&gt;Cars 3&lt;/em&gt;. This is crucial with characters such as Jackson Storm, where a new lacquered paint job and visible paint flakes are part of his shiny &quot;new-guy&quot; persona. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-container mb-5&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;expanded&quot; src=&quot;https://pixar-community-production.s3-us-west-1.amazonaws.com/Cars_3/cars3-storm-01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;copyright&quot;&gt;© Disney/ Pixar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Paint flakes were part of Storm's aesthetic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article-content-container medium&quot; readability=&quot;45&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though Bump-Roughness is great for paint flakes and clear coat scratches, its usefulness doesn't stop there, it can be used to significantly improve render times by adding detail without having to increase sampling. Also, the tech benefits a wide range of materials, from carbon fiber to textiles as shown below...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-container mb-5&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;expanded&quot; src=&quot;https://pixar-community-production.s3-us-west-1.amazonaws.com/Cars_3/bump-roughness-materials-01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;copyright&quot;&gt;© Disney/ Pixar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Many surface types benefit from the added detail&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...but it's also incredibly useful in organic and heavily displaced surfaces because we can keep microfacet detail at more coarse sampling variance settings, as illustrated in this Lizard render.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-container&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;expanded&quot; src=&quot;https://pixar-community-production.s3-us-west-1.amazonaws.com/Cars_3/lizard-vs-sampling.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;copyright&quot;&gt;© Disney/Pixar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article-content-container medium&quot; readability=&quot;65.295791345584&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Added detail is gained out-of-the-box and the artist experience is seamless.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;-Junyi Ling, Character Co-Supervisor Cars 3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice all the lost displacement and bump detail when using 1 sample per-pixel. We need to use 100 samples per-pixel to bring back the original look-dev on a wide shot. Bump-Roughness, on the other hand, can use only 1 sample per-pixel while keeping the same visual appeal, as illustrated in the closeups below.  The best part is that &quot;the added detail is gained out-of-the-box and the artist experience is seamless because it all happens automatically when RenderMan converts the textures,&quot; said Junyi Ling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-container mb-5&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;product-card blog-post light with-toggle&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;blog-post-image-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;blog-post-image-container-inner&quot; data-twentytwenty=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://pixar-community-production.s3-us-west-1.amazonaws.com/Cars_3/Lizard-vs-100-samples.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://pixar-community-production.s3-us-west-1.amazonaws.com/Cars_3/Lizard-vs-1-sample.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;medium-8 columns&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;copyright&quot;&gt;© Disney/Pixar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Shading Rate at 0.01 vs Shading Rate at 1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-container mb-5&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;product-card blog-post light with-toggle&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;blog-post-image-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;blog-post-image-container-inner&quot; data-twentytwenty=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://pixar-community-production.s3-us-west-1.amazonaws.com/Cars_3/Lizard-vs-100-samples.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://pixar-community-production.s3-us-west-1.amazonaws.com/Cars_3/Lizard-vs-1-sample-plus-bump-roughness.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;medium-8 columns&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;copyright&quot;&gt;© Disney/Pixar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Shading Rate at 0.01 vs Shading Rate at 1 + Bump Roughness&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;inline-quote&quot; title=&quot;Since the beginnings at Pixar, we've tried to make skin look realistic...&quot;&gt;Another big success story for the technology has been skin. &quot;We've been using Bump-Roughness on human skin with great success,&quot; says Junyi Ling. &quot;Specular detail on pores and other previously lost detail is more vivid than ever thanks to Bump-Roughness. It's taking realism to a new level at Pixar,&quot; he added.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the image below we can see how Bump-Roughness is maintaining highlight information more accurately, which improves the specular breakup in pores, this is even more pronounced when zoomed out. &quot;Refining the specular model was crucial to revealing textural detail. We were able to light shots more accurately without resorting to tricks,&quot; said Jean-Claude Kalache, lighting DP at Pixar, &quot;before, we had to rely on manual light rigs to reveal minor detail at glancing angles,&quot; he added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-container&quot; readability=&quot;5.9586776859504&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;product-card blog-post light with-toggle&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;blog-post-image-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;blog-post-image-container-inner&quot; data-twentytwenty=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://pixar-community-production.s3-us-west-1.amazonaws.com/Cars_3/bump-roughness-humans-SR-1-off.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://pixar-community-production.s3-us-west-1.amazonaws.com/Cars_3/bump-roughness-humans-SR-1-on.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Skin also benefits from retaining subtle micro surface details&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article-content-container medium&quot; readability=&quot;44&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To see how much he could improve his renders with the new Bump Roughness tech, Jean-Claude Kalache did several lighting tests to match photography. &quot;Since the beginnings at Pixar, we've tried to make skin look realistic, and I thought Bump-Roughness could get us a step closer,&quot; said JC. &quot;Traditionally, at Pixar we approached our shading and lighting aesthetic with stylization as a priority, from which point we tried to make things as realistic as possible, but now, we've shifted to relying on light transport first and manipulating its stylistic possibilities,&quot; added Jean-Claude Kalache. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;article-content-container medium&quot; readability=&quot;48.288268156425&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;inline-quote&quot; title=&quot;We noticed a significant improvement on environment detail&quot;&gt;The sets department was also able to leverage the developments with Bump-Roughness. &quot;We noticed a significant improvement on environment detail, especially surfaces such as concrete and marble,&quot; said Junyi Ling. &quot;Typically with Marble, we try to avoid a glassy look, where the marble is too shiny. With Bump-Roughness we were able to capture all the subtle imperfections that give marble its most distinctive properties,&quot; said Junyi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The benefits don't stop there, as previously mentioned, &lt;em&gt;Cars 3&lt;/em&gt; saw huge improvements in render times. Bump-Roughness is over 35% faster than bump alone because RenderMan no longer has to calculate all 3 vectors, it now uses the newly supplied vector to decrease the shading context complexity. &quot;Using Bump-Roughness was fundamental to achieving this level of detail because &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Supersampling&quot;&gt;supersampling&lt;/a&gt; was never an option...render times would have been too long,&quot; said Junyi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-container&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;expanded&quot; src=&quot;https://pixar-community-production.s3-us-west-1.amazonaws.com/Cars_3/cars3-sunset-bridge.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;copyright&quot;&gt;© Disney/Pixar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article-content-container medium&quot; readability=&quot;81.665698880133&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“At the end of the day, technology has to help the visuals in a subtle and useful way.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;-Junyi Ling, Character Co-Supervisor Cars 3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall render times are also reduced when surfaces are shiny because the BXDF is importance sampled, this means the secondary ray is also importance sampled, and so on...this gave the &lt;em&gt;Cars 3&lt;/em&gt; team upwards of 30% reduction in render times in many scenes, and even though scenes with rough specular surfaces saw fewer render time reductions, there was never an increase in sampling times. &quot;Future feature films at Pixar are using Bump Roughness with great success, from skin shading to shading most arbitrary assets, the effects on detail preservation are the new status quo for quality,&quot; said George Nguyen. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This overall improvement in sampling variance has led Pixar to new heights of image quality when defining micro detail, in which quality doesn't have to compromise render times. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;inline-quote&quot; title=&quot;it's so fun to get carried away by the possibilities of visual complexity&quot;&gt;Looking ahead is always in Pixar's DNA and Christophe Hery, &lt;span&gt;Head of Pixar illumination group and research scientist, is already planning to expand RenderMan's Bump capabilities even further by implementing leading work in the field. &quot;There is more work to be done, in regards to Bump in general. The remaining big issue with Bump is that it is not reciprocal (at least as currently implemented) and we resort to alternative solutions (such as nudging the bumped normal to stay on the visible hemisphere, i.e. on the same side as the geometric normal), in order to keep a consistency with bi-directional transports. This might lead to dark non-lit areas on a piece of bumped geometry. To help avoid these issues, we are investigating several compelling ideas including Unity Labs' research on &lt;a href=&quot;https://labs.unity.com/article/microfacet-based-normal-mapping-robust-monte-carlo-path-tracing&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Microfacet-based Normal Mapping for Robust Monte Carlo Path Tracing&lt;/a&gt;,&quot; said Christophe. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-container&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;expanded&quot; src=&quot;https://pixar-community-production.s3-us-west-1.amazonaws.com/Cars_3/microfacetnormalmapping1.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;copyright&quot;&gt;© ACM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Vincent Schüßler, Eric Heitz, Johannes Hanika, and Carsten Dachsbacher. 2017. Microfacet-basedNormalMapping for RobustMonte Carlo Path Tracing. ACM Trans. Graph. 36, 6, Article 205 (November 2017), 12 pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photorealism is a never-ending journey, &quot;it's so fun to get carried away by the possibilities of visual complexity&quot; said Junyi, &quot;but at the end of the day, technology has to help the visuals in a subtle and useful way, not the other way around, the focus should always be the characters and their journey.&quot; This is the balance between technology and storytelling we strive for at Pixar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 05:24:23 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mariuz</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://renderman.pixar.com/stories/cars-3</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>