<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Two Photographers Unknowingly Shot the Same Millisecond in Time</title>
<link>https://petapixel.com/2018/03/07/two-photographers-unknowingly-shot-millisecond-time/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://petapixel.com/2018/03/07/two-photographers-unknowingly-shot-millisecond-time/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://petapixel.com/assets/uploads/2018/03/twophotossametimefeatt-800x420.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;420&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-305598&quot; srcset=&quot;https://petapixel.com/assets/uploads/2018/03/twophotossametimefeatt-800x420.jpg 800w, https://petapixel.com/assets/uploads/2018/03/twophotossametimefeatt-320x168.jpg 320w, https://petapixel.com/assets/uploads/2018/03/twophotossametimefeatt.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On March 3rd, during a large East Coast winter storm, I headed to the ocean to capture some wave action. My travels eventually took me to Great Island Commons in New Castle, New Hampshire, where Whaleback Lighthouse is prominently featured .8 miles offshore. I was hoping to capture big waves crashing around the lighthouse, and Mother Nature didn’t disappoint.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Great Island Common is a wide open park where people come to picnic during the summer and to watch the ocean during the winter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After arriving, I set up my tripod and my Canon 5D Mark IV with Sigma 150-600mm lens on a tripod and positioned myself just to the right of a tree in order to help reduce the pummeling Northerly winds. As many of you know it’s a challenge keeping 600mm stable in high winds, even on a tripod.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I set the camera up and then waited until I saw a wave starting to hit the lighthouse. I then kept firing until the splash ended, not knowing ahead of time the action of the wave. Most shots never panned out, but about three of them over the course of about 45 minutes were pretty decent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once back at home I culled through the images, and choose one to edit and upload to Instagram, replacing an earlier upload that was done in haste while still in the parking lot. When a local TV station shared the photo to their Facebook page (with permission) it started to receive a large amount of shares, comments, and likes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, there was one comment that mentioned that I had stolen the image from another New England photographer, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/ericgendronphotography/&quot; data-wpel-link=&quot;external&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;follow external noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Eric Gendon&lt;/a&gt;. After letting the commenter know that it was indeed my image and that I possess the original RAW file, I headed over to the other photographers page and was blown away. We had what looked like the exact same image, taken at the exact millisecond in time, from what looked like the same exact location and perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://petapixel.com/assets/uploads/2018/03/Full-Image_by_RonRisman-800x525.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;525&quot; class=&quot;size-large wp-image-305600&quot; srcset=&quot;https://petapixel.com/assets/uploads/2018/03/Full-Image_by_RonRisman-800x525.jpg 800w, https://petapixel.com/assets/uploads/2018/03/Full-Image_by_RonRisman-320x210.jpg 320w, https://petapixel.com/assets/uploads/2018/03/Full-Image_by_RonRisman-120x80.jpg 120w, https://petapixel.com/assets/uploads/2018/03/Full-Image_by_RonRisman.jpg 1200w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px&quot;/&gt;Photo by me, Ron Risman. &lt;img src=&quot;https://petapixel.com/assets/uploads/2018/03/Full-Image_by_Eric_Gendron-800x525.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;525&quot; class=&quot;size-large wp-image-305601&quot; srcset=&quot;https://petapixel.com/assets/uploads/2018/03/Full-Image_by_Eric_Gendron-800x525.jpg 800w, https://petapixel.com/assets/uploads/2018/03/Full-Image_by_Eric_Gendron-320x210.jpg 320w, https://petapixel.com/assets/uploads/2018/03/Full-Image_by_Eric_Gendron-120x80.jpg 120w, https://petapixel.com/assets/uploads/2018/03/Full-Image_by_Eric_Gendron.jpg 1200w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px&quot;/&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ericgendronphotography.com/&quot; data-wpel-link=&quot;external&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;follow external noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Eric Gendon&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from choices made in Lightroom, the photos at first glance look virtually identical aside from water in front and some of the white caps being in different position. Even then, the white caps were identical in size and shape – and I know those things are easily moved using the clone stamp in Photoshop – so I was concerned that maybe MY image was stolen and altered a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially, I only had access to his shared, low-resolution, image so I wasn’t able to make out some of the very fine details that ultimately helped to convince me that we both had originals. After overlaying and aligning the images in Photoshop I was blown away that the lighthouse and waves were carbon copies, almost to the pixel. As mentioned already, there were many differences in the foreground water and the white caps on the horizon, and it was these differences that held me back from claiming he stole my image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t until another local photographer started comparing my photo to a higher resolution version of Eric’s image that he noticed that the iron gating around the top of the lighthouse had slightly different spacing between the vertical bars compared to my image. This would indicate that the other photographer was likely standing just a little bit left of where I was standing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://petapixel.com/assets/uploads/2018/03/Photographers_Position-800x688.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;688&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-305602&quot; srcset=&quot;https://petapixel.com/assets/uploads/2018/03/Photographers_Position-800x688.jpg 800w, https://petapixel.com/assets/uploads/2018/03/Photographers_Position-320x275.jpg 320w, https://petapixel.com/assets/uploads/2018/03/Photographers_Position.jpg 1125w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the 60D uses an APS-C sensor he would have also likely been back a little further to compensate for the 1.6x “zoom” / crop of the sensor or using a shorter focal length to compensate. This would also explain the white caps being in different positions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://petapixel.com/assets/uploads/2018/03/Compare_with_circles.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;507&quot; height=&quot;306&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-305603&quot; srcset=&quot;https://petapixel.com/assets/uploads/2018/03/Compare_with_circles.jpg 507w, https://petapixel.com/assets/uploads/2018/03/Compare_with_circles-320x193.jpg 320w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 507px) 100vw, 507px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the fact that the lighthouse doesn’t really show any rotational changes and the crashing wave is an exact match – makes this all the more remarkable that these were captured randomly from two different photographers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next morning Eric woke up to a flood of messages from me as well as other photographers, and immediately contacted me to share his EXIF data, and to agree that it was astounding that we both captured the exact same image of water motion at the exact millisecond in time. What makes this even more amazing is that this wasn’t a planned event (aka. Sporting event, shuttle launch, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also didn’t know Eric; we each chose this location randomly; we both shot with different cameras (60D and 5D Mark IV) with different size sensors; the 60D has a burst mode of 5.3fps, the 5DMKIV is 7fps; we both used a 600mm focal length; our exposures and depth-of-field were almost the same as well (f/8 aperture, ISO 400, 1/1600th shutter vs. f/8, ISO 320, 1/1000th shutter); and ultimately we both selected the same photo from that day to promote. Come to find out we were only 28 meters away from each other. He was hunkered down under a picnic enclosure to help block some of the wind and I was up against a tree to help reduce the wind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did a Google search to see how often this happens and could only find one article from 2011 where two photographers filming a surf competition on Huntington Beach ended up catching a virtually identical image of a surfer and its wave action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you shoot water in burst mode you know how different each exposure is even when the difference in time is just 1/7th of a second between shots. And I have been leading night-sky photography workshops for five years and have had well over 200 photographers who are often aiming at the same subject, shooting with similar cameras and lenses, and capturing at the same moment in time, even doing continuous shooting for time lapse, and until now I have never seen two images that were so close as to be virtual clones of each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fluid-iframe&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/258671812&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this is a rare occurrence, I believe that with cameras getting faster and photographers taking more time to prepare for their shots, I have to imagine that these situations will happen more frequently. It happens every day with stationary or slow motion objects (buildings, sun/moon rise) but almost never with water movement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About the author&lt;/strong&gt;: Ron Risman is a timelapse photographer and owner of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.timelapseworkshops.com/&quot; data-wpel-link=&quot;external&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;follow external noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Timelapse Workshops&lt;/a&gt;. The opinions expressed in this article are solely those of the author. You can find more of his work on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/ron.risman&quot; data-wpel-link=&quot;external&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;follow external noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/Timeographer/&quot; data-wpel-link=&quot;external&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;follow external noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 05:01:55 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>shawndumas</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>How Two Photographers Unknowingly Shot the Same Millisecond in Time</og:title>
<og:description>On March 3rd, during a large East Coast winter storm, I headed to the ocean to capture some wave action. My travels eventually took me to Great Island Comm</og:description>
<og:url>https://petapixel.com/2018/03/07/two-photographers-unknowingly-shot-millisecond-time/</og:url>
<og:image>https://petapixel.com/assets/uploads/2018/03/twophotossametimefeatt.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://petapixel.com/2018/03/07/two-photographers-unknowingly-shot-millisecond-time/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Some terrible personal news</title>
<link>https://www.mattcutts.com/blog/cindy-cutts/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.mattcutts.com/blog/cindy-cutts/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Cindy Cutts, my wife and best friend, passed away earlier this week. While I was traveling for work recently, Cindy went to visit her family in Omaha, Nebraska. On Sunday, while enjoying time with family, Cindy started having trouble breathing. Her family quickly called 911 and paramedics took Cindy to the hospital, but Cindy lost and never regained consciousness. She passed away on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cindy didn’t want any callouts on my blog, so I always just referred to her as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=site%3Amattcutts.com+%22my+wife%22&quot;&gt;my wife&lt;/a&gt;. But I’d like to tell you something about her. She loved her family and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mattcutts.com/blog/why-do-i-blog/&quot;&gt;her&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mattcutts.com/blog/meet-my-other-cat-ozzie/&quot;&gt;cats&lt;/a&gt;, Emmy and Ozzie. She danced in the Bay Area with a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bigmoves.org/&quot;&gt;fantastic troop of kick-ass women&lt;/a&gt; for years. She ran a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sanjosefit.com/&quot;&gt;half-marathon once&lt;/a&gt; and then decided that she never needed to do that again. She sang in show choir in high school and could still rock a karaoke room with an Adele song. She wrestled with anxiety and depression at times, as so many people do. We should all talk about mental health more to lessen the stigma for other people who think they’re alone when they’re not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cindy enjoyed falling asleep to &lt;em&gt;Parks and Rec&lt;/em&gt;. She liked re-reading William Gibson’s novel &lt;em&gt;Pattern Recognition&lt;/em&gt;. Cindy made quilts for her family and crocheted scarves. She kept me healthy and on track and moving in the right direction, and I paid her back with occasional head rubs. Cindy was whip smart, with a particular gift with languages, from French to Chinese. I tackled small details like paperwork and license plates and paying bills, but she was the one who looked at the big picture. Cindy was the person who said “Let’s go try this Google thing for a while.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cindy and I knew each other for 23 years and we were married for 18 years, which is no small thing. I’m unmanned and unmoored without her. I’m just going to tackle the details in front of me and count on time and family and friends to pull me back on course at some point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anyone wants to send flowers, the service is at Heafey-Hoffmann-Dworak-Cutler at 7805 W Center Rd in Omaha on Saturday, March 10th, starting at 3pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the people who didn’t get to meet her, Cindy looked like a movie star:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.mattcutts.com/images/cindy-movie-star.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cindy movie star&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She loved hanging with her family:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.mattcutts.com/images/cindy-family.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cindy with her family&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She had the best smile and amazing green eyes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.mattcutts.com/images/cindy-smile.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cindy smiling&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And her cat Ozzie adored her as much as I did:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.mattcutts.com/images/cindy-ozzie.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cindy and Ozzie&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please give your friends or family a hug for me. We never know how much time we have with someone, and sometimes it’s all too short.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 01:04:16 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rpledge</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Some terrible personal news</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.mattcutts.com/blog/cindy-cutts/</og:url>
<og:description>Cindy Cutts, my wife and best friend, passed away earlier this week. While I was traveling for work recently, Cindy went to visit her family in Omaha, Nebraska. On Sunday, while enjoying time with …</og:description>
<og:image>https://s0.wp.com/i/blank.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.mattcutts.com/blog/cindy-cutts/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>All of Oculus’s Rift headsets have stopped working due to an expired certificate</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/07/all-of-oculuss-rift-headsets-have-stopped-working-due-to-an-expired-certificate/?ncid=rss</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/07/all-of-oculuss-rift-headsets-have-stopped-working-due-to-an-expired-certificate/?ncid=rss</guid>
<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/10/oculus-rift-price.png?w=738&quot; class=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot;&gt;Someone at Oculus screwed up pretty badly today: An expired certificate appears to have soft-bricked all of the company’s Rift VR headsets, with users still unable to fire up software on the devices and no word of an incoming fix from the company yet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Issues were first reported several hours ago on &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/oculus/comments/82nuzi/cant_reach_oculus_runtime_service/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Reddit&lt;/a&gt;, where a post on the topic has already garnered hundreds of comments. The problem &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.neowin.net/news/every-oculus-rift-vr-headset-bricked-due-to-expired-certificate?utm_source=dlvr.it&amp;amp;utm_medium=twitter&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;seems to have resulted&lt;/a&gt; from Oculus failing to update an expired certificate with the update, which is now leaving users with an error message saying that the system “Can’t reach Oculus Runtime Service.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; The company has confirmed that the problem is a result of “an issue with our software certification…”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users are not happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The embarrassing issue has left the company’s flagship device unusable. This comes as the company continues to deliver major software updates that it announced at its most recent developer conference. This issue is a bummer to gamers who aren’t going to get to play the titles they’ve purchased until the issue is resolved — but it’s a much less forgivable issue for commercial users who use the headset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oculus co-founder Nate Mitchell confirmed on Twitter that there was an issue affecting the company’s Rift headset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-twitter&quot; readability=&quot;7.2624113475177&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; align=&quot;center&quot; data-width=&quot;500&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot; readability=&quot;8.1702127659574&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;We're aware of an issue affecting Rift on PC, and we're working on resolving now. Stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Nate Mitchell (@natemitchell) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/natemitchell/status/971428374982705152?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;March 7, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve reached out to Oculus for more details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some users are reporting that they’ve been able to get things back up-and-running by messing with their system clock, but this is generally a bad solution and can often screw up a lot of things, so it’s probably best to wait for a patch from Oculus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An Oculus staffer on the company’s forums further confirmed the issues, apologizing on behalf of the company. “Our teams apologize for any inconvenience this may be causing you and appreciate your patience while we work on a resolution. We’ll share more updates here as we have them. Thanks.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 00:23:42 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>twinkletwinkle</dc:creator>
<og:title>All of Oculus’s Rift headsets have stopped working due to an expired certificate</og:title>
<og:description>Someone at Oculus screwed up pretty badly today: An expired certificate appears to have soft-bricked all of the company's Rift VR headsets, with users still..</og:description>
<og:image>https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/10/oculus-rift-price.png</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2018/03/07/all-of-oculuss-rift-headsets-have-stopped-working-due-to-an-expired-certificate/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/07/all-of-oculuss-rift-headsets-have-stopped-working-due-to-an-expired-certificate/?ncid=rss</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Tell HN: Slack decides to close down IRC and XMPP gateways</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16539857</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16539857</guid>
<description>&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.55737704918033&quot;&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=&quot;#FF6600&quot;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.8448074679113&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;fatitem&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.6656942823804&quot;&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing&quot; id=&quot;16539857&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;title&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16539857&quot; class=&quot;storylink&quot;&gt;Tell HN: Slack decides to close down IRC and XMPP gateways&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.73170731707317&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;subtext&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;score&quot; id=&quot;score_16539857&quot;&gt;799 points&lt;/span&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/user?id=elektron&quot; class=&quot;hnuser&quot;&gt;elektron&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;age&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16539857&quot;&gt;10 hours ago&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span id=&quot;unv_16539857&quot;/&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/hide?id=16539857&amp;amp;goto=item%3Fid%3D16539857&quot;&gt;hide&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://hn.algolia.com/?query=Tell%20HN%3A%20Slack%20decides%20to%20close%20down%20IRC%20and%20XMPP%20gateways&amp;amp;sort=byDate&amp;amp;dateRange=all&amp;amp;type=story&amp;amp;storyText=false&amp;amp;prefix&amp;amp;page=0&quot; class=&quot;hnpast&quot;&gt;past&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=Tell%20HN%3A%20Slack%20decides%20to%20close%20down%20IRC%20and%20XMPP%20gateways&quot;&gt;web&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/fave?id=16539857&amp;amp;auth=c33ea2865cd55911df7158412e8dd973e76c0525&quot;&gt;favorite&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16539857&quot;&gt;388 comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;19.5&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;24&quot;&gt;11:14 -!- Message of the day
&lt;p&gt;Hello! We have news to share — we've decided it's time to close down the IRC and XMPP gateways to Slack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After years of evolving, Slack is at the point where the gateways can no longer handle all of our features or security needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you've been using the gateways for accessibility reasons, we're glad to let you know that it's now possible to navigate Slack by keyboard and with a screen reader — and we're making more improvements on a continual basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, we know this is a disruptive change, and we want to help with this transition in any way we can. Please follow this link to learn more about the upcoming changes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;slack.com/account/gateways&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11:14 -!- End of MOTD command&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.73972602739726&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ycombinator.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Applications are open for YC Summer 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;yclinks&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsguidelines.html&quot;&gt;Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsfaq.html&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Support&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/HackerNews/API&quot;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/security.html&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/lists&quot;&gt;Lists&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/bookmarklet.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Bookmarklet&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/legal/&quot;&gt;Legal&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Apply to YC&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Contact&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 21:01:51 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>elektron</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16539857</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Facebook Really Is Spying on You, Just Not Through Your Phone&amp;#039;s Mic</title>
<link>https://www.wsj.com/articles/facebook-really-is-spying-on-you-just-not-through-your-phones-mic-1520448644</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.wsj.com/articles/facebook-really-is-spying-on-you-just-not-through-your-phones-mic-1520448644</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt; “Can I try the Cole Haans in a size 8?”  Later that night on Facebook: An advertisement for Cole Haan pumps. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;OK, maybe a coincidence.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; “What’s the best high-tech scale?” my wife asks aloud.  Five minutes later on Instagram: An ad for scales. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Wait,...
  &lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 20:12:40 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>asclepi</dc:creator>
<og:title>Facebook Really Is Spying on You, Just Not Through Your Phone’s Mic</og:title>
<og:description>Facebook is now so good at watching what we do online—and even offline, wandering around the physical world—it doesn’t need to hear us to know what we like. Here are some ways to limit the amount of data Facebook and advertisers are collecting about you.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.wsj.com/articles/facebook-really-is-spying-on-you-just-not-through-your-phones-mic-1520448644</og:url>
<og:image>https://si.wsj.net/public/resources/images/BN-XT668_STERN0_SOC_20180307132149.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.wsj.com/articles/facebook-really-is-spying-on-you-just-not-through-your-phones-mic-1520448644</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Previewing Android P</title>
<link>http://android-developers.googleblog.com/2018/03/previewing-android-p.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://android-developers.googleblog.com/2018/03/previewing-android-p.html</guid>
<description></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 18:34:39 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ingve</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Previewing Android P</og:title>
<og:url>https://android-developers.googleblog.com/2018/03/previewing-android-p.html</og:url>
<og:description>The latest Android and Google Play news and tips for app and game developers.</og:description>
<og:image>https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-yjp7X2zK0S8/Wp2Atb3uzgI/AAAAAAAAFHY/C89cA9g_K9gMAAyGw3Q9R9DbfXWqQYcLQCLcBGAs/w1200-h630-p-k-no-nu/image7.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://android-developers.googleblog.com/2018/03/previewing-android-p.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The New Wave of Indian Type</title>
<link>https://design.google/library/new-wave-indian-type-design/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://design.google/library/new-wave-indian-type-design/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;As mobile access grows and more people around the world start using the internet—a billion people are expected to come online over the next few years in emerging markets alone—it’s also necessary to elevate the quality and range of digital typefaces available in different writing systems. This challenge is especially striking in India, a country that recognizes 23 official languages, but counted almost 1600 (including dialects) in their last census. Some of these languages and their scripts have descended from ancient Brahmi, others are based in Arabic, while the ongoing use of English, a language that's reach and influence has grown considerably since India's independence from Britain in 1947, means that Latin letters are also a common sight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bombay-based type designer Girish Dalvi has a gift for conveying the sheer scale of this typographic challenge. A professor of design at the Indian Institute of Technology and a co-founder of the Ek Type collective, Dalvi describes the immensity of Indian culture and language with a quote from the Argentine writer Jorge Luis Borges, “India is larger than the world.” Dalvi allows a beat to pass before adding that Borges did, in fact, have a good rationale for this saying. “India is an extremely diverse country,” says Dalvi. “The language and script change every five hundred miles, and so does Indian design.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keeping pace with the subcontinent’s linguistic diversity is challenging enough in print, but the relatively small number of digital fonts available for Indic languages reveals a striking disparity. Even the most widely used Indian script, Devanagari, has far fewer typographic options compared to the superabundance of Latin fonts. Some scripts like Bengali, Tamil, Urdu, and Tibetan have even fewer fonts available. But the balance is beginning to shift as a cohort of Indian type designers develop new digital fonts, and the movement is still growing in part because many of these designers release their designs with open source licenses. The code is then readily available for others to experiment and develop their own contributions, improving the quality and variety of typography across India’s many writing systems.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 17:24:13 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>carbolite103</dc:creator>
<og:description>Studying the open source, collaborative work of Indian typographers, as a model for global font design</og:description>
<og:title>The New Wave of Indian Type</og:title>
<og:image>https://storage.googleapis.com/gd-wagtail-prod-assets/original_images/the_new_wave_of_open_source_indian_type_design_share.png</og:image>
<og:url>https://design.google/library/new-wave-indian-type-design/</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://design.google/library/new-wave-indian-type-design/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Statement on Potentially Unlawful Online Platforms for Trading Digital Assets</title>
<link>https://www.sec.gov/news/public-statement/enforcement-tm-statement-potentially-unlawful-online-platforms-trading</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.sec.gov/news/public-statement/enforcement-tm-statement-potentially-unlawful-online-platforms-trading</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;31&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field_speaker_name_and_title&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Divisions of Enforcement and Trading and Markets&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;133.49011317&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Online trading platforms have become a popular way investors can buy and sell digital assets, including coins and tokens offered and sold in so-called Initial Coin Offerings (&quot;ICOs&quot;).  The platforms often claim to give investors the ability to quickly buy and sell digital assets.  Many of these platforms bring buyers and sellers together in one place and offer investors access to automated systems that display priced orders, execute trades, and provide transaction data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A number of these platforms provide a mechanism for trading assets that meet the definition of a &quot;security&quot; under the federal securities laws.  If a platform offers trading of digital assets that are securities and operates as an &quot;exchange,&quot; as defined by the federal securities laws, then the platform must register with the SEC as a national securities exchange or be exempt from registration.  The federal regulatory framework governing registered national securities exchanges and exempt markets is designed to protect investors and prevent against fraudulent and manipulative trading practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Considerations for Investors Using Online Trading Platforms&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get the protections offered by the federal securities laws and SEC oversight when trading digital assets that are securities, investors should use a platform or entity registered with the SEC, such as a national securities exchange, alternative trading system (&quot;ATS&quot;), or broker-dealer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SEC staff has concerns that many online trading platforms appear to investors as SEC-registered and regulated marketplaces when they are not.  Many platforms refer to themselves as &quot;exchanges,&quot; which can give the misimpression to investors that they are regulated or meet the regulatory standards of a national securities exchange.  Although some of these platforms claim to use strict standards to pick only high-quality digital assets to trade, the SEC does not review these standards or the digital assets that the platforms select, and the so-called standards should not be equated to the listing standards of national securities exchanges.  Likewise, the SEC does not review the trading protocols used by these platforms, which determine how orders interact and execute, and access to a platform's trading services may not be the same for all users.  Again, investors should not assume the trading protocols meet the standards of an SEC-registered national securities exchange.  Lastly, many of these platforms give the impression that they perform exchange-like functions by offering order books with updated bid and ask pricing and data about executions on the system, but there is no reason to believe that such information has the same integrity as that provided by national securities exchanges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In light of the foregoing, here are some questions investors should ask before they decide to trade digital assets on an online trading platform: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Do you trade securities on this platform?  If so, is the platform registered as a national securities exchange (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sec.gov/fast-answers/divisionsmarketregmrexchangesshtml.html&quot;&gt;see our link to the list below&lt;/a&gt;)?   &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does the platform operate as an ATS?  If so, is the ATS registered as a broker-dealer and has it filed a Form ATS with the SEC (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sec.gov/foia/docs/atslist.htm&quot;&gt;see our link to the list below&lt;/a&gt;)? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is there information in &lt;a href=&quot;https://brokercheck.finra.org/&quot;&gt;FINRA's BrokerCheck&lt;/a&gt;® about any individuals or firms operating the platform?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does the platform select digital assets for trading? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who can trade on the platform?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the trading protocols?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How are prices set on the platform?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are platform users treated equally? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the platform's fees?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does the platform safeguard users' trading and personally identifying information? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the platform's protections against cybersecurity threats, such as hacking or intrusions?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What other services does the platform provide?  Is the platform registered with the SEC for these services?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does the platform hold users' assets?  If so, how are these assets safeguarded?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Resources for Investors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.investor.gov/additional-resources/specialized-resources/spotlight-initial-coin-offerings-digital-assets&quot;&gt;Investor.gov Spotlight on Initial Coin Offerings and Digital Assets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sec.gov/news/public-statement/statement-clayton-2017-12-11&quot;&gt;Chairman Jay Clayton Statement on Cryptocurrencies and Initial Coin Offerings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sec.gov/news/testimony/testimony-virtual-currencies-oversight-role-us-securities-and-exchange-commission&quot;&gt;Chairman Jay Clayton's Testimony on Virtual Currencies: The Roles of the SEC and CFTC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sec.gov/litigation/investreport/34-81207.pdf&quot;&gt;Report of Investigation Pursuant to Section 21(a) of the Securities and Exchange Act of 1934:  The DAO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investors can find a list of SEC-registered national securities exchanges here:  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sec.gov/fast-answers/divisionsmarketregmrexchangesshtml.html&quot;&gt;List of Active National Securities Exchanges&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investors can find a list of ATSs that have filed a Form ATS with the SEC here:  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sec.gov/foia/docs/atslist.htm&quot;&gt;List of Active Alternative Trading Systems&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Considerations for Market Participants Operating Online Trading Platforms&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A platform that trades securities and operates as an &quot;exchange,&quot; as defined by the federal securities laws, must register as a national securities exchange or operate under an exemption from registration, such as the exemption provided for ATSs under SEC Regulation ATS.  An SEC-registered national securities exchange must, among other things, have rules designed to prevent fraudulent and manipulative acts and practices.  Additionally, as a self-regulatory organization (&quot;SRO&quot;), an SEC-registered national securities exchange must have rules and procedures governing the discipline of its members and persons associated with its members, and enforce compliance by its members and persons associated with its members with the federal securities laws and the rules of the exchange.  Further, a national securities exchange must itself comply with the federal securities laws and must file its rules with the Commission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An entity seeking to operate as an ATS is also subject to regulatory requirements, including registering with the SEC as a broker-dealer and becoming a member of an SRO.  Registration as a broker-dealer subjects the ATS to a host of regulatory requirements, such as the requirement to have reasonable policies and procedures to prevent the misuse of material non-public information, books and records requirements, and financial responsibility rules, including, as applicable, requirements concerning the safeguarding and custody of customer funds and securities.  The overlay of SRO membership imposes further regulatory requirements and oversight.  An ATS must comply with the federal securities laws and its SRO's rules, and file a Form ATS with the SEC. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some online trading platforms may not meet the definition of an exchange under the federal securities laws, but directly or indirectly offer trading or other services related to digital assets that are securities.  For example, some platforms offer digital wallet services (to hold or store digital assets) or transact in digital assets that are securities.  These and other services offered by platforms may trigger other registration requirements under the federal securities laws, including broker-dealer, transfer agent, or clearing agency registration, among other things.  In addition, a platform that offers digital assets that are securities may be participating in the unregistered offer and sale of securities if those securities are not registered or exempt from registration. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In advancing the SEC's mission to protect investors, the SEC staff will continue to focus on platforms that offer trading of digital assets and their compliance with the federal securities laws. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Consultation with Securities Counsel and the SEC Staff&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We encourage market participants who are employing new technologies to develop trading platforms to consult with legal counsel to aid in their analysis of federal securities law issues and to contact SEC staff, as needed, for assistance in analyzing the application of the federal securities laws.In particular, staff providing assistance on these matters can be reached at FinTech@sec.gov.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Resources for Market Participants&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gpo.gov/fdsys/pkg/FR-1998-12-22/pdf/98-33299.pdf&quot;&gt;Regulation of Exchanges and Alternative Trading Systems&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Select Commission Enforcement Actions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sec.gov/news/press-release/2018-23&quot;&gt;SEC v. Jon E. Montroll and Bitfunder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sec.gov/news/press-release/2014-273&quot;&gt;In re BTC Trading, Corp. and Ethan Burnside.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sec.gov/news/press-release/2017-185-0&quot;&gt;SEC v. REcoin Group Foundation, LLC et al.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sec.gov/news/press-release/2017-219&quot;&gt;SEC v. PlexCorps et al.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sec.gov/news/press-release/2017-227&quot;&gt;In re Munchee, Inc.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sec.gov/news/press-release/2018-8&quot;&gt;SEC v. AriseBank et al.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 16:47:02 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>matthewbauer</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.sec.gov/news/public-statement/enforcement-tm-statement-potentially-unlawful-online-platforms-trading</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Economist behind Uber study admits error, adjusts numbers</title>
<link>https://twitter.com/StephenZoepf/status/970754550968676352/photo/1?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&amp;ref_url=https:%2F%2Fwww.recode.net%2F2018%2F3%2F3%2F17074782%2Fuber-mit-study-less-than-4-hour-flawed</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://twitter.com/StephenZoepf/status/970754550968676352/photo/1?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.recode.net%2F2018%2F3%2F3%2F17074782%2Fuber-mit-study-less-than-4-hour-flawed</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I did 100+ rides and tracked *all* my hours. Uber tells you the hours *app is on*, which eliminates time getting to/from market, deadheading long fares, cleaning, maintenance, refueling, breaks, etc. I figured $19/hr gross but only ~1/2 that net in SF/Oak: &amp;lt;min wage.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 15:53:35 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>resalisbury</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mobile.twitter.com/StephenZoepf/status/970754550968676352/photo/1</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Research suggests some potential benefits to being a loner</title>
<link>http://www.bbc.com/future/story/20180228-there-are-benefits-to-being-antisocial-or-a-loner</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.bbc.com/future/story/20180228-there-are-benefits-to-being-antisocial-or-a-loner</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I can be a reluctant socialiser. I’m sometimes secretly pleased &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecut.com/2017/11/why-canceling-plans-is-so-satisfying.html&quot;&gt;when social plans are called off&lt;/a&gt;. I get restless a few hours into a hangout. I even once went on a free 10-day silent meditation retreat – not for the meditation, but for the silence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So I can relate to author Anneli Rufus, who recounted in Party of One: The Loners’ Manifesto:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“When parents on TV shows punished their kids by ordering them to go to their rooms, I was confused. I loved my room. Being there behind a locked door was a treat. To me a punishment was being ordered to play Yahtzee with my cousin Louis.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You might also like:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;• &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.com/future/story/20170518-the-everyday-habits-that-reveal-our-personalities&quot;&gt;The everyday habits that reveal our personalities&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt;• &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.com/future/story/20180213-five-myths-about-loneliness&quot;&gt;Five myths about loneliness &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;• &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.com/future/story/20180219-toxic-perfectionism-is-on-the-rise&quot;&gt;The dangerous downsides of perfectionism&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Asocial tendencies like these are often far from ideal. Abundant research shows the harms of social isolation, considered a serious public health problem in countries that have rapidly ageing populations (though talk of a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.com/future/story/20180213-five-myths-about-loneliness&quot;&gt;‘loneliness epidemic’&lt;/a&gt; may be overblown). In the UK, the Royal College of General Practitioners says that loneliness has the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/society/2017/oct/12/loneliness-as-bad-for-health-as-long-term-illness-says-gps-chief&quot;&gt;same risk level for premature death&lt;/a&gt; as diabetes. Strong social connections are important for &lt;a href=&quot;https://greatergood.berkeley.edu/article/item/how_social_connections_keep_seniors_healthy#gsc.tab=0&quot;&gt;cognitive functioning&lt;/a&gt;, motor function and a smoothly running immune system.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is especially clear from cases of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.com/future/story/20140514-how-extreme-isolation-warps-minds&quot;&gt;extreme social isolation&lt;/a&gt;. Examples of people kept in captivity, children kept isolated in abusive orphanages, and prisoners kept in solitary confinement all show how prolonged solitude can lead to hallucinations and other forms of mental instability.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But these are severe and involuntary cases of aloneness. For those of us who just prefer plenty of alone time, emerging research suggests some good news: there are upsides to being reclusive – for both our work lives and our emotional well-being.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creative space&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One key benefit is improved creativity. Gregory Feist, who focuses on the psychology of creativity at California’s San Jose State University, has defined creativity as thinking or activity with &lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.co.uk/books?hl=en&amp;amp;lr=&amp;amp;id=1EBT3Qj5L5EC&amp;amp;oi=fnd&amp;amp;pg=PA113&amp;amp;dq=gregory+feist&amp;amp;ots=7LcrBBYETm&amp;amp;sig=EpMJ9fPRAmcoKAWwGapzB_VC8ZQ#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=gregory%20feist&amp;amp;f=false&quot;&gt;two key elements&lt;/a&gt;: originality and usefulness. He has found that personality traits commonly associated with creativity are openness (receptiveness to new thoughts and experiences), self-efficacy (confidence), and autonomy (independence) – which may include “a lack of concern for social norms” and “a preference for being alone”. In fact, Feist’s research on both artists and scientists shows that one of the most prominent features of creative folks is their lesser interest in socialising.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One reason for this is that such people are likely to spend sustained time alone working on their craft. Plus, Feist says, many artists “are trying to make sense of their internal world and a lot of internal personal experiences that they’re trying to give expression to and meaning to through their art.” Solitude allows for the reflection and observation necessary for that creative process.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A recent vindication of these ideas came from University at Buffalo psychologist Julie Bowker, who researches social withdrawal. Social withdrawal usually is categorised into three types: shyness caused by fear or anxiety; avoidance, from a dislike of socialising; and unsociability, from a preference for solitude.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0191886917304920&quot;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; by Bowker and her colleagues was the first to show that a type of social withdrawal could have a positive effect – they found that creativity was linked specifically to unsociability. They also found that unsociability had no correlation with aggression (shyness and avoidance did).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This was significant because while previous research had suggested that unsociability might be harmless, Bowker and colleagues’ paper showed that it could actually be beneficial. Unsociable people are likely to be “having just enough interaction,” Bowker says. “They have a preference for being alone, but they also don’t mind being with others.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is gender and cultural variation, of course. For instance, some research suggests that &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/sode.12181/abstract&quot;&gt;unsociable children in China&lt;/a&gt; have more interpersonal and academic problems than unsociable kids in the West. Bowker says that these differences are narrowing as the world becomes more globalised.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Still, it turns out that solitude is important for more than creativity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inward focus&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s commonly believed that leaders need to be gregarious. But this depends – among other things, on the personalities of their employees. One &lt;a href=&quot;https://hbr.org/2010/12/the-hidden-advantages-of-quiet-bosses&quot;&gt;2011 study&lt;/a&gt; showed that in branches of a pizza chain where employees were more passive, extroverted bosses were associated with higher profits. But in branches where employees were more proactive, introverted leaders were more effective. One reason for this is that introverted people are less likely to feel threatened by strong personalities and suggestions. They’re also &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.com/capital/story/20150819-is-there-room-for-introverts-at-the-top&quot;&gt;more likely to listen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since ancient times, meanwhile, people have been aware of a link between isolation and mental focus. After all, cultures with traditions of religious hermits believe that solitude is important for enlightenment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recent research has given us a better understanding of why. One benefit of unsociability is the brain’s state of active mental rest, which goes hand-in-hand with the stillness of being alone. When another person is present, your brain &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.boston.com/bostonglobe/ideas/articles/2011/03/06/the_power_of_lonely/?page=3&quot;&gt;can’t help but pay some attention&lt;/a&gt;. This can be a positive distraction. But it’s still a distraction.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Daydreaming in the absence of such distractions activates the brain’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.com/capital/story/20171204-the-compelling-case-for-working-a-lot-less&quot;&gt;default-mode networ&lt;/a&gt;k. Among other functions, this network helps to consolidate memory and understand others’ emotions. Giving free rein to a wandering mind not only helps with focus in the long term but strengthens your sense of both yourself and others. Paradoxically, therefore, periods of solitude actually help when it comes time to socialise once more. And the occasional absence of focus ultimately helps concentration in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A more recent proponent of thoughtful and productive solitude is Susan Cain, author of Quiet: The Power of Introverts in a World That Can’t Stop Talking and founder of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quietrev.com/&quot;&gt;Quiet Revolution&lt;/a&gt;, a company that promotes quiet and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.com/capital/story/20170331-how-do-younetworkin-anation-of-introverts&quot;&gt;introvert-friendly workplaces&lt;/a&gt;. “These days, we tend to believe that creativity emerges from a decidedly gregarious process, but in fact it requires sustained attention and deep focus,” she says. “Also, humans are such porous, social beings that when we surround ourselves with others, we automatically take in their opinions and aesthetics. To truly chart our own path or vision, we have to be willing to sequester ourselves, at least for some period of time.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hermit health&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Still, the line between useful solitude and dangerous isolation can be blurry. “Almost anything can be adaptive and maladaptive, depending on how extreme they get,” Feist says. A disorder has to do with dysfunction. If someone stops caring about people and cuts off all contact, this could point to a pathological neglect of social relations. But creative unsociability is a far cry from this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In fact, Feist says, “there’s a real danger with people who are never alone.” It’s hard to be introspective, self-aware, and fully relaxed unless you have occasional solitude. In addition, introverts tend to have fewer but stronger friendships – which has been linked to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.independent.co.uk/voices/comment/having-fewer-friends-is-better-for-you-and-that-s-great-news-for-introverts-like-me-10459033.html&quot;&gt;greater happiness&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As with many things, quality reigns over quantity. Nurturing a few solid relationships without feeling the need to constantly populate your life with chattering voices ultimately may be better for you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thus, if your personality tends toward unsociability, you shouldn’t feel the need to change. Of course, that comes with caveats. But as long as you have regular social contact, you are choosing solitude rather than being forced into it, you have at least a few good friends and your solitude is good for your well-being or productivity, there’s no point agonising over how to fit a square personality into a round hole.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So feel free to de-clutter your social calendar. It’s psychologist-approved.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Join 800,000+ Future fans by liking us on &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/BBCFuture&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Facebook&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, or follow us on &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/bbc_future&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Twitter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you liked this story, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pages.emails.bbc.com/subscribe/?ocid=fut.bbc.email.we.email-signup&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;sign up for the weekly bbc.com features newsletter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, called “If You Only Read 6 Things This Week”. A handpicked selection of stories from BBC Future, Earth, Culture, Capital, and Travel, delivered to your inbox every Friday.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                        </description>
<pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 15:17:03 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>raphar</dc:creator>
<og:title>Why being a loner may be good for your health</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>http://www.bbc.com/future/story/20180228-there-are-benefits-to-being-antisocial-or-a-loner</og:url>
<og:description>We tend to decry being alone. But emerging research suggests some potential benefits to being a loner – including for our creativity, mental health and even leadership skills.
</og:description>
<og:image>http://ichef.bbci.co.uk/wwfeatures/live/624_351/images/live/p0/5z/w1/p05zw18v.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.bbc.com/future/story/20180228-there-are-benefits-to-being-antisocial-or-a-loner</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>