<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Dank-selfhosted: automated deployment of email, web, DNS, XMPP, ZNC on OpenBSD</title>
<link>https://github.com/cullum/dank-selfhosted</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/cullum/dank-selfhosted</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;Box-body p-6&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/a610ebf78eac8436ad45eec034b0c8cf51cc1b2f/68747470733a2f2f692e696d6775722e636f6d2f413436686b70642e676966&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/a610ebf78eac8436ad45eec034b0c8cf51cc1b2f/68747470733a2f2f692e696d6775722e636f6d2f413436686b70642e676966&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/A46hkpd.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi! This is my ansible playbook for self-hosting your own email, web hosting, XMPP chat, and DNS records using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openbsd.org/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;OpenBSD&lt;/a&gt;. I use it to host everything on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.c0ffee.net&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;c0ffee.net&lt;/a&gt;, but you can easily adapt it for your own domain by setting a few variables in &lt;code&gt;vars.yml&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;TLDR&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Configure a &lt;a href=&quot;https://cp.dnsmadeeasy.com/u/122648&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;secondary DNS provider&lt;/a&gt; and set them as your nameservers at your registrar. Set up reverse DNS for your server.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;./scripts/bootstrap_openbsd.sh&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;cp vars-sample.yml vars.yml &amp;amp;&amp;amp; vi vars.yml&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;ansible-playbook site.yml&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;./scripts/ds_records.sh YOURDOMAIN&lt;/code&gt; and set DS records at your registrar for DNSSEC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Assumptions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;You have a public-facing server (probably a VPS) running OpenBSD, with an IPv4 and IPv6 address. I recommend &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vultr.com/?ref=6845125&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Vultr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have your own domain name, and a registrar that supports DNSSEC. I recommend &lt;a href=&quot;https://affiliate.namecheap.com/?affId=108349&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Namecheap&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have a secondary DNS provider that supports DNSSEC. I recommend &lt;a href=&quot;https://cp.dnsmadeeasy.com/u/122648&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;DNS Made Easy&lt;/a&gt;. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.c0ffee.net/blog/dns-hidden-master/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Why do I need this?&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You're crazy enough to run your own mail server :-)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A small and secure OpenBSD platform to host email, DNS, XMPP chat, and some web sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scale:&lt;/strong&gt; you and your family members, and maybe a few technically oriented friends.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Really not suited for the general public, no automated password reset, no web GUIs...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use as much of the OpenBSD base system as possible:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, some packages from the ports tree will be necessary:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Encryption Everywhere:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Automated DNSSEC with &lt;code&gt;nsd&lt;/code&gt; and cron tasks using &lt;code&gt;ldns-signzone&lt;/code&gt; for daily zone re-signing and slave &lt;code&gt;NOTIFYs&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TLS for all public-facing services using LetsEncrypt certificates with automated renewal and daemon reload hooks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatic publishing of &lt;a href=&quot;https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc4255&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;SSHFP&lt;/a&gt; records for authoritative SSH fingerprints&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatic publishing of &lt;a href=&quot;https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc6698&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;TLSA&lt;/a&gt; records for &lt;a href=&quot;https://halon.io/blog/what-is-dane/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;DANE email encryption&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatic publishing of DKIM records for outgoing email verification&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep it Simple&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Unopinionated baseline for what most people want from a personal domain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep dependencies to a minimum and stick to UNIX conventions (simple &lt;code&gt;passwd&lt;/code&gt; auth, mail stored in &lt;code&gt;~/Maildir&lt;/code&gt;, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automate the tedious stuff, so you can focus on hacking!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Boot up your OpenBSD server.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create at least one user account. You will use this account to administer the system, so make sure to add yourself to the &lt;code&gt;wheel&lt;/code&gt; group.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;scripts/bootstrap_openbsd.sh&lt;/code&gt; as root to add a package repo URL and set up &lt;a href=&quot;http://man.openbsd.org/cgi-bin/man.cgi/OpenBSD-current/man1/doas.1&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;doas&lt;/a&gt; for your user (required for Ansible).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configure your secondary DNS provider to accept &lt;code&gt;NOTIFYs&lt;/code&gt; and perform zone transfers from your server's IP address.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;cp vars-sample.yml vars.yml&lt;/code&gt; and edit the configuration to your liking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run the playbook! &lt;code&gt;ansible-playbook site.yml&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure you have reverse DNS in place for your server's IP address. This is a critical step to avoid your outgoing mail being flagged as spam. At Vultr, this is configured under &quot;Settings &amp;gt; IPv4&quot;. You should set one for your primary IPv6 address as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The last step is to configure DS records for DNSSEC at your domain registrar. Run &lt;code&gt;scripts/ds_records.sh YOURDOMAIN&lt;/code&gt; to generate the records. At Namecheap, this is configured under &quot;Advanced DNS &amp;gt; DNSSEC&quot; in the web portal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yell at me on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cullumsmith&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; when you inevitably find bugs in my code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Operational Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Login info:&lt;/strong&gt; the credentials for SMTP (STARTTLS, port 587) and IMAP (SSL, port 993) are simply your username (&lt;em&gt;without&lt;/em&gt; the @domain.com portion) and login password. XMPP uses the &lt;code&gt;username@domain.com&lt;/code&gt; syntax for logins, but the password is the same. Mail is stored under &lt;code&gt;~/Maildir&lt;/code&gt; in each user's home directory for easy access using local clients like &lt;code&gt;mutt&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Email Filtering&lt;/strong&gt;: any &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki2.dovecot.org/Pigeonhole/Sieve/Examples&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;sieve script&lt;/a&gt; located at &lt;code&gt;~/.dovecot.sieve&lt;/code&gt; will automatically apply filters to your incoming mail. You can compile the sieve script and check for syntax errors using &lt;code&gt;sievec ~/.dovecot.sieve&lt;/code&gt;. For example, to filter all your cron emails into a folder called &lt;code&gt;Logs&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;require [&quot;regex&quot;, &quot;fileinto&quot;, &quot;imap4flags&quot;, &quot;mailbox&quot;, &quot;envelope&quot;, &quot;variables&quot;];

if allof ( address :is &quot;from&quot; &quot;root@hostname.example.com&quot;,
           anyof ( header :contains &quot;subject&quot; &quot;cron&quot;,
                   header :contains &quot;subject&quot; &quot;output&quot; )) {
  fileinto :create &quot;Logs&quot;;
  stop;
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;XMPP Chat:&lt;/strong&gt; the XMPP server, Prosody, is really slick. As configured here, it supports HTTP file upload for image sharing, delivery to multiple devices via carbons, push notifications, group chats, message history, and basically everything you'd expect from a modern chat solution. XMPP isn't all that bad! The best clients are &lt;a href=&quot;https://chatsecure.org/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;ChatSecure&lt;/a&gt; for iOS, &lt;a href=&quot;https://conversations.im/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Conversations&lt;/a&gt; for Android, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://gajim.org/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Gajim&lt;/a&gt; for *nix and Windows. No decent clients for OS X, sadly. All those clients support end-to-end crypto via &lt;a href=&quot;https://conversations.im/omemo/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;OMEMO&lt;/a&gt;. Easily federate with others on separate XMPP servers for truly decentralized, open communication!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Additional accounts&lt;/strong&gt;: to add more accounts, just use &lt;code&gt;adduser&lt;/code&gt;. Unless they need a shell, it's probably best to set their shell to &lt;code&gt;/sbin/nologin&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IPv6:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;spamd&lt;/code&gt; does not currently support IPv6, so don't go adding a AAAA record for &lt;code&gt;mail&lt;/code&gt; in the zonefile!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monitoring spamd&lt;/strong&gt;: just run &lt;code&gt;spamdb&lt;/code&gt; to see a list of senders currently greylisted/whitelisted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Virtual Hosts&lt;/strong&gt;: a default vhost will be created for &lt;code&gt;www.domain.com&lt;/code&gt;, with a bare domain redirect. Shove HTML files into &lt;code&gt;/var/www/htdocs/www.domain.com&lt;/code&gt; to start sharing your worthless opinions with the internet! To add more vhosts, just put a configuration file in &lt;code&gt;/etc/sites&lt;/code&gt; and include it in &lt;code&gt;/etc/httpd.d/sites.conf&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Greylisting pitfalls:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;spamd&lt;/code&gt; works by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.greylisting.org/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;greylisting&lt;/a&gt;. Unfortunately, big mailers like GMail often don't retry delivery from the same address, resulting in a greylist black hole described &lt;a href=&quot;https://poolp.org/posts/2018-01-08/spfwalk/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. To alleviate this, I included a daily cron job that whitelists the IP addresses found in the SPF records for some of the big mailers like GMail and Yahoo. If you notice any other problematic domains, override the to the &lt;code&gt;bigmailers&lt;/code&gt; list defined in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cullum/dank-selfhosted/blob/master/roles/spamd/defaults/main.yml&quot;&gt;roles/spamd/deaults/main.yml&lt;/a&gt; to have their IP ranges whitelisted. (And be sure to send me a pull request!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Password Resets:&lt;/strong&gt; I'm leaving password management up to you. Since this configuration uses plain UNIX accounts, you won't be able to add a password reset webpage without some kind of crappy setuid CGI script (yikes!). Look into LDAP authentication if you have a bunch of non-neckbeard users. Otherwise, &lt;code&gt;man login.conf&lt;/code&gt; for information on enforcing password expiration and complexity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Backups&lt;/strong&gt;: another thing I'm leaving up to you, since your requirements will almost certainly be unique. Shouldn't be too difficult:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maildirs&lt;/strong&gt;: tar them up, maybe encrypt them, and scp them offsite periodically.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;User accounts&lt;/strong&gt;: back up &lt;code&gt;/etc/{passwd,master.passwd,group}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Backup MX records:&lt;/strong&gt; I don't bother with a backup MX. They are a massive target for spammers, and legit mail servers will keep retrying delivery for multiple days if your primary MX goes down.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prosody:&lt;/strong&gt; periodically tar up the HTTP upload dir and do a &lt;code&gt;pg_dump&lt;/code&gt; to save user info and message archives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keys:&lt;/strong&gt; tar up your DNSSEC keys (&lt;code&gt;/var/nsd/keys&lt;/code&gt;) and DKIM keys (&lt;code&gt;/etc/mail/dkim&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assuming you copy all these items back to their original locations, the playbook won't generate new keys if they already exist.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 21:05:47 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>indigodaddy</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars2.githubusercontent.com/u/4296097?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>cullum/dank-selfhosted</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/cullum/dank-selfhosted</og:url>
<og:description>Automated solution for hosting email, web, DNS, XMPP, and ZNC on OpenBSD. - cullum/dank-selfhosted</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/cullum/dank-selfhosted</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Swedish ISP Protests ‘Site Blocking’ by Blocking Rightsholders Website Too</title>
<link>https://torrentfreak.com/swedish-isp-protest-site-blocking-by-blocking-rightsholders-website-and-more-181102/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://torrentfreak.com/swedish-isp-protest-site-blocking-by-blocking-rightsholders-website-and-more-181102/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://torrentfreak.com/images/bahnhof.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;222&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; class=&quot;alignright size-full wp-image-128056&quot;/&gt;As a staunch defender of an open Internet, ISP &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bahnhof.se/&quot;&gt;Bahnhof&lt;/a&gt; has repeatedly spoken out against pirate site blocking efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company has also argued the matter in court recently, after academic publisher Elsevier applied for an order to ban a series of domain names, including Sci-Hub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, Bahnhof announced that it has been ordered to block the sites in question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the worst possible outcome for Bahnhof. TorrentFreak spoke to CEO Jon Karlung who describes it as a “horrifying” decision that “goes against the soul of the Internet.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result, starting today, is that sci-hub.tw, sci-hub.mu, sci-hub.se, libgen.io, and several other domains are being &lt;a href=&quot;http://kampa-for-ett-fritt-internet-utan-upphovsmaffians-blockering.se/&quot;&gt;blocked by the ISP&lt;/a&gt;. But Bahnhof wouldn’t be Bahnhof if it went down without a fight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company has no faith in an expensive appeal, which another ISP lost last year in a similar blocking case. However, it does have another ace up its sleeve. Now that they are blocking anyway, they can easily an extra domain name to make a point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, in addition, Bahnhof has gone ahead and banned its visitors from accessing the official Elsevier.com website as well. Elsevier wanted a site blockade – it now has one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visitors attempting to visit the domains now see a 90s style website explaining what’s going on, complete with an old &lt;a href=&quot;http://this-copyright-syndicate-is-killing-internet-by-blocking-sites.se/SuzanneBeDell-MarciaBalisciano-YoungSukChi-JohnDanaher-HannfriedvonHindenburg-NikunjJinsi-BeverlyMalone-EmilieMarcus-RonMobed-GeraldineRichmond/&quot;&gt;dial-up tone in the background&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Bahnhof opposes censorship in every way, shape and form, but it looks like we won’t be able to dodge Elsevier’s blocking requirement. That’s why we have placed this barrier in front of Elsevier’s website – to make sure that they themselves also get a taste of the blocking they’re currently evoking against others,” it reads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elsevier.com banned&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://torrentfreak.com/images/elseban.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;611&quot; height=&quot;341&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-163648&quot;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The page goes on to explain what Elsevier is, making note of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://torrentfreak.com/sci-hub-tears-down-academias-illegal-copyright-paywalls-150627/&quot;&gt;controversy&lt;/a&gt; surrounding the company’s role in academic publishing. This is one of the reasons why the blocked “pirate” sites have become so popular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bahnhof’s CEO informs TorrentFreak that the company sees no point in appealing the case. The Patent and Market Court, which handles these matters, is made up of people who are biased towards copyright holders, he believes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make another point, the Internet provider also decided to send the court a message. Starting today, users of the court’s network can no longer access Bahnhof’s website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The computer or network you are using belongs to the Patent and Market Court and is therefore blocked from the domain bahnhof.se. You at the Patent and Market Court have recently decided that operators should block certain domains so their customers can no longer visit them,” the message reads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Court banned&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://torrentfreak.com/images/courtban1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;611&quot; height=&quot;275&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-163647&quot;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the ISP is clearly disappointed with the court’s decision, it will not stop its protests. It may not be able to undo the blocking order but the company will continue to make its voice heard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Bahnhof has repeatedly demonstrated how copyright law is being abused and exploited by greedy opportunists, and in the end it is always ordinary people who have to pay,” Bahnhof notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This page you’ve got before you right now is the result, this is what awaits in a future where private interests can regulate community information. Is our legal system really being used in this way?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ISP also hopes that its subscribers will help with its efforts. On the &lt;a href=&quot;http://&quot; http:=&quot;&quot; kampa-for-ett-fritt-internet-utan-upphovsmaffians-blockering.se=&quot;&quot;&gt;blocking page&lt;/a&gt; it provides a form allowing them to send a letter to Justice Minister Morgan Johansson, to share their outrage.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 14:52:07 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kawera</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Swedish ISP Protests 'Site Blocking' by Blocking Rightsholders Website Too - TorrentFreak</og:title>
<og:description>Bahnhof has suffered a major defeat against publisher Elsevier after a court ordered the Swedish ISP to block a series of domain names, including Sci-Hub. The decision goes against everything the company stands for but it can't ignore the blocking order. Instead, the ISP has gone on the offensive by blocking Elsevier's own website and barring the court from visiting Bahnhof.se.</og:description>
<og:url>https://torrentfreak.com/swedish-isp-protest-site-blocking-by-blocking-rightsholders-website-and-more-181102/</og:url>
<og:image>https://torrentfreak.com/images/blocked-1.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://torrentfreak.com/swedish-isp-protest-site-blocking-by-blocking-rightsholders-website-and-more-181102/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>OpenBSD on a Laptop</title>
<link>https://www.c0ffee.net/blog/openbsd-on-a-laptop/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.c0ffee.net/blog/openbsd-on-a-laptop/</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;meta charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;viewport&quot; content=&quot;width=device-width, initial-scale=1&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;description&quot; content=&quot;A guide to a secure and streamlined installation of OpenBSD 6.4 on a laptop.&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;author&quot; content=&quot;Cullum Smith&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;date&quot; content=&quot;2018-11-02&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot; href=&quot;/css/style.css&quot;/&gt;&lt;title&gt;OpenBSD on a Laptop&lt;/title&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;305.15050969418&quot;&gt;
&lt;nav&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.c0ffee.net/&quot;&gt;Home&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.c0ffee.net/blog&quot;&gt;Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/nav&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;posted-on&quot;&gt;2 Nov 2018&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;header readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;subtitle&quot;&gt;A guide to a secure and streamlined installation of OpenBSD 6.4 on a laptop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/header&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cullumsmith/status/1058784327000055808&quot;&gt;Screenshot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; of the completed setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's been almost a year since I've posted any articles, and I'm afraid I have a confession to make...I've joined the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openbsd.org/&quot;&gt;dark side&lt;/a&gt;! Most people know my site from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.c0ffee.net/blog/mail-server-guide/&quot;&gt;How to Run a Mail Server&lt;/a&gt; post, which targeted FreeBSD. A few months ago, I converted all that infrastructure to an &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cullum/dank-selfhosted&quot;&gt;automated OpenBSD platform&lt;/a&gt;. Turns out OpenBSD was so much easier, I decided to run it as a desktop too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You won't find nearly as many online resources about setting up OpenBSD, because honestly, you really don't need any. Unlike much of Linux and FreeBSD, the included manuals are high quality, coherent, and filled with practical examples. You also need very little third party software to do basic tasks—almost everything you need is well-integrated into the base system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You'll notice that many features that require toil to achieve on FreeBSD, such as suspend on lid close, working volume buttons, and decent battery life, work out of the box on OpenBSD. You can tell the developers actually use this thing on their personal devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And while the official &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openbsd.org/faq/&quot;&gt;OpenBSD FAQ&lt;/a&gt; has all you need to get an installation up and running, it takes a bit of grinding to massage the base installation into a seamless laptop experience. So, I wrote this guide to give you a jump start. Things should &lt;em&gt;just work&lt;/em&gt; as long as you have a non-bleeding-edge, semi-mainstream laptop, but ThinkPads are your best bet. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.c0ffee.net/blog/openbsd-on-a-laptop/#installation&quot;&gt;Installation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.c0ffee.net/blog/openbsd-on-a-laptop/#networking&quot;&gt;Network Setup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.c0ffee.net/blog/openbsd-on-a-laptop/#initial-configuration&quot;&gt;Initial Configuration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.c0ffee.net/blog/openbsd-on-a-laptop/#x11&quot;&gt;X11&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.c0ffee.net/blog/openbsd-on-a-laptop/#cwm&quot;&gt;The CWM Window Manager&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.c0ffee.net/blog/openbsd-on-a-laptop/#base-utilities&quot;&gt;Customizing the Base Utilities&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.c0ffee.net/blog/openbsd-on-a-laptop/#mail&quot;&gt;Sending Mail&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.c0ffee.net/blog/openbsd-on-a-laptop/#packages&quot;&gt;Installing Packages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.c0ffee.net/blog/openbsd-on-a-laptop/#chromium&quot;&gt;Chromium on OpenBSD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.c0ffee.net/blog/openbsd-on-a-laptop/#multimedia&quot;&gt;Multimedia and Battery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.c0ffee.net/blog/openbsd-on-a-laptop/#updates&quot;&gt;Updating the Base System&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.c0ffee.net/blog/openbsd-on-a-laptop/#resources&quot;&gt;Other Resources&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;section readability=&quot;267.66995183732&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;installation&quot;&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OpenBSD has one of the most user-friendly installers in the Unix ecosystem. Grab a USB stick and download the &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;amd64&lt;/span&gt; disk image:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
curl -OJ https://cdn.openbsd.org/pub/OpenBSD/6.4/amd64/install64.fs
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plug in the USB stick and copy the disk image using &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;dd&lt;/span&gt;. This command assumes the disk is recognized as &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;sdb&lt;/span&gt; (check &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;dmesg&lt;/span&gt; to verify):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
dd if=install64.fs of=/dev/sdb bs=1m
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boot your laptop to the USB installer. This guide assumes you're booting via UEFI—if your laptop has any &quot;BIOS compatibility mode&quot; options, you should disable them. OpenBSD boots happily in pure UEFI mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you reach the installation prompt, choose &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;(S)hell&lt;/span&gt;. We'll need some manual steps to enable full-disk encryption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;full-disk-encryption&quot;&gt;Full Disk Encryption with SoftRAID&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're even a little paranoid, you should start by overwriting the disk with random data. We'll assume your hard disk is &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;sd0&lt;/span&gt;—you can use &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;dmesg&lt;/span&gt; to check. The &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;c&lt;/span&gt; suffix is OpenBSD's way of specifying the entire disk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
dd if=/dev/urandom of=/dev/rsd0c bs=1m
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will take a &lt;em&gt;long&lt;/em&gt; time. You can check the status by hitting &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;Ctrl-T&lt;/span&gt;. Once that's done, create a new partition table using &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/fdisk&quot;&gt;fdisk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. This command will automatically create the EFI System Partition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
fdisk -iy -g -b 960 sd0
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OpenBSD uses &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/softraid.4&quot;&gt;softraid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; for full-disk encryption. We'll make one partition for the whole disk. Use the values in boldface for the &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/disklabel&quot;&gt;disklabel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; prompts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;disklabel -E sd0&lt;/strong&gt;
Label editor (enter '?' for help at any prompt)
&amp;gt; &lt;strong&gt;a a&lt;/strong&gt;
offset: [1024]
size: [500117105]
FS type: [4.2BSD] &lt;strong&gt;RAID&lt;/strong&gt;
&amp;gt; &lt;strong&gt;w&lt;/strong&gt;
&amp;gt; &lt;strong&gt;q&lt;/strong&gt;
No label changes.
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, create the encrypted softraid. You will prompted for a passphrase. Choose a strong one, but remember that if you forget it, you're SOL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
bioctl -c C -l sd0a softraid0
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should see a message like &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;CRYPTO volume attached as &lt;strong&gt;sd2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. This is the name of your new &quot;virtual&quot; disk. You'll need to make a device node and clear out the first megabyte. We want a nice, clean region for the disklabel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
cd /dev &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sh MAKEDEV sd2
dd if=/dev/zero of=/dev/rsd2c bs=1m count=1
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now type &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;exit&lt;/span&gt; to return to the installation menu, and choose &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;(I)nstall&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The OpenBSD Installer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The installer will ask you a series of questions to set up your system. You'll be prompted for your keyboard layout, hostname, root password, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also connect to your network during the installation, but your wireless card might not be functional. Most wireless cards require non-free firmware that OpenBSD doesn't include in the base install. For now, you can just skip the network setup. We'll come back to it once the installation is finished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're installing on a laptop, you probably want to enable &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/xenodm.1&quot;&gt;xenodm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; for X11 and disable &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;sshd&lt;/span&gt; from starting on boot. You can also go ahead and create your user account when prompted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The installer will ask you to specify a root disk. Make sure to choose the &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;softraid&lt;/span&gt; disk you created earlier (most likely &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;sd2&lt;/span&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
Which disk is the root disk ('?' for details) [sd0] &lt;strong&gt;sd2&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go ahead and select the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;whole disk (G)PT&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; option to let OpenBSD utilize the entire encrypted softraid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You'll be prompted to choose a partition layout. If you have a sufficiently large hard disk (greater than 128 GB or so), the &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;auto&lt;/span&gt; layout is probably your best bet. You can customize it if you so choose—for example, if you intend to compile a lot of ports, you'd probably want larger &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;/usr/src&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;/usr/obj&lt;/span&gt; partitions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After partitioning the disk, you'll be prompted to specify the location of the &quot;sets&quot;, which contain various components of the OpenBSD base system. Since we used a USB stick, we'll select &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;disk&lt;/span&gt;. Your USB stick is most likely &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;sd1&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
Location of sets? (cd0 disk http or 'done') [cd0] &lt;strong&gt;disk&lt;/strong&gt;
Is the disk partition already mounted? [no] &lt;strong&gt;no&lt;/strong&gt;
Which disk contains the install media? (or 'done') [sd0] &lt;strong&gt;sd1&lt;/strong&gt;
Available sd1 partitions are: a i.
Which sd1 partition has the install sets? (or 'done') [a]
Pathname to the sets? (or 'done') [6.4/amd64]
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can then specify which sets you'd like installed. I recommend accepting the defaults, and installing all of them. If you're installing from a disk, it's safe to continue without SHA256 verification, provided you verified the installation image as decribed &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openbsd.org/faq/faq4.html#Download&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
Directory does not contain SHA256.sig. Continue without verification? [no] &lt;strong&gt;yes&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the sets are installed, you'll be prompted for your timezone. After that, you're good to go! Just &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;reboot&lt;/span&gt; to boot into your new OpenBSD installation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section readability=&quot;60.197852760736&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;networking&quot;&gt;Network Setup&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you've logged in at the xenodm prompt, you'll be greeted by the default desktop environment, &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/fvwm&quot;&gt;fvwm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. (It's charming to say the least. Don't worry, we'll change it later.) Go ahead and run &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/su.1&quot;&gt;su&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; in the &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/xterm.1&quot;&gt;xterm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; window to get a root shell. Use the root password you created in the installer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, you need to figure out the name of your ethernet interface. Run &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/ifconfig&quot;&gt;ifconfig&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; to print the attached network interfaces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
ifconfig
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have an Intel ethernet card, the device will probably be called &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;em0&lt;/span&gt;. Otherwise, just go with whichever device shows &quot;Ethernet&quot; for the media field. Plug in an ethernet cable and run &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/dhclient.8&quot;&gt;dhclient&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; to get an IP address.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
dhclient em0
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now you should be connected to the internet. Use the &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/fw_update&quot;&gt;fw_update&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; tool to download firmware for your wireless card. When run with no arguments, it will scan your hardware and install any necessary firmware packages from &lt;a href=&quot;http://firmware.openbsd.org/firmware/&quot;&gt;OpenBSD's firmware repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
fw_update
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; If your laptop doesn't have an ethernet card, you'll have to download the firmware packages for your hardware on another device and copy them to your OpenBSD installation by some other means (like a FAT32-formatted USB stick). Check the &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/fw_update&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;fw_update&lt;/span&gt; man page&lt;/a&gt; for details on local installation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now you're ready to connect to WiFi. Run &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;ifconfig&lt;/span&gt; again, and you should see a new wireless network interface. If you have an Intel wireless card, it will probably be called &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;iwn0&lt;/span&gt;. Bring it up and scan for networks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
ifconfig iwn0 up
ifconfig iwn0 scan
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite things about OpenBSD is how well integrated the base system is. For example, to connect to a WPA2-protected network, you can do everything with a simple &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;ifconfig&lt;/span&gt; command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
ifconfig iwn0 nwid YOUR_SSID wpakey &quot;YOUR_PASSPHRASE&quot;
dhclient iwn0
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linux would require some kind of &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;wpa_supplicant&lt;/span&gt; nightmare. Anyway, you'll probably want to make this configuration persistent. In OpenBSD, this is done in a &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/hostname.if.5&quot;&gt;hostname.if&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; file. Lucky for you, OpenBSD &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mail-archive.com/source-changes@openbsd.org/msg99921.html&quot;&gt;recently added&lt;/a&gt; the ability to configure multiple WiFi profiles! Previously you had to write your own hacky script to manage different networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assuming your wireless card is &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;iwn0&lt;/span&gt;, create &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;/etc/hostname.iwn0&lt;/span&gt; with the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/etc/hostname.iwn0&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
join &quot;YOUR_SSID&quot; wpakey &quot;YOUR_PASSPHRASE&quot;



dhcp
inet6 autoconf
up powersave
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To test your changes, undo the manual configuration we performed and run the &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/netstart&quot;&gt;netstart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; script:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
ifconfig em0 down
ifconfig iwn0 down
pkill dhclient
sh /etc/netstart
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This should automatically tighten up permissions on the &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;hostname.if&lt;/span&gt; file and join your network. Now that you're online (and can easily copy-paste from this guide) we can start tweaking some configs!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;initial-configuration&quot;&gt;Initial Configuration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing to do is disable the annoying &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/xconsole.1&quot;&gt;xconsole&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; window from autostarting at each login. We'll also disable the system beep in the session manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
sed -i 's/xconsole/#xconsole/' /etc/X11/xenodm/Xsetup_0
echo 'xset b off' &amp;gt;&amp;gt; /etc/X11/xenodm/Xsetup_0
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also disable the beep when logged into a virtual console:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
echo keyboard.bell.volume=0 &amp;gt; /etc/wsconsctl.conf
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Configure &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/OpenBSD-6.0/doas.1&quot;&gt;doas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; so you can run commands with elevated privileges from your normal user account. This is OpenBSD's reimagination of &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;sudo&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
echo 'permit persist keepenv YOUR_USERNAME' &amp;gt; /etc/doas.conf
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This line permits your user to run &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;doas&lt;/span&gt; for all commands, maintains your environment variables, and gives you a grace period between commands where you don't have to enter your password over and over again. This is what most users would expect from an interactive session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since this is a laptop, you'll want to enable power management to save battery life:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
rcctl enable apmd
rcctl set apmd flags -A
rcctl start apmd
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add your user to the &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;staff&lt;/span&gt; group. This group has higher resource limits in &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/login.conf.5&quot;&gt;login.conf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. You'll need to log out and back in for this change to take effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
usermod -G staff YOUR_USERNAME
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The default resource limits in OpenBSD are extremely conservative. For running modern applications like web browsers, we'll need to bump them up significantly. Use &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/vi.1&quot;&gt;vi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; to modify the &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;staff&lt;/span&gt; login class in &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/login.conf.5&quot;&gt;/etc/login.conf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; as follows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/etc/login.conf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
staff:\
  :datasize-cur=1024M:\
  :datasize-max=8192M:\
  :maxproc-cur=512:\
  :maxproc-max=1024:\
  :openfiles-cur=4096:\
  :openfiles-max=8192:\
  :stacksize-cur=32M:\
  :ignorenologin:\
  :requirehome@:\
  :tc=default:
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You'll need to logout and log back in for those changes to take effect. There are also some kernel &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/sysctl.2&quot;&gt;sysctls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; we'll need to bump up for desktop use. Add the following values to &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/sysctl.conf.5&quot;&gt;/etc/sysctl.conf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. The &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;shm&lt;/span&gt; variables are for my laptop, which has 16 GB of RAM. You should scale them accordingly for your machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/etc/sysctl.conf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;

kern.shminfo.shmall=2147483648
kern.shminfo.shmmax=8589934592
kern.shminfo.shmmni=1024


kern.shminfo.shmseg=1024
kern.seminfo.semmns=4096
kern.seminfo.semmni=1024

kern.maxproc=32768
kern.maxfiles=65535
kern.bufcachepercent=90
kern.maxvnodes=262144
kern.somaxconn=2048
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can greatly improve disk performance by enabling &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openbsd.org/faq/faq14.html#SoftUpdates&quot;&gt;softupdates&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;noatime&lt;/span&gt; option for all your local partitions in &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/fstab&quot;&gt;/etc/fstab&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. Add the &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;softdep,noatime&lt;/span&gt; options to each partition (except &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;swap&lt;/span&gt;) as I've demonstrated below. Don't copy and paste this directly, as your disk identifier will be different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/etc/fstab&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
0364c44477d30004.b none swap sw
0364c44477d30004.a / ffs rw,softdep,noatime 1 1
0364c44477d30004.l /home ffs rw,softdep,noatime,nodev,nosuid 1 2
0364c44477d30004.d /tmp ffs rw,softdep,noatime,nodev,nosuid 1 2
0364c44477d30004.f /usr ffs rw,softdep,noatime,nodev 1 2
0364c44477d30004.g /usr/X11R6 ffs rw,softdep,noatime,nodev 1 2
0364c44477d30004.h /usr/local ffs rw,softdep,noatime,wxallowed,nodev 1 2
0364c44477d30004.k /usr/obj ffs rw,softdep,noatime,nodev,nosuid 1 2
0364c44477d30004.j /usr/src ffs rw,softdep,noatime,nodev,nosuid 1 2
0364c44477d30004.e /var ffs rw,softdep,noatime,nodev,nosuid 1 2
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since this is a laptop, you'll probably want your screen to lock automatically when you close the lid. You can configure &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/apmd&quot;&gt;apmd&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; to do this for you. (Note that this won't be effective until we configure X11 in the section below.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, make the directory:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
mkdir /etc/apm
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, create the file &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;/etc/apm/suspend&lt;/span&gt; with the following contents:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/etc/apm/suspend&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
#!/bin/sh
pkill -USR1 xidle
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And make it executable:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
chmod +x /etc/apm/suspend
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm paranoid and don't like the fact that &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.com/ntpd&quot;&gt;ntpd&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; reaches out to &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;www.google.com&lt;/span&gt; of all places to sanity check each clock update. You can turn that off easily:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
sed -i '/google/d' /etc/ntpd.conf
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or, even better, you can replace Google with domain you feel comfortable pinging all the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
sed -i 's/www\.google\.com/www.example.com/' /etc/ntpd.conf
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you do either of those, be sure to restart &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;ntpd&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
rcctl restart ntpd
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now you've got a pretty robust OpenBSD installation. You could probably take over the world with just the base system, but we'll take some time to make OpenBSD into a more pleasant desktop experience. Exit from your root shell, and we'll start configuring X11.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section readability=&quot;60.950875780149&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;x11&quot;&gt;Setting Up X11&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The default OpenBSD desktop is an ancient window manager called &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/fvwm&quot;&gt;fvwm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. I'm not sure if anyone uses it other than Theo himself. You can find various people online who have made it somewhat usable and not-ugly, but those kind of people enjoy suffering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll set the newer &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;cwm&lt;/span&gt; as our default window manager in &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;~/.xsession&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;~/.xsession&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;

export LANG=en_US.UTF-8


export ENV=$HOME/.kshrc


xrdb -merge $HOME/.Xresources


xsetroot -solid dimgray


xidle &amp;amp;



LANG= xclock -strftime &quot;%a %e %b %Y %H:%M&quot; &amp;amp;


xset b off



xinput set-prop &quot;/dev/wsmouse&quot; &quot;WS Pointer Wheel Emulation&quot; 1 
xinput set-prop &quot;/dev/wsmouse&quot; &quot;WS Pointer Wheel Emulation Button&quot; 2 
xinput set-prop &quot;/dev/wsmouse&quot; &quot;WS Pointer Wheel Emulation Axes&quot; 6 7 4 5 


xmodmap $HOME/.xmodmaprc


exec cwm
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;~/.xmodmaprc&lt;/span&gt; to remap caps lock to the control key. This is a necessity if you ever use emacs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;~/.xmodmaprc&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
clear lock
clear control
keycode 66 = Control_L
add control = Control_L Control_R
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A man's &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;Xresources&lt;/span&gt; file is a very personal thing. You don't have to copy what I've done here. It's just some settings I find pleasant to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;~/.Xresources&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;

Xft.autohint  : 0
Xft.lcdfilter : lcddefault
Xft.hintstyle : hintslight
Xft.hinting   : 1
Xft.antialias : 1
Xft.rgba      : rgb

*font         : -misc-fixed-medium-r-semicondensed-*-13-*-*-*-*-*-iso10646-1



xidle*position : sw

xidle*delay    : 1

xidle*timeout  : 300



xlock.description : off
xlock.echokeys    : off
xlock.info        :
xlock.background  : black
xlock.foreground  : white
xlock.mode        : blank
xlock.username    : username: 
xlock.password    : password: 
xlock.font        : -misc-fixed-medium-r-normal-*-15-*-*-*-*-*-iso10646-1
xlock.planfont    : -misc-fixed-medium-r-normal-*-13-*-*-*-*-*-iso10646-1



XClock*analog      : false
XClock*twentyfour  : true
XClock*padding     : 0
XClock*geometry    : -2-2
XClock*render      : false
XClock*font        : -misc-fixed-bold-r-normal-*-13-*-*-*-*-*-iso10646-1
XClock*height      : 12
XClock*background  : dimgray
XClock*foreground  : white
XClock*borderWidth : 0



XTerm*background     : #3f3f3f
XTerm*foreground     : #dcdccc
XTerm*cursorColor    : #aaaaaa
XTerm*colorUL        : #366060
XTerm*underlineColor : #dfaf8f
XTerm*color0         : #3f3f3f
XTerm*color1         : #cc9393
XTerm*color2         : #7f9f7f
XTerm*color3         : #d0bf8f
XTerm*color4         : #6ca0a3
XTerm*color5         : #dc8cc3
XTerm*color6         : #93e0e3
XTerm*color7         : #dcdccc
XTerm*color8         : #000000
XTerm*color9         : #dca3a3
XTerm*color10        : #bfebbf
XTerm*color11        : #f0dfaf
XTerm*color12        : #8cd0d3
XTerm*color13        : #dc8cc3
XTerm*color14        : #93e0e3
XTerm*color15        : #ffffff


XTerm*borderWidth            : 0
XTerm*internalBorder         : 2

XTerm*termName               : xterm-256color

XTerm*vt100.metaSendsEscape  : true

XTerm*v100.saveLines         : 10240

XTerm*vt100.scrollBar        : false

XTerm*vt100.bellIsUrgent     : true

XTerm*allowBoldFonts         : false

XTerm*scrollKey              : true

XTerm*fullscreen             : never

XTerm*cutToBeginningOfLine   : false

XTerm*cutNewline             : false

XTerm*charClass              : 33:48,36-47:48,58-59:48,61:48,63-64:48,95:48,126:48

XTerm*on2Clicks              : word

XTerm*on3Clicks              : line

XTerm*VT100*Translations     : #override Shift : exec-formatted(&quot;chrome --enable-unveil '%t'&quot;, PRIMARY)
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OpenBSD's GTK port is built with the default key theme set to emacs (heresy!). This means that normal key shortcuts (like Ctrl-A to select all) don't work. You can fix that by changing the &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;gtk-key-theme-name&lt;/span&gt; in the GTK configuration. First, make the directory:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
mkdir -p ~/.config/gtk-3.0
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then create the file &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;settings.ini&lt;/span&gt; with your desired customizations. Here's what I use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;~/.config/gtk-3.0/settings.ini&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
[Settings]
gtk-theme-name=Adwaita
gtk-icon-theme-name=Adwaita
gtk-font-name=Arimo 9
gtk-toolbar-style=GTK_TOOLBAR_ICONS
gtk-toolbar-icon-size=GTK_ICON_SIZE_SMALL_TOOLBAR
gtk-button-images=1
gtk-menu-images=1
gtk-enable-event-sounds=1
gtk-enable-input-feedback-sounds=1
gtk-xft-antialias=1
gtk-xft-hinting=1
gtk-xft-hintstyle=hintslight
gtk-xft-rgba=rgb
gtk-cursor-theme-size=0
gtk-cursor-theme-name=Default
gtk-key-theme-name=Default
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, get yourself some decent looking fonts. Edit &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;~/.config/fontconfig/fonts.conf&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;~/.config/fontconfig/fonts.conf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&amp;lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot;?&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;!DOCTYPE fontconfig SYSTEM &quot;fonts.dtd&quot;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;fontconfig&amp;gt;
  
  &amp;lt;match target=&quot;font&quot;&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;edit mode=&quot;assign&quot; name=&quot;antialias&quot;&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;bool&amp;gt;true&amp;lt;/bool&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/edit&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;edit mode=&quot;assign&quot; name=&quot;hinting&quot;&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;bool&amp;gt;true&amp;lt;/bool&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/edit&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;edit mode=&quot;assign&quot; name=&quot;hintstyle&quot;&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;const&amp;gt;hintslight&amp;lt;/const&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/edit&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;edit mode=&quot;assign&quot; name=&quot;lcdfilter&quot;&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;const&amp;gt;lcddefault&amp;lt;/const&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/edit&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;edit mode=&quot;assign&quot; name=&quot;rgba&quot;&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;const&amp;gt;rgb&amp;lt;/const&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/edit&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;/match&amp;gt;

  
  &amp;lt;alias&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;family&amp;gt;sans-serif&amp;lt;/family&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;prefer&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;family&amp;gt;Arimo&amp;lt;/family&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;family&amp;gt;Liberation Sans&amp;lt;/family&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;family&amp;gt;DejaVu Sans&amp;lt;/family&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/prefer&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;/alias&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;alias&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;family&amp;gt;serif&amp;lt;/family&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;prefer&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;family&amp;gt;Tinos&amp;lt;/family&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;family&amp;gt;Liberation Serif&amp;lt;/family&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;family&amp;gt;DejaVu Serif&amp;lt;/family&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/prefer&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;/alias&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;alias&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;family&amp;gt;monospace&amp;lt;/family&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;prefer&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;family&amp;gt;Cousine&amp;lt;/family&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;family&amp;gt;Liberation Mono&amp;lt;/family&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;family&amp;gt;DejaVu Sans Mono&amp;lt;/family&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/prefer&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;/alias&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/fontconfig&amp;gt; 
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all the graphical goodness configured, the next step is to discover your new window manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section readability=&quot;23.729196050776&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;cwm&quot;&gt;The CWM Window Manager&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;fvwm&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/cwm.1&quot;&gt;cwm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; is a somewhat recent development. It's a simple window manager with a keyboard-focused workflow, perfect for laptops. It's also very easy to learn: the man page is ten times shorter than that of &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;fvwm&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;cwm&lt;/span&gt; configuration goes in &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;~/.cwmrc&lt;/span&gt;. You can read about all the configuration options on &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/cwmrc.5&quot;&gt;the man page&lt;/a&gt;. I've reproduced my config below to give you a head start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a long history with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://i3wm.org&quot;&gt;i3 window manager&lt;/a&gt;, so I emulated most of &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;i3&lt;/span&gt;'s default keybindings with their &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;cwm&lt;/span&gt; equivalents. The concepts are pretty similar in both: you have multiple numbered groups (basically virtual desktops), and can switch between them, move windows from one to the other, etc. There's also support for basic tiling, and it has a &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;dmenu&lt;/span&gt;-like program launcher built right in!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;~/.cwmrc&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;

sticky yes

snapdist 4

gap 0 14 0 0


fontname &quot;fixed:pixelsize=13:style=semicondensed&quot;


unbind-key all








bind-key 4-Return terminal

bind-key CM-l lock

bind-key 4-BackSpace window-hide


bind-key 4-Down window-lower

bind-key 4-Up window-raise

bind-key 4-Tab window-cycle
bind-key M-Tab window-cycle

bind-key 4S-Tab window-rcycle
bind-key MS-Tab window-rcycle

bind-key 4-w window-delete

bind-key 4-n window-menu-label



bind-key 4-1 group-only-1
bind-key 4-2 group-only-2
bind-key 4-3 group-only-3
bind-key 4-4 group-only-4
bind-key 4-5 group-only-5
bind-key 4-6 group-only-6
bind-key 4-7 group-only-7
bind-key 4-8 group-only-8
bind-key 4-9 group-only-9


bind-key 4S-1 window-movetogroup-1
bind-key 4S-2 window-movetogroup-2
bind-key 4S-3 window-movetogroup-3
bind-key 4S-4 window-movetogroup-4
bind-key 4S-5 window-movetogroup-5
bind-key 4S-6 window-movetogroup-6
bind-key 4S-7 window-movetogroup-7
bind-key 4S-8 window-movetogroup-8
bind-key 4S-9 window-movetogroup-9


bind-key 4-a group-toggle-all

bind-key 4-g window-group



bind-key 4-Right group-cycle

bind-key 4-Left group-rcycle

bind-key 4-s window-stick


bind-key 4-f window-fullscreen

bind-key 4-m window-maximize

bind-key 4-equal window-vmaximize

bind-key 4S-equal window-hmaximize


bind-key 4-h window-move-left-big
bind-key 4-j window-move-down-big
bind-key 4-k window-move-up-big
bind-key 4-l window-move-right-big


bind-key 4S-h window-resize-left-big
bind-key 4S-j window-resize-down-big
bind-key 4S-k window-resize-up-big
bind-key 4S-l window-resize-right-big


bind-key 4-v window-vtile

bind-key 4-c window-htile


bind-key 4-slash menu-window

bind-key 4-d menu-cmd

bind-key 4-question menu-exec

bind-key 4-period menu-ssh


bind-key 4S-r restart

bind-key 4S-e quit


unbind-mouse M-1
unbind-mouse CM-1
unbind-mouse M-2
unbind-mouse M-3
unbind-mouse CMS-3


bind-mouse 4-1 window-move

bind-mouse 4-3 window-resize

bind-mouse 4-2 window-lower

bind-mouse 4S-2 window-hide


command xterm  xterm
command chrome &quot;chrome --enable-unveil&quot;
command xclock xclock
command xcalc  xcalc


ignore xclock
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section readability=&quot;42.399936568348&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;base-utilities&quot;&gt;Customizing the Base Utilities&lt;/h2&gt;
You'll get a much more streamlined, well documented experience if you stick to utilities in the base system. Undeadly puts it best: &lt;a href=&quot;https://undeadly.org/cgi?action=article;sid=20080607131856&quot;&gt;when in doubt, use it from base.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;ksh&quot;&gt;ksh&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OpenBSD's default shell is &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/ksh.1&quot;&gt;ksh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. While it's not as feature-rich as &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;bash&lt;/span&gt;, it's more than capable and has a few neat quirks all its own. The standard configuration is rather sparse, so feel free to borrow some of my configuration to feel more at home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;ksh&lt;/span&gt; uses the &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;$ENV&lt;/span&gt; environment variable to determine the location of its config file. Start by setting that in &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;~/.profile&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;~/.profile&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
export ENV=$HOME/.kshrc
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then you can edit &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;~/.kshrc&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;~/.kshrc&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;

case &quot;$(command -v vim)&quot; in
  */vim) VIM=vim ;;
  *)     VIM=vi  ;;
esac

export EDITOR=$VIM
export FCEDIT=$EDITOR
export PAGER=less
export LESS='-iMRS -x2'
export LANG=en_US.UTF-8
export LC_CTYPE=en_US.UTF-8
export CLICOLOR=1
HISTFILE=$HOME/.ksh_history
HISTSIZE=20000


set -o emacs


if command -v colorls &amp;gt; /dev/null ; then
  LS='colorls'
else
  LS='ls'
fi
alias ls=&quot;$LS -FHh&quot;
alias ll='ls -l'
alias la='ls -lA'
alias ..='cd ..'
alias ...='cd ...'
alias mkdir='mkdir -p'
alias df='df -h'
alias du='du -ch'
alias weather='curl http://wttr.in/New_York'
command -v neomutt &amp;gt; /dev/null &amp;amp;&amp;amp; alias mutt='neomutt'
alias svim=&quot;doas vim&quot;
alias svi=&quot;doas vi&quot;


_PS1_CLEAR='\033[0m\]'
_PS1_BLUE='\033[34m\]'
case &quot;$(id -u)&quot; in
  0) _PS1_COLOR='\033[1;31m' ;;
  *) _PS1_COLOR='\033[32m\]' ;;
esac
PS1='\A $_PS1_COLOR\u@\h$_PS1_CLEAR:$_PS1_BLUE\w$_PS1_COLOR\$$_PS1_CLEAR '
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;vi&quot;&gt;vi&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always end up installing &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;vim&lt;/span&gt; for serious editing of source code, but OpenBSD's base &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/vi.1&quot;&gt;vi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; is blazing fast. If it had syntax highlighting, it would be my default editor. It's configuration lives at &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;~/.exrc&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;~/.exrc&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;

set showmode

set showmatch

set ruler

set shiftwidth=2

set tabstop=2

set verbose

set leftright

set extended

set iclower

set searchincr

set report=1
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;tmux&quot;&gt;tmux&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/tmux.1&quot;&gt;tmux&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; is also part of the OpenBSD base system. I use the following config to get &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;vi&lt;/span&gt;-like navigation and a pretty status bar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;~/.tmux.conf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
set -g default-terminal &quot;screen-256color&quot;


setw -g mode-keys vi
bind h select-pane -L
bind j select-pane -D
bind k select-pane -U
bind l select-pane -R
bind-key -T copy-mode-vi 'v' send -X begin-selection
bind-key -T copy-mode-vi 'y' send -X copy-selection


setw -g clock-mode-colour colour117
setw -g mode-attr bold
setw -g mode-fg colour117
setw -g mode-bg colour238
set -g status-bg colour235
set -g status-fg colour248
setw -g window-status-current-fg colour223
setw -g window-status-current-bg colour237
setw -g window-status-current-attr bold
set -g message-attr bold
set -g message-fg colour117
set -g message-bg colour235


set-option -g status-right &quot;#(whoami)@#(hostname -s) #[fg=colour187,bold]%a %Y-%m-%d %H:%M&quot;
set -g status-right-length 50
set -g status-left-length 20
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;ssh&quot;&gt;ssh&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, since &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/ssh&quot;&gt;ssh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; is ubiquitous, here are some tweaks I find useful. The &lt;span class=&quot;monospce&quot;&gt;ControlPersist&lt;/span&gt; option is great, but it does require you to create the &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;~/.ssh/sockets&lt;/span&gt; directory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;~/.ssh/config&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;

TCPKeepAlive no

ServerAliveInterval 60
ServerAliveCountMax 10

ControlPersist 4h
ControlMaster auto
ControlPath ~/.ssh/sockets/socket-%r@%h:%p

VerifyHostKeyDNS yes

HashKnownHosts no

AddKeysToAgent yes
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section readability=&quot;28.772845953003&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;mail&quot;&gt;Sending Mail&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like to have a working mail transfer agent on all my devices. Being able to pipe a command to &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;mail&lt;/span&gt; can be surprisingly useful! OpenBSD includes the &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/smtpd&quot;&gt;OpenSMTPD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; mail server in the base system. You can configure your own relay, or use something like GMail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, grab a root shell and make a secrets file to store your mail credentials for the relay:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/etc/mail/secrets&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
myrelay relay_username:relay_password
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be sure to lock down permissions on that file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
chown root:_smtpd secrets
chmod 640 secrets
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then edit the &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;smtpd&lt;/span&gt; config file at &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;/etc/mail/smtpd.conf&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/etc/mail/smtpd.conf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
listen on lo0

table aliases file:/etc/mail/aliases
table secrets file:/etc/mail/secrets

action &quot;local&quot; mbox alias 
action &quot;relay&quot; relay host smtp+tls://myrelay@mail.example.com:587 auth 

match for local action &quot;local&quot;
match for any action &quot;relay&quot;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Restart &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;smtpd&lt;/span&gt; for the changes to take effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
rcctl restart smtpd
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should now have a working MTA. Test it out with the &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;mail&lt;/span&gt; command. A line containing a single dot terminates the message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
mail -s &quot;test email from laptop&quot; you@example.com
This is a test message.
.
EOT
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can check &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;/var/log/maillog&lt;/span&gt; for any errors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section readability=&quot;9.5639534883721&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;packages&quot;&gt;Installing Packages&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The base system is great, but you'll most likely want a web browser. On OpenBSD, you can install packages with &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/pkg_add&quot;&gt;pkg_add&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
doas pkg_add chromium
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can search for other packages to install with the &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/pkg_info&quot;&gt;pkg_info&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
pkg_info -Q python
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, we should probably talk a little bit about the browser situation on OpenBSD first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section readability=&quot;39.026804123711&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;chromium&quot;&gt;Chromium on OpenBSD&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firefox and Chromium are basically your only options for a decent browser that works with today's &lt;strike&gt;JavaScript cesspool&lt;/strike&gt; modern web. I've found Chromium to be much faster than Firefox, so that's what I use. However, I stay cognizant of that fact that this browser is somewhat of a botnet distributed by the world's most insidious advertising company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be sure to turn off all it's phone-home settings in the settings panel:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;disable Auto Sign-In&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;set default search engine to DuckDuckGo (or anything except Google—lots of additional telemetry gets turned on by default when Google is the default search engine)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;disable &quot;prediction service to help complete searches and URLs&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;disable &quot;prediction service to load pages more quickly&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;disable &quot;web service to help resolve navigation errors&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;disable &quot;Safe Browsing&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;disable &quot;improve Safe Browsing&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;disable &quot;Do Not Track&quot; header—it really just makes it easier to fingerprint you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;block third-party cookies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;disable &quot;offer to translate pages&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;disable &quot;show notifications when new printers are detected&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;disable &quot;continue running background apps when Chromium is closed&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also, set the following in &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;chrome://flags&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Smooth Scrolling:&lt;/em&gt; (personal preference)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;UI Layout for the browser's top chrome:&lt;/em&gt; set to &quot;Normal&quot; to get the classic Chromium look back&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Identity consistency between browser and cookie jar:&lt;/em&gt; set to &quot;Disabled&quot; to keep Google from hijacking any Google login to sign you into Chrome&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;SafeSearch URLs reporting:&lt;/em&gt; disabled&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;It should go without saying, but don't sign in to Chrome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, Chromium on OpenBSD recently got &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/unveil&quot;&gt;unveil&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; support. If you run it with &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://marc.info/?l=openbsd-ports-cvs&amp;amp;m=153250162128188&amp;amp;w=2&quot;&gt;--enable-unveil&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Chromium will be prevented (at the OS level) from accessing anything other than your &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;~/Downloads&lt;/span&gt; folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Installing &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/ublock-origin/cjpalhdlnbpafiamejdnhcphjbkeiagm&quot;&gt;uBlock Origin&lt;/a&gt; is a must—almost all websites &lt;em&gt;crawl&lt;/em&gt; without it. Switching to &lt;a href=&quot;https://duckduckgo.com/&quot;&gt;DuckDuckGo&lt;/a&gt;, along with unticking all the Google botnet &quot;features&quot; on the settings page, will greatly reduce the amount of telemetry Google collects about you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OpenBSD does have packages for &lt;a href=&quot;https://iridiumbrowser.de/&quot;&gt;Iridium Browser&lt;/a&gt;, but it's based on an older Chromium version. You'll get added privacy by using it, since they disable things at compile time that simply can't be turned off in Chromium. However, it's inherently less secure since you won't have the latest patches and security fixes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides, using uBlock, disabling third party cookies, and turning off all the Google stuff will do 90% of what Iridium does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section readability=&quot;25.418655097614&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All that's left now is to get sound working, keyboard shortcuts for changing the volume, figure out which commands set the display brightness, determine which ACPI events we need to hook into to get the laptop to suspend when you close the lid...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JUST KIDDING!&lt;/strong&gt; All that stuff works out of the box (at least on most ThinkPads). You can tell the OpenBSD developers actually dogfood this stuff, unlike another BSD derivative which I won't slander here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you do want to fiddle with the audio settings, check out &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/mixerctl&quot;&gt;mixterctl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. For example, you can get the current volume with the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
mixerctl ouputs.master
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just remember that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openbsd.org/faq/faq13.html#recordaudio&quot;&gt;audio recording is now disabled by default&lt;/a&gt; if you want to use the microphone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get the current battery status, just use &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/apm.8&quot;&gt;apm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
$ &lt;strong&gt;apm&lt;/strong&gt;
Battery state: high, 69% remaining, 274 minutes life estimate
A/C adapter state: not connected
Performance adjustment mode: auto (1200 MHz)
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section readability=&quot;15.572700296736&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;updates&quot;&gt;Updating the Base System&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OpenBSD releases binary patches for security issues found in the base system, which you can download and apply via the &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/syspatch&quot;&gt;syspatch&lt;/a&gt; utility. Just run it as root:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
syspatch
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be sure to join the &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;announce@openbsd.org&lt;/span&gt; mailing list, and run &lt;span class=&quot;monospace&quot;&gt;syspatch&lt;/span&gt; whenever a security errata is released. You can subscribe to the official OpenBSD mailing lists &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.openbsd.org&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OpenBSD does not release binary updates or patches for packages in the ports tree. If there's an update you need for a third-party package, you'll need to build it yourself, or subscribe to &lt;a href=&quot;https://stable.mtier.org/&quot;&gt;M:Tier&lt;/a&gt;. It's free for the most recent version of OpenBSD, but packages for older versions require a paid subscription.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section readability=&quot;6.9894736842105&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Other Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other than the awesome man pages, here's some additional OpenBSD resources that I've found helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openbsd.org/faq/&quot;&gt;OpenBSD FAQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: additional documentation in more of a how-to style. Definitely worth reading all the way through.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://undeadly.org&quot;&gt;OpenBSD Journal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: the &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/&quot;&gt;LWN.net&lt;/a&gt; of the OpenBSD world.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.romanzolotarev.com/&quot;&gt;Roman Zolotarev's Blog&lt;/a&gt;: this guy has a ton of resources about getting the most out of OpenBSD. Follow him on Twitter, lots of great tips!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;What are your OpenBSD laptop tweaks? Did I miss anything? Let me know on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cullumsmith&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/blakkheim&quot;&gt;@blakkheim&lt;/a&gt; for corrections and suggestions on this post!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 14:32:43 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>perlgod</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.c0ffee.net/blog/openbsd-on-a-laptop/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Aether – Free, privacy-sensitive public communities</title>
<link>https://getaether.net</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://getaether.net</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;feature-block&quot; readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;👀 Private&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aether is a &lt;strong&gt;peer-to-peer&lt;/strong&gt; app, and it has no servers. A result of this is that source IP of any specific public post cannot &lt;em&gt;(easily)&lt;/em&gt; be determined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most people use pseudonyms, though you can use your real name, or company. Aether is private by default, so that you can choose to be fully private, or fully public yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;feature-block&quot; readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;👻 Ephemeral&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aether keeps a &lt;strong&gt;6 months of content&lt;/strong&gt; by default. It's gone after. If something is worth keeping, someone will save it within six months — but not from beyond that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you screw up, argue for the wrong opinion, and then think otherwise, that's okay. No one is going to come after you — it gives you the freedom to be wrong, and move on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;feature-block&quot; readability=&quot;17&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🔮 Transparent&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actions of moderators are visible to users. &lt;strong&gt;No content can just 'disappear'&lt;/strong&gt;, if something gets deleted, you'll know who did it, why they did it, and if you want, how to get it back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moderation is important for healthy communities, and Aether adds onto it some checks-and-balances. Everyone watches the watchmen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;feature-block&quot; readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📨 Democratic&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Communities can &lt;strong&gt;elect and impeach their own mods by voting&lt;/strong&gt;. If a mod behaves inappropriately, users can disable that mod locally as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doing so reverts all changes by that moderator for the user, and counts for one impeachment vote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 14:10:24 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>HostFat</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://getaether.net/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why I&amp;#039;m Ditching Android</title>
<link>https://kevq.uk/why-im-ditching-android/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://kevq.uk/why-im-ditching-android/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Regular readers of this blog will know that I went through a process of &lt;a href=&quot;https://kevq.uk/category/de-googling&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;de-Googling my life&lt;/a&gt; a while ago. For the most part I think the process was pretty successful, however there were &lt;a href=&quot;https://kevq.uk/de-googling-my-life-06-what-i-cant-replace/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;some things that I couldn’t replace&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward a year, and after a lot of trial and error I’m ready to now take the next step in removing Google from my life – I’m ditching Android.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First I tried to ditch my smartphone completely, but that was a &lt;a href=&quot;https://kevq.uk/ditching-my-smartphone-fail/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;massive fail&lt;/a&gt;. Then I tried replacing Android with Lineage OS on a old phone I had. Whilst that meant I didn’t have any Google Apps on my device, it was still Android underneath. Also many apps kept complaining that I didn’t have Google services on the device. That got very old, very quick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So last night I decided that I’m ditching Android completely and I’ve ordered an Apple iPhone SE. You probably think I’ve jumped out of the frying pan and into the fire, but let me explain the rationale behind the decision…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Google Ad Vortex&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unless you’ve been living under a rock for the last decade, I’m sure you’re probably aware that Google’s business model is based around advertising. That’s how they make their money, and that’s why a lot of their services are free – because you are the product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, Apple’s business model is based around hardware. Yes their hardware is grossly overpriced, but the flagship Android phones are pretty much inline with Apple these days. So it’s a moot point really.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because Google make their money from advertising, it’s in their best interest to get as much information about you as possible. You only need to look at the recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://digitalcontentnext.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/DCN-Google-Data-Collection-Paper.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Digital Content Next&lt;/em&gt; paper&lt;/a&gt;, where they proved Android sends 10x more data about you back to Google than Apple does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a good &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/google/idle-android-phones-send-data-to-google-ten-times-more-often-than-ios-devices-to-apple/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;summary about the paper&lt;/a&gt; on Bleeping Computer if you can’t be bothered reading all 55 pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://kevq.uk/wp/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DCN-google-apple-stats.png&quot; data-rel=&quot;lightbox-image-0&quot; data-rl_title=&quot;&quot; data-rl_caption=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-734&quot; src=&quot;https://kevq.uk/wp/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DCN-google-apple-stats.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;792&quot; height=&quot;472&quot; srcset=&quot;https://kevq.uk/wp/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DCN-google-apple-stats.png 792w, https://kevq.uk/wp/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DCN-google-apple-stats-300x179.png 300w, https://kevq.uk/wp/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DCN-google-apple-stats-768x458.png 768w, https://kevq.uk/wp/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DCN-google-apple-stats-671x400.png 671w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 792px) 100vw, 792px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bloatware&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Android vendors are almost as bad as Windows when it comes to bundling additional applications with their devices. It’s almost a meme at this point. But at least on Windows you can uninstall all the bloatware. Most of the bloatware on Android devices I’ve used over the years cannot be removed as they’re marked as system apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you want to remove Google’s proprietary apps like Google Drive, Google Search, or Google Photos, forget it. They’re all “system apps” that cannot be uninstalled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://kevq.uk/wp/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/android-system-apps.png&quot; data-rel=&quot;lightbox-image-1&quot; data-rl_title=&quot;&quot; data-rl_caption=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-736 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://kevq.uk/wp/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/android-system-apps.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; srcset=&quot;https://kevq.uk/wp/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/android-system-apps.png 900w, https://kevq.uk/wp/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/android-system-apps-300x167.png 300w, https://kevq.uk/wp/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/android-system-apps-768x427.png 768w, https://kevq.uk/wp/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/android-system-apps-720x400.png 720w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 900px) 100vw, 900px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same is also true of iOS to a certain degree. However, on Android it’s much more prevalent. I don’t use HiCare, or Huawei Weather, or Huawei Music – let me bloody remove them!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Notifications&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the last update I received for my Android (around 6 months ago now), the new battery saving measures were implemented. Whilst the battery life on my Huawei is really good, it has done something funky to my notifications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hardly ever get notifications for emails, calendar events, social media etc. I assume this is because the battery saving measures kill the background processes. So the apps can’t carry out background tasks, like checking for new email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve tried to work around this by using the battery optimisation settings in Android, but I just can’t get it to work. On a number of occasions now I’ve missed very important emails, all because my phone decides it doesn’t want to notify me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why the iPhone SE?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I’m gonna flip to Apple, why not get the latest device, right? Well, one of my pet hates about phones these days is the sheer size of them – they’re basically a tablet in your pocket. I want a phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The iPhone SE is actually a phone sized device. It’s cheap, and it’s still supported by Apple. It’s seemed like a no-brainer to give it a try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-742 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://kevq.uk/wp/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/iPhone-SE.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;506&quot; srcset=&quot;https://kevq.uk/wp/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/iPhone-SE.jpg 900w, https://kevq.uk/wp/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/iPhone-SE-300x169.jpg 300w, https://kevq.uk/wp/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/iPhone-SE-768x432.jpg 768w, https://kevq.uk/wp/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/iPhone-SE-711x400.jpg 711w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 900px) 100vw, 900px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I doubt I will have any issues flipping to the iPhone SE, as I already have an iPad. Whilst not the perfect solution, ditching Android in favour of iOS is another step towards getting rid of Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m never going to completely get rid of Google, that’s impossible at this point,  but I think this is the right decision for me. My SE gets delivered this week, so I will post an update after a few months of use to let you guys know how I’m getting on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have you ditched Android? Or have you ditched iOS? Let me know your thoughts below.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 13:54:13 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kevq</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Why I'm Ditching Android - Kev Quirk</og:title>
<og:description>Regular readers of this blog will know that I went through a process of de-Googling my life a while ago. For the most part I think the process was pretty successful, however there were some things that I couldn’t replace. Fast forward a year, and after a lot of trial and error I’m ready to…</og:description>
<og:url>https://kevq.uk/why-im-ditching-android/</og:url>
<og:image>https://kevq.uk/wp/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/ditching-android-feature.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-GB</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://kevq.uk/why-im-ditching-android/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>What Is The Morning Writing Effect?</title>
<link>https://www.gwern.net/Morning-writing</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.gwern.net/Morning-writing</guid>
<description>&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ericsson 1993 notes that many major writers or researchers prioritized writing by making it the first activity of their day, often getting up early in the morning. This is based largely on writers anecdotally reporting they write best first thing early in the morning, apparently even if they are not morning people, although there is some additional survey/software-logging evidence of morning writing being effective. I compile all the anecdotes of writers discussing their writing times I have come across thus far. Do they, and why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interviews with writers often touch on their writing process; the hope of the reader is, deep down, to learn &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; they do the things they do and perhaps the reader can do the same thing. For the most part, the lesson I’ve taken away from such profiles is that every writer is different and there do not seem to be many generalizable practices; for every writer that thrives on writing in longhand with goose quills on parchment, another is unable to think outside a computer text editor, or needs to inhale rotting bananas, or sharpen pencils, or write in a cork-lined room, or insist on a &lt;a href=&quot;https://qualiacomputing.com/2018/06/21/john-von-neumann/&quot; title=&quot;Passing of a Great Mind: John von Neumann, a Brilliant, Jovial Mathematician, was a Prodigious Servant of Science and his Country&quot;&gt;loud phonograph/party&lt;/a&gt; for inspiration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gwern.net/docs/psychology/writing/1993-ericsson.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;q&gt;The Role of Deliberate Practice&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Ericsson 1993 (among &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newappsblog.com/2011/05/new-apps-interview-la-paul.html&quot;&gt;others&lt;/a&gt;), Ericsson draws on some anecdotes and particular long-running &amp;amp; somewhat-standardized &lt;em&gt;Paris Review&lt;/em&gt; interviews of famous writers to make some interesting points about the relative brevity of most writing sessions (perhaps not too surprising as the physical typing/writing is not the bottleneck) but also the &lt;em&gt;timing&lt;/em&gt; of it typically in the morning:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;25.037071362373&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best data on sustained intellectual activity comes from financially independent authors. While completing a novel famous authors tend to write only for 4 hr during the morning, leaving the rest of the day for rest and recuperation ([Cowley, M. (Ed.). (1959). &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Writers-Work-Paris-Review-Interviews/dp/0140045406/?tag=gwernnet-20&quot;&gt;Writers at work&lt;/a&gt;: The &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The%20Paris%20Review%23Interview%20series&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: The Paris Review#Interview series&quot;&gt;Paris review interviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.]; [&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/George%20Plimpton&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: George Plimpton&quot;&gt;Plimpton, G.&lt;/a&gt; (Ed.). (1977). &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Writers-Work-02-Paris-Review/dp/0140045414/?tag=gwernnet-20&quot;&gt;Writers at work&lt;/a&gt;: The Paris review. Interviews, second series&lt;/em&gt;.]). Hence successful authors, who can control their work habits and are motivated to optimize their productivity, limit their most important intellectual activity to a fixed daily amount when working on projects requiring long periods of time to complete…Biographies report that famous scientists such as Charles Darwin, (Erasmus Darwin, 1888), Pavlov (Babkin, 1949), Hans Selye (Selye, 1964), and B.F. Skinner (Skinner, 1983) adhered to a rigid daily schedule where the first major activity of each morning involved writing for a couple of hours. In a large questionnaire study of science and engineering faculty, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gwern.net/docs/psychology/writing/1986-kellogg.pdf&quot; title=&quot;Writing method and productivity of science and engineering faculty&quot;&gt;Kellogg (1986)&lt;/a&gt; found that writing on articles occurred most frequently before lunch and that limiting writing sessions to a duration of 1-2 hr was related to higher reported productivity…In this regard, it is particularly interesting to examine the way in which famous authors allocate their time. These authors often retreat when they are ready to write a book and make writing their sole purpose. Almost without exception, they tend to schedule 3-4 hr of writing every morning and to spend the rest of the day on walking, correspondence, napping, and other less demanding activities (Cowley, 1959; Plimpton, 1977).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Boice &amp;amp; Johnson 1984, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gwern.net/docs/psychology/writing/1984-boice.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;q&gt;Perception and practice of writing for publication by faculty at a doctoral-granting university&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hartley 1980, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gwern.net/docs/psychology/writing/1980-hartley-thepsychologyofwrittencommunication.djvu&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Psychology of Written Communication: Selected Readings&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hartley &amp;amp; Knapper 1984, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gwern.net/docs/psychology/writing/1984-hartley.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;q&gt;Academics and their writing&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lowenthal &amp;amp; Wason 1977, &lt;q&gt;Academics and their writing&lt;/q&gt;. &lt;em&gt;London Times Literary Supplement&lt;/em&gt;, June 24, p. 782.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stein 1974, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gwern.net/docs/psychology/writing/1974-stein-stimulatingcreativity-v1individualprocedures.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stimulating Creativity, Volume 1: Individual Procedures&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. New York: Academic Press.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ghiselin 1952, &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.org/details/creativeprocessa013702mbp&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Creative Process: A Symposium&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vernon et al 1970, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gwern.net/docs/psychology/writing/1970-vernon-creativity.djvu&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Creativity&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was interesting to me because I generally do not write in the morning, so knowing that morning is better would be valuable to me, and because it confused me why it would be true. If you are a morning person, you should write in the morning, and vice-versa if you are an evening person. Why would you write when you are miserable? I was especially not a morning person when I was a teenager, and it certainly showed in my first period class at 8:20AM after waking up at 6AM; certainly I never noticed any hidden gift for writing novels manifesting, even when it was a literature class. (Although I did notice a hidden gift for completely forgetting anything said in the first period.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the post hoc explanations for why morning might be better make no sense. It is true people are less likely to interrupt you early in the morning; but they are less likely to interrupt you at midnight. It is true people can find time for writing by getting up before their job; but they can sacrifice the same amount of sleep to write by staying up later at night. It is true that the morning might not be a circadian nadir; but that’s not helpful to anyone who is an owl, who by definition is sluggish in the morning, and where does all this energy come from for walking or exercising or partying or researching in the evening, when not writing, if the writer is hopelessly fashed after the vicissitudes of the day? (If the secret of morning writing is merely the nigh-tautological &lt;q&gt;if you’re a morning person who writes best in the morning, you should write in the morning, and if you’re an evening person, you should write in the evening&lt;/q&gt;, then it’s surely of no value - is there anyone who doesn’t already know whether they are more of a morning or evening person?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further, morning writing runs counter to the usual stereotype of great writers as rising late and being &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chronotype&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Chronotype&quot;&gt;chronometric&lt;/a&gt; &lt;q&gt;night owls&lt;/q&gt;. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Night%20owl%20%28person%29&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Night owl (person)&quot;&gt;&lt;q&gt;owl&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/a&gt; chronotype is usually linked with creativity &amp;amp; intelligence while morning &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lark%20%28person%29&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Lark (person)&quot;&gt;&lt;q&gt;larks&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/a&gt; are considered less creative (but more industrious &amp;amp; favored in many contexts like schools, to the detriment of owls &amp;amp; teenagers), so one would expect the opposite: writers to report writing mostly in the evening. (And amusingly, the Wikipedia article on &lt;q&gt;owls&lt;/q&gt; includes a list of dozens of writers or other creative types while the &lt;q&gt;lark&lt;/q&gt; article is devoid.) What could be more writerly or bohemian than spending the day researching or enjoying nature or drinking to jazz at the club and then returning to one’s attic in the witching hours to author deathless verse? Nevertheless, great authors routinely rehearse the advantages of living like a farmer and rising with the sun to milk the Muses. (Cal Newport’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://calnewport.com/books/deep-work/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Deep Work&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; book points this way, and there is even a writer self-help fad, &lt;q&gt;The Miracle Morning&lt;/q&gt;, whose central gimmick is getting up early.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Puzzled, I began noticing in author interviews or writings that when writing times were mentioned, it was indeed more, often than not, partially or entirely in the morning (sometimes disgustingly early like pre-dawn), rather than usually in the evening as expected, and it became startling when I ran into an exception like Ian Fleming or Winston Churchill, who wrote at all in the evening, or Brandon Sanderson or Robert Frost, who work entirely into the wee hours. I am, again, not a morning person but I forced myself up early a few days and skipped my usual email &amp;amp; news-reading routine to focus on writing, and darn if it didn’t seem to work and the writing was worth the price in afternoon circadian slumps. Still couldn’t make myself do it regularly, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section id=&quot;causes&quot; class=&quot;level1&quot; readability=&quot;5.8574648864227&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the morning writing effect is real (in the sense that successful writers do disproportionately write in the morning - which is still in doubt given the existing systematic survey evidence is limited to ordinary writers while the elite writers are represented so far purely by haphazardly-selected anecdotes), what is causing it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;35.578758290346&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;23&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One possibility is that there is some sort of ecological fallacy going on: it is possible that, creativity really is higher in owls at night, owls do not improve by writing in the morning, but the best authors are still larks (rather than owls as one would assume from the population-level correlation) and do benefit from writing in the morning (or at least aren’t hurt); and this is because larks have other advantages in becoming the best authors, perhaps related to sheer writing volume &amp;amp; consistent output. No matter how creative it is, an unwritten book is no good. Larks then could write fine at any time and would be overrepresented among the best authors either way, because writing time is confounded with other Conscientiousness-related attributes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking through the anecdotes so far, while it’s true that devotees of &lt;q&gt;The Miracle Morning&lt;/q&gt; and others frequently claim to not be larks and struggle to reap the benefits of morning writing, the &lt;em&gt;elite&lt;/em&gt; writers who happen to write in the morning (currently) do not mention major struggles with getting up early or focusing in the morning, implying that they may well all be larks in the first place!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Simonton’s &lt;q&gt;equal-odds rule&lt;/q&gt; suggests that volume of writing output is much more important than it is usually given credit for being, and that writing or research is too random a process to permit siting down for several years and decide to bang out a beloved masterpiece: one can only try as many things as possible and be surprised when one turns out well, or happens to become a hit.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;A related but somewhat simpler possibility is that people are bad at scheduling and while late-night writing is no different than morning writing and just as effective in theory, people tend to choose to fill up their schedules, and repeatedly accidentally find themselves with too little time to write at night; every hour of evening writing that people do get done is just as effective as morning hours, but there are fewer such hours. Doing it in the morning is then simply a little trick to make sure that other obligations literally cannot come first.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;6.7756833176249&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another possibility is that the day really does use up some sort of &lt;q&gt;willpower&lt;/q&gt; or &lt;q&gt;creativity&lt;/q&gt;: all the little things one does before the writing late in evening fill up one’s mind. There is nothing special about morning hours, they merely happen to be the conscious hours closest in time to sleep pushing the big reset button on the brain. If someone slept during the day &amp;amp; woke up at midnight, that person would then be best off writing at midnight, right after waking up, rather than 8 hours later in the morning, equivalent to their afternoon. (Tononi’s SHY theory of sleep would be a low-level neurobiological explanation along these lines.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;A version of this &lt;q&gt;thing building up/wearing out over the day&lt;/q&gt; is that it is related to ego depletion or &lt;q&gt;decision fatigue&lt;/q&gt; or opportunity cost, where the increasing number of accomplished activities it becomes an excuse to write less - &lt;q&gt;I had a busy day, I can take it easy tonight.&lt;/q&gt; - or one has difficulty truly focusing because there are so many other things which one could do (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sas.upenn.edu/psych/kable_lab/Joes_Homepage/Publications_files/Kurzban,%20Duckworth,%20Kable,%20Myers%20response.pdf&quot; title=&quot;'An opportunity cost model of subjective effort and task performance', Kurzban et al 2013&quot;&gt;Kurzban’s opportunity cost model&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;38.176991150442&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet another version might be that sleep itself is the key: sleep, aside from any resetting, is also responsible for memory formation and appears involved in unconscious processes of creativity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sleep is a long time period in between phases of working, allowing for &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Incubation%20%28psychology%29&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Incubation (psychology)&quot;&gt;the incubation effect&lt;/a&gt; to operate, and the incubation effect may be particularly benefited by sleep. So, one wakes up primed to work on the next piece of writing (that one has likely been mulling a long time), and by instead puttering around making tea or breakfast, one dissipates the potential. In this model, instead of one’s writing potential gradually deteriorating over the course of the day as the mind fills up/willpower is used up, it falls sharply and then hits a baseline and perhaps follows the usual circadian rhythms thereafter with a nadir at siesta time etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or, perhaps there is something special about the liminal half-sleep state, which makes fantasizing or imaging easier. One parallel we might draw is with the ancient connection between fiction writers and alcohol: writers are notorious for drinking, often to excess. Is there something about the depressant or loosening of inhibitions of alcohol which assists writing, which might also be reproduced in the morning? On the other hand, nonfiction writers like journalists or philosophers or scientists tend to be associated with stimulants, particularly &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/nicotine&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: nicotine&quot;&gt;nicotine&lt;/a&gt;, caffeine, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gwern.net/!Wikipeida&quot;&gt;amphetamines&lt;/a&gt; (not to mention &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gwern.net/Modafinil&quot;&gt;modafinil&lt;/a&gt;); while those, particularly amphetamines, are less associated with fiction writers. (This makes me wonder if there is a connection to another anomalous anecdotal phenomenon, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gwern.net/Notes#open-questions&quot;&gt;the so-called alcohol &lt;q&gt;afterglow&lt;/q&gt; effect&lt;/a&gt;, and if my poor &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gwern.net/LSD-microdosing&quot;&gt;LSD microdosing&lt;/a&gt; results reflect my own nonfiction tendencies.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This half-asleep explanation neatly explains why evening doesn’t work. It wouldn’t apply to falling asleep as there is an asymmetry: a half-asleep person in the morning who is writing is getting gradually more alert and spending the rest of the day awake, and can build on whatever mental seeds were planted; while a half-asleep person in the evening would frustrate sleep by trying to write, can’t write for long before falling asleep, and when they do fall asleep, would forget the preceding ~10 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section id=&quot;directions&quot; class=&quot;level1&quot; readability=&quot;1.9644760213144&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few things one could do to generate a little more data on this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol type=&quot;1&quot; readability=&quot;1.9615014436959&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;systematically go through the &lt;em&gt;Paris Review&lt;/em&gt; interviews and the similar &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/featured_lists/1-author-interviews&quot;&gt;GoodReads interviews&lt;/a&gt; to note down all cases where an author is asked about writing time, rather than a few examples; this avoids the risk that morning writing advocates have selectively chosen examples from the interviews. As the writers are not chosen for their writing habits and the interview question are fairly formulaic, presumably the interview series could be considered a quasi-random survey sample of successful authors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;run a population-sample survey (I have done one USA survey myself but more extensive surveys &amp;amp; surveys elsewhere would be useful)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;run surveys in more elite-writer samples&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;run a (non-blinded) self-experiment: create a list of things to systematically work on; flip a coin to decide whether to get up early, record total words-written+time-spent etc. (I can’t decide if I would be biased towards wanting it to work or wanting it to fail: of course I want to be better at writing, but on the other hand - surely there’s some easier way!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section id=&quot;research&quot; class=&quot;level1&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;36.256906077348&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;8.2507774322523&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gwern.net/docs/psychology/writing/1986-kellogg.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;q&gt;Writing method and productivity of science and engineering faculty&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Kellogg 1986: to go into more detail, it reports:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The respondents tended to schedule their work between 8AM and 8PM, with the morning hours being the most common time of day (Table 3). Positive but nonsignificant correlations were obtained for these time intervals. Night owls were rare and not unique in their productivity. In terms of the duration of writing sessions, the data indicate a preference for one to three hours. Working for 1 to 2 hours was significantly correlated with productivity. But as will be explained later in describing the multiple regression analyses, this effect is best attributed to other factors correlated with the frequency of working for 1 to 2 hours. Highly regular work scheduling was not the rule; the most common response was only a 3 on the 7 point scale. &lt;q&gt;Write in spurts&lt;/q&gt; and &lt;q&gt;marathon writing just before a deadline&lt;/q&gt; were comments listed by respondents that match the pattern commonly observed in Boice and Johnson’s (op. cit.) survey. As in Boice and Johnson’s study, regular writing was positively correlated with productivity, but here the relationship was weak and nonsignificant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead/&gt;&lt;tbody readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;odd&quot; readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Midnight-4AM (hour of day)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.76&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.29&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.01&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;even&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;4AM-8AM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.87&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.49&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.04&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;odd&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;8AM-Noon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.61&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.44&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.17&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;even&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Noon-4PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.34&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.33&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.15&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;odd&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;4PM-8PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.60&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.54&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.13&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;even&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;8PM-Midnight&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.80&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.80&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.05&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;odd&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;0-1 hour (Duration)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.50&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.58&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.09&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;even&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;1-2 hours&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.46&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.40&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.22*&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;odd&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;2-3 hours&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.44&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.36&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.07&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;even&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;3-4 hours&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.49&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.63&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-0.04&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;odd&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;More than 4 hours&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2.76&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.73&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-0.12&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;even&quot; readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Every working day (regularity)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.01&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.50&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.11&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;Table 3: Analysis of Work Scheduling (&lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt;=121; The response scale ranged from &lt;q&gt;Never&lt;/q&gt; (1) to &lt;q&gt;Always&lt;/q&gt; (7). * = &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt;&amp;lt;0.05)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Another interesting aspect of Kellogg 1986 is that almost all variables correlate non-statistically-significantly with &lt;q&gt;productivity&lt;/q&gt; (defined in Kellogg as the total number of books/papers/reports/grant-applications/grant-reports written in the previous 3 years), and most are of small magnitude. Measurement error &amp;amp; range restriction come to mind as biasing effects towards zero, but it’s still consistent with my own experience that it is difficult to find anything which strongly correlates with &lt;q&gt;productivity&lt;/q&gt;, much less causes it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;6.0350665054414&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gwern.net/docs/psychology/writing/1989-hartley.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;q&gt;The psychologist as wordsmith: a questionnaire study of the writing strategies of productive British psychologists&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Hartley &amp;amp; Branthwaite 1989 conduct a similar survey as Kellogg but do not give any statistical details that I can find, saying merely&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the present study most of our productive psychologists had no real preference for any time of day at which to work. The morning appeared to be slightly preferred to the afternoon and the afternoon slightly preferred to the evening. Regular working times were correlated with overall productivity, but productive book writers wrote sporadically (in term time). These findings were very similar to those of Kellogg (1986) who showed that the majority of his 121 engineers worked in the morning, and then the afternoon, but that a highly regular work schedule was not the rule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;3.7746096401901&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.rescuetime.com/225-million-hours-productivity/&quot;&gt;&lt;q&gt;Productivity in 2017: What we learned from analyzing 225 million hours of work time&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, RescueTime 2018; analytics over hundreds of thousands of users:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at the time spent in software development tools, our data paints a picture of a workday that doesn’t get going until the late morning and peaks between 2–6pm daily…While writers are more likely to be early birds…Writing apps were used more evenly throughout each day with the most productive writing time happening on Tuesdays at 10AM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Time spent in writing tools (light blue): RescueTime analysis of distributing of writing app use over time of day over the week: note intense band 10-11AM every day&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gwern.net/images/2018-01-04-rescuetime-writingoverweek.png&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;/&gt;&lt;q&gt;Time spent in writing tools (light blue)&lt;/q&gt;: RescueTime analysis of distributing of writing app use over time of day over the week: note intense band 10-11AM every day&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Allowing for the different time buckets, the RescueTime results closely parallel Kellogg 1986’s survey responses. Aside from being an enormous data sample, RescueTime notes an interesting contrast: despite being apparently similar activities (both mostly involve slinging text), the temporal timing of software development &amp;amp; writing are strikingly different. Thinking back, I don’t recall early-morning programming being a trend among programmers (programmers are infamous for preferring to come in late and late-night programming sessions which may wrap around the clock, especially in college - though the original reason, that &lt;q&gt;the computers are less busy at night&lt;/q&gt;, has long since expired). It’s fascinating that the stereotypes about writing vs programming line up so well with the RescueTime data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;62.547392815759&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2018 Google Surveys, general USA population sample, asking self-identified writers/researchers/scientists their chronotype &amp;amp; ideal writing time&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ran this survey in October 2018, using &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Google%20Surveys&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Google Surveys&quot;&gt;Google Surveys&lt;/a&gt;, asking a question akin to Kellogg 1986’s survey, like &lt;q&gt;if you are a professional writer, blogger, researcher, or scientist do you find you write best at: [not a writer]/[Midnight-4AM]/[4-8AM]/etc?&lt;/q&gt; At $0.10 a response, if 5% of the population could be considered some sort of writer (which sounds reasonable to me) and we want another &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt;=121 to equal Kellogg 1986’s sample size, the survey would only cost 0.10⋅20⋅121=$2420.10\cdot 20 \cdot 121 = \$242. A second question could be added to ask if the respondent considers themselves more of a morning or evening person, however, it dectuples the cost; as in my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gwern.net/Catnip-survey&quot;&gt;catnip surveys&lt;/a&gt;, it should be possible to combine the questions into a single question which can hopefully provide a useful datapoint. (GS tries for a representative population sample by techniques like reweighting; I don’t know if they take time-of-day into account and thus lark/owl type, but the surveys typically run over several days so hopefully they wind up being inherently balanced anyway.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If morning is the most common (replicating the Kellogg 1986 &amp;amp; RescueTime results), and if many evening-preferring respondents still answer that mornings work better for writing, that would be pretty good evidence for morning writing being a real phenomenon (although still leaving the causal status ambiguous and not answering the question of whether owls - like me - would benefit from switching to morning writing).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On 27 October 2018, I launched an all-ages all-gender USA population survey on Google Surveys. Because of the need to run as a 1-question survey, I condensed the two questions into one and simplified it considerably into just morning/evening preference and morning/evening self-estimated writing performance, giving 5 possible responses (1+2x2=5). As most respondents will be useless - I guesstimate 5% would consider them professional writers of some sort, so for a few hundred responses, I need 20x as many; I settled on &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt;=5000/$500 for the survey, which should deliver a precise enough result. The question looked as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol type=&quot;1&quot; readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are a writer/researcher/scientist, are you a morning/evening person &amp;amp; when do you write best? [answers displayed either ascending or descending at random]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;I don’t write or blog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Morning person; best writing during morning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Morning person; best writing during evening&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evening person; best writing during morning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evening person; best writing during evening&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The survey finished 29 October 2018 with the following results (percentage is population-weighted out of equivalent &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt;=3,999; &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; is raw counts out of the &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt;=5004 actually collected; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gwern.net/docs/psychology/writing/2018-10-27-googlesurveys-morningwriting.csv&quot;&gt;CSV&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol type=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;70% (3515)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;9.9% (467)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4.0% (196)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4.0% (193)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;12.1% (633)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;The percentage of people willing to claim to be writers was ~6x larger than I expected, which is troubling (do really &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; many people write large amounts?). Otherwise, the responses appear reasonably evenly balanced: 663 morning people vs 826 evening people. The percentage of overall counter-chronotype self-rated writing performance is 26%. On average, 55% of respondents thought evening-writing was best. The key question, of course, is whether morning-writing is more preferred for counter-chronotype writing: there is a slight preference here, but it is the &lt;em&gt;opposite&lt;/em&gt; of predicted, with 29% of morning people believing they write best in evening versus 23% of evening people saying morning is best for them. (The difference is statistically-significant at &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt;=0.008/&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt;~1.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This does not strongly endorse morning-writing, although it is surprising how many people think they write best counter-chronotype. Of course, the fact that fewer people believe they write better in the morning rather than evening doesn’t prove morning-writing isn’t a thing: one possibility is that people simply haven’t given it a fair try, or that it only works for professional writers at a high level, or that it is heterogeneous and there is a small fraction of people for whom morning-writing works really well (and so everyone should give it a try just in case). The overall even split of chronotype does give a baseline expectation for elite writers, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section id=&quot;anecdotes&quot; class=&quot;level1&quot; readability=&quot;0.96280941839404&quot;&gt;
&lt;section id=&quot;table&quot; class=&quot;level2&quot;&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Table&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead/&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;odd&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Kellogg survey&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1986&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Nonfiction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Morning-afternoon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8AM-12PM, 12PM-4PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;even&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;RescueTime users&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2018&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Nonfiction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Morning&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10AM-11AM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;odd&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Gwern Google Surveys&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2018&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fiction+Nonfiction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Evening&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;even&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Kazuo Ishiguro&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2014&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fiction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Morning&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9AM-10:30AM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;odd&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Dan Brown&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2017&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fiction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Morning&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4AM-12PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;even&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Philip Pullman&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2017&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fiction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Morning-afternoon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10AM-1PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;odd&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Ian Fleming&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1964&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fiction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Morning-evening&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10AM-12PM, 6-7PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;even&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Joseph Campbell&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Nonfiction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Morning-evening&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9AM-6PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;odd&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Charles Dickens&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fiction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Morning-afternoon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9AM-2PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;even&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Robert Frost&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fiction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Afternoon-evening&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1PM?-3AM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;odd&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Winston Churchill&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Nonfiction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Morning-evening&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11AM-1PM, 11PM-2AM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;even&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Frank Herbert&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1969&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fiction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Morning-evening&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5AM-7AM, 5PM-1AM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;odd&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Harry Harrison&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1968&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fiction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Afternoon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;12:30PM-5PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;even&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Toni Morrison&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2015&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fiction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Morning&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6AM-10AM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;odd&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Chimamanda N. Adichie&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2013&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fiction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Any&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Any&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;even&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Michael Connelly&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2017&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fiction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Morning&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4AM-7AM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;odd&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Stephenie Meyer&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2016&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fiction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Evening&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8PM-12PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;even&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Stephen King&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2014&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fiction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Morning&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8AM-12PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;odd&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Paulo Coelho&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2014&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fiction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;evening&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;?PM-4AM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;even&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Brandon Sanderson&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2012&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fiction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Evening&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;12PM-4PM, 4PM-3AM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;odd&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Margaret Atwood&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2014&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fiction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Morning-afternoon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;?AM-?PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;even&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Saint-Exupéry&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1947&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fiction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Evening&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11PM-8AM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;odd&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Neil Gaiman&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2004&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fiction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Evening&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;?PM-?AM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;even&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;John Irving&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1986&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fiction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Morning-afternoon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;?AM-?PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;odd&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Donald Hall&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2018&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fiction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Morning-afternoon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5AM-?PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;even&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Hunter Thompson&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Nonfiction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Evening&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;12AM?-6AM?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section id=&quot;examples&quot; class=&quot;level2&quot; readability=&quot;1.9213984943218&quot;&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Examples&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additional anecdotes of writers’ preferred time I’ve collected:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;32.659383801314&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;2.7281553398058&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kazuo%20Ishiguro&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Kazuo Ishiguro&quot;&gt;Kazuo Ishiguro&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/books/2014/dec/06/kazuo-ishiguro-the-remains-of-the-day-guardian-book-club&quot; title=&quot;Kazuo Ishiguro: how I wrote _The Remains of the Day_ in four weeks: The author reveals how the Tom Waits song Ruby's Arms served as inspiration for his Booker prize-winning classic novel&quot;&gt;2014 interview&lt;/a&gt;): morning+evening&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would, for a four-week period, ruthlessly clear my diary and go on what we somewhat mysteriously called a &lt;q&gt;Crash&lt;/q&gt;. During the Crash, I would do nothing but write from 9AM to 10:30PM, Monday through Saturday. I’d get one hour off for lunch and two for dinner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;8.3424101969873&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dan%20Brown&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Dan Brown&quot;&gt;Dan Brown&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/09/30/books/dan-brown-origin.html&quot; title=&quot;The World According to Dan Brown&quot;&gt;profile&lt;/a&gt;): morning (&amp;gt;4AM-noon)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;22&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr. Brown, 53, spent four years writing and researching the book. He is nothing if not disciplined. He rises at 4AM each day and prepares a smoothie comprising &lt;q&gt;blueberries, spinach, banana, coconut water, chia seeds, hemp seeds and … what’s the other kind of seed?&lt;/q&gt; he asked. &lt;q&gt;Flax seeds, and this sort of weird protein powder made out of peas.&lt;/q&gt; He also makes so-called bulletproof coffee, with butter and coconut oil, which he says changes &lt;q&gt;the way your brain processes the caffeine&lt;/q&gt; so as to sharpen your mind. His computer is programmed to freeze for 60 seconds each hour, during which time Mr. Brown performs push-ups, situps and anything else he needs to do. Though he stops writing at noon, it’s hard for him to get the stories out of his head. &lt;q&gt;It’s madness,&lt;/q&gt; he said of his characters. &lt;q&gt;They talk to you all day.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;8.85&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Philip%20Pullman&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Philip Pullman&quot;&gt;Philip Pullman&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/10/12/magazine/philip-pullman-returns-to-his-fantasy-world.html&quot; title=&quot;Philip Pullman Returns to His Fantasy World: After 17 years, the author of the trilogy &amp;quot;His Dark Materials&amp;quot; carries on the story of one of literature's most indelible heroines.&quot;&gt;profile&lt;/a&gt;): late morning-early afternoon (10AM-1PM)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;23&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every day from roughly 10 until 1, Pullman sits at his desk in a monkish study at the top of the house and produces three pages, longhand. He has written three pages a day ever since he started writing. Habit, he is fond of saying, has written far more books than talent. The ritual is sacred. As is the space. &lt;q&gt;Nobody’s photographed this, and nobody will ever photograph this,&lt;/q&gt; he told me, both fierce and faintly amused by the severity of his own rule. &lt;q&gt;I’m superstitious about that, very superstitious about that.&lt;/q&gt;…For a man whose novels are restless, whose characters never stop traveling, Pullman leads a relatively static life. After the morning shift at his desk, he spends his afternoons either tending to the 800-odd trees he and Judith have planted in the fields behind their house or in his carpentry workshop, where he makes things like reading stands and chopsticks. Occasionally, he drives an elderly woman in the village to the library, and he goes to the cinema once a week with his publisher and close friend David Fickling and their wives. &lt;q&gt;I have the company of the people I’m writing about,&lt;/q&gt; Pullman told me. &lt;q&gt;Jude and I are quite happy here with our hermit-like existence.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;26.588375416865&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ian%20Fleming&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Ian Fleming&quot;&gt;Ian Fleming&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/002-Interview-Barry-G-Golson/dp/0399507698?tag=gwernnet-20&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Playboy Interviews II&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, December 1964 interview; pg56-57): morning+evening (10AM-noon, 6-7PM)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;53&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Playboy&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;q&gt;Do you spend most of your time there at the typewriter?&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Ian Fleming&lt;/code&gt;: “By no means. I get up with the birds, which is about half-past 7, because they wake one up, and then I go and bathe in the ocean before breakfast. We don’t have to wear a swimsuit there, because it’s so private; my wife and I bathe and swim a hundred yards or so and come back and have a marvelous proper breakfast with some splendid scrambled eggs made by my housekeeper, who’s particularly good at them, and then I sit out in the garden to get a sunburn until about 10. Only then do I set to work. I sit in my bedroom and type about fifteen hundred words straightaway, without looking back on what I wrote the day before. I have more or less thought out what I’m going to write, and, in any case, even if I make a lot of mistakes, I think, well, hell, when the book’s finished I can change it all. I think the main thing is to write fast and cursively in order to get narrative speed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, about quarter-past 12, I chuck that and go down, with a snorkel and a spear, around the reefs looking for lobsters or whatever there may be, sometimes find them, sometimes don’t, and then I come back, I have a couple of pink gins, and we have a very good lunch, ordinary Jamaican food, and I have a siesta from about half-past 2 until 4. Then I sit again in the garden for about an hour or so, have another swim, and then I spend from 6 to 7 - the dusk comes very suddenly in Jamaica; at 6 o’clock it suddenly gets very dark - doing another five hundred words. I then number the pages, of which by that time there are about seven, put them away 1n a folder, and have a couple of powerful drinks, then dinner, occasionally a game of Scrabble with my wife - at which she thinks she is very much better than I am, but I know I’m the best - and straight off to bed and into a dead sleep.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Playboy&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;q&gt;And you return to England in March with a completed manuscript?&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Ian Fleming&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;q&gt;Except for minor revisions, yes.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;5.2118263473054&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joseph Campbell (&lt;a href=&quot;https://betterhumans.coach.me/joseph-campbells-daily-routine-for-the-most-important-period-of-my-scholarship-and-study-68d1c35dd0d5&quot; title=&quot;Joseph Campbell's daily routine for 'the most important period of my scholarship and study'&quot;&gt;quoted from &lt;em&gt;The Hero’s Journey: Joseph Campbell on His Life and Work&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;): researched/studied in multiple blocks morning-evening&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So during the years of the Depression I had arranged a schedule for myself. When you don’t have a job or anyone to tell you what to do, you’ve got to fix one for yourself. I divided the day into four four-hour periods, of which I would be reading in three of the four-hour periods, and free one of them. By getting up a 8 o’clock in the morning, by 9 I could sit down to read. That meant that I used the first hour to prepare my own breakfast and take care of the house and put things together in whatever shack I happened to be living in at the time. Then three hours of that first four-hour period went to reading. Then came an hour break for lunch and another three-hour unit. And then comes the optional next section. It should normally be three hours of reading and then an hour out for dinner and then three hours free and an hour getting to bed so I’m in bed by 12. On the other hand, if I were invited out for cocktails or something like that, then I would put the work hour in the evening and the play hour in the afternoon. It worked very well. I would get nine hours of sheer reading done in a day. And this went on for five years straight. You get a lot done in that time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;7.0680345572354&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charles%20Dickens&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Charles Dickens&quot;&gt;Charles Dickens&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/books/booksblog/2011/oct/27/best-times-to-write&quot; title=&quot;The best of times to write: Dickens was all done by 2pm, long before Robert Frost got going. Do your words flow better at certain times of day?&quot;&gt;based on &lt;em&gt;Charles Dickens: A Life&lt;/em&gt;, Tomalin 2011, cited by McCrum&lt;/a&gt;): morning-afternoon (9AM-2PM)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then, as you go deeper into Tomalin, you discover that Dickens, in his prime, used to compress his literary energies into five hours, roughly 9am to 2pm, after which he would walk incessantly, and put his mind into neutral. He might return to what he’d written in the morning later in the evening, but those five hours held the key to his output.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;3.3546712802768&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert%20Frost&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Robert Frost&quot;&gt;Robert Frost&lt;/a&gt; (McCrum): afternoon-late evening (?-3AM)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robert Frost, whose remote Vermont cabin I visited recently in company with his biographer Jay Parini, never started work till the afternoon, and often stayed up till two or three in the morning, not rising until midday, or even later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;15.742089552239&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Winston%20Churchill&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Winston Churchill&quot;&gt;Winston Churchill&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.artofmanliness.com/2014/12/15/the-churchill-school-of-adulthood-lesson-2-establish-a-daily-routine/&quot;&gt;as cited to &lt;em&gt;The Last Lion&lt;/em&gt;, Manchester&lt;/a&gt;): morning+late evening (~11AM-1:15PM, 11PM-2AM)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;37.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once all the newspapers have been perused, it’s time to answer the enormous amount of mail Churchill receives each day. A secretary stands by as Churchill dictates (his preferred method of &lt;q&gt;writing&lt;/q&gt;) correspondence to private citizens and government officials. Once the mail is finished, it’s time to dictate memoranda and greet any visitors who have stopped by Chartwell. &lt;q&gt;He will receive anyone except the King in his bedchamber,&lt;/q&gt; and visitors are often tickled by the image which greets them; Vice Admiral Sir Douglas Brownrigg said he presented &lt;q&gt;a most extraordinary spectacle, perched up in a huge bed, with the whole of the counterpane littered with dispatch boxes, red and all colours, and a stenographer sitting at the foot - Mr. Churchill himself with an enormous Corona in his mouth.&lt;/q&gt; Churchill’s next task is to look through galley proofs of the latest book he’s working on, and ask his chief researcher to check and verify certain details. At this point, he often begins to work on his speeches. He paces the room, issuing phrase after phrase at a speed his secretaries have trouble keeping up with. Churchill, one of them recalls, would be &lt;q&gt;dashing around in shorts and undershirt and a bright red cummerbund while I trotted behind him from room to room with a pad and pencil struggling to keep pace with the torrential flow of words.&lt;/q&gt; This flow of masterful oratory increases as the wordsmith warms up and finds his groove; &lt;q&gt;By noon the cadences of his prose have begun to trot; by 1:00PM they are galloping.&lt;/q&gt; Lunch is at 1:15, so Churchill sets aside business and gets dressed to the nines (hence the aforementioned cummerbund)…Churchill believes his afternoon naps help him be much more productive. He has found that he can only produce good writing for a few hours at a stretch, before his brain gets tired and the quality diminishes. So by breaking up his schedule with a nap, he is able to have two creative working periods each day - one in the morning and one late at night - while also having time for socializing and duck feeding…The guests have gone home or retired to their bedrooms to stay over, Churchill begins his second working shift of the day. It’s 11:00 PM, and most of his fellow Englishmen are sleeping, but Churchill is rearing to go. He slips into something more comfortable and asks his aides to join him in the library:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His appearance heralded by the harff, harff of his slippers, he enters the room in his scarlet, green, and gold dressing gown, the cords trailing behind him. Before greeting his researcher and the two secretaries on duty tonight, he must read the manuscript he dictated the previous evening and then revise the latest galleys, which arrived a few hours earlier from London. Since Churchill’s squiggled red changes exceed the copy set - the proofs look as though several spiders stained in crimson ink wandered across the pages - his printers’ bills are shocking. But the expense is offset by his extraordinary fluency. Before the night is out, he will have dictated between four thousand and five thousand words. On weekends he may exceed ten thousand words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Churchill’s night usually ends around 2 am, but when there is extra work to be done, he may not retire until 3 or 4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;7.6047700170358&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Frank%20Herbert&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Frank Herbert&quot;&gt;Frank Herbert&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sinanvural.com/seksek/inien/tvd/tvd2.htm&quot;&gt;3 February 1969 interview with Willis McNelly&lt;/a&gt;): morning+evening (5PM-1AM and 5AM-7AM)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;19&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Willis McNelly&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;q&gt;What is your writing schedule?&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Frank Herbert&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;q&gt;Well, it varies…depends on what I’m doing…writing for the magazine…but as a general rule it goes like this: I’ll get home somewhere around 5 o’clock when Bev is here, when she’s not working as she has been the last couple of weeks. She’ll have dinner ready at that time or very close to that time. I’ll then take an hour’s nap and then work sometimes until 1 o’clock in the morning. Then I hit the sack and get up and sometimes if a story is strong in me I get up in the morning and write…get up at 5 o’clock in the morning or so and write for an hour or two sometimes before going down to San Francisco.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;WM&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;q&gt;Yes.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;FH&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;q&gt;And this is the thing I want to get out of because I can write 8 hours a day in 2 bursts and I don’t see any reason why I shouldn’t be doing what I want…writing what I want to write during those times. I don’t envision supporting myself entirely by science fiction writing in the sense of writing only science fiction, because I have other axes to grind, too.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;3.9138461538462&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Harry%20Harrison%20%28writer%29&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Harry Harrison (writer)&quot;&gt;Harry Harrison&lt;/a&gt; (McNelly interview with Frank Herbert): afternoon (12:30PM-5PM)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Willis McNelly&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;q&gt;It’s interesting…Harry Harrison describes the writing process with him rather well in a tape I made with him a few months ago. He is absolutely uninterruptible from, say, 12:30 in the afternoon ’til 5:00 at night, because the ideas as they form in his mind sort of becomes extensions of his [cough] excuse me, fingers in his typewriter and that they are up here and that …that any interruption, whether it be a telephone ringing or his wife knocking at the door or anything at all is liable to shatter that idea as it transforms itself into paper.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;4.6404494382022&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Toni%20Morrison&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Toni Morrison&quot;&gt;Toni Morrison&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/interviews/show/1029.Toni_Morrison&quot; title=&quot;Interview with Toni Morrison&quot;&gt;Goodreads interview&lt;/a&gt;): early morning (6AM-10AM?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Goodreads&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;q&gt;What’s your average writing day like? When do you write?&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Toni Morrison&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;q&gt;Very early in the morning, before the sun comes up. Because I’m very smart at that time of day. Now, at this time of day [4PM], it’s all drifting away. But tomorrow morning I will be sharp for about 4 hours, say from 6AM to 10AM. If I get up before the sun and greet it, that’s when I start.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;2.2371638141809&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chimamanda%20Ngozi%20Adichie&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Chimamanda Ngozi Adichie&quot;&gt;Chimamanda Ngozi Adichie&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/interviews/show/857.Chimamanda_Ngozi_Adichie&quot; title=&quot;Interview with Chimamanda Ngozi Adichie&quot;&gt;Goodreads interview&lt;/a&gt;): no particular time&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote the book in both Nigeria and the U.S. I don’t have a routine. I like silence and space whenever and wherever I can get it. When the writing is going well, I’m obsessive - I roll out of bed and go to work. I write and rewrite a lot and shut everything out. When it is not going well, I sink into a dark place and read books I love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;6.3783251231527&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Michael Connelly (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/interviews/show/1275.Michael_Connelly&quot;&gt;Goodreads interview&lt;/a&gt;): very early morning when possible (4AM-6AM? pre-dawn)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;18&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Goodreads&lt;/code&gt;: What’s your writing process?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Michael Connelly&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;q&gt;Because of working on a TV show [&lt;em&gt;Bosch&lt;/em&gt;], my writing process is to write whenever I get a chance. Also, my training in journalism has taught me to write - I don’t need to be coddled. I can write in my office, I can write on planes, I can write in cars. I was on a plane last night for five hours, squeezed in so tight, my elbows were pushing into my ribs, but I wrote the whole time and got a lot done. That’s my process: to try to write whenever I can. A perfect day would be to get up before the light gets up in the sky and start writing and get a lot done before the rest of the city wakes up. That’s what I try to do when I’m at home or even when I’m in a hotel on the road. Morning hours are really good for me, dark morning hours. So in that regard I kind of share something with Renée [&lt;em&gt;The Late Show&lt;/em&gt; character] because I like to work till dawn.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;29.151239958086&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stephenie%20Meyer&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Stephenie Meyer&quot;&gt;Stephenie Meyer&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/interviews/show/1189.Stephenie_Meyer&quot; title=&quot;Interview with Stephenie Meyer&quot;&gt;Goodreads interview&lt;/a&gt;): evening (8PM-?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;18&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Goodreads&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;q&gt;Do you have any writing rituals?&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Stephenie Meyer&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;q&gt;None, really, besides time of day. I can never get truly immersed in writing during the daytime. I know it’s a product of being interrupted by work calls and emails, children’s and husband’s questions about where fill-in-the-blank is located, and the dog’s bladder needs. Subconsciously my brain believes that there is no point in trying to focus when my office door is just about to slam open in three…two…one…. So now, even when I’m in a quiet, private environment, I can’t make my brain accept that it is possible to write while the sun is out. When I’m in the middle of a story, I do my self-editing during the day. That part handles interruptions better.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://entertainment.inquirer.net/86937/stephenie-meyer-recaps-twilight-journey&quot; title=&quot;Stephenie Meyer recaps 'Twilight' journey&quot;&gt;2013 interview&lt;/a&gt; clarifies that darkness means late night, not early morning pre-dawn:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That vivid scene took place in the kitchen but these days, she writes in an office room in her house. Like most writers, Stephenie prefers to write in the evening. &lt;q&gt;I write best at night, which is one of the reasons that I’m so slow now,&lt;/q&gt; she said. &lt;q&gt;My kids’ school schedule has forced me to be a morning person, which I am not. I don’t get so much done during the day. There are too many interruptions. It’s better if I can start at 8PM and work through till I pass out.&lt;/q&gt; Laughing, she quipped, &lt;q&gt;Maybe, I should move back into the kitchen.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://stepheniemeyer.com/the-story-of-twilight-getting-published/&quot; title=&quot;The Story Behind _Twilight_&quot;&gt;an autobiographical piece&lt;/a&gt;, Meyers says that the idea for &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Twilight%20%28Meyer%20novel%29&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Twilight (Meyer novel)&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Twilight&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; came in a dream &amp;amp; was initially written in the morning but the bulk was written at night:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;23&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I woke up (on that June 2nd) from a very vivid dream…Though I had a million things to do (i.e. making breakfast for hungry children, dressing and changing the diapers of said children, finding the swimsuits that no one ever puts away in the right place, etc.), I stayed in bed, thinking about the dream. I was so intrigued by the nameless couple’s story that I hated the idea of forgetting it; it was the kind of dream that makes you want to call your friend and bore her with a detailed description. (Also, the vampire was just so darned good-looking, that I didn’t want to lose the mental image.) Unwillingly, I eventually got up and did the immediate necessities, and then put everything that I possibly could on the back burner and sat down at the computer to write-something I hadn’t done in so long that I wondered why I was bothering. But I didn’t want to lose the dream, so I typed out as much as I could remember, calling the characters &lt;q&gt;he&lt;/q&gt; and &lt;q&gt;she.&lt;/q&gt; From that point on, not one day passed that I did not write &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt;. On bad days, I would only type out a page or two; on good days, I would finish a chapter and then some. I mostly wrote at night, after the kids were asleep so that I could concentrate for longer than five minutes without being interrupted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;2.7639593908629&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stephen%20King&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Stephen King&quot;&gt;Stephen King&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/interviews/show/989.Stephen_King&quot;&gt;Goodreads interview&lt;/a&gt;): morning (8AM-noon)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Goodreads&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;q&gt;What’s your average working day like? Do you have any unusual habits/rituals?&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Stephen King&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;q&gt;I start work around 8AM and usually finish around noon. If there’s more to do, I do it in the late afternoon, although that isn’t prime time for me. The only ritual is making tea. I use the loose leaves and drink it by the gallon.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;6.2478097622028&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paulo%20Coelho&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Paulo Coelho&quot;&gt;Paulo Coelho&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/interviews/show/971.Paulo_Coelho&quot;&gt;Goodreads interview&lt;/a&gt;): late evening? (?-4AM)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;18&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Goodreads&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;q&gt;Do you write as soon as you wake up in the morning?&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Paulo Coelho&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;q&gt;First I say that I’m going to write as soon as I wake up. Then I postpone and postpone and start feeling guilty and horrible and feel that I don’t deserve anything. Then I say, OK, today I’m not going to write. Then I write just to not feel guilty, and I’m going to write the first sentence. Then once I’m off the ground, the plane takes off…when I’m writing, I wake up around 12 o’clock because I write until 4 in the morning. Only two weeks. Then of course, I have to make the corrections and do another draft. I have to correct the second draft. So the first draft has, let’s say, one-third more pages than the final draft. So I start cutting.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;11.598971722365&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brandon%20Sanderson&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Brandon Sanderson&quot;&gt;Brandon Sanderson&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;http://faq.brandonsanderson.com/node/351&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt;): afternoon+late evening (noon-5PM, 8PM-3AM)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was in college, I got a job working the graveyard shift at a hotel, which was great for my writing because I was there most weeknights from 11 pm until 7 am, and the only requirements that they put me to were, &lt;q&gt;Just don’t fall asleep. Do whatever you want, just don’t fall asleep. We need you awake in case there’s an emergency or if anyone comes in.&lt;/q&gt; I ended up spending a lot of my time working on novels during those early morning hours, and that’s how I was able to pay for school, attend it full-time, and still have time for writing. I still do most of my writing in the middle of the night…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theoryland.com/intvmain.php?i=740&quot;&gt;2012 chat interview&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sanderson works best at night. &lt;q&gt;I get up about noon,&lt;/q&gt; he says, &lt;q&gt;write until five, and then spend a few hours with the family before starting work again about eight o’clock and then I write until the early morning hours. I often don’t get to bed before three am.&lt;/q&gt; He did try getting up at what most people would consider to be a more normal hour, but after a few weeks his wife capitulated, saying, &lt;q&gt;This routine is making you miserable. Go back to being a night owl!&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;5.3924897119342&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Margaret Atwood (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/interviews/show/990.Margaret_Atwood&quot;&gt;Goodreads interview&lt;/a&gt;): morning-afternoon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Goodreads&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;q&gt;Can you describe a typical day spent writing?&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Margaret Atwood&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;q&gt;There are no typical days spent writing. Let’s pretend there is one. I would get up. We would have breakfast. Then we have the coffee. That is something I really like to have to get myself started. Then I would probably sit down and type something that I had written in manuscript the day before. It’s a kind of overlap method, in which I’m typing out what I did the day before to get myself going for what I’m going to add on to that. I’m revising and then continuing to write in the same day. Then I do the next bit of new writing in the afternoon. I don’t go by how much time I spent at it but how many pages I managed to complete.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Goodreads&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;q&gt;Would you say you have any unusual writing habits?&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Margaret Atwood&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;q&gt;I’m not particularly obsessive about that. But I don’t like other people using my computer. Who does like that?&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;13.483757682177&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saint-Exupéry, in writing &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The%20Little%20Prince%23Tone%20and%20writing%20style&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: The Little Prince#Tone and writing style&quot;&gt;The Little Prince&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; preferred evenings, starting at 11PM, or even later, as described by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.trussel.com/saint-ex/galant.htm&quot;&gt;Lewis Galantière in 1947&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;23&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saint-Exupéry wrote beautifully, but at the price of great effort. He went out rarely, but he had friends in almost every day to lunch and dinner. In the evening, when his friends had gone, he would brew himself a great pot of coffee and sit down to work at his dining table (his desk served merely as a catchall in which his checkbook could never be found). Now and then he would write in an all-night restaurant, where, having eaten a dish of raw chopped beef drowned in olive oil and crusted with pepper, be was likely to scribble from 2 in the morning until dawn. When be had written himself stiff, be would stretch out at home on a sofa under a lamp, take up the mouthpiece of a dictaphone, and record his copy, revising as he went along. Then, towards 7 or 8 o’clock in the morning, he would go to bed. The secretary would come in at 9 and type while be slept. Often, when friends arrived for lunch at 1 o’clock, they would ring and pound for 20 minutes before he woke up and let them in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neil%20Gaiman&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Neil Gaiman&quot;&gt;Neil Gaiman&lt;/a&gt; is described as a night owl (eg collaborators interviewed in &lt;em&gt;Conversations With the Dream King&lt;/em&gt; describe him as phoning them usually late at night or as a &lt;q&gt;vampire&lt;/q&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;6.7678391959799&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John%20Irving&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: John Irving&quot;&gt;John Irving&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theparisreview.org/interviews/2757/john-irving-the-art-of-fiction-no-93-john-irving&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Paris Review&lt;/em&gt; interview&lt;/a&gt;) appears to write mostly in the morning to afternoon:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;19&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A novel is such a long involvement; when I’m beginning a book, I can’t work more than two or three hours a day. I don’t know more than two or three hours a day about a new novel. Then there’s the middle of a book. I can work eight, nine, twelve hours then, seven days a week - if my children let me; they usually don’t. One luxury of making enough money to support myself as a writer is that I can afford to have those eight-, nine-, and twelve-hour days. I resented having to teach and coach, not because I disliked teaching or coaching or wrestling but because I had no time to write. Ask a doctor to be a doctor two hours a day. An eight-hour day at the typewriter is easy; and two hours of reading over material in the evening, too. That’s routine. Then when the time to finish the book comes, it’s back to those two- and three-hour days. Finishing, like beginning, is more careful work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;0.95925925925926&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theparisreview.org/blog/2018/08/08/notes-nearing-ninety-learning-to-write-less/&quot; title=&quot;Notes Nearing Ninety: Learning to Write Less&quot;&gt;Donald Hall&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back then, I wrote all day, getting up at five. By this time, I rise scratchy at six or twitch in bed until seven. I drink coffee before I pick up a pen. I look through the newspaper. I try to write all morning, but exhaustion shuts me down by ten o’clock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;5.9324462640737&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hunter%20Thompson&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Hunter Thompson&quot;&gt;Hunter Thompson&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://mentalfloss.com/article/33487/hunter-s-thompsons-daily-routine&quot;&gt;Carroll’s biography&lt;/a&gt; includes a supposed daily schedule where Thompson starts writing at midnight until 6AM (but the schedule is so clearly exaggerated &amp;amp; humorous in the level of drug use claimed that I don’t know how seriously to take any of it); one of his editors, &lt;a href=&quot;https://lithub.com/so-youve-decide-to-write-what-i-learned-editing-hunter-s-thompson/&quot;&gt;Terry McDonnell&lt;/a&gt; says &lt;q&gt;When he got you on the phone in the middle of the night to listen to someone in his kitchen read to you what he had just written, all you could say was that it sounded good and that he should send it to you&lt;/q&gt;; a collection of letters includes him &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.signature-reads.com/2018/07/hunter-s-thompson-sanity-writers/&quot;&gt;telling a landlady to put down carpets so his typing late at night won’t keep her up&lt;/a&gt;; his &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theparisreview.org/interviews/619/hunter-s-thompson-the-art-of-journalism-no-1-hunter-s-thompson&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Paris Review&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; interviewer describes him as keeping late hours on &lt;q&gt;Owl Farm&lt;/q&gt; and the interview went into the night, where he describes his first writing job as having the advantage of letting him write entirely at night. All together, there’s no doubt Thompson preferred late night, and midnight-6AM specifically does seem plausible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section id=&quot;external-links&quot; class=&quot;level1&quot;&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 09:07:10 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jxub</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.gwern.net/Morning-writing</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Housing can’t both be a good investment and be affordable</title>
<link>http://cityobservatory.org/housing-cant-be-affordable_and_be-a-good-investment/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://cityobservatory.org/housing-cant-be-affordable_and_be-a-good-investment/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A fundamental contradiction lies beneath most of our housing policy debates&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;At City Observatory, we’ve frequently &lt;a href=&quot;http://cityobservatory.org/homeownership-can-exacerbate-inequality/&quot;&gt;made&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://cityobservatory.org/homeownership-a-failed-wealth-creation-strategy/&quot;&gt;the case&lt;/a&gt; that promoting homeownership as an investment strategy is a risky proposition. No financial advisor would recommend going into debt in order to put such a massive part of your savings in any other single financial instrument—and one that, as we learned just a few years ago, carries a great deal of risk.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Even worse, that risk isn’t random: It falls most heavily on low-income, black, and Hispanic buyers, who are given worse mortgage terms, and whose neighborhoods are systematically more likely to see low or even falling home values, with devastating effects on the racial wealth gap.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;But let’s put all that aside for a moment. What if housing&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;were&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;a low-risk, can’t-miss bet for growing your personal wealth? What would that world look like?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Well, in order for your home to offer you a real profit, its price would need to increase faster than the rate of inflation. Let’s pick something decent, but not too crazy—say, annual increases of 2.5 percent, taking inflation into account. So if you bought a home for $200,000 and sold it ten years later, you’d be looking at a healthy profit of just over $56,000.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Sound good? Well, what if I told you that such a city existed? What if I told you it was in a beautiful natural setting, with hills and views of the ocean? And a booming economy? And lots of organic produce?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/otolithe/2241690292/in/photolist-4q6fqC-b6FVfD-eUcDoN-gHEHs-r6YMmE-mQjN7i-abigRk-wS7pFF-btG3uS-skiDQA-ex6mwr-mMULyD-9qb3U3-HbtCbX-ntADcs-967ktA-by84f2-E47bZs-4fbu38-aPq48M-7KiNFB-eNfNcL-4tDJ7J-b7HmjZ-c19dku-b9NGQ4-oiNog-G4oxfZ-ax1vSy-9qySWt-s1KQAh-8D5f6w-bNQKrD-5TTbt5-bLNVaR-bzqxbU-xcxTxV-7U64ZE-qbXBJy-Ecaiho-jAQenG-kppUf-dNoXM5-fkDJe-hUtGLi-4X6kq9-bvtjvR-F98iZ6-diR2Tc-9rRADb&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-2848&quot; src=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/cityobservatory.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/2241690292_bdf4d335b4_b.jpg?resize=640%2C480&quot; alt=&quot;Credit: Olivier ROUX, Flickr&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; srcset=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/cityobservatory.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/2241690292_bdf4d335b4_b.jpg?w=1024 1024w, https://i1.wp.com/cityobservatory.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/2241690292_bdf4d335b4_b.jpg?resize=300%2C225 300w, https://i1.wp.com/cityobservatory.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/2241690292_bdf4d335b4_b.jpg?resize=768%2C576 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Credit: Olivier ROUX, Flickr
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Maybe you’ve guessed by now: The wonderland of ever-increasing housing prices is San Francisco. When researcher&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://cityobservatory.org/the-long-road-to-san-francisco/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Eric Fischer went back to construct a database of rental prices&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;there, he found that rents had been growing by about 2.5 percent, net of inflation, for about 60 years. And&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.economist.com/blogs/graphicdetail/2015/11/daily-chart-0&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;this Zillow data suggests&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;that San Francisco owner-occupied home prices have been growing by just over 2.5 percent since 1980 as well.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Like I said, over ten years, that gives you a profit of just over 25 percent. But compound interest is an amazing thing, and the longer this consistent wealth-building goes on, the more out of hand housing prices get. In 1980, Zillow’s home price index for San Francisco home prices was about $310,000 (in 2015 dollars). By 2015, after 35 years of averaging 2.5 percent growth, home prices were over $750,000.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-2851&quot; src=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/cityobservatory.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/Screen-Shot-2016-07-19-at-9.46.59-PM.png?resize=592%2C480&quot; alt=&quot;Screen Shot 2016-07-19 at 9.46.59 PM&quot; width=&quot;592&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; srcset=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/cityobservatory.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/Screen-Shot-2016-07-19-at-9.46.59-PM.png?w=592 592w, https://i1.wp.com/cityobservatory.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/Screen-Shot-2016-07-19-at-9.46.59-PM.png?resize=300%2C243 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 592px) 100vw, 592px&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Now, if all you cared about were wealth building, this would be fantastic news. The system works! (Although actually even this rosy scenario is missing some wrinkles: San Francisco real estate prices did suffer enormously, if briefly, during the late-2000s crash, and if you bought in the mid-2000s and had to sell in, say, 2010, you would have taken a massive loss.)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;But this sort of wealth building is predicated on a never-ending stream of new people who are willing and able to pay current home owners increasingly absurd amounts of money for their homes. It is, in other words, a massive up-front transfer of wealth from younger people to older people, on the implicit promise that when those young people become old, there will be new young people willing to give them even&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;more&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;money. And of course, as prices rise, the only young people able to buy into this ponzi scheme are quite well-to-do themselves. And because we’re not talking about stocks, but homes, “buying into this ponzi scheme” means “able to live in San Francisco.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In other words, possibly the only thing worse than a world in which homeownership doesn’t work as a wealth-building tool is a world in which it does work as a wealth-building tool.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;This also means that the two stated pillars of American housing policy—homeownership as wealth-building and housing affordability—are fundamentally at odds. Mostly, American housing policy resolves this contradiction by quietly deciding that it really doesn’t care that much about affordability after all. While funds for low-income subsidized housing languish, much larger pots of money are set aside for promoting homeownership through subsidies like the mortgage interest deduction and capital gains exemption, most of which goes to upper-middle- or upper-class households.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;But even markets with large amounts of affordable housing demonstrate the contradiction. Since at least the second half of the 20th century, the vast majority of actually affordable housing has been created via&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://cityobservatory.org/what-filtering-can-and-cant-do/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;“filtering”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;: that is, the falling relative prices of market-rate housing as it ages, or its neighborhood loses social status, often as a result of racial changes. Low-income affordability, where it does exist, is predicated on large portions of the housing market acting as terrible investments.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;And to the extent that low-income people do find a subsidized, price-fixed housing unit to live in, that means that they won’t be building any wealth, even as their richer, market-housing-dwelling neighbors do, increasing wealth inequality.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Even the community land trust, which seems to be a way of squaring the wealth-building/affordability circle, ultimately fails. Community land trusts typically provide subsidized or reduced price ownership opportunities to initial buyers, and assure longer term affordability by limiting the resale price of the home. In other words, CLT-financed homes remain affordable only because they restrict how much wealth building the initial owners are allowed to capture. The result is that CLT-financed homes&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/local/flawed-dc-housing-program-sticks-developer-with-2-unsold-condos-for-3-years/2014/11/01/47fbdaf0-6154-11e4-8b9e-2ccdac31a031_story.html&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;only attract those who couldn’t otherwise purchase a home&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;—which means that the lower-income people in CLTs will be building wealth more slowly than higher-income people in market-rate housing, a fundamentally inequality-increasing situation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We say we want housing to be cheap and we want home ownership to be a great financial investment. Until we realize that these two objectives are mutually exclusive, we’ll continue to be frustrated by failed and oftentimes counterproductive housing policies.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 23:49:02 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>DoreenMichele</dc:creator>
<og:title>City Observatory - Housing can’t both be a good investment and be affordable</og:title>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>http://cityobservatory.org/housing-cant-be-affordable_and_be-a-good-investment/</og:url>
<og:image>http://cityobservatory.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/8885270785_63a210196a_h.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>The City Observatory is a study of modern-day cities and urban development practices.</og:description>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://cityobservatory.org/housing-cant-be-affordable_and_be-a-good-investment/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Thelio – System76</title>
<link>https://system76.com/desktops</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://system76.com/desktops</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Thelio Shells&quot; src=&quot;https://system76.com/assets/assets/thelio/page/pricelist-bg_640.jpg&quot; type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot; data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;summaries&quot; data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot; readability=&quot;13.073529411765&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;theio title&quot; data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;Thelio&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Thelio Motherboard&quot; src=&quot;https://system76.com/assets/assets/thelio/page/thelio-mb-regular_640.jpg&quot; type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot; data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;ul class=&quot;thelio specs&quot; data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;li data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;Ryzen or Core CPUs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;Up to 32GB of Memory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;Radeon or GeForce GPUs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;Up to 24TB of Storage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;Space-Saving Design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;$1,099&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;Pre-Order now!&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;Shipments begin early December&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;major title&quot; data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;Thelio Major&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Thelio Major Motherboard&quot; src=&quot;https://system76.com/assets/assets/thelio/page/thelio-mb-major_640.jpg&quot; type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot; data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;ul class=&quot;major specs&quot; data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;li data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;Threadripper or Core-X CPUs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;Up to 128GB of Memory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;Up to 4 GPUs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;Up to 46TB of Storage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;Maximum Configurability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;$2,299&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;Pre-Order now!&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;Shipments begin early December&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;massive title&quot; data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;Thelio Massive&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Thelio Massive Motherboard&quot; src=&quot;https://system76.com/assets/assets/thelio/page/thelio-mb-massive_640.jpg&quot; type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot; data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;ul class=&quot;massive specs&quot; data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;li data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;Dual XEON CPUs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;Up to 768GB of ECC Memory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;Up to 4 GPUs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;Up to 86TB of Storage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;Epitome of performance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;$2,899&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;Pre-Order now!&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;Shipments begin late December&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 data-v-646c34ae=&quot;&quot;&gt;Easily Expandable&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot; data-v-646c34ae=&quot;&quot;&gt;Tinker to your heart’s desire. Thelio systems are created for you to customize with ease. Slip in drives, add memory, upgrade graphics cards. Add your own personal touch and make your computer feel like it’s really, truly yours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;button&quot; data-v-646c34ae=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Easily Expandable&quot; src=&quot;https://system76.com/assets/assets/thelio/page/expandable-video_640.jpg&quot; type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot; data-v-646c34ae=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Play Icon&quot; src=&quot;data:image/svg+xml;base64,PHN2ZyBpZD0icGxheS1pY29uIiB2ZXJzaW9uPSIxLjEiIHZpZXdCb3g9IjAgMCAxNTAgMTUwIiB4bWxucz0iaHR0cDovL3d3dy53My5vcmcvMjAwMC9zdmciPgogIDxwYXRoIGlkPSJjaXJjbGUiIGQ9Im03NSAwYy00MS40MDggMC03NSAzMy41OS03NSA3NSAwIDQxLjQxIDMzLjU5IDc1IDc1IDc1IDQxLjQwOCAwIDc1LTMzLjU5IDc1LTc1IDAtNDEuNDEtMzMuNTktNzUtNzUtNzV6bTAgMi4wODc0YzQwLjI4IDAgNzIuOTEgMzIuNjMxIDcyLjkxIDcyLjkxIDAgNDAuMjc5LTMyLjYzMSA3Mi45MS03Mi45MSA3Mi45MS00MC4yOCAwLTcyLjkxLTMyLjYzMS03Mi45MS03Mi45MSAwLTQwLjI3OSAzMi42MzEtNzIuOTEgNzIuOTEtNzIuOTF6IiBzdHlsZT0iZmlsbDojZmZmIi8+CiAgPHBhdGggaWQ9InRyaWFuZ2xlIiBkPSJtNTYuNDY1IDEwNy4wN3YtNjQuMTIzbDU1LjUzIDMyLjA2MXoiIHN0eWxlPSJmaWxsOiNmZmYiLz4KPC9zdmc+Cg==&quot; class=&quot;icon&quot; data-v-646c34ae=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Pop!_OS overview layers&quot; src=&quot;https://system76.com/assets/assets/thelio/page/thumbnail-monitor_640.jpg&quot; type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot; data-v-47f87702=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;div data-v-47f87702=&quot;&quot; readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 data-v-47f87702=&quot;&quot;&gt;Perfect with Pop!_OS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot; data-v-47f87702=&quot;&quot;&gt;Pop!_OS by System76 and Thelio together form the perfect platform to create and discover. Thelio is optimized for maximum performance. Pop!_OS provides tools and development platforms that are always up-to-date and just a single click or command away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot; data-v-47f87702=&quot;&quot;&gt;Write software. Build robots. Train AI models. Dev those ops. Frag your Steam friends on the side! Have fun making a better world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Thelio IO board&quot; src=&quot;https://system76.com/assets/assets/thelio/page/thumbnail-thelio-io_640.jpg&quot; type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot; data-v-47f87702=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;div data-v-47f87702=&quot;&quot; readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 data-v-47f87702=&quot;&quot;&gt;Optimized by Thelio Io&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot; data-v-47f87702=&quot;&quot;&gt;Thelio Io is a System76 designed chassis controller and hard drive backplane that moves proprietary functionality from the mainboard to the open source Thelio Io daughterboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot; data-v-47f87702=&quot;&quot;&gt;Moving chassis and thermal control to Thelio Io enables far more granular performance optimization. Motherboard data, fan speed, and GPU and OS data are used to coordinate optimal airflow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot; data-v-47f87702=&quot;&quot;&gt;Thelio Massive also includes an open source System76 designed SAS backplane for high performance 2.5” PCIe storage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Unleash with tux&quot; src=&quot;https://system76.com/assets/assets/thelio/page/thumbnail-tux_640.jpg&quot; type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot; data-v-47f87702=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;div data-v-47f87702=&quot;&quot; readability=&quot;19.399624765478&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 data-v-47f87702=&quot;&quot;&gt;Open hardware licensed to give you rights&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot; data-v-47f87702=&quot;&quot;&gt;Thelio, Thelio Major, Thelio Massive, and Thelio Io are OSHWA certified open source hardware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot; data-v-47f87702=&quot;&quot;&gt;Licensed under GPL v3 and CC-BY-SA, everyone can learn from what we've created, adapt it, improve it, and make derivative works inspired by the Thelio design. We hope Thelio can be a spark for open source hardware, just as GNU and Linux were the sparks that forever changed the way software was developed and shared nearly three decades ago. Thelio and Thelio Io design files are &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/system76/thelio&quot; data-v-47f87702=&quot;&quot;&gt;hosted on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d1vhcvzji58n1j.cloudfront.net/assets/v3/img/us-flag.bf68c63.svg&quot; class=&quot;flag&quot; data-v-0e1d6ed1=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;h2 data-v-0e1d6ed1=&quot;&quot;&gt;Designed and Manufactured in Colorado&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot; data-v-0e1d6ed1=&quot;&quot;&gt;US-sourced wood and aluminum are formed, finished, etched, and built by artisans in our Denver, Colorado factory. Premium components from around the world are then assembled to your final specifications. And to offset environmental impact, &lt;strong data-v-0e1d6ed1=&quot;&quot;&gt;every Thelio sold plants a tree with the National Forest Foundation&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot; data-v-0e1d6ed1=&quot;&quot;&gt;We back Thelio with a 30-day money back guarantee, lifetime technical support, free two-year hardware warranty, and rapid software updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Colorado Mountains&quot; src=&quot;https://system76.com/assets/assets/thelio/page/colorado-bg_640.jpg&quot; type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot; data-v-0e1d6ed1=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 22:52:41 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>secure</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://system76.com/</og:url>
<og:title>Thelio</og:title>
<og:description>Thelio Desktops boast an arsenal of components for maximum configurability to achieve the epitome of performance. System76 computers are custom-built to run Linux flawlessly.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://system76.com/desktops</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>New antimatter gravity experiments begin at CERN</title>
<link>https://home.cern/about/updates/2018/11/new-antimatter-gravity-experiments-begin-cern</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://home.cern/about/updates/2018/11/new-antimatter-gravity-experiments-begin-cern</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;We learn it at high school: release two objects of different mass in the absence of friction forces and they fall down at the same rate in Earth’s gravity. What we haven’t learned, because it hasn’t been directly measured in experiments, is whether &lt;a href=&quot;https://home.cern/topics/antimatter&quot;&gt;antimatter&lt;/a&gt; falls down at the same rate as ordinary matter or if it might behave differently. Two new experiments at CERN, ALPHA-g and GBAR, have now started their journey towards answering this question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ALPHA-g is very similar to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://home.cern/about/experiments/alpha&quot;&gt;ALPHA experiment&lt;/a&gt;, which makes neutral antihydrogen atoms by taking antiprotons from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://home.cern/about/accelerators/antiproton-decelerator&quot;&gt;Antiproton Decelerator&lt;/a&gt; (AD) and binding them with positrons from a sodium-22 source. ALPHA then confines the resulting neutral antihydrogen atoms in a magnetic trap and shines laser light or microwaves onto them to measure their internal structure. The ALPHA-g experiment has the same type of apparatus for making and trapping antiatoms, except that it is oriented vertically. With this vertical set-up, researchers can precisely measure the vertical positions at which the antihydrogen atoms annihilate with normal matter once they switch off the trap’s magnetic field and the atoms are under the sole influence of gravity. The values of these positions will allow them to measure the effect of gravity on the antiatoms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The GBAR experiment, also located in the AD hall, takes a different tack. It plans to use antiprotons supplied by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://home.cern/about/updates/2016/11/new-ring-slow-down-antimatter&quot;&gt;ELENA deceleration ring&lt;/a&gt; and positrons produced by a small &lt;a href=&quot;https://home.cern/tags/linear-accelerator&quot;&gt;linear accelerator&lt;/a&gt; to make antihydrogen ions, consisting of one antiproton and two positrons. Next, after trapping the antihydrogen ions and chilling them to an ultralow temperature (about 10 microkelvin), it will use laser light to strip them of one positron, turning them into neutral antiatoms. At this point, the neutral antiatoms will be released from the trap and allowed to fall from a height of 20 centimetres, during which the researchers will monitor their behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After months of round-the-clock work by researchers and engineers to put together the experiments, ALPHA-g and GBAR have received the first beams of antiprotons, marking the beginning of both experiments. ALPHA-g began taking beam on 30 October, after receiving the necessary safety approvals. ELENA sent its first beam to GBAR on 20 July, and since then the decelerator and GBAR researchers have been trying to perfect the delivery of the beam. The ALPHA-g and GBAR teams are now racing to commission their experiments before CERN’s accelerators shut down in a few weeks for a two-year period of maintenance work. Jeffrey Hangst, spokesperson of the ALPHA experiments, says: “We are hoping that we’ll get the chance to make the first gravity measurements with antimatter, but it’s a race against time”. Patrice Pérez, spokesperson of GBAR, says: “The GBAR experiment is using an entirely new apparatus and an antiproton beam still in its commissioning phase. We hope to produce antihydrogen this year and are working towards being ready to measure the gravitational effects on antimatter when the antiprotons are back in 2021”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another experiment at the AD hall, AEgIS, which has been in operation for several years, is also working towards measuring the effect of gravity on antihydrogen using yet &lt;a href=&quot;https://home.cern/about/experiments/aegis&quot;&gt;another approach&lt;/a&gt;. Like GBAR, AEgIS is also hoping to produce its first antihydrogen atoms this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discovering any difference between the behaviour of antimatter and matter in connection with gravity could point to a quantum theory of gravity and perhaps cast light on why the universe seems to be made of matter rather than antimatter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/0bgyi4skk9s?rel=0&quot; width=&quot;560&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jeffrey Hangst at the Antiproton Decelerator hall, explaining the ALPHA-g set-up in the run-up to the start of the experiment. (Video: Jacques Fichet/CERN)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 21:19:05 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>lainon</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://home.cern/about/updates/2018/11/new-antimatter-gravity-experiments-begin-cern</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Goldman Sachs Ensnarled in Vast 1MDB Fraud Scandal</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/01/business/goldman-sachs-malaysia-investment-fund.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/01/business/goldman-sachs-malaysia-investment-fund.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;css-18sbwfn StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Goldman Sachs is facing one of the most significant scandals in its history, a multibillion-dollar international fraud that investigators say was masterminded by a flamboyant financier with a taste for Hollywood and carried out with help from the Wall Street firm’s bankers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Federal prosecutors on Thursday unveiled a guilty plea from one former Goldman Sachs banker and announced bribery and money laundering charges against a second banker, as part of an investigation into the alleged embezzlement of billions of dollars from a state-run investment fund in Malaysia. Prosecutors also brought charges against the Malaysian businessman they believe stole some of the money: Jho Low, who spent millions of dollars on gifts to celebrities like the actor Leonardo DiCaprio and the model Miranda Kerr.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The money was used to buy a Picasso painting, diamond necklaces and Birkin bags as well as to pay for the Hollywood blockbuster “The Wolf of Wall Street.” Najib Razak, the Malaysian prime minister who established and oversaw the so-called sovereign wealth fund, lost his re-election bid over the scandal, in which American prosecutors said $731 million of the missing money was deposited into his own bank accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The charges against senior employees of a major American bank, a rare move in the decade since the financial crisis, put enormous pressure on Goldman Sachs and its new chief executive, David M. Solomon. American prosecutors are continuing to investigate other bankers and Goldman itself, according to three people with knowledge of the matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;css-18sbwfn StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The bank has spent years trying to rehabilitate a reputation that was severely damaged by allegations of misconduct and putting profits ahead of clients during the financial crisis. Goldman executives today take pains to emphasize the good that their bank does in societies around the world — efforts that could be eroded by the bank’s role in the sprawling Malaysian scandal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The lengthy court filings by prosecutors in Brooklyn paint an ugly picture for Goldman, which was instrumental in raising money for the fund, 1Malaysia Development Berhad, or 1MDB. According to court documents, the former bankers paid bribes and kickbacks to foreign leaders to secure $6 billion in bond underwriting deals for Goldman that generated $600 million in fees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The authorities said that at least one high-ranking executive in the bank’s Asian operations was aware of the scheme, which dodged Goldman’s systems to detect the payment of bribes. That person, unidentified in the court filings, has not been charged. According to three people familiar with the matter, the executive was Andrea Vella, who was the co-head of Goldman’s Asian investment banking business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Federal prosecutors said Tim Leissner, a former Goldman investment banker who spent years courting Mr. Low, pleaded guilty in August to taking part in the bribery and money laundering scheme. He left the firm in 2016 after the scandal first emerged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The court filings were sealed until Thursday when the two other men, Mr. Low and Roger Ng, Mr. Leissner’s former deputy, were charged. Mr. Ng, who left Goldman in 2014, was arrested in Malaysia; Mr. Low remains at large.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-18sbwfn StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Although the bank knew Mr. Leissner was at the center of the investigation, the breadth of the charges appeared to have caught Goldman off guard. The bank was not expecting a leader of its Asian investment bank to be implicated as well. Goldman on Thursday suspended Mr. Vella, according to a person with direct knowledge but was not authorized to speak publicly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Goldman has repeatedly played down its role in the 1MDB scandal, saying it was unaware of how money from the fund was being used. The company said in a statement that it was cooperating with the investigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Goldman’s chairman, Lloyd Blankfein, sought to frame the matter as the misdeeds of rogue employees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“These are guys who evaded our safeguards, and lie, stuff like that’s going to happen,” Mr. Blankfein said on the sidelines of The New York Times DealBook conference on Thursday. “Somebody’s going to use phones away from us, and personal this and personal that,” he said, referring to personal devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Federal prosecutors have depicted Mr. Low as the mastermind of the scheme to loot the Malaysian sovereign wealth fund. During one exchange with Mr. Leissner, Mr. Low advised of the need to “suck up to” 1MDB officials, including sending “cakes” — that is to say, bribes, according to government filings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Court filings unsealed on Thursday showed that federal prosecutors have built out their case since they first filed charges against Mr. Leissner in June. Back then, the charges did not contain any reference to the co-conspirator identified by people familiar with the matter as Mr. Vella. But the court documents associated with Mr. Leissner’s plea on Aug. 28 do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;According to that filing, the co-conspirator identified separately as Mr. Vella agreed with Mr. Leissner and Mr. Ng, in a 2012 meeting, to keep Goldman’s compliance department in the dark about the scheme to bribe government officials to secure financing for a deal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“This looks pretty terrible and a far cry from post-financial crisis settlements,” said Alex Turnbull, the son of the former Australian prime minister, Malcolm Turnbull, and a former Goldman Sachs employee in Singapore who raised concerns about how Goldman valued the bond deals in 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-18sbwfn StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Vella could not be reached for comment. He has retained a lawyer, according to three people familiar with the case, but those people declined to identify the lawyer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Court papers filed by federal prosecutors describe a long-running scheme begun in 2009 by the Goldman bankers to conceal Mr. Low’s involvement in the fund’s businesses and the money paid out on his advice. Those bribes and kickbacks helped secure business for the bank while a group of people with close ties to the former Malaysian prime minister &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/06/16/world/asia/1mdb-malaysia-najib-razak.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;stole from some of the bond proceeds&lt;/a&gt; to fuel their lavish lifestyles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Prosecutors contend that the bankers had to conceal Mr. Low’s unofficial involvement in the fund because the Goldman’s legal team had concerns about the source of his wealth. Mr. Leissner and other Goldman bankers helped 1MDB raise money through three bond issues while making hundreds of millions of dollars in commissions. During each deal, Mr. Leissner followed Mr. Low’s directions about whom to bribe to win contracts for bond issues that were internally nicknamed “Project Magnolia,” “Project Maximus” and “Project Catalyze.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The money raised was supposed to be spent on projects to help the Malaysian people like those described in the deals’ financing documents. Instead, the court filings describe an elaborate plan to funnel millions of dollars of bond proceeds to so-called shell companies controlled by Mr. Low and others. Some of the money went into bank accounts in Hong Kong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Internal emails, included in the court documents, show that Mr. Leissner and his team referred to one of the bank’s earliest proposed deals with the Malaysians as “Project Tiara.” Among the luxury goods Malaysian authorities eventually seized because they had been purchased with money from 1MDB: 14 diamond-studded tiaras.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Until recently, public attention toward the scandal focused mainly on where that money ended up. Federal prosecutors in Los Angeles &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2016/07/21/world/asia/1mdb-malaysia-us-assets-seized.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;have filed multiple civil suits&lt;/a&gt; to recoup assets bought with some of the money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;According to those lawsuits, Mr. Najib’s wife, Rosmah Mansor, received $30 million worth of jewelry bought with money originating from 1MDB, including a 22-carat pink diamond necklace worth $27.3 million alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-18sbwfn StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Leissner also kept some of the funds for himself, according to the authorities. In pleading guilty, he was ordered to forfeit nearly $44 million that he earned from scheme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Leissner’s lawyer did not return a request for comment. It was not known who was representing Mr. Ng.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;A spokesman for Mr. Low said Mr. Low was innocent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“As noted in the indictment today, Mr. Low held no formal position at 1MDB, nor was he ever employed by Goldman Sachs,” the spokesman, Jim Haggerty, said. He added, “Furthermore, the bond offerings detailed in the indictment were undertaken openly and lawfully between experienced, well-regulated financial institutions and government entities.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The fraud led Malaysian voters to oust Mr. Najib in May; prosecutors there brought corruption charges against him in July. The new prime minister, Mahathir Mohamad, has moved quickly to investigate. The Malaysian government is &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/06/14/business/1mdb-malaysia-goldman-sachs.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;seeking restitution from Goldman Sachs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 19:33:42 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>SREinSF</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/01/business/goldman-sachs-malaysia-investment-fund.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Goldman Sachs Ensnarled in Vast 1MDB Fraud Scandal</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/11/02/us/02goldman/02goldman-facebookJumbo-v3.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>The filing of federal charges could increase pressure on Goldman, the primary bond underwriter for the development fund at the center of the so-called 1MDB scandal.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/01/business/goldman-sachs-malaysia-investment-fund.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>