<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>In Japan, small children take the subway and run errands alone (2015)</title>
<link>https://www.citylab.com/transportation/2015/09/why-are-little-kids-in-japan-so-independent/407590/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.citylab.com/transportation/2015/09/why-are-little-kids-in-japan-so-independent/407590/</guid>
<description>&lt;p itemprop=&quot;description&quot;&gt;In Japan, small children take the subway and run errands alone, no parent in sight. The reason why has more to do with social trust than self-reliance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;article-section-1&quot;&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;It’s a common sight on Japanese mass transit: children troop through train cars, singly or in small groups, looking for seats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;They wear knee socks, polished patent leather shoes, and plaid jumpers, with wide-brimmed hats fastened under the chin and train passes pinned to their backpacks. The kids are as young as six or seven, on their way to and from school, and there is nary a guardian in sight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Parents in Japan regularly send their kids out into the world at a very young age. A popular television show called &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/raisingkids/comments/166in4/hajimete_no_otsukai_first_errand_is_a_japanese_tv/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Hajimete no Otsukai&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, or &lt;em&gt;My First Errand&lt;/em&gt;, features children as young as two or three being sent out to do a task for their family. As they tentatively make their way to the greengrocer or bakery, their progress is secretly filmed by a camera crew. The show has been running for more than 25 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; class=&quot; lazyload&quot; data-src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/e5k5XTZy0rA?enablejsapi=1&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this English-subtitled segment from &lt;em&gt;My First Errand&lt;/em&gt;, a brother and sister head out to buy groceries for the first time, not without a few tears.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kaito, a 12-year-old in Tokyo, has been riding the train by himself between the homes of his parents, who share his custody, since he was nine. “At first I was a little worried,” he admits, “whether I could ride the train alone. But only a little worried.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;article-section-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;callout special-report&quot;&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h4 class=&quot;module-tag&quot;&gt;Series&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.citylab.com/special-report/global-shifts/&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.theatlantic.com/assets/media/img/posts/2015/08/global_shifts_promo-2/0a151ed7c.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;sans&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.citylab.com/special-report/global-shifts&quot;&gt;City Makers: Global Shifts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;“Honestly, what I remember thinking at the time is, the trains are safe and on time and easy to navigate, and he’s a smart kid,” Kaito’s stepmother says. (His parents asked not to publish his last name and their names for the sake of privacy.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;“I took the trains on my own when I was younger than him in Tokyo,” his stepmother recalls. “We didn’t have cell phones back in my day, but I still managed to go from point A to point B on the train. If he gets lost, he can call us.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;What accounts for this unusual degree of independence? Not self-sufficiency, in fact, but “group reliance,” according to Dwayne Dixon, a cultural anthropologist who wrote his doctoral &lt;a href=&quot;http://scalar.usc.edu/students/endlessquestion/index&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;dissertation&lt;/a&gt; on Japanese youth. “[Japanese] kids learn early on that, ideally, any member of the community can be called on to serve or help others,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;This assumption is reinforced at school, where children take turns cleaning and serving lunch instead of relying on staff to perform such duties. This “distributes labor across various shoulders and rotates expectations, while also teaching everyone what it takes to clean a toilet, for instance,” Dixon says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;article-section-3&quot;&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Taking responsibility for shared spaces means that children have pride of ownership and understand in a concrete way the consequences of making a mess, since they’ll have to clean it up themselves. This ethic extends to public space more broadly (one reason Japanese streets are generally so clean). A child out in public knows he can rely on the group to help in an emergency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;article-section-4&quot;&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Japan has &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.civitas.org.uk/crime/crime_stats_oecdjan2012.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a very low crime rate&lt;/a&gt;, which is surely a key reason parents feel confident about sending their kids out alone. But small-scaled urban spaces and a culture of walking and transit use also foster safety and, perhaps just as important, the perception of safety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;“Public space is scaled so much better—old, human-sized spaces that also control flow and speed,” Dixon notes. In Japanese cities, people are accustomed to walking everywhere, and public transportation trumps car culture; in Tokyo, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lta.gov.sg/ltaacademy/doc/J14Nov_p54ReferenceModeShares.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;half of all trips are made on rail or bus, and a quarter on foot&lt;/a&gt;. Drivers are used to sharing the road and yielding to pedestrians and cyclists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Kaito’s stepmother says&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; she wouldn’t let a 9-year-old ride the subway alone in London or New York—just in Tokyo. &lt;span&gt;That’s not to say the Tokyo subway is risk-free. The persistent problem of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.citylab.com/commute/2012/02/why-women-only-transit-options-have-caught/1171/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;women and girls being groped&lt;/a&gt;, for example, led to the introduction of women-only cars on select lines starting in 2000. Still, many city children continue to take the train to school and run errands in their neighborhood without close supervision.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;By giving them this freedom, parents are placing significant trust not only in their kids, but in the whole community.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;“Plenty of kids across the world are self-sufficient,” Dixon observes. “But the thing that I suspect Westerners are intrigued by [in Japan] is the sense of trust and cooperation that occurs, often unspoken or unsolicited.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 05:56:15 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>lighttower</dc:creator>
<og:description>In Japan, small children take the subway and run errands alone, no parent in sight. The reason why has more to do with social trust than self-reliance.</og:description>
<og:image>https://cdn.citylab.com/media/img/citylab/2015/09/RTX1HW1X/facebook.jpg?1494536602</og:image>
<og:title>Why Little Kids in Japan Are So Independent</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>http://www.citylab.com/commute/2015/09/why-are-little-kids-in-japan-so-independent/407590/</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.citylab.com/transportation/2015/09/why-are-little-kids-in-japan-so-independent/407590/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>IOTA: A tangled mess</title>
<link>http://codesuppository.blogspot.com/2017/12/iota-tangled-mess.html?m=1</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://codesuppository.blogspot.com/2017/12/iota-tangled-mess.html?m=1</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-8W8TqCXEFhE/WjP3cJowavI/AAAAAAAA_5U/qXx8GiWKHJshyNfmYQYnK1J8mSj6AreXwCLcBGAs/s1600/Dollarphotoclub_59709632-1.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1067&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1600&quot; height=&quot;266&quot; src=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-8W8TqCXEFhE/WjP3cJowavI/AAAAAAAA_5U/qXx8GiWKHJshyNfmYQYnK1J8mSj6AreXwCLcBGAs/s400/Dollarphotoclub_59709632-1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;I wanted to take a brief moment and explain in a form that is a bit more detailed than a tweet offers my experience with the crytpocurrency called &lt;a href=&quot;https://iota.org/&quot;&gt;IOTA&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;A number of months ago some people I respect in the cryptocurrency community started telling me about this amazing new system called IOTA.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;The supporters of IOTA make a number a fabulous claims.  As you hear them tell it, IOTA is the holy grail of cryptocurrencies.  It solves all of the problems presented by blockchains that we still struggle with today.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;Here are the claims about IOTA:&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;IOTA is deflationary (has a fixed number of tokens, there will never be any more, and has no inflation at all, no issuance schedule for new tokens).  All tokens which will ever exist were created on day one and pre-distributed to people who signed onto the project very early.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IOTA has zero fees.  Period.  Forever.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IOTA has fast confirmation times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IOTA is nearly infinitely scalable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IOTA has no centralized miners, instead every participant in the system is effectively a 'miner' or more accurately a transaction validator.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;This all sounds great, of course.  This invention is supposedly possible through the use of something called a '&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Directed_acyclic_graph&quot;&gt;directed-acyclic-graph&lt;/a&gt;' and in IOTA terminology called a 'tangle'.  It's a data structure dramatically different than how blockchains function and, supposedly, does not suffer from their scaling problems.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To evaluate these claims new users are directed to read the '&lt;a href=&quot;https://iota.org/IOTA_Whitepaper.pdf&quot;&gt;whitepaper&lt;/a&gt;' for IOTA.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before I bought a single IOTA, I read this whitepaper and it's pretty indecipherable.  I'm a pretty technical person myself, but this paper was not written in a way that anyone can easily understand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After reading the paper, I really didn't feel like I could evaluate whether or not this technology actually works.  I just had a general understanding of the basic concepts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My next step was to go to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/iotaledger&quot;&gt;GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt; and take a brief look at the source code.  The IOTA source code is written in JAVA instead of C++ like most professional cryptocurrencies are.  That did not instill me with confidence.  In my brief review of the source code it seemed written by someone who knows how to code, but it was entirely devoid of useful and relevant documentation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As you can see, this evaluation of mine did not inspire enough confidence that I felt I should rush out, sell all of my bitcoin, and buy IOTA instead.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What I did do, next, was just try to use it.  So, I installed the IOTA wallet on my cell phone.  I had one of my friends online send me a single IOTA (worth like a zillionth of a penny) and, sure enough, my single IOTA arrived quickly, showed up as confirmed, and cost nothing to send.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That was certainly a cool experience since fees on the bitcoin network are high and confirmations are slow.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
The wallet software was extremely crude and simplistic, with just a 'send' and 'receive' button, but it seemed to work and I assumed they would improve the wallet over time.&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;tr-caption-container&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-0CgNl1BEJs8/WjQGo_QkhFI/AAAAAAAA_5k/ANG7dUwNWu0N_Wq1r0LvSyDxccCZ1kttwCLcBGAs/s1600/iota-wallet.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;971&quot; data-original-width=&quot;712&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-0CgNl1BEJs8/WjQGo_QkhFI/AAAAAAAA_5k/ANG7dUwNWu0N_Wq1r0LvSyDxccCZ1kttwCLcBGAs/s400/iota-wallet.png&quot; width=&quot;292&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tr-caption&quot;&gt;A screen capture of the highly sophisticated and advanced IOTA wallet.  Just be sure you hit the 'send' button the right way, otherwise all of your money will be lost and it will be your fault!&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, next I decided to buy a small amount of IOTA as an investment.  I did, and I made my original buy of 45,000MI at 21 cents apiece.  This was just a speculative bet thinking, hey, maybe this thing really works.  I didn't buy the 45,000MI all at once.  I bought them over a period of time and, during that period, I was able to move IOTA to and from an exchange without any problems.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At this point, the system actually seemed to work and I had a generally positive attitude about it just based on my initial experience using the network.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After a period of time IOTA increased in price as more people heard about it and began using the network. Once the price rose to a little over 65 cents apiece, I sold all of my IOTA because, as I said in the beginning, I was just making a speculative play and a 3x return on investment in a matter of weeks seemed like a great return for me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over time, as IOTA hype continued to rise, eventually the price rose to well over a $1.20.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I decided that maybe this IOTA thing might actually work and I should put a some money back into it.  Eventually IOTA saw a price correction down to 85 cents and I decided that was a decent re-entry point.  So, I bought back in 26,000MI at 85 cents and figured I would let that ride.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It turns out, that was hardly the best time to 'get back in' to this market.  The price went lower and lower as more people began to post criticism of the network online.  The network began to have more and more technical problems as well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The price dropped below 30 cents at one point, and I was thinking I definitely made a pretty bad call going back in.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That said, I figured IOTA is a longer term bet and there was no point in selling at a loss, so I just decided to hold the 26,000 and wait it out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even though my initial experience with actually trying to use the IOTA network was fairly positive, when I tried to use the network later things changed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The IOTA foundation did a tangle reorg multiple times.  Every time this happened, if you logged into your IOTA wallet it would show a zero balance.  Which was incredibly disconcerting.  This didn't just happen once, but multiple times.  To get your balance back you had to keep clicking the 'receive button' to generate a new address, wait a minute, and then do that again and again and again, maybe a 100 times before your money would show up again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The IOTA foundation also announced they were going to have to 'recover funds' from some users after the re-org.  This is when it became abundantly clear that IOTA is radically centralized.  If some foundation could just re-org the database and claim funds for users, that's about as centralized as you can get.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ability to send and receive transactions on the mobile wallet pretty much just stopped working for me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;So, as time went on, I was losing confidence in the IOTA network simply because it was no longer working as advertised and the market price reflected that.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;The IOTA team dismissed all of the criticisms of their network as organized FUD propaganda (fear-uncertainty-doubt) from detractors who had major investments in blockchain technology and viewed IOTA as a threat.  If you were a 'believer' in the IOTA technology, this explanation made perfect sense.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;A few weeks ago the IOTA foundation really whipped the public-relations team into high gear and started making announcement after announcement about how major corporations were supporting their technology.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;This led to a massive pump cycle in the market and the price of IOTA suddenly rose dramatically; reaching a height of well over $5 for a period of time.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;Since I had last bought in at 85 cents, that represented a significant return on investment for me.  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;I had been 'underwater' for a long time; not only because the price was below 85 cents but, also, because the price of bitcoin was rising dramatically during this period.  So, even at 85 cents, while I might have reached USD parity with my initial investment, I was still way underwater relative to the bitcoin cost.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;It was my intention to sell enough of my IOTA to at least get my original bitcoin investment back out.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;So, I decided to send my IOTA to an exchange to trade for bitcoin. &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;And, at this point, is when I realized just how bad the IOTA network situation had become.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;I first did a very small transfer to my exchange to make sure everything was safe to do.  It transferred ok, I exchanged it, and was able to do a withdrawal.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;I then tried to send more IOTA and that is when things started going south.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;My IOTA never showed up on the exchange as having been confirmed.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;So, I started asking around in the IOTA slack channel and was told this was a 'known problem' and 'all I had to do was re-attach' or 'try a different node'.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;It turns out that even though IOTA is a live cryptocurrency network with a market cap in the billions of dollars, it doesn't even function as a true peer-to-peer network.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;Rather than having thousands and thousands of decentralized nodes worldwide forming a peer-to-peer network, nodes which are discoverable using a dynamic routing system, instead IOTA has a tiny number of hard-coded dedicated nodes that people connect to.  Most of these nodes don't work, or are supposedly, allegedly, 'overwhelmed with traffic'.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;Instead of an IOTA transaction being confirmed in a matter of minutes, users were unable to get transactions to confirm for days, sometimes weeks at a time.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;I did start changing which nodes I connected to.  I did keep 're-attaching' my transaction, over, and over again.  Some users reported doing this process literally hundreds of times for weeks on end with no success.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;Eventually, through this process, I managed to get most of my IOTA to an exchange over a week and sell them. I was never able to sell them anywhere near the price of $5 when I originally sent them but, frankly, at this point I was glad I was able to get any of my money back at all.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;Meanwhile, if you went into reddit or twitter the supporters of IOTA were behaving like members of a brainwashed religious cult.  Even though the Slack channel was filled with users having the same experience I was having, the IOTA supporters were 'blaming the victim'.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;It was all our fault because, apparently I guess, we were not hitting the 'send transaction' button correctly.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;Remember, the IOTA wallet is incredibly dumb and simplistic.  It has a 'send' and a 'receive' button on the menu.  One would expect, and I know this is crazy talk, that hitting 'send' would send money and hitting 'receive' would receive money.  Apparently, and I apologize for being so dumb, this doesn't actually work.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;After successfully managing to dump most of my IOTA, even though I lost many, many, thousands of dollars because I had to sell at a much lower price than I wanted to, I finally reached an impasse with my remaining 5,600mi.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;I posted on Twitter a statement of fact, that the IOTA network was not functioning for most users.  I might as well have stuck my hand in a hornets nest.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;Rather than a guy trying to use a cryptocurrency network and finding that it simply does not work, an army of IOTA cult followers began to attack me.  To such an extent, and I kid you not, that one guy actually wrote an article for PyschologyToday about how 'organized FUD' manipulates markets.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;The irony that a guy who has been brainwashed to believe the IOTA network actually functions as advertised would attack people simply stating facts was just too much.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;Rather than a guy who invested in the technology and found that it is not, at this time, in a functioning state, instead I was running an organized psychological operations campaign against the holy IOTA network.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;So, that's where we are today.  I still maybe, or maybe not, I really don't know, own 5,600mi.  I can't sell them because the network will no longer process my transactions.  I'm just going to hold onto them until some point in the future when, maybe, they reorganize their database again, maybe they fix their software and maybe I can sell them.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;On the one hand, I'm happy I got my original investment back out.  On the other hand, at the $5 price I wanted to sell at, 5,600 MI is $28,000USD and, last I checked, that's still a lot of money to a lot of people, including myself.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;I do want to close with this.  Some people on reddit and Twitter, rather than attacking me or my motives, actually tried to help.  And they were sincere, and I really do appreciate it.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;However, I must leave you with this.&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;div&gt;This is one of the craziest things I have ever seen in cryptocurrency.  The absurdity of this is mindboggling and truly represents the sheer denial that IOTA supporters are in if they think, in any way, this is acceptable.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;It states:&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;RULE 1: NEVER re-use an address. NEVER. NO exceptions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RULE 2: ALWAYS attach a new receive address to the Tangle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RULE 3: ALWAYS wait for a transaction to be confirmed before sending anything else. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div&gt;So, rule #1 is an admission that the network is fundamentally broken.  A cryptocurrency that doesn't let you send funds to the same public key more than once, because a hacker could derive your private key, is just about the single most insane thing I have ever heard.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;And, of course, there is nothing to prevent an end user from doing this by accident.  In fact, one of the popular exchanges says that if you accidentally send funds to the same deposit address twice you will *lose your money*.  I kid you not.  This is real.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;tr-caption-container&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-GtFQzhwom1Q/WjQJEIxo3SI/AAAAAAAA_5w/GLVh7eI49IMARVtkvPRzndBacYpFNFfJACLcBGAs/s1600/binance.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;414&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1600&quot; height=&quot;163&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-GtFQzhwom1Q/WjQJEIxo3SI/AAAAAAAA_5w/GLVh7eI49IMARVtkvPRzndBacYpFNFfJACLcBGAs/s640/binance.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tr-caption&quot;&gt;Screenshot of binance exchange deposit page.  Note warning not to send funds to the same public key twice. Note that you cannot withdraw purchased IOTA because the network is currently in a broken state.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;div&gt;So, rule #2.  Get this, says that before you can send money, you must first generate an empty receive address.  Why?  Who the fuck knows.  This is just more insanity.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;Rule #3 is just another admission of a broken network.  Really not much else to say.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;During conversations online, not only was I accused of engaging in an organized and orchestrated propaganda campaign I was also victim blamed.  I'm the one who lost tens of thousands of dollars because the network is in a broken state but, clearly that is all my fault because, oh, I don't know, because I didn't hit the send button correctly?  Or find a functioning node to attach to?  Or because I didn't generate a receive address before I tried to send to a new address and, dear lord, don't ever, ever, ever, send funds to the same public key.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;I cannot believe I even have to explain how completely and utterly insane this is.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;However, it gets worse.  The other narrative online from IOTA supporters, people who can see no wrong with any of these issues; those who believe all fault lies with the people trying to use the network rather than those who created it, is as follows. &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;The supporters will constantly make statements like 'IOTA is in alpha', 'you should expect bugs'.  As if this was a JavaScript some 12 year old was writing for his homebrew website.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;Look, let's be very clear.  IOTA is a live cryptocurrency with a market cap in the billions of dollars. Real people have large amounts of value tied up on that network.  It is hosted on several exchanges.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;You do not release financial software to the general public in such a buggy state.  You do not blame the victims for your software failing to function.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;Maybe IOTA will work some day?  Maybe.  I don't know.  But the experience to date does not inspire confidence.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;Maybe the team will 'fix all of these problems', and it will become the technology of the future.  Maybe.  But they have done little to inspire confidence.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;When I made my first tweet reporting that I couldn't get transactions sent to an exchange, do you know what happened?&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;The founder of IOTA, the lead dev who created it, offered to buy my IOTA at just 10% of their market value to get me to shut up.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;Seriously.  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;I'm not making this up.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;So, good luck with IOTA.  I still own 5,600, well, maybe I own them, I don't really know because I can't send them.  So, when the IOTA fan-boys pump the price up to new heights, here's hoping I can send it to an exchange to sell.&lt;p&gt;--------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;A Brief Post Script&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;I was finally able to get my remaining 5,600 MI 'unstuck'.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;Here is the trick to make it work.&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Create a new seed/wallet you control&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generate and attach a new receive address, copy it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now go back to your original seed which has the 'stuck' funds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Before you do a send, *FIRST*, click on' receive' and 'attach'.  For whatever reason, and I don't know why, this gets your account straightened out.  Before I did this people told me my funds were 'double spent' but after doing this, the funds were available to be sent again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now go to send, and send to the new wallet/seed you control.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try this with a small amount first to test that it all works, then repeat the process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div&gt;I don't know why this 'fixes' the problem, nor do I really care.  Apparently all of those people telling you to try new nodes, re-attach your transaction, or rebroadcast it, were not really addressing this specific problem of stuck, seemingly double-spent, funds.  For whatever reason doing a receive before you do a send gets the funds in a spendable state again.&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 04:30:06 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>wglb</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://codesuppository.blogspot.com/2017/12/iota-tangled-mess.html</og:url>
<og:title>IOTA : A Tangled Mess</og:title>
<og:description>I wanted to take a brief moment and explain in a form that is a bit more detailed than a tweet offers my experience with the crytpocu...</og:description>
<og:image>https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-8W8TqCXEFhE/WjP3cJowavI/AAAAAAAA_5U/qXx8GiWKHJshyNfmYQYnK1J8mSj6AreXwCLcBGAs/w1200-h630-p-k-no-nu/Dollarphotoclub_59709632-1.jpg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://codesuppository.blogspot.com/2017/12/iota-tangled-mess.html?_escaped_fragment_=</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>In B-Flat</title>
<link>http://www.inbflat.net</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.inbflat.net</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;play these together, some or all, start them at any time, in any order.   &lt;a href=&quot;javascript:unhide('moreinfo');&quot;&gt;more info...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;moreinfo&quot; readability=&quot;14.493638676845&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;boldish&quot;&gt;In Bb 2.0&lt;/span&gt; is a collaborative music and spoken word project conceived by Darren Solomon &lt;span class=&quot;boldish&quot;&gt;(&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.darrensolomon.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/#!/Darsolo&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; and developed with contributions from users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The videos can be played simultaneously -- the soundtracks will work together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.inbflat.net/faq.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may also enjoy &lt;span class=&quot;boldish&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.markermusic.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;marker/music&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, another music, video and spoken word project, produced in collaboration with NSU in South Dakota.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:info@scienceforgirls.net&quot;&gt;Contact!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2017 20:27:59 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>sdenton4</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.inbflat.net/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Norway votes to decriminalise drugs and offer treatment instead of jail time</title>
<link>https://inews.co.uk/news/world/norway-votes-decriminalise-drugs-offer-treatment-instead-jail-time/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://inews.co.uk/news/world/norway-votes-decriminalise-drugs-offer-treatment-instead-jail-time/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Norway’s parliament has voted to decriminalise drugs and offer treatment to addicts instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;133 seats out of 175 voted in favour of decriminalising illegal drugs across the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Norway’s 2017 Country Drug Report, 266 people died from drug-related deaths this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of being handed a prison sentence, drug users would be given treatment. People with addictions to drugs would be regarded as needing treatment for an illness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The majority will stop punishing people who struggle, but instead give them help and treatment.”&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nicolas Wilinson, health spokesman for the Socialist Left&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sveinung Stensland, deputy chairman of the Storting Health Committee told &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vg.no/nyheter/innenriks/rusmidler/historisk-i-stortinget-slutt-paa-straff-for-rusmisbrukere/a/24209948/&quot;&gt;VG&lt;/a&gt;: “It is important to emphasise that we do not legalise cannabis and other drugs, but we decriminalise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The change will take some time, but that means a changed vision: those who have a substance abuse problem should be treated as ill, and not as criminals with classical sanctions such as fines and imprisonment.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nicolas Wilinson, health spokesman for the Socialist Left told VG: “The majority will stop punishing people who struggle, but instead give them help and treatment.”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Norway’s Country Drug Report, 266 people died from drug-related deaths which is said to be an increase on last year, reports &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.independent.co.uk/news/health/norway-parliament-drugs-decriminalise-recreational-cocaine-heroin-marijuana-a8111761.html&quot;&gt;The Independent&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Portugal model&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The move follows that of Portugal which decriminalised drugs in 2001. Drug addicts in the country are given therapy or community service rather than fines or jail time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However drugs still remain illegal in the country which means that those found to be growing drugs, dealing substances or trafficking them will still be handed criminal penalties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a person is found in possession of a small amount of drugs, the drugs are confiscated and the person is interviewed by a psychiatrist, a social worker and a lawyer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following this, a number of sanctions can be put in place such as a ban on visiting certain places, a foreign travel ban and a small fine, in line with the country’s minimum wage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result in Portugal has been positive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the latest &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.emcdda.europa.eu/publications/country-drug-reports/2017/portugal_en&quot;&gt;European Monitoring Centre for Drugs and drug addiction report&lt;/a&gt;, there are six drug related deaths in Portugal for every one million people. While in the UK, there are 60 deaths for every million people.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2017 19:34:24 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pimeys</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Norway votes to decriminalise drugs and offer treatment instead of jail time - The i newspaper online iNews</og:title>
<og:description>Norway’s parliament has voted to decriminalise drugs and offer treatment to addicts instead. 133 seats out of 175 voted in favour of decriminalising illega</og:description>
<og:url>https://inews.co.uk/news/world/norway-votes-decriminalise-drugs-offer-treatment-instead-jail-time/</og:url>
<og:image>https://inews.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/GettyImages-113831946.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-GB</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://inews.co.uk/news/world/norway-votes-decriminalise-drugs-offer-treatment-instead-jail-time/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Pentagon’s U.F.O. Program</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2017/12/16/us/politics/pentagon-program-ufo-harry-reid.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2017/12/16/us/politics/pentagon-program-ufo-harry-reid.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;330&quot; data-total-count=&quot;2211&quot; id=&quot;story-continues-3&quot;&gt;Officials with the program have also studied videos of encounters between unknown objects and American military aircraft — including one released in August of a whitish oval object, about the size of a commercial plane, chased by two Navy F/A-18F fighter jets from the aircraft carrier Nimitz off the coast of San Diego in 2004.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;329&quot; data-total-count=&quot;2540&quot;&gt;Mr. Reid, who retired from Congress this year, said he was proud of the program. “I’m not embarrassed or ashamed or sorry I got this thing going,” Mr. Reid said in a recent interview in Nevada. “I think it’s one of the good things I did in my congressional service. I’ve done something that no one has done before.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;237&quot; data-total-count=&quot;2777&quot;&gt;Two other former senators and top members of a defense spending subcommittee — Ted Stevens, an Alaska Republican, and Daniel K. Inouye, a Hawaii Democrat — also supported the program. Mr. Stevens died in 2010, and Mr. Inouye in 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;441&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3218&quot;&gt;While not addressing the merits of the program, Sara Seager, an astrophysicist at M.I.T., cautioned that not knowing the origin of an object does not mean that it is from another planet or galaxy. “When people claim to observe truly unusual phenomena, sometimes it’s worth investigating seriously,” she said. But, she added, “what people sometimes don’t get about science is that we often have phenomena that remain unexplained.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;Video&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;headline&quot;&gt;Video: U.S. Military Jets Encounter Unknown Object&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-video&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;summary-credit&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;A video shows a 2004 encounter near San Diego between two Navy F/A-18F fighter jets and an unknown object. It was released by the Defense Department's Advanced Aerospace Threat Identification Program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit video-credit&quot; itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot;&gt;By Courtesy of U.S. DEPARTMENT OF DEFENSE on &lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;Publish Date&lt;/span&gt; December 16, 2017.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;credit photo-credit&quot; itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot;&gt;Photo by U.S Department of Defense.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;442&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3660&quot;&gt;James E. Oberg, a former NASA space shuttle engineer and the author of 10 books on spaceflight who often debunks U.F.O. sightings, was also doubtful. “There are plenty of prosaic events and human perceptual traits that can account for these stories,” Mr. Oberg said. “Lots of people are active in the air and don’t want others to know about it. They are happy to lurk unrecognized in the noise, or even to stir it up as camouflage.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;93&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3753&quot;&gt;Still, Mr. Oberg said he welcomed research. “There could well be a pearl there,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;241&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3994&quot;&gt;In response to questions from The Times, Pentagon officials this month acknowledged the existence of the program, which began as part of the Defense Intelligence Agency. Officials insisted that the effort had ended after five years, in 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;story-ad-2&quot; class=&quot;story-ad ad ad-placeholder nocontent robots-nocontent&quot;&gt;

&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/12/16/us/politics/pentagon-program-ufo-harry-reid.html#story-continues-4&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;248&quot; data-total-count=&quot;4242&quot; id=&quot;story-continues-4&quot;&gt;“It was determined that there were other, higher priority issues that merited funding, and it was in the best interest of the DoD to make a change,” a Pentagon spokesman, Thomas Crosson, said in an email, referring to the Department of Defense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;386&quot; data-total-count=&quot;4628&quot;&gt;But Mr. Elizondo said the only thing that had ended was the effort’s government funding, which dried up in 2012. From then on, Mr. Elizondo said in an interview, he worked with officials from the Navy and the C.I.A. He continued to work out of his Pentagon office until this past October, when he resigned to protest what he characterized as excessive secrecy and internal opposition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;142&quot; data-total-count=&quot;4770&quot;&gt;“Why aren’t we spending more time and effort on this issue?” Mr. Elizondo wrote in a resignation letter to Defense Secretary Jim Mattis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;Photo&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/12/17/us/politics/17dc-ufo3/merlin_131167458_f793a760-756f-4cfb-9e90-67c54072639c-master675.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;media-viewer-candidate&quot; data-mediaviewer-src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/12/17/us/politics/17dc-ufo3/merlin_131167458_f793a760-756f-4cfb-9e90-67c54072639c-superJumbo.jpg&quot; data-mediaviewer-caption=&quot;Pentagon officials say the program ended in 2012, five years after it was created, but the official who led it said that only the government funding had ended then.&quot; data-mediaviewer-credit=&quot;Charles Dharapak/Associated Press&quot; itemprop=&quot;url&quot; itemid=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/12/17/us/politics/17dc-ufo3/merlin_131167458_f793a760-756f-4cfb-9e90-67c54072639c-master675.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;Pentagon officials say the program ended in 2012, five years after it was created, but the official who led it said that only the government funding had ended then.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt; Charles Dharapak/Associated Press&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;98&quot; data-total-count=&quot;4868&quot;&gt;Mr. Elizondo said that the effort continued and that he had a successor, whom he declined to name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;474&quot; data-total-count=&quot;5342&quot;&gt;U.F.O.s have been repeatedly investigated over the decades in the United States, including by the American military. In 1947, the Air Force began a series of studies that investigated more than 12,000 claimed U.F.O. sightings before it was officially ended in 1969. The project, which included a study code-named Project Blue Book, started in 1952, concluded that most sightings involved stars, clouds, conventional aircraft or spy planes, although 701 remained unexplained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;241&quot; data-total-count=&quot;5583&quot;&gt;Robert C. Seamans Jr., the secretary of the Air Force at the time, said in a memorandum announcing the end of Project Blue Book that it “no longer can be justified either on the ground of national security or in the interest of science.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;272&quot; data-total-count=&quot;5855&quot;&gt;Mr. Reid said his interest in U.F.O.s came from Mr. Bigelow. In 2007, Mr. Reid said in the interview, Mr. Bigelow told him that an official with the Defense Intelligence Agency had approached him wanting to visit Mr. Bigelow’s ranch in Utah, where he conducted research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;237&quot; data-total-count=&quot;6092&quot;&gt;Mr. Reid said he met with agency officials shortly after his meeting with Mr. Bigelow and learned that they wanted to start a research program on U.F.O.s. Mr. Reid then summoned Mr. Stevens and Mr. Inouye to a secure room in the Capitol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;409&quot; data-total-count=&quot;6501&quot;&gt;“I had talked to John Glenn a number of years before,” Mr. Reid said, referring to the astronaut and former senator from Ohio, who died in 2016. Mr. Glenn, Mr. Reid said, had told him he thought that the federal government should be looking seriously into U.F.O.s, and should be talking to military service members, particularly pilots, who had reported seeing aircraft they could not identify or explain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;Photo&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/12/17/us/17dc-ufo1/10dc-ufo-master675.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;media-viewer-candidate&quot; data-mediaviewer-src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/12/17/us/17dc-ufo1/10dc-ufo-superJumbo.jpg&quot; data-mediaviewer-caption=&quot;Luis Elizondo, who led the Pentagon effort to investigate U.F.O.s until October. He resigned to protest what he characterized as excessive secrecy and internal opposition to the program.&quot; data-mediaviewer-credit=&quot;Justin T. Gellerson for The New York Times&quot; itemprop=&quot;url&quot; itemid=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/12/17/us/17dc-ufo1/10dc-ufo-master675.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;Luis Elizondo, who led the Pentagon effort to investigate U.F.O.s until October. He resigned to protest what he characterized as excessive secrecy and internal opposition to the program.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt; Justin T. Gellerson for The New York Times&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;167&quot; data-total-count=&quot;6668&quot;&gt;The sightings were not often reported up the military’s chain of command, Mr. Reid said, because service members were afraid they would be laughed at or stigmatized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;story-ad-3&quot; class=&quot;story-ad ad ad-placeholder nocontent robots-nocontent&quot;&gt;

&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/12/16/us/politics/pentagon-program-ufo-harry-reid.html#story-continues-5&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;109&quot; data-total-count=&quot;6777&quot; id=&quot;story-continues-5&quot;&gt;The meeting with Mr. Stevens and Mr. Inouye, Mr. Reid said, “was one of the easiest meetings I ever had.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;223&quot; data-total-count=&quot;7000&quot;&gt;He added, “Ted Stevens said, ‘I’ve been waiting to do this since I was in the Air Force.’” (The Alaska senator had been a pilot in the Army’s air force, flying transport missions over China during World War II.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;161&quot; data-total-count=&quot;7161&quot;&gt;During the meeting, Mr. Reid said, Mr. Stevens recounted being tailed by a strange aircraft with no known origin, which he said had followed his plane for miles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;338&quot; data-total-count=&quot;7499&quot;&gt;None of the three senators wanted a public debate on the Senate floor about the funding for the program, Mr. Reid said. “This was so-called black money,” he said. “Stevens knows about it, Inouye knows about it. But that was it, and that’s how we wanted it.” Mr. Reid was referring to the Pentagon budget for classified programs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;Photo&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/12/17/us/politics/17dc-ufo2/merlin_35316034_611e71cf-6b2f-4150-b5db-af6bb88c7c2f-master675.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;media-viewer-candidate&quot; data-mediaviewer-src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/12/17/us/politics/17dc-ufo2/merlin_35316034_611e71cf-6b2f-4150-b5db-af6bb88c7c2f-superJumbo.jpg&quot; data-mediaviewer-caption=&quot;Robert Bigelow, a billionaire entrepreneur and longtime friend of Mr. Reid, received most of the money allocated for the Pentagon program. On CBS&amp;amp;rsquo;s &amp;amp;ldquo;60 Minutes&amp;amp;rdquo; in May, Mr. Bigelow said he was &amp;amp;ldquo;absolutely convinced&amp;amp;rdquo; that aliens exist and that U.F.O.s have visited Earth.&quot; data-mediaviewer-credit=&quot;Isaac Brekken for The New York Times&quot; itemprop=&quot;url&quot; itemid=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/12/17/us/politics/17dc-ufo2/merlin_35316034_611e71cf-6b2f-4150-b5db-af6bb88c7c2f-master675.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;Robert Bigelow, a billionaire entrepreneur and longtime friend of Mr. Reid, received most of the money allocated for the Pentagon program. On CBS’s “60 Minutes” in May, Mr. Bigelow said he was “absolutely convinced” that aliens exist and that U.F.O.s have visited Earth.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt; Isaac Brekken for The New York Times&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;240&quot; data-total-count=&quot;7739&quot;&gt;Contracts obtained by The Times show a congressional appropriation of just under $22 million beginning in late 2008 through 2011. The money was used for management of the program, research and assessments of the threat posed by the objects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;130&quot; data-total-count=&quot;7869&quot;&gt;The funding went to Mr. Bigelow’s company, Bigelow Aerospace, which hired subcontractors and solicited research for the program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;498&quot; data-total-count=&quot;8367&quot;&gt;Under Mr. Bigelow’s direction, the company modified buildings in Las Vegas for the storage of metal alloys and other materials that Mr. Elizondo and program contractors said had been recovered from unidentified aerial phenomena. Researchers also studied people who said they had experienced physical effects from encounters with the objects and examined them for any physiological changes. In addition, researchers spoke to military service members who had reported sightings of strange aircraft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;story-ad-4&quot; class=&quot;story-ad ad ad-placeholder nocontent robots-nocontent&quot;&gt;

&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/12/16/us/politics/pentagon-program-ufo-harry-reid.html#story-continues-6&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;426&quot; data-total-count=&quot;8793&quot; id=&quot;story-continues-6&quot;&gt;“We’re sort of in the position of what would happen if you gave Leonardo da Vinci a garage-door opener,” said Harold E. Puthoff, an engineer who has conducted research on extrasensory perception for the C.I.A. and later worked as a contractor for the program. “First of all, he’d try to figure out what is this plastic stuff. He wouldn’t know anything about the electromagnetic signals involved or its function.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;440&quot; data-total-count=&quot;9233&quot;&gt;The program collected video and audio recordings of reported U.F.O. incidents, including footage from a Navy F/A-18 Super Hornet showing an aircraft surrounded by some kind of glowing aura traveling at high speed and rotating as it moves. The Navy pilots can be heard trying to understand what they are seeing. “There’s a whole fleet of them,” one exclaims. Defense officials declined to release the location and date of the incident.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;521&quot; data-total-count=&quot;9754&quot;&gt;“Internationally, we are the most backward country in the world on this issue,” Mr. Bigelow said in an interview. “Our scientists are scared of being ostracized, and our media is scared of the stigma. China and Russia are much more open and work on this with huge organizations within their countries. Smaller countries like Belgium, France, England and South American countries like Chile are more open, too. They are proactive and willing to discuss this topic, rather than being held back by a juvenile taboo.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;463&quot; data-total-count=&quot;10217&quot;&gt;By 2009, Mr. Reid decided that the program had made such extraordinary discoveries that he argued for heightened security to protect it. “Much progress has been made with the identification of several highly sensitive, unconventional aerospace-related findings,” Mr. Reid said in a letter to William Lynn III, a deputy defense secretary at the time, requesting that it be designated a “restricted special access program” limited to a few listed officials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;328&quot; data-total-count=&quot;10545&quot;&gt;A 2009 Pentagon briefing summary of the program prepared by its director at the time asserted that “what was considered science fiction is now science fact,” and that the United States was incapable of defending itself against some of the technologies discovered. Mr. Reid’s request for the special designation was denied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;516&quot; data-total-count=&quot;11061&quot;&gt;Mr. Elizondo, in his resignation letter of Oct. 4, said there was a need for more serious attention to “the many accounts from the Navy and other services of unusual aerial systems interfering with military weapon platforms and displaying beyond-next-generation capabilities.” He expressed his frustration with the limitations placed on the program, telling Mr. Mattis that “there remains a vital need to ascertain capability and intent of these phenomena for the benefit of the armed forces and the nation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;364&quot; data-total-count=&quot;11425&quot;&gt;Mr. Elizondo has now joined Mr. Puthoff and another former Defense Department official, Christopher K. Mellon, who was a deputy assistant secretary of defense for intelligence, in a new commercial venture called To the Stars Academy of Arts and Science. They are speaking publicly about their efforts as their venture aims to raise money for research into U.F.O.s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;292&quot; data-total-count=&quot;11717&quot;&gt;In the interview, Mr. Elizondo said he and his government colleagues had determined that the phenomena they had studied did not seem to originate from any country. “That fact is not something any government or institution should classify in order to keep secret from the people,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;185&quot; data-total-count=&quot;11902&quot;&gt;For his part, Mr. Reid said he did not know where the objects had come from. “If anyone says they have the answers now, they’re fooling themselves,” he said. “We do not know.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;story-ad-5&quot; class=&quot;story-ad ad ad-placeholder nocontent robots-nocontent&quot;&gt;

&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/12/16/us/politics/pentagon-program-ufo-harry-reid.html#story-continues-7&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;47&quot; data-total-count=&quot;11949&quot; id=&quot;story-continues-7&quot;&gt;But, he said, “we have to start someplace.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/12/16/us/politics/pentagon-program-ufo-harry-reid.html#whats-next&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2017 17:54:45 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>farseer</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2017/12/16/us/politics/pentagon-program-ufo-harry-reid.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Glowing Auras and ‘Black Money’: The Pentagon’s Mysterious U.F.O. Program</og:title>
<og:description>The shadowy program began in 2007 and was largely funded at the request of Harry Reid, the former Senate majority leader, who has had a longtime interest in space phenomena.</og:description>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/12/16/autossell/STILL2/STILL2-facebookJumbo-v2.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2017/12/16/us/politics/pentagon-program-ufo-harry-reid.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Amazon&amp;#039;s Fake Review Problem</title>
<link>http://www.brianbien.com/amazons-fake-review-problem/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.brianbien.com/amazons-fake-review-problem/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;One reason we buy from Amazon: plenty of reviews. But what if many of Amazon’s top-reviewed items have fake, paid reviews?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was looking for a sunrise alarm clock this morning and started searching through the many reviews, filtering by ones that mentioned “minutes,” since I wanted to learn about the product’s timer feature. This surfaced a bunch of similar-looking reviews:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.brianbien.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/Screen-Shot-2017-12-16-at-8.37.47-AM.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-722 size-full alignnone&quot; src=&quot;http://www.brianbien.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/Screen-Shot-2017-12-16-at-8.37.47-AM.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1097&quot; height=&quot;532&quot; srcset=&quot;http://www.brianbien.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/Screen-Shot-2017-12-16-at-8.37.47-AM.png 1097w, http://www.brianbien.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/Screen-Shot-2017-12-16-at-8.37.47-AM-300x145.png 300w, http://www.brianbien.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/Screen-Shot-2017-12-16-at-8.37.47-AM-768x372.png 768w, http://www.brianbien.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/Screen-Shot-2017-12-16-at-8.37.47-AM-1024x497.png 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1097px) 100vw, 1097px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, we see both the top and bottom review with the sentence,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The light can be pretty bright, you can adjust it where it’ll be dim and slowly brighten 30 minutes before the alarm time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did “Becky” and “Dione Milton” really both happen to write a review with the exact same 23-word sentence? Or, is it more likely that they are agents sourcing reviews from a script, and they sloppily pasted their reviews without rewriting them (as they were presumably instructed to do)? Note also the post dates: December 12, 2017. “Becky” and “Dione Milton” both had private profiles, where their 5-6 reviews were hidden – very similar looking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon – who has some of the world’s most advanced ML – really needs to step up its review fraud detection game. Imagine how great the Amazon shopping experience would be if we could trust its reviews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Third party meta review sites like Fakespot will identify problems for us (in this case, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fakespot.com/product/wake-up-light-digital-sunrise-alarm-clock-2017-updated-clock-with-multi-colorful-night-light-6-nature-sounds-fm-radio-sunrise-and-sunset-simulation-perfect-suit-for-bedside&quot;&gt;the product got an “F” grade&lt;/a&gt;) – so why doesn’t Amazon?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon: you can do better.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2017 16:57:17 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>doglet</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.brianbien.com/amazons-fake-review-problem/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Firefox is on a slippery slope</title>
<link>https://drewdevault.com/2017/12/16/Firefox-is-on-a-slippery-slope.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://drewdevault.com/2017/12/16/Firefox-is-on-a-slippery-slope.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;For a long time, it was just setting the default search provider to Google in exchange for a beefy stipend. Later, paid links in your new tab page were added. Then, a proprietary service, Pocket, was bundled into the browser - not as an addon, but a hardcoded feature. In the past few days, we’ve discovered an advertisement in the form of browser extension was sideloaded into user browsers. Whoever is leading these decisions at Mozilla needs to be stopped.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here’s a breakdown of what happened a few days ago. Mozilla and NBC Universal did a “collaboration” (read: promotion) for the TV show Mr. Robot. It involved sideloading a sketchy browser extension which will &lt;strong&gt;invert&lt;/strong&gt; text that matches a list of Mr. Robot-related keywords like “fsociety”, “robot”, “undo”, and “fuck”, and does a number of other things like adding an HTTP header to certain sites you visit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This extension was sideloaded into browsers via the “experiments” feature. Not only are these experiments enabled by default, but updates &lt;a href=&quot;https://redd.it/7i4puf&quot;&gt;have been known&lt;/a&gt; to re-enable it if you turn it off. The advertisement addon shows up &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bolcer.org/looking-glass2.png&quot;&gt;like this&lt;/a&gt; on your addon page, and was added to Firefox stable. If I saw this before I knew what was going on, I would think my browser was compromised! Apparently it was a mistake that this showed up on the addon page, though - it was supposed to be &lt;em&gt;silently&lt;/em&gt; sideloaded into your browser!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1423003&quot;&gt;a ticket&lt;/a&gt; on Bugzilla (Firefox’s bug tracker) for discussing this experiment, but it’s locked down and no one outside of Mozilla can see it. There’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1424977&quot;&gt;another ticket&lt;/a&gt;, filed by concerned users, which has since been disabled and had many comments removed, particularly the angry (but respectful) ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mozilla, this is &lt;strong&gt;not okay&lt;/strong&gt;. This is wrong on so many levels. Frankly, whoever was in charge should be fired over this - which is not something I call for lightly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, web browsers are a &lt;em&gt;tool&lt;/em&gt;. I don’t want my browser to fool around, I just want it to display websites faithfully. This is the prime directive of web browsers, and you broke that. When I compile vim with gcc, I don’t want gcc to make vim sporadically add “fsociety” into every document I write. I want it to compile vim and go away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More importantly, these advertising anti-features gravely - perhaps terminally - violate user trust. This event tells us that “Firefox studies” into a backdoor for advertisements, and I will &lt;em&gt;never&lt;/em&gt; trust it again. But it doesn’t matter - you’re going to re-enable it on the next update. You know what that means? I will never trust &lt;em&gt;Firefox&lt;/em&gt; again. I switched to &lt;a href=&quot;http://qutebrowser.org/&quot;&gt;qutebrowser&lt;/a&gt; as my daily driver because this crap was starting to add up, but I still used Firefox from time to time and never resigned from it entirely or stopped recommending it to friends. Well, whatever goodwill was left is gone now, and I will only recommend other browsers henceforth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mozilla, you fucked up &lt;em&gt;bad&lt;/em&gt;, and you still haven’t apologised. The study is still active and ongoing. There is no amount of money that you should have accepted for this. This is the last straw - and I took a lot of straws from you. Goodbye forever, Mozilla.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been clarified that an about:config flag must be set for this addon’s behavior to be visible. This improves the situation considerably, but I do not think it exenorates Mozilla and I stand firm behind most of my points. The study has also been rolled back by Mozilla, and Mozilla has issued &lt;a href=&quot;https://gizmodo.com/mozilla-slipped-a-mr-robot-promo-plugin-into-firefox-1821332254&quot;&gt;statements&lt;/a&gt; to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://gizmodo.com/after-blowback-firefox-will-move-mr-robot-extension-t-1821354314&quot;&gt;media&lt;/a&gt; justifying the study (no apology has been issued).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Responses&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.jeaye.com/2017/12/16/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla, Firefox, Looking Glass, and you&lt;/a&gt; via jeaye.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2017 16:16:40 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Sir_Cmpwn</dc:creator>
<og:title>Firefox is on a slippery slope</og:title>
<og:description>For a long time, it was just setting the default search provider to Google in exchange for a beefy stipend. Later, paid links in your new tab page were added. Then, a proprietary service, Pocket, was bundled into the browser - not as an addon, but a hardcoded feature. In the past few days, we’ve discovered an advertisement in the form of browser extension was sideloaded into user browsers. Whoever is leading these decisions at Mozilla needs to be stopped.</og:description>
<og:url>http://sircmpwn.github.io/2017/12/16/Firefox-is-on-a-slippery-slope.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://drewdevault.com/2017/12/16/Firefox-is-on-a-slippery-slope.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Aren’t Any Bankers in Prison for Causing the Financial Crisis? (2016)</title>
<link>https://www.theatlantic.com/business/archive/2016/08/why-arent-any-bankers-in-prison-for-causing-the-financial-crisis/496232/?single_page=true</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theatlantic.com/business/archive/2016/08/why-arent-any-bankers-in-prison-for-causing-the-financial-crisis/496232/?single_page=true</guid>
<description>&lt;section id=&quot;article-section-1&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;If hotheaded online commenters ran the Justice Department, would America's prisons be full of traders responsible for the financial crisis? It is tempting to think so—that the lack of corporate prosecutions is due to a lack of will rather than a lack of way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But convicting bankers—or any other white-collar workers whose decisions at work have ostensibly damaged the economy—is difficult because while it is easy to identify systematic wrongdoing, it's much harder to pin blame, at least in the way a court might approve of, on an individual within that system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sam Buell, a Duke law professor, argues in his recent book &lt;a href=&quot;http://books.wwnorton.com/books/Capital-Offenses/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'link',r'0',r'496232'&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Capital Offenses: Business Crime and Punishment in America’s Corporate Age&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that this is no accident. The difficulties that government prosecutors face in cobbling together fraud cases against even the most nefarious executives illuminates the fact that, legally, corporations are big, fancy responsibility-diffusion mechanisms. It’s what they were designed to do: Let a bunch of people get together, take some strategic risks they might otherwise not take, and then make sure none of them is devastated individually if things go south.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id=&quot;article-section-2&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;In his book, Buell, who served as the lead prosecutor for the Justice Department’s Enron Task Force, sets out to soften some Americans’ lock-’em-up mentalities by providing some perspective on how the criminal-justice system works and why it works that way. I recently spoke with Buell about the anger many Americans feel about corporate crime, other potential targets of that anger, and why convicting white-collar criminals is not as straightforward as many people think it should be. Our conversation has been edited for context and clarity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Joe Pinsker:&lt;/strong&gt; I wanted to start by asking you the question that I think is probably the one that people are most likely to have asked at some point: Why are there no bankers in prison as a result of the financial crisis?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sam Buell:&lt;/strong&gt; Well, the short answer is we don't know, because prosecutors aren't required to make a report when they decide not to prosecute a case, so we don't know what exactly the evidence is that whichever prosecutors looked at these cases decided wasn't sufficient. So with that big caveat, which is to say we have to speculate, my view is that it's likely that these cases weren't brought because it's very difficult to establish a theory of criminal fraud when you have essentially one sophisticated bank trader selling a product to another sophisticated bank trader and the person who lost in the trade is saying, &quot;Hey, there's more about this that you should have told me that you didn't tell me.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id=&quot;article-section-3&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;And these are not special fiduciary relationships, like the relationship between some investment advisers and average investors—this is trader against trader in a very sophisticated market. In a criminal case you've got to prove intent to deceive—that is, you've got to prove that there was an individual who at the time they sold that security to the other banker knew that what they were saying was false about that security. So these are hard cases to make, and I think, bottom line, maybe if we were to go through every single one of them, maybe we could find a case here, a case there, to quibble with the government's decision. But the idea that this is an area where you could have imprisoned large numbers of mortgage-backed-securities traders for what they did and the government just sat by and didn't do it, to me, is just totally implausible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The frustrating thing about the financial crisis is that the victims, of which there were so, so many of us who were severely victimized when this happened, were not parties to the trades that created the problem. We weren't the ones who bought the mortgage-backed securities. So yes, we were victimized in the sense that we were downstream victims in the economy from a sort of risk fiesta that was allowed to go out of control because it wasn't regulated. But because we were victimized doesn't mean that somebody can be put in prison.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pinsker:&lt;/strong&gt; It would be easy to, after reading a Matt Taibbi article or watching &lt;em&gt;The Big Short&lt;/em&gt;, to come away with the feeling that you just alluded to, that a lot of people should have been locked up. Can you talk a little bit about what narratives like that don't necessarily capture?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id=&quot;article-section-4&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buell:&lt;/strong&gt; Well, I think what my book's trying to fill the gap in is for a layperson to understand what's going on in the legal system. Certainly the legal system is not optimal, and there are a lot of deficiencies in it, like in any society, but the reason why there's a lot of friction in the legal system is that it's actually very difficult to draw lines between right and wrong in an area where we're essentially saying two things at once: Be aggressive, take risks, make money—but don't hurt people while you're doing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So when we have situations like the financial crisis, where a lot of people end up hurt in the end, if you don't look at the question of, “Well, what are the questions that really have to get answered for there to be a result legally?” then it's very easy to say, &quot;Oh, a bunch of people got hurt, so a bunch of people should go to jail.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But would we really want a legal system that did that? Would we really want a legal system that just said, “White-collar crime is going to be the thing that we don't like in retrospect when things go bad.” Which is not the system that we have. We have a system that says, “Look, there need to be rules of the road,” and in order to convict somebody of a crime, you have to really establish that those rules of the road were broken at the time, and that the person who broke them knew that they were breaking the rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So in some sense, I agree colloquially with Steve Carell's character in &lt;em&gt;The Big Short&lt;/em&gt; when he says, roughly, &quot;Oh my gosh, this was all a big fraud!&quot; In a sense, yes, the mortgage-backed-securities market was a grand deception, but that's not how the law deals with the question of whether Trader Frank or Trader Harry should go to prison for their participation in that system. That's got to be a much more specific question legally. And it should be, because the way we deal with disasters in the capital markets shouldn't be just to have a big sweep and send a bunch of people to jail just to send a message. That's not the way that the American legal system works and I don't think it's the way most people would want it to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pinsker:&lt;/strong&gt; At various times in the book you liken the American appetite for prosecuting white-collar criminals to some sort of bloodlust. Can you talk about why that attitude may actually be counterproductive for making businesses operate in a way that people probably want them to operate and is fair to anyone involved in the economy?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id=&quot;article-section-5&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buell:&lt;/strong&gt; I wouldn't use, and I don't think I actually used in the book, the term “bloodlust.” I think that's a little strong. But I do think there is a sense that people are particularly outraged about this form of crime, understandably, because it's generally perpetrated by people who are in a position of economic and social advantage in society. There's no reason to have sympathy for the plight of this person in the way that you might for some kinds of street criminals. So there's an anger there about, how dare the privileged abuse their position in society like this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it's very understandable, then, that people would turn to the criminal-justice system as an outlet for that anger. But as you alluded to, one of the arguments I make in the book is, while that's understandable, it may not be the most productive thing in the end because the criminal-justice system is not well-suited and perhaps should not be primarily a vehicle for venting anger. It should be a vehicle for trying individual cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we go into that system with that anger, number one, we may not get what we're looking for, and number two, it's an entirely backward-looking exercise. We're just saying, &quot;What should we do with these people now that we're angry at them?&quot; As opposed to, &quot;What can we learn about how the systems were set up in a bad way, and how can we fix the systems?&quot; whether it's the regulations that apply in a particular industry—banking, automotive manufacturing, oil drilling, whatever the industry is that has produced the problem—or it's the incentives that apply generally in the corporate structure, the structure of large corporations, and the question of personal responsibility for corporate management. Could we think about maybe arranging corporations in a different way to lower the appetite for risk or at least the appetite for bad kinds of big risks?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id=&quot;article-section-6&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;And those conversations, it seems to me, can be displaced a bit, and have been, in fact, in the wake of the financial crisis, by the dominance of the &quot;why no bankers in jail?&quot; narrative, which I think has a corollary to it implicit in it, which is, &quot;If only the bankers were in jail, we would have fixed the problem.&quot; That's the part that I'm actually quite skeptical of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming in from the Enron prosecutions, and in that era, there were some very serious sentences doled out to the kind of people who, 20 or 30 years ago, it would have been considered unthinkable that they would go to federal prison for a decade or more. I mean, managers of Fortune 500 companies, Fortune 100 companies, Fortune 10 companies, getting long prison sentences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet there's very little evidence that that changed behavior in some larger sense, and in fact a lot of what went on in the banks leading up to the financial crisis was risk-taking and accounting maneuvers that were quite similar in a lot of ways to what went on at Enron—harder to prosecute, because they had lawyer and accountant approvals all over them, but similar in the types of risks that were being taken and the kinds of assumptions that were being made. So in that sense it seems that the prosecution process, as important as it is when there's serious wrong conduct, and there's plenty of examples of that—the Bernard Madoffs of the world, and others—it's mostly a backward-looking exercise. It's not a constructive, forward-looking one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id=&quot;article-section-7&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pinsker:&lt;/strong&gt; I think part of that “Why aren’t more bankers in jail?” narrative is an impulse to, as you say in the book, treat them “like common criminals.” And you recognize the mass incarceration of people who commit street crime as morally reprehensible. Can you walk me through, though, what it would have to look like if, when it comes to policing, white-collar criminals actually were treated like common criminals?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buell:&lt;/strong&gt; Well, it's an apples-and-oranges problem, because, when we talk about white-collar criminals, certainly in the corporate context, we're talking about people who are working in lawfully created and licensed industries. Not only are they lawfully created and licensed—they're encouraged. This is not the case with dealing cocaine or heroin or human trafficking and the other kinds of things that we see producing large segments of the federal prison population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To say, &quot;Oh, we just need to police white-collar crime the way we police street crime&quot; kind of makes no sense, because we police street crime the way we police street crime because it's people engaged in entire realms of behavior that are banned. They're black markets, so you can have a pervasive policing presence in that context and any amount of the activity that's observed justifies legal intervention. What are you going to do in the context of lawful industries? Are you just going to send the cops in to patrol the corridors of office buildings? What are they supposed to be looking for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id=&quot;article-section-8&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now, we do have, obviously, regulators that monitor many of these industries, and we could do a lot better job of regulating some of these industries, but that's different. That's a process of working with the rules to set the boundaries. It's not a question of having cops wandering around making arrests all the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pinsker:&lt;/strong&gt; How do you bridge the gap between the argument you’re making—which, however sound, is still rationalizing the status quo—and the average person's frustrations with the system?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buell:&lt;/strong&gt; I think we're getting to a place where that gap may be bridging a little bit on its own, in that, in contrast to where we were 10 or 20 years ago, we've got a widespread understanding that the system for policing street crime is unfair. But the way to fix street crime is not to necessarily get unreasonably harsh on white collar crime. That may be a way of satisfying some of the anger about the way the criminal-justice system has exploded in the United States with regard to drugs and other forms of street crime, but it doesn't really address the street-crime problem—it maybe just makes people feel better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If in fact we're going to start looking at street-crime policing and saying—and I'm not the first one to make this point—“What if street-crime policing looked a little bit more like other forms of regulation where we actually have government systems that are trying to deal with the root causes of the problems rather than just locking up enormous amounts of people and expecting it to change something?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id=&quot;article-section-9&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pinsker:&lt;/strong&gt; Do you think people will ever be satisfied with how corporate crime is punished in the U.S., or are they just going to continue railing against what is an inevitable frustrating feature of the way the economy is set up?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buell:&lt;/strong&gt; Well, I hope that their attitudes will change if they read my book, but I'm not that unrealistic as to think that my book is going to become a bestseller or something. But the book is intended to be more thought-provoking than problem-solving, and one of the points I make in the book is that this whole subject has to do with something that we as a culture are deeply ambivalent about, and I don't expect us to stop being ambivalent about that. I think we have an ambivalent relationship with the large corporation and with capitalism. It's a relationship that involves need and dependency and some level of celebration but also resentment, anger, and victimization. As long as that relationship, as long as the big corporation and the capital economy continue to define us as a society, that relationship is going to remain ambivalent. And as long as that relationship is ambivalent, I don't expect people to reach a point of happiness and satisfaction in the way that the system deals with white-collar crime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pinsker:&lt;/strong&gt; You teach a class at Duke on corporate crime. How do the law students that you teach today differ from your generation and your peers in how they think about corporate crime?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id=&quot;article-section-10&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buell:&lt;/strong&gt; I think there's a huge difference with the level of awareness of these issues. When I was a law student in the early ‘90s, I was at NYU Law School, which, of all the law schools in the country, is probably the one that's most connected to what's happening on Wall Street and in the corporate-law space. In many ways that's kind of what's defined NYU as a law school. We didn't even have a course in white-collar crime when I was at NYU law school, and most of the big New York firms to which NYU was feeding students didn't even have practices in this space. It's not like we didn't know what white-collar crime was, but it just did not have the prominence in the legal profession and in the public realm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The students that I get now, they're coming to me having read &lt;em&gt;The Big Short&lt;/em&gt; or having seen the movie, or watched &lt;em&gt;Billions&lt;/em&gt;. They've been reading about this stuff in the newspapers; they know about the financial crisis. Some of them even remember something about Enron or being told about Enron. There's an understanding among students now that this topic is an important piece of the public-policy space in the United States, in ways that it did not have that prominence when I was in law school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I think that's because the scale of the problem's gotten bigger, and crisis after crisis has showed us that these problems are very difficult to get under control. And that's maybe not good news for the American people, but it's great news for me as a scholar and a teacher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2017 15:58:32 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>sidcool</dc:creator>
<og:title>Why Aren’t Any Bankers in Prison for Causing the Financial Crisis?</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>http://www.theatlantic.com/business/archive/2016/08/why-arent-any-bankers-in-prison-for-causing-the-financial-crisis/496232/</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn.theatlantic.com/assets/media/img/mt/2016/08/RTR2O9RK/facebook.jpg?1471443564</og:image>
<og:description>Sam Buell, the government’s lead prosecutor in the Enron scandal, explains why convicting white-collar criminals isn’t as straightforward as most people think it should be.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theatlantic.com/business/archive/2016/08/why-arent-any-bankers-in-prison-for-causing-the-financial-crisis/496232/?single_page=true</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Attention Is All You Need</title>
<link>https://papers.nips.cc/paper/7181-attention-is-all-you-need</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://papers.nips.cc/paper/7181-attention-is-all-you-need</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Part of: &lt;a href=&quot;https://papers.nips.cc/book/advances-in-neural-information-processing-systems-30-2017&quot;&gt;Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems 30 (NIPS 2017) pre-proceedings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Pre-Proceedings&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://papers.nips.cc/paper/7181-attention-is-all-you-need.pdf&quot;&gt;[PDF]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://papers.nips.cc/paper/7181-attention-is-all-you-need/bibtex&quot;&gt;[BibTeX]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://papers.nips.cc/paper/7181-attention-is-all-you-need-supplemental.zip&quot;&gt;[Supplemental]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://media.nips.cc/nipsbooks/nipspapers/paper_files/nips30/reviews/3058.html&quot;&gt;[Reviews]&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Authors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Conference Event Type: Poster&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;The dominant sequence transduction models are based on complex recurrent orconvolutional neural networks in an encoder and decoder configuration. The best performing such models also connect the encoder and decoder through an attentionm echanisms. We propose a novel, simple network architecture based solely onan attention mechanism, dispensing with recurrence and convolutions entirely.Experiments on two machine translation tasks show these models to be superiorin quality while being more parallelizable and requiring significantly less timeto train. Our single model with 165 million parameters, achieves 27.5 BLEU onEnglish-to-German translation, improving over the existing best ensemble result by over 1 BLEU. On English-to-French translation, we outperform the previoussingle state-of-the-art with model by 0.7 BLEU, achieving a BLEU score of 41.1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Neural Information Processing Systems (NIPS)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Papers published at the Neural Information Processing Systems Conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2017 06:15:42 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>espeed</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://papers.nips.cc/paper/7181-attention-is-all-you-need</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Statistics, we have a problem</title>
<link>https://medium.com/@kristianlum/statistics-we-have-a-problem-304638dc5de5</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://medium.com/@kristianlum/statistics-we-have-a-problem-304638dc5de5</guid>
<description>&lt;p name=&quot;9a82&quot; id=&quot;9a82&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;Recently, while browsing Twitter, I saw a few machine learning researchers post about an incident at one of their big conferences (NIPS) in which a band performing at the closing party made jokes about sexual assault. This is a band that is composed mostly of famous academics in machine learning and statistics. I was completely unsurprised to learn that a person involved in making the troubling comments is a well-respected academic who is widely known to behave inappropriately at conferences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;147b&quot; id=&quot;147b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Right before I ever attended my first conference, one of the women who was a year ahead of me in my program pulled me aside to warn about him. She told me to do my best to avoid him at the conference but “every woman has a story about him, so it’s only a matter of time.” Of course, she was right. Months before my defense, while at a poster session to present my dissertation work, he touched me on the leg and told me that my dress was “way too sexy for a poster session.” I remember feeling deflated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;aae0&quot; id=&quot;aae0&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;In the years since, he’s sent me several inappropriate private Facebook messages. In the first, he responded to a Facebook post I had made asking for people’s experiences with Lasik eye surgery with a message that some activities would become much better. Trying to deflect what I thought was going to be an awkward interaction, I responded that I was looking forward to better bird watching. He followed up with a private message that “the activity [he was] thinking about was sex, but bird watching would be better too ;)”. I ignored him. On another occasion, I posted about some data visualizations using data from a medical journal that involved the relationship between age and pubic hair. He sent me a private message explaining how the data is corroborated by his own experiences watching a certain genre of porn. What his personal preferences regarding porn are is something I definitely did not want to know. Perhaps I shouldn’t have posted about the data given the racy topic, but I thought it was in-bounds since it was a comment on data in a medical journal. I guess I was wrong. I responded but tried to end the conversation quickly. On another occasion, he sent me a private message out of the blue to let me know that there was another researcher with a name very similar to my own who published an article that “is even about sex, broadly defined (fecundity). You guys related?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;5541&quot; id=&quot;5541&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The thing is, he’s not even the worst in our field. At ISBA 2010 (the same conference where the comments were made about my dress), I saw and experienced things that, in retrospect, were instrumental in my decision to (mostly) leave the field. In my opinion, the worst offender is S (full name left out intentionally). He spent the first half of the conference befriending my friend and me and acting interested in our research. He would occasionally say things that were questionable but would immediately follow up with pictures of his young daughters or stories to make himself out to be a doting husband and father. I now believe this was to gain our trust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;0058&quot; id=&quot;0058&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;One night after the conference talks were over, a bunch of conference participants and I went for a swim in the ocean. While I was swimming around, S repeatedly grabbed me under the water, putting his hands on my torso, hips, and thighs. I tried to play it off and swim away. He picked me up and pulled me into his chest. He then started to carry me away from the rest of the group, presumably to have some sort of private moment with me that I had absolutely no interest in sharing with him. I struggled, gently at first and then more forcefully, and he let me go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;441c&quot; id=&quot;441c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;As I swam back to the group, I remember again feeling totally humiliated. I felt that this was evidence that, like S, all of the other more senior men who had showed interest in my research must actually have only been trying to sleep with me. I felt embarrassed that I had been seen being friendly with him, like everyone else was in on it and they all thought I must like this sort of attention. I felt that I had brought it on myself by actively participating in the conference culture that rewarded provocative comments and excessive drunkenness with social approval and acceptance into an old boys club of sorts. I felt like a joke, and I carried this feeling with me for years after.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;0bdc&quot; id=&quot;0bdc&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I was not the only person who was bothered by S’s behavior. He relentlessly pressured my friend, a female graduate student, to have sex with him by saying that because he was married and she was engaged, those two things “cancelled each other out”. Therefore, he argued, they should have sex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;13e8&quot; id=&quot;13e8&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;At this same conference, the morning after a particularly debaucherous night, a married professor was overheard imploring other people to smell his fingers following an encounter with a junior colleague. With the benefit of hindsight, I now recognize my experience at that conference as a critical moment in my career, one I looked back on shortly thereafter when I decided that perhaps this version of academia was not for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;1d9d&quot; id=&quot;1d9d&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;At JSM (another stats conference) a few years later at the Google reception, S was standing right behind me talking loudly about “banging smokin’ hot chicks.” I turned around to give him a look that I hoped would tell him to knock it off but he replied that I was just jealous that he wasn’t talking about me. The group he was standing with laughed, and I felt disgusted that he actually thought that I’d liked how he’d groped me at the conference years before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;1eda&quot; id=&quot;1eda&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I debated saying something about him at the time, but who would have cared? It was a story passed down among female graduate students in my circles that when one woman graduate student was groped at a party by a professor and reported it to a senior female professor, she was told that if she wanted to stay in the field, she’d just have to get used to it. On many occasions, I have been smacked on the butt at conferences. No one ever seemed to think it was a problem. I knew it would be even more difficult to get people to find S’s behavior problematic since he is employed by a large tech company and his participation in academic conferences, I have heard, often comes with sponsorship money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;56ee&quot; id=&quot;56ee&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;About two years ago, there was a turning point that made me decide to start speaking up about what I’d experienced in statistics. I made it a point to privately tell anyone I felt I could trust in my field about all of my experiences. Privately, I named names. I told my male friends and colleagues in the field about how these experiences had impacted my career trajectory in hopes that they would be vigilant for this type of behavior. I told women who the bad actors were, hoping they would be able to avoid them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;e343&quot; id=&quot;e343&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I started doing this because I heard that S (for the second time to my knowledge) had taken advantage of a junior person who had had too much to drink. This time, his act had been witnessed first-hand by several professors at the conference. Since then, I have heard one professor who witnessed the incident openly lament that he’ll have to find a way to delicately advise his female students on “how not to get raped by S” so as not to lose promising students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;5ae3&quot; id=&quot;5ae3&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;To say that S’s bad behavior is an open secret in the community is an understatement. With the current turning of the tides in regards to how seriously sexual harassment in professional settings is taken, I’d been hoping that this behavior would stop and that those who were known to have engaged in this behavior would not be elevated to positions of prestige and authority. But, a few weeks ago I received an email announcing that S was up for election to the ISBA Board of Directors. I appealed to two incredible friends/colleagues with more senior standing in the organization (who have always taken complaints about these things very seriously), and at their urging, he was removed from the ballot. This makes me hopeful that change is coming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;1e26&quot; id=&quot;1e26&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;However, the fact that he even made the ballot, combined with hearing that jokes about sexual assault are brazenly being made by a person we all know to be one of the harassers is the second turning point for me. It’s clear change isn’t coming fast enough. I don’t want to only speak quietly behind the scenes, hoping that someone with more academic clout than I have will do something about it. While comments alone certainly do not rise to the level of assault, they normalize the hostile atmosphere, particularly for women, in the field. The fact that people are comfortable publicly making jokes about sexual assault on stage at a conference reveals how toxic the environment remains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;28b9&quot; id=&quot;28b9&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p graf--trailing&quot;&gt;We need to start holding prominent individuals accountable for how their inappropriate behavior negatively impacts the careers of their junior colleagues. I’m saying this publicly because whenever I have shared these stories privately with my colleagues, both men and women, they are appalled. It is time for us to be publicly and openly appalled, not just attempting to tactfully deflect inappropriate advances and privately warning other women. We need to remove the power of the “open secret” that these people use to take advantage of their respected positions in our field. We know who these people are, and we should stop tolerating this culture of harassment, or else we become complicit in it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2017 04:11:37 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>stablemap</dc:creator>
<og:title>Statistics, we have a problem. – Kristian Lum – Medium</og:title>
<og:url>https://medium.com/@kristianlum/statistics-we-have-a-problem-304638dc5de5</og:url>
<og:description>Recently, while browsing Twitter, I saw a few machine learning researchers post about an incident at one of their big conferences (NIPS) in…</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://medium.com/@kristianlum/statistics-we-have-a-problem-304638dc5de5</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>