<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>URL shorteners set ad tracking cookies</title>
<link>https://ylukem.com/blog/url-shorteners-set-ad-tracking-cookies</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://ylukem.com/blog/url-shorteners-set-ad-tracking-cookies</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;light&quot;&gt;January 2, 2021 ☼ &lt;a class=&quot;light&quot; href=&quot;https://ylukem.com/tagged/writing&quot;&gt;writing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Christmas, a family member sent me a &lt;span class=&quot;small-caps&quot;&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt; to a family Zoom call. However, they didn’t send me a direct link to Zoom. Instead, they sent me a &lt;span class=&quot;pull-double&quot;&gt;“&lt;/span&gt;tinyurl.com” link.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I clicked on the link, my &lt;span class=&quot;small-caps&quot;&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt; bar flashed an intermediate domain that was neither Zoom nor TinyURL. Later, I used cURL to see where this &lt;span class=&quot;small-caps&quot;&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt; was really going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;hljs bash&quot;&gt;$ curl -v https://tinyurl.com/examplezoom
...
&amp;gt; GET /examplezoom HTTP/2
&amp;gt; Host: tinyurl.com
...
&amp;lt; location: https://redirect.viglink.com?key=a7e37b5f6ff1de9cb410158b1013e54a&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fzoom.us%2Fj%2F123456789&amp;amp;prodOvrd=RAC&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;(all &lt;span class=&quot;small-caps&quot;&gt;HTTP&lt;/span&gt; responses abridged for clarity)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure enough, the redirect wasn’t clean at all. TinyURL was first sending me to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/VigLink&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;VigLink&lt;/a&gt;. VigLink is an advertising (tracking) company that specializes in affiliate marketing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the redirect in cURL reveals another unsavory fact. VigLink &lt;em&gt;sets cookies&lt;/em&gt; before they send me to the intended destination on Zoom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;hljs bash&quot;&gt;$ curl -v &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-string&quot;&gt;'https://redirect.viglink.com?key=a7e37b5f6ff1de9cb410158b1013e54a&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fzoom.us%2Fj%2F123456789&amp;amp;prodOvrd=RAC'&lt;/span&gt;
&amp;gt; GET /?key=a7e37b5f6ff1de9cb410158b1013e54a&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fzoom.us%2Fj%2F123456789&amp;amp;prodOvrd=RAC HTTP/1.1
&amp;gt; Host: redirect.viglink.com
...
&amp;lt; Set-Cookie: vglnk.PartnerRfsh.p=; Domain=.viglink.com; Path=/; SameSite=None; Expires=Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 GMT; Secure
&amp;lt; Set-Cookie: vglnk.Agent.p=v-c935c520ecc561fe60a9418874e023b7; Domain=.viglink.com; Path=/; SameSite=None; Expires=Mon, 01 Feb 2021 16:52:34 GMT; Secure&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These cookies give them the ability to track me across every other site that uses their advertising tech. Who knows what VigLink is doing with my data, but I personally wouldn’t trust an advertising company to keep my browsing history to themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, they didn’t give me a chance to opt-out of this tracking. I’m currently based in Europe and I would expect to see at least an interstitial asking for consent to be tracked. &lt;a href=&quot;https://tinyurl.com/privacy.php&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;TinyURL’s privacy policy&lt;/a&gt;, last updated in 2012, has no mention of either third party data-sharing nor the cookies they share from affiliates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn’t a phenomenon limited to TinyURL. More common &lt;span class=&quot;small-caps&quot;&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt; shorteners like t.co (Twitter) and bit.ly set cookies when you click on a link. While neither redirect you to an advertising company like TinyURL, Twitter’s primary business model is advertising, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitly.com/pages/privacy&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;bit.ly’s privacy policy&lt;/a&gt; says they share data with third parties to &lt;span class=&quot;pull-double&quot;&gt;“&lt;/span&gt;…provide advertising products and services…”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t use &lt;span class=&quot;small-caps&quot;&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt; shorteners. And if you click on a link from a &lt;span class=&quot;small-caps&quot;&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt; shortener, I recommend using tools like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/temporary-containers/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Temporary Containers Firefox extension&lt;/a&gt; to limit the scope of ad tracking. Personally, I took the time to send Sovrn (VigLink’s parent company) a &lt;a href=&quot;https://ylukem.com/files/_viglink-gdpr-email.png&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;small-caps&quot;&gt;GDPR&lt;/span&gt; request&lt;/a&gt;, and made sure to give them my tracking cookie. I’ll update this blog and &lt;a href=&quot;https://ylukem.com/newsletter&quot;&gt;my newsletter&lt;/a&gt; if I actually get anything substantive back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 19:05:23 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>firloop</dc:creator>
<og:title>URL shorteners set ad tracking cookies</og:title>
<og:description>This Christmas, a family member sent me a URL to a family Zoom call. However, they didn’t send me a direct link to Zoom. Instead, they sent me a</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://ylukem.com/blog/url-shorteners-set-ad-tracking-cookies</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Unanswered user makes question their MS thesis and answers self 2 years later</title>
<link>https://stackoverflow.com/questions/47444189/immediate-mode-gui-performance</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://stackoverflow.com/questions/47444189/immediate-mode-gui-performance</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Since there seems to be some interest in this question still (judging by the views), I thought I might aswell post an update:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ended up implementing an immediate mode GUI as my masters thesis, and have some numbers in on the performance. The gist is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Immediate Mode is better/faster in a lot of cases, and worse only in some cases. Overall, it is a completely viable approach to creating a GUI that responds fast and does not drain your battery.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I created a Spotify clone with about 50% of the UI-elements and rendering a single frame was in the microsecond range. The application consistently hit &amp;lt;400us for a single frame. With V-Sync enabled and a 60 Hz monitor, this equates to roughly 3% (400us per 16ms) CPU-Load &lt;em&gt;on a single core&lt;/em&gt;. Furthermore: a decent chunk of these 400us were constant factors, that wouldn't scale with more UI elements (e.g. Input, or setting up GPU).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The perfectionist in me still dislikes the fact that a GUI that does nothing consumes cycles, but the upsides were tremendous: When the GUI was being heavily interacted with, or when the window was being resized, it was still hitting 400us! This blows retained-mode GUIs out of the water. Try resizing Spotify, Windows Explorer, Visual Studio or basically anything else and see how they react to understand what I mean. I would guess Spotify goes down to 2 fps on my PC when resizing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Changing the UI is basically free. If you displayed 100 Buttons in a frame, and then exchange them all for Textboxes in the next, there is still no difference to the performance. Again, retained-mode GUIs tend to struggle with this scenario.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 more thoughts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Most of the time is spent on text-rendering, the rest is close to irrelevant. If you want to heavily optimize, this is going to be the hard problem. But even with only a little optimization, it's gonna be decent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I doubt that the vast performance difference is only or even mostly due to the difference of retained vs. immediate mode. Spotify for example uses a web-stack for UI, thats bound to be slow. I guess WPF, Win32 and the likes are just slow because they can get away with it, or because they were optimized for completely different PCs than we have now. They also do more, but not remotely enough to justify the difference.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am sure you could make a retained mode GUI that is a lot faster than my immediate mode GUI. There is just little incentive for it in general, which is a little sad tbh. I like efficient things.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;The key takeway for me is: It's fine, You can make it fast.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 18:57:52 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>anderspitman</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://stackoverflow.com/questions/47444189/immediate-mode-gui-performance</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn.sstatic.net/Sites/stackoverflow/Img/apple-touch-icon@2.png?v=73d79a89bded</og:image>
<og:title>immediate mode GUI performance</og:title>
<og:description>I am currently working on a standard windows desktop application (standard meaning no fancy stuff, just buttons, text, sliders and stuff) and have decided to write the gui-framework on my own, after</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://stackoverflow.com/questions/47444189/immediate-mode-gui-performance</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Uber discovered they’d been defrauded out of 2/3 of their ad spend</title>
<link>https://twitter.com/nandoodles/status/1345774768746852353</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://twitter.com/nandoodles/status/1345774768746852353</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/nandoodles/status/1345774768746852353&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/nandoodles/status/1345774768746852353&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25623858&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25623858&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 937&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 398&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 18:37:25 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rbanffy</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://stackoverflow.com/questions/47444189/immediate-mode-gui-performance</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn.sstatic.net/Sites/stackoverflow/Img/apple-touch-icon@2.png?v=73d79a89bded</og:image>
<og:title>immediate mode GUI performance</og:title>
<og:description>I am currently working on a standard windows desktop application (standard meaning no fancy stuff, just buttons, text, sliders and stuff) and have decided to write the gui-framework on my own, after</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://stackoverflow.com/questions/47444189/immediate-mode-gui-performance</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Rust is now overall faster than C in benchmarks</title>
<link>https://benchmarksgame-team.pages.debian.net/benchmarksgame/which-programs-are-fastest.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://benchmarksgame-team.pages.debian.net/benchmarksgame/which-programs-are-fastest.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;How many times slower, the fastest &lt;a href=&quot;https://benchmarksgame-team.pages.debian.net/benchmarksgame/description/summary.html&quot;&gt;benchmark programs&lt;/a&gt; for selected programming language implementations are, compared to the fastest written in any of the programming languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;chart-fastest-more&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://benchmarksgame-team.pages.debian.net/benchmarksgame/download/fastest-more.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Toy benchmark program busy seconds compared to the fastest for more programming language implementations.&quot; title=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice which boxes overlap completely. Notice which spread across too large a range of values for confidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The boxes are broken into separate groups, at the minima of the kernel density estimate for the geometric mean scores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;order&quot;&gt;You can see that &lt;strong&gt;the order would be different&lt;/strong&gt; if it was based on the median scores instead of the &lt;a class=&quot;external&quot; href=&quot;http://ece.uprm.edu/~nayda/Courses/Icom5047F06/Papers/paper4.pdf&quot;&gt;[pdf] geometric mean&lt;/a&gt; scores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;chart-fastest&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://benchmarksgame-team.pages.debian.net/benchmarksgame/download/fastest.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Toy benchmark program busy seconds compared to the fastest for selected programming language implementations.&quot; title=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 18:16:45 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>wiineeth</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://benchmarksgame-team.pages.debian.net/benchmarksgame/which-programs-are-fastest.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>I logged my activities at 15-minute intervals for the whole year</title>
<link>https://samplesize.one/blog/posts/my_year_in_data/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://samplesize.one/blog/posts/my_year_in_data/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;At around this time last year, I was being flooded with various articles on new year's resolutions and yearly summaries - as is typical in early January. I was trying to decide whether there is anything I hoped to change in my life. One of the big points on my 'roadmap to becoming a better human' google doc (everyone has one, right?) was being more aware of what happens with my time (what do I spend it on? am I sure I'm making &lt;em&gt;most&lt;/em&gt; of it?). This sounded like an actionable new year's resolution, so I decided to give it a try. However, I tend to get a bit intense sometimes and so I kind of logged all my activities at 15-minute intervals for the whole year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;You did what!?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I logged my activities at 15-minute intervals for the whole year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, check out this screenshot from my google sheet (btw, the spreadsheet title is just &quot;Life&quot;):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://samplesize.one/img/spreadsheet_banner.png&quot; alt=&quot;A screenshot of a google sheet I used to track my data with different activities coloured differently&quot; title=&quot;Life&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Why would you do this!?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to see what happens with my time. I knew I was spending quite a lot of it on social media, but I wasn't sure how much exactly. I also knew I was working quite a lot and wanted to quantify exactly how much (spoiler alert: not that much). I hoped that keeping track of what I do would help me to identify chunks of time that were being wasted and to turn them into &lt;em&gt;quality&lt;/em&gt; time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was also a purely scientific curiosity - there were many less important questions that I was curious to find answers to: do I get less sleep while at uni? How much time do I spend with people vs on my own? What are the effects of drinking alcohol? and many others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Ok, sure, whatever. How much effort did this take?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not that much actually!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I started, I was fully expecting to get bored with the whole thing and stop after maybe a month or so. Surprisingly, logging what I do turned out to be quite easy. As you might have noticed, I get quite excited about data so seeing my spreadsheet getting bigger and more colourful was enough of an incentive to keep me going. In the few instances, when I came close to stopping, a strong FOMD (fear of missing data) would always get me back on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Technicalities&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://samplesize.one/blog/posts/my_year_in_data/#data&quot; class=&quot;int_link&quot;&gt;I don't care, I want to see the data.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;I decided to log my activities in 15-minute intervals - I wanted to be able to catch shorter activities (especially procrastination) but didn't want it to be too crazy (though I might have lost the right to decide what is crazy when I started the whole project)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was using google sheets to log my data. I liked them because are online by default allowing me to log my data both on my laptop and my phone, the drag-to-copy cell content function makes it easy to log longer activities and the conditional formatting makes the spreadsheet nice and colourful providing instant gratification. You can access my template &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1XBUFCJGVL73kFvD0yO5e63fLfRuebemcqhnQoafXad4/edit?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I divided my activities into broad categories to make noting them down easier. Some categories were divided further into subcategories. For me, the categories were:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sleeping:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;focused work&lt;/strong&gt; - what I really understand as productivity:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;uni&lt;/strong&gt; - university (until June) and PhD (since October)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;self-improvement&lt;/strong&gt; - job applications, but also working on my personal projects (like writing code to analyse my data, or learning to draw)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;admin&lt;/strong&gt; - answering emails, filling forms etc (btw filling my time tracking spreadsheet was in this category)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;organising&lt;/strong&gt; - things like organising events for a society, conferences and other extracurricular things&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;German&lt;/strong&gt; - to track language learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;low-focus work&lt;/strong&gt; - same subcategories as in focused work. Low-focus work included activities that were more mechanical and didn't require too much brain power. For example, admin or organising my notes would be low-focus, while reading papers or writing essays would be focused work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;socialising&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;culture&lt;/strong&gt; (with subcategories: &lt;strong&gt;books&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;films&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;documentaries&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;TV shows&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;other&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;human function&lt;/strong&gt; - the boring stuff I need to do to stay alive (showering, making food, eating and things like that. On trips also setting tents etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;other quality time&lt;/strong&gt; - things that didn't really fit into the other categories. Subcategories: &lt;strong&gt;blogs&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;podcasts&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;news&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;games&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;YouTube&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;chilling&lt;/strong&gt; (for the times when I needed to just lie down or stare at the wall), and &lt;strong&gt;other&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;travelling&lt;/strong&gt; - time spent in buses/cars/planes etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;exercising&lt;/strong&gt; - deliberate exercise - running, cycling, exercise routines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;exercising (lower intensity)&lt;/strong&gt; - mostly walking/slow cycling, but also stretching&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;procrastinating&lt;/strong&gt; - mostly social media&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;idle&lt;/strong&gt; - waiting in queues etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The data&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alright, so now that I hopefully managed to calm you down, let's use the data I have to answer a few questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;What did I do in 2020?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://samplesize.one/img/year_props.png&quot; alt=&quot;A calendar showing how much time in total I spent on different activities&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turns out my top three activities of the year are sleeping (7h 45min on average per day and I'm very proud of this), working (6h 20 min on average per day) and socialising (3h 25 min on average per day). It is mostly what I would expect except that it always scares me how much time we actually spend unconscious. I can't decide whether 1h 20 min spent on human function (eating and showering etc) is a lot or not (a downside of a small sample size, I guess). On one hand, I could probably use that time to do more fun things but on the other hand maybe I should just chill. The procrastination time (on average 10 mins per day) is definitely less than it actually is - I will talk more about it in the productivity section below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another cool feature of the way I was logging my data was that I could log more than one activity into a single time slot (walking and listening to a podcast is a classic). This means that the total time spent on all activities sums up to more than 365 days - you can see this as 'extra days' on the plot above. Turns out that this year, I had 395 surplus hours or 16.5 surplus days. I hope I didn't spend them on human function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the categories from the plot above were divided into more helpful subcategories:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://samplesize.one/img/High_intensity_work.png&quot; alt=&quot;A calendar showing how much time I spent on different subcategories within focused work&quot;/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://samplesize.one/img/Low_intensity_work.png&quot; alt=&quot;A calendar showing how much time I spent on different subcategories within low-focus work&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By far, most of my work was towards uni and PhD - 51 days in total. After excluding the time from June to September, when I had holidays, this gives around 5hrs of work per day. While this includes weekends, this does not seem like a lot, especially that weekends are not really well respected at uni.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finding out how little focused work I do, even on the days that feel productive, was one of the biggest surprises of analysing my data. It turns out that a typical working day (9-17) would usually only give around 5-6 hours of actual work, while the rest of time would dissolve on low-focus work, chatting to people, coffee breaks and other little distractions. While there were days when I would reach 8 hours of focused work (for focused uni work I had 32 such days this year), they required either spending the whole day (9-22) working or a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of effort to stay focused. Both were quite tiring and unsustainable in the long run. I guess the lesson here is that when it comes to focused work, the 8-hour working day is an unattainable target and should not be used as a benchmark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also do a lot of admin - nearly half of all the time I spend on culture. This is fairly sad and a potential action point for the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://samplesize.one/img/culture.png&quot; alt=&quot;A calendar showing how much time I spent on different subcategories within culture&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent a fair amount of time reading books - nearly 1.5h per day on average! I'm quite happy with this since this is a habit I consciously worked to develop this year. During this time, I have read 35 books (12,715 pages according to Goodreads&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://samplesize.one/blog/posts/my_year_in_data/#fn1&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; ). If you want some recommendations, my top three would be: A Gentleman in Moscow, The Places in Between, and Little Fires Everywhere. On the other hand, I can't really find films or TV shows that I would really get into, so if you have any that you love, let me know! Also a bonus: the 'documentaries' are really just Louis Theroux and I don't regret a single minute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://samplesize.one/img/Quality.png&quot; alt=&quot;A calendar showing how much time I spent on different subcategories within quality time&quot; title=&quot;Other quality time subcategories&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;How did the time spent on different activities change over the months?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://samplesize.one/img/hrs_per_month_timeline.png&quot; alt=&quot;A stacked plot showing how the average daily hours spent on different activities changed throughout the months&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As above, the hours sum to more than 24 because of logging two activities in a single time slot if I was doing them simultaneously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can quite clearly identify the 'hard lockdown' times - April+May and November. In both periods, there is a noticeable increase in working hours, reduction in socialising and increase in culture. In the spring I was finishing my Master's thesis and revising for my exams so I would expect the increase in productivity regardless of lockdown. However, seeing the same pattern in November (when we were discouraged from coming to office) seems to suggests that I am actually working more when working from home. This is probably due to both fewer distractions but also to the lack of alternatives. Normally, I would often stop working to meet friends. During the lockdown, when this is not an option, I often just continue working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would love to talk about all the other categories, but the post is getting quite lengthy so you can explore them here (another bonus: look for my binge of playing Zoo Planet):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Hacking my monkey brain to increase productivity&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I was analysing at my data throughout the year, I was quite disappointed in how little I worked and was looking for a way to increase it. Inspired by &lt;a href=&quot;https://putanumonit.com/2017/05/09/time-well-spent/&quot;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt; I decided to gamify my productivity by giving myself points for activities I wanted to do more of. I was hoping that they would act as sources of instantenous pleasure for my monkey brain (which wants fun &lt;em&gt;now&lt;/em&gt; and doesn't really care about future me) to make it do things that might be less fun but beneficial in the long run. Given that I already had data on my activities throughout the day, assigning points was pretty straightforward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would get:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;4 points per hour for the most productive activities (focused work towards uni &amp;amp; self-improvement and exercising)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 points for reading books&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 points for reading blogs, listening to podcasts, lower intensity work etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0 points for things that are important but I do them anyway (socialising, sleep etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;-4 points for procrastination&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;And here are my points for this year:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://samplesize.one/img/points.png&quot; alt=&quot;A calendar with days coloured according to the amounts of points I got on a given day&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and their distributions throughout the months:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://samplesize.one/img/points_per_month.png&quot; alt=&quot;A plot of the distributions of points throughout the months&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turns out my monkey brain is &lt;strong&gt;crazy&lt;/strong&gt; about points. The moment I started, every day became an exercise in optimisation. You can see that from April, nearly all months have higher averages and fewer days with very low scores than January, February and March.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is already pretty cool, but the most important outcome of introducing these points is that I stopped thinking about productivity in binary terms. Before the points, whenever I was too tired to do work, my thinking process would go like this: &quot;Since I'm not doing work (bad), I might as well scroll some social media (also bad)&quot;, while after the points this became &quot;Alright, I am too tired to do work (not gaining 4 points) but maybe I can read a book (3 points) or go for a walk and listen to a podcast (3 points) instead&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, there are some caveats. Remember how I was unconvinced about the very low procrastination times? Since I started scoring myself, my monkey brain had a high incentive to find ways around logging in procrastination. I have frequently caught myself making sure that I only spend 5 or 6 minutes on Facebook so that I didn't reach the threshold of 7 minutes for logging in an activity in my spreadsheet. Sadly, I don't have any other source of data on how much time I was spending on social media to verify the accuracy of my tracking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another important consideration is that 'hours spent on' is not a great measure of productivity - I want to achieve things and not just spend time doing busywork. To make sure that this is the case, I do weekly summaries, where I compare what I wanted to accomplish vs what I actually did accomplish in the past week and plan for the upcoming week. However, for many activities, the points work well enough (a longer walk is more beneficial than shorter walk). And as for working, there is still some merit in making sure I do at least x hours of work per day - if I manage to accomplish something after 4 hours, I can still read a paper or do some less focused work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Final thoughts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Lessons learned&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Logging a full year of activities is apparently possible?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I work less than I thought I did and that's ok&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I'm much more productive when working from home&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Giving myself points for activities is an incredible life hack. Turns out that getting some non-existent tokens is enough of an incentive for me now to do things that me from the future wants done. I want to experiment with this a bit more (what happens if I give myself points for spending time with people? or for going on walks?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Should you also track your time?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;... I don't know? Do you want to? Personally, I found it fun and rewarding but you might not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Coming soon&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I. Have. So. Much. Data. (over 35k data points) This post barely scratched the surface. Stay tuned to learn how do different activities influence my mood, how important was spending time with people, whether lockdowns made me less unhappy and much more!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Bonus plot&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://samplesize.one/img/alcohol.png&quot; alt=&quot;A calendar with days coloured depending on whether I did or didn't drink alcohol on a given day&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Resources:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grab the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1XBUFCJGVL73kFvD0yO5e63fLfRuebemcqhnQoafXad4/edit?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;template&lt;/a&gt; I used to log my data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Footnotes:&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 17:04:02 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>HuangYuSan</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://samplesize.one/blog/posts/my_year_in_data/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>ECC matters</title>
<link>https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;curpostid=198647</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;curpostid=198647</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;entry-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;rwtforum-post&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;rwtforum-post-by&quot;&gt;By: &lt;span class=&quot;rwtforum-post-by-user&quot;&gt;Linus Torvalds&lt;/span&gt; (torvalds.delete@this.linux-foundation.org), January 2, 2021 12:21 pm
&lt;div class=&quot;rwtforum-post-room&quot;&gt;Room: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?roomid=1&quot;&gt;Moderated Discussions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;rwtforum-post-body&quot;&gt;Jukka Larja (roskakori2006.delete@this.gmail.com) on January 1, 2021 10:28 pm wrote:&lt;br/&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;&amp;gt; So yeah, I do very much agree AMD has superior offering. ECC doesn't really matter here though.&lt;p&gt;ECC absolutely matters.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;ECC availability matters a lot - exactly because Intel has been instrumental in killing the whole ECC industry with it's horribly bad market segmentation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Go out and search for ECC DIMMs - it's really hard to find. Yes - probably entirely thanks to AMD - it may have been gotten slightly better lately, but that's exactly my point.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Intel has been detrimental to the whole industry and to users because of their bad and misguided policies wrt ECC. Seriously.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And if you don't believe me, then just look at multiple &lt;em&gt;generations&lt;/em&gt; of rowhammer, where each time Intel and memory manufacturers bleated about how it's going to be fixed next time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Narrator: &quot;No it wasn't&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And yes, that was - again - entirely about the misguided and arse-backwards policy of &quot;consumers don't need ECC&quot;, which made the market for ECC memory go away.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The arguments against ECC were always complete and utter garbage. Now even the memory manufacturers are starting do do ECC internally because they finally owned up to the fact that they absolutely &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; to.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And the memory manufacturers claim it's because of economics and lower power. And they are lying bastards - let me once again point to row-hammer about how those problems have existed for several generations already, but these f*ckers happily sold broken hardware to consumers and claimed it was an &quot;attack&quot;, when it always was &quot;we're cutting corners&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;How many times has a row-hammer like bit-flip happened just by pure bad luck on real non-attack loads? We will never know. Because Intel was pushing shit to consumers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And I absolutely &lt;em&gt;guarantee&lt;/em&gt; they happened. The &quot;modern DRAM is so reliable that it doesn't need ECC&quot; was always a bedtime story for children that had been dropped on their heads a bit too many times.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We have decades of odd random kernel oopses that could never be explained and were likely due to bad memory. And if it causes a kernel oops, I can guarantee that there are several orders of magnitude more cases where it just caused a bit-flip that just never ended up being so critical.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yes, I'm pissed off about it. You can find me complaining about this literally for decades now. I don't want to say &quot;I was right&quot;. I want this &lt;em&gt;fixed&lt;/em&gt;, and I want ECC.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And AMD did it. Intel didn't.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; I don't really see AMD's unofficial ECC support being a big deal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I disagree. The difference between &quot;the market for working memory actually exists&quot; and &quot;screw consumers over by selling them subtly unreliable hardware&quot; is an absolutely enormous one.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And the fact that it's &quot;unofficial&quot; for AMD doesn't matter. It works. And it allows the markets to - admittedly probably very slowly - start fixing themselves.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But I blame Intel, because they were the big fish in the pond, and they were the ones that caused the ECC market to basically implode over a couple of decades.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;ECC DRAM (or just parity) used to be standard and easily accessible back when. ECC and parity isn't a new thing. It was literally killed by bad Intel policies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And don't let people tell you that DRAM got so reliable that it wasn't needed. That was never ever really true. See above.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Linus&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;rwtforum-post-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th class=&quot;rwtforum-header-topic&quot;&gt;Topic&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class=&quot;rwtforum-header-user&quot;&gt;Posted By&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class=&quot;rwtforum-header-tstamp&quot;&gt;Date&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198497&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198497&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198497&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198497&quot;&gt;Ryzen 9 5000 series processor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Phil995511&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2020/12/29 05:12 AM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198498&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198498&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;  &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198498&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198498&quot;&gt;Ryzen 9 5000 series processor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Adrian&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2020/12/29 07:31 AM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198503&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198503&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;    &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198503&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198503&quot;&gt;Ryzen 9 5000 series processor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Dummond D. Slow&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2020/12/29 10:33 AM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198509&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198509&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;      &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198509&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198509&quot;&gt;Ryzen 9 5000 series processor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Phil995511&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2020/12/29 04:09 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198513&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198513&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;        &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198513&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198513&quot;&gt;Ryzen 9 5000 series processor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Dummond D. Slow&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2020/12/29 06:00 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198517&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198517&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;          &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198517&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198517&quot;&gt;Ryzen 9 5000 series processor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;anon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2020/12/30 02:50 AM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198518&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198518&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;          &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198518&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198518&quot;&gt;Ryzen 9 5000 series processor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Foo_&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2020/12/30 02:50 AM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198522&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198522&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;            &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198522&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198522&quot;&gt;Ryzen 9 5000 series processor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Phil995511&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2020/12/30 05:22 AM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198523&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198523&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;              &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198523&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198523&quot;&gt;Ryzen 9 5000 series processor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Phil995511&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2020/12/30 05:25 AM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198525&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198525&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;              &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198525&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198525&quot;&gt;Ryzen 9 5000 series processor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Adrian&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2020/12/30 06:00 AM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198530&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198530&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;            &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198530&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198530&quot;&gt;Ryzen 9 5000 series processor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Linus Torvalds&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2020/12/30 12:00 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198531&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198531&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;              &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198531&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198531&quot;&gt;Ryzen 9 5000 series processor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Phil995511&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2020/12/31 06:45 AM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198533&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198533&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;                &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198533&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198533&quot;&gt;Ryzen 9 5000 series processor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Adrian&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2020/12/31 09:49 AM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198534&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198534&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;                &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198534&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198534&quot;&gt;Ryzen 9 5000 series processor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Linus Torvalds&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2020/12/31 12:05 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198536&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198536&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;                  &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198536&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198536&quot;&gt;Ryzen 9 5000 series processor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;me&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2020/12/31 04:56 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198537&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198537&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;                    &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198537&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198537&quot;&gt;Ryzen 9 5000 series processor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Anon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2020/12/31 05:48 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198545&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198545&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;                      &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198545&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198545&quot;&gt;Ryzen 9 5000 series processor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;me&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2021/01/01 04:06 AM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198549&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198549&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;                    &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198549&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198549&quot;&gt;Ryzen 9 5000 series processor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Gabriele Svelto&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2021/01/01 07:10 AM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198550&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198550&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;                      &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198550&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198550&quot;&gt;Ryzen 9 5000 series processor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;David Hess&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2021/01/01 07:37 AM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198557&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198557&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;                        &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198557&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198557&quot;&gt;Ryzen 9 5000 series processor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jukka Larja&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2021/01/01 10:52 AM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198568&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198568&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;                          &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198568&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198568&quot;&gt;Ryzen 9 5000 series processor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Linus Torvalds&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2021/01/01 12:48 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198600&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198600&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;                            &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198600&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198600&quot;&gt;Ryzen 9 5000 series processor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jukka Larja&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2021/01/01 10:28 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198647&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198647&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;                              &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198647&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198647&quot;&gt;Ryzen 9 5000 series processor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Linus Torvalds&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2021/01/02 12:21 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198653&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198653&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;                                &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198653&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198653&quot;&gt;Ryzen 9 5000 series processor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Adrian&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2021/01/02 01:17 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198663&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198663&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-highlight-topic rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;                                &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198663&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198663&quot;&gt;Ryzen 9 5000 series processor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-highlight-user&quot;&gt;Anon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-highlight-tstamp&quot;&gt;2021/01/02 06:08 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198670&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198670&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-highlight-topic rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;                                &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198670&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198670&quot;&gt;Ryzen 9 5000 series processor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-highlight-user&quot;&gt;Jukka Larja&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-highlight-tstamp&quot;&gt;2021/01/02 11:10 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198677&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198677&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-highlight-topic rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;                                  &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198677&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198677&quot;&gt;Ryzen 9 5000 series processor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-highlight-user&quot;&gt;David Hess&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-highlight-tstamp&quot;&gt;2021/01/03 01:03 AM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198683&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198683&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-highlight-topic rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;                                    &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198683&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198683&quot;&gt;Ryzen 9 5000 series processor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-highlight-user&quot;&gt;Jukka Larja&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-highlight-tstamp&quot;&gt;2021/01/03 03:28 AM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198705&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198705&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-highlight-topic rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;                                &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198705&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198705&quot;&gt;ECC (or lack of)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-highlight-user&quot;&gt;Tim McCaffrey&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-highlight-tstamp&quot;&gt;2021/01/03 09:28 AM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198730&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198730&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-highlight-topic rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;                                  &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198730&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198730&quot;&gt;ECC (or lack of)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-highlight-user&quot;&gt;Adrian&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-highlight-tstamp&quot;&gt;2021/01/03 01:14 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198734&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198734&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-highlight-topic rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;                                    &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198734&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198734&quot;&gt;ECC (or lack of)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-highlight-user&quot;&gt;Yuhong Bao&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-highlight-tstamp&quot;&gt;2021/01/03 01:51 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198715&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198715&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-highlight-topic rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;                                &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198715&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198715&quot;&gt;AMD ECC not enabled but says it is&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-highlight-user&quot;&gt;Ian Cutress&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-highlight-tstamp&quot;&gt;2021/01/03 11:09 AM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198724&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198724&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-highlight-topic rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;                                  &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198724&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198724&quot;&gt;AMD ECC not enabled but says it is&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-highlight-user&quot;&gt;Maxwell&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-highlight-tstamp&quot;&gt;2021/01/03 12:28 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198726&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198726&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-highlight-topic rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;                                  &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198726&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198726&quot;&gt;AMD ECC not enabled but says it is&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-highlight-user&quot;&gt;Adrian&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-highlight-tstamp&quot;&gt;2021/01/03 12:50 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198728&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198728&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-highlight-topic rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;                                    &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198728&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198728&quot;&gt;AMD ECC not enabled but says it is&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-highlight-user&quot;&gt;Gabriele Svelto&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-highlight-tstamp&quot;&gt;2021/01/03 01:08 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198733&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198733&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-highlight-topic rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;                                      &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198733&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198733&quot;&gt;AMD ECC not enabled but says it is&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-highlight-user&quot;&gt;Adrian&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-highlight-tstamp&quot;&gt;2021/01/03 01:34 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198556&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198556&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;                      &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198556&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198556&quot;&gt;Ryzen 9 5000 series processor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jukka Larja&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2021/01/01 10:43 AM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198567&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198567&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;                        &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198567&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198567&quot;&gt;Ryzen 9 5000 series processor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;David Hess&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2021/01/01 12:31 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198570&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198570&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;                          &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198570&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198570&quot;&gt;Ryzen 9 5000 series processor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Dan Strother&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2021/01/01 01:12 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198571&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198571&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;                        &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198571&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198571&quot;&gt;Ryzen 9 5000 series processor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Adrian&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2021/01/01 01:28 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198608&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198608&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;                          &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198608&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198608&quot;&gt;Ryzen 9 5000 series processor vs. M1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Adrian&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2021/01/02 02:45 AM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198651&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198651&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;                            &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198651&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198651&quot;&gt;Ryzen 9 5000 series processor vs. M1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Dummond D. Slow&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2021/01/02 12:50 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198654&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198654&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;                              &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198654&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198654&quot;&gt;Ryzen 9 5000 series processor vs. M1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Adrian&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2021/01/02 02:00 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198586&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198586&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;                        &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198586&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198586&quot;&gt;Ryzen 9 5000 series processor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Gabriele Svelto&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2021/01/01 03:31 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198599&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198599&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;                          &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198599&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198599&quot;&gt;Ryzen 9 5000 series processor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jukka Larja&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2021/01/01 09:58 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198612&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198612&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;                            &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198612&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198612&quot;&gt;Ryzen 9 5000 series processor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Gabriele Svelto&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2021/01/02 05:51 AM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198627&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198627&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;                              &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198627&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198627&quot;&gt;Ryzen 9 5000 series processor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jukka Larja&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2021/01/02 07:57 AM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198657&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198657&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;                                &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198657&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198657&quot;&gt;Ryzen 9 5000 series processor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;me&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2021/01/02 04:30 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198666&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198666&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-highlight-topic rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;                                  &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198666&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198666&quot;&gt;Ryzen 9 5000 series processor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-highlight-user&quot;&gt;Jukka Larja&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-highlight-tstamp&quot;&gt;2021/01/02 10:43 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198597&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198597&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;                        &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198597&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198597&quot;&gt;Ryzen 9 5000 series processor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Björn Ragnar Björnsson&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2021/01/01 08:41 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198598&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198598&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;                          &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198598&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198598&quot;&gt;Ryzen 9 5000 series processor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jukka Larja&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2021/01/01 09:53 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198604&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198604&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;                            &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198604&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198604&quot;&gt;Ryzen 9 5000 series processor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Adrian&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2021/01/02 01:03 AM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198624&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198624&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;                              &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198624&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198624&quot;&gt;Ryzen 9 5000 series processor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jukka Larja&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2021/01/02 07:39 AM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198602&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198602&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;                          &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198602&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198602&quot;&gt;Ryzen 9 5000 series processor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Adrian&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2021/01/02 12:52 AM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198613&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198613&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;                          &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198613&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198613&quot;&gt;Ryzen 9 5000 series processor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;me&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2021/01/02 05:56 AM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198646&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198646&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;                            &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198646&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198646&quot;&gt;Ryzen 9 5000 series processor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Michael S&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2021/01/02 11:41 AM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198649&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198649&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;                              &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198649&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198649&quot;&gt;Ryzen 9 5000 series processor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Adrian&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2021/01/02 12:43 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198667&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198667&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-highlight-topic rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;                              &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198667&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198667&quot;&gt;Ryzen 9 5000 series processor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-highlight-user&quot;&gt;Jukka Larja&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-highlight-tstamp&quot;&gt;2021/01/02 10:50 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198615&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198615&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;                          &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198615&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198615&quot;&gt;Crucial/Micron ECC UDIMMs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Gabriele Svelto&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2021/01/02 06:09 AM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198635&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198635&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;                            &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198635&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198635&quot;&gt;Crucial/Micron ECC UDIMMs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Maxwell&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2021/01/02 09:45 AM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198664&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198664&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-highlight-topic rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;                              &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198664&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198664&quot;&gt;Crucial/Micron ECC UDIMMs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-highlight-user&quot;&gt;Yuhong Bao&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-highlight-tstamp&quot;&gt;2021/01/02 06:29 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198696&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198696&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-highlight-topic rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;                  &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198696&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198696&quot;&gt;Ryzen 9 5000 series processor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-highlight-user&quot;&gt;Phil995511&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-highlight-tstamp&quot;&gt;2021/01/03 07:46 AM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr trbold=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;post_row_198719&quot; data-post-id=&quot;198719&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-highlight-topic rwtforum-thread-title&quot;&gt;  &lt;a id=&quot;post_link_198719&quot; href=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198719&quot;&gt;Ryzen 9 5000 series processor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-highlight-user&quot;&gt;H_Heckuba&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-thread-highlight-tstamp&quot;&gt;2021/01/03 12:06 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;form method=&quot;post&quot; onsubmit=&quot;return validateInputs();&quot; action=&quot;https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;amp;curpostid=198647&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;rwtforum-reply-post&quot;&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rwtforum-reply-post-table&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;Reply to this Topic&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;post-tr-1&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-userheader rwtforum-left&quot;&gt;Name:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;input id=&quot;postuser&quot; class=&quot;regular-text&quot; type=&quot;text&quot; name=&quot;postuser&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;post-tr-2&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-emailbody rwtforum-left&quot;&gt;Email:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;input id=&quot;postemail&quot; class=&quot;regular-text&quot; type=&quot;text&quot; name=&quot;postemail&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum_replyheader rwtforum-left&quot;&gt;Topic:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;input id=&quot;posttitle&quot; class=&quot;regular-text&quot; type=&quot;text&quot; maxlength=&quot;100&quot; name=&quot;posttitle&quot; value=&quot;Ryzen 9 5000 series processor &quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-replybody rwtforum-left&quot;&gt;Body:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; name=&quot;notext&quot; id=&quot;notext&quot; value=&quot;1&quot; onchange=&quot;javascript:changeNoText ();&quot;/&gt;No Text&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;wp-postbody-wrap&quot; class=&quot;wp-core-ui wp-editor-wrap html-active&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;wp-postbody-editor-container&quot; class=&quot;wp-editor-container&quot;&gt;

&lt;textarea class=&quot;wp-editor-area&quot; rows=&quot;20&quot; cols=&quot;40&quot; name=&quot;postbody&quot; id=&quot;postbody&quot;&gt;
Linus Torvalds (torvalds.delete@this.linux-foundation.org) on January 2, 2021 12:21 pm wrote:
&amp;gt; Jukka Larja (roskakori2006.delete@this.gmail.com) on January 1, 2021 10:28 pm wrote:
&amp;gt; &amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; &amp;gt; So yeah, I do very much agree AMD has superior offering. ECC doesn't really matter here though.
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; ECC absolutely matters.
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; ECC availability matters a lot - exactly because Intel has been instrumental in 
&amp;gt; killing the whole ECC industry with it's horribly bad market segmentation.
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; Go out and search for ECC DIMMs - it's really hard to find. Yes - probably entirely thanks 
&amp;gt; to AMD - it may have been gotten slightly better lately, but that's exactly my point.
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; Intel has been detrimental to the whole industry and to users because 
&amp;gt; of their bad and misguided policies wrt ECC. Seriously.
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; And if you don't believe me, then just look at multiple generations of rowhammer, where each 
&amp;gt; time Intel and memory manufacturers bleated about how it's going to be fixed next time.
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; Narrator: &quot;No it wasn't&quot;.
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; And yes, that was - again - entirely about the misguided and arse-backwards policy 
&amp;gt; of &quot;consumers don't need ECC&quot;, which made the market for ECC memory go away.
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; The arguments against ECC were always complete and utter garbage. Now even the memory manufacturers are 
&amp;gt; starting do do ECC internally because they finally owned up to the fact that they absolutely have to.
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; And the memory manufacturers claim it's because of economics and lower power. And they are 
&amp;gt; lying bastards - let me once again point to row-hammer about how those problems have existed 
&amp;gt; for several generations already, but these f*ckers happily sold broken hardware to consumers 
&amp;gt; and claimed it was an &quot;attack&quot;, when it always was &quot;we're cutting corners&quot;.
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; How many times has a row-hammer like bit-flip happened just by pure bad luck on real 
&amp;gt; non-attack loads? We will never know.  Because Intel was pushing shit to consumers.
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; And I absolutely guarantee they happened. The &quot;modern DRAM is so reliable that it doesn't need ECC&quot; 
&amp;gt; was always a bedtime story for children that had been dropped on their heads a bit too many times.
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; We have decades of odd random kernel oopses that could never be explained and were likely due to 
&amp;gt; bad memory. And if it causes a kernel oops, I can guarantee that there are several orders of magnitude 
&amp;gt; more cases where it just caused a bit-flip that just never ended up being so critical.
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; Yes, I'm pissed off about it. You can find me complaining about this literally for decades 
&amp;gt; now. I don't want to say &quot;I was right&quot;. I want this fixed, and I want ECC.
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; And AMD did it. Intel didn't.
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; &amp;gt; I don't really see AMD's unofficial ECC support being a big deal.
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; I disagree. The difference between &quot;the market for working memory actually exists&quot; and &quot;screw 
&amp;gt; consumers over by selling them subtly unreliable hardware&quot; is an absolutely enormous one.
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; And the fact that it's &quot;unofficial&quot; for AMD doesn't matter. It works. And it allows 
&amp;gt; the markets to - admittedly probably very slowly - start fixing themselves.
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; But I blame Intel, because they were the big fish in the pond, and they were the 
&amp;gt; ones that caused the ECC market to basically implode over a couple of decades.
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; ECC DRAM (or just parity) used to be standard and easily accessible back when. ECC 
&amp;gt; and parity isn't a new thing. It was literally killed by bad Intel policies.
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; And don't let people tell you that DRAM got so reliable that it 
&amp;gt; wasn't needed. That was never ever really true. See above.
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt;           Linus

&lt;/textarea&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-left&quot;&gt;How do you spell avocado?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;input id=&quot;postblue&quot; class=&quot;regular-text&quot; type=&quot;text&quot; name=&quot;postblue&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rwtforum-left&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;submit&quot; name=&quot;submit&quot; value=&quot;Post&quot;/&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;hidden&quot; name=&quot;preview&quot; id=&quot;preview&quot; value=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;  &lt;input type=&quot;submit&quot; name=&quot;submit1&quot; value=&quot;Preview&quot; onclick=&quot;return setPreview();&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;entry-content&quot;/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 15:38:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rajesh-s</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=198497&amp;curpostid=198647</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How to Stop Endless Discussions</title>
<link>https://candost.blog/how-to-stop-endless-discussions/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://candost.blog/how-to-stop-endless-discussions/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I often see people believe in their solution and think theirs are better than the others'. They defend their cases without having an exact reason. These situations often create long and meaningless discussions that go nowhere. Often they result in conflicts and people being offended by others' behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people take action and implement their idea. Act fast, fail fast, and learn quicker. But this doesn't work when two or more people discuss how to implement a change or use new hyped technology. When people only talk a bit and implement a new hype, it often ends up with resentment. When we act and embrace failing that fast, we cannot keep someone accountable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, some people try to get everyone's confirmation to implement something that affects a large group. This strategy doesn't work either. Because it's impossible to get everyone on the same page, because each person has a different opinion. When we try convincing everyone, we cannot implement anything at all. We just talk, and decisions come later than we need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's why we need to balance both taking action and asking people to present their opinion on a topic. This balance is achievable with an excellent process.&lt;br/&gt;I helped build this balanced process in an organization where we aimed to solve another problem - the lack of feedback. We introduced a process called &lt;strong&gt;Request For Comments (RFC).&lt;/strong&gt; It is a common feedback mechanism in the software world presented by the Internet Society (ISOC) and used currently in the Rust language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The RFC process uses a document written by someone about their proposal on a topic. It has &lt;strong&gt;a specific timeframe&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;everyone can give feedback&lt;/strong&gt; on it. The RFC and feedbacks are posted &lt;strong&gt;publicly&lt;/strong&gt;. Everyone can join the discussion. The goal is to include as many people as possible to access more points of view and spread the knowledge simultaneously. The good thing is that people focus on the proposed idea and give their feedback based on facts instead of only beliefs. On the other hand, it has a way bigger effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the initial goal of the RFC is collecting feedback, I think it achieves a way more significant benefit by only &lt;strong&gt;writing the document itself&lt;/strong&gt;. Writing shapes thoughts. Everyone has an opinion on any topic. But people who write their ideas form them into great content that is based on the facts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing helps to clear the mind. When we write on any topic, we separate our proposal from ourselves. It's still part of us. But since we plan to present it to the public and leave it there forever, we start being careful. And most of the time, we are not starting with blank white paper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The RFC processes use either a template or follow one standard style in documents. The aim is to help the authors to explain their plan in a structured way and, at the same time, make giving feedback easier. Each section of the document has its own goal, which helps separate the intent from the idea in a certain way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We used &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.stanford.edu/class/educ303x/wiki-old/uploads/Main/SRI_NABC.doc&quot;&gt;the NABC model from Stanford&lt;/a&gt;. The model starts with defining the &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;N&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;eed, followed by &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;pproach, &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;enefits, and lastly, &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;C&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;ompetitors. Separating the Need from the approach is very smart. While writing the need, the authors have to understand it very well. The approach and benefits sections are pretty straightforward, where authors define their strategy and list down the advantages. Since most people focus on them when they talk about ideas, it's also easy to write. Then the competition section comes. It is the part the authors have to consider competitors of their proposal. Thinking about an alternative solution instead of their suggestion requires people to focus on the problem instead of blindly loving and defending their solutions. With these four parts, the NABC is a pretty good model. But it's not the only one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone has different needs. Therefore the formats might differ. Our manager at work also came up with a way more straightforward structure with only four questions to answer. It was only for our team, while the engineering department had the RFC process for a wider audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The RFCs have another effect on the organization. The process seeks a &lt;strong&gt;consent-based&lt;/strong&gt; environment, &lt;strong&gt;not a consensus-based&lt;/strong&gt; one. If some people care about a topic a lot and come up with a written document that explains many things in detail, everyone can (and should) trust them. The authors shouldn't wait for everyone's confirmation of their proposal. When they get enough feedback, they should be able to continue further with or abandon the idea. It's their decision. Since they prepared the doc and collected many comments on it, they can have a better judgment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process brings &lt;strong&gt;accountability&lt;/strong&gt;, as well. Whoever writes the proposal should be kept accountable. When people know that they will be accountable, they tend to approach more carefully and consider different aspects seriously. Holding someone accountable doesn't mean that there will be a blame in case of failure. It only means that they have to follow up on their proposals, make sure it results in some way, and answer questions on the way. Also, most of the time, the RFC process is separated from the implementation process. While the author is accountable for the RFC itself, the implementation can be done by different people, and the RFC author might not be involved in it at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These hidden gems of writing the idea in a structured way and asking people for comments afterward prevents many endless debates. The culture changes with it as well. Instead of endless debates, we create discussions and solutions based on facts. The process prevents people from talking and doing nothing. Even though the RFC process might not be perfect itself, writing is enough to halt the endless and meaningless discussions. It also helps build trust in the community. So, if you are new to the RFC system, start with writing down your proposal. I'm pretty sure that the result will be way better than expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cover Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@30daysreplay&quot;&gt;30daysreplay Marketingberatung&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 15:07:38 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>candost</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>How to Stop Endless Discussions</og:title>
<og:description>When we find ourselves in endless debates where everyone defends their idea, we don't know how to handle the situation.</og:description>
<og:url>https://candost.blog/how-to-stop-endless-discussions/</og:url>
<og:image>https://candost.blog/content/images/2020/12/30daysreplay-marketingberatung-KpTZRPEpGC0-unsplash-1.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://candost.blog/how-to-stop-endless-discussions/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Great Suspender: New maintainer is probably malicious</title>
<link>https://github.com/greatsuspender/thegreatsuspender/issues/1263</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/greatsuspender/thegreatsuspender/issues/1263</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;meta charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;dns-prefetch&quot; href=&quot;https://github.githubassets.com&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;dns-prefetch&quot; href=&quot;https://avatars0.githubusercontent.com&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;dns-prefetch&quot; href=&quot;https://avatars1.githubusercontent.com&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;dns-prefetch&quot; href=&quot;https://avatars2.githubusercontent.com&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;dns-prefetch&quot; href=&quot;https://avatars3.githubusercontent.com&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;dns-prefetch&quot; href=&quot;https://github-cloud.s3.amazonaws.com&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;dns-prefetch&quot; href=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/&quot;/&gt;&lt;link crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; media=&quot;all&quot; integrity=&quot;sha512-BSy+E+S5PJuDWKcXiIXBoFJ7uJ+88y6hFdIhZpf7nf9MVNVvnJDPUaotaxFUQi8UXCLJOcGv1uifxVMc9o5DYQ==&quot; rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; href=&quot;https://github.githubassets.com/assets/frameworks-052cbe13e4b93c9b8358a7178885c1a0.css&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot;/&gt;&lt;link crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; media=&quot;all&quot; integrity=&quot;sha512-tuayzhY7bkBEq/qU4J930ofI//FEC8Na42y8grGUvaSDLLvJi8/hbKbZ7zxph9o0cZecDALcD+Ks9ppE9YmS5w==&quot; rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; href=&quot;https://github.githubassets.com/assets/site-b6e6b2ce163b6e4044abfa94e09f77d2.css&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot;/&gt;&lt;link crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; media=&quot;all&quot; integrity=&quot;sha512-zZEYWrT2WyrAqN2Nm29ttIz36AXxSxE+Mf4ARvtJCQrVVOFpnh0nRYu5fbAjtXXTRBDytc8BGLPA7sCsjvGQLw==&quot; rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; href=&quot;https://github.githubassets.com/assets/github-cd91185ab4f65b2ac0a8dd8d9b6f6db4.css&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;viewport&quot; content=&quot;width=device-width&quot;/&gt;&lt;title&gt;URGENT: SECURITY: New maintainer is probably malicious · Issue #1263 · greatsuspender/thegreatsuspender · GitHub&lt;/title&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;description&quot; content=&quot;It occurred to me that our current discussion of this is hard to find. It is happening in #1175, the issue about the new maintainer. To summarize, the maintainer recently updated their chrome store package. The update raised red flags fo...&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;search&quot; type=&quot;application/opensearchdescription+xml&quot; href=&quot;/opensearch.xml&quot; title=&quot;GitHub&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;fluid-icon&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/fluidicon.png&quot; title=&quot;GitHub&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;fb:app_id&quot; content=&quot;1401488693436528&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;apple-itunes-app&quot; content=&quot;app-id=1477376905&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:image:src&quot; content=&quot;https://avatars0.githubusercontent.com/u/11603828?s=400&amp;amp;v=4&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:site&quot; content=&quot;@github&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:card&quot; content=&quot;summary&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:title&quot; content=&quot;URGENT: SECURITY: New maintainer is probably malicious · Issue #1263 · greatsuspender/thegreatsuspender&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:description&quot; content=&quot;It occurred to me that our current discussion of this is hard to find. It is happening in #1175, the issue about the new maintainer. To summarize, the maintainer recently updated their chrome store...&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:image&quot; content=&quot;https://avatars0.githubusercontent.com/u/11603828?s=400&amp;amp;v=4&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:site_name&quot; content=&quot;GitHub&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:type&quot; content=&quot;object&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:title&quot; content=&quot;URGENT: SECURITY: New maintainer is probably malicious · Issue #1263 · greatsuspender/thegreatsuspender&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:url&quot; content=&quot;https://github.com/greatsuspender/thegreatsuspender/issues/1263&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:description&quot; content=&quot;It occurred to me that our current discussion of this is hard to find. It is happening in #1175, the issue about the new maintainer. To summarize, the maintainer recently updated their chrome store...&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;assets&quot; href=&quot;https://github.githubassets.com/&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;request-id&quot; content=&quot;A2BF:6BB1:6AE202F:A94DD11:5FF268E6&quot; data-pjax-transient=&quot;true&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;html-safe-nonce&quot; content=&quot;f9df166508a65ede9ae8ac7ed3451e65212fe850dfc29645653b590cfdeb8ca0&quot; data-pjax-transient=&quot;true&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;visitor-payload&quot; content=&quot;eyJyZWZlcnJlciI6Imh0dHA6Ly93d3cuZ29vZ2xlLmNvLnVrL3VybD9zYT10XHUwMDI2c291cmNlPXdlYlx1MDAyNmNkPTEiLCJyZXF1ZXN0X2lkIjoiQTJCRjo2QkIxOjZBRTIwMkY6QTk0REQxMTo1RkYyNjhFNiIsInZpc2l0b3JfaWQiOiIxNzc5MDE3MDQ1MzgzODQ2MTQiLCJyZWdpb25fZWRnZSI6ImlhZCIsInJlZ2lvbl9yZW5kZXIiOiJpYWQifQ==&quot; data-pjax-transient=&quot;true&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;visitor-hmac&quot; content=&quot;91046bfd7a2dd4231fa3e2cf844f4279e859ba5510d1946c58984e1ac40201e7&quot; data-pjax-transient=&quot;true&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;hovercard-subject-tag&quot; content=&quot;issue:735408387&quot; data-pjax-transient=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;github-keyboard-shortcuts&quot; content=&quot;repository,issues&quot; data-pjax-transient=&quot;true&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;selected-link&quot; value=&quot;repo_issues&quot; data-pjax-transient=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;google-site-verification&quot; content=&quot;c1kuD-K2HIVF635lypcsWPoD4kilo5-jA_wBFyT4uMY&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;google-site-verification&quot; content=&quot;KT5gs8h0wvaagLKAVWq8bbeNwnZZK1r1XQysX3xurLU&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;google-site-verification&quot; content=&quot;ZzhVyEFwb7w3e0-uOTltm8Jsck2F5StVihD0exw2fsA&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;google-site-verification&quot; content=&quot;GXs5KoUUkNCoaAZn7wPN-t01Pywp9M3sEjnt_3_ZWPc&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;octolytics-host&quot; content=&quot;collector.githubapp.com&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;octolytics-app-id&quot; content=&quot;github&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;octolytics-event-url&quot; content=&quot;https://collector.githubapp.com/github-external/browser_event&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;analytics-location&quot; content=&quot;/&amp;lt;user-name&amp;gt;/&amp;lt;repo-name&amp;gt;/issues/show&quot; data-pjax-transient=&quot;true&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;optimizely-datafile&quot; content=&quot;{&amp;quot;version&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;4&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;rollouts&amp;quot;: [], &amp;quot;typedAudiences&amp;quot;: [], &amp;quot;anonymizeIP&amp;quot;: true, &amp;quot;projectId&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;16737760170&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;variables&amp;quot;: [], &amp;quot;featureFlags&amp;quot;: [], &amp;quot;experiments&amp;quot;: [{&amp;quot;status&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;Running&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;audienceIds&amp;quot;: [], &amp;quot;variations&amp;quot;: [{&amp;quot;variables&amp;quot;: [], &amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;19512260014&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;key&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;separate_plans_and_usage&amp;quot;}, {&amp;quot;variables&amp;quot;: [], &amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;19509770036&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;key&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;control&amp;quot;}], &amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;19536000020&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;key&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;account_billing_plans_and_usage&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;layerId&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;19545220022&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;trafficAllocation&amp;quot;: [{&amp;quot;entityId&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;19509770036&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;endOfRange&amp;quot;: 2500}, {&amp;quot;entityId&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;endOfRange&amp;quot;: 5000}, {&amp;quot;entityId&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;19512260014&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;endOfRange&amp;quot;: 7500}, {&amp;quot;entityId&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;endOfRange&amp;quot;: 10000}], &amp;quot;forcedVariations&amp;quot;: {&amp;quot;1238720267648ea2c88a74b410aa3c5c&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;separate_plans_and_usage&amp;quot;}}], &amp;quot;audiences&amp;quot;: [{&amp;quot;conditions&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;[\&amp;quot;or\&amp;quot;, {\&amp;quot;match\&amp;quot;: \&amp;quot;exact\&amp;quot;, \&amp;quot;name\&amp;quot;: \&amp;quot;$opt_dummy_attribute\&amp;quot;, \&amp;quot;type\&amp;quot;: \&amp;quot;custom_attribute\&amp;quot;, \&amp;quot;value\&amp;quot;: \&amp;quot;$opt_dummy_value\&amp;quot;}]&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;$opt_dummy_audience&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;name&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;Optimizely-Generated Audience for Backwards Compatibility&amp;quot;}], &amp;quot;groups&amp;quot;: [], &amp;quot;attributes&amp;quot;: [{&amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;16822470375&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;key&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;user_id&amp;quot;}, {&amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;17143601254&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;key&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;spammy&amp;quot;}, {&amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;18175660309&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;key&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;organization_plan&amp;quot;}, {&amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;18813001570&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;key&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;is_logged_in&amp;quot;}, {&amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;19073851829&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;key&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;geo&amp;quot;}], &amp;quot;botFiltering&amp;quot;: false, &amp;quot;accountId&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;16737760170&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;events&amp;quot;: [{&amp;quot;experimentIds&amp;quot;: [], &amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;17911811441&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;key&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;hydro_click.dashboard.teacher_toolbox_cta&amp;quot;}, {&amp;quot;experimentIds&amp;quot;: [], &amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;18124116703&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;key&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;submit.organizations.complete_sign_up&amp;quot;}, {&amp;quot;experimentIds&amp;quot;: [], &amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;18145892387&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;key&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;no_metric.tracked_outside_of_optimizely&amp;quot;}, {&amp;quot;experimentIds&amp;quot;: [], &amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;18178755568&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;key&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;click.org_onboarding_checklist.add_repo&amp;quot;}, {&amp;quot;experimentIds&amp;quot;: [], &amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;18180553241&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;key&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;submit.repository_imports.create&amp;quot;}, {&amp;quot;experimentIds&amp;quot;: [], &amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;18186103728&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;key&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;click.help.learn_more_about_repository_creation&amp;quot;}, {&amp;quot;experimentIds&amp;quot;: [], &amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;18188530140&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;key&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;test_event.do_not_use_in_production&amp;quot;}, {&amp;quot;experimentIds&amp;quot;: [], &amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;18191963644&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;key&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;click.empty_org_repo_cta.transfer_repository&amp;quot;}, {&amp;quot;experimentIds&amp;quot;: [], &amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;18195612788&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;key&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;click.empty_org_repo_cta.import_repository&amp;quot;}, {&amp;quot;experimentIds&amp;quot;: [], &amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;18210945499&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;key&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;click.org_onboarding_checklist.invite_members&amp;quot;}, {&amp;quot;experimentIds&amp;quot;: [], &amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;18211063248&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;key&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;click.empty_org_repo_cta.create_repository&amp;quot;}, {&amp;quot;experimentIds&amp;quot;: [], &amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;18215721889&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;key&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;click.org_onboarding_checklist.update_profile&amp;quot;}, {&amp;quot;experimentIds&amp;quot;: [], &amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;18224360785&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;key&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;click.org_onboarding_checklist.dismiss&amp;quot;}, {&amp;quot;experimentIds&amp;quot;: [], &amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;18234832286&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;key&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;submit.organization_activation.complete&amp;quot;}, {&amp;quot;experimentIds&amp;quot;: [], &amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;18252392383&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;key&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;submit.org_repository.create&amp;quot;}, {&amp;quot;experimentIds&amp;quot;: [], &amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;18257551537&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;key&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;submit.org_member_invitation.create&amp;quot;}, {&amp;quot;experimentIds&amp;quot;: [], &amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;18259522260&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;key&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;submit.organization_profile.update&amp;quot;}, {&amp;quot;experimentIds&amp;quot;: [], &amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;18564603625&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;key&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;view.classroom_select_organization&amp;quot;}, {&amp;quot;experimentIds&amp;quot;: [], &amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;18568612016&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;key&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;click.classroom_sign_in_click&amp;quot;}, {&amp;quot;experimentIds&amp;quot;: [], &amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;18572592540&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;key&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;view.classroom_name&amp;quot;}, {&amp;quot;experimentIds&amp;quot;: [], &amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;18574203855&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;key&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;click.classroom_create_organization&amp;quot;}, {&amp;quot;experimentIds&amp;quot;: [], &amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;18582053415&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;key&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;click.classroom_select_organization&amp;quot;}, {&amp;quot;experimentIds&amp;quot;: [], &amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;18589463420&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;key&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;click.classroom_create_classroom&amp;quot;}, {&amp;quot;experimentIds&amp;quot;: [], &amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;18591323364&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;key&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;click.classroom_create_first_classroom&amp;quot;}, {&amp;quot;experimentIds&amp;quot;: [], &amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;18591652321&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;key&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;click.classroom_grant_access&amp;quot;}, {&amp;quot;experimentIds&amp;quot;: [], &amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;18607131425&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;key&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;view.classroom_creation&amp;quot;}, {&amp;quot;experimentIds&amp;quot;: [], &amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;18831680583&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;key&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;upgrade_account_plan&amp;quot;}, {&amp;quot;experimentIds&amp;quot;: [], &amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;19064064515&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;key&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;click.signup&amp;quot;}, {&amp;quot;experimentIds&amp;quot;: [], &amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;19075373687&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;key&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;click.view_account_billing_page&amp;quot;}, {&amp;quot;experimentIds&amp;quot;: [], &amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;19077355841&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;key&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;click.dismiss_signup_prompt&amp;quot;}, {&amp;quot;experimentIds&amp;quot;: [], &amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;19079713938&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;key&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;click.contact_sales&amp;quot;}, {&amp;quot;experimentIds&amp;quot;: [&amp;quot;19536000020&amp;quot;], &amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;19120963070&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;key&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;click.compare_account_plans&amp;quot;}, {&amp;quot;experimentIds&amp;quot;: [&amp;quot;19536000020&amp;quot;], &amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;19151690317&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;key&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;click.upgrade_account_cta&amp;quot;}, {&amp;quot;experimentIds&amp;quot;: [], &amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;19424193129&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;key&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;click.open_account_switcher&amp;quot;}, {&amp;quot;experimentIds&amp;quot;: [], &amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;19520330825&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;key&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;click.visit_account_profile&amp;quot;}, {&amp;quot;experimentIds&amp;quot;: [], &amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;19540970635&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;key&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;click.switch_account_context&amp;quot;}], &amp;quot;revision&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;380&amp;quot;}&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;hostname&quot; content=&quot;github.com&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;user-login&quot; content=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;expected-hostname&quot; content=&quot;github.com&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;enabled-features&quot; content=&quot;MARKETPLACE_PENDING_INSTALLATIONS,ACTIONS_ENVIRONMENTS,ACTIONS_ENVIRONMENTS&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;x-pjax-version&quot; content=&quot;b702340b647a683f5cc84dcf3cb6927f9b5ea2d77a8654b9f9d4822ec9543628&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;go-import&quot; content=&quot;github.com/greatsuspender/thegreatsuspender git https://github.com/greatsuspender/thegreatsuspender.git&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;octolytics-dimension-user_id&quot; content=&quot;11603828&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;octolytics-dimension-user_login&quot; content=&quot;greatsuspender&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;octolytics-dimension-repository_id&quot; content=&quot;5773100&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;octolytics-dimension-repository_nwo&quot; content=&quot;greatsuspender/thegreatsuspender&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;octolytics-dimension-repository_public&quot; content=&quot;true&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;octolytics-dimension-repository_is_fork&quot; content=&quot;false&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;octolytics-dimension-repository_network_root_id&quot; content=&quot;5773100&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;octolytics-dimension-repository_network_root_nwo&quot; content=&quot;greatsuspender/thegreatsuspender&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;octolytics-dimension-repository_explore_github_marketplace_ci_cta_shown&quot; content=&quot;false&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;browser-stats-url&quot; content=&quot;https://api.github.com/_private/browser/stats&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;browser-errors-url&quot; content=&quot;https://api.github.com/_private/browser/errors&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;browser-optimizely-client-errors-url&quot; content=&quot;https://api.github.com/_private/browser/optimizely_client/errors&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;mask-icon&quot; href=&quot;https://github.githubassets.com/pinned-octocat.svg&quot; color=&quot;#000000&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;alternate icon&quot; class=&quot;js-site-favicon&quot; type=&quot;image/png&quot; href=&quot;https://github.githubassets.com/favicons/favicon.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;icon&quot; class=&quot;js-site-favicon&quot; type=&quot;image/svg+xml&quot; href=&quot;https://github.githubassets.com/favicons/favicon.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;theme-color&quot; content=&quot;#1e2327&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;color-scheme&quot; content=&quot;light dark&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;manifest&quot; href=&quot;/manifest.json&quot; crossorigin=&quot;use-credentials&quot;/&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body class=&quot;logged-out env-production page-responsive&quot; id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;16.45159172957&quot;&gt;


&lt;div data-pjax-replace=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;js-flash-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;flash flash-full {{ className }}&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot; px-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;{{ message }}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;application-main&quot; data-commit-hovercards-enabled=&quot;&quot; data-discussion-hovercards-enabled=&quot;&quot; data-issue-and-pr-hovercards-enabled=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/SoftwareSourceCode&quot; class=&quot;&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;container-xl clearfix new-discussion-timeline px-3 px-md-4 px-lg-5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;repository-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;js-check-all-container&quot; data-pjax=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;show_issue&quot; class=&quot;js-issues-results js-socket-channel js-updatable-content&quot; data-channel=&quot;eyJjIjoiaXNzdWU6NzM1NDA4Mzg3OnRpbWVsaW5lIiwidCI6MTYwOTcyMjA4N30=--4637894cd699614d0aea7d46c5a7d0c83b1166b9d70f96ffb7a9b809b050656b&quot;&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;sr-only&quot;&gt;Comments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;discussion_bucket&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gutter-condensed gutter-lg flex-column flex-md-row d-flex&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;flex-shrink-0 col-12 col-md-9 mb-4 mb-md-0&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;js-quote-selection-container&quot; data-quote-markdown=&quot;.js-comment-body&quot; data-discussion-hovercards-enabled=&quot;&quot; data-issue-and-pr-hovercards-enabled=&quot;&quot; data-team-hovercards-enabled=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;js-discussion ml-0 pl-0 ml-md-6 pl-md-3&quot;&gt;

&lt;div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;js-timeline-item js-timeline-progressive-focus-container&quot; data-gid=&quot;MDIwOkNyb3NzUmVmZXJlbmNlZEV2ZW50MTA1NTA2NTM2MQ==&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;TimelineItem&quot; readability=&quot;0.70227457351747&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;TimelineItem-body&quot; readability=&quot;3.5653939886271&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was referenced Nov 4, 2020&lt;/p&gt;

















&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;










&lt;div class=&quot;js-timeline-item js-timeline-progressive-focus-container&quot; data-gid=&quot;MDE3OlJlbmFtZWRUaXRsZUV2ZW50Mzk2OTU1NTk5OQ==&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;TimelineItem js-targetable-element&quot; data-team-hovercards-enabled=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;event-3969555999&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;TimelineItem-body&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;d-inline-block&quot; data-hovercard-type=&quot;user&quot; data-hovercard-url=&quot;/users/TheMageKing/hovercard&quot; data-octo-click=&quot;hovercard-link-click&quot; data-octo-dimensions=&quot;link_type:self&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/TheMageKing&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;avatar avatar-user&quot; height=&quot;20&quot; width=&quot;20&quot; alt=&quot;@TheMageKing&quot; src=&quot;https://avatars1.githubusercontent.com/u/13556193?s=60&amp;amp;v=4&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;author link-gray-dark text-bold&quot; data-hovercard-type=&quot;user&quot; data-hovercard-url=&quot;/users/TheMageKing/hovercard&quot; data-octo-click=&quot;hovercard-link-click&quot; data-octo-dimensions=&quot;link_type:self&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/TheMageKing&quot;&gt;TheMageKing&lt;/a&gt; changed the title &lt;del class=&quot;text-bold&quot;&gt;SECURITY: New maintainer appears malicious&lt;/del&gt; &lt;ins class=&quot;text-bold no-underline&quot;&gt;SECURITY: New maintainer is probably malicious&lt;/ins&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/greatsuspender/thegreatsuspender/issues/1263#event-3969555999&quot; class=&quot;link-gray&quot;&gt;Nov 7, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


























&lt;div class=&quot;js-timeline-item js-timeline-progressive-focus-container&quot; data-gid=&quot;MDE3OlJlbmFtZWRUaXRsZUV2ZW50NDE2MjkzNjM4MA==&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;TimelineItem js-targetable-element&quot; data-team-hovercards-enabled=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;event-4162936380&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;TimelineItem-body&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;d-inline-block&quot; data-hovercard-type=&quot;user&quot; data-hovercard-url=&quot;/users/TheMageKing/hovercard&quot; data-octo-click=&quot;hovercard-link-click&quot; data-octo-dimensions=&quot;link_type:self&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/TheMageKing&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;avatar avatar-user&quot; height=&quot;20&quot; width=&quot;20&quot; alt=&quot;@TheMageKing&quot; src=&quot;https://avatars1.githubusercontent.com/u/13556193?s=60&amp;amp;v=4&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;author link-gray-dark text-bold&quot; data-hovercard-type=&quot;user&quot; data-hovercard-url=&quot;/users/TheMageKing/hovercard&quot; data-octo-click=&quot;hovercard-link-click&quot; data-octo-dimensions=&quot;link_type:self&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/TheMageKing&quot;&gt;TheMageKing&lt;/a&gt; changed the title &lt;del class=&quot;text-bold&quot;&gt;SECURITY: New maintainer is probably malicious&lt;/del&gt; &lt;ins class=&quot;text-bold no-underline&quot;&gt;URGENT: SECURITY: New maintainer is probably malicious&lt;/ins&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/greatsuspender/thegreatsuspender/issues/1263#event-4162936380&quot; class=&quot;link-gray&quot;&gt;Jan 4, 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can’t perform that action at this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;js-stale-session-flash flash flash-warn flash-banner&quot; hidden=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;js-stale-session-flash-signed-in&quot; hidden=&quot;&quot;&gt;You signed in with another tab or window. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/greatsuspender/thegreatsuspender/issues/1263&quot;&gt;Reload&lt;/a&gt; to refresh your session.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;js-stale-session-flash-signed-out&quot; hidden=&quot;&quot;&gt;You signed out in another tab or window. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/greatsuspender/thegreatsuspender/issues/1263&quot;&gt;Reload&lt;/a&gt; to refresh your session.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;details class=&quot;details-reset details-overlay details-overlay-dark lh-default text-gray-dark hx_rsm&quot; open=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 14:41:37 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>AdamGibbins</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars0.githubusercontent.com/u/11603828?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>URGENT: SECURITY: New maintainer is probably malicious · Issue #1263 · greatsuspender/thegreatsuspender</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/greatsuspender/thegreatsuspender/issues/1263</og:url>
<og:description>It occurred to me that our current discussion of this is hard to find. It is happening in #1175, the issue about the new maintainer. To summarize, the maintainer recently updated their chrome store...</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/greatsuspender/thegreatsuspender/issues/1263</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Indian Government proposes to buy bulk subscriptions of all scientific journals</title>
<link>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/pune/one-nation-one-subscription-govt-draft-policy-7128799/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://indianexpress.com/article/india/pune/one-nation-one-subscription-govt-draft-policy-7128799/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;In an ambitious move to make scientific knowledge and data available to all, the government has proposed an open data policy that will make information generated by all publicly funded research, including its results, freely accessible to everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More significantly, the government has also proposed to buy bulk subscriptions of all the important scientific journals across the world, and provide everyone in India free access to them. The proposals have been made in the draft Science, Technology and Innovation Policy that was released to the public on New Year’s Day for comments and suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ‘One Nation, One Subscription’ policy for scientific journals is a radical move that could prove to be a game changer for the scientific community and individual researchers. There are more than 3,000 to 4,000 high-impact scientific journals, and sources say the government might have to spend a few hundred crore rupees every year to get their bulk subscriptions. But its impact on the scientific research community could be huge, given that access to these journals are highly priced and even big institutions are selective in buying subscriptions.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The Ministry of Science and Technology, which has drafted the new policy, proposes to set up a new Science, Technology and Innovation Observatory which will serve as a central repository for all kinds of data generated from research in India. All data generated from publicly-funded research is proposed to be made freely available to everyone. In cases where, for reasons of privacy, national security or intellectual property rights, the availability of data has to be restricted, “suitably anonymised and/or redacted data” will still be provided. Even in cases where it cannot be released to the general public, genuine researchers would be given access to it, the policy has proposed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, libraries of all publicly-funded institutions are proposed to be made accessible to general public “subject only to reasonable security protocols”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The policy also talks about promoting the goal of “Atmanirbhar Bharat” in the field of science and technology. “A two-way approach of indigenous development of technology as well as technology indigenisation will be adopted,” it says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Greater emphasis will be given on promoting traditional knowledge systems, developing indigenous technologies and encouraging grassroots innovations,” it says.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 14:03:52 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>sandGorgon</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/pune/one-nation-one-subscription-govt-draft-policy-7128799/</og:url>
<og:title>Govt proposes to buy bulk subscriptions of all scientific journals, provide free access to all</og:title>
<og:description>The 'One Nation, One Subscription' policy for scientific journals is a radical move that could prove to be a game changer for the scientific community and individual researchers.</og:description>
<og:image>https://images.indianexpress.com/2021/01/research.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/pune/one-nation-one-subscription-govt-draft-policy-7128799/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>When Big Brands Stopped Spending on Digital Ads, Nothing Happened. Why?</title>
<link>https://www.forbes.com/sites/augustinefou/2021/01/02/when-big-brands-stopped-spending-on-digital-ads-nothing-happened-why/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.forbes.com/sites/augustinefou/2021/01/02/when-big-brands-stopped-spending-on-digital-ads-nothing-happened-why/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;When P&amp;amp;G turned off $200 million of their digital ad spending, they saw NO CHANGE in business outcomes [&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.adweek.com/brand-marketing/when-procter-gamble-cut-200-million-in-digital-ad-spend-its-marketing-became-10-more-effective/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot; title=&quot;https://www.adweek.com/brand-marketing/when-procter-gamble-cut-200-million-in-digital-ad-spend-its-marketing-became-10-more-effective/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot; data-ga-track=&quot;ExternalLink:https://www.adweek.com/brand-marketing/when-procter-gamble-cut-200-million-in-digital-ad-spend-its-marketing-became-10-more-effective/&quot; aria-label=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;]. When Chase reduced their programmatic reach from 400,000 sites showing its ads to 5,000 sites (a 99% decrease), they saw NO CHANGE in business outcomes [&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/03/29/business/chase-ads-youtube-fake-news-offensive-videos.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot; title=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/03/29/business/chase-ads-youtube-fake-news-offensive-videos.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot; data-ga-track=&quot;ExternalLink:https://www.nytimes.com/2017/03/29/business/chase-ads-youtube-fake-news-offensive-videos.html&quot; aria-label=&quot;2&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;]. When Uber turned off $120 million of their digital ad spending meant to drive more app installs, they saw NO CHANGE in the rate of app installs [&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/stone-meet-glass-house-significance-ubers-second-ad/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot; title=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/stone-meet-glass-house-significance-ubers-second-ad/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot; data-ga-track=&quot;ExternalLink:https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/stone-meet-glass-house-significance-ubers-second-ad/&quot; aria-label=&quot;3&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;]. When big brands stopped spending on digital ads, nothing happened. Even further back in time, in 2012, eBay turned off their paid search ad spending, and saw NO CHANGE in sales coming from those sources [&lt;a href=&quot;https://hbr.org/2013/03/did-ebay-just-prove-that-paid&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot; title=&quot;https://hbr.org/2013/03/did-ebay-just-prove-that-paid&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot; data-ga-track=&quot;ExternalLink:https://hbr.org/2013/03/did-ebay-just-prove-that-paid&quot; aria-label=&quot;4&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;]. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why? Does that mean that digital advertising doesn’t work? Or does it mean something else?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a small business owner doing Facebook advertising turned off FAN (Facebook Audience Network), he saw the number of ad impressions plummet by about 90%. He also saw the number of clicks drop dramatically and the effective CPM (cost per thousand) prices go up. But the sales of his music and merchandise went back up, despite getting far fewer clicks, buying 90% less quantity of ad impressions, and spending less on ads overall. Further, the discrepancy between the clicks reported by Facebook advertising and the number of arrivals on his website, reported by Google Analytics, vanished. In other words, the number of arrivals on his website started to match the number of clicks reported on his Facebook ads. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In another example, a small business owner turned on a Google Adwords campaign and immediately saw a dramatic increase in traffic coming to her site. Any marketer would be ecstatic at how “well” and immediate the digital ads worked, right? Well, she was not. Looking at Google Analytics on her own site, she saw a 118,600% increase in Android devices coming to her site, and not much else. And those Android visitors were mostly “bouncing” — leaving after a few seconds. When she un-checked the checkboxes that allowed ads to run on “search partners” and “display network,” she saw this anomalous Android traffic mostly vanish. Did this harm her ecommerce sales? No. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What the heck is going on? Big brands turned off millions of dollars of digital ad spending, and saw no change in business outcomes. Small businesses tuned their digital marketing and reduced the number of ad impressions, clicks, and traffic to their sites, but saw business activity go up, instead of down. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Digital marketing works; but the vast majority of impressions and clicks are from bot activity currently.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;recirc-module seo&quot; data-type=&quot;standard&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;recirc-module-body&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MORE FOR YOU&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much of the problem with digital advertising today stems from marketers’ obsession with big numbers. But big numbers of ads and clicks do not translate into more business activity and sales. They are just large numbers in dashboards and spreadsheets. Marketers could be spending far fewer dollars and getting the same levels of business outcomes; or spending the dollars more smartly in digital and getting even more business outcomes than they are now. How?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some brands paused digital ad spending in 2020, due to the pandemic. If they saw no change in business outcomes, they can be very selective in what spending they turn back on, because those expenses were not driving incremental business anyway. Other advertisers reduced the number of websites and mobile apps showing their ads by going to a strict include-list. This prevents the vast majority of fly-by-night fake sites and mobile apps from sapping their digital ad budgets. And finally, smart advertisers should run more controlled experiments like eBay did in 2012 and prove to themselves what portion of digital advertising truly drives incremental business outcomes, versus the portion of the spending that is just wasted to bot activity. Be sure to read the details of how eBay ran the controlled experiment in the Harvard Business Review article: &lt;a href=&quot;https://hbr.org/2013/03/did-ebay-just-prove-that-paid&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot; title=&quot;https://hbr.org/2013/03/did-ebay-just-prove-that-paid&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot; data-ga-track=&quot;ExternalLink:https://hbr.org/2013/03/did-ebay-just-prove-that-paid&quot; aria-label=&quot;Did eBay Just Prove That Paid Search Ads Don’t Work?&quot;&gt;Did eBay Just Prove That Paid Search Ads Don’t Work?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through these experiments marketers large and small made digital ads work better for them. Chase did not need to show their ads on 400,000 websites, when showing ads to humans on 5,000 yielded the same outcomes. Small business owners did not need to buy millions of ad impressions, when buying 1/10 the quantity yielded more sales. Nowhere else is the phrase “you get what you pay for” more applicable than in digital marketing. If you are buying large numbers of low-cost ad impressions from programmatic channels, you’re likely getting ripped off instead of doing digital marketing. Run your own experiments — give your digital ad spending a “time out.” It’d be “fou” (“crazy”) if you don’t. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;And, if you have experienced this yourself, or have stories of your own, please reach out and let me know. I love hearing more about how marketers big and small saw and solved ad fraud themselves, without using any specialized fraud detection tech tools — just common sense, analytics, and a healthy dose of skepticism.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Further reading:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/augustinefou/2020/11/19/virtually-all-fraudwere-you-the-perp-the-conduit-or-the-sucker/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot; title=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/augustinefou/2020/11/19/virtually-all-fraudwere-you-the-perp-the-conduit-or-the-sucker/&quot; data-ga-track=&quot;InternalLink:https://www.forbes.com/sites/augustinefou/2020/11/19/virtually-all-fraudwere-you-the-perp-the-conduit-or-the-sucker/&quot; aria-label=&quot;‘Virtually All Fraud’—Were You The Perp, The Conduit, Or The Sucker?&quot;&gt;‘Virtually All Fraud’—Were You The Perp, The Conduit, Or The Sucker?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/augustinefou/2020/10/30/gaping-security-loopholes---why-marketers-should-care/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot; title=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/augustinefou/2020/10/30/gaping-security-loopholes---why-marketers-should-care/&quot; data-ga-track=&quot;InternalLink:https://www.forbes.com/sites/augustinefou/2020/10/30/gaping-security-loopholes---why-marketers-should-care/&quot; aria-label=&quot;Fraudsters Cheat By Tricking The Reporting To Look Awesome&quot;&gt;Fraudsters Cheat By Tricking The Reporting To Look Awesome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/augustinefou/2020/10/09/how-to-find-bot-traffic-with-google-analytics/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot; title=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/augustinefou/2020/10/09/how-to-find-bot-traffic-with-google-analytics/&quot; data-ga-track=&quot;InternalLink:https://www.forbes.com/sites/augustinefou/2020/10/09/how-to-find-bot-traffic-with-google-analytics/&quot; aria-label=&quot;How To Find Bot Traffic With Google Analytics&quot;&gt;How To Find Bot Traffic With Google Analytics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://specials-images.forbesimg.com/imageserve/5ff07d45bcd52228b578e8e7/960x0.jpg?cropX1=349&amp;amp;cropX2=4498&amp;amp;cropY1=415&amp;amp;cropY2=2361&quot; alt=&quot;Hand in protective latex gloves pressing pause button on the virtual screen&quot; data-height=&quot;3666&quot; data-width=&quot;5254&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;color-body light-text&quot;&gt;&lt;small&gt;getty&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 09:29:33 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ZeljkoS</dc:creator>
<og:title>When Big Brands Stopped Spending On Digital Ads, Nothing Happened. Why?</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.forbes.com/sites/augustinefou/2021/01/02/when-big-brands-stopped-spending-on-digital-ads-nothing-happened-why/</og:url>
<og:image>https://thumbor.forbes.com/thumbor/fit-in/1200x0/filters%3Aformat%28jpg%29/https%3A%2F%2Fspecials-images.forbesimg.com%2Fimageserve%2F5ff07d45bcd52228b578e8e7%2F0x0.jpg%3FcropX1%3D235%26cropX2%3D4677%26cropY1%3D183%26cropY2%3D2265</og:image>
<og:description>When P&amp;G, Chase, Uber, and eBay reduced or paused their digital ad spending, they saw NO CHANGE in business outcomes. Do those examples mean digital marketing doesn't work; or does it mean something else?</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.forbes.com/sites/augustinefou/2021/01/02/when-big-brands-stopped-spending-on-digital-ads-nothing-happened-why/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>