<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>How to hack a turned-off computer, or running unsigned code in Intel ME [pdf]</title>
<link>https://www.blackhat.com/docs/eu-17/materials/eu-17-Goryachy-How-To-Hack-A-Turned-Off-Computer-Or-Running-Unsigned-Code-In-Intel-Management-Engine-wp.pdf</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.blackhat.com/docs/eu-17/materials/eu-17-Goryachy-How-To-Hack-A-Turned-Off-Computer-Or-Running-Unsigned-Code-In-Intel-Management-Engine-wp.pdf</guid>
<description>&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blackhat.com/docs/eu-17/materials/eu-17-Goryachy-How-To-Hack-A-Turned-Off-Computer-Or-Running-Unsigned-Code-In-Intel-Management-Engine-wp.pdf&quot;&gt;Download PDF&lt;/a&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 16:08:44 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>danjoc</dc:creator>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.blackhat.com/docs/eu-17/materials/eu-17-Goryachy-How-To-Hack-A-Turned-Off-Computer-Or-Running-Unsigned-Code-In-Intel-Management-Engine-wp.pdf</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Airbus ready to axe A380 if fails to win Emirates deal</title>
<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-airbus-a380/airbus-ready-to-axe-a380-if-fails-to-win-emirates-deal-sources-idUSKBN1EL11L</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.reuters.com/article/us-airbus-a380/airbus-ready-to-axe-a380-if-fails-to-win-emirates-deal-sources-idUSKBN1EL11L</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;PARIS (Reuters) - Airbus is drawing up contingency plans to phase out production of the world’s largest jetliner, the A380 superjumbo, if it fails to win a key order from Dubai’s Emirates, three people familiar with the matter said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The moment of truth for the slow-selling airliner looms after just 10 years in service and leaves one of Europe’s most visible international symbols hanging by a thread, despite a major airline investment in new cabins unveiled this month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If there is no Emirates deal, Airbus will start the process of ending A380 production,” a person briefed on the plans said. A supplier added such a move was logical due to weak demand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Airbus and Emirates declined to comment. Airbus also declined to say how many people work on the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any shutdown is expected to be gradual, allowing Airbus to produce orders it has in hand, mainly from Emirates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has enough orders to last until early next decade at current production rates, according to a Reuters analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The A380 was developed at a cost of 11 billion euros to carry some 500 people and challenge the reign of the Boeing 747.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But demand for these four-engined goliaths has fallen as airlines choose smaller twin-engined models, which are easier to fill and cheaper to maintain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emirates, however, has been a strong believer in the A380 and is easily the largest customer with total orders of 142 aircraft, of which it has taken just over 100.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talks between Airbus and Emirates over a new order for 36 superjumbos worth $16 billion broke down at the Dubai Airshow last month. Negotiations are said to have resumed, but there are no visible signs that a deal is imminent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although airlines such as British Airways have expressed interest in the A380, Airbus is reluctant to keep factories open without the certainty that a bulk Emirates order would provide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emirates, for its part, wants a guarantee that Airbus will keep production going for a decade to protect its investment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Image_container_1tVQo&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;Image_caption_KoNH1&quot;&gt;FILE PHOTO: Visitors walk down an Airbus A380, showing a picture of United Arab Emirates' Former President Sheikh Zayed bin Sultan al-Nahayan, during the Dubai Airshow in Dubai, United Arab Emirates November 13, 2017. REUTERS/Satish Kumar/File Photo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A decision to cancel would mark a rupture between Airbus and one of its largest customers and tie Emirates’ future growth to recent Boeing orders. European sources say that reflects growing American influence in the Gulf under President Donald Trump, but U.S. and UAE industry sources deny politics are involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are also potential hurdles to a deal over engine choices and after-sales support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;SAFETY NET&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet if talks succeed, European sources say there is a glimmer of hope for the double-deck jet, which Airbus says will become more popular with airlines due to congestion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Image_container_1tVQo&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;Image_caption_KoNH1&quot;&gt;FILE PHOTO: An Airbus logo is pictured during the delivery of the new Airbus A380 aircraft to Singapore Airlines at the French headquarters of aircraft company Airbus in Colomiers near Toulouse, France, December 13, 2017. REUTERS/Regis Duvignau&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Singapore Airlines, which first introduced the A380 to passengers in 2007, showcased an $850 million cabin re-design this month and expressed confidence in the model’s future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Airbus hopes to use an Emirates order to stabilise output and establish a safety net from which to attract A380 sales to other carriers, but has ruled out trying to do this the other way round, industry sources said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of the end of November, Airbus had won orders for 317 A380s and delivered 221, leaving 96 unfilled orders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But based on airlines’ intentions or finances, 47 of those are unlikely to be delivered, according to industry sources, which halves the number of jets in play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Airbus needs to sell at least another 30 to keep lines open for 10 years and possibly more to justify the price concessions likely to be demanded by any new buyers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To bridge the gap, Airbus plans to cut output to six a year beyond 2019, from 12 in 2018 and 8 in 2019, even if it means producing at a loss, Reuters recently reported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chief Operating Officer Fabrice Bregier confirmed this month Airbus was looking at cutting output to 6-7 a year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If Airbus does decide to wind down production, some believe Emirates will ask Airbus to deliver the remaining 41 it has on order and then keep most A380s in service as long as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even so, some A380s are likely to be heading for scrap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Attribution_attribution_o4ojT&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Attribution_content_27_rw&quot;&gt;Reporting by Tim Hepher; Editing by Mark Potter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;StandardArticleBody_trustBadgeContainer_1gqgJ&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;StandardArticleBody_trustBadgeTitle_7sKLj&quot;&gt;Our Standards:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;trustBadgeUrl&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thomsonreuters.com/en/about-us/trust-principles.html&quot;&gt;The Thomson Reuters Trust Principles.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 14:18:50 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tiff</dc:creator>
<og:title>Airbus ready to phase out A380 if fails to win Emirates deal: sources</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-airbus-a380/airbus-ready-to-axe-a380-if-fails-to-win-emirates-deal-sources-idUSKBN1EL11L</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Airbus is drawing up contingency plans to phase out production of the world's largest jetliner, the A380 superjumbo, if it fails to win a key order from Dubai's Emirates, three people familiar with the matter said.</og:description>
<og:image>https://s4.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;d=20171227&amp;t=2&amp;i=1217514537&amp;w=1200&amp;r=LYNXMPEDBQ0RT</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-airbus-a380/airbus-ready-to-axe-a380-if-fails-to-win-emirates-deal-sources-idUSKBN1EL11L</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A History of the Silmarils in the Fifth Age</title>
<link>http://slatestarcodex.com/2017/12/26/a-history-of-the-silmarils-in-the-fifth-age/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://slatestarcodex.com/2017/12/26/a-history-of-the-silmarils-in-the-fifth-age/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;[Spoiler warning for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Silmarillion-J-R-R-Tolkien/dp/0618135049/ref=as_li_ss_tl?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1514328533&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=slatestarcode-20&amp;amp;linkId=5ec80baf6613d15d413cb1b13f29ecb8&quot;&gt;The Silmarillion&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Silmarillion&lt;/em&gt; describes the fate of the three Silmarils. Earendil kept one, and traveled with it through the sky, where it became the planet Venus. Maedhros stole another, but regretted his deed and jumped into a fiery chasm. And Maglor took the last one, but threw it into the sea in despair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, Venus is still around. But what happened to the latter two? Surely over all the intervening millennia, with so many people wanting a Silmaril, they haven’t just hung around in the earth and ocean?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some research, I’ve developed a couple of promising leads for the location of the Silmarils in the Fifth Age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;II.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I &lt;a href=&quot;https://slatestarscratchpad.tumblr.com/post/152824927151/slatestarscratchpad-slatestarscratchpad&quot;&gt;previously sketched out&lt;/a&gt; the argument that Maglor’s Silmaril probably belongs to a Los Angeles crime lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie &lt;em&gt;Pulp Fiction&lt;/em&gt; centers around a mysterious briefcase. We’re never told exactly what’s inside, but we get some clues:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. It’s described as “so beautiful” and captivates anyone who looks at it&lt;br/&gt;2. It shines with an inner light&lt;br/&gt;3. When Jules and Vincent are trying to get it, all the shots aimed at them miss, implying they’re miraculously immune to bullets, implying that they’re on some kind of divine quest.&lt;br/&gt;4. Marsellus Wallace really wants to get it, and keeps killing anyone else who has it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far this is only suggestive, but there’s more. While searching for the briefcase, Jules (!) keeps quoting a verse:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The path of the righteous man is beset on all sides by the inequities of the selfish and the tyranny of evil men. Blessed is he who, in the name of charity and good will, shepherds the weak through the valley of the darkness, for he is truly his brother’s keeper and the finder of lost children. And I will strike down upon thee with great vengeance and furious anger those who would attempt to poison and destroy my brothers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They describe this as Ezekiel 25:17, but &lt;a href=&quot;http://truthbygrace.org/pulp-fiction-and-ezekiel-2517/&quot;&gt;it isn’t&lt;/a&gt;. In fact, it isn’t anywhere in the Bible, and it doesn’t match any Biblical story. This isn’t from the Old Testament at all. It’s a description of the life of Maglor in the &lt;em&gt;Silmarillion&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the First Age, Maglor ruled “Maglor’s Gap”, a valley which connected the lands of the Elves and the lands of Morgoth. Maglor held Maglor’s Gap for 450 years until Morgoth finally conquered the valley; Maglor led the retreat of his people, thus “shepherding the weak through the valley of darkness”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He fled to the fortress of his brother, Maedhros, in Himling, where he helped defend Maedhros’ lands and people in battle – making him “his brother’s keeper”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the ensuing battles, he captured the young Elrond and Elros, who had been orphaned after their parents fled across the sea, and adopted them – making him “the finder of lost children”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for “striking down with great vengeance and furious anger those who would attempt to poison and destroy my brothers”, that’s about as Noldor as it gets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is going on here, and why do we keep finding these connections to Maglor?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maglor is unique as possibly the only Noldo still remaining in the world. According to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maglor&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maglor, along with Galadriel and Gil-galad, was the greatest surviving Noldo at the beginning of the Second Age. There is speculation that he remained even after the Third Age in Middle-earth, forbidden forever from returning to Valinor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If he were still alive in our times, he would remain bound by his oath and be hunting the Silmaril. So: could Marsellus Wallace, the mysterious gang boss who wants the briefcase so badly, be Maglor himself? Given that the name “Maglor” is a Sindarinization of his birth name “Makalaure”, “Marsellus” doesn’t even sound like much of a pseudonym.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main argument against this point is that Tolkien’s elves are usually depicted as fair-skinned and lithe, but Marsellus Wallace is shown in the movie as a big black guy. Does this disprove the theory?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would, &lt;em&gt;unless&lt;/em&gt; Marsellus were under some kind of magical glamor to hide his true appearance. And there’s actually some evidence for this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s one character in &lt;em&gt;Pulp Fiction&lt;/em&gt; who is clearly able to cast illusion-related magic: Mia Wallace. In the parking lot of the restaurant, she tells Vinnie “Don’t be a…”. Then she traces a square in the air with her finger, and the square appears in glittering light. Marsellus Wallace is married to someone who can cast visual illusions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But why should we believe Marsellus’ appearance is itself such an illusion? Well, in the scene with Jules and Brett, Jules puts a gun to Brett’s head and asks him what Marsellus looks like. Brett says he looks like a tall bald black guy, which seems to satisfy Jules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hit men try to play this off as some kind of intimidation thing, but they’re just going to shoot Brett anyway – there’s no need to intimidate him. It would only make sense if they’re actually checking how Marsellus appears to Brett – ie whether a certain illusion he’s projecting is working. When they follow up with “Does he look like a bitch?“, this is their foul-mouthed way of asking whether he looks androgynous. When Brett confirms that he looks masculine, this seems to satisfy the hit men, who then go ahead and shoot him. Unclear why they’re expecting the illusion to fail in Brett’s case, but it seems like if it has they’ll need to interrogate him further and maybe track down anybody else who might have learned too much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How is Mia Wallace able to cast these illusions?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would guess that “Mia” is actually Maia, ie one of the Maiar who is sent from Valinor to guide Elves and Men with their good counsel and magic powers. There’s a previous example of a female Maia marrying an elflord to guide him: Melian and Thingol. Mia is following in this tradition, and just as Melian granted Thingol’s kingdom invulnerability to attack, so Mia grants Maglor/Marsellus the ability to look like a big muscular black guy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We actually have further proof of this in the movie. Mia overdoses on heroin and goes unconscious. It looks like she goes a really long time without breathing. You get anoxic brain injury in like four or five minutes; Mia was out way longer than that. But once they give her adrenaline, she instantly and completely recuperates in a medically implausible way. Suffice it to say that she’s proven beyond a shadow of a doubt that she doesn’t have a human circulatory system, and given us at least strong evidence that she is literally immortal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would guess that Maglor survived, found his Silmaril, lost his Silmaril again, and that &lt;em&gt;Pulp Fiction&lt;/em&gt; is an account of him getting it back. “Quentin Tarantino” is probably a made-up pen name for a group of elvish historians – the name “Quentin” obviously deriving from “Quendi”, the elvish word for elves. “Tarantino” is more obscure, but it may be a reference to &lt;a href=&quot;http://tolkiengateway.net/wiki/Tar-Atanamir&quot;&gt;Tar-Atanamir&lt;/a&gt;, the Numenorean king who refused to die when his time came – something which must carry a lot of metaphorical associations for any elves remaining on Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If all of this is true, Maglor’s Silmaril probably remains with Maglor in his Los Angeles mansion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;III.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fate of Maedhros’ Silmaril is less clear, but one promising possibility is linked with the fate of Utumno.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Utumno was the fortress of the dark god Melkor during the First Age. It was built in the far north of Middle-Earth, “upon the borders of the regions of everlasting cold”. &lt;a href=&quot;http://tolkiengateway.net/wiki/Dor_Daidelos&quot;&gt;Tolkien Gateway writes&lt;/a&gt; that “the frigid temperatures of the northern regions were thought to originate from the evil of [Melkor’s] realm”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What was Utumno like? Like most of Tolkien’s villains, Melkor was at least partly a technologist; his realm was one of forges and smithies ceaselessly building weapons for his war against the gods. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thelandofshadow.com/utumno/&quot;&gt;This page&lt;/a&gt; describes it as “a fortress for war, with many armories, forges, dungeons and breeding pits.” Some of the descriptions sound like it was emitting pollution, destroying the land around it: “The lands of the far north were all made desolate in those days; for there Utumno was delved exceeding deep, and its pits were filled with fires and with great hosts of the servants of Melkor.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who manned these factories? Enslaved elves. As per the book, “All those of the Quendi who came into the hands of Melkor, ere Utumno was broken, were put there in prison, and by slow arts of cruelty were corrupted and enslaved”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually the gods decided enough was enough and marched against Utumno with a mighty host led by Tulkas, God of War. He wrestled with Melkor, defeated him, and bound him with a mighty chain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happened to Utumno after this? The &lt;em&gt;Silmarillion&lt;/em&gt; is vague, but in retrospect it’s super obvious. &lt;em&gt;What happened to the magical factory at the North Pole run by elves?&lt;/em&gt; Everyone knows the answer to that one!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presumably Tulkas and the other gods, after defeating Melkor, decided it was poetically appropriate to turn Utumno from a place of darkness to a wonderland of holiday cheer. The elves agreed to stay on to help, and they repurposed Melkor’s forges to create toys for children around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Santa Claus” supposedly derives from St. Nicholas, on the grounds that “Santa” means “saint” and “Claus” is short for “Nicholas”. But “Santa” means a female saint; a male saint is “San”. Santa is male, so a more reasonable derivation would be “San Tulkas”. Once a year, Tulkas goes forth and distributes the toys created by the elves of Utumno.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(remember, the &lt;em&gt;Silmarillion&lt;/em&gt; describes Tulkas as a huge bearded man who “laughs ever, in sport or in war, and even in the face of Melkor he laughed in battles before the Elves were born”. And remember, of his wife Nessa, it says “Deer she loves, and they follow her train whenever she goes in the wild”. Having deer follow your family around everywhere seems sounds pretty annoying, but at least it gives you a ready-made supply of draft animals.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we never see Santa’s workshop, it must be hidden from the world in the same manner as the Undying Lands. How does Tulkas cross back into the mortal world to deliver gifts?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only successful example of such a journey we have from Tolkien is that of Earendil, who travels from Middle-Earth to the Undying Lands using a Silmaril worn on his brow. Later, even after the two worlds are separated entirely, he is able use the same Silmaril to voyage through the sky in his flying boat. “The wise have said that it was by reason of the power of that holy jewel that they came in time to waters that no vessels save those of the Teleri had known”. So presumably any living being with a Silmaril upon their head can fly through the gulfs between the worlds safely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tulkas is a god and should have no trouble finding the only unclaimed Silmaril, the one Maedhros dropped into a chasm in the earth. His main issue would be preventing the surviving Noldor from learning what he has and invoking their vendetta. He would have to disguise it as something else, something so ridiculous that the stick-up-their-ass Noldor would never think to identify it with their holy jewels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer&lt;br/&gt;Had a very shiny nose&lt;br/&gt;And if you ever saw it&lt;br/&gt;You would even say it glows…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;robots-nocontent sd-block sd-social sd-social-icon-text sd-sharing&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Share this:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 13:30:45 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mpweiher</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>A History Of The Silmarils In The Fifth Age</og:title>
<og:url>http://slatestarcodex.com/2017/12/26/a-history-of-the-silmarils-in-the-fifth-age/</og:url>
<og:description>[Spoiler warning for The Silmarillion] I. The Silmarillion describes the fate of the three Silmarils. Earendil kept one, and traveled with it through the sky, where it became the planet Venus. Maed…</og:description>
<og:image>http://slatestarcodex.com/wp-content/themes/two_column_pujugama/images/codex_spotlight.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://slatestarcodex.com/2017/12/26/a-history-of-the-silmarils-in-the-fifth-age/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>From inboxing to thought showers: how business bullshit took over</title>
<link>https://www.theguardian.com/news/2017/nov/23/from-inboxing-to-thought-showers-how-business-bullshit-took-over</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theguardian.com/news/2017/nov/23/from-inboxing-to-thought-showers-how-business-bullshit-took-over</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;drop-cap&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;drop-cap__inner&quot;&gt;I&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;n early 1984, executives at the telephone company Pacific Bell made a fateful decision. For decades, the company had enjoyed a virtual monopoly on telephone services in California, but now it was facing a problem. The industry was about to be deregulated, and Pacific Bell would soon be facing tough competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The management team responded by doing all the things managers usually do: restructuring, downsizing, rebranding. But for the company executives, this wasn’t enough. They worried that Pacific Bell didn’t have the right culture, that employees did not understand “the profit concept” and were not sufficiently entrepreneurial. If they were to compete in this new world, it was not just their balance sheet that needed an overhaul, the executives decided. Their 23,000 employees needed to be overhauled as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;element element-rich-link element--thumbnail element-rich-link--not-upgraded&quot; data-component=&quot;rich-link&quot; data-link-name=&quot;rich-link-2 | 1&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;The company turned to a well-known organisational development specialist, Charles Krone, who set about designing a management-training programme to transform the way people thought, talked and behaved. The programme was based on the ideas of the 20th-century Russian mystic George Gurdjieff. According to Gurdjieff, most of us spend our days mired in “waking sleep”, and it is only by shedding ingrained habits of thinking that we can liberate our inner potential. Gurdjieff’s mystical ideas originally appealed to members of the modernist avant garde, such as the writer &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/books/booksblog/2008/aug/05/abriefsurveyoftheshortst9&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline in-body-link--immersive&quot;&gt;Katherine Mansfield&lt;/a&gt; and the architect Frank Lloyd Wright. More than 60 years later, senior executives at Pacific Bell were likewise seduced by Gurdjieff’s ideas. The company planned to spend $147m (£111m) putting their employees through the new training programme, which came to be known as Kroning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the course of 10 two-day sessions, staff were instructed in new concepts, such as “the law of three” (a “thinking framework that helps us identify the quality of mental energy we have”), and discovered the importance of “alignment”, “intentionality” and “end-state visions”. This new vocabulary was designed to awake employees from their bureaucratic doze and open their eyes to a new higher-level consciousness. And some did indeed feel like their ability to get things done had improved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there were some unfortunate side-effects of this heightened corporate consciousness. First, according to one former middle manager, it was virtually impossible for anyone outside the company to understand this new language the employees were speaking. Second, the manager said, the new language “led to a lot more meetings” and the sheer amount of time wasted nurturing their newfound states of higher consciousness meant that “everything took twice as long”. “If the energy that had been put into Kroning had been put to the business at hand, we all would have gotten a lot more done,” said the manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although Kroning was packaged in the new-age language of psychic liberation, it was backed by all the threats of an authoritarian corporation. Many employees felt they were under undue pressure to buy into Kroning. For instance, one manager was summoned to her superior’s office after a team member walked out of a Kroning session. She was asked to “force out or retire” the rebellious employee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some Pacific Bell employees wrote to their congressmen about Kroning. Newspapers ran damning stories with headlines such as “Phone company dabbles in mysticism”. The Californian utility regulator launched a public inquiry, and eventually closed the training course, but not before $40m dollars had been spent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this period, a young computer programmer at Pacific Bell was spending his spare time drawing a cartoon that mercilessly mocked the management-speak that had invaded his workplace. The cartoon featured a hapless office drone, his disaffected colleagues, his evil boss and an even more evil management consultant. It was a hit, and the comic strip was syndicated in newspapers across the world. The programmer’s name was Scott Adams, and the series he created was &lt;a href=&quot;http://dilbert.com/&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline in-body-link--immersive&quot;&gt;Dilbert&lt;/a&gt;. You can still find these images pinned up in thousands of office cubicles around the world today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although Kroning may have been killed off, Kronese has lived on. The indecipherable management-speak of which Charles Krone was an early proponent seems to have infected the entire world. These days, Krone’s gobbledygook seems relatively benign compared to much of the vacuous language circulating in the emails and meeting rooms of corporations, government agencies and NGOs. Words like “intentionality” sound quite sensible when compared to “ideation”, “imagineering”, and “inboxing” – the sort of management-speak used to talk about everything from educating children to running nuclear power plants. This language has become a kind of organisational lingua franca, used by middle managers in the same way that freemasons use secret handshakes – to indicate their membership and status. It echoes across the cubicled landscape. It seems to be everywhere, and refer to anything, and nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;section-rule&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;drop-cap&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;drop-cap__inner&quot;&gt;I&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;t hasn’t always been this way. A certain amount of empty talk is unavoidable when humans gather together in large groups, but the kind of bullshit through which we all have to wade every day is a remarkably recent creation. To understand why, we have to look at how management fashions have changed over the past century or so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the late 18th century, firms were owned and operated by businesspeople who tended to rely on tradition and instinct to manage their employees. Over the next century, as factories became more common, a new figure appeared: the manager. This new class of boss faced a big problem, albeit one familiar to many people who occupy new positions: they were not taken seriously. To gain respect, managers assumed the trappings of established professions such as doctors and lawyers. They were particularly keen to be seen as a new kind of engineer, so they appropriated the stopwatches and rulers used by them. In the process, they created the first major workplace fashion: scientific management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;u-responsive-ratio&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;gu-image&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; alt=&quot;Charlie Chaplin ‘satirising the cult of scientific management’ in 1936 film Modern Times.&quot; src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c707bd015e89b5aa3bcf1b9a60c9c686d198c05f/0_372_2383_1430/master/2383.jpg?w=300&amp;amp;q=55&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;usm=12&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=acdd532b58e181b8ad9f34759e2149a6&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

Charlie Chaplin ‘satirising the cult of scientific management’ in 1936 film Modern Times. Photograph: Allstar/Cinetext
&lt;p&gt;Firms started recruiting efficiency experts to conduct time-and-motion studies. After recording every single movement of a worker in minute detail, the time-and-motion expert would rearrange the worker’s performance of tasks into a more efficient order. Their aim was to make the worker into a well-functioning machine, doing each part of the job in the most efficient way. Scientific management was not limited to the workplaces of the capitalist west – Stalin pushed for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/books/2016/dec/29/stalin-and-the-scientists-simon-ings-review&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline in-body-link--immersive&quot;&gt;similar techniques&lt;/a&gt; to be imposed in factories throughout the Soviet Union.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Workers found the new techniques alien, and a backlash inevitably followed. Charlie Chaplin famously satirised the cult of scientific management in his 1936 film &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/media/from-the-archive-blog/2011/may/25/review-chaplin-modern-times-1936&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline in-body-link--immersive&quot;&gt;Modern Times&lt;/a&gt;, which depicts a factory worker who is slowly driven mad by the pressures of life on the production line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As scientific management became increasingly unpopular, executives began casting around for alternatives. They found inspiration in a famous series of experiments conducted by psychologists in the 1920s at the Hawthorne Works, a factory complex in Illinois where tens of thousands of workers were employed by Western Electric to make telephone equipment. A team of researchers from Harvard had initially set out to discover whether changes in environment, such as adjusting the lighting or temperature, could influence how much workers produced each day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To their surprise, the researchers found that no matter how light or dark the workplace was, employees continued to work hard. The only thing that seemed to make a difference was the amount of attention that workers got from the experimenters. This insight led one of the researchers, an Australian psychologist called Elton Mayo, to conclude that what he called the “human aspects” of work were far more important than “environmental” factors. While this may seem obvious, it came as news to many executives at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Mayo’s ideas caught hold, companies attempted to humanise their workplaces. They began talking about human relationships, worker motivation and group dynamics. They started conducting personality testing and running teambuilding exercises: all in the hope of nurturing good human relations in the workplace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;section-rule&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;drop-cap&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;drop-cap__inner&quot;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;his newfound interest in the human side of work did not last long. During the second world war, as the US and UK military invested heavily in trying to make war more efficient, management fashions began to shift. A bright young Berkeley graduate called Robert McNamara led a US army air forces team that used statistics to plan the most cost-effective way to flatten Japan in bombing campaigns. After the war, many military leaders brought these new techniques into the corporate world. McNamara, for instance, joined the Ford Motor Company, rising quickly to become its CEO, while the mathematical procedures that he had developed during the war were enthusiastically taken up by companies to help plan the best way to deliver cheese, toothpaste and Barbie dolls to American consumers. Today these techniques are known as supply-chain management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the postwar years, the individual worker once again became a cog in a large, hierarchical machine. While many of the grey-suited employees at these firms savoured the security, freedom and increasing affluence that their work brought, many also complained about the deep lack of meaning in their lives. The backlash came in the late 1960s, as the youth movement railed against the conformity demanded by big corporations. Protesters sprayed slogans such as “live without dead time” and “to hell with boundaries” on to city walls around the world. They wanted to be themselves, express who they really were, and not have to obey “the Man”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In response to this cultural change, in the 1970s, management fashions changed again. Executives began attending new-age workshops to help them “self actualise” by unlocking their hidden “human potential”. Companies instigated “encounter groups”, in which employees could explore their deeper inner emotions. Offices were redesigned to look more like university campuses than factories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;u-responsive-ratio&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;gu-image&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; alt=&quot;Mad Men’s liberated adman Don Draper (Jon Hamm).&quot; src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/4e906d14db2b887454a2c1a72c8266608a5666a7/70_53_1711_1026/master/1711.jpg?w=300&amp;amp;q=55&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;usm=12&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=fa994abd8a56a5af1c354981f203180c&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

Mad Men’s liberated adman Don Draper (Jon Hamm). Photograph: Courtesy of AMC/AMC
&lt;p&gt;Nowhere is this shift better captured than in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2015/may/18/mad-men-recap-season-seven-episode-14-person-to-person-warning-spoilers&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline in-body-link--immersive&quot;&gt;the final episode&lt;/a&gt; of the television series Mad Men. Don Draper had been the exemplar of the organisational man, wearing a standard-issue grey suit when we met him at the beginning of the show’s first series. After suffering numerous breakdowns over the intervening years, he finds himself at the Esalen institute in northern California, the home of the human potential movement. Initially, Draper resists. But soon he is sitting in a confessional circle, sobbing as he tells his story. His personal breakthrough leads him to take up meditating and chanting, looking out over the Pacific Ocean. The result of Don Draper’s visit to Esalen isn’t just personal transformation. The final scene shows the now-liberated adman’s new creation – an iconic Coca-Cola commercial in which a multiracial group of children stand on a hilltop singing about how they would like to buy the world a Coke and drink it in perfect harmony.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the fictional Don Draper visited Esalen, work became a place you could go to find yourself. Corporate mission statements now sounded like the revolutionary graffiti of the 1960s. The company training programme run by Charles Krone at Pacific Bell came straight from the Esalen playbook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since new-age ideas first permeated the workplace in the 1970s, the spin cycle of management-speak has sped up. During the 1980s, management experts went in search of fresh ideas in Japan. Management became a kind of martial art, with executives visiting “quality dojos” to earn “lean black-belts”. In their 1982 bestseller, In Search of Excellence, Tom Peters and Robert Waterman – both employees of McKinsey, the huge management consultancy agency – recommended that firms foster the same commitment to the company that they found among Honda employees in Japan. The book included the story of one Japanese employee who happens upon a damaged Honda on a public street. He stops and immediately begins repairing the car. The reason? He can’t bear to see a Honda that isn’t perfect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While McKinsey consultants were mining the wisdom of the east, the ideas of Harvard Business School’s Michael Jensen started to find favour among Wall Street financiers. Jensen saw the corporation as a portfolio of assets. Even people – labelled as “human resources” – were part of this portfolio. Each company existed to create returns for shareholders, and if managers failed to do this, they should be fired. If a company didn’t generate adequate returns, it should be broken up and sold off. Every little part of the company was seen as a business. Seduced by this view, many organisations started creating “internal markets”. In the 1990s, under director general John Birt, the BBC created a system in which everything from time in a recording studio to toilet cleaning was traded on a complex internal market. The number of accountants working for the broadcaster exploded, while people who created TV and radio shows were laid off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;section-rule&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;drop-cap&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;drop-cap__inner&quot;&gt;A&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;s companies have become increasingly ravenous for the latest management fad, they have also become less discerning. Some bizarre recent trends include &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/money/2012/may/25/equine-assisted-coaching-horses&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline in-body-link--immersive&quot;&gt;equine-assisted coaching&lt;/a&gt; (“You can lead people, but can you lead a horse?”) and rage rooms (a room where employees can go to take out their frustrations by smashing up office furniture, computers and images of their boss).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A century of management fads has created workplaces that are full of empty words and equally empty rituals. We have to live with the consequences of this history every day. Consider a meeting I recently attended. During the course of an hour, I recorded 64 different nuggets of corporate claptrap. They included familiar favourites such as “doing a deep dive”, “reaching out”, and “thought leadership”. There were also some new ones I hadn’t heard before: people with “protected characteristics” (anyone who wasn’t a white straight guy), “the aha effect” (realising something), “getting our friends in the tent” (getting support from others).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the meeting, I found myself wondering why otherwise smart people so easily slipped into this kind of business bullshit. How had this obfuscatory way of speaking become so successful? There are a number of familiar and credible explanations. People use management-speak to give the impression of expertise. The inherent vagueness of this language also helps us dodge tough questions. Then there is the simple fact that even if business bullshit annoys many people, in most work situations we try our hardest to be polite and avoid confrontation. So instead of causing a scene by questioning the bullshit flying around the room, I followed the example of Simon Harwood, the director of strategic governance in the BBC’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/media/shortcuts/2015/jul/05/wimbledon2day-bbc-w1a-difference-quiz&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline in-body-link--immersive&quot;&gt;self-satirising TV sitcom W1A&lt;/a&gt;. I used his standard response to any idea – no matter how absurd – “hurrah”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, these explanations did not seem to fully account for the conquest of bullshit. I came across one further explanation in a short article by the anthropologist David Graeber. As factories producing goods in the west have been dismantled, and their work outsourced or replaced with automation, large parts of western economies have been left with little to do. In the 1970s, some sociologists worried that this would lead to a world in which people would need to find new ways to fill their time. The great tragedy for many is that just the opposite seems to have happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;u-responsive-ratio&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;gu-image&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; alt=&quot;Simon Harwood (Jason Watkins, centre) of W1A, the BBC’s fictional director of strategic governance.&quot; src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/031c51657af050a40400c03156884662fea57ccd/0_267_4000_2400/master/4000.jpg?w=300&amp;amp;q=55&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;usm=12&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=e512cdafd2a05e088e8ed332fd2d8408&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

Simon Harwood (Jason Watkins, centre) of W1A, the BBC’s fictional director of strategic governance. Photograph: Jack Barnes/BBC
&lt;p&gt;At the very point when work seemed to be withering away, we all became obsessed with it. To be a good citizen, you need to be a productive citizen. There is only one problem, of course: there is less than ever that actually needs to be produced. As Graeber pointed out, the answer has come in the form of what he calls “bullshit jobs”. These are jobs in which people experience their work as “utterly meaningless, contributing nothing to the world”. In a YouGov poll conducted in 2015, 37% of respondents in the UK said their job made &lt;a href=&quot;http://&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline in-body-link--immersive&quot;&gt;no meaningful contribution&lt;/a&gt; to the world. But people working in bullshit jobs need to do &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt;. And that something is usually the production, distribution and consumption of bullshit. According to a 2014 survey by the polling agency Harris, the average US employee now spends &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/business/archive/2014/12/the-wasted-workday/383380/&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline in-body-link--immersive&quot;&gt;45% of their working&lt;/a&gt; day doing their real job. The other 55% is spent doing things such as wading through endless emails or attending pointless meetings. Many employees have extended their working day so they can stay late to do their “real work”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing continued to puzzle me: why was it that so many people were paid to do this kind of empty work. One reason that David Graeber gives, in his book The Utopia of Rules, is rampant bureaucracy: there are more forms to be filled in, procedures to be followed and standards to be complied with than ever. Today, bureaucracy comes cloaked in the language of change. Organisations are full of people whose job is to create change for no real reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Manufacturing hollow change requires a constant supply of new management fads and fashions. Fortunately, there is a massive industry of business bullshit merchants who are quite happy to supply it. For each new change, new bullshit is needed. Looking back over the list of business bullshit I had noted down during the meeting, I realised that much of it was directly related to empty new bureaucratic initiatives, which were seen as terribly urgent, but would probably be forgotten about in a few years’ time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the corrosive effects of business bullshit can be seen in the statistic that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/education/2016/mar/22/teachers-plan-leave-five-years-survey-workload-england&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline in-body-link--immersive&quot;&gt;43% of all teachers&lt;/a&gt; in England are considering quitting in the next five years. The most frequently cited reasons are increasingly heavy workloads caused by excessive administration, and a lack of time and space to devote to educating students. A remarkably similar picture appears if you look at the healthcare sector: in the UK, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/society/2015/sep/10/nhs-lose-80-per-cent-senior-doctors-workplace-stress&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline in-body-link--immersive&quot;&gt;81% of senior doctors&lt;/a&gt; say they are considering retiring from their job early; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bma.org.uk/news/2014/march/gp-morale-damaged-by-workload-says-survey&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline in-body-link--immersive&quot;&gt;57% of GPs&lt;/a&gt; are considering leaving the profession; 66% of nurses say &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/healthcare-network/views-from-the-nhs-frontline/2017/feb/13/moved-canada-nurse-uk-quit&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline in-body-link--immersive&quot;&gt;they would quit&lt;/a&gt; if they could. In each case, the most frequently cited reason is stress caused by increasing managerial demands, and lack of time to do their job properly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is not just employees who feel overwhelmed. During the 1980s, when Kroning was in full swing, empty management-speak was confined to the beige meeting rooms of large corporations. Now, it has seeped into every aspect of life. Politicians use business balderdash to avoid grappling with important issues. The machinery of state has also come down with the word-virus. The NHS is crawling with “quality sensei”, “lean ninjas”, and “blue-sky thinkers”. Even schools are flooded with the latest business buzzwords like “grit”, “flipped learning” and “mastery”. Naturally, the kids are learning fast. One teacher recalled how a seven-year-old described her day at school: “Well, when we get to class, we get out our books and start on our non-negotiables.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;section-rule&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;drop-cap&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;drop-cap__inner&quot;&gt;I&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;n the introduction to his 2015 book, Trust Me, PR Is Dead, the former PR executive Robert Phillips tells a fascinating story. One day he was called up by the CEO of a global corporation. The CEO was worried. A factory which was part of his firm’s supply chain had caught fire and 100 women had burned to death. “My chairman’s been giving me grief,” said the CEO. “He thinks we’re failing to get our message across. We are not emphasising our CSR [corporate social responsibility] credentials well enough.” Phillips responded: “While 100 women’s bodies are still smouldering?” The CEO was “struggling to contain both incredulity and temper”. “I know,” he said. “Please help.” Phillips responded: “You start with actions, not words.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In many ways, this one interaction tells us how bullshit is used in corporate life. Individual executives facing a problem know that turning to bullshit is probably not the best idea. However, they feel compelled. The problem is that such compulsions often cloud people’s best judgements. They start to think empty words will trump reasonable reflection and considered action. Sadly, in many contexts, empty words win out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we hope to improve organisational life – and the wider impact that organisations have on our society – then a good place to start is by reducing the amount of bullshit our organisations produce. Business bullshit allows us to blather on without saying anything. It empties out language and makes us less able to think clearly and soberly about the real issues. As we find our words become increasingly meaningless, we begin to feel a sense of powerlessness. We start to feel there is little we can do apart from play along, benefit from the game and have the occasional laugh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;element element-rich-link element--thumbnail element-rich-link--not-upgraded&quot; data-component=&quot;rich-link&quot; data-link-name=&quot;rich-link-2 | 2&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;But this does not need to be the case. Business bullshit can and should be challenged. This is a task each of us can take up by refusing to use empty management-speak. We can stop ourselves from being one more conduit in its circulation. Instead of just rolling our eyes and checking our emails, we should demand something more meaningful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clearly, our own individual efforts are not enough. Putting management-speak in its place is going to require a collective effort. What we need is an anti-bullshit movement. It would be made up of people from all walks of life who are dedicated to rooting out empty language. It would question management twaddle in government, in popular culture, in the private sector, in education and in our private lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aim would not just be bullshit-spotting. It would also be a way of reminding people that each of our institutions has its own language and rich set of traditions which are being undermined by the spread of the empty management-speak. It would try to remind people of the power which speech and ideas can have when they are not suffocated with bullshit. By cleaning out the bullshit, it might become possible to have much better functioning organisations and institutions and richer and fulfilling lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Business Bullshit by André Spicer is published by Taylor &amp;amp; Francis. Buy it for £16.99 at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.guardianbookshop.com/business-bullshit.html&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline in-body-link--immersive&quot;&gt;bookshop.theguardian.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;bullet&quot;&gt;•&lt;/span&gt; Follow the Long Read on Twitter at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/@gdnlongread&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline in-body-link--immersive&quot;&gt;@gdnlongread&lt;/a&gt;, or sign up to the long read weekly email &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/info/ng-interactive/2017/may/05/sign-up-for-the-long-read-email&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline in-body-link--immersive&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 12:32:21 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tomduncalf</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://www.theguardian.com/news/2017/nov/23/from-inboxing-to-thought-showers-how-business-bullshit-took-over</og:url>
<og:description>The long read: Vacuous management-speak is easily laughed off – but is there a real cost to talking rubbish?</og:description>
<og:image>https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/0a2bf5c8c724dbaf65c16a37fe3dfa13652e14eb/0_0_5333_3200/master/5333.jpg?w=1200&amp;h=630&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;fit=crop&amp;crop=faces%2Centropy&amp;bm=normal&amp;ba=bottom%2Cleft&amp;blend64=aHR0cHM6Ly91cGxvYWRzLmd1aW0uY28udWsvMjAxNi8wNS8yNS9vdmVybGF5LWxvZ28tMTIwMC05MF9vcHQucG5n&amp;s=696c9a4fc7f7670360b349cf14cb8e9e</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>From inboxing to thought showers: how business bullshit took over</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theguardian.com/news/2017/nov/23/from-inboxing-to-thought-showers-how-business-bullshit-took-over</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A pattern language for microservices</title>
<link>http://microservices.io/patterns/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://microservices.io/patterns/</guid>
<description>&lt;img src=&quot;http://gravatar.com/avatar/a290a8643359e2495e1c6312e662012f&quot; class=&quot;img-circle&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Microservices.io is brought to you by Chris Richardson. Experienced software architect, author of POJOs in Action and the creator of the original CloudFoundry.com. His latest startup is &lt;a href=&quot;http://eventuate.io&quot;&gt;eventuate.io&lt;/a&gt;, a microservices application platform.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Public training in Minneapolis&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll be teaching a 2 day microservices workshop in Minneapolis in January and then keynoting at the CodeFreeze conference. &lt;a class=&quot;btn btn-info btn-xs&quot; href=&quot;http://microservices.io/microservices/news/2017/12/04/microservices-at-code-freeze.html&quot;&gt;Learn more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Learn more about microservices&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris offers a comprehensive set of resources for learning about microservices including articles, an O'Reilly training video, and example code. &lt;a class=&quot;btn btn-info btn-xs&quot; href=&quot;http://learnmicroservices.io&quot;&gt;Learn more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Microservices consulting and training&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris offers a comprehensive consulting services, workshops and hands on training classes to help you use microservices effectively. &lt;a class=&quot;btn btn-primary btn-xs&quot; href=&quot;http://www.chrisrichardson.net/microserviceslanding.html&quot;&gt;Get advice&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Example microservices applications&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want to see an example? Check out Chris Richardson's example applications. &lt;a class=&quot;btn btn-info btn-xs&quot; href=&quot;http://eventuate.io/exampleapps.html&quot;&gt;See code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Get the book: Microservice patterns&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.manning.com/books/microservice-patterns&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.manning.com/220/270/resize/book/1/738c547-3799-4f62-895f-ba65d72082aa/Richardson-MP-MEAP-HI.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 12:05:10 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>exploreshaifali</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:title>Microservices Pattern: A pattern language for microservices</og:title>
<og:url>http://microservices.io/patterns/</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://microservices.io/patterns/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>ESP8266 ePaper WiFi Display Kit Runs for Months on a Charge</title>
<link>https://blog.tindie.com/2017/12/esp8266-epaper-display/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.tindie.com/2017/12/esp8266-epaper-display/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-6828&quot; src=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/blog.tindie.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/espaper1.jpg?resize=676%2C343&quot; alt=&quot;espaper1&quot; srcset=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/blog.tindie.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/espaper1.jpg?resize=676%2C343 676w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.tindie.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/espaper1.jpg?resize=300%2C152 300w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.tindie.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/espaper1.jpg?w=1352 1352w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 676px) 100vw, 676px&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my humble opinion—as I’ve mentioned elsewhere—ePaper is really an amazing display technology that has never really burst onto the mainstream. ePaper is incredibly energy efficient, requiring power only to change the display, the refresh rate is atrocious compared to television or smartphones, but seems to have been relegated to dedicated e-readers and the odd smartwatch. The natural outlet then would be makers and hobbyists, but options are less numerous than most other display methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other market I could see for this type of device is as a static display, such as in office meeting rooms, or for weather and other stats which needs to only be updated intermittently. You can try to hack something together yourself, but the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tindie.com/products/11123&quot;&gt;2.9″ ESPaper Plus Kit&lt;/a&gt; has everything you need to get started with your semi-static display, including an ESP8266 WiFi module.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;embed-youtube&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe class=&quot;youtube-player&quot; type=&quot;text/html&quot; width=&quot;676&quot; height=&quot;411&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/MuhyX1ao3yc?version=3&amp;amp;rel=1&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;autohide=2&amp;amp;showsearch=0&amp;amp;showinfo=1&amp;amp;iv_load_policy=1&amp;amp;wmode=transparent&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means that your display can grab the info it needs over WiFi, then go back to sleep, running for weeks or even months on a single LiPo charge. Importantly, it’s also programmable in the Arduino IDE, and its creator Daniel Eichhorn has written a library to make creating your own display easy. There’s also a web app in the works to allow configuration via the web, which will be especially appealing to those who aren’t particularly comfortable programming in the Arduino IDE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It looks like a great time to get started with this tech, and it’s wonderful to see Tindie serving as a market for awesome niche devices like this. The Plus Kit linked above includes a battery, programmer, and case, but the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tindie.com/products/10747&quot;&gt;lite Kit is available&lt;/a&gt; without these accessories for $10 less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;embed-youtube&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe class=&quot;youtube-player&quot; type=&quot;text/html&quot; width=&quot;676&quot; height=&quot;411&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ioWDxy7PtYE?version=3&amp;amp;rel=1&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;autohide=2&amp;amp;showsearch=0&amp;amp;showinfo=1&amp;amp;iv_load_policy=1&amp;amp;wmode=transparent&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;robots-nocontent sd-block sd-social sd-social-icon-text sd-sharing&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Share this:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;jp-relatedposts-headline&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Related&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 11:21:26 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>okket</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>ESP8266 ePaper WiFi Display Kit Runs for Months on a Charge - Tindie Blog</og:title>
<og:description>In my humble opinion—as I’ve mentioned elsewhere—ePaper is really an amazing display technology that has never really burst onto the mainstream. ePaper is incredibly energy efficient, requiring power only to change the display, the refresh rate is atrocious compared to television or smartphones, but seems to have been relegated to dedicated e-readers and the odd...</og:description>
<og:url>https://blog.tindie.com/2017/12/esp8266-epaper-display/</og:url>
<og:image>https://blog.tindie.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/espaper1.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.tindie.com/2017/12/esp8266-epaper-display/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>34th Chaos Communication Congress Live Streams</title>
<link>http://streaming.media.ccc.de</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://streaming.media.ccc.de</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;http://streaming.media.ccc.de&quot;&gt;http://streaming.media.ccc.de&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16013960&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16013960&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Points: 278&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 59&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 10:25:39 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>lawl</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://streaming.media.ccc.de/34c3</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Learning from Scratch by Thinking Fast and Slow</title>
<link>https://davidbarber.github.io/blog/2017/11/07/Learning-From-Scratch-by-Thinking-Fast-and-Slow-with-Deep-Learning-and-Tree-Search/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://davidbarber.github.io/blog/2017/11/07/Learning-From-Scratch-by-Thinking-Fast-and-Slow-with-Deep-Learning-and-Tree-Search/</guid>
<description>&lt;span class=&quot;post-date&quot; itemprop=&quot;datePublished&quot; content=&quot;2017-11-07&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;fa fa-calendar&quot; title=&quot;Date published&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;permalink&quot; href=&quot;https://davidbarber.github.io/blog/2017/11/07/Learning-From-Scratch-by-Thinking-Fast-and-Slow-with-Deep-Learning-and-Tree-Search/&quot; itemprop=&quot;url&quot; title=&quot;Permanent link to this post&quot;&gt;07 Nov 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;post-tags&quot; itemprop=&quot;keywords&quot; content=&quot;deep learning, Monte Carlo Tree Search, Hex, reinforcement learning, AlphaGo, and Dual Process Theory&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://davidbarber.github.io/tags/#deep+learning&quot; title=&quot;Pages tagged deep learning&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;deep learning&lt;/a&gt; • &lt;a href=&quot;https://davidbarber.github.io/tags/#Monte+Carlo+Tree+Search&quot; title=&quot;Pages tagged Monte Carlo Tree Search&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Monte Carlo Tree Search&lt;/a&gt; • &lt;a href=&quot;https://davidbarber.github.io/tags/#Hex&quot; title=&quot;Pages tagged Hex&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Hex&lt;/a&gt; • &lt;a href=&quot;https://davidbarber.github.io/tags/#reinforcement+learning&quot; title=&quot;Pages tagged reinforcement learning&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;reinforcement learning&lt;/a&gt; • &lt;a href=&quot;https://davidbarber.github.io/tags/#AlphaGo&quot; title=&quot;Pages tagged AlphaGo&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;AlphaGo&lt;/a&gt; • &lt;a href=&quot;https://davidbarber.github.io/tags/#Dual+Process+Theory&quot; title=&quot;Pages tagged Dual Process Theory&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Dual Process Theory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;social-icons&quot;&gt;     &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Training powerful reinforcement learning agents from scratch by Thinking Fast and Slow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;no_toc&quot; id=&quot;dual-process-theory&quot;&gt;Dual Process Theory&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dual_process_theory&quot;&gt;dual process theory&lt;/a&gt; human reasoning consists of two different kinds of thinking. System 1 is a fast, unconscious and automatic mode of thought, also known as intuition. System 2 is a slow, conscious, explicit and rule-based mode of reasoning that is believed to be an evolutionarily recent process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://web4.cs.ucl.ac.uk/staff/D.Barber/images//behaviour-design-predicting-irrational-decisions-12-638.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;dual process&quot; title=&quot;dual process theory&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.slideshare.net/AshDonaldson/behaviour-design-predicting-irrational-decisions&quot;&gt;image credit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When learning to complete a challenging planning task, such as playing a board game, humans exploit both processes: strong intuitions allow for more effective analytic reasoning by rapidly selecting interesting lines of play for consideration. Repeated deep study gradually improves intuitions. Stronger intuitions feedback to stronger analysis, creating a closed learning loop. In other words, humans learn by thinking fast and slow&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:TFAS&quot;/&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;no_toc&quot; id=&quot;whats-wrong-with-current-deep-rl&quot;&gt;What’s wrong with current Deep RL?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In current Deep Reinforcement Learning (RL) algorithms such as Policy Gradients&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:Williams&quot;/&gt; and DQN&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:DQN&quot;/&gt;, neural networks make action selections with no lookahead; this is analogous to System 1. Unlike human intuition, their training does not benefit from a ‘System 2’ to suggest strong policies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A criticism of some AI algorithms such as AlphaGo&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:AlphaGo&quot;/&gt; is that they use a database of human expert play&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:AlphaGo:1&quot;/&gt;. In the initial phase of training the RL agent mimics the moves of a human expert – only after this initial phase does it begin to learn potentially more powerful super-human play. This is somewhat unsatisfactory since the resulting algorithm may be heavily biased toward a human style of playing, blind to potentially more powerful lines of play. Whilst, in areas such as game playing, it may be natural to assume that there will be a database of human expert play available, in other settings in which we wish to train an AI machine, no such database may be available. Therefore, showing how to train a state-of-the-art board game player &lt;em&gt;ex nihilo&lt;/em&gt; is a major challenge for AI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;no_toc&quot; id=&quot;expert-iteration-exit&quot;&gt;Expert Iteration (ExIt)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expert Iteration&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:NIPSpaper&quot;/&gt; (ExIt) is a general framework for learning that we introduced in May 2017 and can result in powerful AI machines, without needing to mimic human strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://web4.cs.ucl.ac.uk/staff/D.Barber/images//ExIt.png&quot; alt=&quot;ExIt&quot; title=&quot;Expert Iteration&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ExIt can be viewed as an extension of Imitation Learning (IL) methods to domains where the best known experts are unable to achieve satisfactory performance. In standard IL an apprentice is trained to imitate the behaviour of an expert. In ExIt, we extend this to an iterative learning process. Between each iteration, we perform an Expert Improvement step, where we bootstrap the (fast) apprentice policy to increase the performance of the (comparatively slow) expert.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To give some intuition around this idea, consider playing a board game such as chess. Here the expert is analogous to chess player playing on slow time controls (having lots of time to decide on her move), and the apprentice is playing on blitz time controls (having little time to decide which move to make).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During independent study, the player considers multiple possible moves from a position, thinking deeply (and slowly) about each possible move move. She discovers which moves are successful and which are not in this position. When she encounters a similar board state in the future, her study will have given her an intuitive understanding of what moves are likely to be good, allowing her to play well, even under blitz time controls. Her intuition is imitating the strong play she calculated via deep thinking. Humans do not become become excellent chess players by only playing blitz matches, deeper study is an essential part of the learning process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For an AI game playing machine, this imitation could be achieved, for example, by fitting a neural network to the move made by another `machine expert’ from a game position. The apprentice learns a fast policy that is able to quickly imitate the play of the expert on the moves seen so far. A key point here is that, assuming that there is structure underlying the game, Machine Learning enables the apprentice to generalise their intuition to take quick decisions on positions not previously seen. That is, the apprentice isn’t just a creating a look-up-table of moves made by the human from a fixed database of positions. The neural network thus plays the role of both generalising and imitating the play of the expert.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that the apprentice has learned a fast imitation of the expert (on the moves seen so far), it can try to be of use to the expert. When the expert now wishes to make a move, a small set of candidate moves are suggested very quickly by the apprentice which the expert can then consider in depth, possibly also guided during this slow thought process by other quick insights from the apprentice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of this phase, the expert will have made a set of apprentice-aided moves, with each move being typically much stronger than either the apprentice or expert could have made alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above process now repeats, with the apprentice retraining on the moves suggested by the expert. This completes one full iteration of the learning phase and we iterate this process until the apprentice converges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a Dual Process perspective, the Imitation Learning step is analogous to a human improving their intuition for the task by studying example problems, while the Expert Improvement step is analogous to a human using their improved intuition to guide future analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;no_toc&quot; id=&quot;tree-search-and-deep-learning&quot;&gt;Tree Search and Deep Learning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exit is a general strategy for learning and the apprentice and expert can be specified in a variety of ways. In board games Monte Carlo Tree Search (MCTS) is a strong playing strategy&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:MCTS&quot;/&gt; and is a natural candidate to play the role of the expert. Deep Learning has been shown to be a successful method to imitate the play of strong players&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:AlphaGo:2&quot;/&gt; which we therefore use as the apprentice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the Expert Improvement phase we use the apprentice to direct the MCTS algorithm toward promising moves, effectively reducing the game tree search breadth and depth. In this way, we bootstrap the knowledge acquired by Imitation Learning back into the planning algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;no_toc&quot; id=&quot;the-board-game-hex&quot;&gt;The board game Hex&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hex_(board_game)&quot;&gt;Hex&lt;/a&gt; is a classic two-player board game played on a  hexagonal grid. The players, denoted by colours black and white, alternate placing stones of their colour in empty cells. The black player wins if there is a sequence of adjacent black stones connecting the North edge of the board to the South edge. White wins if he achieves a sequence of adjacent white stones running from the West edge to the East edge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://web4.cs.ucl.ac.uk/staff/D.Barber/images//hexBW.png&quot; alt=&quot;hex&quot; title=&quot;Hex&quot;/&gt;&lt;em&gt;An example game on a  Hex board.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above represents play on a  board, with white winning (reproduced from &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:MOHEX&quot;/&gt;). Hex has deep strategy, making it challenging for machines to play and its large action set and connection-based rules means it shares similar challenges for AI to Go. Compared to Go, however, the rules are simpler and there can be no draws.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because the rules of Hex are so simple, the game is relatively amenable to mathematical analysis (compared for example to Go) and the current best machine player MoHex&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:MOHEX:1&quot;/&gt; uses a combination of MCTS and smart mathematical insights. MoHex has won every Computer Games Olympiad Hex tournament since 2009. It is noteworthy, that MoHex uses a rollout policy trained on datasets of human expert play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We wanted to see if we can use our ExIt training strategy to learn an AI player than can outperform MoHex, without using any game-specific knowledge or human example play (beside the rules of the game). To do this, our expert is a MCTS player that is guided by the apprentice neural network. Our neural network is a form of deep convolutional network with two output policies – ones for black play and one for white (see &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:NIPSpaper:1&quot;/&gt; for details).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expert Improvement is achieved by using the modified MCTS formula&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:OnlineOffline&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here  is the state of the Hex board,  is a possible action (i.e. move) from . The term  represents the classical Upper Confidence Bound for Trees&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:MCTS:1&quot;/&gt; used in MCTS. The additional term helps the neural network apprentice guide the search to more promising moves. In this term  is the policy (suggested relative strength of each possible action  from the board state ) of the apprentice and  the number of visits currently made by the search algorithm through state  and taking action ;  is an empirically chosen weighting factor that balances the slow thinking of the expert with the fast intuition of the apprentice. Through the additional term, the neural network apprentice guides the search to more promising moves, and rejects weak moves more quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To generate the data for training the apprentice (during each Imitation Learning phase), the batch approach generates data afresh, discarding all data from previous iterations. We also consider a online version in which we instead keep a running buffer of the most recent moves generated; we further consider an online version that retains all data, but with exponentially more data from more recent experts (which correspond to the strongest play). A comparison of these different approaches is given below in which we compare the strength (measured in terms of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Elo_rating_system&quot;&gt;ELO&lt;/a&gt; score) of each learned policy network against a measure of training time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://web4.cs.ucl.ac.uk/staff/D.Barber/images//BatchOnline.png&quot; alt=&quot;results&quot; title=&quot;results&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also show the result of using a more traditional Reinforcement Learning approach in which a policy  is learned only through self play (i.e. no MCTS). This is essentially the method used within AlphaGo&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:AlphaGo:3&quot;/&gt; to train their policy network. The figure shows that the ExIt training approach is considerably more effective than more classical approaches. It is worth noting that in this example training has not yet fully converged and the apprentice would be expected to improve in ability further given additional training time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our paper&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:NIPSpaper:2&quot;/&gt; we include an additional mechanism to improve play, namely a value network  that approximates the probability that the apprentice (alone) would win the game from position . Both the policy and value network are then used in combination to help guide the final apprentice-aided MCTS player. The policy network and value networks guide the final MCTS player using an equation similar \eqref{eq:uct}, but modified to include the apprentice’s value of the state  (see &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:NIPSpaper:3&quot;/&gt; for details).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our final MCTS player outperforms the best known machine Hex player, MoHex, beating it in 75% of games played on a  board. These results are even more remarkable considering that training has not fully converged. A couple of examples of game-play of our ExIt trained player versus the state-of-the-art MoHex player are shown below&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:RyanHayward&quot;/&gt;. We contrast the play of each algorithm when started at the same position. See the paper&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:NIPSpaper:4&quot;/&gt; for more examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://web4.cs.ucl.ac.uk/staff/D.Barber/images//game1.png&quot; alt=&quot;results&quot; title=&quot;game1&quot;/&gt;&lt;em&gt;ExIt (black) versus MoHex (white)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://web4.cs.ucl.ac.uk/staff/D.Barber/images//game2.png&quot; alt=&quot;results&quot; title=&quot;game2&quot;/&gt;&lt;em&gt;MoHex (black) versus ExIt (white)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;no_toc&quot; id=&quot;why-does-exit-work-so-well&quot;&gt;Why does ExIt work so well?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imitation Learning is generally appreciated to be easier than Reinforcement Learning, and this partly explains why ExIt is more successful than model-free methods like REINFORCE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, for MCTS to recommend a move, it must be unable to find any weakness with its search. Effectively, therefore, a move played by MCTS is good against a large selection of possible opponents. In contrast, in regular self play (in which the opponent move is made by the network playing as the opposite colour), moves are recommended if they beat only this single opponent under consideration. This is, we believe, a key insight into why ExIt works well (when using MCTS as the expert) — the apprentice effectively learns to play well against many opponents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;no_toc&quot; id=&quot;relation-to-alphago-zero&quot;&gt;Relation to AlphaGo Zero&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AlphaGo Zero&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:AlphaGoZero&quot;/&gt; (developed independently of our work&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:AXpaper&quot;/&gt;) also implements an ExIt style algorithm and shows that it is possible to achieve state-of-the-art performance in Go without the use of human expert play. A detailed comparison of the approaches is given in our paper&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:NIPSpaper:5&quot;/&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;no_toc&quot; id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expert Iteration is a new Reinforcement Learning algorithm, motivated by the dual process theory of human thought. ExIt decomposes the Reinforcement Learning into the separate subproblems of generalisation and planning. Planning is performed on a case-by-case basis, and only once a strong plan is found is the resultant policy generalised. This allows for long-term planning and results in faster learning and state-of-the-art final performance, particularly for challenging problems. This training strategy is powerful enough to learn state-of-the-art board game AI players without requiring any examples of expert human play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;no_toc&quot; id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;social-icons&quot;&gt;     &lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;hr/&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;post-tags&quot; itemprop=&quot;keywords&quot; content=&quot;deep learning, Monte Carlo Tree Search, Hex, reinforcement learning, AlphaGo, and Dual Process Theory&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://davidbarber.github.io/tags/#deep+learning&quot; title=&quot;Pages tagged deep learning&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;deep learning&lt;/a&gt; • &lt;a href=&quot;https://davidbarber.github.io/tags/#Monte+Carlo+Tree+Search&quot; title=&quot;Pages tagged Monte Carlo Tree Search&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Monte Carlo Tree Search&lt;/a&gt; • &lt;a href=&quot;https://davidbarber.github.io/tags/#Hex&quot; title=&quot;Pages tagged Hex&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Hex&lt;/a&gt; • &lt;a href=&quot;https://davidbarber.github.io/tags/#reinforcement+learning&quot; title=&quot;Pages tagged reinforcement learning&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;reinforcement learning&lt;/a&gt; • &lt;a href=&quot;https://davidbarber.github.io/tags/#AlphaGo&quot; title=&quot;Pages tagged AlphaGo&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;AlphaGo&lt;/a&gt; • &lt;a href=&quot;https://davidbarber.github.io/tags/#Dual+Process+Theory&quot; title=&quot;Pages tagged Dual Process Theory&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Dual Process Theory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 08:06:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rusht</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Learning From Scratch by Thinking Fast and Slow with Deep Learning and Tree Search</og:title>
<og:description>Reinforcement Learning</og:description>
<og:url>https://davidbarber.github.io/blog/2017/11/07/Learning-From-Scratch-by-Thinking-Fast-and-Slow-with-Deep-Learning-and-Tree-Search/</og:url>
<og:image>http://web4.cs.ucl.ac.uk/staff/D.Barber/images/sitelogo.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://davidbarber.github.io/blog/2017/11/07/Learning-From-Scratch-by-Thinking-Fast-and-Slow-with-Deep-Learning-and-Tree-Search/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>India’s IT industry laid off more than 56k employees this year</title>
<link>https://qz.com/1152683/indian-it-layoffs-in-2017-top-56000-led-by-tcs-infosys-cognizant/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://qz.com/1152683/indian-it-layoffs-in-2017-top-56000-led-by-tcs-infosys-cognizant/</guid>
<description>&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Indian techies, 2017 was the stuff of nightmares.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ibef.org/industry/information-technology-india.aspx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;top employment generators&lt;/a&gt; until a few years ago, India’s $160 billion IT industry laid off more than &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.livemint.com/Industry/4CXsLIIZXf8uVQLs6uFQvK/Top-7-IT-firms-including-Infosys-Wipro-to-lay-off-at-least.html&quot;&gt;56,000 employees&lt;/a&gt; this year. Some analysts believe this spree was worse &lt;a href=&quot;https://tech.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/corporate/its-layoff-crisis-may-be-bigger-than-2008-recession/58691201&quot;&gt;than the one during the 2008 financial crisis&lt;/a&gt;. Meanwhile, hiring plummeted, with entry-level openings having more than halved in 2017, according to experts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tata Consultancy Services (TCS) and Infosys, two of India’s largest IT companies and once leaders in job creation, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.livemint.com/Industry/UbruIMQLdE5tzyuUR1f8CO/Infosys-TCS--Tech-Mahindra-see-workforce-shrink-for-the-fi.html&quot;&gt;reduced their headcounts for the first time ever&lt;/a&gt;. Even mid-sized players like Tech Mahindra retrenched several employees. (However, TCS’s staff addition recovered after a fall during April-June 2017 and rose 0.8% in the following quarter).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Digitisation and automation brought about disruption in traditional roles, which means that most of the IT firms found themselves reassessing the capability of the talent pool to stay market relevant,” Arun Paul, vice-president of human resources at Incedo, an IT service management company, told Quartz.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When hell broke loose&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Compared to the normal rate of forced attrition (i.e. asking non-performers to leave) of around 1% in earlier years, 2017 saw&lt;/span&gt; Indian IT companies letting go of &lt;span&gt;between&lt;/span&gt; 2% and 6% of their employees, said &lt;span&gt;Alka Dhingra, general manager of IT staffing at TeamLease Services.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Infosys &lt;a href=&quot;https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/business/india-business/infosys-releases-9000-employees-due-to-automation/articleshow/56678827.cms&quot;&gt;cut 9,000 jobs&lt;/a&gt; in January. “Instead of 10 people, what if we have three people to work on (a project). If we don’t have the software, then some others will take the advantage (away from us),” Vishal Sikka, the former CEO of the Bengaluru-based company, &lt;a href=&quot;http://smartinvestor.business-standard.com/market/Compnews-441429-Compnewsdet-Automation_to_impact_Indian_jobs_the_most_Infosys_CEO_Vishal_Sikka.htm#.WjtLJ7T1XBI&quot;&gt;said in February&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, around 6,000 Indian employees at Cognizant &lt;a href=&quot;http://profit.ndtv.com/news/corporates/article-it-major-cognizant-likely-to-lay-off-6-000-employees-1671345&quot;&gt;reportedly lost their jobs&lt;/a&gt; to automation. Mumbai-based Tech Mahindra implemented a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.business-standard.com/article/companies/less-manpower-is-goal-says-tech-mahindra-s-vineet-nayyar-117110200135_1.html&quot;&gt;cost optimisation plan&lt;/a&gt; of increasing automation and reducing manpower. It turned ugly in July when the firm made headlines over a controversial audio clip that featured an HR personnel purportedly coercing an employee &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/it-employee-gets-fired-uploads-conversation-with-hr-on-social-media-2320069.html&quot;&gt;into quitting by 10am&lt;/a&gt; the next day, or risk being fired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, it wasn’t just about those at the bottom of the IT pyramid. Pink slips were doled out to even senior employees with outdated skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;“There is a change in the trend where automation has taken the driver’s seat to propel cost efficiency and utilisation of human resources for less mundane and routine work,” N Shivakumar, business head of recruitment process outsourcing at TeamLease, said.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Slamming the brakes on hiring&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the hiring front, too, bad news abounded. In 2017, campus hiring by IT companies fell by a massive 50-70%, Santanu Paul, CEO and managing director at skills training firm TalentSprint, told Quartz.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was mainly because companies changed their hiring practice: While earlier they’d hire freshers in bulk in anticipation of future contracts, the strategy has now shifted to just-in-time contract hiring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With revenue growth under stress, companies &lt;a href=&quot;https://qz.com/1002252/the-bench-in-indian-it-infosys-wipro-cognizant-look-to-reduce-underutilised-workers-not-on-projects/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;did not want to hold a bench&lt;/a&gt;—an employee pool on a company’s payroll, awaiting projects. “The focus shifted to increase in hiring of specialised talent or up-skilling existing (talent),” Incedo’s Paul said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For several years now, Indian IT firms have anyway been moving &lt;a href=&quot;http://in.reuters.com/article/usa-trump-india-tech-idINKBN13N05H&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;away from labour-intensive projects&lt;/a&gt; towards more remote and technology-based solutions such as video conferencing, cloud computing, and artificial intelligence (AI). This has resulted in hundreds of entry-level roles like data entry and server maintenance becoming obsolete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The IT job market is not as lucrative as it used to be and the dream run is over for the next few years,” DD Mishra, a research director at Gartner, said. “With IT service providers feeling the heat, the job market will remain under pressure for some more time.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In the long run, automation &lt;a href=&quot;https://qz.com/1070560/the-robots-will-actually-create-more-jobs-for-high-skilled-tech-workers-in-india/&quot;&gt;may increase the number of jobs available&lt;/a&gt; for workers with niche skill sets. But lower-level workers will continue to suffer. N&lt;/span&gt;early one-third (700,000) of the low-skilled workers in India’s IT sector stand to lose their jobs by 2022, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hfsresearch.com/market-analyses/impact-of-automation-and-ai-on-services-jobs-2016-2022&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;recent report&lt;/a&gt; (paywall) by market analysis firm HfS Research says. &lt;a href=&quot;https://qz.com/964843/less-than-5-of-india-engineers-are-cut-out-for-high-skill-programming-jobs/&quot;&gt;Less than 5% of Indian techies&lt;/a&gt; are equipped to handle high-skilled jobs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This dearth of trained talent is especially worrying as, within the next few years, roughly 40% of the less sophisticated tech jobs will be replaced by high-paying ones like data scientist and data analyst, estimates Kris Lakshmikanth, founder of recruitment firm Head Hunters India.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, the layoffs and lack of bankable employment prospects &lt;a href=&quot;https://qz.com/1042138/battling-job-loss-and-irrelevance-wrecked-indian-techies-are-seeking-emotional-help-online/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;wreaked mental and emotional havoc&lt;/a&gt; on employees as they battled a cash-crunch, anxiety, depression, low self-esteem, and lack of motivation. “Most IT sector employees are migrants, with little social support in their adoptive cities,” Dr BN Gangadhar of the National Institute of Mental Health and Neuro Sciences, Bengaluru, &lt;a href=&quot;http://content.time.com/time/business/article/0,8599,1737872,00.html&quot;&gt;told Time magazine&lt;/a&gt;. “Being young, they’re often single and lonely. If married, they have little time for their families. And when things go wrong, whether at work or at home, they have no one to turn to for help.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Side effects of “America First”&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Donald Trump’s arrival at the White House earlier this year hasn’t helped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since Trump took office, the fate of the H-1B, a six-year temporary work visa that Indian IT companies heavily depend on&lt;strong&gt;,&lt;/strong&gt; has been hanging fire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In March 2017, the US government &lt;a href=&quot;https://qz.com/924906/slowly-and-surely-the-donald-trump-government-has-begun-dismantling-the-h1b-visa/&quot;&gt;stalled the premium processing&lt;/a&gt; of this visa category.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The criteria for computer programmers to apply for the H-1B visa &lt;a href=&quot;https://qz.com/950090/trumps-new-h1-b-rules-will-end-era-of-cheap-indian-engineers-on-us-outsourcing-gigs/&quot;&gt;became tougher&lt;/a&gt;. In April, Trump signed the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whitehouse.gov/the-press-office/2017/04/18/presidential-executive-order-buy-american-and-hire-american&quot;&gt;“Buy American, Hire American” executive order,&lt;/a&gt; promising to bring jobs back to the country, putting migrant workers in jeopardy. In November, the judicial committee of the US House of Representatives gave its nod to the Protect and Grow American Jobs Act (titled HR 170) which classifies any company that has more 15% of its workforce working on-site as “visa-dependent.” With this, the pressure is mounting on Indian outsourcing giants which sometimes have over 50% of their manpower working on-site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even the current workers have cause for concern—to clamp down on visa fraud, the United States Customs and Immigration Services (USCIS) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.americanbazaaronline.com/2017/11/30/uscis-prepares-to-double-on-site-visits-to-detect-h-1b-visa-and-l-1-visa-frauds/&quot;&gt;plans to double the number of visits&lt;/a&gt; to workplaces. &lt;span&gt;“Indian IT companies, thus far champions of IT-based outsourcing, have been forced to go back to the drawing board in order to reposition themselves higher up in the value chain,” Anshul Prakash, a partner at Mumbai-based legal services firm Khaitan &amp;amp; Co, told Quartz.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;In the trenches&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IT companies have &lt;a href=&quot;https://qz.com/901292/indian-it-firms-like-wipro-tcs-and-infosys-have-been-preparing-for-changes-in-h1b-visa-laws-and-donald-trumps-america-for-several-years/&quot;&gt;tried to make fixes&lt;/a&gt; as &lt;a href=&quot;https://qz.com/963530/h-1b-its-not-just-trumps-america-indian-techies-are-unwanted-from-east-to-west/&quot;&gt;doors shut on Indian techies&lt;/a&gt;. “…there were concerted efforts on the part of larger IT companies to hire locally, and set up near-shore delivery centres,” said Sandeep Sharma, associate research manager of software and IT services at International Data Corporation (IDC) India. Other have &lt;a href=&quot;https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/tech/ites/fearing-tighter-us-visa-regime-tcs-infosys-and-wipro-rush-to-hire-acquire/articleshow/55659537.cms&quot;&gt;spent on acquisitions&lt;/a&gt;. These efforts may help stay afloat but job opportunities for Indians are still shrinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trepidation is unlikely to end anytime soon. By next year, automation will &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thehindubusinessline.com/info-tech/automation-to-kill-70-of-it-jobs/article9960555.ece&quot;&gt;put nearly 70%&lt;/a&gt; of the roles in the Indian IT workforce at risk, according to analysts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“After years of job creation in developing economies, the shoe is now on the other foot. Developed economies will be creating jobs for their own citizens in the foreseeable future,” TalentSprint’s Paul said. “India, on the other hand, will see high-value jobs being created, but not in high volume.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the choice between skill versus scale, companies will continue to lean on the former.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Much of the creative destruction will continue for a while and disruptions are inevitable over the next two to three years,” Mishra of Gartner said. “A positive shift will be visible from 2020 onwards and we expect to see new opportunities getting created out of the current disruptions.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: The post has been updated to reflect that TCS’s headcount rose after the April-June quarter.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article-aside&quot;&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;popular-stories-module&quot;&gt;&lt;article&gt;&lt;h4 class=&quot;module-title&quot;&gt;Most Popular&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://qz.com/1152683/indian-it-layoffs-in-2017-top-56000-led-by-tcs-infosys-cognizant/&quot; title=&quot;56,000 layoffs and counting: India’s IT bloodbath this year may just be the start&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://qzprod.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/rtxxw8x-e1514349325828.jpg?quality=80&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=240&quot; alt=&quot;An employee arrives at Tech Mahindra office building in Noida on the outskirts of New Delhi March 18, 2013. India's IT outsourcers are promoting &amp;quot;mini CEOs&amp;quot; capable of running businesses on their own, while trimming down on the hordes of entry-level computer coders they normally hire as they try to squeeze more profits out of their staff. To match Analysis INDIA-TECH/STAFFING Picture taken March 18, 2013. REUTERS/Adnan Abidi (INDIA - Tags: BUSINESS SCIENCE TECHNOLOGY EMPLOYMENT) - GM1E93P0CB401&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://qz.com/1152683/indian-it-layoffs-in-2017-top-56000-led-by-tcs-infosys-cognizant/&quot; title=&quot;56,000 layoffs and counting: India’s IT bloodbath this year may just be the start&quot;&gt;56,000 layoffs and counting: India’s IT bloodbath this year may just be the start&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;button class=&quot;read-full-story-button&quot;&gt;Read full story&lt;/button&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 07:40:40 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>codesternews</dc:creator>
<og:title>56,000 layoffs: India's IT bloodbath this year may just be the start</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://qzprod.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/rtxxw8x-e1514349325828.jpg?quality=80&amp;strip=all&amp;w=1600</og:image>
<og:url>https://qz.com/1152683/indian-it-layoffs-in-2017-top-56000-led-by-tcs-infosys-cognizant/</og:url>
<og:description>For Indian techies, 2017 was the stuff of nightmares.</og:description>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://qz.com/1152683/indian-it-layoffs-in-2017-top-56000-led-by-tcs-infosys-cognizant/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Candy Japan 2017 Year in Review</title>
<link>https://www.candyjapan.com/behind-the-scenes/2017-year-in-review</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.candyjapan.com/behind-the-scenes/2017-year-in-review</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Hello internets, Bemmu here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I run a site called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.candyjapan.com/&quot;&gt;Candy Japan&lt;/a&gt;, which ships boxes of Japanese surprise candies to subscribers around the world, twice a month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Five years ago I started writing these annual review posts after being inspired by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kalzumeus.com/2011/12/21/bingo-card-creator-etc-year-in-review-2011/&quot;&gt;patio11's year in review posts&lt;/a&gt;. They are a great way to reflect on each year, and inspire me to improve. In this one I'll start off with some background for those who haven't been following the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.candyjapan.com/behind-the-scenes&quot;&gt;previous ones&lt;/a&gt; and then proceed to the numbers for this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;My background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a computer science student in Finland I had a lot of side projects, with some of them generating some income as well. Learning Japanese has always been a major life goal for me. My minor subject was Japanese, and as part of my studies I spent 2 years as an exchange student in Tokyo. I was still eager to continue to improve, and wanted to live in Japan again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After graduating and having saved up some money, in 2011 I decided to make it happen and moved to Japan with my wife. She is from Japan, and I first met her when she was an exchange student at my university. We settled in Tokushima, which is a smallish city (by Japanese standards) in Shikoku island. The reason for picking Tokushima was the company she entered after graduating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though I had no job waiting for me in Tokushima, I could follow along as some online projects I had started in Finland were still generating revenue. Pretty soon however they started to dry up, so I had to come up with something new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Starting Candy Japan&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting to look for a new project, I recalled bouncing around some ideas with a friend while we had been on a holiday together. I had mentioned to him this website I had heard of called &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Birchbox#History&quot;&gt;BirchBox&lt;/a&gt;, a service that sends people makeup samples on a monthly basis. I thought it was an interesting model – a subscription not for software, but for surprises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is there anything we could send like that? Maybe introduce items from around Asia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we were both busy with other projects at the time, we didn't end up doing any of the ideas we had bounced around. But now that I found myself in Japan with free time to start something new, I decided to try it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With my wife's work locking her here in Tokushima, I didn't want to start traveling around the world to hunt for items, so I decided to find something I could just send from Japan instead. Anything would be fine at first, I could always expand later (&lt;em&gt;never did though&lt;/em&gt; ). What would be easy to try to send? I saw a lot of unique candies here, and looking into it I discovered that they were also &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_T2_80viWps&quot;&gt;trending on YouTube&lt;/a&gt;. So candy it was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I was an exchange student I had a side income from selling comic books (by using the university post office no less) from Japan to Finland, so I emailed those past customers to see if they would be interested in subscribing to candy. Two people agreed, so I started sending stuff to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next I put up a simple website. At first it was just a landing page, but over time as it grew, I &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.candyjapan.com/behind-the-scenes/how-many-lines-of-code-is-candy-japan&quot;&gt;wrote a bunch of code&lt;/a&gt; to automate things (no readymade solution existed back then). I submitted the website to Hacker News, where some bloggers spotted it and posted about it. Other bloggers saw those posts and reblogged it. This in turn caused the site to rank #1 in Google for the head term &quot;Japanese candy&quot;, sending even more visitors to the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Story up to 2016&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Hacker News post, blog mentions and Google rankings combined to mean that by the end of 2011 a total of 300 people had become subscribers. It turned out to be a stable number that lasted all the way to 2014. It wasn't just that people were subscribing for that long, but also new subscriptions were roughly matching the number of cancellations to keep the subscriber count stable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's a chart showing the number of members subscribing to Candy Japan:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Story up to 2016&quot; src=&quot;https://www.candyjapan.com/static/2016_chart_real.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might notice that in 2014 something wonderful happened: the subscriber count roughly tripled. I didn't do anything clever to make that happen, rather I got lifted by a wave as the whole concept of Japanese candy started to trend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below is a chart from Google Trends showing how many people were searching for japanese candy:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Story up to 2016&quot; src=&quot;https://www.candyjapan.com/static/candy_google_trends.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see the number of searches slowly builds, but from 2014 to 2015 it rapidly doubles, making it about three times as much as it had been in the early days. This was directly reflected in our subscriber count.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By no means was this still a big business, but Candy Japan alone could now cover &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.candyjapan.com/life-in-japan/what-it-costs-to-live-in-japan&quot;&gt;our living expenses&lt;/a&gt;, and I started to get hopeful that it could get bigger still.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next year in 2015 it seemed that my hopes were coming true; the subscriber count crossed 1200. Or so I thought. What seemed to be the best year ever turned out to be miserable: I discovered that I had been &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.candyjapan.com/candy-japan-hit-with-credit-card-fraud&quot;&gt;hit by credit card fraud&lt;/a&gt;. All those new subscribers beyond the first 800 were actually fakes who had subscribed with stolen credit card numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had already sent them the items, but now had to return all the money and on top of that pay a bunch of fees. Add insult to injury a lot of shipping addresses turned out to be fake as well, so I had hundreds of boxes returned to my address. Our mailbox was constantly swamped and our apartment was littered with returned boxes I had to manually examine to see if they were from legit subscribers or fakes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this fraud issue was going on, I was also in the process of moving my tax residency to Japan. It was a stressful year spent dealing with fraud and taxes. I even got a phone call from a US police officer after someone had complained to them about an unknown charge on their card, because their number had been stolen and someone used it to place a candy order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I survived, but discovered I don't handle stress quite as well as I thought I would. I was panicky and high-anxiety a lot of the time. I'd rather forget that year, but it did teach me a valuable lesson:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fraud is something that affects any business that accepts credit cards, &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.watsi.org/donation-fraud/&quot;&gt;even charities&lt;/a&gt;. Even if everything seems to be OK, make a habit of reading through new orders as they come in. Pay attention to email addresses, shipping addresses and bursts of failed payments. You can spot suspicious behavior if you do this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought I didn't have a problem, until thousands of dollars started getting reversed. While I did know that a small percentage of all ecommerce is fraud, I always understood that as fraud being interlaced with legit orders. 100 real payments, 1 fake payment, 100 real payments, 1 fake payment. But that's not how it played out. Rather it was 10000 real payments over years lulling you into believing that everything is fine, then suddenly getting hit by hundreds of fake payments in a matter of days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If 2015 was a high-anxiety year, 2016 was rather quiet by comparison. Subscriber numbers did continue to slide, as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.candyjapan.com/behind-the-scenes/nobodys-going-to-steal-your-idea&quot;&gt;competition was getting tough&lt;/a&gt; while also the overall interest in Japanese candy was waning. I ran some marketing experiments, but was unable to find any good channels. Japanese yen becoming increasingly expensive, forcing me to increase prices and leading to even less sales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;2017&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year was a bloodbath. From the start of 2017 to the end, subscribers declined by 40%, going from 636 to 385 members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's the subscriber chart extended to include 2017:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;2017&quot; src=&quot;https://www.candyjapan.com/static/2017-subscriber-chart.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Sales stats&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sales net of refunds: $141,220&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expenses: $102,846 (candy, shipping, boxes, ads)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Profit: $38,374&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wage per hour (assuming ~2 hours per day): ~$50&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Site stats&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visits: 138k&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unique visitors: 114k&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Page views: 241k&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traffic sources of note: Search engines (30%), Social media (22%), Paid ads (13%)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What went wrong?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year I didn't have as much to blog about. In 2016 I had five popular posts (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.candyjapan.com/behind-the-scenes/how-i-got-credit-card-fraud-somewhat-under-control&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.candyjapan.com/behind-the-scenes/results-from-box-design-ab-test&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.candyjapan.com/life-in-japan/%E5%8F%A3&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.candyjapan.com/behind-the-scenes/how-many-lines-of-code-is-candy-japan&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.candyjapan.com/behind-the-scenes/algorithmic-fitting-of-japanese-candy&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;), while in 2017 I only managed two (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.candyjapan.com/behind-the-scenes/sales-cross-million-dollars&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.candyjapan.com/behind-the-scenes/twice-as-happy-half-the-price&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;). The posts tend to send a lot of high-quality traffic, so the impact was bigger than you might expect. I haven't figured out how to invent posts from thin air when I simply have nothing new to share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organic search traffic declined from 68,383 clicks in 2016 to 41,358 clicks in 2017. I think the reason for this is twofold. First, competition is getting tougher, meaning there is fierce competition for head search terms. I have been pushed off the first page completely for some.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly overall searches for Japanese candy declined by 33% according to Google Trends, while on YouTube it more than halved. There was a point when a lot of YouTubers were doing a video showing their reactions to eating strange Japanese candy, but now that is ancient history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Changes in USDJPY exchange rates made me decide to increase USD prices. Naturally a higher price leads to less conversions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another major hit was that all the packages we were sending to Germany started bouncing back. After this continued for several shipments, I decided just not to ship to Germany any more. This meant losing 10% of subscribers and needing to send a lot of refunds for packages that never arrived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Things I tried&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tried paid YouTube ads, and while I did get some subscribers, in the end they were just too expensive to keep running. Tweaking the ads was very time consuming and expensive (but fun). I learned a lot though and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hs30WPkRpsY&quot;&gt;gave a presentation about it&lt;/a&gt; at a Hacker News meetup in Osaka. I managed to decrease their cost, but not enough to break even.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tried putting &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.candyjapan.com/past-boxes&quot;&gt;all of our old newsletters&lt;/a&gt; on the site. Had to reformat them by hand from ill-defined HTML newsletters to MarkDown. Attempts at automating with BeautifulSoup failed, as there was no coherent layout. I submitted them to webmaster tools, but this resulted in… silence. Less than one organic search click per day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;2017&quot; src=&quot;https://www.candyjapan.com/static/webmaster-tools-click-stats.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Improved response time by serving the landing page from a static file served by Google CDN instead of from Python. This may increase conversions slightly and could improve SEO, but there is still a lot of work to do to make the site faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tried to branch out by asked my customers if they would like to subscribe to Gashapon capsule toys, but the result was near-silence. I have a bimonthly newsletter with a great open rate, I wonder what other ideas I could throw at them?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tried redesigning the site to be more colorful and not so gloomy, but am not sure if it helped or hurt. I don't have enough data anymore to say for sure, as you need hundreds of conversions to say anything meaningful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tried to learn how to take better product photos for putting on the site to match what my competitors are doing, but was unable to take decent shots by myself. In the end hired a photographer to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;2017&quot; src=&quot;https://www.candyjapan.com/static/candy_japan_october_2017.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pictures look good, and will probably boost conversions a bit. Again I can't be sure of the impact due to lack of data. Who knows, maybe visitors might feel that seeing the products ruins the surprise or something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish I could report having discovered some kind of a breakthrough marketing trick to reverse the decline, but sadly no.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the time being &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.candyjapan.com/&quot;&gt;Candy Japan&lt;/a&gt; is still popular enough to keep running, and since I have most things automated I see no reason to shut it down. If the trends of declining popularity of Japanese candy and increasing competition continue, 2018 will be another down year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will start spending more time trying new projects again. Hopefully nothing involving physical products this time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading, and do &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.candyjapan.com/&quot;&gt;subscribe&lt;/a&gt; if you'd like to try some candy for yourself. You can use the code HACKERNEWS to get 10% off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.candyjapan.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Conclusion&quot; src=&quot;https://www.candyjapan.com/static/illustration-4.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 05:55:52 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>hamstercat</dc:creator>
<og:title>Candy Japan 2017 Year in Review</og:title>
<og:description>This was another tough year for Candy Japan, with many factors combining to a sharp decline in subscriber numbers. Contains revenue numbers, site statistics and learnings from 2017.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.candyjapan.com/behind-the-scenes/2017-year-in-review</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://www.candyjapan.com/static/2017-year-in-review-illustration.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.candyjapan.com/behind-the-scenes/2017-year-in-review</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>