<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Popular iPhone apps caught sending user location data to monetization firms</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/07/a-dozen-popular-iphone-apps-caught-quietly-sending-user-locations-to-monetization-firms/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/07/a-dozen-popular-iphone-apps-caught-quietly-sending-user-locations-to-monetization-firms/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;A group of security researchers say dozens of popular iPhone apps are quietly sharing the location data of “tens of millions of mobile devices” with third-party data monetization firms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost all require access to a user’s location data to work properly, like weather and fitness apps, but share that data often as a way to generate revenue for free-to-download apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In many cases, the apps send precise locations and other sensitive, identifiable data “at all times, constantly,” and often with “little to no mention” that location data will be shared with third-parties, say security researchers &lt;a href=&quot;https://guardianapp.com/ios-app-location-report-sep2018.html&quot;&gt;at the GuardianApp project&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I believe people should be able to use any app they wish on their phone without fear that granting access to sensitive data may mean that this data will be quietly sent off to some entity who they do not know and do not have any desire to do business with,” said Will Strafach, one of the researchers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using tools to monitor network traffic, the researchers found 24 popular iPhone apps that were collecting location data — like Bluetooth beacons to Wi-Fi network names — to know where a person is and where they visit. These data monetization firms also collect other device data from the accelerometer, battery charge status and cell network names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In exchange for data, often these data firms pay app developers to collect data and grow their databases and often to deliver ads based on a person’s location history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But although many claim they don’t collect personally identifiable information, Strafach said that latitude and longitude coordinates can pin a person to a house or their work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To name a few:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/askfm-ask-anonymous-questions/id635896473?mt=8&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ASKfm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a teen-focused anonymous question-and-answer app, has 1,400 ratings on the Apple App Store and touts tens of millions of users. It asks for access to a user’s location that “won’t be shared with anyone.” But the app sends that location data to two data firms, AreaMetrics and Huq. When reached, the app maker said it believes its location collection practices “fit industry standards, and are therefore acceptable for our users.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/noaa-weather-radar/id749133753?mt=8&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOAA Weather Radar&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; has more than 266,000 reviews and has millions of downloads. Access to your location “is used to provide weather info.” But an earlier version of the app from March was sending location data to three firms, Factual, Sense360 and Teemo. The code has since been removed. A spokesperson for Apalon, which built the app, said it “conducted a limited, brief test with a few of these providers” earlier this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/homes-for-sale-rent/id306423353?mt=8&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Homes.com&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a popular app that asks that you switch on your location to help “find nearby homes.” But the code, thought to be old code, still sends precise coordinates to AreaMetrics. The app maker said it used AreaMetrics “for a short period” last year but said the code was deactivated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/perfect365/id475976577?mt=8&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perfect365&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, an augmented reality beauty app with more than 100 million users, asks for location to “customize your experience based on your location and more,” and refers users &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.perfect365.com/about/privacy-policy&quot;&gt;to the privacy policy&lt;/a&gt; for more — which does state that location data will be used for advertising. The app was briefly pulled &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/nicolenguyen/how-apps-take-your-data-and-sell-it-without-you-even&quot;&gt;after a BuzzFeed News story&lt;/a&gt; earlier this year outed the researchers, but returned to the app store days later. The current app version contains code for eight separate data monetization firms in the latest version of the app. The app maker did not return a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the list goes on — including more than a hundred Sinclair-owned local news and weather apps, which share location data with Reveal, a data tracking and monetization firm, &lt;a href=&quot;https://revealmobile.com/2015930reveal-mobile-and-sinclair-broadcast-group-partner-for-mobile-audience-data-and-ad-targeting/&quot;&gt;which the company says&lt;/a&gt; will help the media giant bolster its sales by “providing advertisers with target audiences.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That can quickly become a lucrative business for developers with popular apps and monetization firms alike, some of which collect billions of locations each day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the data monetization firms deny any wrongdoing and say that users can opt out at any time. Most said that they demand that app makers explicitly state that they require app developers to explicitly state that they are collecting and sending data to third-party firms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team’s research shows that those requirements are almost never verified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reveal said it requires customers “state the use cases for location data in their privacy policy” and that users can opt-out at any time. Huq, like Reveal, said it carries out “regular checks on our partner apps to ensure that they have implemented” measures that explain the company’s services. AreaMetrics, which collects primarily Bluetooth beacon data from public areas like coffee shops and retail stores, says it has “no interest” in receiving personal data from users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/sense360&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;sense360&quot;&gt;Sense360&lt;/a&gt; said the data it collects is anonymous and requires apps to get explicit consent from its users, but Strafach said few apps he’s seen contained text that sought assurances. But the company did not answer a specific question why it no longer works with certain apps. Wireless Registry said it also requires apps seek consent from users, but would not comment on the security measures it uses to ensure user privacy. And in remarks, inMarket said it follows advertising standards and guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/cuebiq&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;cuebiq&quot;&gt;Cuebiq&lt;/a&gt; claims to use an “advanced cryptography method” to store and transmit data, but Strafach said he found “no evidence” that any data was scrambled. It says it’s not a “tracker” but says while some app developers look to monetize users’ data, most are said to use it for insights. And, &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/factual&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;factual&quot;&gt;Factual&lt;/a&gt; said it uses location data for advertising and analytics, but must obtain in-app consent from users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When reached, &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/databerries&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;databerries&quot;&gt;Teemo&lt;/a&gt; did not answer our questions. SafeGraph, &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/mobiquity&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;mobiquity&quot;&gt;Mobiquity&lt;/a&gt; and Fysical did not respond to requests for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“None of these companies appear to be legally accountable for their claims and practices, instead there is some sort of self-regulation they claim to enforce,” said Strafach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He said there isn’t much users can do, but limiting ad tracking in your iPhone’s privacy settings can make it more difficult for location trackers to identify users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple’s crackdown on apps that don’t have privacy policies kicks in next month. But given how few people read them in the first place, don’t expect apps to change their behavior any time soon.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 23:58:41 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tareqak</dc:creator>
<og:title>Dozens of popular iPhone apps caught sending user location data to monetization firms</og:title>
<og:description>A group of security researchers say dozens of popular iPhone apps are quietly sharing the location data of “tens of millions of mobile devices” with third-party data monetization firms. Almost all require access to a user’s location data to work properly, like weather and fitness …</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/GettyImages-578768440.jpg?w=600</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2018/09/07/a-dozen-popular-iphone-apps-caught-quietly-sending-user-locations-to-monetization-firms/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/07/a-dozen-popular-iphone-apps-caught-quietly-sending-user-locations-to-monetization-firms/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Academic Activists Send a Published Paper Down the Memory Hole</title>
<link>https://quillette.com/2018/09/07/academic-activists-send-a-published-paper-down-the-memory-hole/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://quillette.com/2018/09/07/academic-activists-send-a-published-paper-down-the-memory-hole/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;In the highly controversial area of human intelligence, the ‘Greater Male Variability Hypothesis’ (GMVH) asserts that there are more idiots and more geniuses among men than among women. Darwin’s research on evolution in the nineteenth century found that, although there are many exceptions for specific traits and species, there is generally more variability in males than in females of the same species throughout the animal kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Evidence for this hypothesis is fairly robust and has been reported in species ranging from adders and sockeye salmon to wasps and orangutans, as well as humans. Multiple studies have found that boys and men are over-represented at both the high and low ends of the distributions in categories ranging from birth weight and brain structures and 60-meter dash times to reading and mathematics test scores. There are significantly more men than women, for example, among Nobel laureates, music composers, and chess champions—and also among homeless people, suicide victims, and federal prison inmates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Darwin had also raised the question of &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; males in many species might have evolved to be more variable than females, and when I learned that the answer to his question remained elusive, I set out to look for a scientific explanation. My aim was not to prove or disprove that the hypothesis applies to human intelligence or to any other specific traits or species, but simply to discover a &lt;em&gt;logical&lt;/em&gt; reason that could help explain how gender differences in variability might naturally arise in the same species.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I came up with a simple intuitive mathematical argument based on biological and evolutionary principles and enlisted Sergei Tabachnikov, a Professor of Mathematics at Pennsylvania State University, to help me flesh out the model. When I posted a preprint on the open-access mathematics archives in May of last year, a variability researcher at Durham University in the UK got in touch by email. He described our joint paper as “an excellent summary of the research to date in this field,” adding that “it certainly underpins my earlier work on impulsivity, aggression and general evolutionary theory and it is nice to see an actual theoretical model that can be drawn upon in discussion (which I think the literature, particularly in education, has lacked to date). I think this is a welcome addition to the field.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, so good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once we had written up our findings, Sergei and I decided to try for publication in the &lt;em&gt;Mathematical Intelligencer&lt;/em&gt;, the ‘Viewpoint’ section of which specifically welcomes articles on contentious topics. The &lt;em&gt;Intelligencer&lt;/em&gt;’s editor-in-chief is Marjorie Wikler Senechal, Professor Emerita of Mathematics and the History of Science at Smith College. She liked our draft, and declared herself to be untroubled by the prospect of controversy. “In principle,” she told Sergei in an email, “I am happy to stir up controversy and few topics generate more than this one. After the Middlebury fracas, in which none of the protestors had read the book they were protesting, we could make a real contribution here by insisting that all views be heard, and providing links to them.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Professor Senechal suggested that we might enliven our paper by mentioning Harvard President Larry Summers, who was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2005/02/why-feminist-careerists-neutered-larry-summers/303795/&quot;&gt;swiftly defenestrated in 2005&lt;/a&gt; for saying that the GMVH might be a contributing factor to the dearth of women in physics and mathematics departments at top universities. With her editorial guidance, our paper underwent several further revisions until, on April 3, 2017, our manuscript was officially accepted for publication. The paper was typeset in India, and proofread by an assistant editor who is also a mathematics professor in Kansas. It was scheduled to appear in the international journal’s first issue of 2018, with an acknowledgement of funding support to my co-author from the National Science Foundation. All normal academic procedure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*     *     *&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coincidentally, at about the same time, anxiety about gender-parity erupted in Silicon Valley. The same anti-variability argument used to justify the sacking of President Summers resurfaced when Google engineer James Damore suggested that several innate biological factors, including gender differences in variability, might help explain gender disparities in Silicon Valley hi-tech jobs. For sending out an internal memo to that effect, he too &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Google%27s_Ideological_Echo_Chamber&quot;&gt;was summarily fired&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No sooner had Sergei posted a preprint of our accepted article on his website than we began to encounter problems. On August 16, a representative of the Women In Mathematics (WIM) chapter in his department at Penn State contacted him to warn that the paper might be damaging to the aspirations of impressionable young women. “As a matter of principle,” she wrote, “I support people discussing controversial matters openly … At the same time, I think it’s good to be aware of the effects.” While &lt;em&gt;she&lt;/em&gt; was obviously able to debate the merits of our paper, she worried that other, presumably less sophisticated, readers “will just see someone wielding the authority of mathematics to support a very controversial, and potentially sexist, set of ideas…”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few days later, she again contacted Sergei on behalf of WIM and invited him to attend a lunch that had been organized for a “frank and open discussion” about our paper. He would be allowed 15 minutes to describe and explain our results, and this short presentation would be followed by readings of prepared statements by WIM members and then an open discussion. “We promise to be friendly,” she announced, “but you should know in advance that many (most?) of us have strong disagreements with what you did.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On September 4, Sergei sent me a weary email. “The scandal at our department,” he wrote, “shows no signs of receding.” At a faculty meeting the week before, the Department Head had explained that sometimes values such as academic freedom and free speech come into conflict with other values to which Penn State was committed. A female colleague had then instructed Sergei that he needed to admit and fight bias, adding that the belief that “women have a lesser chance to succeed in mathematics at the very top end is bias.” Sergei said he had spent “endless hours” talking to people who explained that the paper was “bad and harmful” and tried to convince him to “withdraw my name to restore peace at the department and to avoid losing whatever political capital I may still have.” Ominously, “analogies with scientific racism were made by some; I am afraid, we are likely to hear more of it in the future.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following day, I wrote to the three organisers of the WIM lunch and offered to address any concrete concerns they might have with our logic or conclusions or any other content. I explained that, since I was the paper’s lead author, it was not fair that my colleague should be expected to take all the heat for our findings. I added that it would still be possible to revise our article before publication. I never received a response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, on September 8, Sergei and I were ambushed by two unexpected developments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, the National Science Foundation wrote to Sergei requesting that acknowledgment of NSF funding be removed from our paper with immediate effect. I was astonished. I had never before heard of the NSF requesting removal of acknowledgement of funding for any reason. On the contrary, they are usually delighted to have public recognition of their support for science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ostensible reason for this request was that our paper was unrelated to Sergei’s funded proposal. However, a Freedom of Information request subsequently revealed that Penn State WIM administrator Diane Henderson (“Professor and Chair of the Climate and Diversity Committee”) and Nate Brown (“Professor and Associate Head for Diversity and Equity”) had secretly co-signed a letter to the NSF that same morning. “Our concern,” they explained, “is that [this] paper appears to promote pseudoscientific ideas that are detrimental to the advancement of women in science, and at odds with the values of the NSF.” Unaware of this at the time, and eager to err on the side of compromise, Sergei and I agreed to remove the acknowledgement as requested. At least, we thought, the paper was still on track to be published.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, that same day, the &lt;em&gt;Mathematical Intelligencer&lt;/em&gt;’s editor-in-chief Marjorie Senechal notified us that, with “deep regret,” she was rescinding her previous acceptance of our paper. “Several colleagues,” she wrote, had warned her that publication would provoke “extremely strong reactions” and there existed a “very real possibility that the right-wing media may pick this up and hype it internationally.” For the second time in a single day I was left flabbergasted. Working mathematicians are usually thrilled if even five people in the world read our latest article. Now some progressive faction was worried that a fairly straightforward logical argument about male variability might encourage the conservative press to actually read and cite a science paper?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my 40 years of publishing research papers I had never heard of the rejection of an already-accepted paper. And so I emailed Professor Senechal. She replied that she had received no criticisms on scientific grounds and that her decision to rescind was entirely about the reaction she feared our paper would elicit. By way of further explanation, Senechal even compared our paper to the Confederate statues that had recently been removed from the courthouse lawn in Lexington, Kentucky. In the interests of setting our arguments in a more responsible context, she proposed instead that Sergei and I participate in a ‘Round Table’ discussion of our hypothesis argument, the proceedings of which the &lt;em&gt;Intelligencer&lt;/em&gt; would publish in lieu of our paper. Her decision, we learned, enjoyed the approval of Springer, one of the world’s leading publishers of scientific books and journals. An editorial director of Springer Mathematics later apologized to me twice, in person, but did nothing to reverse the decision or to support us at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what in the world had happened at the &lt;em&gt;Intelligencer&lt;/em&gt;? Unbeknownst to us, Amie Wilkinson, a senior professor of mathematics at the University of Chicago, had become aware of our paper and written to the journal to complain. A back-and-forth had ensued. Wilkinson then enlisted the support of her father—a psychometrician and statistician—who wrote to the &lt;em&gt;Intelligencer&lt;/em&gt; at his daughter’s request to express his own misgivings, including his belief that “[t]his article oversimplifies the issues to the point of embarrassment.” Invited by Professor Senechal to participate in the proposed Round Table discussion, he declined, admitting to Senechal that “others are more expert on this than he is.” We discovered all this after he gave Senechal permission to forward his letter, inadvertently revealing Wilkinson’s involvement in the process (an indiscretion his daughter would later—incorrectly—blame on the &lt;em&gt;Intelligencer&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote polite emails directly to both Wilkinson and her father, explaining that I planned to revise the paper for resubmission elsewhere and asking for their criticisms or suggestions. (I also sent a more strongly worded, point-by-point rebuttal to her father.) Neither replied. Instead, even long after the &lt;em&gt;Intelligencer&lt;/em&gt; rescinded acceptance of the paper, Wilkinson continued to trash both the journal and its editor-in-chief on social media, inciting her &lt;em&gt;Facebook&lt;/em&gt; friends with the erroneous allegation that an entirely different (and more contentious) article had been accepted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, faced with career-threatening reprisals from their own departmental colleagues and the diversity committee at Penn State, as well as displeasure from the NSF, Sergei and his colleague who had done computer simulations for us withdrew their names from the research. Fortunately for me, I am now retired and rather less easily intimidated—one of the benefits of being a Vietnam combat veteran and former U.S. Army Ranger, I guess. So, I continued to revise the paper, and finally &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1703.04184.pdf&quot;&gt;posted it on the online mathematics archives&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*     *     *&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On October 13, a lifeline appeared. Igor Rivin, an editor at the widely respected online research journal, the &lt;em&gt;New York Journal of Mathematics&lt;/em&gt;, got in touch with me. He had learned about the article from my erstwhile co-author, read the archived version, and asked me if I’d like to submit a newly revised draft for publication. Rivin said that Mark Steinberger, the &lt;em&gt;NYJM&lt;/em&gt;’s editor-in-chief, was also very positive and that they were confident the paper could be refereed fairly quickly. I duly submitted a new draft (this time as the sole author) and, after a very positive referee’s report and a handful of supervised revisions, Steinberger wrote to confirm publication on November 6, 2017. Relieved that the ordeal was finally over, I forwarded the link to interested colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three days later, however, the paper had vanished. And a few days after that, a completely different paper by different authors appeared at &lt;em&gt;exactly the same page of the same volume&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;NYJM&lt;/em&gt; Volume 23, p 1641+) where mine had once been. As it turned out, Amie Wilkinson is married to Benson Farb, a member of the &lt;em&gt;NYJM&lt;/em&gt; editorial board. Upon discovering that the journal had published my paper, Professor Farb had written a furious email to Steinberger demanding that it be deleted at once. “Rivin,” he complained, “is well-known as a person with extremist views who likes to pick fights with people via inflammatory statements.” Farb’s “father-in law…a famous statistician,” he went on, had “already poked many holes in the ridiculous paper.” My paper was “politically charged” and “pseudoscience” and “a piece of crap” and, by encouraging the &lt;em&gt;NYJM&lt;/em&gt; to accept it, Rivin had “violat[ed] a scientific duty for purely political ends.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unaware of any of this, I wrote to Steinberger on November 14, to find out what had happened. I pointed out that if the deletion were permanent, it would leave me in an impossible position. I would not be able to republish anywhere else because I would be unable to sign a copyright form declaring that it had not already been published elsewhere. Steinberger replied later that day. Half his board, he explained unhappily, had told him that unless he pulled the article, they would all resign and “harass the journal” he had founded 25 years earlier “until it died.” Faced with the loss of his own scientific legacy, he had capitulated. “A publication in a dead journal,” he offered, “wouldn’t help you.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*     *     *&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colleagues I spoke to were appalled. None of them had ever heard of a paper in any field being disappeared after formal publication. Rejected prior to publication? Of course. Retracted? Yes, but only after an investigation, the results of which would then be made public by way of explanation. But simply &lt;em&gt;disappeared&lt;/em&gt;? Never. If a formally refereed and published paper can later be erased from the scientific record and replaced by a completely different article, without any discussion with the author or any announcement in the journal, what will this mean for the future of electronic journals?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Professor Wilkinson had now widened her existing social media campaign against the &lt;em&gt;Intelligencer&lt;/em&gt; to include attacks on the &lt;em&gt;NYJM&lt;/em&gt; and its editorial staff. As recently as April of this year, she was threatening Facebook friends with ‘unfriending’ unless they severed social media ties with Rivin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In early February, a friend and colleague suggested that I write directly to University of Chicago President Robert Zimmer to complain about the conduct of Farb and Wilkinson, both of whom are University of Chicago professors. The previous October, the conservative &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt; columnist Bret Stephens &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/10/20/opinion/robert-zimmer-chicago-speech.html&quot;&gt;had called Zimmer&lt;/a&gt; “America’s Best University President.” The week after I wrote to Zimmer, the &lt;em&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt; would &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/the-free-speech-university-1518824261&quot;&gt;describe Chicago&lt;/a&gt; as “The Free-Speech University” based upon its president’s professed commitment to the principles of free inquiry and expression. Furthermore, Professor Zimmer is a mathematician from the same department and even the same subfield as Farb and Wilkinson, the husband-wife team who had successfully suppressed my variability hypothesis research and trampled on the principles of academic liberty. Surely I would receive a sympathetic hearing there?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so I wrote directly to Professor Zimmer, mathematician to mathematician, detailing five concrete allegations against his two colleagues. When I eventually received a formal response in late April, it was a somewhat terse official letter from the vice-provost informing me that an inquiry had found no evidence of “academic fraud” and that, consequently, “the charges have been dismissed.” But I had made no allegation of academic fraud. I had alleged “unprofessional, uncollegial, and unethical conduct damaging to my professional reputation and to the reputation of the University of Chicago.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I appealed the decision to the president, I received a second official letter from the vice-provost, in which he argued that Farb and Wilkinson had “exercised their academic freedom in advocating against the publication of the papers” and that their behavior had not been either “unethical or unprofessional.” A reasonable inference is that I was the one interfering in their academic freedom and not vice versa. My quarrel, the vice-provost concluded, was with the editors-in-chief who had spiked my papers, decisions for which the University of Chicago bore no responsibility. At the Free Speech University, it turns out, talk is cheap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*     *     *&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the years there has undoubtedly been significant bias and discrimination against women in mathematics and technical fields. Unfortunately, some of that still persists, even though many of us have tried hard to help turn the tide. My own efforts have included tutoring and mentoring female undergraduates, graduating female PhD students, and supporting hiring directives from deans and departmental chairs to seek out and give special consideration to female candidates. I have been invited to serve on two National Science Foundation gender and race diversity panels in Washington.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which is to say that I understand the importance of the causes that equal opportunity activists and progressive academics are ostensibly championing. But pursuit of greater fairness and equality cannot be allowed to interfere with dispassionate academic study. No matter how unwelcome the implications of a logical argument may be, it must be allowed to stand or fall on its merits not its desirability or political utility. First Harvard, then Google, and now the editors-in-chief of two esteemed scientific journals, the National Science Foundation, and the international publisher Springer have all surrendered to demands from the radical academic Left to suppress a controversial idea. Who will be the next, and for what perceived transgression? If bullying and censorship are now to be re-described as ‘advocacy’ and ‘academic freedom,’ as the Chicago administrators would have it, they will simply replace empiricism and rational discourse as the academic instruments of choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Educators must practice what we preach and lead by example. In this way, we can help to foster intellectual curiosity and the discovery of fresh reasoning so compelling that it causes even the most sceptical to change their minds. But this necessarily requires us to reject censorship and open ourselves to the civil discussion of sensitive topics such as gender differences, and the variability hypothesis in particular. In 2015, the University of Chicago’s Committee on Freedom of Expression summarized the importance of this principle beautifully &lt;a href=&quot;https://freeexpression.uchicago.edu/sites/freeexpression.uchicago.edu/files/FOECommitteeReport.pdf&quot;&gt;in a report&lt;/a&gt; commissioned by none other than Professor Robert Zimmer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a word, the University’s fundamental commitment is to the principle that debate or deliberation may not be suppressed because the ideas put forth are thought by some or even by most members of the University community to be offensive, unwise, immoral, or wrong-headed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ted Hill is Professor Emeritus of Mathematics at Georgia Tech, and currently a research scholar in residence at the California Polytechnic State University in San Luis Obispo. His memoir &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2CERP8K&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PUSHING LIMITS: From West Point to Berkeley and Beyond&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; was recently published jointly by the American Mathematical Society and the Mathematical Association of America.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;cb_p6_patreon_button&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cb_p6_message_over_post_button&quot;&gt;If you liked this article please consider becoming a patron of Quillette&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.patreon.com/Quillette&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/quillette.com/wp-content/plugins/patron-button-and-widgets-by-codebard/images/become_a_patron_button.png?w=1023&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;robots-nocontent sd-block sd-social sd-social-official sd-sharing&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Share this:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;quads-location quads-ad6&quot; id=&quot;quads-ad6&quot;/&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 23:09:19 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>alexmat</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Academic Activists Send a Published Paper Down the Memory Hole - Quillette</og:title>
<og:description>In the highly controversial area of human intelligence, the ‘Greater Male Variability Hypothesis’ (GMVH) asserts that there are more idiots and more geniuses among men than among women. Darwin’s research on evolution in the nineteenth century found that, although there are many exceptions for specific traits and species, there is generally more variability in males than in females of the same species throughout the animal kingdom. Evidence for this hypothesis is fairly robust and has been reported in species ranging from adders and sockeye salmon to wasps and orangutans, as well as humans. Multiple studies have found that boys and men are over-represented at both the high and low ends of the distributions in categories ranging from birth weight and brain structures and 60-meter dash times to reading and mathematics test scores. There are significantly more men than women, for example, among Nobel laureates, music composers, and chess champions—and also among homeless people, suicide victims, and federal prison inmates. Darwin had also raised the question of why males in many species might have evolved to …</og:description>
<og:url>https://quillette.com/2018/09/07/academic-activists-send-a-published-paper-down-the-memory-hole/</og:url>
<og:image>https://i0.wp.com/d24fkeqntp1r7r.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/07020822/AdobeStock_61396442.jpeg?fit=1200%2C800&amp;ssl=1</og:image>
<dc:language>en-AU</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://quillette.com/2018/09/07/academic-activists-send-a-published-paper-down-the-memory-hole/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Jack Ma to Retire from Alibaba</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/09/07/technology/alibaba-jack-ma-retiring.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2018/09/07/technology/alibaba-jack-ma-retiring.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;44.352860096485&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;36.245348035837&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;HONG KONG — Alibaba’s co-founder and executive chairman, Jack Ma, said he planned to step down from the Chinese e-commerce giant on Monday to pursue philanthropy in education, a changing of the guard for the $420 billion internet company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2014/05/08/technology/the-unlikely-ascent-of-jack-ma-alibabas-founder.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;A former English teacher&lt;/a&gt;, Mr. Ma started Alibaba in 1999 and built it into one of the world’s most consequential e-commerce and digital payments companies, transforming how Chinese people shop and pay for things. That fueled his net worth to more than $40 billion, making him China’s richest man. He is revered by many Chinese, some of whom have put his portrait in their homes to worship in the same way that they worship the God of Wealth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Ma is retiring as China’s business environment has soured, with Beijing and state-owned enterprises increasingly playing more interventionist roles with companies. Under President Xi Jinping, China’s internet industry has grown and become more important, prompting the government to tighten its leash. The Chinese economy is also facing slowing growth and increasing debt, and the country is embroiled in an &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/09/07/business/trump-china-trade-war-tariffs.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;escalating trade war with the United States&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“He’s a symbol of the health of China’s private sector and how high they can fly whether he likes it or not,” Duncan Clark, author of the book “Alibaba: The House Jack Ma Built,” said of Mr. Ma. “His retirement will be interpreted as frustration or concern whether he likes it or not.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;47.148066298343&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;41.909392265193&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;In an interview, Mr. Ma said his retirement is not the end of an era but “the beginning of an era.” He said he would be spending more of his time and fortune focused on education. “I love education,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Ma will remain on Alibaba’s board of directors and continue to mentor the company’s management. Mr. Ma turns 54 on Monday, which is also a holiday in China known as Teacher’s Day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The retirement makes Mr. Ma one of the first founders among a generation of prominent Chinese internet entrepreneurs to step down from their companies. Firms including Alibaba, Tencent, Baidu and JD.com have flourished in recent years, growing to nearly rival American internet behemoths like Amazon and Google in their size, scope and ambition. For Chinese tycoons to step aside in their 50s is rare; they usually remain at the top of their organizations for many years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The departure of Mr. Ma is likely to jolt China’s internet industry, which has been reeling from the &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/09/04/technology/jdcom-richard-liu-arrest-rape.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;arrest last weekend of Liu Qiangdong&lt;/a&gt;, the billionaire founder of the online retailer JD.com. Mr. Liu, who goes by Richard Liu in the English-speaking world, was arrested on a rape allegation in Minneapolis during a business trip. He was released and has since returned to Beijing, where JD.com is based.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;For Alibaba, Mr. Ma’s retirement completes a transition of power to other executives. Mr. Ma stepped down as Alibaba’s chief executive in 2013; the company’s current &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2015/05/08/business/international/alibaba-q4-earnings-new-ceo.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;chief executive is Daniel Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, who is a candidate to succeed Mr. Ma. Yet Mr. Ma had remained active as the face of the e-commerce firm, as well as an architect of its long-term strategy. He owns &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://otp.investis.com/clients/us/alibaba/SEC/sec-show.aspx?Type=page&amp;amp;FilingId=12879202-870682-963516&amp;amp;CIK=0001577552&amp;amp;Index=11800&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a 6.4 percent stake&lt;/a&gt; of Alibaba, according to securities filings, but has considerably more sway over the company thanks to its complicated legal structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;50.089014222658&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;48.684649337911&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Ma, a natural salesman and charismatic leader, co-founded Alibaba with 17 others — some of them his students — out of his apartment in Hangzhou in eastern Zhejiang province in 1999.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Alibaba started as an online marketplace for businesses to sell their products to other businesses. But it did not take off until it began the Taobao marketplace in 2003, which merchants used to sell goods directly to consumers. Alibaba later rolled out Alipay, an online payment service, to facilitate transactions in a country where few people had credit cards. Alipay later became Ant Financial, the financial subsidiary that Mr. Ma also controls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Today, Alibaba’s empire encompasses e-commerce, online banking, cloud computing, digital media and entertainment — and even a corporate messaging service similar to Slack. The company owns or holds stakes in some of China’s most important media assets, including the Twitter-like social media site Weibo and the Hong Kong-based English-language newspaper The South China Morning Post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Among China’s biggest companies, Alibaba is viewed as one of the firms with the deepest ranks of management talent. Many of the co-founders are still around, and professionals who joined the company later are now in charge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Last month, Alibaba &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/08/23/technology/alibaba-earnings.html?rref=collection%2Ftimestopic%2FAlibaba&amp;amp;action=click&amp;amp;contentCollection=business&amp;amp;region=stream&amp;amp;module=stream_unit&amp;amp;version=latest&amp;amp;contentPlacement=2&amp;amp;pgtype=collection&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;reported a 60 percent increase&lt;/a&gt; in quarterly sales, even as profits fell. The company’s annual revenue totals about 250 billion yuan, or $40 billion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;While Alibaba has become dominant in China, it has faced a tougher time expanding internationally. The company has increased its presence outside of China by investing in e-commerce and online finance companies in India and Southeast Asia. But its efforts to muscle into the United States largely have not been successful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Even after &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/video/business/100000004861537/trump-and-alibabas-founder.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Mr. Ma met with President-elect Donald J. Trump&lt;/a&gt; in early 2017 and promised to bring one million jobs to the United States, the federal government rejected Ant Financial’s bid to &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/01/02/business/moneygram-ant-financial-china-cfius.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;acquire the American money transfer company MoneyGram&lt;/a&gt; this year over national security concerns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;44.359550561798&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;36.808988764045&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;As Beijing has increased its involvement in the private sector, Mr. Ma has shifted what he has said about China’s government. He used to say that businesses should be in love with the government but never get married to each other, indicating that an arms-length relationship was preferred.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;At a conference last November, Mr. Ma was more positive. “There’s no country like China in the world,” he said. “With political stability, social safety and 6 percent-plus economic growth, we have the best business environment.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;As Alibaba has flourished, Mr. Ma has talked many times about how he did not want to spend his whole life at the company, saying he would retire one day and go back to teaching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;In 2014, he created the Jack Ma Foundation, which has worked to improve education in rural China. Mr. Ma’s Weibo social media handle is “spokesman for village teachers — Jack Ma.” Within Alibaba, he is known and referred to as “Teacher Ma.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;In an &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-09-06/billionaire-jack-ma-prepares-for-life-after-alibaba&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;interview with Bloomberg TV this week&lt;/a&gt;, Mr. Ma signaled he was thinking about focusing more on philanthropy. He cited the Microsoft co-founder and philanthropist Bill Gates as an example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Ma said he could never be as rich as Mr. Gates — but that he could retire earlier than Mr. Gates. Mr. Gates &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2014/02/05/technology/new-boss-at-microsoft-with-gates-at-his-side.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;stepped down as Microsoft’s chairman&lt;/a&gt; in 2014, at the age of 58.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;28.427295918367&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;css-k8fkhk&quot; readability=&quot;8.3333333333333&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Follow Li Yuan on Twitter: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/LiYuan6&quot;&gt;@LiYuan6&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interested in All Things Tech?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/newsletters/signup/TU&quot;&gt;Get the Bits newsletter&lt;/a&gt; delivered to your inbox weekly for the latest from Silicon Valley and the technology industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-3glrhn&quot; readability=&quot;7.3317073170732&quot;&gt;A version of this article appears in print on , on Page B1 of the New York edition with the headline: Founder Sees A ‘Beginning’ As He Retires From Alibaba&lt;span&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytreprints.com/&quot;&gt;Order Reprints&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/pages/todayspaper/index.html&quot;&gt;Today’s Paper&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/subscriptions/Multiproduct/lp8HYKU.html?campaignId=48JQY&quot;&gt;Subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 22:54:38 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tysone</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/09/07/technology/alibaba-jack-ma-retiring.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Alibaba’s Jack Ma, China’s Richest Man, to Retire From Company He Co-Founded</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/09/08/business/08alibaba-print-dress/08alibaba1-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>In an interview, Mr. Ma said it was “the beginning of an era” for him and that he planned to focus on philanthropy in education.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/09/07/technology/alibaba-jack-ma-retiring.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Intel can’t supply 14nm Xeons, HPE recommends AMD Epyc</title>
<link>https://www.semiaccurate.com/2018/09/07/intel-cant-supply-14nm-xeons-hpe-directly-recommends-amd-epyc/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.semiaccurate.com/2018/09/07/intel-cant-supply-14nm-xeons-hpe-directly-recommends-amd-epyc/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.semiaccurate.com/assets/uploads/2017/11/Intel_logo.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-thumbnail wp-image-41481&quot; src=&quot;https://www.semiaccurate.com/assets/uploads/2017/11/Intel_logo-87x61.png&quot; alt=&quot;Intel Logo&quot; width=&quot;87&quot; height=&quot;61&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.semiaccurate.com/assets/uploads/2017/11/Intel_logo-87x61.png 87w, https://www.semiaccurate.com/assets/uploads/2017/11/Intel_logo-300x211.png 300w, https://www.semiaccurate.com/assets/uploads/2017/11/Intel_logo.png 522w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 87px) 100vw, 87px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Intel can’t seem to supply 14nm Xeons so HPE is recommending AMD Epycs instead. Most SemiAccurate readers will understand why there is a 14nm shortage at Intel but even with that background, this page is pretty brutal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The page in question is titled, “&lt;em&gt;Reseller update:Overcoming supply constraints on Intel Xeon-SP processors&lt;/em&gt;” and it is dated August 7, 2018 so this is not a new issue. You might have heard rumblings of it on the consumer side, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.semiaccurate.com/2017/08/10/cannon-lake-going-impact-intels-margins/&quot;&gt;SsmiAccurate went into the reasons for it happening almost exactly a year before the HPE page&lt;/a&gt; in question was written, just from a different angle. That said there is a serious shortage of Intel Xeons, and consumer iSomethingmeaningless, CPUs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The page is marked, “&lt;em&gt;Confidential | HPE Internal &amp;amp; Authorized Partner Use Only&lt;/em&gt;” but it is quite open and does not require a login. (Note: We are not linking it because of all the sites that steal our stories, rip us off, and don’t credit) All sub-pages linked do however require a login as of this writing. The page says in no uncertain terms that Intel can not supply Xeon-SP CPUs and it is definitely impacting sales for HPE and presumably every other large industry player as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“&lt;em&gt;Supply continues to be dynamic and constrained on specific SKUs, but HPE teams are working with Intel to drive additional supply with significant recovery being forecasted in September and October.&lt;/em&gt;” It is going to get a bit better soon, maybe, but how many months has this been going on for? How much will this cost Intel? Will the slush fund tap have to open even harder soon?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing we can say for sure is that HPE has a way out, “&lt;em&gt;Recommending alternative platforms such as the ProLiant DL325 Gen10 and ProLiant DL385 Gen10 servers based on AMD EPYC processors.&lt;/em&gt;” Seems clear enough to us, the other two bullet points in the mitigation strategies box are basically corporate BS-speak and not anything a sales person can do. I guess AMD is going to be having a good quarter and Intel… less so. Enjoy the screen captures of the page in full in case it goes poof before you read this.&lt;strong&gt;S|A&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.semiaccurate.com/assets/uploads/2018/09/HPE_Xeon_supply_page_1.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-large wp-image-42085&quot; src=&quot;https://www.semiaccurate.com/assets/uploads/2018/09/HPE_Xeon_supply_page_1-617x766.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;HPE Xeon Supply Issue Page 1&quot; width=&quot;617&quot; height=&quot;766&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.semiaccurate.com/assets/uploads/2018/09/HPE_Xeon_supply_page_1-617x766.jpg 617w, https://www.semiaccurate.com/assets/uploads/2018/09/HPE_Xeon_supply_page_1-70x87.jpg 70w, https://www.semiaccurate.com/assets/uploads/2018/09/HPE_Xeon_supply_page_1-242x300.jpg 242w, https://www.semiaccurate.com/assets/uploads/2018/09/HPE_Xeon_supply_page_1-768x953.jpg 768w, https://www.semiaccurate.com/assets/uploads/2018/09/HPE_Xeon_supply_page_1.jpg 870w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 617px) 100vw, 617px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.semiaccurate.com/assets/uploads/2018/09/HPE_Xeon_supply_page_2.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-large wp-image-42086&quot; src=&quot;https://www.semiaccurate.com/assets/uploads/2018/09/HPE_Xeon_supply_page_2-617x657.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;HPE Xeon Supply Issue Page 2&quot; width=&quot;617&quot; height=&quot;657&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.semiaccurate.com/assets/uploads/2018/09/HPE_Xeon_supply_page_2-617x657.jpg 617w, https://www.semiaccurate.com/assets/uploads/2018/09/HPE_Xeon_supply_page_2-82x87.jpg 82w, https://www.semiaccurate.com/assets/uploads/2018/09/HPE_Xeon_supply_page_2-282x300.jpg 282w, https://www.semiaccurate.com/assets/uploads/2018/09/HPE_Xeon_supply_page_2-768x818.jpg 768w, https://www.semiaccurate.com/assets/uploads/2018/09/HPE_Xeon_supply_page_2.jpg 836w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 617px) 100vw, 617px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.semiaccurate.com/assets/uploads/2018/09/HPE_Xeon_supply_page_3.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-large wp-image-42087&quot; src=&quot;https://www.semiaccurate.com/assets/uploads/2018/09/HPE_Xeon_supply_page_3-617x638.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;HPE Xeon Supply Issue Page 3&quot; width=&quot;617&quot; height=&quot;638&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.semiaccurate.com/assets/uploads/2018/09/HPE_Xeon_supply_page_3-617x638.jpg 617w, https://www.semiaccurate.com/assets/uploads/2018/09/HPE_Xeon_supply_page_3-84x87.jpg 84w, https://www.semiaccurate.com/assets/uploads/2018/09/HPE_Xeon_supply_page_3-290x300.jpg 290w, https://www.semiaccurate.com/assets/uploads/2018/09/HPE_Xeon_supply_page_3-768x794.jpg 768w, https://www.semiaccurate.com/assets/uploads/2018/09/HPE_Xeon_supply_page_3.jpg 844w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 617px) 100vw, 617px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.semiaccurate.com/assets/uploads/2018/09/HPE_Xeon_supply_page_4.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-large wp-image-42088&quot; src=&quot;https://www.semiaccurate.com/assets/uploads/2018/09/HPE_Xeon_supply_page_4-617x413.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;HPE Xeon Supply Issue Page 4&quot; width=&quot;617&quot; height=&quot;413&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.semiaccurate.com/assets/uploads/2018/09/HPE_Xeon_supply_page_4-617x413.jpg 617w, https://www.semiaccurate.com/assets/uploads/2018/09/HPE_Xeon_supply_page_4-87x58.jpg 87w, https://www.semiaccurate.com/assets/uploads/2018/09/HPE_Xeon_supply_page_4-300x201.jpg 300w, https://www.semiaccurate.com/assets/uploads/2018/09/HPE_Xeon_supply_page_4-768x514.jpg 768w, https://www.semiaccurate.com/assets/uploads/2018/09/HPE_Xeon_supply_page_4.jpg 846w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 617px) 100vw, 617px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;ts-fab-below&quot; class=&quot;ts-fab-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;The following two tabs change content below.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ts-fab-tabs&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ts-fab-tab&quot; id=&quot;ts-fab-bio-below&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ts-fab-avatar&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.semiaccurate.com/wp-content/plugins/jetpack/modules/lazy-images/images/1x1.trans.gif&quot; class=&quot;avatar avatar-80 photo jetpack-lazy-image&quot; height=&quot;80&quot; width=&quot;80&quot; data-lazy-src=&quot;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/626719a589cca64dfafcc89dfb333fc3?s=80&amp;amp;r=pg&quot; data-lazy-srcset=&quot;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/626719a589cca64dfafcc89dfb333fc3?s=160&amp;amp;r=pg 2x&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/626719a589cca64dfafcc89dfb333fc3?s=80&amp;amp;r=pg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/626719a589cca64dfafcc89dfb333fc3?s=160&amp;amp;r=pg 2x&quot; class=&quot;avatar avatar-80 photo&quot; height=&quot;80&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ts-fab-text&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;ts-fab-content&quot;&gt;Charlie Demerjian is the founder of Stone Arch Networking Services and SemiAccurate.com. SemiAccurate.com is a technology news site; addressing hardware design, software selection, customization, securing and maintenance, with over one million views per month. He is a technologist and analyst specializing in semiconductors, system and network architecture. As head writer of SemiAccurate.com, he regularly advises writers, analysts, and industry executives on technical matters and long lead industry trends. Charlie is also a council member with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.glgresearch.com/&quot;&gt;Gerson Lehman Group.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://75.146.151.149/fullyaccurate/&quot;&gt;FullyAccurate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ts-fab-tab&quot; id=&quot;ts-fab-latest-posts-below&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ts-fab-avatar&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.semiaccurate.com/wp-content/plugins/jetpack/modules/lazy-images/images/1x1.trans.gif&quot; class=&quot;avatar avatar-80 photo jetpack-lazy-image&quot; height=&quot;80&quot; width=&quot;80&quot; data-lazy-src=&quot;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/626719a589cca64dfafcc89dfb333fc3?s=80&amp;amp;r=pg&quot; data-lazy-srcset=&quot;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/626719a589cca64dfafcc89dfb333fc3?s=160&amp;amp;r=pg 2x&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/626719a589cca64dfafcc89dfb333fc3?s=80&amp;amp;r=pg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/626719a589cca64dfafcc89dfb333fc3?s=160&amp;amp;r=pg 2x&quot; class=&quot;avatar avatar-80 photo&quot; height=&quot;80&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ts-fab-text&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ts-fab-header&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Latest posts by Charlie Demerjian &lt;span class=&quot;latest-see-all&quot;&gt;(&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.semiaccurate.com/author/charlie/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;see all&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;robots-nocontent sd-block sd-social sd-social-icon-text sd-sharing&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Share this:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 19:48:49 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>davidgerard</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Intel can’t supply 14nm Xeons, HPE directly recommends AMD Epyc</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.semiaccurate.com/2018/09/07/intel-cant-supply-14nm-xeons-hpe-directly-recommends-amd-epyc/</og:url>
<og:description>Intel can’t seem to supply 14nm Xeons so HPE is recommending AMD Epycs instead.</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.semiaccurate.com/assets/uploads/2017/11/Intel_logo.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.semiaccurate.com/2018/09/07/intel-cant-supply-14nm-xeons-hpe-directly-recommends-amd-epyc/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>My Story as a Homeless Developer</title>
<link>https://medium.com/@jessehorne/my-story-as-a-homeless-developer-5874731c42ed</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://medium.com/@jessehorne/my-story-as-a-homeless-developer-5874731c42ed</guid>
<description>&lt;p name=&quot;7e7f&quot; id=&quot;7e7f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;I’ve been writing code, good and bad, since I was eleven years old. Living at my grandmothers at the time, entertainment for me usually consisted of flipping on the television to Cartoon Network and watching “Ed, Edd n Eddy” or my favorite, “Dexter's Laboratory”. I would see the lab that Dexter, a child, had built, and would try to recreate it using variations of crayon-covered paper and oddly-stacked furniture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;4628&quot; id=&quot;4628&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The moment I received my first computer, I was hooked. A friend of the family who also was our go-to plumber, gave me a Pentium II. He handed me a CD of Ubuntu. It took me a couple of years to convert but I’ve been using variations of Ubuntu ever since. Before I convinced my grandmother to pay for internet, I would take floppy-drives to school and download antiquated BASIC interpreters and copy-n-pasted tutorials from old textfiles. I’d bring them back home and try to learn as much as I could. She finally agreed to pay the bill for the lowest speed available. My machine could not run the games that my friends were playing, so alone in my room, I coded the days and nights away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*taDJv04g7gae5u7TrN8bkA.png&quot; data-width=&quot;400&quot; data-height=&quot;250&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*taDJv04g7gae5u7TrN8bkA.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;9765&quot; id=&quot;9765&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;As the years went by, my interest in computers and programming was more like an intense obsession. It affected my ability to focus at school. I started doing poorly in 6th grade. From that grade, I barely was able to pass each year. I was learning so much at home, that I had no interest in the mundane and ineffective methods used at my schools. I’d rarely do homework, and when I needed to know something for a test, I waited until the last night before the exam and I would find tutorials that covered the subject. I wish I had understood the value of school, then. I began to learn the hard lessons of life when I decided to drop out, in 10th grade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;cdab&quot; id=&quot;cdab&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I quickly received my GED but ended up at my grandmothers house on and off, because of family problems, searching for freelance work and finding just enough to keep my portfolio growing. I knew I had to escape my neighborhood and my family. Undiagnosed mental-health problems led to some fairly poor decisions. I was seventeen when I experienced homelessness for the first time. I was kicked out of my friends house and my grandmother didn’t want me there. She was adamantly Christian and I was a stubborn, computer-obsessed Atheist. She looked at me the day I showed up to her door-step, desktop in hand, and said “You can’t live here. I will call the police if you do not leave.”. I did nothing wrong to her. I never stole from her, always demanded my brothers to respect her even with her faults and practically begged her to love me. But nearly an adult, I knew I had to get on my feet and survive on my own from that moment on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;0*2QCFJPn_4A8c4uvM&quot; data-width=&quot;4032&quot; data-height=&quot;3024&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;0*2QCFJPn_4A8c4uvM&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/0*2QCFJPn_4A8c4uvM&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
“red neon light cross signage” by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@dvbarrantes?utm_source=medium&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&quot; data-href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@dvbarrantes?utm_source=medium&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--figure-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;photo-creator nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Diana Vargas&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com?utm_source=medium&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&quot; data-href=&quot;https://unsplash.com?utm_source=medium&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--figure-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;photo-source nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;a878&quot; id=&quot;a878&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;Luckily, I was not homeless for long. I made a few calls to people across the country that I had worked on projects with and a very good friend knew someone in Atlanta that could pick me up and house me. They saved my life. I ended up staying there for three months. I would help with yard-work and every moment awake not doing that, I would be working on my portfolio. After the third month, I was offered to be flown to a small town in Wyoming and interviewed. I had been offered to be flown to California a couple of times when I was sixteen years old for interviews, but my grandmother wouldn’t let me go. She said that it was a trap and that I would be kidnapped, even after I showed her printed pages of evidence that it wasn’t some psychotic scam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;e7e8&quot; id=&quot;e7e8&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I spent eight months or so there working hard on antiquated PHP accounting software and introduced the company to better ways to maintain their sites. They weren’t the most moral of employers. They took care of me but demanded more than I could offer as far as over-time. The pay was low and the living costs were high. My hourly wasn’t working for me. So after a couple months of searching for a new position, in private, I found a contracting firm in Iowa that offered to fly me out for an interview. I landed in Des Moines late one night and the recruiter picked me up. They put me up in a hotel and gave me rides to work long enough for me to get into my own apartment. Getting on my feet from that moment became easier to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;cb00&quot; id=&quot;cb00&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I worked hard and advanced in that position fast. We were writing RESTful JSON API’s in Python 2.7. I learned so much in my time there. It was a great experience. Relationship issues for a now twenty year old developer proved to be too much. Emotionally I was devastated when that relationship ended. It affected me and I had no one to help me through the emotional stresses of the situation. It affected my work. It affected my activism (that’s a story for another day). My contract was ending and my manager, a friendly and intelligent guy, suggested that I figure out my problems and work somewhere else for a little while and then come back. Sadly, I haven’t been employed since then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;f0d4&quot; id=&quot;f0d4&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I ended up losing my apartment, made more poor decisions, and couch-surfed. I’ve been couch-surfing ever since. Slowly I lost every amount of savings I had, my car, and friends that tried their best to support me through that time. When I got a chance to sit at a computer, I would obsessively write code and start projects that I thought could potentially earn funds. I was able to get back to my hometown in Georgia, where I had no friends at the time, that were willing to let me spend the night, much less put me up. I’d hang out at the bars downtown and the nights I had a place to sleep were the nights they had friends over to drink and play card games. That wasn’t working for me so I managed to get back to Iowa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;0*g4R3JvYM9fBHr3Sq&quot; data-width=&quot;2823&quot; data-height=&quot;1933&quot; data-is-featured=&quot;true&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;0*g4R3JvYM9fBHr3Sq&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/0*g4R3JvYM9fBHr3Sq&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@benhershey?utm_source=medium&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&quot; data-href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@benhershey?utm_source=medium&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--figure-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;photo-creator nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ben Hershey&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com?utm_source=medium&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&quot; data-href=&quot;https://unsplash.com?utm_source=medium&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--figure-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;photo-source nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;7481&quot; id=&quot;7481&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;I quickly lost my living arrangement there with a friend and was on the streets again. Being homeless is hard. It’s hard to get access to wifi without walking miles every day and keeping a charge was almost impossible without running into police who didn’t want a smelly young guy sitting in the public walkways with his bag. My friends were the ones I was around in the shelter and on the streets around the neighborhood I was in. It gets very cold in Iowa, in the winter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;511f&quot; id=&quot;511f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I was still stubborn and would not agree to believing in the almighty bearded creator in the sky, so one of the two shelters would not help me. I was still obsessively interested in programming and had no interest in any other job. I didn’t take advantage of the other shelter. My days consisted of walking around downtown, keeping a charge on my phone, calling people looking for work and reading tutorials that I couldn’t really put into practice. My limited time at the library was spent trying to write code in a browser because I could not download the editor that I preferred. Yes, I also tried to write code on my phone. The projects I started never went anywhere and I never received any work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;149a&quot; id=&quot;149a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Being homeless is very hard. It’s never as easy as anyone says it is, to get back on your feet. I’ve been trying to find jobs in this small town but that hasn’t worked so far. I have no car and I do not find enough freelance work to save, so I don’t imagine I will have one anytime soon. I’ve had countless calls with recruiters and so on… The calls usually go something like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;db80&quot; id=&quot;db80&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Me: “First thing, is I am looking for a remote position just long enough to allow me to save for a vehicle.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;2695&quot; id=&quot;2695&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Recruiter: “Sure. *spends 20 minutes gathering as much information about me as they can*”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;a922&quot; id=&quot;a922&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Recruiter: “We’d love to move forward with a position but you do not have a vehicle and the position requires you to have reliable transportation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;eca3&quot; id=&quot;eca3&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Me: “Thank you for your time. I’m sorry for the inconvenience.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;0*QgPMddzPrAYIzeBm&quot; data-width=&quot;5184&quot; data-height=&quot;3456&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;0*QgPMddzPrAYIzeBm&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/0*QgPMddzPrAYIzeBm&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
“seal laying on bench” by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@jackmanchiu?utm_source=medium&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&quot; data-href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@jackmanchiu?utm_source=medium&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--figure-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;photo-creator nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Jackman Chiu&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com?utm_source=medium&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&quot; data-href=&quot;https://unsplash.com?utm_source=medium&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--figure-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;photo-source nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;90e4&quot; id=&quot;90e4&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;So all this being said, being homeless is *hard*. I blame no one but myself for this situation. I now have a chance to get back on my feet and although I have a ton of obstacles in my way, I believe I will succeed. I’m working on projects every second that I’m awake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;6178&quot; id=&quot;6178&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I appreciate your time, readers. I woke up this morning not knowing what to do and feeling like there’s no hope at all for me. Finishing this article up has given me the motivation that I will need to work another day. Any and all feedback is welcome. I’d love to hear about other similar situations. Are you struggling with similar problems? Let’s talk. Two poor, homeless minds are better than one. If you are in a similar situation as I, don’t give up just yet. I know there’s stability and peace in my future, and I’m not any more important than you are in this universe, so it’s there for you too. We just have to go and get it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;0*5llWngMCryyu-GmP&quot; data-width=&quot;4608&quot; data-height=&quot;3072&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;0*5llWngMCryyu-GmP&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/0*5llWngMCryyu-GmP&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
“asphalt road between the trees” by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@aldyrkhanov?utm_source=medium&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&quot; data-href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@aldyrkhanov?utm_source=medium&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--figure-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;photo-creator nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Arthur Aldyrkhanov&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com?utm_source=medium&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&quot; data-href=&quot;https://unsplash.com?utm_source=medium&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--figure-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;photo-source nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 19:08:43 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jessehorne</dc:creator>
<og:title>My Story as a Homeless Developer – Jesse Horne – Medium</og:title>
<og:url>https://medium.com/@jessehorne/my-story-as-a-homeless-developer-5874731c42ed</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/0*g4R3JvYM9fBHr3Sq</og:image>
<og:description>I’ve been writing code, good and bad, since I was eleven years old. Living at my grandmothers at the time, entertainment for me usually…</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://medium.com/@jessehorne/my-story-as-a-homeless-developer-5874731c42ed</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>EU copyright reform: the facts</title>
<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/netpolicy/2018/09/07/eu-copyright-reform-the-facts/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.mozilla.org/netpolicy/2018/09/07/eu-copyright-reform-the-facts/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;On Wednesday 12 September, Members of the European Parliament will hold a crucial vote on new copyright rules that could fundamentally damage the internet in Europe. If adopted, the new rules will force online services to universally monitor and filter the content that users post online. Ahead of the vote, we wish to set the facts straight and explain exactly what these new rules will mean for openness and decentralisation in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FACT: The proposed new copyright rules will harm Europe’s open source community.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mandatory upload filters and copyright licensing provisions in article 13 of the proposed law are unworkable for open source software firms like Mozilla and the open source ecosystem generally. The obligations cover &lt;em&gt;all forms&lt;/em&gt; of copyright-protected content, including software. Indeed, the cost and legal risk associated with these new rules would push smaller open source software developers out of Europe and threaten the code-sharing platforms (e.g. GitHub) on which they depend to innovate. The fluid nature of technology and software development means that any carve-outs — say for software development platforms — would still risk creating a risk-laden environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FACT: The proposed new copyright rules will negatively affect everyday user’s internet experiences.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When internet users want to share a witty meme online, or a home movie in which background music is audible, or even a photo of themselves wearing a t-shirt with an album cover printed on it, they may well find that their favourite online service blocks the content upload. Internet services of all sizes will be forced to implement automatic filtering technology,  likely suppressing anything that looks like it might be infringing copyright, irrespective of whether the user has a right or permission to use the content. Given the crucial role the internet plays in citizens’ everyday lives, the impact on creativity, communication, and free expression from such blanket filtering would be palpable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FACT: The proposed new copyright rules will lead to direct surveillance of users’ activities online.​&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Article 13 demands that online services build or buy specific technology to monitor and categorise each and every user upload. At a time when the EU is showing global leadership on privacy and data protection, it is deeply regrettable that lawmakers are nonetheless seeking to codify a regime that would compel service providers to monitor European internet users’ activity with even more vigour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FACT: The proposed new copyright rules will negatively impact independent creators.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Article 13 will be used to restrict the freedom of expression and creative potential of independent artists who depend upon online services to directly reach their audience and bypass the rigidities and limitations of the commercial content industry. Sadly, the fight over this legislation has been construed as giant rightsholders versus giant online platforms. But in reality, the true victims will be creators and fans themselves. There’s a bitter irony at play: the directors, actors, songwriters, and artists who benefit from the viral sharing of their creations are now pitted against their fans, who in fact do some of the most efficient online marketing artists can hope for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FACT: Smaller online services – and not giant platforms – will be hit hardest by the new rules&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to its impact on user experience, this law will have another, more insidious impact: it will further entrench the power of the biggest online platforms. Only a handful of the largest tech companies have the technical and financial means to operate the sprawling filtering systems that this law demands. Ironically, the companies at which this law is aimed are already filtering content — and so will have a competitive advantage vis-a-vis their smaller rivals and startups, who will need to invest heavily to comply with the law. In addition, the biggest platforms also have the resources and clout to mount legal defences when larger corporate rightsholders seek to suppress legal content. This is not an option for smaller players who will face a high-stakes game of legal risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We encourage anyone who shares these concerns to reach out to members of the European Parliament – you can call them directly via &lt;a href=&quot;https://changecopyright.org/en-US/&quot;&gt;changecopyright.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 13:35:35 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>raleighm</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://blog.mozilla.org/netpolicy/2018/09/07/eu-copyright-reform-the-facts</og:url>
<og:title>EU copyright reform: the facts – Open Policy &amp; Advocacy</og:title>
<og:description>Ahead of the crucial EU copyright vote on 12 Sept., we set the facts straight and explain exactly what the new rules will mean for the internet in Europe.</og:description>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.mozilla.org/netpolicy/2018/09/07/eu-copyright-reform-the-facts/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Firefox about:config privacy settings</title>
<link>https://gist.github.com/0XDE57/fbd302cef7693e62c769</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://gist.github.com/0XDE57/fbd302cef7693e62c769</guid>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;about:config settings to harden the Firefox browser. Privacy and performance enhancements.&lt;br/&gt;To change these settings type 'about:config' in the url bar. Then search the setting you would like to change and modify the value. Some settings may break certain websites from functioning and rendering normally. Some settings may also make firefox unstable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;I am not liable for any damages/loss of data.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not all these changes are necessary and will be dependent upon your usage and hardware. Do some research on settings if you don't understand what they do. These settings are best combined with your standard privacy extensions (HTTPS Everywhere, NoScript/Request Policy, uBlock origin, agent spoofing, Privacy Badger etc), and all plugins set to &quot;Ask To Activate&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: some keys may not be listed and must be added manually, or they are no longer relavent as firefox changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: you can check current connections via: about:networking&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;dom.event.contextmenu.enabled = false
        Don't allow websites to prevent use of right-click, 
        or otherwise messing with the context menu.

dom.event.clipboardevents.enabled = false
        Don't allow websites to prevent copy and paste.
        Disable notifications of copy, paste, or cut functions. 
        Stop webpage knowing which part of the page had been selected.

network.IDN_show_punycode = true
        Show punycode. Help protect from character 'spoofing' eg:
        xn--80ak6aa92e.com -&amp;gt; аррӏе.com
        [IDN homograph attacks](https://www.xudongz.com/blog/2017/idn-phishing/)

&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;plugins.enumerable_names = blank
        Disable site reading installed plugins.

network.http.sendRefererHeader = 0
        Tells website where you came from. Disabling may break some sites.
        0 = Disable referrer headers. 
        1 = Send only on clicked links.
        2 = (default) Send for links and image.
        
network.http.sendSecureXSiteReferrer = false
        Disable referrer headers between https websites.
                
network.http.referer.spoofSource = true
        Send fake referrer (if choose to send referrers).
                
privacy.trackingprotection.enabled = true
        Mozilla’s built in tracking protection.
                
geo.enabled = false
geo.wifi.uri = blank
browser.search.geoip.url = blank
        Disables geolocation and firefox logging geolocation requests.


browser.safebrowsing.enabled = false
browser.safebrowsing.phishing.enabled = false
browser.safebrowsing.malware.enabled = false    
browser.safebrowsing.downloads.enabled = false
browser.safebrowsing.provider.google4.dataSharing.enabled = blank
browser.safebrowsing.provider.google4.updateURL = blank
browser.safebrowsing.provider.google4.reportURL = blank
browser.safebrowsing.provider.google4.reportPhishMistakeURL = blank
browser.safebrowsing.provider.google4.reportMalwareMistakeURL = blank
browser.safebrowsing.provider.google4.lists = blank
browser.safebrowsing.provider.google4.gethashURL = blank
browser.safebrowsing.provider.google4.dataSharingURL = blank
browser.safebrowsing.provider.google4.dataSharing.enabled = false
browser.safebrowsing.provider.google4.advisoryURL = blank
browser.safebrowsing.provider.google4.advisoryName = blank
browser.safebrowsing.provider.google.updateURL = blank
browser.safebrowsing.provider.google.reportURL = blank
browser.safebrowsing.provider.google.reportPhishMistakeURL = blank
browser.safebrowsing.provider.google.reportMalwareMistakeURL = blank
browser.safebrowsing.provider.google.pver = blank
browser.safebrowsing.provider.google.lists = blank
browser.safebrowsing.provider.google.gethashURL = blank
browser.safebrowsing.provider.google.advisoryURL = blank
browser.safebrowsing.downloads.remote.url = blank
        Disable Google Safe Browsing and malware and phishing protection.
        Stop sending links and downloading lists from google.   
        Security risk, but privacy improvement.
        Note: this list may be incomplete as firefox updates, be sure to search for browser.safebrowsing.provider.google*
        Also simply setting safebrowsing.*.enabled to false should make setting the URL's to blank redundant, but better to be safe.
        If you see anything pointing google, probably best to nuke it.


browser.selfsupport.url = blank
browser.aboutHomeSnippets.updateUrL = blank
browser.startup.homepage_override.mstone = ignore
browser.startup.homepage_override.buildID = blank
startup.homepage_welcome_url = blank
startup.homepage_welcome_url.additional = blank
startup.homepage_override_url = blank
        Can call home to every time firefox is started or home page is visited.
        https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/how-stop-firefox-making-automatic-connections
        http://kb.mozillazine.org/Connections_established_on_startup_-_Firefox


toolkit.telemetry.cachedClientID = blank

browser.send_pings = false
        Prevent website tracking clicks.
                
browser.send_pings.require_same_host = true
        Only send pings if send and receiving host match (same website).
        
dom.battery.enabled = false
        Disable website reading how much battery your mobile device or laptop has.

network.cookie.alwaysAcceptSessionCookies = false
        Disables acceptance of session cookies.
                
network.cookie.cookieBehavior
        Disable cookies.
        0 = All cookies are allowed. (Default) 
        1 = Only cookies from the originating server are allowed. (block third party cookies)
        2 = No cookies are allowed. 
        3 = Third-party cookies are allowed only if that site has stored cookies already from a previous visit 
                        
network.cookie.lifetimePolicy 
        cookies are deleted at the end of the session
        0 = The cookie's lifetime is supplied by the server. (Default) 
        1 = The user is prompted for the cookie's lifetime. 
        2 = The cookie expires at the end of the session (when the browser closes). 
        3 = The cookie lasts for the number of days specified by network.cookie.lifetime.days.   

network.dnsCacheEntries = 100
        Number of cached DNS entries. Lower number = More requests but less data stored.
    
network.dnsCacheExpiration = 60
        Time DNS entries are cached in seconds.
    
places.history.enabled = false
        Disables recording of visited websites.
    
browser.formfill.enable = false
        Disables saving of form data.
    
browser.cache.disk.enable = false
        Disables caching on hardrive.
    
browser.cache.disk_cache_ssl = false
        Disables caching for ssl connections.
    
browser.cache.memory.enable = false
        Disables caching in memory.
   
browser.cache.offline.enable = false
        Disables offline cache.
    
network.dns.disableIPv6 = true
        If your OS or ISP does not support IPv6, there is no reason to have this preference set to false. 

network.predictor.enabled = false
network.dns.disablePrefetch = true   
network.prefetch-next = false
        Link prefetching is when a webpage hints to the browser that certain pages are likely to be visited, 
        so the browser downloads them immediately so they can be displayed immediately when the user requests it. 

network.http.speculative-parallel-limit = 0
        Disable prefetch link on hover.
        
media.peerconnection.enabled = false    
network.websocket.enabled = false
        WebSockets is a technology that makes it possible to open an interactive communication 
        session between the user's browser and a server. (May leak IP when using proxy/VPN)
   
loop.enabled = false
        Disable 3rd party closed-source Hello integration.
        Note: only affects older versions of firefox as &quot;Hello&quot; has been discontinued as in favor of webrtc: https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/hello-status
        
extensions.pocket.enabled = false
extensions.pocket.site = blank
extensions.pocket.oAuthConsumerKey = blank
extensions.pocket.api = blank
        Disable 3rd party closed-source Pocket integration.
        Note, this is browser.pocket.enabled for older versions of firefox
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;layout.frame_rate.precise = true
        Increases animation speed. May mitigate choppy scrolling.
        
webgl.force-enabled = true
layers.acceleration.force-enabled = true
layers.offmainthreadcomposition.enabled = true
layers.offmainthreadcomposition.async-animations = true
layers.async-video.enabled = true
html5.offmainthread = true
        Enable Hardware Acceleration and Off Main Thread Compositing (OMTC).
        It's likely your browser is already set to use these features.
        May introduce instability on some hardware.

&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;browser.cache.memory.capacity = xx
        Limit memory cache size. (xx = value in MB)
        
browser.sessionhistory.max_entries = xx
        Limit maximum pages in session history. (how many URLs you can traverse using the Forward or Back button)
        
browser.sessionstore.max_tabs_undo = xx
        Limit max closed tabs you can reopen.
        
browser.tabs.animate = false
browser.download.animateNotifications = false
        Disable some animations.
        
config.trim_on_minimize = true
        Reduce memory usage when minimized. (Windows only)
        
image.mem.max_decoded_image_kb = xx
        How much info Firefox stores of uncompressed images.
        Higher value = improve speed at the expense of increased memory usage.
        
javascript.options.mem.max == xx
        Limit amount of memory javascript may consume.
        -1 = Automatic

javascript.options.mem.high_water_mark == xx
        Tell garbage collector to start running when javascript is using xx MB of memory. 
        Garbage collection releases memory back to the system.
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one is not for firefox, but for Flash if you have it installed. Font Enumeration allows a site to read which fonts you have installed which can be used to identify users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Default Location:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;Windows: 
        C:\Windows\SysWOW64\Macromed\Flash\mms.cfg
        C:\Windows\system32\Macromed\Flash\mms.cfg
Linux:
        /etc/adobe/mms.cfg
OSX:
        ~/Library/Application Support/Google/Chrome/Default/Pepper Data/Shockwave Flash/System/mms.cfg
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add this line to the mms.cfg file:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;DisableDeviceFontEnumeration = 1
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Better yet, simply uninstall flash. Flash is garbage...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;___&lt;br/&gt;**I do my best to keep this list up to date. Additions and corrections are greatly appreciated.**</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 13:31:36 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>krn</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars3.githubusercontent.com/u/3465882?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Firefox about:config privacy settings</og:title>
<og:url>https://gist.github.com/0XDE57/fbd302cef7693e62c769</og:url>
<og:description>Firefox about:config privacy settings. GitHub Gist: instantly share code, notes, and snippets.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://gist.github.com/0XDE57/fbd302cef7693e62c769</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Try OCaml</title>
<link>https://try.ocamlpro.com/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://try.ocamlpro.com/</guid>
<description>&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ocamlpro.com/&quot;&gt;Connect to OCamlPro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to know more about OCaml, and how Functional Programming can boost software projects in your company, contact us at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ocamlpro.com/&quot;&gt;OCamlPro&lt;/a&gt;. We provide &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ocamlpro.com/services/training.html&quot;&gt;on-site training&lt;/a&gt; from beginners to experts, and our highly-experienced experts will always give insightfull advises on your ongoing projects.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 09:26:34 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dna_polymerase</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://try.ocamlpro.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Keybase’s browser extension subverts its encryption</title>
<link>https://palant.de/2018/09/06/keybase-our-browser-extension-subverts-our-encryption-but-why-should-we-care</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://palant.de/2018/09/06/keybase-our-browser-extension-subverts-our-encryption-but-why-should-we-care</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Two days ago I decided to take a look at Keybase. Keybase does crypto, is open source and offers security bug bounties for relevant findings — just the perfect investigation subject for me. It didn’t take long for me to realize that their browser extension is deeply flawed, so I reported the issue to them via their bug bounty program. The response was rather… remarkable. It can be summed up as: “Yes, we know. But why should we care?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;What is Keybase?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The self-description of Keybase emphasizes its secure end-to-end encryption (emphasis in original):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine a &lt;strong&gt;Slack&lt;/strong&gt; for the whole world, except &lt;strong&gt;end-to-end encrypted&lt;/strong&gt; across all your devices. Or a &lt;strong&gt;Team Dropbox&lt;/strong&gt; where the server can’t leak your files or be hacked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the app allows you to exchange messages or files with other people, with the encryption happening on sender’s computer in such a way that decryption is only possible by the designated recipient. This app is available for both desktop and mobile platforms. And for desktop you get a bonus: you can install the Keybase browser extension. It will add a “Keybase Chat” button to people’s profiles on Facebook, Twitter, GitHub, Reddit or Hacker News. This button allows you to connect to people easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://palant.de/images/12.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;417&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clicking the button will open a chat window and allow you to enter a message directly in the browser. Only after that initial message is sent the conversation will be transferred to the Keybase app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;So what’s the issue?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The issue here is a very common one, merely a week ago I listed it as #6 in &lt;a href=&quot;https://palant.de/2018/08/29/password-managers-please-make-sure-autofill-is-secure&quot;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt;. The extension injects its user interface (the button and the chat window) into third-party websites, yet it fails to isolate it from these websites. So the first consequence is: the Keybase message you enter on Facebook is by no means private. Facebook’s JavaScript code can read it out as you type it in, so much for end-to-end encryption. This is quite contrary to the promise Keybase still makes on their Mozilla Add-ons and Chrome Web Store installation pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://palant.de/images/13.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;428&quot; height=&quot;333&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t believe that Facebook would intentionally spy on you? Maybe not, but by now it is pretty common to protocol all of user’s actions, for “site optimization” purposes — this includes anything entered into text fields of course. But in my opinion, that’s not even the worst issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A website could do more than passively spying on you. It could just as well instrument the Keybase user interface in order to send messages in your name, while also making this user interface invisible so that you don’t notice anything. Why would Facebook want to do something like that? Not necessary them, rather anybody who discovered a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cross-site_scripting&quot;&gt;Cross-Site Scripting (&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;XSS&lt;/span&gt;) vulnerability&lt;/a&gt; in one of the websites that Keybase integrates with. So if hundreds of people complain about you sending them spam messages via Keybase, it might be somebody exploiting the Keybase extension on your computer via an &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;XSS&lt;/span&gt; vulnerability in Reddit. Have fun explaining how you didn’t do it, even though the messages were safely encrypted on your computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;What does Keybase think about this?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Keybase, “this is all clearly described on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://keybase.io/docs/extension&quot;&gt;install page&lt;/a&gt; and is known.” In fact, close to the bottom of that page you find the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What if my browser is compromised?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Keybase extension uses a compose box inside your browser. If you fear your browser or the social network site’s JavaScript has been compromised — say by another extension or even the social network acting fishy — then just compose the message inside the Keybase app directly. Or send a quick hello note through the extension and save the jucier private details for inside the app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To me, this is thoroughly confusing. First of all, “browser is compromised” to me sounds more like malware. Trouble is, malware affecting the browser will affect the Keybase app just as well, so the advise makes no sense. But let’s say that it really is “the social network acting fishy,” how are you supposed to know? And is Facebook spying on you “fishy” or just its usual self?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not that this issue is unavoidable. Avoiding it is fairly easy, by isolating all of the extension’s user interface in an &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;iframe&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; element. This would prevent both the website and other extensions from accessing it. Disaster averted, nothing to see here. But according to Keybase:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;there were technical reasons why iframes didn’t work, though I forget the details&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I translate this as: “Using iframes required a slightly more complicated approach, so we couldn’t figure it out.” Also:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s such a minor feature for us, it’s not worth a fix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I translate this as: “We will keep pushing this extension because it gets users to promote our app for free. But we don’t care enough to make it secure.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;And now?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only advise I can give you: uninstall the Keybase browser extension &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;ASAP&lt;/span&gt;. As to the app itself, it &lt;em&gt;might&lt;/em&gt; be secure. But as &lt;a href=&quot;https://palant.de/2018/07/11/ftapi-secutransfer-the-secure-alternative-to-emails-not-quite&quot;&gt;experience shows&lt;/a&gt;, the claim “end-to-end encryption” doesn’t automatically translate into a secure implementation. Initially, I planned to take a closer look at the crypto in Keybase, to see whether I can find weaknesses in their implementation. But that’s off the table now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 05:45:20 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>fallenhitokiri</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Keybase: &quot;Our browser extension subverts our encryption, but why should we care?&quot;</og:title>
<og:description>The Keybase browser extension subverts the app's end-to-end encryption. Keybase considers that &quot;an acceptable risk&quot; and not worth fixing.</og:description>
<og:url>https://palant.de/2018/09/06/keybase-our-browser-extension-subverts-our-encryption-but-why-should-we-care</og:url>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://palant.de/2018/09/06/keybase-our-browser-extension-subverts-our-encryption-but-why-should-we-care</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Huawei caught cheating performance test for new phones</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/06/huawei-caught-cheating-performance-test-for-new-phones/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/06/huawei-caught-cheating-performance-test-for-new-phones/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;UL, the company behind the tablet and phone performance benchmark app 3DMark, has delisted new Huawei phones from its “Best Smartphone” leaderboard after &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anandtech.com/show/13318/huawei-benchmark-cheating-headache&quot;&gt;AnandTech&lt;/a&gt; discovered the phone maker was boosting its performance to ace the app’s test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The phones delisted were the P20, P20 Pro, Nova 3 and the Honor Play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“After testing the devices in our own lab and confirming that they breach our rules, we have decided to delist the affected models and remove them from our performance rankings,” the company &lt;a href=&quot;https://benchmarks.ul.com/news/ul-delists-huawei-phones-with-suspect-benchmark-scores&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;said in a statement&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the Huawei case, the rules are actually a little fuzzy. Phones are permitted to adjust performance based on workload, which results in peaks or dips in performance for different apps, but they are not permitted to hard-code peaks in performance specifically for the benchmark app. Huawei reportedly claimed that the peak in performance seen during the run of the benchmark app was an intuitive jump determined by AI; however, when an unlabeled version of the benchmark test was run, the phones were unable to recognize it and, as a result, displayed lower performances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, the phones aren’t so smart after all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huawei is not the first company caught overstepping these rules. Samsung &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2018/9/6/17828534/huawei-benchmarks-rigged-p20-3dmark-ai&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;did as well in 2013&lt;/a&gt;, and ironically the results of these benchmark tests actually mean little in terms of overall general performance of the phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While they can point to how a phone may perform during heavy stress, average performance is still best discovered through individual testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huawei did not immediately return a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update: &lt;/strong&gt;In a comment late Thursday night, a Huawei spokesperson told TechCrunch:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;20&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huawei always prioritizes the user experience rather than pursuing high benchmark scores – especially since there isn’t a direct connection between smartphone benchmarks and user experiences. Huawei smartphones use advanced technologies such as AI to optimize the performance of hardware, including the CPU, GPU and NPU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In normal benchmarking scenarios, once Huawei’s software recognizes a benchmarking application, it intelligently adapts to “Performance Mode” and delivers optimum performance. Huawei is planning to provide users with access to “Performance Mode” so they can use the maximum power of their device when they need to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huawei – as the industry leader – is willing to work with partners to find the best benchmarking standards that can accurately evaluate the user experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 02:56:41 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tango24</dc:creator>
<og:title>Huawei caught cheating performance test for new phones</og:title>
<og:description>UL, the company behind the tablet and phone performance benchmark app 3DMark, has delisted new Huawei phones from its “Best Smartphone” leaderboard after AnandTech discovered the phone maker was boosting its performance to ace the app’s test. The phones delisted were the P20, P20 …</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/GettyImages-954075096.jpg?w=625</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2018/09/06/huawei-caught-cheating-performance-test-for-new-phones/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/06/huawei-caught-cheating-performance-test-for-new-phones/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>