<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>2018 Stellar roadmap</title>
<link>https://www.stellar.org/blog/2018-Stellar-Roadmap/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.stellar.org/blog/2018-Stellar-Roadmap/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Hello and welcome. First of all, before we dig into our strategic goals for the upcoming year, I want to share the exciting recent growth Stellar has seen in r.p.w.—a seldom-discussed, yet crucial, cryptocurrency metric:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.stellar.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/stellar-randos-per-week.png&quot; alt=&quot;Stellar – Randos per week&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As any industry insider will tell you, this is &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; critical indicator for a decentralized protocol. We seem to have finally hit the inflection point, where one rando sees another rando talking to someone wearing a Stellar tee-shirt and just comes over and stands there. Recent milestones include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What exactly are your services? Create ICO tokens on the stellar network?” – MoonTtrading&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“So . . . how are you different from bitcoins?” – coin_spy_pro&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Hey man remember me? We met once a long time ago and now my brother is really into cryptocurrency.” – Kevin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our internal projections, based on the most recent data, estimate that by quarter’s end all mankind will stride up to Stellar, take a wide stance, and ask us what we think about RaiBlocks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above notwithstanding, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.stellar.org/blog/Q1-2018-stellar-and-state-of-crypto/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;our last post&lt;/a&gt; has the best information on Stellar’s recent performance metrics. Today, we’ll be discussing how to keep all those metrics moving up and to the right. This is our 2018 Roadmap; it has two main goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Goal #1: &lt;span&gt;SDEX – the Stellar Decentralized Exchange&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of 2017 we recruited a veteran team, with a substantial track record of product and marketing success, to build a front-end for Stellar’s inherent decentralized exchange. &lt;strong&gt;SDEX&lt;/strong&gt; is the working name for the project, and internal prototypes are underway. We’ll reveal further details on SDEX’s specific roadmap, brand, and leadership in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SDEX will be the world-class front-end that our underlying technology has long deserved. It will enable on-chain, protocol-level trades for any Stellar token, and we will create liquidity to minimize spreads and maximize choice of assets. Specific niceties the SDEX implies:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;– &lt;strong&gt;Day One&lt;/strong&gt; trading for any Stellar ICO token&lt;br/&gt;– atomic pathfinding to discover the &lt;strong&gt;cheapest rates&lt;/strong&gt; between any two assets&lt;br/&gt;– very &lt;strong&gt;low trading fees&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;– end-user control of secret keys&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For SDEX to compete with other major exchanges we will need to increase the quality and number of &lt;strong&gt;anchors&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;market-makers&lt;/strong&gt; on our network. We continue to offer &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.stellar.org/lumens/stellar-partnership-grant-program/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;grants of up to $2M&lt;/a&gt; for partners in these areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Exchange also promotes our vision of moving more real-world assets on the blockchain. ICOs are already coming to Stellar because we’re cheap, scalable, and fast. See Mobius’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/mobius-network/mobius-we-did-it-ae32826f2c2a&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We Did It!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; announcement, posted just a few days ago, for their impression of our platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2018, we will put significant energy into bringing a wider variety of financial instruments on to the network. SDEX will be the exchange of first resort for all Stellar tokens, and we foresee a future where, say, carbon credits, oil futures, and the latest digital asset are all traded together—cheaply and quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Secondary Product Objective: Better Ecosystem Support&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We recognize that our platform is only as useful as the tools built on top of it. As noted, we’re seeing more interest in Stellar than ever before, from randos and !randos alike, and we want to make sure it’s easy for anyone to begin building on our network. We need a robust and informed community of developers and entrepreneurs alongside us to become a global financial protocol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2018, we plan:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;– better overall brand communication&lt;br/&gt;– more implementation walk-throughs to help people get going&lt;br/&gt;– better technical documentation, including release notes&lt;br/&gt;– continued improvement to our Horizon API and the surrounding SDKs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will also continue to award lumens, via the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.stellar.org/lumens/build/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Stellar Build Challenge&lt;/a&gt;, to people and businesses who contribute to our ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Goal #2: &lt;span&gt;Lightning Network on Stellar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technology has always been the strongest part of the Stellar story, and we will make it even stronger in 2018. We’ve noted the market demand for more private channel transactions on Stellar, and we will integrate Lightning in 2018. For those of you unfamiliar with the tech, this &lt;em&gt;Vice&lt;/em&gt; piece is a decent introduction: &lt;a href=&quot;https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/gyw9aq/wtf-is-the-lightning-network-and-will-it-save-bitcoin&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;WTF is the Lightning Network and Will It Save Bitcoin?&lt;/a&gt; Of course, unlike Bitcoin, Stellar doesn’t need “saving” . . . we’re just going from a good place to an even better one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lightning will have a huge positive effect on Stellar’s long-term scalability and &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@thecryptoconomy/the-barely-discussed-incredible-benefit-of-the-lightning-network-4ce82c75eb58&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;security&lt;/a&gt;. We’ve been aware of Lightning’s potential for Stellar &lt;a href=&quot;http://jedmccaleb.com/blog/bitcoin-lightning-stellar/&quot;&gt;for a while&lt;/a&gt;, and we’ve recently collaborated with Stellar advisor and Bitcoin Core developer &lt;a href=&quot;https://rubin.io/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Jeremy Rubin&lt;/a&gt; to optimize our implementation. Expect a detailed technical post on this soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We intend to extend Stellar Core with a &lt;strong&gt;Bump Sequence&lt;/strong&gt; operation; you can see our progress and read the formal spec on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/stellar/stellar-protocol/issues/53&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Secondary Tech Objectives&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hardening&lt;/em&gt;: as we make performance improvements, the network must remain resilient and secure. We will reduce the attack surface at the protocol layer by adding invariant support (with checks performed constantly by the validator). Those checks will reduce the impact of bugs on the ledger state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Decentralization:&lt;/em&gt; we want to make it easier to run a full validator. In order for the network to be as decentralized as possible, the overhead of running nodes should be minimal. By making nodes more reliable and self sufficient, node operators can spend time doing other things. We’ll also be making improvements to how we monitor the network’s health, and the way nodes exchange data, by revisiting some characteristics of the peer-to-peer code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always, encourage our community to modify and audit Core’s protocol implementation. We are rewriting part of the data layer for improved code semantics. Check our github to get involved:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/stellar&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://github.com/stellar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/stellar/go&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://github.com/stellar/go&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/stellar/stellar-core&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://github.com/stellar/stellar-core&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/stellar/horizon&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://github.com/stellar/horizon&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;That’s It&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those of you hoping for splashy partnership announcements, that’s not our goal here. Also, at a philosophical level, we believe that applauding our &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt;th partner is less important than ensuring existing partnerships are successful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We closed 37 partners last year and highlighted a few, including &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ibm.com/press/us/en/pressrelease/53290.wss&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;IBM&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://tempo.eu.com/en&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Tempo&lt;/a&gt;, in our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.stellar.org/blog/Q1-2018-stellar-and-state-of-crypto/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Stellar and the State of Cryptocurrency&lt;/a&gt; post from last week. Corporate development work will continue: we’ve planned major partnership events around the world this Spring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, we are focused on making sure Stellar as a platform is ready for the vastly increased attention, growth, and scrutiny to come in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 17:14:48 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>manojlds</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>2018 Stellar Roadmap - Stellar</og:title>
<og:description>Hello and welcome. First of all, before we dig into our strategic goals for the upcoming year, I want to …</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.stellar.org/blog/2018-Stellar-Roadmap/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.stellar.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/stellar-randos-per-week.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.stellar.org/blog/2018-Stellar-Roadmap/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Senator asks FBI director to name the cryptographers who support backdoors</title>
<link>https://gizmodo.com/senator-demands-fbi-director-explain-his-encryption-bac-1822400040</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://gizmodo.com/senator-demands-fbi-director-explain-his-encryption-bac-1822400040</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrapper lazy-image&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-permalink-sub-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;js_lightbox-wrapper lightbox-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.kinja-img.com/gawker-media/image/upload/s--AbB5F2TH--/c_scale,fl_progressive,q_80,w_800/ftfrbwp9m4iklz19lupg.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lazyload ls-lazy-image-tag&quot; data-sizes=&quot;auto&quot; data-width=&quot;1024&quot; data-chomp-id=&quot;ftfrbwp9m4iklz19lupg&quot; data-format=&quot;jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Christopher Wray prepares to testify during his confirmation hearing before the Senate Judiciary Committee July 12, 2017. Photo: Getty&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One US senator is calling out the director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation for pushing the moronic notion that there is somehow a good way to add backdoors to encryption used to protect devices like Apple’s iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-cyber-fbi/fbi-chief-calls-unbreakable-encryption-urgent-public-safety-issue-idUSKBN1EY1S7&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; onclick=&quot;window.ga('send', 'event', 'Embedded Url', 'External link', 'https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-cyber-fbi/fbi-chief-calls-unbreakable-encryption-urgent-public-safety-issue-idUSKBN1EY1S7', {metric25:1})&quot;&gt;speech&lt;/a&gt; earlier this month, FBI Director Christopher Wray carried on the time-honored agency tradition of claiming that Silicon Valley can backdoor encryption safely if its workforce just &lt;em&gt;nerds&lt;/em&gt; a little bit harder. The argument, made by Wray and other officials before him, is that the tech industry’s best and brightest are just being recalcitrant and could offer up a golden key for law enforcement to access encrypted communications if they really wanted to. After all, these are the people that created self-driving cars, the thinking goes. Why can’t they break encryption in a good way while they’re at it?&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The problem, according to Wray, is that law enforcement is stymied by phone encryption, which is now widespread. During his January 9th speech at the International Conference on Cyber Security in New York, Wray called the prevalence of encryption an “urgent public safety issue” and said it had prevented law enforcement from accessing some 7,800 devices in the last fiscal year. Tech companies, Wray said, “should be able to design devices that both provide data security and permit lawful access with a court order.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But this is exactly what cryptographers and tech companies have repeatedly warned they can’t do, arguing that creating “lawful access” would also open the door to all sorts of hackers and malicious actors, undermining the security of the entire internet in the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wray’s speech undoubtedly spurred frustration in Silicon Valley, and it appears he pissed off Sen. Ron Wyden as well. During Wray’s confirmation process last summer, Wyden pressed him on the topic of encryption. Wray claimed he hadn’t formed a policy position on the issue, and Wyden requested that Wray consult with him before going public with his position. That apparently didn’t happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;js_ad-mobile-dynamic js_ad-dynamic ad-mobile-dynamic&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-unit js_ad-unit hide-contents ad-mobile js_ad-mobile&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-mobile-inner&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ad-label proxima&quot;&gt;&lt;small class=&quot;proxima&quot;&gt;Advertisement&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wyden.senate.gov/download/?id=B31DD6FF-98E8-490C-B491-7DE6C7559C71&amp;amp;download=1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; onclick=&quot;window.ga('send', 'event', 'Embedded Url', 'External link', 'https://www.wyden.senate.gov/download/?id=B31DD6FF-98E8-490C-B491-7DE6C7559C71&amp;amp;download=1', {metric25:1})&quot;&gt;letter&lt;/a&gt; sent to Wray today, Wyden chastised him for advocating “a flawed policy that would harm American security, liberty, and our economy” and for not contacting Wyden prior to giving his speech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wyden ripped into Wray’s speech:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your stated position parrots the same debunked arguments espoused by your predecessors, all of whom ignored the widespread and vocal consensus of cryptographers. For years, these experts have repeatedly stated that what you are asking for is not, in fact, possible. Building secure software is extremely difficult, and vulnerabilities are often introduced inadvertently in the design process. Eliminating these vulnerabilities is a mammoth task, and experts are unified in their opinion that introducing deliberate vulnerabilities would likely create catastrophic unintended consequences that could debilitate software functionality and security entirely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Democratic senator also demanded that Wray release a list of the cryptographers he’d met with to form his opinions on encryption, specifically identifying which experts advised backdooring encryption:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to learn more about how you arrived at and justify this ill-informed policy proposal. Please provide me with a list of the cryptographers with whom you’ve personally discussed this topic since our July 2017 meeting and specifically identify those experts who advised you that companies can feasibly design government access features into their products without weakening cybersecurity. Please provide this information by February 23, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re guessing it’s a short list.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 16:45:33 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>enraged_camel</dc:creator>
<og:title>Senator Demands FBI Director Explain His Encryption Backdoor Bullshit</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://i.kinja-img.com/gawker-media/image/upload/s--A0iU-DWI--/c_fill,fl_progressive,g_center,h_450,q_80,w_800/ftfrbwp9m4iklz19lupg.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>https://gizmodo.com/senator-demands-fbi-director-explain-his-encryption-bac-1822400040</og:url>
<og:description>One US senator is calling out the director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation for pushing the moronic notion that there is somehow a good way to add backdoors to encryption used to protect devices like Apple’s iPhone.</og:description>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://gizmodo.com/senator-demands-fbi-director-explain-his-encryption-bac-1822400040</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Robinhood Crypto – Invest in Bitcoin and other cryptocurrencies</title>
<link>https://crypto.robinhood.com/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://crypto.robinhood.com/</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;62.353846153846&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robinhood Financial LLC and Robinhood Crypto, LLC are wholly-owned subsidiaries of Robinhood Markets, Inc. Equities and options are offered to self-directed customers by Robinhood Financial. Robinhood Financial is a member of the Financial Industry Regulatory Authority (FINRA) and the Securities Investor Protection Corporation (SIPC), which protects securities customers of its members up to $500,000 (including $250,000 for claims for cash). Explanatory brochure available upon request or at www.sipc.org. Cryptocurrency trading is offered through an account with Robinhood Crypto. Robinhood Crypto is not a member of FINRA or SIPC. Cryptocurrencies are not stocks and your cryptocurrency investments are not protected by either FDIC or SIPC insurance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting “early access” to options or Web is defined as signing up with a valid email address for a spot in Robinhood Financial’s respective waitlist queues for Web or for options. Getting “early access” to Robinhood Crypto is defined as signing up with a valid email address for a spot in Robinhood Crypto’s waitlist queue. Early access to the waitlist for Web, options, or Robinhood Crypto should in no way be construed as confirmation that a brokerage account with Robinhood Financial has been opened or will even be approved for opening. Priority may be given to Robinhood Gold subscribers and existing customers of Robinhood Financial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Free trading of stocks and options refers to $0 commissions for Robinhood Financial self-directed individual cash or margin brokerage accounts that trade U.S. listed securities via mobile devices or Web. Relevant SEC &amp;amp; FINRA fees may apply. Please see the &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://d2ue93q3u507c2.cloudfront.net/assets/robinhood/legal/RHF%20Retail%20Commisions%20and%20Fees%20Schedule.pdf&quot;&gt;Commission and Fee Schedule&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robinhood Financial is currently registered in the following &lt;a href=&quot;https://d2ue93q3u507c2.cloudfront.net/assets/robinhood/legal/RHF%20Jurisdictions.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;jurisdictions&lt;/a&gt;. This is not an offer, solicitation of an offer, or advice to buy or sell securities, or open a brokerage account in any jurisdiction where Robinhood Financial is not registered. Additional information about your broker can be found by clicking&lt;a href=&quot;https://brokercheck.finra.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Margin trading involves interest charges and risks, including the potential to lose more than deposited or the need to deposit additional collateral in a falling market. Before using margin, customers must determine whether this type of trading strategy is right for them given their specific investment objectives, experience, risk tolerance, and financial situation. For more information please see Robinhood Financial’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://d2ue93q3u507c2.cloudfront.net/assets/robinhood/legal/RHF%20Margin%20Account%20Disclosure.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Margin Disclosure Statement&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://d2ue93q3u507c2.cloudfront.net/assets/robinhood/legal/RHF%20Margin%20Agreement.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Margin Agreement&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.finra.org/Investors/SmartInvesting/AdvancedInvesting/MarginInformation/P005927&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;FINRA Investor Information&lt;/a&gt;. These disclosures contain information on Robinhood Financial’s lending policies, interest charges, and the risks associated with margin accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investors should consider the investment objectives and unique risk profile of Exchange Traded Funds (ETFs) carefully before investing. ETFs are subject to risks similar to those of other diversified portfolios. Leveraged and Inverse ETFs may not be suitable for all investors and may increase exposure to volatility through the use of leverage, short sales of securities, derivatives and other complex investment strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although ETFs are designed to provide investment results that generally correspond to the performance of their respective underlying indices, they may not be able to exactly replicate the performance of the indices because of expenses and other factors. A prospectus contains this and other information about the ETF and should be read carefully before investing. Customers should obtain prospectuses from issuers and/or their third party agents who distribute and make prospectuses available for review. ETFs are required to distribute portfolio gains to shareholders at year end. These gains may be generated by portfolio rebalancing or the need to meet diversification requirements. ETF trading will also generate tax consequences. Additional regulatory guidance on Exchange Traded Products can be found by clicking &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sec.gov/investor/alerts/etfs.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Options transactions may involve a high degree of risk. Please review the options disclosure document entitled the Characteristics and Risks of Standardized Options available through &lt;a href=&quot;https://about.robinhood.com/legal&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://about.robinhood.com/legal&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theocc.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://www.theocc.com&lt;/a&gt; to learn more about the risks associated with options trading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;83.025695931478&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Third party information provided for product features, communications, and communications emanating from social media communities, market prices, data and other information available through Robinhood Markets, Inc., Robinhood Financial LLC or Robinhood Crypto, LLC are meant for informational purposes only and are not intended as an offer or solicitation for the purchase or sale of any financial instrument or cryptocurrency or as an official confirmation of any transaction. The information provided is not warranted as to completeness or accuracy and is subject to change without notice. Any information about Robinhood Crypto on any Robinhood website (including &lt;a href=&quot;https://robinhood.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.robinhood.com&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.robinhood.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;blog.robinhood.com&lt;/a&gt;), the Robinhood platform, e-mails, or any other communications, are meant for informational purposes only and are not intended as an offer, solicitation, or advertisement for Robinhood Crypto or any goods or services offered by Robinhood Crypto. The Robinhood website provides its users links to social media sites and email. The linked social media and email messages are pre-populated. However, these messages can be deleted or edited by users, who are under no obligation to send any pre-populated messages. Any comments or statements made herein do not reflect the views of Robinhood Markets Inc., Robinhood Financial LLC, Robinhood Crypto, LLC, or any of their subsidiaries or affiliates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investors should be aware that system response, execution price, speed, liquidity, market data, and account access times are affected by many factors, including market volatility, size and type of order, market conditions, system performance, and other factors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All investments involve risk and the past performance of a security, or financial product does not guarantee future results or returns. Keep in mind that while diversification may help spread risk it does not assure a profit, or protect against loss, in a down market. There is always the potential of losing money when you invest in securities, or other financial products. Investors should consider their investment objectives and risks carefully before investing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cryptocurrency is a digital representation of value that functions as a medium of exchange, a unit of account, or a store of value, but it does not have legal tender status. Cryptocurrencies are sometimes exchanged for U.S. dollars or other currencies around the world, but they are not currently backed nor supported by any government or central bank. Their value is completely derived by market forces of supply and demand, and they are more volatile than traditional currencies. Trading in cryptocurrencies comes with significant risks, including volatile market price swings or flash crashes, market manipulation, and cybersecurity risks. In addition, cryptocurrency markets and exchanges are not regulated with the same controls or customer protections available in equity, option, futures, or foreign exchange investing. Cryptocurrency trading requires knowledge of cryptocurrency markets. In attempting to profit through cryptocurrency trading, you must compete with traders worldwide. You should have appropriate knowledge and experience before engaging in substantial cryptocurrency trading. Cryptocurrency trading may not generally be appropriate, particularly with funds drawn from retirement savings, student loans, mortgages, emergency funds, or funds set aside for other purposes. Cryptocurrency trading can lead to large and immediate financial losses. Under certain market conditions, you may find it difficult or impossible to liquidate a position quickly at a reasonable price. This can occur, for example, when the market for a particular cryptocurrency suddenly drops, or if trading is halted due to recent news events, unusual trading activity, or changes in the underlying cryptocurrency system. Several federal agencies have also published advisory documents surrounding the risks of virtual currency. For more information see, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://files.consumerfinance.gov/f/201408_cfpb_consumer-advisory_virtual-currencies.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CFPB’s Consumer Advisory&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cftc.gov/idc/groups/public/@customerprotection/documents/file/customeradvisory_urvct121517.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CFTC’s Customer Advisory&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://investor.gov/additional-resources/news-alerts/alerts-bulletins/investor-alert-bitcoin-other-virtual-currency&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;SEC’s Investor Alert&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.finra.org/investors/alerts/bitcoin-more-bit-risky&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;FINRA’s Investor Alert&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;© 2018 Robinhood. All rights reserved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 16:07:54 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>uptown</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://d2ue93q3u507c2.cloudfront.net/assets/marketing/images/og/robinhood.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://crypto.robinhood.com</og:url>
<og:description>Invest in cryptocurrencies, stocks, ETFs, and options commission-free — all in one app.</og:description>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://crypto.robinhood.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why I left Google (HN search results)</title>
<link>https://hn.algolia.com/?query=why%20i%20left%20google&amp;sort=byPopularity&amp;prefix&amp;page=0&amp;dateRange=all&amp;type=story</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://hn.algolia.com/?query=why%20i%20left%20google&amp;sort=byPopularity&amp;prefix&amp;page=0&amp;dateRange=all&amp;type=story</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://hn.algolia.com/?query=why%20i%20left%20google&amp;sort=byPopularity&amp;prefix&amp;page=0&amp;dateRange=all&amp;type=story&quot;&gt;https://hn.algolia.com/?query=why%20i%20left%20google&amp;sort=byPopularity&amp;prefix&amp;page=0&amp;dateRange=all&amp;type=story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16231658&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16231658&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Points: 305&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 183&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 15:52:38 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kelukelugames</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://hn.algolia.com/?query=why%20i%20left%20google&amp;sort=byPopularity&amp;prefix&amp;page=0&amp;dateRange=all&amp;type=story</og:url>
<og:title>HN Search powered by Algolia</og:title>
<og:description>Hacker News Search, millions articles and comments at your fingertips.</og:description>
<og:image>https://d3nb9u6x572n0.cloudfront.net/yc-logo.png</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://hn.algolia.com/?query=why%20i%20left%20google&amp;sort=byPopularity&amp;prefix&amp;page=0&amp;dateRange=all&amp;type=story</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Waze Carpool</title>
<link>https://www.waze.com/carpool/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.waze.com/carpool/</guid>
<description>&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;194&quot;&gt;Every day, millions of drivers in thousands of cities use Waze to get around. So what if, instead of working together to outsmart traffic, we found a way for them to just get rid of it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;195&quot;&gt;People created traffic. People can end it. So, what are we waiting for? Let’s put those extra seats to work, and get everyone unstuck.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 14:29:02 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>artsandsci</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:image>/carpool/c9f48a27d89438a9eba77d31e0a2a8fe.png</og:image>
<og:description>Too many cars. So many empty seats. Let's fix that.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.waze.com/carpool/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>It’s About Time for Time Series Databases</title>
<link>https://www.nextplatform.com/2018/01/25/time-time-series-databases/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nextplatform.com/2018/01/25/time-time-series-databases/</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;posted&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;date_time&quot;&gt;January 25, 2018&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;postedby&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nextplatform.com/author/tpmn/&quot; title=&quot;Posts by Timothy Prickett Morgan&quot; rel=&quot;author&quot;&gt;Timothy Prickett Morgan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img width=&quot;200&quot; height=&quot;177&quot; src=&quot;https://3s81si1s5ygj3mzby34dq6qf-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/timescale-logo-bw-200x177.jpg&quot; class=&quot;feat-img wp-post-image&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;https://3s81si1s5ygj3mzby34dq6qf-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/timescale-logo-bw-200x177.jpg 200w, https://3s81si1s5ygj3mzby34dq6qf-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/timescale-logo-bw-300x266.jpg 300w, https://3s81si1s5ygj3mzby34dq6qf-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/timescale-logo-bw-339x300.jpg 339w, https://3s81si1s5ygj3mzby34dq6qf-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/timescale-logo-bw.jpg 508w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;To get straight to the point: nobody wants to have large grain snapshots of data for any dataset that is actually comprised of a continuous stream of data points. With the data storage and stream processing now so cost-effective (relatively speaking, of course) that anybody can do it – not just national security agencies or hedge funds and brokerages with big budgets – there is pent up demand for a SQL-friendly time series database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that is what the founders of Timescale set out to create. And while they are by no means alone in this market, the open source TimescaleDB that they let loose on the world last summer is getting traction and on the rise, in part because of the growing popularity of the PostgreSQL database engine that it overlays with time series capabilities and enhanced scalability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hyperscalers have had databases that, to varying degrees, offer time series data storage and analysis as well as SQL capabilities and ACID properties, the most notable ones being &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nextplatform.com/2017/02/15/googles-spanner-database-wont-well-clone/&quot;&gt;the Spanner database from Google&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nextplatform.com/2017/02/22/google-spanner-inspires-cockroachdb-outrun/&quot;&gt;its open source clone, CockroachDB&lt;/a&gt;. There are dozens of time series databases out there, &lt;a href=&quot;https://misfra.me/2016/04/09/tsdb-list/&quot;&gt;the majority of which are listed or commented on here&lt;/a&gt;, and the kdb+ database from Kx Systems is probably the most widely used commercial time series database installed, particularly within the trading systems of financial services firms. The kdb+ database is popular because of its wickedly fast performance, for which companies pay a premium, and Timescale is not trying to take on Kx Systems directly in this core market. In fact, company co-founders Ajay Kulkarni and Mike Freedman, who were roommates at MIT two decades ago before their paths diverged and then reconverged, tell &lt;em&gt;The Next Platform&lt;/em&gt; that they were aiming the TimescaleDB database at machine-to-machine applications but have seen early adopters use it in a number of more traditional applications, where enterprises have added time series data to traditional databases like Oracle’s eponymous database or Microsoft SQL Server or are replacing scale out clusters running the open source Redis, Cassandra, or Riak key-value stores or their commercial variants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both Kulkarni, who is Timescale’s CEO, and Freedman, who is the CTO, are serial entrepreneurs, but Freedman is notable in that he was on the Stanford University team that created the Ethane programmable network architecture that resulted in the OpenFlow software defined networking protocol that has been commercialized in various forms; he also created the CoralCDN decentralized content management system that was popular in the early days of the Web in the early 2000s, and has been a professor of computer science at Princeton University since 2007 as his other day job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two Timescale founders believe, like the rest of us, that computing comes in waves, starting with mainframes and then Unix systems and then X86 servers in the datacenter and PCs and laptops and smartphones on the desktop or in our hands, and with every leap in technology, the computers get more powerful and more useful and they generate and process more data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It used to be a PC on every desktop, and then a smartphone in every pocket, and now we are entering a new phase where there is a computer in every &lt;em&gt;thing&lt;/em&gt;, whether it is our vehicles or manufacturing lines, power plants, homes, and even our bodies,” explains Kulkarni. “We have gotten to this point where we are living with all of these machines, and businesses are swimming in machine data. The key insight we had is that no database was ready for this challenge.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://3s81si1s5ygj3mzby34dq6qf-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/timescale-database-popularity-db-engines.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-35916&quot; src=&quot;https://3s81si1s5ygj3mzby34dq6qf-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/timescale-database-popularity-db-engines.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1212&quot; height=&quot;611&quot; srcset=&quot;https://3s81si1s5ygj3mzby34dq6qf-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/timescale-database-popularity-db-engines.jpg 1212w, https://3s81si1s5ygj3mzby34dq6qf-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/timescale-database-popularity-db-engines-300x151.jpg 300w, https://3s81si1s5ygj3mzby34dq6qf-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/timescale-database-popularity-db-engines-768x387.jpg 768w, https://3s81si1s5ygj3mzby34dq6qf-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/timescale-database-popularity-db-engines-1024x516.jpg 1024w, https://3s81si1s5ygj3mzby34dq6qf-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/timescale-database-popularity-db-engines-200x101.jpg 200w, https://3s81si1s5ygj3mzby34dq6qf-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/timescale-database-popularity-db-engines-500x252.jpg 500w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1212px) 100vw, 1212px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The natural question here is: Why not? There are plenty of time series databases (or extensions to them) in the market, as we pointed out above. But it turns out that machine data is unique in that it is generated at very high volumes and it also needs to be analyzed in complex ways and usually very quickly and generally very reliably. (The eventual consistency of NoSQL datastores like Cassandra does not pass the ACID test of relational databases, which enterprises are used to.) It is one thing to use a database for consumer mobile apps, but quite another to use one to monitor and manage a nuclear power plant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Back in 2014, when we started, developers have essentially two choices,” Kulkarni continues. “They could use relational databases with SQL interfaces, which are easy to use but they don’t scale well. Or they could use NoSQL databases that scale well but were not as reliable and are harder to use. The choice between reliability and scalability was a terrible choice, and we also realized that machine data, for them most part, was time series data. It is a timestamp, some data, and some metadata around the measurement of the device.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Timescale, the idea is to reverse that terrible choice and get the reliability and SQL interface of a relational database with the speed and scalability of a NoSQL database. The important thing is that most time series data is immutable and is appended to the existing data – you don’t change it and it is tacked on in the order that events happen. This is distinct from relational databases that do online transaction processing, where rows in databases are updated as the transactions are run and more or less randomly; taking an order for an existing customer, for instance, updates the customer table to add items purchased and also updates the inventory table to show that they are no longer available for sale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://3s81si1s5ygj3mzby34dq6qf-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/timescale-github-stars.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-35917&quot; src=&quot;https://3s81si1s5ygj3mzby34dq6qf-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/timescale-github-stars.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;565&quot; height=&quot;319&quot; srcset=&quot;https://3s81si1s5ygj3mzby34dq6qf-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/timescale-github-stars.jpg 565w, https://3s81si1s5ygj3mzby34dq6qf-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/timescale-github-stars-300x169.jpg 300w, https://3s81si1s5ygj3mzby34dq6qf-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/timescale-github-stars-200x113.jpg 200w, https://3s81si1s5ygj3mzby34dq6qf-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/timescale-github-stars-500x282.jpg 500w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 565px) 100vw, 565px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of building this time series database from scratch, Timescale created an overlay on top of PostgreSQL database engine, leaving the backend engine that stores information on disks the same and allowing for all of the tools that speak to PostgreSQL to keep doing what they are doing. To be more technical, Timescale takes over the front end of the engine, taking in a query and rewrite it, doing its own query planning and execution against that engine, which is tweaked to support an abstraction layer that Timescale calls a hypertable. (This is in contrast with the MySQL open source relational database, which has a thin compatibility layer that sits on top of many different styles of storage engines.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hypertable shards data into chunks, and the chunk size is set either by the database or manually to provide good performance for transactions. The chunks are carved into the data stream based on time interval and by other columns stored in each chunk – tick data for stocks, customer location for Uber, closest cell tower for an iPhone – and each server node can have a hypertable abstracting across tens of thousands of chunks that are spread across many disk or flash drives to scale out capacity. The indexes for the chunks are stored in memory for fast scanning, and Timescale has come up with what it calls “aggressive” low level distributed query optimizations to limit the number of chunks accessed to answer a query and therefore boost performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We don’t muck around with how the data is stored on disk, and therefore we inherit all of the reliability of PostgreSQL,” explains Freedman. “We also enforce the same PostgreSQL interface, so all of the tooling for this database works with TimescaleDB. They part is in the middle is that we have figured out how to scale PostgreSQL for time series data, and we are 20X faster at inserts than PostgreSQL. And we are 10X faster than Cassandra, and unlike Cassandra, we also support full SQL.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a neat trick, and that, in part, explains how TimescaleDB is a rising star on GitHub and why the database has been downloaded over 100,000 times since it was launched last April and rolled out over the summer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the moment, TimescaleDB is an example of what we call a &lt;em&gt;scale in&lt;/em&gt; product, meaning that it can replace either a big &lt;em&gt;scale up&lt;/em&gt; system, like a NUMA machine, or &lt;em&gt;scale out&lt;/em&gt; system, like a cluster of distributed systems sharing work in a looser fashion, without needing to scale beyond a single node. At the moment, TimescaleDB is being used for fairly modest workloads, replacing systems that might have a dozen or so nodes running Cassandra or Redis with a single server that has JBODs and JBOFs for disk and flash scalability in those nodes. On such machines, the queries on time series data on a single node of TimescaleDB are running anywhere from 10X to 50X faster than on the modestly sized Redis and Cassandra clusters, and inserts of new data are around 10X faster. In the next year or so, Timescale will have a scale out version of its own for those who have larger workloads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Our initial goal is not to build the kind of scale that Google needs,” says Freedman. “But we certainly want to scale out to ten, twenty, or forty nodes with sustained performance of millions of inserts per second and petabyte scale storage.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current product supports around 100 TB of time series data on a single node, with more than 10 billion rows of data, and it can do between 100,000 and 200,000 inserts per second. The software allows for the elastic attachment of additional storage on a single server node, which means it does not have to be brought down to add capacity. The database is supported on Linux, Windows Server, and MacOS platforms, although there are no real commercial MacOS servers so it almost doesn’t count. (Pity, that.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is how TimescaleDB stacks up against the real PostgreSQL 10 database with inserts on a single row:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://3s81si1s5ygj3mzby34dq6qf-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/timescale-versus-postgres-performance-1-row.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-35919&quot; src=&quot;https://3s81si1s5ygj3mzby34dq6qf-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/timescale-versus-postgres-performance-1-row.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;685&quot; height=&quot;425&quot; srcset=&quot;https://3s81si1s5ygj3mzby34dq6qf-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/timescale-versus-postgres-performance-1-row.jpg 685w, https://3s81si1s5ygj3mzby34dq6qf-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/timescale-versus-postgres-performance-1-row-300x186.jpg 300w, https://3s81si1s5ygj3mzby34dq6qf-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/timescale-versus-postgres-performance-1-row-200x124.jpg 200w, https://3s81si1s5ygj3mzby34dq6qf-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/timescale-versus-postgres-performance-1-row-484x300.jpg 484w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 685px) 100vw, 685px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here is how it looks against PostgreSQL with 1,000 rows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://3s81si1s5ygj3mzby34dq6qf-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/timescale-versus-postgres-performance-1000-row.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-35920&quot; src=&quot;https://3s81si1s5ygj3mzby34dq6qf-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/timescale-versus-postgres-performance-1000-row.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;685&quot; height=&quot;412&quot; srcset=&quot;https://3s81si1s5ygj3mzby34dq6qf-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/timescale-versus-postgres-performance-1000-row.jpg 685w, https://3s81si1s5ygj3mzby34dq6qf-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/timescale-versus-postgres-performance-1000-row-300x180.jpg 300w, https://3s81si1s5ygj3mzby34dq6qf-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/timescale-versus-postgres-performance-1000-row-200x120.jpg 200w, https://3s81si1s5ygj3mzby34dq6qf-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/timescale-versus-postgres-performance-1000-row-500x300.jpg 500w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 685px) 100vw, 685px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The TimescaleDB software is available with an Apache 2.0 license as an open source package that includes the PostgreSQL engine. Timescale is crafting an enterprise version, which has additional governance and security features and that will likely also include the scale out extensions when they become available. Pricing has not been set yet, but it is fairly likely that the cost will be per node and fall somewhere between generic Hadoop storage and the Oracle database. (Yes, that was meant to be funny in that this is anywhere from thousands to many hundreds of thousands of dollars per node.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that things are humming along, Timescale’s founders are copping to the fact that they had already raised $3.7 million in seed funding, including investments from Spender Kimball, one of the founders of Cockroach Labs, and Rob Bearden, the CEO at Hadoop distributor Hortonworks and who used to run the SpringSource and JBoss businesses before they were sold to VMware and Red Hat, respectively. And just now, Timescale has raised $12.4 million in Series A funding, which was by Benchmark with participation from New Enterprise Associates and Two Sigma Ventures. So that is a tidy $16.1 million to help get that scale out version of TimescaleDB done and to scale up the marketing, sales, and technical staff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;robots-nocontent sd-block sd-social sd-social-icon-text sd-sharing&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Share this:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;zem_rp_wrap zem_rp_th_vertical&quot; id=&quot;zem_rp_first&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;zem_rp_content&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;related_post_title&quot;&gt;Similar Vein&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meta_tags&quot;&gt;Categories: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nextplatform.com/category/compute/&quot; rel=&quot;category tag&quot;&gt;Compute&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nextplatform.com/category/enterprise/&quot; rel=&quot;category tag&quot;&gt;Enterprise&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nextplatform.com/category/store/&quot; rel=&quot;category tag&quot;&gt;Store&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meta_tags&quot;&gt;Tags: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nextplatform.com/tag/database/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Database&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nextplatform.com/tag/postgresql/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;PostgreSQL&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nextplatform.com/tag/relational/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;relational&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nextplatform.com/tag/sql/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;SQL&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nextplatform.com/tag/time-series/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;time series&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nextplatform.com/tag/timescale/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Timescale&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nextplatform.com/tag/timescaledb/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;TimescaleDB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 12:52:45 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>okket</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>It’s About Time For Time Series Databases</og:title>
<og:description>To get straight to the point: nobody wants to have large grain snapshots of data for any dataset that is actually comprised of a continuous stream of data</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.nextplatform.com/2018/01/25/time-time-series-databases/</og:url>
<og:image>https://3s81si1s5ygj3mzby34dq6qf-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/timescale-logo-bw.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nextplatform.com/2018/01/25/time-time-series-databases/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why social media bosses don’t use social media</title>
<link>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2018/jan/23/never-get-high-on-your-own-supply-why-social-media-bosses-dont-use-social-media</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theguardian.com/media/2018/jan/23/never-get-high-on-your-own-supply-why-social-media-bosses-dont-use-social-media</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;drop-cap&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;drop-cap__inner&quot;&gt;M&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;ark Zuckerberg doesn’t use Facebook like you or me. The 33-year-old chief executive has a team of 12 moderators dedicated to deleting comments and spam from his page, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-01-18/this-team-runs-mark-zuckerberg-s-facebook-page&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline in-body-link--immersive&quot;&gt;according to Bloomberg&lt;/a&gt;. He has a “handful” of employees who help him write his posts and speeches and a number of professional photographers who take perfectly stage-managed pictures of him &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=10104183418273041&amp;amp;set=a.529237706231.2034669.4&amp;amp;type=3&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline in-body-link--immersive&quot;&gt;meeting veterans in Kentucky&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=10104177997725861&amp;amp;set=a.612287952871.2204760.4&amp;amp;type=3&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline in-body-link--immersive&quot;&gt;small-business owners in Missouri&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=10104061149435771&amp;amp;set=a.529237706231.2034669.4&amp;amp;type=3&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline in-body-link--immersive&quot;&gt;cheesesteak vendors in Philadelphia&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook’s locked-down nature means mere mortals can’t see the private posts on Zuckerberg’s timeline, but it is hard to imagine him getting into arguments about a racist relative’s post of an anti-immigration meme. And it is not just Zuckerberg. None of the company’s key executives has a “normal” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/facebook&quot; data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline in-body-link--immersive&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; presence. You can’t add them as friends, they rarely post publicly and they keep private some information that the platform suggests be made public by default, such as the number of friends they have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over at Twitter, the story is the same. Of the company’s nine most senior executives, only four tweet more than once a day on average. Ned Segal, its chief financial officer, has been on the site for more than six years and has sent fewer than two tweets a month. Co-founder Jack Dorsey, a relatively prolific tweeter, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Jack&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline in-body-link--immersive&quot;&gt;has sent about 23,000&lt;/a&gt; since the site was launched, but that is a lot less than even halfway engaged users have sent over the same period. Dorsey rarely replies to strangers and avoids discussions or arguments on the site. He doesn’t live-tweet TV shows or sporting fixtures. In fact, he doesn’t really “use” Twitter; he just posts on it occasionally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;element element-rich-link element--thumbnail element-rich-link--not-upgraded&quot; data-component=&quot;rich-link&quot; data-link-name=&quot;rich-link-2 | 1&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is a pattern that holds true across the sector. For all the industry’s focus on “eating your own dog food”, the most diehard users of social media are rarely those sitting in a position of power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a compulsive social media user. I have sent about 140,000 tweets since I joined &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/twitter&quot; data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline in-body-link--immersive&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; in April 2007 – six Jacks’ worth. I use Instagram, Snapchat and Reddit daily. I have accounts on Ello, Peach and Mastodon (remember them? No? Don’t worry). Three years ago, I managed to quit Facebook. I went cold turkey, deleting my account in a moment of lucidity about how it made me feel and act. I have never regretted it, but I haven’t been able to pull the same stunt twice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to look at the heads of the social networks and get annoyed that they didn’t understand their own sites. Regular users encounter bugs, abuse or bad design decisions that the executives could never understand without using the sites themselves. How, I would wonder, could they build the best service possible if they didn’t use their networks like normal people?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I wonder something else: what do they know that we don’t?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sean Parker, the founding president of Facebook, broke the omertà in October last year, telling a conference in Philadelphia that he was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.axios.com/sean-parker-unloads-on-facebook-2508036343.html&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline in-body-link--immersive&quot;&gt;“something of a conscientious objector” to social media&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The thought process that went into building these applications, Facebook being the first of them … was all about: ‘How do we consume as much of your time and conscious attention as possible?’ That means that we need to sort of give you a little dopamine hit every once in a while, because someone liked or commented on a photo or a post or whatever. And that’s going to get you to contribute more content and that’s going to get you … more likes and comments,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;element element-pullquote element--supporting&quot;&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;pullquote-paragraph&quot;&gt;The short-term, dopamine-driven feedback loops that we have created are destroying how society works&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;footer&gt;&lt;cite class=&quot;pullquote-cite&quot;&gt;Former Facebook executive Chamath Palihapitiya&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;“It’s a social-validation feedback loop … exactly the kind of thing that a hacker like myself would come up with, because you’re exploiting a vulnerability in human psychology. The inventors, creators – me, Mark [Zuckerberg], &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2015/oct/02/instagram-kevin-systrom-interview-working-on-time-travel&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline in-body-link--immersive&quot;&gt;Kevin Systrom&lt;/a&gt; on Instagram, all of these people – understood this consciously. And we did it anyway.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A month later, Parker was joined by another Facebook objector, former vice-president for user growth Chamath Palihapitiya. “The short-term, dopamine-driven feedback loops that we have created are destroying how society works. No civil discourse, no cooperation; misinformation, mistruth,” Palihapitiya &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2017/dec/11/facebook-former-executive-ripping-society-apart&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline in-body-link--immersive&quot;&gt;said at a conference in Stanford, California&lt;/a&gt;. “This is not about Russian ads. This is a global problem. It is eroding the core foundations of how people behave by and between each other. I can control my decision, which is that I don’t use that shit. I can control my kids’ decisions, which is that they’re not allowed to use that shit.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Palihapitiya’s statements rattled Facebook so much that the company issued a response acknowledging its past failings – a rare move for a business that, despite its mission to “connect people”, is notoriously taciturn about its shortcomings. “When Chamath was at Facebook, we were focused on building new social media experiences and growing Facebook around the world,” a company spokeswoman said. “Facebook was a very different company back then ... as we have grown, we have realised how our responsibilities have grown, too. We take our role very seriously and we are working hard to improve.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few days later, the site pulled a more interesting move, releasing the results of research that suggested that Facebook did make users feel bad – &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2017/dec/15/facebook-mental-health-psychology-social-media&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline in-body-link--immersive&quot;&gt;but only if they didn’t post enough&lt;/a&gt;. “In general, when people spend a lot of time passively consuming information – reading, but not interacting with people – they report feeling worse afterward,” &lt;a href=&quot;https://newsroom.fb.com/news/2017/12/hard-questions-is-spending-time-on-social-media-bad-for-us/&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline in-body-link--immersive&quot;&gt;two Facebook researchers said&lt;/a&gt; in a review of the existing literature. On the other hand, “actively interacting with people – especially sharing messages, posts and comments with close friends and reminiscing about past interactions – is linked to improvements in wellbeing”. How convenient.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Adam Alter, a psychologist and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/books/2017/apr/21/irresistible-by-adam-alter-review-technology-addiction&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline in-body-link--immersive&quot;&gt;the author of Irresistible&lt;/a&gt;, an examination of technology addiction, it is almost beside the point whether social media makes you happy or sad in the short term. The deeper issue is that your usage is compulsive – or even addictive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The addiction concept applies much more broadly and to many more behaviours than we perhaps thought and also therefore applies to many more people in the population,” Alter says. “Roughly half the adult population has at least one behavioural addiction. Not many of us have substance addictions, but the way the world works today there are many, many behaviours that are hard for us to resist and a lot of us develop self-undermining attachments to those behaviours that border on or become addictions.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;u-responsive-ratio&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;gu-image&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; alt=&quot;Social media taking over people's lives&quot; src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/066d67c110bd3384b5a29453680645c3022fa7c4/548_503_2740_3424/master/2740.jpg?w=300&amp;amp;q=55&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;usm=12&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=4cf3eb2c91ca8625d2118de4934d8c43&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

Our addictions to social media ‘haven’t happened accidentally’, says psychologist Adam Alter. Illustration: Jason Ford for the Guardian
&lt;p&gt;These addictions haven’t happened accidentally, Alter argues. Instead, they are a direct result of the intention of companies such as Facebook and Twitter to build “sticky” products, ones that we want to come back to over and over again. “The companies that are producing these products, the very large tech companies in particular, are producing them with the intent to hook. They’re doing their very best to ensure not that our wellbeing is preserved, but that we spend as much time on their products and on their programs and apps as possible. That’s their key goal: it’s not to make a product that people enjoy and therefore becomes profitable, but rather to make a product that people can’t stop using and therefore becomes profitable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What Parker and Palihapitiya are saying is that these companies, companies that they’ve been exposed to at the highest levels and from very early on, have been founded on these principles – that we should do everything we possibly can to hack human psychology, to understand what it is that keeps humans engaged and to use those techniques not to maximise wellbeing, but to maximise engagement. And that’s explicitly what they do.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parker and Palihapitiya aren’t the only Silicon Valley residents to open up about their unease with the habit-forming nature of modern technology. As &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2017/oct/05/smartphone-addiction-silicon-valley-dystopia&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline in-body-link--immersive&quot;&gt;the Guardian reported in October&lt;/a&gt;, a growing number of coders and designers are quitting their jobs in disillusionment at what their work entails. From Chris Marcellino – one of the inventors of Apple’s system for push notifications, who quit the industry to train as a neurosurgeon – to Loren Britcher – who created the pull-to-refresh motion that turns so many apps into miniature one-armed-bandits and is now devoting his time to building a house in New Jersey – many of the workers at the coalface of interface design have had second thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Others have had the same realisation, but have decided to embrace the awkwardness – such as LA-based retention consultants Dopamine Labs. The company offers a plugin service that personalises “moments of joy” in apps that use it. &lt;a href=&quot;https://usedopamine.com/&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline in-body-link--immersive&quot;&gt;It promises customers&lt;/a&gt;: “Your users will crave it. And they’ll crave you.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this is the case, then social media executives are simply following the rule of pushers and dealers everywhere, the fourth of the Notorious BIG’s Ten Crack Commandments: “Never get high on your own supply.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Many tech titans are very, very careful about how they privately use tech and how they allow their kids to use it and the extent to which they allow their kids access to screens and various apps and programs,” says Alter. “They will get up on stage, some of them, and say things like: ‘This is the greatest product of all time,’ but then when you delve you see they don’t allow their kids access to that same product.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;element element-pullquote element--supporting&quot;&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;pullquote-paragraph&quot;&gt;Tech by itself doesn’t want to be good ... It takes humans to make sure that the things that you do with it are good&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;footer&gt;&lt;cite class=&quot;pullquote-cite&quot;&gt;Apple chief executive Tim Cook&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last week, Apple’s chief executive, Tim Cook, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2018/jan/19/tim-cook-i-dont-want-my-nephew-on-a-social-network&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline in-body-link--immersive&quot;&gt;told the Guardian&lt;/a&gt;: “I don’t have a kid, but I have a nephew that I put some boundaries on. There are some things that I won’t allow. I don’t want them on a social network.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He added: “Technology by itself doesn’t want to be good and it doesn’t want to be bad either. It takes humans to make sure that the things that you do with it are good. And it takes humans in the development process to make sure the creation of the product is a good thing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alter says that the classic example of this approach is Cook’s predecessor, Steve Jobs, “who spoke about all the virtues of the iPad and then wouldn’t let his kids near it”. (“They haven’t used it,” Jobs &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2014/09/11/fashion/steve-jobs-apple-was-a-low-tech-parent.html&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline in-body-link--immersive&quot;&gt;told a New York Times reporter&lt;/a&gt; a few months after the iPad was released. “We limit how much technology our kids use at home.”)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is not only children. “You can see it in their own behaviour,” Alter says. “Jack Dorsey, the way he uses Twitter, it seems he’s very careful about how much time he spends. He’s obviously a very busy guy and a very high-functioning guy, but as a result he’s probably distracted by a lot of other things and he’s able to tear himself away from the platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“But that’s not true for all of the users of Twitter – many of them report being, using the colloquial term, addicted. Whether or not that’s clinical addiction, it feels to them like they would like to be doing less; it’s undermining their wellbeing. And I think that’s absolutely right: for many Twitter users, it’s sort of a black hole that sucks you in and it’s very hard to stop using the program.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is certainly how I feel about Twitter. I have tried to cut back, after realising how much of my time was spent staring at a scrolling feed of aphorisms ranging from mildly amusing to vaguely traumatic. I deleted 133,000 tweets, in an effort to reduce the feeling that I couldn’t give up on something into which I had sunk so much time. I removed the apps from my phone and my computer, forcing any interaction through the web browser. I have taken repeated breaks. But I keep coming back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is one thing to be a child with a protective parent keeping technology away from you. It is quite another to live like a technology executive yourself, defeating the combined effort of thousands of the world’s smartest people to instil a craving to open their app every day. I am not alone in struggling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;element element-rich-link element--thumbnail element-rich-link--not-upgraded&quot; data-component=&quot;rich-link&quot; data-link-name=&quot;rich-link-2 | 2&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kevin Holesh, a freelance app developer, is one of those who tried to cut back. He wrote a program, &lt;a href=&quot;https://inthemoment.io/&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline in-body-link--immersive&quot;&gt;Moment&lt;/a&gt;, that tracks how long you spend looking at your phone each day. For the average user, it is more than three hours every day. Holesh’s stats were enough to provide the motivation for change. “Once I had the hard data, that itself was helping me use my phone less. I’ve taken a few steps in that direction since, but I knew just seeing the number itself was half the battle. Seeing that number really changed my approach … I was spending an hour a day not doing anything productive, just wasting time.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Holesh eventually removed all social networks, and his work email account, from his phone. “That’s the step that helps me the most, simply not having it accessible. At first, my mission was just: find out what amount of phone time makes you happy. But now I’ve started a little more extreme approach, I’m less stressed out about news articles or my uncle posting something inflammatory on Facebook. I find I do a better job of communicating in more old-fashioned methods.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alter says willpower can help to a certain extent, while leaving things out of reach for casual, thoughtless use can help more. Ultimately, however, addictions are hard to break alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s possible that in 20 years we’ll look back at the current generation of children and say: ‘Look, they are socially different from every other generation of humans that came before and as a result this is a huge problem and maybe we need to regulate these behaviours.’ Or perhaps we’ll look back and say: ‘I don’t know what the fuss was – I’m not sure why we were so concerned.’ Until we have some evidence, until there’s something that seems tangible, I think it’s going to be very hard to get people en masse to change how they behave.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can’t bring yourself to cut back on social media, you could try following Zuckerberg’s example and hire a team of 12 to do it for you. It might not be as cheap and easy as deleting Facebook, but it is probably easier to stick to.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 08:17:54 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>imartin2k</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://www.theguardian.com/media/2018/jan/23/never-get-high-on-your-own-supply-why-social-media-bosses-dont-use-social-media</og:url>
<og:description>Developers of platforms such as Facebook have admitted that they were designed to be addictive. Should we be following the executives’ example and going cold turkey – and is it even possible for mere mortals?</og:description>
<og:image>https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/5aa3f8eb4f325ca6c4ff85144a5209de98c34429/94_70_3870_2323/master/3870.jpg?w=1200&amp;h=630&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;fit=crop&amp;crop=faces%2Centropy&amp;bm=normal&amp;ba=bottom%2Cleft&amp;blend64=aHR0cHM6Ly91cGxvYWRzLmd1aW0uY28udWsvMjAxOC8wMS8xOC9mYWNlYm9va19kZWZhdWx0LnBuZw&amp;s=892770bfe8b2a58b762357990af1da86</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>‘Never get high on your own supply’ – why social media bosses don’t use social media</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2018/jan/23/never-get-high-on-your-own-supply-why-social-media-bosses-dont-use-social-media</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Surviving 75 hours alone in the ocean</title>
<link>https://www.outsideonline.com/2275116/how-survive-75-hours-alone-ocean?utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=twitter&amp;utm_campaign=onsiteshare</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.outsideonline.com/2275116/how-survive-75-hours-alone-ocean?utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=twitter&amp;utm_campaign=onsiteshare</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;In February 2006, Robert Hewitt was scuba diving near Mana Island, off the coast of New Zealand’s North Island. Hewitt was an experienced navy diving instructor with 20 years in the service, and he told his dive buddy that he would swim back to shore himself. Instead, when he next surfaced, he had been pulled several hundred meters away by a strong current. The dive boat had moved on, and Hewitt was left alone, the tide pushing him farther and farther from shore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/29241234&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a recent issue&lt;/a&gt; of the journal &lt;em&gt;Diving and Hyperbaric Medicine&lt;/em&gt;, a team of researchers led by physiologist Heather Massey of the University of Portsmouth in the UK take a closer look at what happened next: Hewitt’s progressive deterioration over the next four days and three nights, how he survived, and what took place after his eventual rescue. It’s an interesting glimpse at a branch of extreme physiology that most of us hope we’ll never encounter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Massey’s interest isn’t purely theoretical. She’s currently training to swim across the English Channel, which will require prolonged immersion in cool water. She also took home a &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/i/web/status/818866624417689601&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;gold medal&lt;/a&gt; from the World Ice Swimming Championships last year, in temperatures just a few degrees above freezing, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://uopnews.port.ac.uk/2016/08/16/olympic-swimmers-trained-at-portsmouth/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;helped British open-water swimmers&lt;/a&gt; prepare for the Rio Olympics.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most pressing challenge facing Hewitt was the water temperature of 61 to 63 degrees Fahrenheit (16 to 17 degrees Celsius), well below body temperature. According to physiological models, when water is 59 degrees Fahrenheit (15 degrees Celsius), the median survival time is between 4.8 and 7.7 hours. Amazingly, Hewitt spent the next 75 hours in the water, drifting back and forth over a distance of nearly 40 miles before he was spotted by Navy diving friends and rescued.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, immersion in cold water produces a four-stage response. First is the “cold shock response” that triggers “an inspiratory gasp, uncontrollable hyperventilation, hypertension, and increased cardiac workload.” If you’re not ready for it, this shock response can cause you to inhale water and drown and can set off heart arrhythmias. Hewitt had two key defenses against the cold shock: a five-millimeter custom-fit wetsuit and habituation from more than 1,000 previous dives, which eventually blunts the initial shock response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the cold shock, which peaks within 30 seconds and diminishes after a few minutes, the next stage of immersion is peripheral muscle cooling. For every 1.8 degrees Fahrenheit (1 degree Celsius) that your muscles cool, your maximum muscle power drops by about 3 percent. That means you can lose the ability to swim before your core actually gets hypothermic. Hewitt did indeed lose the ability to swim at some points during his ordeal—sometimes because he lost consciousness—but he had a buoyancy compensator that kept him floating with his head above water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third stage is deep body cooling, which affects both physical and mental function and eventually results in loss of consciousness and then death. No one took Hewitt’s temperature until he had been wrapped in blankets and received warm drinks after his rescue. At that point, it was 96.3 degrees Fahrenheit (35.7 degrees Celsius), which isn’t particularly low. He did have some episodes of confusion and disorientation that suggest he was on the border of hypothermia, but it’s hard to be sure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One key factor that helped stave off hypothermia was the fact that Hewitt is (in the words of the researchers) “a large, muscular male”; at 5'11&quot; and 220 pounds, he clearly had a decent amount of insulation. In fact, for every 1 percent increase in body fat, you slow your rate of heat loss by 0.18 degrees Fahrenheit (0.1 degree Celsius) per hour—a big deal when you extrapolate to 75 hours. Hewitt also tried to maintain the fetal position, which minimizes heat loss and extends survival time in cool water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fourth and final stage of immersion, if you make it that far, is the “circum-rescue” phase. It’s apparently quite common for people to collapse during rescue, thanks in part to the change in pressure when you leave the water and the strong nervous system reaction to the idea of being rescued. With this in mind, Hewitt’s rescuers kept him horizontal to maintain blood flow to the brain and gave him “verbal encouragement” to keep fighting for his life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, cold water wasn’t the only challenge in play. Despite water, water, everywhere, dehydration is a serious problem—in fact, the squeeze of the wetsuit and water pressure shunt blood to your core, which stimulates urination, even when you’re already dehydrated. The practical guidance in situations like this is that you should avoid drinking for the first day; this will trigger hormone changes that make your body start conserving water. After that, aim to scrounge up half a liter per day. Hewitt used his mask and wetsuit jacket to collect rainwater, but this was far below his needs. When he was rescued, he drank a liter and a half of water, then received another six liters intravenously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prolonged soaking in seawater, along with the friction from his wetsuit and fins, damaged Hewitt’s skin pretty badly. When found (put your spoon down for a moment), “his body was covered with sea lice feeding on his macerated skin.” And then there’s the psychological challenge, both during and after the ordeal. By the third day, he was contemplating (and half-heartedly attempting) suicide, but he managed to keep fighting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can we extract any lessons from Hewitt’s ordeal? Well, wearing a wetsuit and weighing more than 200 pounds obviously helped, but those aren’t particularly useful takeaways. Staying in the fetal position—sometimes known as the “heat escape lessening posture,” or HELP—was a good idea. Ultimately, the most pointed lesson, and the one Hewitt himself now spreads as a water safety advocate, is that he shouldn’t have been in that situation in the first place. Rather than diving alone, he should have aborted the dive and joined another group or, at the very least, used a surface-marker buoy to flag his position. “In some ways, Rob almost contributed to his own demise,” the police search team leader said bluntly. “He took some shortcuts.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, shit sometimes happens. And if it does, the other big lesson to keep in mind is that in defiance of all the physiological models, Rob Hewitt survived for an astounding 75 hours alone in the cold water. If you find yourself out there, don’t give up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Discuss this post on&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/sweatscience&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Twitter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;or&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/sweatscience1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Facebook&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, sign up for the Sweat Science&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://alexhutchinson.us10.list-manage1.com/subscribe?u=16b257be614b5f18187d3b50a&amp;amp;id=4111e620a3&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;email newsletter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, and check out my forthcoming book,&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2g7dSKS&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Endure: Mind, Body, and the Curiously Elastic Limits of Human Performance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 00:19:56 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>DanBC</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>How to Survive 75 Hours Alone in the Ocean</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.outsideonline.com/2275116/how-survive-75-hours-alone-ocean</og:url>
<og:description>A new case study digs into the medical records of a lost diver's incredible survival story</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.outsideonline.com/sites/default/files/styles/full-page/public/2018/01/17/survival-at-sea-sweat-science_h.jpg?itok=VPP2RKx_</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.outsideonline.com/2275116/how-survive-75-hours-alone-ocean</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Eve programming language project is winding down</title>
<link>https://groups.google.com/d/msg/eve-talk/YFguOGkNrBo/EozaCfheAQAJ</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://groups.google.com/d/msg/eve-talk/YFguOGkNrBo/EozaCfheAQAJ</guid>
<description>&lt;tr readability=&quot;14.817905918058&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;messageContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;10.866464339909&quot;&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; readability=&quot;24.202579666161&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi everyone,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite some promising leads and lots of meetings over the past several months, we weren't able to find a good home for Eve. Unfortunately that means we have to start the process of winding the company down and looking for other opportunities for ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to thank all of you for your support over the years. Through your feedback and championing we accomplished more than we could have ever imagined. Thank you for following along and believing in the vision we set out - it means a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div readability=&quot;19.555555555556&quot;&gt;I think Josh and Corey are going to follow up with more of their thoughts, so I don't want to steal their thunder, but this has been an amazing experience and we covered so much of the space that it's hard to even begin to summarize what we've learned. Once things settle down a bit more, I hope to write out more of our thoughts and show some things we hadn't shown publicly yet. We also open sourced the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/witheve/eve-native&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;0.4 Rust runtime&lt;/a&gt; today, so that's there to play with if you want (though there are definitely still some bugs in it). It's been a long 6 years between Light Table and Eve and, at least for the immediate future, I'll be taking a much needed break - though I'm sure I won't stay away from the problem for too long :)&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wish you all the best of luck - so long, and thanks for all the fish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 22:56:20 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mrry</dc:creator>
<og:title>Eve is winding down</og:title>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://groups.google.com/forum/#!msg/eve-talk/YFguOGkNrBo/EozaCfheAQAJ</og:url>
<og:description>Posted by Chris Granger, Jan 24, 2018 12:12 PM</og:description>
<og:image>http://www.google.com/images/icons/product/groups-128.png</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://groups.google.com/forum/?_escaped_fragment_=msg/eve-talk/YFguOGkNrBo/EozaCfheAQAJ</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Zstandard – Real-time data compression algorithm</title>
<link>http://facebook.github.io/zstd/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://facebook.github.io/zstd/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Zstandard is a real-time compression algorithm, providing high compression ratios. It offers a very wide range of compression / speed trade-off, while being backed by a very fast decoder (see &lt;a href=&quot;http://facebook.github.io/zstd/#benchmarks&quot;&gt;benchmarks&lt;/a&gt; below). It also offers a special mode for small data, called &lt;a href=&quot;http://facebook.github.io/zstd/#small-data&quot;&gt;dictionary compression&lt;/a&gt;, and can create dictionaries from any sample set. Zstandard library is provided as open source software using a BSD license.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 22:25:31 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>josephscott</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://facebook.github.io/zstd/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>