<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Qualcomm and Apple agree to drop all litigation</title>
<link>https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2019/04/qualcomm-and-apple-agree-to-drop-all-litigation/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2019/04/qualcomm-and-apple-agree-to-drop-all-litigation/</guid>
<description>Qualcomm invents breakthrough technologies that transform how the world connects, computes and communicates. When we connected the phone to the Internet, the mobile revolution was born. Today, our inventions are the foundation for life-changing products, experiences, and industries. As we lead the world to 5G, we envision this next big change in cellular technology spurring a new era of intelligent, connected devices and enabling new opportunities in connected cars, remote delivery of health care services, and the IoT — including smart cities, smart homes, and wearables. Qualcomm Incorporated includes our licensing business, QTL, and the vast majority of our patent portfolio. Qualcomm Technologies, Inc., a subsidiary of Qualcomm Incorporated, operates, along with its subsidiaries, all of our engineering, research and development functions, and all of our products and services businesses, including, the QCT semiconductor business. For more information, visit Qualcomm’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.qualcomm.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.qualcomm.com/news/onq&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;OnQ blog&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/qualcomm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.facebook.com/qualcomm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; pages.</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 19:23:12 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>saeedjabbar</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Qualcomm and Apple agree to drop all litigation</og:title>
<og:description>The companies have reached a global patent license agreement and a chipset supply agreement.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2019/04/qualcomm-and-apple-agree-to-drop-all-litigation/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/defaultog.png.large.png?201904161906</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2019/04/qualcomm-and-apple-agree-to-drop-all-litigation/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>EU gives &amp;#039;high-level&amp;#039; protection to whistleblowers</title>
<link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-47936682</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-47936682</guid>
<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape has-caption full-width lead&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                &lt;img class=&quot;js-image-replace&quot; alt=&quot;People hold placards reading 'stand up for the whistle-blowers', as they demonstrate outside the courthouse in Luxembourg&quot; src=&quot;https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/320/cpsprodpb/9E75/production/_106456504_gettyimages-524412274.jpg&quot; width=&quot;976&quot; height=&quot;549&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    The legislation would mark the first time whistleblowers have been given EU-wide protection
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body__introduction&quot;&gt;Whistleblowers across the European Union have won greater protection under landmark legislation aimed at encouraging reports of wrongdoing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new law, approved by the European Parliament on Tuesday, shields whistleblowers from retaliation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It also creates &quot;safe channels&quot; to allow them to report breaches of EU law. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is the first time whistleblowers have been given EU-wide protection.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The rules have previously been in the hands of member states, resulting in a range of vastly different approaches. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The law was &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.europarl.europa.eu/news/en/press-room/20190410IPR37529/protecting-whistle-blowers-new-eu-wide-rules-approved&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link-external&quot;&gt;approved by 591 votes, with 29 votes against and 33 abstentions. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;What does the law say? &lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new legislation gives whistleblowers who report breaches of EU law a &quot;high level of protection&quot;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It establishes &quot;safe channels&quot; for reporting the information, both within an organisation and to public authorities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If no appropriate action is taken or in cases where reporting to the authorities would not work, whistleblowers are permitted to make a public disclosure – including by speaking to the media. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.europarl.europa.eu/RegData/docs_autres_institutions/commission_europeenne/com/2018/0218/COM_COM(2018)0218_EN.pdf&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link-external&quot;&gt;The law&lt;/a&gt; protects whistleblowers against dismissal, demotion and other forms of punishment. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;National authorities are required to train officials in how to deal with whistleblowers under the legislation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class=&quot;story-body__line&quot;/&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;You may also be interested in:&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;hr class=&quot;story-body__line&quot;/&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;Why was it introduced?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The legislation says whistleblowers play a &quot;key role&quot; in preventing breaches of EU law and protecting society.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But, it argues, &quot;potential whistleblowers are often discouraged from reporting their concerns or suspicions for fear of retaliation.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;We should protect whistleblowers from being punished, sacked, demoted or sued in court for doing the right thing for society,&quot; European Commission Vice President Frans Timmermans said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;This will help tackle fraud, corruption, corporate tax avoidance and damage to people's health and the environment.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Transparency International has said the &quot;pathbreaking legislation&quot; will also give employers &quot;greater legal certainty around their rights and obligations&quot;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class=&quot;story-body__line&quot;/&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;High-profile leaks&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul class=&quot;story-body__unordered-list&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;LuxLeaks: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-36662636&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;Whistleblowers working for PricewaterhouseCoopers leaked documents&lt;/a&gt; exposing favourable tax arrangements offered by Luxembourg to some of the world's biggest companies while European Commission President Jean-Claude Juncker was prime minister.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Paradise Papers: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-41880153&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;Millions of financial documents were leaked&lt;/a&gt;, detailing offshore tax-avoidance schemes. The papers revealed details about how the ultra-wealthy secretly invest cash in offshore tax havens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Cambridge Analytica: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-43465968&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;The British data analytics company was accused of harvesting the personal data of millions of Facebook users&lt;/a&gt; without their consent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Panama Papers:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-46449696&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;About 11 million confidential documents were leaked from a Panamanian law firm&lt;/a&gt;, showing how it helped clients to launder money, dodge sanctions and evade tax.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr class=&quot;story-body__line&quot;/&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;What were the previous rules on whistleblowing? &lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Laws on whistleblowing were previously handled by the individual member states, resulting in major differences in legislation across the bloc. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The European Commission says just 10 members - France, Hungary, Ireland, Italy, Lithuania, Malta, the Netherlands, Slovakia, Sweden and the UK - had a &quot;comprehensive law&quot; protecting whistleblowers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;Has everyone supported the legislation?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;During the talks, some states sought to water down the legislation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Luxembourg, Ireland and Hungary wanted tax matters to be excluded, but they were ultimately retained, according to Reuters.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If member states fail to properly implement the law, the European Commission can take formal disciplinary steps against the country and could ultimately refer the case to the European Court of Justice.  &lt;/p&gt;
            </description>
<pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 15:16:01 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>toyg</dc:creator>
<og:title>Whistleblowers get EU-wide protection</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>New rules approved by the European Parliament aim to encourage people to report breaches of EU law.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-47936682</og:url>
<og:image>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/9E75/production/_106456504_gettyimages-524412274.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-GB</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-47936682</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>5G Is Likely to Put Weather Forecasting at Risk</title>
<link>https://hackaday.com/2019/04/16/5g-buildout-likely-to-put-weather-forecasting-at-risk/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://hackaday.com/2019/04/16/5g-buildout-likely-to-put-weather-forecasting-at-risk/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;If the great Samuel Clemens were alive today, he might modify the famous meteorological quip often attributed to him to read, “Everyone complains about weather forecasts, but I can’t for the life of me see why!” In his day, weather forecasting was as much guesswork as anything else, reading the clouds and the winds to see what was likely to happen in the next few hours, and being wrong as often as right. Telegraphy and better instrumentation made forecasting more scientific and improved accuracy steadily over the decades, to the point where we now enjoy 10-day forecasts that are at least good for planning purposes and three-day outlooks that are right about 90% of the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What made this increase in accuracy possible is supercomputers running sophisticated weather modeling software. But models are only as good as the raw data that they use as input, and increasingly that data comes from on high. A constellation of satellites with extremely sensitive sensors watches the planet, detecting changes in winds and water vapor in near real-time. But if the people tasked with running these systems are to be believed, the quality of that data faces a mortal threat from an unlikely foe: the rollout of 5G cellular networks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Where’s the Water?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To understand how a new generation of wireless technology can deleteriously impact weather forecasting, it helps to take a look at exactly what powers the weather, and what these satellites are looking at. Our weather is largely the result of differences between air masses. Pressure, temperature, and moisture, each determined by energy inputs from the Sun, all team up in a complex manner to determine where and when clouds will form and which direction the winds will come from. Remotely sensing these differences is the key to accurately forecasting the weather.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The satellites that watch our weather are largely passive sensor platforms that measure the energy reflected or emitted by objects below them. They gather data on temperature and moisture — pressure is still measured chiefly by surface measurements and by radiosondes — by looking at the planet in different wavelengths. Temperature is measured mainly in the optical wavelengths, both visible and infrared, but water vapor is a bit harder to measure. That’s where microwaves come in, and where weather prediction stands to run afoul of the 5G rollout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/AMSU-A1_instrument.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;354362&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://hackaday.com/2019/04/16/5g-buildout-likely-to-put-weather-forecasting-at-risk/amsu-a1_instrument/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/AMSU-A1_instrument.jpg&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1600,1253&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;AMSU-A1_instrument&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/AMSU-A1_instrument.jpg?w=400&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/AMSU-A1_instrument.jpg?w=798&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-354362 size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/AMSU-A1_instrument.jpg?w=400&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;313&quot; srcset=&quot;https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/AMSU-A1_instrument.jpg 1600w, https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/AMSU-A1_instrument.jpg?resize=250,196 250w, https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/AMSU-A1_instrument.jpg?resize=400,313 400w, https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/AMSU-A1_instrument.jpg?resize=798,625 798w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 400px) 100vw, 400px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;NASA’s Advanced Microwave Sounding Unit (ASMU-A1). Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.esa.int/Our_Activities/Observing_the_Earth/Meteorological_missions/MetOp/About_AMSU-A1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ESA&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything on Earth – the plants, the soil, the surface water, and particularly the gases in the atmosphere – both absorb and, to a lesser degree, emit microwave radiation. Measuring those signals from space is the business of satellites carrying microwave radiometers, essentially sensitive radio receivers tuned to microwave frequencies. By looking at the signals received at different wavelengths, and by adding in information about the polarization of the signal, microwave radiometry can tell us what’s going on within a vertical column of the atmosphere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For water vapor, 23.8-GHz turns out to be very useful, and very much in danger of picking up interference from 5G, which will use frequencies very close to that. Since microwave radiometers are passive receivers, they’ll see pretty much everything that emits microwave signals in that range, like the thousands of cell sites that will be needed to support a full 5G rollout. Losing faint but reliable water vapor signals in a sea of 5G noise is the essential problem facing weather forecasters, and it’s one they’ve faced before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Real World Consequences&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At &lt;a href=&quot;https://ams.confex.com/ams/2019Annual/meetingapp.cgi/ModuleProgramBook/0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the 2019 annual meeting of the American Meteorological Society&lt;/a&gt;, Sidharth Misra, a research engineer at NASA’s Jet Propulsion Laboratory, presented data showing how commercial enterprises can have unintended consequences on the scientific community. Between 2004 and 2007, satellite-based microwave radiometers detected an increase in noise in a curious arc across the top of the United States. A similar signal was detected by another satellite, with the addition of huge signals being returned from the waters off each coast and the Great Lakes. The signals turned out to be reflections from geosynchronous direct TV satellites, bouncing off the surface and swamping the water vapor signals the weather satellites were trying to measure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/interference.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;354359&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://hackaday.com/2019/04/16/5g-buildout-likely-to-put-weather-forecasting-at-risk/interference/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/interference.png&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1861,1012&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;interference&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/interference.png?w=400&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/interference.png?w=800&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-354359 size-large&quot; src=&quot;https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/interference.png?w=800&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;435&quot; srcset=&quot;https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/interference.png 1861w, https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/interference.png?resize=250,136 250w, https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/interference.png?resize=400,218 400w, https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/interference.png?resize=800,435 800w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Reflections from DTV satellites can effectively blind microwave radiometers. Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://ams.confex.com/ams/2019Annual/videogateway.cgi/id/51518?recordingid=51518&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;AMS meeting panel discussion, “The Wizard Behind the Curtain?—The Important, Diverse, and Often Hidden Role of Spectrum Allocation for Current and Future Environmental Satellites and Water, Weather, and Climate”&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But surely the scientists are overreacting, right? Can losing one piece of data from as complex a puzzle as weather prediction really have that much of an impact? Probably yes. The water vapor data returned by microwave radiometers like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.esa.int/Our_Activities/Observing_the_Earth/Meteorological_missions/MetOp/About_AMSU-A1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Advanced Microwave Sounding Unit&lt;/a&gt; (AMSU) aboard a number of weather satellites is estimated to reduce the error of weather forecasts by 17%, the largest contributor by far among a group of dozens of other modalities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The loss of microwave water vapor data could have catastrophic real-world consequences. In late October of 2012, as Hurricane Sandy barreled up the East coast of the United States, forecasts showed that the storm would take a late turn to the northwest and make landfall in New Jersey. An analysis of the forecast if the microwave radiometer data had not been available showed the storm continuing in a wide arc and coming ashore in the Gulf of Maine. The availability of ASMU data five days in advance of the storm’s landfall bought civil authorities the time needed to prepare, and probably reduced the casualties caused by the “Storm of the Century”, still the deadliest storm of the 2012 season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/sandy.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;354361&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://hackaday.com/2019/04/16/5g-buildout-likely-to-put-weather-forecasting-at-risk/sandy/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/sandy.png&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1159,755&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;sandy&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/sandy.png?w=400&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/sandy.png?w=800&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-354361 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/sandy.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1159&quot; height=&quot;755&quot; srcset=&quot;https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/sandy.png 1159w, https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/sandy.png?resize=250,163 250w, https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/sandy.png?resize=400,261 400w, https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/sandy.png?resize=800,521 800w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1159px) 100vw, 1159px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Superstorm Sandy would have been predicted to track into the Gulf of Maine (red) without microwave water vapor data. It actually landed in New Jersey, as predicted five days out with the satellite data (black).
&lt;h2&gt;Auction Time&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So exactly where are we with this process? The &lt;a href=&quot;https://auctiondata.fcc.gov/public/projects/auction102&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;FCC auction&lt;/a&gt; of licenses for the Upper Microwave Flexible Use Service (UMFUS), which offers almost 3000 licenses in the 24-GHz band, began on March 14, 2019, despite a letter from NASA Administrator Jim Bridenstine and Secretary of Commerce Wilbur Ross requesting that it be delayed. FCC Chairman Ajit Pai rejected the request, stating that there was an “absence of any technical basis for the objection.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will the 5G rollout negatively impact weather forecasts? It’s not clear. Licensees are required to limit out-of-band emissions, but with so many 5G sites needed to cover the intended service areas, and with the critical 23.8-GHz water vapor frequency so close to the UMFUS band, there’s not much room for error. And once the 5G cat is out of the bag, it’ll be difficult to protect that crucial slice of the microwave spectrum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever happens, it doesn’t look good for weather forecasting. The UMFUS auction proceeds apace, and has raised almost $2 billion so far. Companies willing to spend that much on spectrum will certainly do whatever it takes to realize their investment, and in the end, not only will science likely suffer, but lives may be put at risk for the sake of 5G as our toolset for predicting dangerous weather faces this new data-gathering challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 15:02:52 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>szczys</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>How 5G is Likely to Put Weather Forecasting at Risk</og:title>
<og:url>https://hackaday.com/2019/04/16/5g-buildout-likely-to-put-weather-forecasting-at-risk/</og:url>
<og:description>If the great Samuel Clemens were alive today, he might modify the famous meteorological quip often attributed to him to read, “Everyone complains about weather forecasts, but I can’t fo…</og:description>
<og:image>https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/5G.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://hackaday.com/2019/04/16/5g-buildout-likely-to-put-weather-forecasting-at-risk/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Tech Industry-Funded Think Tanks Work to Overturn California Privacy Law</title>
<link>https://theintercept.com/2019/04/16/consumer-privacy-laws-california/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://theintercept.com/2019/04/16/consumer-privacy-laws-california/</guid>
<description>&lt;div data-reactid=&quot;195&quot; readability=&quot;167.77195281782&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;After years of&lt;/u&gt; ignoring the issue, lawmakers on Capitol Hill are suddenly engaged in a furious fight over enacting national legislation to establish basic online privacy rights for consumers. As with the crafting of much legislation dealing with complicated issues, legislators are relying on experts to help codify the consumer protections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a twist that is all too familiar in Washington, D.C., however, many of the groups that have positioned themselves as expert voices on consumer privacy are pushing for a bill that hews closely to tech industry interests. Lawmakers who are famously ignorant on technology issues are hearing largely from an army of industry lobbyists and experts funded by social media companies, online platforms, data brokers, advertisers, and telecommunication giants — the very same corporate interests that profit from the collection and sale of internet data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take the Center for Democracy and Technology, one of the most prominent privacy-centered Beltway think tanks. The group is considered to be well-respected among congressional staffers, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnet.com/news/privacy-advocates-tell-senators-what-they-want-in-a-data-protection-law/&quot;&gt;routinely&lt;/a&gt; testifies before committees on privacy legislation, and is a prime mover in the national online privacy bill discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Late last year, the organization circulated draft federal privacy legislation that would &lt;a href=&quot;https://cdt.org/insight/cdts-federal-privacy-legislation-section-by-section-analysis-and-explanation/&quot;&gt;nullify&lt;/a&gt; major state-level regulations. In March, when the Senate Judiciary Committee held its first hearing of the session on how to formulate a federal consumer privacy standard, the center’s Privacy and Data Project Director Michelle Richardson testified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Center for Democracy and Technology is also awash in corporate money from the tech sector. Amazon, Verizon, and Google are among the corporate donors that each provide over $200,000 to the group. AT&amp;amp;T, Verizon, Uber, and Twitter are also major donors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last Wednesday, the group hosted its annual gala, known as “&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/techpromcdt?f=tweets&amp;amp;vertical=default&amp;amp;src=hash&quot;&gt;Tech Prom&lt;/a&gt;,” which &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/SpencerOverton/status/1116141809586135040&quot;&gt;brought&lt;/a&gt; together lobbyists and government affairs officials from leading Silicon Valley and telecom firms. Facebook, Google, Amazon, and Microsoft purchased tables at the event and served as sponsors, a privilege that came in exchange for a &lt;a href=&quot;https://cdt.org/files/2019/03/Tech-Prom-2019-Sponsorships.pdf&quot;&gt;$35,000&lt;/a&gt; donation to the center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;stylized pull-right&quot; data-shortcode-type=&quot;pullquote&quot; data-pull=&quot;right&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Every one of these groups working on privacy that takes corporate money should return it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These industry-funded think tanks are pushing legislation in a direction that would have weak enforcement mechanisms, give consumers limited means for recourse, and perhaps most importantly for the industry, roll back state-level privacy standards being enacted by state legislatures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The stakes of the online privacy fight could have ramifications the world over. American standards on data collection could shape political and business decisions across the world, said Jeff Chester, president of the Center for Digital Democracy, a privacy think tank that opposes overturning of state-level privacy laws.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This is much bigger than Cambridge Analytica,” Chester said. Cambridge Analytica was involved in a scandal when, while working on behalf of Donald Trump’s presidential campaign, the data analytics firm illicitly scraped consumer data from Facebook in order to build advanced voter-targeting methods. The events stoked outrage over Facebook’s security around its users’ private data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chester said the money lavished by the tech industry on privacy think tanks was tantamount to funding lobbyists. “These groups should not take a dime of corporate money. This is basically lobbying dollars,” Chester said. “I think every one of these groups working on privacy that takes corporate money should return it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, actual tech industry lobby groups are pushing federal legislation along the same lines as that proposed by the tech-funded think tanks. One of the largest lobbying groups for Silicon Valley, NetChoice, has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-01-30/tech-group-favors-privacy-bill-that-preempts-tougher-state-laws&quot;&gt;rallied behind&lt;/a&gt; Sen. Marco Rubio’s, R-Fla., privacy bill. His bill would roll back state regulation and place enforcement authority largely under the Federal Trade Commission, a notoriously toothless federal agency with no rule-making power, instead of letting consumers directly sue tech companies under the law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NetChoice lobbies on behalf of Facebook, Google, Twitter, Airbnb, and eBay, among other tech companies. (Pierre Omidyar, founder of The Intercept&lt;em&gt;’&lt;/em&gt;s parent company, First Look Media, is the chair of eBay.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;The sudden moves&lt;/u&gt; around online privacy kicked into high gear with a state-level privacy law that passed in California last year. In June 2018, state legislators passed California Consumer Privacy Act, a surprise turn of events that enshrined the strongest consumer privacy standard in the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The law, set to take effect next year, gives California residents the power to view the types of data companies collect from them, request that the data be deleted, and allows residents to declare that their data not be sold to third parties. In response, similar bills are being proposed in several &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infosecurity-magazine.com/infosec/washington-privacy-law-1-1-1/&quot;&gt;other&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lexology.com/library/detail.aspx?g=e453c554-8292-49a5-8203-a40ed60fe3ad&quot;&gt;states&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lobbying push to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2019/02/08/theres-going-be-fight-here-weaken-it-inside-lobbying-war-over-californias-landmark-privacy-law/?utm_term=.3b84c6e96ab4&quot;&gt;water down&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bizjournals.com/sacramento/news/2019/03/06/silicon-valley-lobbies-hard-to-kill-off.html&quot;&gt;overturn&lt;/a&gt; the California law has been so intense that some federal legislators are raising questions about whether the urgency for a national standard is simply a vehicle for lobbyists to push pre-emption, provisions in the federal law that would supersede and roll back the state-level privacy laws.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Are we here just because we don’t like the California law, and we just want the federal pre-emption law to shut it down?” asked Sen. Maria Cantwell, D-Wash., during one of the recent hearings on the bill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Center for Democracy and Technology’s proposal for a draft bill contained such a pre-emption provision. The proposed bill would overturn the California Consumer Privacy Act and the Illinois Biometric Information Privacy Act, which compels technology companies to obtain consent from customers before collecting biometric data, including fingerprints and facial recognition models. Both Google and Facebook could faced &lt;a href=&quot;http://fortune.com/2019/01/28/facebook-face-scanning-bipa/&quot;&gt;lawsuits&lt;/a&gt; under the Illinois law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Center for Democracy and Technology’s vice president for external affairs, Brian Wesolowski, defended the group’s draft proposal. “It’s a stronger bill than the California one when it comes to the privacy rights of all,” he said in an email to The Intercept, adding that the group maintains “clear lines between funding and policy positions.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The proposed draft from the Center for Democracy and Technology, however, does not reproduce the California law’s right for consumers to opt out of data collection. The California law also provides consumers with what is called a private right of action — meaning that they can file a lawsuit if the state attorney general does not act when companies violate the law — while the Center for Democracy and Technology’s draft simply calls for companies to respond to complaints within 30 days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div data-reactid=&quot;205&quot; readability=&quot;57.628034814475&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another think tank, the Center for Information Policy Leadership, which bills itself as a leading voice on privacy, has also called for a provision pre-empting state-level laws. In a memo for policymakers &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.informationpolicycentre.com/uploads/5/7/1/0/57104281/cipl_principles_for_a_revised_us_privacy_framework__21_march_2019_.pdf&quot;&gt;released&lt;/a&gt; last month, the group said the new federal bill should “preempt a patchwork of inconsistent state laws.” Similarly, another group, the Technology Policy Institute, has asked that a federal privacy law pre-empts state regulation and explicitly called for any new national standard to have “fewer restrictions on the use of information.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both groups receive funding from Amazon, Google, and Facebook — and both strongly defended their positions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markus Heyder, a vice president at the Center for Information Policy Leadership, told The Intercept in an email, “CIPL’s mission is not to advocate specific industry positions, but to help develop globally consistent policies and approaches to privacy regulation that maximize both the appropriate protection of consumers from privacy risks and harms and reasonable data use and innovation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David Fish, a spokesperson for the Technology Policy Institute, dismissed concerns about industry funding, noting that his group’s position is “not supported universally by industry.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like NetChoice, the tech industry lobby group, the Center for Information Policy Leadership and the Center for Democracy and Technology have both called for a weak enforcement standard that rests largely with the Federal Trade Commission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The push for pre-emption, however, is not shared by all privacy and consumer think tanks. Electronic Privacy Information Center, Public Citizen, and U.S. Public Interest Research Group are among several major advocacy organizations that have demanded that any federal standard not pre-empt state privacy law. “Federal privacy legislation that preempts stronger state laws would only benefit technology companies at the expense of the public,” the groups wrote in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/document/december-2018-preemption-letter&quot;&gt;letter&lt;/a&gt; to lawmakers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jeff Chester’s group, the Center for Digital Democracy, also signed the letter demanding a redline on pre-emption. None of the four groups that signed the letter take corporate money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 14:21:54 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>aburd</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://theintercept.com/2019/04/16/consumer-privacy-laws-california/</og:url>
<og:description>Silicon Valley-funded privacy think tanks’ positions on a federal online privacy bill mirror the tech industry’s lobbying priorities.</og:description>
<og:image>https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2019/04/silicon-valley-privacy-law-illustration-09-03-03-1555431940.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;q=90&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=1200&amp;h=800</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Silicon Valley-Funded Privacy Think Tanks Fight in D.C. to Unravel State-Level Consumer Privacy Protections</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://theintercept.com/2019/04/16/consumer-privacy-laws-california/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Rust: Beyond the Typechecker</title>
<link>https://blog.merigoux.ovh/en/2019/04/16/verifying-rust.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.merigoux.ovh/en/2019/04/16/verifying-rust.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;This post will be different from the previous ones, since I’m going to present some of the early results of my work as a PhD student at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://prosecco.gforge.inria.fr/&quot;&gt;Prosecco team&lt;/a&gt; in Inria Paris, under the supervision of &lt;a href=&quot;https://prosecco.gforge.inria.fr/personal/karthik/&quot;&gt;Karthikeyan Bhargavan&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://jonathan.protzenko.fr/&quot;&gt;Jonathan Protzenko&lt;/a&gt;. Indeed, my goal is to bring to Rust the power of deductive verification techniques to improve the level of assurance one can have about the correctness of their programs. So far, I can present two compelling case studies from &lt;a href=&quot;https://servo.org/&quot;&gt;Servo&lt;/a&gt; that showcase what using verification techniques can look like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;when-do-we-know-programs-are-correct&quot;&gt;When do we know programs are correct?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, we have to understand what it means for a program to be correct. Usually, programs are tested on a set of selected inputs against expected outputs. If the output of one test case matches, we can be a little bit more confident that our program is correct. But how can we be sure it will work in all situations? What if our test cases missed a corner case in our algorithm?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One way to increase confidence is to test the program in more systematic ways, for instance by doing unit testing or measuring the code coverage and making sure it’s 100%. Let us say that we are testing the function:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-rust&quot; data-lang=&quot;rust&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;fn&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;foo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;i32&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;i32&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;i32&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;...&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unit testing means writing tests for every sub-function used in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;foo&lt;/code&gt;. Having a code coverage of 100% on &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;foo&lt;/code&gt; means that your test case explore all the branches in the code of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;foo&lt;/code&gt;: if &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;foo&lt;/code&gt; contains a test &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;x + y &amp;gt; 1&lt;/code&gt;, it means we should have at least one test case where &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;x + y &amp;gt; 1&lt;/code&gt;, and one where &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;x + y &amp;lt;= 1&lt;/code&gt;. But even a 100% code coverage does not guarantee that your tests reach all the program states that could cover bugs; overflow bugs are not always detected by such testing for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Testing a program in such a systematic way is time-consuming, and requires the programmer to create a mental model on &lt;em&gt;how the code should work&lt;/em&gt;, in order to create test cases as relevant as possible. When all the tests are written with this methodology, there are two correlated outcomes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;The programmer has thought about the behavior of its code for all combinations of the input variables;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The level of assurance about the correctness of the code is high enough for a production release.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, these methods cannot tell you if you missed something; even if you carefully test your code to prevent a certain category of bug, there will always be a possibility that a bug of this category remains hidden somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At &lt;a href=&quot;https://popl19.sigplan.org/&quot;&gt;POPL19&lt;/a&gt;, Mark Harman presented Sapiens, the very sophisticated analysis tool that detect and fixes bugs over the Facebook codebase. However, &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/CbQ6bJlOU7A?t=2792&quot;&gt;he admits&lt;/a&gt; that all the static analysis and machine learning techniques used in Sapiens have so far been devoted to fix null pointer related bugs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why doesn’t this category of bugs exist for Rust programs? Simply because you cannot write a program that contains a null-pointer error. Indeed, the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Option&lt;/code&gt; type forces you to declare when writing the program which values can be &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;None&lt;/code&gt; and which values cannot. By making sure you think about this beforehand, the Rust compiler guides you into thinking about what happens to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;None&lt;/code&gt; values inside your program &lt;em&gt;for all combinations of input values&lt;/em&gt;. Thanks to that mechanism, you do not have to care anymore about null pointer errors when testing the correctness of your program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What we see here is that the type system, by rejecting at compilation time programs susceptible to be buggy, can remove whole categories of bugs out of the way, enabling resources for testing more advanced correctness properties about the program. The specificity of Rust’s type system is that it is capable of guaranteeing that your program is memory safe and data-race free, two properties associated to categories of bugs both dreaded and notoriously hard to debug in C or C++.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how can the typechecking algorithm be so sure that what it claims is true for all combinations of inputs? Let’s take another example that builds on the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Option&lt;/code&gt; type:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-rust&quot; data-lang=&quot;rust&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;fn&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;bar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;Option&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;i32&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;Option&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;i32&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;i32&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;match&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;Some&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;None&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;Some&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;Some&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;None&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;None&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may have already noticed that this program is incorrect; indeed, the Rust compiler reports:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;error[E0004]: non-exhaustive patterns: `(None, Some(_))` not covered
 --&amp;gt; src/main.rs:5:9
  |
2 |   match (x,y) {
  |         ^^^^^ pattern `(None, Some(_))` not covered&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can the typechecker know that you missed this pattern? Actually, what the typechecker does is that it tries to &lt;em&gt;prove&lt;/em&gt; that for all &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;x&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;y&lt;/code&gt; of types &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Option&amp;lt;i32&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;, the function will return a value of type &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;i32&lt;/code&gt;. And how would you do to prove such a property in a more mathematical setting? Simply by considering all the cases associated with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Option&lt;/code&gt;: either &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Some&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;None&lt;/code&gt;. Two cases for two different values so 4 cases in total; since the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;match&lt;/code&gt; statement has only 3, one case is missing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This example shows a correspondance between the code and mathematical concepts, and this idea known as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Curry%E2%80%93Howard_correspondence&quot;&gt;Curry-Howard correspondence&lt;/a&gt; is the foundation of modern programming language design and research. The goal of of this field of Computer Science is to get rid of more and more categories of bugs by proving their absence from programs, and to allow programmers to specify the correctness of their programs thanks to more expressive mathematical theories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-plan-for-bringing-verification-to-rust-developers&quot;&gt;A plan for bringing verification to Rust developers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are multiple ways to produce software that has been verified partially or totally. A lot of very successful techniques involve writing the program into a very high-level &lt;em&gt;specification&lt;/em&gt; language for which we know exactly how every language construct behaves. However, Rust was not designed with this goal in mind and lacks such a complete and official language formalisation. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://plv.mpi-sws.org/rustbelt&quot;&gt;Rustbelt&lt;/a&gt; project has brilliantly started to tackle this problem by proving that the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;unsafe&lt;/code&gt; part of the standard library does not put in jeopardy all the properties that &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;safe&lt;/code&gt; code using the standard library should enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More recently, the team developing the Viper verification framework &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.research-collection.ethz.ch/handle/20.500.11850/311092&quot;&gt;developed a frontend for a subset of Rust&lt;/a&gt; that allows for the automatic verification of memory safety and some arithmetic properties. Internally, Viper uses a verification technique called &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Symbolic_execution&quot;&gt;symbolic execution&lt;/a&gt;, which builds proofs completely free of any user indications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During my PhD, I will experiment with a different verification technique called deductive verification. In this setting, every function of the program has a &lt;em&gt;precondition&lt;/em&gt; (a set of things that need to be true for the function to be called) and a &lt;em&gt;postcondition&lt;/em&gt; (a set of things that need to be true at the end of the function). The verification consists in proving that the body of the function makes the postcondition true, supposing the precondition is true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How could these preconditions and post-conditions be specified in Rust? The syntax and details are &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang-nursery/wg-verification/issues/14&quot;&gt;being discussed&lt;/a&gt;, but it could look like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-rust&quot; data-lang=&quot;rust&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;struct&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Point&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;i32&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;i32&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;fn&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;is_diagonal&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;p&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Point&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;bool&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;p&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;py&quot;&gt;.x&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;p&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;py&quot;&gt;.y&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;cp&quot;&gt;#[requires=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;is_diagonal(p)&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;cp&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;cp&quot;&gt;#[ensures=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;is_diagonal(new_p)&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;cp&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;fn&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;double&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;p&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Point&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;new_p&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Point&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Point&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;p&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;py&quot;&gt;.x&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;p&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;py&quot;&gt;.x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;p&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;py&quot;&gt;.y&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The function &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;is_diagonal&lt;/code&gt; is the &lt;em&gt;specification&lt;/em&gt; of the function &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;double&lt;/code&gt;, and it is not intended to be executed. Rather, it serves as a mathematical description of the function. But how to prove this postcondition? Here, we just need to prove that &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;2 * p.y == p.x + p.x&lt;/code&gt; under the assumption that &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;p.x == p.y&lt;/code&gt;. Rather than building an &lt;em&gt;ad hoc&lt;/em&gt; verification framework for Rust, I am planning to use &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fstar-lang.org/&quot;&gt;F*&lt;/a&gt;, a semi-automatic proof assistant based on deductive verification that uses the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Z3Prover/z3&quot;&gt;Z3&lt;/a&gt; theorem prover to alleviate the proof burden for the user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the Rust typechecker is very powerful and already partially verified thanks to projects like Rustbelt, I will focus on verifying properties not captured by the type system of Rust. Specifically, full functional correctness with properties like arithmetic correctness, in-bounds array accesses, state machines correctness, functional correctness with respect to an abstract specification or security properties. My main PhD work will be to produce a tool, Rox*, most likely integrated in some form to the Rust compiler, that will translate Rust programs into F* code that can later be verified automatically or with additional F* user annotations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rust is very expressive and sophisticated, so I will use a reasonable subset that allows programs meaningful enough so that verification is relevant for them. This subset will probably be built upon &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1903.00982&quot;&gt;Oxide&lt;/a&gt;, a new formalisation that focuses on single-threaded safe code using selected primitives from the standard library. So far, I have produced two case studies that showcase how my work could improve the assurance of correctness of real-world Rust programs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;case-studies--textinput-and-bloom-filter&quot;&gt;Case studies : &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;TextInput&lt;/code&gt; and bloom filter&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two case studies are taken out of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://servo.org/&quot;&gt;Servo&lt;/a&gt; project, a new parallel browser engine written in Rust and sponsored by Mozilla. They are available &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/denismerigoux/rox-star&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. In each case, I identified a piece of code that could benefit from some verification; then I manually translated the Rust code into functionally equivalent pure F* code and proved some properties on the F* code that increase our confidence on the Rust code. I plan to automate this translation later but these case studies help me evaluate how this approach could work before diving in the compiler development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two case studies are presented in two separate posts &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.merigoux.ovh/en/2019/04/16/textinput.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.merigoux.ovh/en/2019/04/16/bloom-filter.html&quot;&gt;there&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion-and-future-work&quot;&gt;Conclusion and future work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These two cases studies helped me identity how verification could benefit real-world pieces of Rust code. Some properties could be specified lightly inside Rust and then be proven automatically, while others require more knowledge of a proof assistant like F*. Not all code needs a confidence level requiring verification, and most of the time systematic testing is enough. However, verification could sometimes be faster than systematic testing, and offer a peace of mind that testing will never provide. The advantage of this method is that it is incremental: you can start from a codebase that just typechecks, and then go on proving one property or invariant at a time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Different verification techniques (symbolic execution, deductive verification) each have their advantages and drawbacks that depend on what you want to prove, so it is important that a future Rust plugin for verification allows to target different verification frameworks. I am planning to use &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1903.00982&quot;&gt;Oxide&lt;/a&gt; as a semantic-full intermediate language accessible after Rust HIR; making it a plaftorm for all the later translations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of my work will not be foundational, in the sense that I am not trying to verify any properties related to the type system of Rust. I do not intend to tackle the difficult problem of interaction between unsafe and safe Rust code; &lt;a href=&quot;http://plv.mpi-sws.org/rustbelt&quot;&gt;Rustbelt&lt;/a&gt; is the correct way to do it. Rather, the focus of my PhD will be to go &lt;em&gt;beyond the typechecker&lt;/em&gt; and enable gradual verification of higher-level properties about Rust code, some examples of which can be seen in the case studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting formal methods into Rust has drawn attention of a number of researchers and companies, that are gathered in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://rust-lang.zulipchat.com/#narrow/stream/183875-wg-formal-methods&quot;&gt;Rust formal methods group&lt;/a&gt;. I hope my future work will help the Rust community to get more familiar with verification techniques and how they can be efficiently used to increase the level of confidence about the correctness of various Rust programs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 14:18:24 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Supermighty</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://denis.merigoux.fr/en/thumbnail.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Literal translations • Rust: beyond the typechecker</og:title>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.merigoux.ovh/en/2019/04/16/verifying-rust.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Notre Dame fire and the future of history</title>
<link>https://www.wired.com/story/the-notre-dame-fire-and-the-future-of-history/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.wired.com/story/the-notre-dame-fire-and-the-future-of-history/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lede&quot;&gt;Some of the&lt;/span&gt; wood that burned in the cathedral of Notre Dame in Paris on Monday was put in place in the year 1160. The beams and exterior of the roof over the nave, the long main section of the building, date from between 1220 and 1240. Nearly a millennium ago it was forest; today, after a catastrophe that cuts to the heart of French culture and human history, it’s ash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It was one of the oldest—until today—surviving roofs of that kind,” says Robert Bork, an architectural historian at the University of Iowa. “It’s incomparable.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt;The fire began Monday evening, around 6:30 pm, in the church’s attic. The building’s familiar towers and flying buttresses loomed over the Ile de la Cité for centuries, prompting the author Victor Hugo to locate Notre Dame not only at the literal center of the city of Paris but also at its historical center, as a symbol. Flames and a column of smoke made it even more striking, and as the flames spread the potential impact of the blaze became more clear. President Emmanuel Macron canceled a speech. Four hundred firefighters mustered. The cathedral’s lead-and-wood spire, built by Eugène-Emmanuel Viollet-le-Duc in 1860 as part of a controversial remodel, caught fire and fell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt;By Monday night, the art and treasured objects kept in the cathedral had been saved, it seemed. But architectural historians around the world were emailing each other frantically: If the lower three-quarters of the building resist, if the stone walls stand, it’ll be possible to imagine restoring Notre Dame. “If the fire burns out while the stone vaults are intact, then the repair is a repair,” Bork says. “If the vaults start to crack and fall down, then the building is going to be lost. We’d be talking about rebuilding, not a repair.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt;Parisian fire brigades held the line. They kept the fire from spreading into the towers of the western face of the cathedral. The wood—itself an architectural treasure—was lost. “Cathedrals like Chartres had all burned off,” Bork says. “This was quite special, and it was from the time that they were really developing roof techniques.” But the rest of the building seems to have been spared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt;As a landmark, Notre Dame lives on in uncountable drawings, paintings, and photographs, not to mention the memories of people who visited, worshipped, and listened to music amid its incomparable acoustics. But because it survived largely intact into the digital era, Notre Dame lives on in the virtual world, too—and that may make its restoration all the more complete. For the last half-decade or so, an architectural historian named Andrew Tallon worked with laser scanners to capture the entirety of the cathedral’s interior and exterior in meticulous &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.nationalgeographic.com/2015/06/150622-andrew-tallon-notre-dame-cathedral-laser-scan-art-history-medieval-gothic/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;3D point clouds&lt;/a&gt;. His billion points of light revealed a living structure; the magnificent flying buttresses had indeed held the walls true, but the Gallery of Kings, statues on the western facade, were a foot out of plumb, Tallon told &lt;em&gt;National Geographic&lt;/em&gt; in 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt;Just as it had in Victor Hugo's day, the entire building had in fact fallen into disrepair by then. In 2017, the problems became too serious to ignore. &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/09/28/world/europe/paris-notre-dame-renovation.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; on stacks of masonry, fallen or removed, in the gardens. Gargoyles had given way to plastic pipes to drain away rainwater. A remodel was imperative, though as &lt;em&gt;Time&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://time.com/4876087/notre-dame-cathedral-is-crumbling/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt;, it wasn’t clear who would pay for it. This is the renovation project that was underway when the fire started, and architects now hope that Tallon’s scans may provide a map for keeping on track whatever rebuilding will have to take place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt;Tallon died late last year, and his mentor, a pioneer in using modern engineering forensics in historic architecture named Robert Mark, died in early 2019. “Both of them loved this building,” Bork says. “I’m just glad they didn’t have to see this.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt;As for what happens next, no one seems sure yet. In a statement, Macron insisted the cathedral would be rebuilt. And even if France finds the money to do so, what exactly will that entail? An exact copy, perhaps using Tallon’s scans? Something different? “This has not ever happened before in my lifetime, so I don’t have a paradigm to go to,” Bork says. “Original hand craftsmanship is irreplaceable. When you restore it, it’s not exactly the same thing. You lose information. You can tell sometimes when a stone has been carved by the kind of chisel marks on it. You can tell sometimes the chemical content of the mortar.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt;That texture and detail—and the knowledge to be gained by studying it—is what a fire burns away. A new wall doesn’t contain any of that, even if it looks exactly like what once stood. “Do we clean it up and make it all look unified, or do we try to let the memory remain?” Bork asks. “Every time they have a cathedral that needs restoration and tender loving care, there’s the question of, do you make it Disneyland, or do you let it decay? In this case, God willing, the cathedral will have some of its original structure left, and they’ll put it back as best as they can.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;paywall&quot;/&gt;&lt;h3 class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt;More Great WIRED Stories&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 13:12:18 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pricklyPaper</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>The Notre Dame Fire and the Future of History</og:title>
<og:description>The fire turned the thousand-year-old roof to ash. But a digital replica of the cathedral could help make its restoration all the more complete.</og:description>
<og:image>https://media.wired.com/photos/5cb4ffc3d7df712212ad11de/191:100/pass/notredamefire-RTX6RSC7.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>https://www.wired.com/story/the-notre-dame-fire-and-the-future-of-history/</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.wired.com/story/the-notre-dame-fire-and-the-future-of-history/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Facebook documents show plans to sell access to user data discussed for years</title>
<link>https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/social-media/mark-zuckerberg-leveraged-facebook-user-data-fight-rivals-help-friends-n994706</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/social-media/mark-zuckerberg-leveraged-facebook-user-data-fight-rivals-help-friends-n994706</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;tabletNewsletter___Av6eE&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;container___jsHMh news___34TC8 dn-print&quot; data-test=&quot;newsletter-signup&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;signupBackground___27LhS&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;signupTitle___15fvr&quot;&gt;Breaking News Emails&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;signupForeground___2FAE6&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get breaking news alerts and special reports. The news and stories that matter, delivered weekday mornings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;button class=&quot;animateSubscribeButton___EAiad signupButton___Vnoko founders-cond lh-none f4 fs-normal ls-normal pv6&quot;&gt;SUBSCRIBE&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;mb7&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;time class=&quot;relative z-1&quot; datetime=&quot;Tue Apr 16 2019 08:30:00 GMT+0000 (UTC)&quot;&gt;April 16, 2019, 8:30 AM GMT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Olivia Solon and Cyrus Farivar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Facebook CEO Mark Zuckerberg oversaw plans to consolidate the social network’s power and control competitors by treating its users’ data as a bargaining chip, while publicly proclaiming to be protecting that data, according to about 4,000 pages of leaked company documents largely spanning 2011 to 2015 and obtained by NBC News.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The documents, which include emails, webchats, presentations, spreadsheets and meeting summaries, show how Zuckerberg, along with his board and management team, found ways to tap Facebook’s trove of user data — including information about friends, relationships and photos — as leverage over companies it partnered with.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;In some cases, Facebook would reward favored companies by giving them access to the data of its users. In other cases, it would deny user-data access to rival companies or apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;inlineVideo___3ZAlE&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;pt4 pl4 pr8 pt5-m pl6-m pr9-m info___3BGcG&quot;&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;infoText___2xq7T f2 ttu mt3&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;date___2i7u0&quot;&gt;April 16, 2019&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;03:26&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;For example, Facebook gave Amazon extended access to user data because it was spending money on Facebook advertising and partnering with the social network on the launch of its Fire smartphone. In another case, Facebook discussed cutting off access to user data for a messaging app that had grown too popular and was viewed as a competitor, according to the documents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;All the while, Facebook was formulating a strategy to publicly frame these moves as a way of protecting user privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Private communication between users is “increasingly important,” Zuckerberg said in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2014/05/23/technology/facebook-offers-privacy-checkup-to-all-1-28-billion-users.html&quot;&gt;2014 New York Times interview&lt;/a&gt;. “Anything we can do that makes people feel more comfortable is really good.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;related related--relatedContent related___2RfEH single___1bpFv dn-print&quot; data-test=&quot;related&quot;&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;But the documents show that behind the scenes, in contrast with Facebook’s public statements, the company came up with several ways to require third-party applications to compensate Facebook for access to its users’ data, including direct payment, advertising spending and data-sharing arrangements. While it’s not unusual for businesses that are working together to share information about their customers, Facebook has access to sensitive data that many other companies don’t possess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Facebook ultimately decided not to sell the data directly but rather to dole it out to app developers who were considered personal “friends” of Zuckerberg or who spent money on Facebook and shared their own valuable data, the documents show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Facebook denied that it gave preferential treatment to developers or partners because of their ad spending or relationship with executives. The company has not been accused of breaking the law.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;mr3&quot;&gt;A man poses for photos in front of the Facebook sign on the company's campus in Menlo Park, California, in 2014.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;f2 ls-tight gray-80 ws-tight founders-mono dib&quot;&gt;Jeff Chiu / AP file&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;About 400 of the 4,000 pages of documents have &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/12/05/technology/facebook-emails-privacy-data.html&quot;&gt;previously&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/facebook-considered-charging-for-access-to-user-data-1543454648&quot;&gt;been&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2019/mar/02/facebook-global-lobbying-campaign-against-data-privacy-laws-investment&quot;&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; by other media outlets, and also by a member of the British Parliament who has been &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/5775204-Note-by-Chair-and-Selected-Documents-Ordered.html&quot;&gt;investigating&lt;/a&gt; Facebook’s data privacy practices in the wake of the Cambridge Analytica scandal. However, this cache represents the clearest and most comprehensive picture of Facebook’s activities during a critical period as the company struggled to adapt to the rise of smartphones following its rocky debut as a public company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The thousands of newly shared documents were anonymously leaked to the British investigative journalist Duncan Campbell, who shared them with a handful of media organizations: NBC News, Computer Weekly and Süddeutsche Zeitung. Campbell, a founding member of the International Consortium of Investigative Journalists, is a computer forensics expert who has worked on international investigations including on offshore banking and big tobacco. The documents appear to be the same ones &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.parliament.uk/documents/commons-committees/culture-media-and-sport/Further-selected-documents-ordered-from-Six4Three-Feb19.pdf&quot;&gt;obtained by Parliament in late 2018&lt;/a&gt; as part of an investigation into Facebook. Facebook did not question the authenticity of the documents NBC News obtained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;related related--relatedContent related___2RfEH single___1bpFv dn-print&quot; data-test=&quot;related&quot;&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The documents stem from a California court case between the social network and the little-known startup Six4Three, which &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.law360.com/articles/701688/facebook-aims-to-kill-bikini-finding-app-developer-s-suit&quot;&gt;sued Facebook in 2015&lt;/a&gt; after the company announced plans to cut off access to some types of user data. Six4Three’s app, Pikinis, which soft-launched in 2013, relied on that data to allow users to easily find photos of their friends in bathing suits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Facebook has acknowledged that it considered &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/facebook-considered-charging-for-access-to-user-data-1543454648&quot;&gt;charging for access to user data&lt;/a&gt;. But Facebook has challenged the significance of those discussions, telling the Wall Street Journal last year and NBC News this month that the company was merely mulling various business models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Facebook has also repeatedly said that the documents had been “&lt;a href=&quot;https://newsroom.fb.com/news/2018/12/response-to-six4three-documents/&quot;&gt;cherry-picked&lt;/a&gt;” and were misleading. Facebook reiterated this stance when NBC News contacted the social media company for comment on the newly leaked documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“As we’ve said many times, Six4Three — creators of the Pikinis app — cherry picked these documents from years ago as part of a lawsuit to force Facebook to share information on friends of the app's users,” Paul Grewal, vice president and deputy general counsel at Facebook, said in a statement released by the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“The set of documents, by design, tells only one side of the story and omits important context. We still stand by the platform changes we made in 2014/2015 to prevent people from sharing their friends' information with developers like the creators of Pikinis. The documents were selectively leaked as part of what the court found was evidence of a crime or fraud to publish some, but not all, of the internal discussions at Facebook at the time of our platform changes. But the facts are clear: we've never sold people’s data.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The finding of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.law.com/therecorder/2019/03/16/judge-grants-facebooks-crime-fraud-exception-request-for-opposing-counsels-documents/&quot;&gt;“evidence of a crime or fraud”&lt;/a&gt; came from a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/5771597-2019-03-15-SCARA-Order-Re-Def-s-Mot-to-Open-Disc.html&quot;&gt;preliminary decision&lt;/a&gt; by the judge in the Six4Three case about an earlier round of leaked documents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;NBC News has not been able to determine whether the documents represent a complete picture. Facebook declined to provide additional evidence to support the claim of cherry-picking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Still, these freshly leaked documents show that the plans to sell access to user data were discussed for years and received support from Facebook’s most senior executives, including Zuckerberg, chief operating officer Sheryl Sandberg, chief product officer Chris Cox and VP of growth Javier Olivan. Facebook declined to make them available for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;After NBC News contacted Facebook for comment, Facebook’s lawyers &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/5837524-CIV533328-36.html&quot;&gt;wrote to the judge&lt;/a&gt; in the Six4Three case, claiming that Six4Three had leaked the documents to a “national broadcast network” and seeking to depose Six4Three’s founders. NBC News received the documents from Campbell, who received them from an anonymous source. Six4Three denied leaking the documents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;related related--relatedContent related___2RfEH single___1bpFv dn-print&quot; data-test=&quot;related&quot;&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;When Facebook ultimately cut off broad access to user data in 2015, the move contributed to the decline of thousands of competitors and small businesses that relied on what Facebook had previously &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scribd.com/doc/81196/Facebook-f8-Platform-FAQ-FINAL&quot;&gt;described as a “level-playing field”&lt;/a&gt; in terms of access to data. In addition to Pikinis, the casualties included Lulu, an app that let women rate the men they dated; an identity fraud-detecting app called Beehive ID; and Swedish breast cancer awareness app Rosa Bandet (Pink Ribbon).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The strategy orchestrated by Zuckerberg had some of his employees comparing the company to villains from Game of Thrones, while David Poll, a senior engineer, called the treatment of outside app developers “sort of unethical,” according to the documents. But Zuckerberg’s approach also earned admiration: Doug Purdy, Facebook’s director of product, described the CEO as a “master of leverage,” according to the documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Facebook declined to comment on these employee communications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;&quot;&gt;A PRIVACY MYTH&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;One of the most striking threads to emerge from the documents is the way that Facebook user data was horse-traded to squeeze money or shared data from app developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;In the wake of the Cambridge Analytica scandal in early 2018 and rising awareness of the Six4Three case, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/zuck/posts/10105559172610321&quot;&gt;Facebook has attempted to frame changes&lt;/a&gt; it made to its platform in 2014 and 2015 as being driven by concerns over user privacy. In statements to media organizations, Facebook has said it locked down its platform to protect users from companies that mishandled user data, such as Cambridge Analytica, as well as apps that spammed users’ news feeds or were creepy, such as Six4Three’s bikini-spotting app Pikinis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;related related--relatedContent related___2RfEH single___1bpFv dn-print&quot; data-test=&quot;related&quot;&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;However, among the documents leaked, there’s very little evidence that privacy was a major concern of Facebook’s, and the issue was rarely discussed in the thousands of pages of emails and meeting summaries. Where privacy is mentioned, it is often in the context of how Facebook can use it as a public relations strategy to soften the blow of the sweeping changes to developers’ access to user data. The documents include several examples suggesting that these changes were designed to cement Facebook’s power in the marketplace, not to protect users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;In Six4Three’s case, for example, Facebook’s head of policy Allison Hendrix acknowledged in a June 2017 deposition obtained by NBC News that the social network never received any complaints about the Pikinis app, nor did Facebook send Six4Three any policy or privacy violation notices. Six4Three, Hendrix confirmed, was playing within the rules Facebook had set for developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Despite this, Six4Three’s access to data, specifically access to a user’s friends’ photos, was cut off in April 2015 as part of sweeping changes to Facebook’s platform announced a year earlier, which affected as many as 40,000 apps. Six4Three shut down the app soon afterward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;mr3&quot;&gt;Ted Kramer, founder of Six4Three.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;f2 ls-tight gray-80 ws-tight founders-mono dib&quot;&gt;Peter DaSilva / for NBC News&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“Our case is about Zuckerberg’s decision to weaponize the reliance of companies on his purportedly neutral platform and to weaponize the private and sensitive data of billions of people,” said Six4Three founder Ted Kramer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;&quot;&gt;A TURNING POINT FOR FACEBOOK&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Facebook recognized early on that working with third-party app developers could help make the social network more interesting and drive the platform’s expansion. Beginning in early 2010, Facebook created tools that allowed the makers of games (remember Farmville?) and other apps to connect with its audience in return for ensuring those users spent more time on Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Facebook achieved this through its “Graph API” (Application Programming Interface), a common means to allow software programs to interact with each other. In Facebook’s case, this meant that third-party apps such as games could post updates on people’s profiles, which would be seen by players’ friends and potentially encourage them to play, too. Beyond that, it allowed the makers of those games to access a slew of data from Facebook users, including their connections to friends, likes, locations, updates, photos and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The Graph API — and particularly the way it let third parties promote their products to and extract data from a user’s social connections — was a key feature of Facebook that Six4Three and thousands of other companies relied upon for viral marketing and user growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;However, after a few years, Facebook decided the app developers were getting more value from the user data they extracted from Facebook than Facebook was getting out of the app developers, the documents show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;embedWidget small___1S8zc&quot;&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;After Facebook went public in May 2012, its stock price plummeted, which &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/tomiogeron/2012/09/11/live-facebooks-mark-zuckerberg-at-techcrunch-disrupt/#6f6c6f6b4fe6&quot;&gt;Zuckerberg later characterized as “disappointing.”&lt;/a&gt; The company was in a desperate position, documents show, with users sharing fewer photos and posts on the platform as they spent more time on their cellphones. An internal Facebook presentation looking back at this period used the phrase “terminal decline” to describe the fall in engagement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Facebook executives, including Zuckerberg and Sandberg, spent months brainstorming ways to turn the company around. An idea that they kept returning to: make money from the app partners, by charging them for access to Facebook’s users and their data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;&quot;&gt;‘SELL DATA FOR $”&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Several proposals for charging developers for access to Facebook’s platform and data were put forward in a presentation to the company’s board of directors, according to emails and draft slides from late August 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Among the suggestions: a fixed annual fee for developers for reviewing their apps; an access fee for apps that requested user data; and a charge for “premium” access to data, such as a user trust score or a ranking of the strongest relationships between users and their friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“Today the fundamental trade is ‘data for distribution’ whereas we want to change it to either ‘data for $’ and/or ‘$ for distribution,’” Chris Daniels, a Facebook business development director, wrote in an August 2012 email to other top leaders in the company discussing the upcoming presentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Discussions continued through October, when Zuckerberg explained to close friend Sam Lessin the importance of controlling third-party apps’ ability to access Facebook’s data and reach people’s friends on the platform. Without that leverage, “I don’t think we have any way to get developers to pay us at all,” Zuckerberg wrote in an email to Lessin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;In the same week, Zuckerberg floated the idea of pursuing 100 deals with developers “as a path to figuring out the real market value” of Facebook user data and then “setting a public rate” for developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“The goal here wouldn’t be the deals themselves, but that through the process of negotiating with them we’d learn what developers would actually pay (which might be different from what they’d say if we just asked them about the value), and then we’d be better informed on our path to set a public rate,” Zuckerberg wrote in a chat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Facebook told NBC News that it was exploring ways to build a sustainable business, but ultimately decided not to go forward with these plans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;quote___U_LGF small___2-X0R&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;collapseContainer___3IP99&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;container___1YAfH mt8 mt2-m mb8&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;pullQuote___PESSR&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;content___3WSQL f8 lh-none founders-cond pt6 mt0 mb5&quot;&gt;&quot;I just can’t think of any instances where that data has leaked from developer to developer and caused a real issue for us.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Zuckerberg was unfazed by the potential privacy risks associated with Facebook’s data-sharing arrangements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“I’m generally skeptical that there is as much data leak strategic risk as you think,” he wrote in the email to Lessin. “I think we leak info to developers but I just can’t think of any instances where that data has leaked from developer to developer and caused a real issue for us.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Facebook told NBC News that this was an example of a cherry-picked email designed to bolster Six4Three’s case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Zuckerberg didn’t know it at the time, but a privacy bug affecting an unnamed third-party app would create precisely this kind of strategic risk the following year, according to a panicked chatlog between Michael Vernal, who was director of engineering, and other senior employees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;It’s not clear exactly what happened or which app was involved, but it appears that Zuckerberg’s private communications could have leaked from Facebook to the external app in an unexpected way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Vernal said that it “could have been near-fatal for Facebook platform” if “Mark had accidentally disclosed earnings ahead of time because a platform app violated his privacy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“Holy crap,” replied Avichal Garg, then director of product management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“DO NOT REPEAT THIS STORY OFF OF THIS THREAD,” added Vernal. “I can’t tell you how terrible this would have been for all of us had this not been caught quickly.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Vernal and Garg did not respond to requests for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;&quot;&gt;‘GOOD FOR THE WORLD’ BUT NOT ‘GOOD FOR US’&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;In late November 2012, Zuckerberg sent a long email to Facebook’s senior leadership team saying that Facebook shouldn’t charge developers for access to basic data feeds. However, he said that access to Facebook data should be contingent on the developers sharing all of the “social content” generated by their apps back to Facebook, something Zuckerberg calls “full reciprocity.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The existing arrangement, where developers weren’t required to share their data back with Facebook, might be “good for the world” but it’s not “good for us,” Zuckerberg wrote in the email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;He noted that though Facebook could charge developers to access user data, the company stood to benefit more from requiring developers to compensate Facebook in kind — with their own data — and by pushing those developers to pay for advertising on Facebook’s platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The endgame: to ensure Facebook maintained its dominant position in the market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“The purpose of the platform is to tie the universe of all the social apps together so we can enable a lot more sharing and still remain the central social hub,” Zuckerberg said in the email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Facebook told NBC News that the focus of “full reciprocity” was to enable users to share their experiences within external apps with their friends on Facebook, not about providing Facebook with user data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;&quot;&gt;CUTTING DEALS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;With Zuckerberg’s vision for Facebook set, the company began making deals with some of its most valued partners, including dozens of app developer friends of Zuckerberg and Sandberg. Facebook whitelisted their access to feeds of user data while restricting that same access to apps that Facebook viewed as competitors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;These data access deals prepared key partners, including Tinder, Sony and Microsoft, for sweeping changes to the Facebook platform that the company planned to announce at its annual developer conference in April 2014 and enforce within a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;In one instance, described in June 2013 documents, Amazon received special treatment for the launch of a group gifting product, despite the fact that it competed with one of Facebook’s own products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“Remind me, why did we allow them to do this? Do we receive any cut of purchases?” Chris Daniels, then Facebook’s director of business development, asked in an email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“No, but Amazon is an advertiser and supporting this with advertisement ... and working with us on deeper integrations for the Fire,” Amazon’s smartphone, replied Jackie Chang, who worked with Facebook’s “strategic partners.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Amazon released a statement to NBC News: “Amazon uses publicly available APIs provided by Facebook in order to enable Facebook experiences for our products and only uses information in accordance with our privacy policy.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Apps that were not considered “strategic partners” got different treatment. In a March 2013 discussion, Justin Osofsky, then director of platform partnerships, described restricting the MessageMe app from accessing Facebook data because it had grown too popular and could compete with Facebook messages. He asked colleagues to see if any other messenger apps have “hit the growth team’s radar recently.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“If so, we'd like to restrict them at the same time to group this into one press cycle,&quot; he wrote in an email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;&quot;&gt;‘IT’S SORT OF UNETHICAL’&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Deal negotiations created confusion among partners who had grown accustomed to unfettered access to Facebook user data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“We gave a bunch of stuff ‘for free’ historically (data, distribution) and now we’re making you ‘pay’ for it via reciprocal value,” Vernal, director of engineering, wrote in an email in June 2013. He added, “The confusing thing here is that we haven’t really announced these changes publicly/broadly yet.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Some Facebook employees were unhappy about this direction, particularly the way the company appeared to be blocking competitors from accessing data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Here’s an extract from a December 2013 chatlog between several senior engineers talking about the changes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Bryan Klimt: “So we are literally going to group apps into buckets based on how scared we are of them and give them different APIs? ... So the message is, ‘if you’re going to compete with us at all, make sure you don’t integrate with us at all’? I’m just dumbfounded.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Kevin Lacker: “Yeah this is complicated.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;David Poll: “More than complicated, it’s sort of unethical.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Lacker and Poll declined to comment. Vernal and Klimt did not respond to requests for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Facebook declined to comment on the employee exchanges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;&quot;&gt;THE PR SPIN&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;When it came to publicly announcing the sweeping changes at Facebook’s annual F8 developer conference in April 2014, members of the communications team worked with Zuckerberg to craft a narrative around user trust, not competition or profitability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;In a March 2014 email discussing Zuckerberg’s keynote speech at the event, where he was due to announce the removal of developers’ access to friends’ data, Jonny Thaw, a director of communications, wrote that it “may be a tough message for some developers as it may inhibit their growth.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“So one idea that came up today was potentially talking in the keynote about some of the trust changes we’re making on Facebook itself. So the message would be: ‘trust is really important to us — on Facebook, we’re doing A, B and C to help people control and understand what they’re sharing — and with platform apps we’re doing D, E and F.’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;If that doesn’t work, he added, “we could announce some of Facebook’s trust initiatives in the run up to F8” to make the changes for developers “seem more natural.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Facebook told NBC News that it was “completely reasonable” for someone on the communications team to discuss the best way to get the message out on changes to the platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;User trust was crucial when Zuckerberg delivered his speech at the event on April 30, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;mr3&quot;&gt;Facebook CEO Mark Zuckerberg delivers the keynote address at the F8 developer conference in San Francisco in 2014.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;f2 ls-tight gray-80 ws-tight founders-mono dib&quot;&gt;Ben Margot / AP file&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“Over the years, one of the things we’ve heard over and over again is that people want more control over how they share their information, especially with apps, and they want more say and control over how apps use their data,” he &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DVu311G5qvI&quot;&gt;told the audience of journalists and developers&lt;/a&gt;. “And we take this really seriously because if people don’t have the tools they need to feel comfortable using your apps, that’s bad for them and that’s bad for you.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;But despite Facebook’s public focus on privacy, staff member emails described confusion over the way third-party apps could override users’ privacy settings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Even if users locked down their account so that their photos and other data were visible to “only me,” those photos could still be transferred to third parties, according to the documents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;In April 2015, Connie Yang, a product designer, told her colleagues that she’d discovered apps collecting profile data she had marked as “only me” and displaying it to “both you and *other people* using that app.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“While ‘whoa how did you start working at Casterly Rock’ is a fun opener,” she wrote, referring to the ancestral stronghold of the most fearsome family in “Game of Thrones,” “isn’t this directly violating what we tell users is ‘only me’?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Yang did not respond to requests for comment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Facebook said this was another example of cherry-picked emails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;&quot;&gt;THE DOCUMENTS’ LEGACY&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Even though Facebook eventually decided not to charge developers directly for access to user data, the extensive discussions around its monetary value, shown in the leaked documents, could create lasting problems for the company, privacy and policy experts say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The biggest threat Facebook faces now is not competition but antitrust regulation, which is designed to promote fair competition among companies for the benefit of consumers, using fines or restrictions on mergers and acquisitions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Regulators have typically struggled to build robust antitrust cases against technology companies that offer services to users for free. If the product is free, then it’s harder to argue that the consumer is being harmed by a monopoly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;But if regulators can show that users were paying for access to Facebook with their personal data, and that Facebook valued that data as leverage against competitors, that could expose Facebook to an antitrust complaint, said Jason Kint, CEO of Digital Content Next, a trade association representing digital publishers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“These emails clearly establish the value of consumer data to Facebook,” Kint said. “It shows that it is not free.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Facebook said that the service has always been free for users and developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;related related--relatedContent related___2RfEH single___1bpFv dn-print&quot; data-test=&quot;related&quot;&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;In February, the Federal Trade Commission announced a task force to monitor anti-competitive behavior in the tech industry to, in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ftc.gov/news-events/press-releases/2019/02/ftcs-bureau-competition-launches-task-force-monitor-technology&quot;&gt;words of FTC chair Joseph Simons&lt;/a&gt;, “ensure consumers benefit from free and fair competition.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Policymakers have called for the FTC to investigate Facebook specifically for violating antitrust laws.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The company “appears to have used its dominance to cripple other competitive threats by cutting them off from its massive network,” Rep. David Cicilline, D-R.I., chairman of the House Judiciary antitrust subcommittee, wrote in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/03/19/opinion/facebook-antitrust-investigation.html&quot;&gt;New York Times op-ed last month&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Facebook appears to be preparing for the inevitable, with Zuckerberg writing his own op-ed in The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/mark-zuckerberg-the-internet-needs-new-rules-lets-start-in-these-four-areas/2019/03/29/9e6f0504-521a-11e9-a3f7-78b7525a8d5f_story.html?utm_term=.bd2bcf695b30&quot;&gt;Washington Post in March calling for regulation&lt;/a&gt; in areas including harmful content and election integrity, but not antitrust. Facebook watchers saw this show of willingness as an attempt by Zuckerberg to curry favor with policymakers at a time when many are baying for the company’s blood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Ashkan Soltani, a privacy expert and former FTC chief technologist, said that Zuckerberg is approaching the looming threat of regulation with “bravado” and trying to “leverage things for his benefit.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Meanwhile, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/profcarroll?lang=en&quot;&gt;David Carroll&lt;/a&gt;, a professor at the New School, who pursued legal claims in the U.K. in the wake of the Cambridge Analytica data scandal, says Zuckerberg is “bracing for impact.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“When the penalty hits they can be like, ‘Yeah, we agree, we deserve this fine.’ It positions them to be conciliatory,” Carroll said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The “master of leverage” strikes again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;lastMarkupItem&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;This report has been prepared and published in conjunction with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.duncancampbell.org&quot;&gt;Duncan Campbell&lt;/a&gt; (U.K.), &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.computerweekly.com&quot;&gt;Computer Weekly&lt;/a&gt; (U.K.) and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sueddeutsche.de&quot;&gt;Süddeutsche Zeitung&lt;/a&gt; (Germany).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;articleBylineContainer mt8&quot; readability=&quot;36&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;articleByline byline___2NGv_ noImage___3G0GY pt3 pb2&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;articleByline__name name___32ZJk founders-mono f3 lh-title ls-tight pt1 pt4-m ml9 ml0-m ml0-print&quot;&gt;Olivia Solon&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;articleByline__social social___kAOJV f2 mt2 mt4-m ml9 ml0-m dn-print&quot; data-test=&quot;article-byline__social&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;articleByline__bio bio___3q2CD publico-txt f2 lh-copy mt3 mt0-m ml9-m&quot;&gt;Olivia Solon is a tech investigations editor for NBC News in San Francisco.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;articleByline byline___2NGv_ hasImage___1TEVp pt3 pb2&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;inner___y8Zvr mt2 mt0-m&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;articleByline__image image___c6bcD mr4&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media1.s-nbcnews.com/i/newscms/2019_11/2784541/cyrus-farivar-1500_600ddbe81f24c1b47efb34ab66625731.jpg&quot; class=&quot;headshot___3D_6B w3-print&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;articleByline__name name___32ZJk founders-mono f3 lh-title ls-tight pt1 pt4-m ml9 ml0-m ml0-print&quot;&gt;Cyrus Farivar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;articleByline__social social___kAOJV f2 mt2 mt4-m ml9 ml0-m dn-print&quot; data-test=&quot;article-byline__social&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;articleByline__bio bio___3q2CD publico-txt f2 lh-copy mt3 mt0-m ml9-m&quot;&gt;Cyrus Farivar is a reporter on the tech investigations unit of NBC News in San Francisco.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jason Abbruzzese, Michael Cappetta, David Ingram and Ben Popken contributed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 11:44:14 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>uptown</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/social-media/mark-zuckerberg-leveraged-facebook-user-data-fight-rivals-help-friends-n994706</og:url>
<og:title>Thousands of leaked Facebook documents show Mark Zuckerberg as ‘master of leverage’ in plan to trade user data</og:title>
<og:description>Facebook’s leaders seriously discussed selling access to user data — and privacy was an afterthought.</og:description>
<og:image>https://media2.s-nbcnews.com/j/newscms/2019_16/2813741/190408-facebook-documents-privacy-main-kh_f4a6bfef6b06cef6f61fdc00decbc67e.nbcnews-fp-1200-630.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/social-media/mark-zuckerberg-leveraged-facebook-user-data-fight-rivals-help-friends-n994706</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Microplastics Are Blowing in the Wind</title>
<link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/microplastics-are-blowing-in-the-wind/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/microplastics-are-blowing-in-the-wind/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;mura-region mura-region-loose&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;mura-region-local&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amid the rugged peaks of the Vicdessos region of the French Pyrenees, the only visible signs of a human presence are a smattering of villages and the odd hiker or skier; it is considered a pristine environment. But even here, scientists have detected tiny pieces of plastic falling out of the air like artificial dust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A first-of-its-kind study finds these particles have blown in on the wind from at least 100 kilometers away and likely much farther. This is a clear indication that atmospheric transport is yet another way plastic pollution is being distributed around the planet, even to remote areas. “And it suggests that this is a far bigger problem than we have currently thought about,” says study co-author Deonie Allen, of the École Nationale Supérieure Agronomique de Toulouse (ENSAT).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study, published Monday in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41561-019-0335-5&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nature Geoscience&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, is one of only a handful that have attempted to measure how much plastic is falling from the atmosphere. It marks the first wave in what is likely to be a flood of such studies in the coming years, in an effort to fill in the picture of how microplastics move around the environment and how &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/from-fish-to-humans-a-microplastic-invasion-may-be-taking-a-toll/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;humans might be exposed&lt;/a&gt; to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-center&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;407&quot; src=&quot;https://static.scientificamerican.com/sciam/assets/Image/2019/Field%20site%20area%20(c)%20D%20Allen.jpg&quot; width=&quot;648&quot;/&gt; The field site in the French Pyrenees where researchers sampled microplastics falling out of the atmosphere. Credit: Deonie Allen&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;“Nobody Had Looked Up”&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microplastics are tiny pieces that break off larger plastic items (such as bottles and bags) as they degrade in the environment, as well as the fibers that slough off synthetic fabrics. They come in a wide range of sizes—from a grain of rice down to a virus—and are made up of a complex variety of polymers and added chemicals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most research to detect &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/earth-has-a-hidden-plastic-problem-mdash-scientists-are-hunting-it-down/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;microplastics in the environment&lt;/a&gt; has been done in the ocean, where they were first noticed, but scientists have slowly realized they are also present in freshwater systems, soil and the atmosphere. The first study to measure plastic fallout from the atmosphere—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.publish.csiro.au/EN/EN14167&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;conducted in Paris&lt;/a&gt;—was published only in 2015. The recent attention to the issue means that there are only a handful of measurements of airborne plastic, and little sense of how the numbers might vary from place to place, depending on weather conditions and where the material is ultimately coming from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Allen and her colleagues knew microplastics had been found in rivers and sediments in the Pyrenees, but no one had determined the sources. The bulk could not have come from local sources because of the small human population and limited industrial activity, so Allen was struck by a key question: “Why haven’t we looked up?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is what she and her colleagues did, taking advantage of atmospheric measuring equipment already in place in the Pyrenees and sampling over five months. They found plastic fibers, films and shards, all in a range of sizes. Most of the polymers that turned up in the samples were polystyrene, polyethylene and polypropylene, which are all common in single-use plastic products such as bags and foam food containers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-center&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1122&quot; src=&quot;https://static.scientificamerican.com/sciam/assets/Image/2019/inverse-image-of-plastic-fibre(1).jpg&quot; width=&quot;1500&quot;/&gt; A close-up image of one of the plastic fibers the researchers found in their samples. Credit: Steve Allen&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;A First Peek&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because the new study included smaller sizes of particles than previous studies, the researchers found more plastic particles overall; this bears out a recurring trend in microplastics research findings that the smaller the size of the particles, the more of them there are. When comparing only the size ranges examined in the 2015 Paris study, Allen and her colleagues found a similar amount of microplastic, which was unexpected given the disparate environments of the two studies. This could mean that the new study “gives us a background level of microplastic that you probably get pretty much everywhere in the world,” says Melanie Bergmann, a marine ecologist with the Alfred Wegener Institute for Polar and Marine Research (AWI), who studies microplastics but was not involved in the new research. But because the samples were averaged over a whole month, it could be that the background level in the Pyrenees is lower but is punctuated by periodic plumes of microplastics coming in from populated areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study did not pinpoint precisely where the microplastics originated, but used computer models of atmospheric currents to attempt to back-trace the air that brought them in—the first study to do so. They could only trace the air masses regionally, but were able to show the primary directions they came from. It was clear that the relatively small towns and villages were unlikely to account for all of the plastic they detected, which suggests the ultimate sources are more distant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-center&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1500&quot; src=&quot;https://static.scientificamerican.com/sciam/assets/Image/2019/white-triangle-fragment(1).jpg&quot; width=&quot;2000&quot;/&gt; A close-up image fragment of white plastic found in the samples. Credit: Steve Allen&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While such tracking is “an important step,” says microplastic researcher Stephanie Wright, of King’s College London, who wasn’t involved in the research, “you kind of need to know the sources to understand the back trajectory more.” Different plastics may be coming from different sources, and “an airstream could just pick up bits as it goes,” she says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The authors say their work is only a first peek at the larger airborne microplastics picture. Many more samples from across the world—as well as lab experiments that see how different shapes, types and sizes of plastics behave in different meteorological conditions—are needed to understand the full scope of the situation, including how much microplastics humans might be inhaling. Both Wright and Bergmann have pending studies that measure microplastic fallout in London and the Arctic, respectively, and these will add more data. Allen and her colleagues, too, are working to expand their research. Co-author Steve Allen, of ENSAT and the University of Strathclyde, says that “we should, in the next few years, get a much better picture of what’s going on.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 10:44:25 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pseudolus</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Microplastics Are Blowing in the Wind</og:title>
<og:description>Atmospheric currents are transporting plastic pollution into remote, pristine areas, showing the global nature of the problem</og:description>
<og:image>https://static.scientificamerican.com/sciam/cache/file/ECDD6AE4-3A28-42B8-BEC4804C91B6207F.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/microplastics-are-blowing-in-the-wind/</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/microplastics-are-blowing-in-the-wind/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Source code for Zork, Hitchhiker’s Guide, and other Infocom games</title>
<link>https://github.com/historicalsource?tab=repositories</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/historicalsource?tab=repositories</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/historicalsource?tab=repositories&quot;&gt;https://github.com/historicalsource?tab=repositories&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19672436&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19672436&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 606&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 192&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 10:26:34 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>laurent123456</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars1.githubusercontent.com/u/49599193?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>profile</og:type>
<og:title>historicalsource - Overview</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/historicalsource</og:url>
<og:description>A collection of historical source files, for education and perusal. - historicalsource</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/historicalsource?tab=repositories</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Apple: Rotate tracking IDs on iPhone each month</title>
<link>https://foundation.mozilla.org/en/campaigns/privacy-thats-iphone-but-is-it/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://foundation.mozilla.org/en/campaigns/privacy-thats-iphone-but-is-it/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;There is a unique ID living on your iPhone right now that allows advertisers to track the ads you click on, the videos you play, and the apps you install.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The good news is, &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT202074&quot;&gt;you can turn this identifier off&lt;/a&gt;. The bad news: most people don’t know that feature exists, let alone that they should turn it off. And we don’t think that they should have to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That’s why we’re asking Apple to change the unique IDs that advertisers use to track us on each iPhone, every month.&lt;/strong&gt; That means we could still get relevant ads – but there’s a real cap that makes it harder for companies to build profiles of us over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Will you add your name to the petition?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 09:54:20 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>denzil_correa</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>http://foundation.mozilla.org/en/campaigns/privacy-thats-iphone-but-is-it/</og:url>
<og:title>“Privacy. That’s iPhone.” But is it?</og:title>
<og:description>Tell Apple to protect iPhone users’ privacy</og:description>
<og:image>https://assets.mofoprod.net/network/images/iPhone.original.jpg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://foundation.mozilla.org/en/campaigns/privacy-thats-iphone-but-is-it/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>