<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Apple blocks Google from running its internal iOS apps</title>
<link>https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/31/18205795/apple-google-blocked-internal-ios-apps-developer-certificate</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/31/18205795/apple-google-blocked-internal-ios-apps-developer-certificate</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;65L3Yj&quot;&gt;Apple has now shut down Google’s ability to distribute its internal iOS apps, following a similar shutdown that was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/30/18203551/apple-facebook-blocked-internal-ios-apps&quot;&gt;issued to Facebook earlier this week&lt;/a&gt;. A person familiar with the situation tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that early versions of Google Maps, Hangouts, Gmail, and other pre-release beta apps have stopped working today, alongside employee-only apps like a Gbus app for transportation and Google’s internal cafe app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;RIm5V4&quot;&gt;“We’re working with Apple to fix a temporary disruption to some of our corporate iOS apps, which we expect will be resolved soon,” says a Google spokesperson in a statement to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. Apple also appears to be working more closely with Google to fix this situation. “We are working together with Google to help them reinstate their enterprise certificates very quickly,” says an Apple spokesperson in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/JohnPaczkowski/status/1091097938393128960&quot;&gt;statement to &lt;em&gt;BuzzFeed&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;c-float-right&quot;&gt;
&lt;aside id=&quot;S36C8N&quot;&gt;&lt;q&gt;Apple blocked Facebook and then Google&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;FexzJt&quot;&gt;Apple’s move to block Google’s developer certificate comes just a day after &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/30/18204064/apple-google-monitoring-phone-usage-screenwise-meter&quot;&gt;Google disabled its Screenwise Meter app&lt;/a&gt; following press coverage. Google’s private app was designed to monitor how people use their iPhones, similar to Facebook’s research app. Google’s app also relied on Apple’s enterprise program, which enables the distribution of internal apps within a company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;BxWOYs&quot;&gt;In an earlier statement over Facebook’s certificate removal, Apple did warn that “any developer using their enterprise certificates to distribute apps to consumers will have their certificates revoked.” Apple is clearly sticking to its rules and applying them equally to Facebook, Google, and likely many other companies that get caught breaking Apple’s rules in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;ujExLR&quot;&gt;Facebook’s internal iOS apps have since resumed functioning, as the social network said this afternoon that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/31/18206020/apple-facebook-internal-ios-apps-restores-enterprise-certificate&quot;&gt;Apple had restored its enterprise certificate&lt;/a&gt;. Similarly, both Apple and Google’s statements make it clear that the companies are working together to fix Google’s issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;xqvA1f&quot;&gt;Meanwhile, there’s growing evidence that a number of companies are using Apple’s enterprise program to distribute apps to consumers. iOS developer &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/thefaj/status/1091087789704105984&quot;&gt;Alex Fajkowski has discovered&lt;/a&gt; that Amazon, DoorDash, and Sonos all distribute beta versions of their apps to non-employees. Apple may be forced to take action against these apps, or to even revamp its entire enterprise program in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;Xag9UC&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update 1/31, 5:45PM ET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;: Article updated with comment from Google, Apple, and details on other companies using Apple’s enterprise program to distribute apps.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;zx5syB&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update 1/31:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;6:18PM ET: Updated with the news that Apple has resumed letting Facebook use internal iOS apps.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 21:20:26 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rising-sky</dc:creator>
<og:description>Google joins Facebook in Apple’s banning spree</og:description>
<og:image>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zecX0cPldoJGxd8xivCIx07sXlA=/0x146:2040x1214/fit-in/1200x630/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/10745895/acastro_180427_1777_0001.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Breaking: Apple blocks Google from running its internal iOS apps</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/31/18205795/apple-google-blocked-internal-ios-apps-developer-certificate</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/31/18205795/apple-google-blocked-internal-ios-apps-developer-certificate</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Product-building articles by PMs at major tech companies</title>
<link>https://find.xyz/map/product-management-search-engine</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://find.xyz/map/product-management-search-engine</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://find.xyz/map/product-management-search-engine&quot;&gt;https://find.xyz/map/product-management-search-engine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19047384&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19047384&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 222&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 66&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 18:36:18 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>itsrishabh</dc:creator>
<og:title>Product Management Search Engine</og:title>
<og:image>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*N9ZPth2o0B2HYsT-o7O0kQ.png</og:image>
<og:url>https://find.xyz/map/product-management-search-engine</og:url>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:description>1000+ articles recommended/written by PMs at Google, FB + almost every other major tech co/startup. No videos/books/product placement, just articles. To suggest new articles, comment on this map. Also accessible at bit.ly/pmengine.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://find.xyz/map/product-management-search-engine</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Stealing the Enemy&amp;#039;s Urban Advantage: The Battle of Sadr City</title>
<link>https://mwi.usma.edu/stealing-enemys-urban-advantage-battle-sadr-city/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://mwi.usma.edu/stealing-enemys-urban-advantage-battle-sadr-city/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;apss-social-share apss-theme-4 clearfix&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;apss-facebook apss-single-icon&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;apss-icon-block clearfix&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;apss-social-text&quot;&gt;Share on Facebook&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;apss-share&quot;&gt;Share&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;apss-twitter apss-single-icon&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;apss-icon-block clearfix&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;apss-social-text&quot;&gt;Share on Twitter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;apss-share&quot;&gt;Tweet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;apss-google-plus apss-single-icon&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;apss-icon-block clearfix&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;apss-social-text&quot;&gt;Share on Google Plus&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;apss-share&quot;&gt;Share&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;apss-linkedin apss-single-icon&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;apss-icon-block clearfix&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;apss-social-text&quot;&gt;Share on LinkedIn&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;apss-share&quot;&gt;Share&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;apss-email apss-single-icon&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;apss-icon-block clearfix&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;apss-social-text&quot;&gt;Send email&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;apss-share&quot;&gt;Mail&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;apss-print apss-single-icon&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;apss-icon-block clearfix&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;apss-social-text&quot;&gt;Print&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;apss-share&quot;&gt;Print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From March 23 to May 12, 2008, US Army and Iraq security forces engaged in an intense urban battle in and around Baghdad’s Shiite neighborhood of Sadr City. The battle forced units that had been mainly focused on counterinsurgency operations to convert overnight into combined-arms teams of armor and mechanized infantry and engage a large enemy element in a high-intensity fight in a city containing around two million noncombatants. The adaptions these units made and the results of this short but pivotal battle provide important lessons for future combat in dense urban environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadr City is a dense Shiite area in eastern Baghdad whose boundaries with adjacent Sunni-dominated neighborhoods represent sectarian fault lines. At the time of the battle, Sadr City contained an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rand.org/pubs/research_reports/RR160.html&quot;&gt;estimated&lt;/a&gt; population of between 1.6 to 2.4 million residents. Purpose built in 1958 to house a large population of migrants moving to Baghdad to look for work, it maintained near slum-like conditions from the time of its construction. It &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/@33.3532107,44.429137,12z&quot;&gt;stands out on a map&lt;/a&gt; of Baghdad as a solid, compact square of streets arranged in a grid pattern. The neighborhood is made up of narrow streets and alleyways, spider webs of power lines, and mostly three-story or shorter buildings that range from simple cinder blocks to reinforced cement construction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Containing around a quarter of Baghdad’s estimated population of seven million in less than five square miles, Sadr City is one of the most densely populated areas where the United States has ever fought. Its population surpasses those of the sites of other urban battles, such as Manila in 1945, whose pre–World War II population was an estimated 1.1 million, or Seoul in 1950, with one million residents. As a battlefield (both in 2008 and an earlier battle in 2004), Sadr City exceeded any other part of Baghdad, in terms of density of both population and structures, where fighting occurred during the 2003 invasion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amid Iraq’s worsening sectarian violence between 2006 and 2008, in Baghdad the two major combatants were the Sunni &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.britannica.com/topic/al-Qaeda-in-Iraq&quot;&gt;Al-Qaeda in Iraq&lt;/a&gt; (AQI) and Shiite &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.stanford.edu/group/mappingmilitants/cgi-bin/groups/view/57&quot;&gt;Jaysh al-Mahdi&lt;/a&gt; (JAM). There were many other terrorist groups, criminal gangs, and war profiteers involved, but most either aligned with, or at a minimum chose not to compete with, AQI or JAM—largely out of fear for their survival. AQI was a militant Sunni terrorist network led by Abu Muṣab al-Zarqawi. JAM was the Shiite paramilitary wing of fiery cleric named Moqtada al-Sadr’s national political movement. Al-Sadr had a major influence on the large Shiite populations and associated JAM militias concentrated in Sadr City, along with those in the southern cities of Najaf, Nasiriya, and Basra. Northeastern Baghdad contained a large JAM presence within Sadr City, but also a large AQI presence in neighboring Sunni areas—Adhamiya to the northwest, Rusafa to the southwest, and Tisa Nissan to the southeast—and the boundaries between Sunni and Shiite neighborhoods were often only demarcated by single roads, making it a fertile sectarian battleground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In late 2006, Thawra District—Sadr City, and two, smaller, adjacent areas—saw fierce cycles of attacks and retaliations between Sunni and Shiite groups. Both sides attacked civilians, Iraqi security forces (ISF), and US troops. AQI frequently employed vehicle-borne improvised explosive devices (VBIEDs) and other mass-casualty attacks that had strategic implications on perceptions of the war in Iraq. The bodies of victims of sectarian murders were found dumped in the streets daily, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rand.org/pubs/research_reports/RR160.html&quot;&gt;averaging&lt;/a&gt; 200–250 per month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In early 2007, the United States implemented a surge of five additional brigade combat teams (BCTs)—about 30,000 troops—to Baghdad and Anbar Province in the country’s west to stop the sectarian violence that had pushed Iraq into chaos. Under what was called the Baghdad Security Plan, one of the surge brigades was assigned to Thawra District, although no US forces would be based in Sadr City itself. The unit implemented an aggressive plan to reduce overall levels of violence that consisted of moving into small outposts within the neighborhoods; using concrete barriers to construct checkpoints, safe neighborhoods, and safe markets that reduced the enemy’s ability to transport resources and to conduct mass-casualty attacks with VBIEDs and other weapons; targeting key insurgent leaders and groups; and improving ISF capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The role and effectiveness of concrete in reducing violence across Baghdad cannot be understated. Concrete barriers had been used throughout Iraq for years to reduce the threat of improvised explosive devices (IEDs) emplaced along major roads. But during the surge, concrete barriers were widely used to limit the enemy’s ability to maneuver freely across Baghdad. The first surge unit in Thawra District, 2nd Brigade Combat Team, 82nd Airborne Division, led by Col. Billy Don Farris, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rand.org/pubs/research_reports/RR160.html&quot;&gt;emplaced&lt;/a&gt; over thirty miles of concrete barriers. One of the first uses of concrete was to protect the Adhamiya neighborhood by building a three-mile wall around it—which would earn a nickname: the “&lt;a href=&quot;https://thelede.blogs.nytimes.com/2007/04/20/baghdads-great-wall-of-adhamiya/&quot;&gt;Great Wall of Adhamiya&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The barriers used to form the walls were &lt;a href=&quot;https://mwi.usma.edu/effective-weapon-modern-battlefield-concrete/&quot;&gt;named&lt;/a&gt; after American states to denote their progressive size. The smallest, Jersey barriers (three feet tall; two tons), were used to block roads and slow traffic approaching checkpoints. Medium to large barriers—Colorado (six feet tall; 3.5 tons), Texas (six feet, eight inches tall; six tons), and Alaska (twelve feet tall; seven tons)—were used to construct checkpoints and protective walls around markets, mosques, and other areas where crowds were being targeted by bombs and shootings. The Texas barrier, due to its width and ease of transport, among other reasons, was predominately used to create the safe neighborhoods. But it was the massive T-walls that were used to create coalition and ISF bases and to maximize protection and prevent infiltration. Similar in size to Alaska barriers, the massive twelve-foot-tall, six-ton T-wall, with its interconnecting edges, created an effective barrier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_10411&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mwi.usma.edu/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/91572.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-10411 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://mwi.usma.edu/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/91572.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; srcset=&quot;/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/91572.jpg 800w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/01/91572-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/01/91572-768x576.jpg 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;As the sun begins to set, soldiers rig a seven-ton T-wall barrier to a crane before it is placed along a 3.2 mile barrier wall along al-Quds street in Sadr City. (Credit: Sgt. Henry Bauer)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The walls turned Baghdad’s densely populated urban areas into more manageable “gated communities.” Once a wall was completed, Iraqi Army, police, or paid local neighborhood militias (called the Sons of Iraq) could occupy check points that allowed them to identify outsiders, search vehicles, and restrict the insurgents’ ability to bring large explosives and other weapons from one area to another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Insurgents and guerrilla fighters rely on their ability to move undetected among the population to survive and operate. The Chinese communist revolutionary Mao Zedong &lt;a href=&quot;https://smallwarsjournal.com/jrnl/art/mao-zedong%E2%80%99s-on-guerrilla-warfare-and-joseph-kabila%E2%80%99s-lost-opportunity&quot;&gt;counseled&lt;/a&gt; fighters to move among the people as a fish swims in the sea. In Baghdad, concrete walls in the sea made it a lot easier to kill or catch fish by creating chokepoints in the terrain that restricted enemy freedom of movement. Using obstacles to restrict insurgent movement in urban &lt;a href=&quot;https://mwi.usma.edu/effective-weapon-modern-battlefield-concrete/&quot;&gt;military operations&lt;/a&gt; is not new. British forces used blockhouses, fences, or other barriers to interdict insurgents in the Second Boer War (1899–1902) and during the 1950s in Malaya. French forces used wire and other obstacles to cordon off entire urban areas in the Casbah during the 1957 Battle of Algiers. Concrete was the barrier of choice in the Iraq War.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of 2007, the Baghdad Security Plan had significantly defeated, or at least neutralized, AQI and had decreased sectarian violence in Baghdad considerably. But JAM continued to use Sadr City as a base of operations to carry out strikes against ISF and coalition forces. While the American and ISF units in Thawra District had begun to isolate Sadr City with their safe neighborhoods and other lines of operations, JAM retained firm &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rand.org/pubs/research_reports/RR160.html&quot;&gt;control&lt;/a&gt; over the population and the terrain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Special operations and conventional forces conducted some raids against JAM leadership in Sadr City, but these were extremely dangerous missions because of how fast the militias could respond to any outside visitors. While these responses varied, a common tactic used by JAM fighters (similar to insurgent tactics in 1993 Battle of Mogadishu and 1994 Battle of Grozny) was to allow the raiding force to enter Sadr City and then barricade the streets behind them (using tires and other debris). This funneled the raiding force into IEDs and prepared ambushes. JAM would also use cranes to put car hulks on roofs, which JAM fighters would use as improvised fighting positions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In October 2007, US special operations forces in Sadr City close to being overrun had to call in an airstrike. In so doing they killed a number of Iraqi civilians and sparked public outrage, fueled by wide media &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-dyn/content/article/2007/10/21/AR2007102100159_pf.html&quot;&gt;reporting&lt;/a&gt; of the event. In response, Iraqi Prime Minster Nouri al-Maliki placed Sadr City off limits to US conventional units except under the most extraordinary circumstances. It would remain under such restrictions for the duration of the US military’s presence in Iraq.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With these political restrictions in place, one of the only things US forces could do to affect Sadr City was work to influence the flows—of fighters and weapons—going in and out by blocking some roads and building small joint security stations (outposts manned by both US and Iraqi forces) and checkpoints along the major routes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Successes in reducing the leadership, capabilities, and influence of AQI after the surge allowed the Iraqi government, mainly under the direction of Prime Minster al-Maliki, to focus on other threats to Iraq’s stability, specifically the Shiite militias. The Iraqi government made plans as early as January 2008 to conduct a major offensive against the Shiite militia stronghold in Basra, Iraq. Two days before the attack, on March 25, JAM militias launched attacks in Baghdad with the hope of halting or diverting resources away from the planned offensive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mwi.usma.edu/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/MWI-shield-50x55.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-7126&quot; src=&quot;https://mwi.usma.edu/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/MWI-shield-50x55.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;50&quot; height=&quot;55&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Battle Begins&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The violence that erupted on March 23 surprised the US forces in Thawra District; the strategic and operational context that drove the violence’s logic didn’t filter down to their tactical level. Their only warning was when their garbage wasn’t picked by a contracted trash collector at the same time it typically was each week. When they called him, he was adamant that he was not coming. Then all hell broke loose—not just in Thawra District but all around Baghdad, and especially in Sadr City.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JAM’s uprising included launching 107-millimeter rockets against targets in and around Baghdad, including the International Zone (commonly referred to as the Green Zone) that served as the central location of Iraqi government offices. They also attacked many joint security stations, ISF checkpoints, and police stations around Sadr City. The ISF, police, and Sons of Iraq manning these locations mostly collapsed or joined forces with the insurgents. By the time the Basra offensive commenced as planned on March 25, JAM forces had cleared the Iraqi Army and police from Sadr City, overrun half of the checkpoints that surrounded Sadr City, and increased their rocket attacks against the Green Zone. The Americans defended and reinforced where they could and began to receive reports on the size and magnitude of the attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prime Minister al-Maliki could not allow JAM’s rockets and uprisings to have a strategic effect on national governance by either derailing the Basra offensive or making the Iraqi government seem ineffectual in providing security. On March 25, he authorized ISF and coalition forces to undertake operations against JAM. The mission was simple: stop the rockets and restore government control in Sadr City. Importantly, he did not change the standing order preventing coalition ground forces from going inside of Sadr City itself. US units would have to fight an enemy who maintained a real physical safe heaven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JAM’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rand.org/pubs/research_reports/RR160.html&quot;&gt;estimated&lt;/a&gt; strength within Sadr City ranged between two thousand and four thousand fighters armed with AK-47s, PKM machine guns, .50-caliber sniper rifles, rocket-propelled grenade (RPG) launchers, 60-, 82-, and 120-millimeter mortars, 107- and 122-millimeter rockets, and an unknown number of SA-7 surface-to-air missiles. The group’s fighters also had a seemingly unending supply of IEDs, especially explosive formed penetrators (EFPs) made of machined copper plates and homemade explosives that form a shaped charge capable of penetrating several inches of steel. JAM fighters ranged from local men with little training and equipped with small arms to foreign-trained “Special Groups” and snipers with advanced individual military skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mission of responding to JAM fell predominantly to the 3rd Brigade Combat Team, 4th Infantry Division, led by Col. John Hort, which had deployed to Iraq three months earlier and was responsible for the area around Sadr City. The two main units that would conduct the majority of the fighting were the 1st Battalion, 68th Armored Regiment (1-68 CAB), a combined arms battalion commanded by Lt. Col. Mike Pappal, and 1st Squadron, 2nd Stryker Cavalry Regiment (1-2SCR), commanded by Lt. Col. Dan Barnett.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The combat during the uprising was fierce. 1-68 CAB and 1-2 SCR responded immediately by attempting to re-secure the lost or abandoned checkpoints along Sadr City’s boundaries. Instead of insurgents fleeing when threatened with battle, they found JAM militants ready to fight, laying in hasty defenses, and attempting to mass against coalition forces. US platoons had to call in attack helicopters for support after finding themselves trapped by large groups of enemy fighters bunkered in multi-story buildings. Soldiers in one &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rand.org/pubs/research_reports/RR160.html&quot;&gt;unit&lt;/a&gt; had 75–100 JAM fighters try to overrun them as they attempted to secure buildings around a soccer field that was being used as a rocket launching site. Luckily, Army attack helicopter teams were able to support the platoon and push the enemy back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_10410&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mwi.usma.edu/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/82994.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-10410 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://mwi.usma.edu/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/82994.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;531&quot; srcset=&quot;/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/82994.jpg 800w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/01/82994-300x199.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/01/82994-768x510.jpg 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;An Iraqi National Police member provides security at a checkpoint on March 31, 2008. (Credit: 1st Sgt. Adrian Cadiz)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The intense nature of the fight caused 1-68 CAB to immediately transition to its fleet of M1 Abrams tanks and M2 Bradley infantry fighting vehicles (IFVs). They had parked these vehicles at Camp Taji, a large US base about a forty-five–minute drive away. Prior to the start of the battle, the battalion had traveled in up-armored High Mobility Multipurpose Wheeled Vehicles (HMMWVs), which were more appropriate to population-centric counterinsurgency operations. A normal patrol consisted of four HMMWVs and 16–20 soldiers. It took three to four days for 1-68 CAB to move and fully convert from a HMMWV-based counterinsurgency formation to an armored task force of Abrams and Bradleys. Patrols were organized at the company level to best use their equipment for the situation and urban environment. Bradleys, tanks, and armored HMMWVs were configured for best effect. For example, patrols consisted of one Bradley and two tanks or two Bradleys and one tank, with dismounted infantry in hunter-killer teams designed more for major urban fighting, rather than counterinsurgency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to the battle, 1-68 CAB had made numerous changes to the normal task organization of a battalion within a heavy brigade combat team (HBCT), which facilitated a quick transition to small-unit mixed armor and infantry teams. A standard CAB from an HBCT had two armor and two infantry companies as its major fighting forces. Normally these companies trained and deployed together, but are also designed to be capable of further task organizing to any variation the mission may require. When 1-68 CAB deployed into Baghdad, the battalion’s leadership quickly realized their armor companies did not have sufficient troops or vehicles to produce enough patrols to manage the considerable battlespace each was responsible for. Each company was therefore reorganized into three platoons; either one armor and two mechanized infantry platoons or two armor and one mechanized infantry platoon. Some companies were further stretched to four platoons. This gave each company the personnel needed to form large enough patrols and to have the total number of patrols needed to maintain a sustainable work/rest balance. But what it also did was create diverse teams of infantry and armor soldiers. Thus when 1-68 CAB converted back to armor and mechanized infantry teams, the command and personnel relationships were already well established.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As 1-68 CAB and 1-2 SCR continued to fight, the battalions’ higher headquarters during the battle, 3rd BCT, 4th Infantry Division, began to plan a movement-to-contact operation around and into parts of Sadr City to recapture all of the lost checkpoints and police stations. This course of action would have been a very destructive, high-risk operation. But the plan was shelved when ISF reinforcements arrived and quickly pushed into many of those locations so that at least the original checkpoints on the major routes into Sadr City were re-established. The mission was successful at pushing JAM back into Sadr City and even allowing for the return of some civilian activity that had ceased during initial days of the battle. Portions of Baghdad’s second largest market, the Jamila Market on al-Quds Street on the border between Sadr City and the Jamila neighborhood, slowly began reopening. But enemy forces maintained their sanctuary and showed their ability to attack at times of their choosing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The primary mission for 3rd BCT was to stop JAM rockets from hitting the Green Zone. From March 23 to March 31, JAM &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rand.org/pubs/research_reports/RR160.html&quot;&gt;launched&lt;/a&gt; over eighty-five rockets at the Green Zone. A major element of the BCT’s ability to go after JAM and the rockets was an unprecedented range of intelligence, surveillance, and reconnaissance (ISR) and strike capabilities, including: Joint Surveillance and Target Attack Radar System (JSTARS) aircraft; counter-battery radar; Global Hawk, Green Dart, Shadow, and Predator unmanned aerial systems, many armed with Hellfire missiles; Guided Multiple Launch Rocket System; air weapons teams of Army attack helicopters; constant Air Force close-air support; and Aerostat balloons and RAID camera feeds. Many of these were theater-level assets pushed all the way down to the brigade level. Previously, these would be considered division-level and above capabilities. But, in the fight for Sadr City, they were all under the BCT’s control. It took 3rd BCT’s headquarters at least three or four days to reconfigure itself to manage the large number of information feeds and assets now under the BCT’s control. Just identifying personnel to watch the different television feeds from the drones was a challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even with the most advanced capabilities available, stopping the rockets still required ground maneuver to seize rocket points of origin (POO). The plan to seize these locations, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rand.org/pubs/research_reports/RR160.html&quot;&gt;Operation Striker Denial&lt;/a&gt;, ran from March 26 to April 14. The US and ISF units conducted combined cordon-and-search operations on the neighborhoods immediately south of Sadr City that were within the maximum range of the enemy 107-millimeter rockets, taking advantage of securing key terrain that provided observation and fields of fire over the relatively level terrain. They occupied one of the few five-story building in the area immediately southwest of Sadr city, the Jamila neighborhood, establishing a patrol base with snipers on the roof. The building gave the snipers the ability to overwatch multiple POO sites and engage any positively identified combatants. Once the POOs were secured, they became a challenge to hold because of the enemy’s sanctuary. JAM fighters could easily slip and in and out of Sadr City, attack coalition forces, and then retreat back into their sanctuary. The routes to the POOs also had IEDs emplaced along them daily; US and ISF units would clear the IEDs one day only to find them there again the next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While coalition forces were prohibited from going inside Sadr City, they maintained an impressive capability to see inside the city and strike when necessary. Persistent observation of all open areas in the city was aided by everything from balloons equipped with modern cameras and positioned just outside the city to loitering drones. The strike capabilities previously mentioned gave coalition forces the ability to strike any JAM forces that came into the open from their concrete sanctuaries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The changing nature of the fight revealed that the Stryker vehicles used by 1-2 SCR were highly vulnerable to the EFPs and RPGs employed by JAM. 1-2 SCR &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rand.org/pubs/research_reports/RR160.html&quot;&gt;lost&lt;/a&gt; six Strykers in six days. Not only were the vehicles not survivable, but their width (especially when fitted with RPG cages due to their vulnerability) limited them to driving on the main roads, making their potential locations predictable and susceptible to ambush. For this and other reasons, 3rd BCT, with assets provided from its parent division, made changes to both 1-68 CAB’s and 1-2 SCR’s task organization and battlespace. Major parts of 1-2 SCR’s assigned battlespace were given to 1-68 CAB, whose Abrams tanks and Bradley IFVs provided soldiers more protection and firepower to fight JAM. 1-68 CAB received an additional tank company and two additional Stryker companies. 1-2 SCR additions included an armor platoon that began leading patrols so the tanks could bear the brunt of attacks before they could destroy the Stryker vehicles. After reorganization, the 1-68 CAB and 1-2 SCR combined task force included nine companies. The total US forces numbered around three thousand, with an additional few thousand ISF depending on the phase of the operation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_10408&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mwi.usma.edu/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/83990.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-10408 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://mwi.usma.edu/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/83990.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;460&quot; srcset=&quot;/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/83990.jpg 800w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/01/83990-300x173.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/01/83990-768x442.jpg 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Soldiers from 4th Platoon, Company A, 1-2 SCR load back onto their Stryker after a dismounted patrol in Sadr City on April 1, 2008. (Credit: Master Sgt. Christina Bhatti)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both of the assigned missions—to stop rockets hitting the Green Zone and to restore government control of Sadr City—were constrained by JAM’s ability to slip in and out of Sadr City to launch rockets from sites closer to their intended targets, lay IEDs, and attack coalition forces. One of the first coalition responses was to use concrete barriers to seal the individual routes leading out of Sadr City to the southwest, increase patrols of these areas, conduct ambushes on known firing points, and secure key terrain by, among other things, reinforcing ISF checkpoints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These initial efforts were troop-intensive and not fully effective in stopping the flows of fighters, weapons, and rocket launches. 3rd BCT decided to construct a continuous wall made up of twelve-foot-tall, six-ton T-wall sections along the entire southern border of Sadr City on al-Quds street, named Route Gold on US military maps. Previous walls had been built along other portions of Sadr City’s boundaries that set the conditions for the planned operation. By this time, the areas bounded by Routes Grizzlies, Gold, Predator, and Pluto were mostly secured, but the effort was troop-intensive and JAM could still infiltrate in and launch rockets as well as plant IEDs and conduct other types of attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On April 15, Operation Gold Wall was started. 1-68 CAB and 1-2 SCR conducted daily concrete-laying missions to construct the continuous wall. The desired purpose of the wall was different than that of previous walls built. Instead of protecting populations by keeping insurgents out of areas, the Gold Wall would be built to affect JAM while keeping them in Sadr City. Like medieval siege engines, the units formed each night in massive convoys consisting of a tank in the lead, flatbed trucks with concrete barriers, a civilian or military crane, Bradleys, and other vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The construction of the wall was heavily contested from the beginning. JAM’s first tactic was to establish a defensive zone by emplacing IEDs along the roads leading up to where construction of the wall would start that day. Because of these IEDs, the concrete-laying patrols had to first do a deliberate breach into the battle area. Streets were lined with trash, each pile a possible IED hiding spot. Combat engineers started by doing route clearance, but the normal procedures required them to stop at each suspected IED location, conduct a detailed search of the area, and, if an IED was present, neutralize the bomb (preferably done by attached explosive ordnance disposal teams) and try to render it safe for collection so that it could be exploited for evidence. The process could take hours for a single device. But JAM had lined the roads with IEDs. Some patrols would encounter twenty IEDs on a single street. US forces adapted with convoys developing new and faster methods. Tanks began to fire 120-millimeter canister rounds (in essence, shotgun-type rounds that, once fired, open into hundreds of tiny pieces) down streets from their main guns. The canister rounds blew the trash off the streets and, in many cases, exploded IEDs lying in wait for the patrol. If an IED was found, they would also shoot at them with 25-millimeter cannons and 7.62-millimeter machine guns to detonate them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once a patrol reached the site where the walls would be emplaced, the tanks, Bradleys, and infantry established overwatch positions for the crane and team of soldiers that would guide the massive concrete walls into place. Initially, JAM heavily targeted these patrols from within the city. This revealed their locations, though, and they were easily engaged. Some JAM militia fired from cover provided by buildings along Route Gold. Snipers would also shoot at the crane cable or the lone soldier that was forced to climb a ladder to unhook each concrete wall. Special operations forces snipers were extremely useful in a counter-sniper role. Nevertheless, there were situations where confirmed snipers and fighters that could not be engaged by US snipers had to be targeted with air-delivered, precision-guided bombs or Guided Multiple Launch Rocket System (GMLRS) rounds that could penetrate the buildings’ layers of concrete. One instance that required a concrete-penetrating option was when a JAM sniper occupied and fortified one of the few five-story buildings north of the Gold Wall was being constructed and at a key intersection where he was able to engage the wall-building team. Direct fire placed on the building did not affect the sniper’s fortified position. 1-68 CAB’s solution was to drop the building using the GMLRS. But for the duration of the Battle of Sadr City, coalition forces used fewer than three mortar or artillery fire missions because of the risk of collateral damage, the prospect of injuring civilians, and the potential political ramifications both locally for the government of Iraq and internationally for political support to the coalition forces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_10409&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mwi.usma.edu/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/85228.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-10409 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://mwi.usma.edu/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/85228.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;532&quot; srcset=&quot;/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/85228.jpg 800w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/01/85228-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/01/85228-768x511.jpg 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Engineers from 3rd BCT, 4th Infantry Division use a crane in the southern portion of Sadr City to place barriers along the road to help increase security in the area on April 20, 2008. (Credit: 1st Sgt. Adrian Cadiz)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The wall construction went slowly. At first, the wall was only constructed at night to take advantage of the American night-vision advantage. But when these forces would return to their bases after the nighttime construction operations, JAM emplaced more IEDs on the routes to the wall construction area. A decision was quickly made to transition to twenty-four–hour operations, rotating 1-68 CAB and 1-2 SCR every thirteen hours to give each patrol both daylight and nighttime hours. The number of concrete barriers that could be emplaced in a single shift varied greatly, depending on the enemy situation, number of tractor trailer vehicles to transport concrete from staging areas, and other factors. A bad night might not see a single barrier emplaced; during the most productive thirteen-hour shift, 105 were laid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The logistical planning and execution of each barrier emplacement is an impressive case study in of itself. The number of personnel, vehicles, and refined tactics to safely emplace an average of over seventy barriers in a single shift is a lesson that must be captured for any similar future operations. A concrete holding area had to be constructed near Route Gold with a continuous flow of barriers and activity. Production at Iraqi concrete batching sites had to be increased. Each operation included a route clearance team to clear the route up to the wall; a security team for the holding area; a holding area team that included a crane, flatbed tractor trailers, and even two armored forklifts that in some cases transported walls all the way down to the wall site using already cleared routes; and a building site team (the main effort responsible for IED clearing around the site and construction of the wall) that included a crane, emplacement crew, and combined-arms team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As JAM realized that IEDs were not going to stop the construction of the wall, the group’s fighters came out in force to fight the besiegers with direct fire. By so doing, they gave up one of the biggest advantages of being an urban fighter: remaining hidden by the city. Once JAM militia engaged the wall construction team, they became visible, easily identified, and targeted by the coalition’s far superior weapons and aerial ISR and strike capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the decision regarding where to place the wall was based primarily on the maximum range of rockets targeting the Green Zone, one of the surprising effects the wall had on the enemy was cutting them off from their financial support. The Gold Wall on al-Quds Street not only separated Sadr City from nearby neighborhoods, which were more affluent and vulnerable to JAM extortion, but also cut JAM off from the Jamila Market, which was a major source of money. JAM extorted residents, merchants, and customers around the market area. The group also sold its own goods and weapons in the market. Coalition forces were not fully aware of the consequent effects on JAM finances before they started constructing the wall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The militia had little choice but to “fight the wall.” Being sealed into the city would eventually force them to enter through heavily armed Iraqi Army checkpoints that would allow government forces to individually target them. It also would prevent their access to the Jamila Market and the population south of the wall. But most importantly, the wall would prevent the group’s ability to move fighters and weapons, conduct rocket attacks, and maintain a flow of resources, all of which were vital to JAM’s ability to function and retain influence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As JAM members fought the wall, they continuously diminished their resources. In the beginning, JAM contested the wall with large groups of fighters. As the days and weeks progressed and the wall continued to grow, the numbers of fighters that would attack the siege party progressively got smaller. Coalition ground forces were successful at killing enemy fighters that contested the wall. At the same time, 3rd BCT also became increasingly effective at destroying rocket teams with the suite of persistent ISR and immediate precision airstrikes (from attack helicopters, fixed-wing aircraft, and drones) that they controlled. As the final barriers of the wall were emplaced, JAM appeared to have exhausted its supplies and fighters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The positive effect of the Gold Wall is hard to argue. From the start of the operations on April 15 to late May, when the wall was connected to other walls that had been previously built or were simultaneously built around Sadr City, the number of SIGACTS recorded in 1-68 CAB’s area of responsibility—attacks and other significant events—went from of a high of 138 a week to just eight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In just over a month, 3rd BCT had emplaced four thousand twelve-foot-tall, six-ton T-wall sections to construct a wall nearly three miles long. During the battle the BCT &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rand.org/pubs/research_reports/RR160.html&quot;&gt;fired&lt;/a&gt; 120 Hellfire missiles, six Guided Multiple Launch Rocket System rounds, eight Air Force guided bombs, and over eight hundred 120-millimeter tank and twelve-thousand 25-millimeter Bradley cannon rounds. Precise JAM casualty numbers are hard to determine (especially since coalition forces weren’t able to go inside Sadr City to conduct battle damage assessments during the operation). Some &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rand.org/pubs/research_reports/RR160.html&quot;&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt; estimated the number JAM fighters killed to be only 700, but it is likely that US and ISF soldiers killed, wounded, or captured thousands of JAM fighters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rand.org/pubs/research_reports/RR160.html&quot;&gt;May 12&lt;/a&gt;, Muqtada al-Sadr announced a ceasefire. The final barrier of the gold wall was emplaced on May 15. Al-Sadr’s decision was clearly made from a position of weakness. JAM fighters within Sadr City had been neutralized. They were surrounded and effectively contained inside a concrete fortress. While the wall’s completion didn’t mean JAM was defeated, it did set the conditions for reestablishing government control of Sadr City. Iraq Army forces were ordered into Sadr City, but faced minimal resistance from JAM’s exhausted forces. Both Iraqi and coalition forces then exploited their success with major reconstruction projects that focused on local economics, government services, and infrastructure. They also transitioned back to counterinsurgency operations to maintain control of the gains they had achieved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mwi.usma.edu/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/MWI-shield-50x55.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-7126&quot; src=&quot;https://mwi.usma.edu/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/MWI-shield-50x55.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;50&quot; height=&quot;55&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lessons from the Battle of Sadr City&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Context in war is everything. The political and military factors involved in the Battle of Sadr City—from the tactical to the strategic level—are in many ways unique. But there are also a number of urban warfare lessons that were learned (and in many cases re-learned) that need to be captured for consideration in future urban combat operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The history of urban warfare includes a wide variety of operations along the full spectrum of conflict (offense, defense, and stability). Since 9/11, the US military has predominantly been engaged in low-intensity counterinsurgency and stability operations, but the Battle of Sadr City was a high-intensity offensive mission against an enemy-held area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Urban terrain gives a distinct advantage to a defender. Military or militarized forces that defend from cities seek to diminish the technological and numerical superiorities of an attacking force, especially ISR and aerial-enabled strike capabilities. Dense urban terrain limits the ability of military forces to maneuver. Hiding among buildings that effectively become concrete bunkers, defenders can funnel military formations into ambushes and terrain that breaks them apart, allowing them to be defeated piecemeal. A city’s maze of fortified structures also allows defenders to maneuver from building to building, often with prepared tunnels or holes in walls, to avoid air-delivered munitions or fixing forces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Populated urban terrain, where it is extremely difficult to distinguish enemy forces from the civilian population, allows an insurgent to employ guerrilla tactics. These include anti-armor near ambushes, sniper attacks, and bombings. If engaged, enemy forces slip back into the population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The entire environment establishes a military dilemma. The advantages that occupying a city gives to a defender will drive them to withdraw into cities. Likewise, the disadvantages for an attacker encourages most modern military forces to adopt an approach used historically, avoiding or bypassing cities whenever possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But warfare includes chance, and militaries often do not get a choice. When a war’s political objectives include destroying an enemy in a city, reclaiming a besieged city, or both, the military must accomplish the mission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many mission-specific variables that will determine a military’s approach to accomplishing an urban operation. Among these are the amount of time and forces available to accomplish the mission, the viability of removing the city’s population, and political will in the face of the destructive nature of an urban battle. History shows that the most common approach a military force will take against any enemy-held urban area is to isolate or surround the city, remove as much of the population as possible, and then conduct costly, block-by-block, house-by-house operations until the enemy is cleared from the city. Because of the advantages afforded the defender, the attacker will typically have to use massive amounts of concrete-penetrating artillery and bombs that destroy most of the structures in the area of operations. This explains a US Army major’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://timesmachine.nytimes.com/timesmachine/1968/02/08/88924930.html&quot;&gt;remark during the Vietnam War’s Tet Offensive&lt;/a&gt; that “it became necessary to destroy the town to save it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These methods were used in most urban operations to retake an enemy captured city in recent history: Stalingrad in 1943, Hue in 1968, Grozny in 1994, and Fallujah in 2004. This is also the approach the world has witnessed in recent operations in cities occupied by the Islamic State, from Mosul to Marawi. But the 2008 Battle of Sadr City revealed a different approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of the lessons of urban warfare discovered in the Battle of Sadr City are enduring; others are unique to the context of the fight. Either way, it is important to ensure the lessons learned, or relearned, are considered by military thinkers when they face the next complex urban mission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strategically, the Battle of Sadr City reminds us that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.clausewitz.com/readings/Echevarria/ECHJFQ.htm&quot;&gt;war is the continuation of policy&lt;/a&gt; by other means and subject to political control, objectives, and rationale. Politics and war are always intertwined. Military forces must account for national political objectives and constraints on the use of force when deciding on military strategy and tactics. In the case of Sadr City, significant political constraints were placed on the military.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since coalition forces were not allowed to go into the city the enemy was using as a base of operations and safe haven, they were forced to create different options. They could not adopt the historical tactics of house-to-house clearing, particularly since the option to evacuate the city’s two million residents was not feasible because of the both the fragile sectarian security situation and political environment in Iraq. While 3rd BCT did execute information operations, telling civilians to leave or stay clear of the battle areas (especially the vicinity of the wall-building operations), the reality of the situation was that there was nowhere for the residents of Sadr City to go. Managing two million internally displaced persons was not something the government of Iraq was capable of, politically or logistically. Unable to clear the enemy safe haven, the military sought to isolate it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of the local, national, and international political dynamics, coalition forces also further self-restrained their methods by only using wide-area effects weapons such as mortars and artillery in very limited circumstances out of concern over civilian casualties and the destruction of infrastructure. The risk to the wall construction could have been reduced with such fire, but it was not used. But, the need for concrete-penetrating munitions, which drove the use of GMLRS, for example, on enemy snipers deep within a five-story building, was consistent with previous urban battles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maintaining the political will to continue urban operations will often prove challenging, but will always be crucial. In the Battle of Sadr City, coalition forces had to worry about the will of their political leaders and casualty-weary populations; six US soldiers &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rand.org/pubs/research_reports/RR160.html&quot;&gt;died&lt;/a&gt; during this battle. They also had to worry about Iraqi political will, as al-Maliki balanced fragile sectarian relationships and populations. Moreover, all perceptions were influenced by a globally connected world and 24/7 media reporting. Journalists were embedded with coalition forces during much of the battle. The total number of civilian casualties is unclear, but had destruction and civilian casualties reached a critical threshold, the military operation would have been impacted by further political constraints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Operationally, it is important to remember that the Battle of Sadr City was fought within a greater campaign. It was influenced by all the other operations going on around the country (and vice versa). There were reports of JAM leadership asking for reinforcements from other strongholds, but those fighters were too busy fighting coalition forces and ISF in their areas. The Iraqi planned offensive against Basra was the spark of JAM’s uprising in Baghdad. A military commander’s ability to understand, visualize, and describe these connections will always be a challenge, and an important part of a commander’s staff’s focus in combat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Battle of Sadr City also strongly contests the overly simplistic notion that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/urban-combat-cities-are-sponges-that-soak-up-troops&quot;&gt;cities are sponges that soak up troops&lt;/a&gt;. Determining force requirements for urban environments cannot only focus on the size of the city and its population. The Battle of Sadr City saw a coalition force of around three thousand defeat an enemy of between two thousand and five thousand within an urban area inhabited by two million residents. The political objective, military mission, forces and tools available, enemy capabilities, security environment, terrain, and time needed to accomplish the mission all are more important factors than just the size of the city. A small military force can accomplish many missions in extremely large urban areas given the right circumstances and objectives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The small American force in the Battle of Sadr City would not have been able to accomplish its mission without the unprecedented theater-level ISR and strike capabilities pushed down to 3rd BCT. The organizational flexibility necessary to make such changes and the skills required to manage those assets are all important lessons to institutionalize and consider when thinking about force size and design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tactically, there are many lessons from the Battle of Sadr City. Adaptions made by the units involved—across all of the Army’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://armypubs.army.mil/epubs/DR_pubs/DR_a/pdf/web/ARN5089_ADP%203-0%20FINAL%20WEB.pdf&quot;&gt;warfighting functions&lt;/a&gt; (mission command, movement and maneuver, intelligence, fires, sustainment, and protection)—could be discussed at length. Selecting available capabilities, accounting for terrain considerations, and the use of concrete obstacles stand out as necessary highlights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Military capabilities are about having the best tools for the job. The way military capabilities are designed is so when a formation faces a situation or environment it wasn’t prepared for, small-unit leaders can adapt their methods and their modular equipment. When a force faces an unfamiliar environment, it must be able to adapt. But good leaders and units adapt; great ones adapt quickly. The units of the Battle of Sadr City quickly adapted from counterinsurgency formations and methods to high-intensity urban combat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These adaptations required employing equipment and weapons for different purposes than they were designed for, like using tank canister rounds to clear streets of IEDs. Adaptations also can call for completely different equipment. The fact that 1-68 CAB had its tanks and armored vehicles within reach—and had trained for high-intensity operations before its deployment to Iraq—allowed the unit to quickly transition from a counterinsurgent force into a combined arms team capable of high-intensity urban combat. Tanks and infantry fighting vehicles proved invaluable, while Stryker vehicles were found wanting in this environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is not that the Stryker is not a useful vehicle. It offers a combination of speed, mobility, and transport options unlike that of other ground combat vehicles. But in “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rand.org/content/dam/rand/pubs/monographs/2011/RAND_MG1093.sum.pdf&quot;&gt;iron triangle&lt;/a&gt;” considerations (payload, performance, and protection) for vehicles in this environment, it did not provide the necessary protection against EFPs and was too wide for most of the urban terrain. Adding tanks that could lead the Stryker patrols was a successful adaptation to the Stryker organization. Other vehicle mixes and tactical changes were also required, such as emplacing Bradley IFVs in overwatch positions on high ground and using highly maneuverable armored HMMVWs to secure the rear of formations. Until the military deploys a combat vehicle more suited for urban terrain with mobile protected firepower capabilities, adaptable leaders and equipment sets will be required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Concrete barriers deserve their own place in urban combat history as one of &lt;a href=&quot;https://mwi.usma.edu/effective-weapon-modern-battlefield-concrete/&quot;&gt;the most effective weapons of modern warfare&lt;/a&gt;—especially in the Battle of Sadr City.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Operation Gold Wall took many of the advantages of fighting in a city away from the enemy. The wall took the enemy’s ability to hide among the population, took away their ability defeat the attacker in detail with guerrilla tactics, separated them from multiple vital support lines, and forced them to fight. If JAM did not come out to resist the emplacement of the wall they faced isolation, being cut off from resupply, firing sites, and their critical financial base. When they did come out to resist, they became visible and were easily targeted by US ISR and ground forces. Instead of fish in the sea, they became fish in a barrel. Building a wall around the enemy’s base of operation created the conditions that made it both impossible for enemy fighters to operate effectively and possible to restore security to the broader population of Baghdad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The use of concrete before and during the battle must be considered for future urban offensive, defensive, and stability operations. These lessons will quickly be lost if not written into doctrine. Creating a formation with effective siege-engine capabilities, able to emplace concrete walls safely and quickly, is both a science and an art. The technologies and tactics all played a role in the speed of wall emplacement and should be used as a starting point. But these methods could also be improved with planning, practice, and possibly new innovations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Operation Gold Wall employed medieval siege warfare tactics with a twist. Instead of a city’s population withdrawing behind castle walls to wait out the besieging army, coalition forces brought a modern version of a siege engine up to the edge of JAM’s safe haven and built a wall around the enemy. This was very similar to the ancient tactic of circumvallation, an example of which was seen when Julius Caesar &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.britannica.com/event/Battle-of-Alesia-52-BCE&quot;&gt;built&lt;/a&gt; a twelve-foot-high, eleven-mile wall around Alesia to defeat 60,000 Gauls in 52 BC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, there are also lessons from ancient siege operations that could be applied to future modern urban combat operations. For instance, during the Middle Ages, a large wicker or wooden screen called a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.revolvy.com/page/Mantlet&quot;&gt;mantlet&lt;/a&gt; was placed in front of a besieging force’s engineers digging trenches up to a castle wall (an activity called “&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ancientfortresses.org/medieval-siege-warfare.htm&quot;&gt;sapping&lt;/a&gt;,” the origin of the modern term “sapper”) to provide concealment and some cover from archers on top of the walls. The coalition forces’ concrete emplacement teams, especially the lone soldier that had to unhook the crane cable from the T-wall section, were extremely vulnerable. A version of the mantlet or modern sniper screens could be placed in front of the barrier operation to provide concealment from attack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even without a historical review, advancements can be made in countermobility, siege, and isolation tactics, especially those involving concrete barrier emplacement operations. Despite the years and miles of concrete operations in Iraq, no notable new technologies were deployed to assist in concrete emplacement. Concrete wall design did not change. Cranes were required to get T-walls off trucks and soldiers had to scale ladders to unhook them from the cranes. A closer examination is warranted, with the aim of enhancing the construction, transportation, and emplacement of barriers and walls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The psychological impacts of the Gold Wall also warrant discussion. The wall clearly agitated the enemy and made JAM fighters come out and fight. The concept of imposing one’s will on the enemy goes back at least to Prussian philosopher Carl von Clausewitz. The actual act of imposing their will on the enemy by building the wall had a positive psychological effect on the coalition soldiers. It was a proactive action, fundamentally different than the reactive responses that had characterized day-to-day operations prior to the battle and especially the emotionally draining experience of waiting to get hit by IEDs without an enemy to strike back at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Battle of Sadr City also serves as a vignette to analyze urban terrain, both for the physical advantages and disadvantages it provides to both sides of a battle and in relation to the complex, social-cultural “system of systems” that are cities. Existing key terrain has to be properly identified and then utilized. Because Sadr City was purpose built, its buildings designed and construction relatively at the same time, its uniform layout of largely three-story structures made the few taller buildings key terrain that could be fortified and used as overwatch positions for key locations such as major intersections, ambush sites, or rocket-launching sites. Key terrain can also be created to shape a battlefield. The Gold Wall fell into this category, but attacking forces might also build a new piece of high ground with a new building, tower, or other structure. Finally, key terrain can also be removed, like when, during the Battle of Sadr City, attacking forces used GMLRS to reduce a sniper bunker in a five-story building. Beyond physical terrain analysis, understanding and balancing the relationship of a city’s systems to enemy and friendly forces will continue to be a vital requirement for the military. The financial and popular support provided by a very specific part of the city was a critical requirement for JAM’s survival, so much so the group gave up all the advantages of city warfare attempting to maintain control of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The US military prefers to avoid cities. But being a global superpower with complex and wide-ranging national interests means the military often does not get to choose where, who, or when it will fight. The Battle of Sadr City provides one alternative to traditional approaches to defeating an enemy force that has chosen to fight from within a city. It breaks the mold of avoiding cities because of the advantages it gives a defender, the troop-intensive requirements of attacking a city, and the destructive results of doing so. The use of combined arms maneuver (tanks and armored infantry fighting vehicles), massive ISR and precision strike capabilities, and elements of ancient siege warfare (walls) allowed a relatively small American force to contain, exhaust, and set the conditions to defeat a large enemy force within a populated dense urban area without destroying the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Special thanks to Dr. Dave Johnson, Col. (ret) Mike Pappal, Lt. Col. (ret) Rob MacMillan, Maj. John Chambers, and Command Sgt. Maj. (ret) John Kurak, who contributed to this article with their experience and research.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;author-shortcodes&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-inner&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mwi.usma.edu/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/john-spencer.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-info&quot;&gt;John Spencer serves as the Chair of Urban Warfare Studies as the Modern War Institute and Co-Director of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://mwi.usma.edu/urban-warfare-project/&quot;&gt;Urban Warfare Project&lt;/a&gt;. He is a retired Army major who served twenty-five years as an infantryman, including two combat deployments to Iraq. Follow him at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/SpencerGuard&quot;&gt;@SpencerGuard&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;The views expressed in this article are those of the authors and do not reflect the official policy or position of the Department of the Army, the Department of Defense, or the US government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Featured image credit: Staff Sgt. Jason Bailey&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;apss-social-share apss-theme-4 clearfix&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;apss-facebook apss-single-icon&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;apss-icon-block clearfix&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;apss-social-text&quot;&gt;Share on Facebook&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;apss-share&quot;&gt;Share&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;apss-twitter apss-single-icon&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;apss-icon-block clearfix&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;apss-social-text&quot;&gt;Share on Twitter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;apss-share&quot;&gt;Tweet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;apss-google-plus apss-single-icon&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;apss-icon-block clearfix&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;apss-social-text&quot;&gt;Share on Google Plus&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;apss-share&quot;&gt;Share&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;apss-linkedin apss-single-icon&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;apss-icon-block clearfix&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;apss-social-text&quot;&gt;Share on LinkedIn&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;apss-share&quot;&gt;Share&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;apss-email apss-single-icon&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;apss-icon-block clearfix&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;apss-social-text&quot;&gt;Send email&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;apss-share&quot;&gt;Mail&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;apss-print apss-single-icon&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;apss-icon-block clearfix&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;apss-social-text&quot;&gt;Print&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;apss-share&quot;&gt;Print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 15:50:38 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jspencer508</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Stealing the Enemy's Urban Advantage: The Battle of Sadr City - Modern War Institute</og:title>
<og:description>From March 23 to May 12, 2008, US Army and Iraq security forces engaged in an intense urban battle in and around Baghdad’s Shiite neighborhood of Sadr City. The battle forced units that had been mainly focused on counterinsurgency operations to convert overnight into combined-arms teams of armor and mechanized infantry and engage a large …</og:description>
<og:url>https://mwi.usma.edu/stealing-enemys-urban-advantage-battle-sadr-city/</og:url>
<og:image>https://mwi.usma.edu/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/97393.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mwi.usma.edu/stealing-enemys-urban-advantage-battle-sadr-city/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Facebook Referred to Kids as Young as Five as “Whales” for Its Monetized Games</title>
<link>https://www.usgamer.net/articles/facebook-unsealed-documents-whales-mobile-games</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.usgamer.net/articles/facebook-unsealed-documents-whales-mobile-games</guid>
<description>&lt;header class=&quot;header-standard&quot; readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;details&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;

&lt;p itemprop=&quot;summary&quot; class=&quot;subtitle&quot;&gt;Facebook wouldn't refund large purchases made by underage gamers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/header&gt;&lt;p&gt;You've heard this story before: kid wants to buy something in the mobile game they're playing, asks their parents for their credit card info, then accidentally racks up a bunch of charges. It turns out the same thing happened on Facebook, newly unsealed court documents reveal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2012 Facebook fought a class-action lawsuit which claimed the social media company profited from children who accidentally racked up huge credit card charges. The lead plaintiff was playing a game on Facebook when they asked to borrow their mother's credit card to make a $20 in-game purchase. According to lawyers, the child continued to make charges to the same card for weeks without realizing it. They believed they were making the purchases &quot;with virtual currency[.]&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.revealnews.org/blog/a-judge-unsealed-a-trove-of-internal-facebook-documents-following-our-legal-action/&quot;&gt;The Reveal&lt;/a&gt; was recently able to unseal internal Facebook documents regarding refunds for games. According to the documents, Facebook conducted an analysis of users playing Facebook games after employees began expressing concern. The results found the average age of Angry Birds players on Facebook was five years old.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/uWk1Is4cEBc?wmode=opaque&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;390&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; allowtransparency=&quot;true&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The internal Facebook memo discovered that while parents are aware of their children playing games on Facebook, many don't believe their child would be able to purchase anything without authorization. This is how purchases on Apple iOS work as buyers must re-authorize every purchase with their password.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Reveal reports that in one of the unsealed documents, two Facebook employees are recorded discussing whether or not to refund a child—whom they refer to as a &quot;whale&quot;—who racked up $6,545 in charges from a Facebook game. &quot;Is the user writing in [as] a parent, or is this user a 13ish year old,&quot; asks one employee recorded as Michael. The other Facebook employee named Gillian responds, &quot;It's a 12ish yr[sic] old. Says [it's] 15. Looks a big younger. She* not its. Lol.&quot; Michael then replies, &quot;...I wouldn't refund.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The class-action lawsuit against Facebook was settled confidentially in 2016, but the judge who unsealed the documents notes the information will &quot;be of great public interest, particularly since it relates specifically to Facebook's transactions with minors.&quot; This comes at a time where Facebook is facing a new level of scrutiny after the company is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usgamer.net/articles/psa-massive-facebook-breach-stole-login-info-of-50-million-accounts&quot;&gt;was accused of using personal data inappropriately&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although gaming is just one part of Facebook, information from the documents should shed light on how Facebook interacts with its users and treats the customers that entrust it with personal data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 14:31:03 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>throwaway2048</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:title>Facebook Referred to Kids as Young as Five as &quot;Whales&quot; for Its Monetized Games</og:title>
<og:description>Facebook wouldn't refund large purchases made by underage gamers.</og:description>
<og:image>https://cdn.gamer-network.net/2019/usgamer/facebook_logo.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.usgamer.net/articles/facebook-unsealed-documents-whales-mobile-games</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Apple leaves Facebook offices in disarray after revoking app permissions</title>
<link>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2019/jan/31/apple-facebook-campus-permissions-revoked-teens-access-data-iphone-app</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2019/jan/31/apple-facebook-campus-permissions-revoked-teens-access-data-iphone-app</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Apple has left Facebook’s campus in disarray after the company revoked the social network’s permission to build or run employee-only applications, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/facebook-employees-angry-after-apple-blocks-its-internal-ios-apps-2019-1?r=US&amp;amp;IR=T&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;according to reports&lt;/a&gt;. Employees were reportedly left unable to read cafeteria menus, call for inter-office transport or use versions of the social network’s own apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The move came on Wednesday, the day after it was revealed that Facebook had allegedly exploited a loophole in Apple’s approval system to bypass rules that banned the harvesting of data about what apps are installed on a user’s phone. Facebook Research, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2019/jan/30/facebook-paid-13-year-olds-for-access-to-all-their-internet-data&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;an app&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2019/jan/30/facebook-paid-13-year-olds-for-access-to-all-their-internet-data&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;the company paid users as young as 13 to install&lt;/a&gt; that routed their iPhone traffic through the company’s own servers, had been built using an enterprise developer certificate (EDC) issued by Apple to companies that need to build applications for internal use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2019/jan/30/facebook-paid-13-year-olds-for-access-to-all-their-internet-data&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Apple revoked Facebook’s EDCs&lt;/a&gt;, telling the Guardian: “We designed our Enterprise Developer Program solely for the internal distribution of apps within an organisation. Facebook has been using their membership to distribute a data-collecting app to consumers, which is a clear breach of their agreement with Apple. Any developer using their enterprise certificates to distribute apps to consumers will have their certificates revoked, which is what we did in this case to protect our users and their data.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The revocation didn’t just hit the Facebook Research app. Every app the company built using its EDC was rendered inoperable, with users reportedly unable to even open the programs from their home screens. That included internal test versions of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/facebook&quot; data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and Instagram, widely distributed to employees so that they can experience newer features before they are released to the general public. Following the revocation, those employees had to download released versions of the iOS apps from Apple’s App Store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Apple’s response also hit some of the basic infrastructure built into Facebook’s offices, particularly its HQ in Menlo Park, California. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/facebook-employees-angry-after-apple-blocks-its-internal-ios-apps-2019-1?r=US&amp;amp;IR=T&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;According to an internal memo&lt;/a&gt;, obtained by Business Insider, apps including Ride, which lets employees take shuttles between buildings on the company’s sprawling campus, and Mobile Home, an employee information portal, were down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook have been approached for comment.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 14:04:40 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>andyjohnson0</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://www.theguardian.com/technology/2019/jan/31/apple-facebook-campus-permissions-revoked-teens-access-data-iphone-app</og:url>
<og:description>Move comes after Facebook exploited loophole to harvest data about apps installed on people’s iPhones</og:description>
<og:image>https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a7607acafc9e4d4060be3e4f6d661b5b820f7af5/297_210_1644_986/master/1644.jpg?width=1200&amp;height=630&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;overlay-align=bottom%2Cleft&amp;overlay-width=100p&amp;overlay-base64=L2ltZy9zdGF0aWMvb3ZlcmxheXMvdGctZGVmYXVsdC5wbmc&amp;s=94961b64633a4129400b3dcfc6aef9b6</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Apple leaves Facebook offices in disarray after revoking app permissions</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2019/jan/31/apple-facebook-campus-permissions-revoked-teens-access-data-iphone-app</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A “gold standard” study finds deleting Facebook is great for your mental health</title>
<link>https://www.salon.com/2019/01/30/a-gold-standard-study-finds-deleting-facebook-is-great-for-your-mental-health/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.salon.com/2019/01/30/a-gold-standard-study-finds-deleting-facebook-is-great-for-your-mental-health/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Many of us have become so accustomed to social media that it is hard to remember when it was not intrinsic to our lives, though in reality it has not existed in a meaningful sense for more than 20 years. Over the last decade, the amount of time spent on social media and in front of screens has slowly yet steadily increased, arousing the interest of many health professionals trying to understand its impact on human health. A &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.stanford.edu/~gentzkow/research/facebook.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;new study,&lt;/a&gt; which is being hailed as the most trustworthy scientific assessment of social media's effects, suggests that quitting Facebook is unequivocally positive for one's mental health.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Researchers at Stanford University and New York University who led the study — which was posted on an open access site called the Social Science Research Network — recruited 2,844 Facebook users via Facebook ads. Those users were initially asked to fill out extensive questionnaires about their overall well-being, political views, and daily routine. Half of the users were then randomly assigned to deactivate their Facebook account for four weeks in exchange for payment. Researchers regularly checked the Facebook accounts during the month to make sure they weren’t reactivated, and regularly received text messages to asses these users' moods, creating a real-time evaluation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;proper-ad-unit&quot; id=&quot;proper-ad-content_1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;proper-caption&quot;&gt;Advertisement:&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, researchers concluded that not using Facebook reduced online activity, including other social media use, and increased offline activity such as watching television and socializing with friends and family more. Those who deactivated also observed a decrease in political polarization and news knowledge, and an increase in subjective well-being. The one-month cleanse also led to a reduction in time spent on Facebook for several weeks after the experiment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Deactivation caused small but significant improvements in well-being, and in particular on self-reported happiness, life satisfaction, depression, and anxiety,” the authors wrote. “Effects on subjective well-being as measured by responses to brief daily text messages are positive but not significant.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the authors of the study explain, “there may be no technology since television that has so dramatically reshaped the way people communicate, get information, and spend their time.” The social media behemoth has nearly 2.3 billion monthly users. According to data from 2016, the average users spends 50 minutes per day on Facebook and its sister platforms Instagram and Facebook Messenger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not the first time researchers have looked at the effect of Facebook and other social media platforms on human health. However, researchers of this study say their findings debunk previous research suggesting Facebook is good for its users. As the researchers state: “We find little evidence to support the hypothesis suggested by prior work that Facebook might be more beneficial for ‘active’ users—for example, users who regularly comment on pictures and posts from friends and family instead of just scrolling through their news feeds.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The authors do advise that there are caveats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“First, effects could differ with the duration or scale of deactivation,” the researchers state. “A longer period without Facebook might have less impact on news knowledge as people find alternative news sources, and either more or less impact on subjective well-being. Furthermore, a larger-scale experiment in which a greater share of the population deactivated could have a different impact due to network effects and equilibrium adjustments.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paper is being praised for its rigor by other academics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This is impressive work, and they do a good job sorting out causality,” Erik Brynjolfsson, director of the Massachusetts Institute of Technology Initiative on the Digital Economy, told &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/01/30/health/facebook-psychology-health.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;the New York Times&lt;/a&gt;. “This is the way to answer these kinds of questions; it’s the gold standard for how to do science. A lot of what we’ve heard before about social media’s effects was based on surveys.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 13:50:32 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>smashcash</dc:creator>
<og:title>A &quot;gold standard&quot; study finds deleting Facebook is great for your mental health</og:title>
<og:description>A unique study praised for its rigor finds numerous upsides to deactivating your Facebook account</og:description>
<og:image>https://media.salon.com/2018/06/facebook-garbage-pile.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>https://www.salon.com/2019/01/30/a-gold-standard-study-finds-deleting-facebook-is-great-for-your-mental-health/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.salon.com/2019/01/30/a-gold-standard-study-finds-deleting-facebook-is-great-for-your-mental-health/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Cal Newport on Why We&amp;#039;ll Look Back at Our Smartphones Like Cigarettes</title>
<link>https://www.gq.com/story/cal-newport-digital-minimalism</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.gq.com/story/cal-newport-digital-minimalism</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;article-heading&quot; data-reactid=&quot;93&quot; readability=&quot;33.972727272727&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;component-responsive-image photo-essay-hero&quot; data-component=&quot;ResponsiveImage&quot; data-reactid=&quot;95&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;marlboro man looking at a smart phone&quot; class=&quot;component-responsive-image-img&quot; src=&quot;https://media.gq.com/photos/5c48a176c6e40853b4876341/16:9/w_1600/Cal-Newport-on-Why-We'll-Look-Back-at-Our-Smartphones-Like-Cigarettes-GQ.jpg&quot; data-reactid=&quot;102&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; data-reactid=&quot;104&quot;&gt;Photo Illustration by Simon Abranowicz&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;div class=&quot;byline-container&quot; data-reactid=&quot;119&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;component-byline byline display-name&quot; data-reactid=&quot;125&quot;&gt;

&lt;time class=&quot;publish-date&quot; data-reactid=&quot;131&quot;&gt;January 23, 2019&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;dek&quot; data-reactid=&quot;132&quot;&gt;A Q+A with the computer scientist about his new book &lt;em&gt;Digital Minimalism&lt;/em&gt;, why future workplaces may go email-free, and why tech backlash is about to go mainstream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;133&quot; readability=&quot;22&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2004, when Cal Newport was still an undergrad at Dartmouth, all his friends were making accounts on a new website called Facebook. Newport opted out. This was not the moral or political objection it might be today. “There was very little scary about 2004 Facebook,” he says. His reasons were twofold. One, he has always disliked listing his favorite things, and back then Facebook “was this presentation of self-fame: ‘Here’s my favorite movies, my favorite books.’” Two, he had, not long before, shut down a tech company he’d started during the dot com boom. He wasn’t exactly jazzed, then, that all of his buddies were so excited about this Zuckerberg guy’s project. “There was probably a little bit of petty jealousy,” Newport says. “Like: ‘Oh why is his company so popular? I'm not gonna give him the satisfaction of using his product.’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;134&quot; readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, anyone who says jealousy doesn’t serve you should speak to Newport. Because that vendetta ended up giving him a unique perspective: While everyone else was sucked up in the ultra-connected, social media vortex, Newport maintained his distance. As Facebook’s presence mushroomed exponentially, Newport found himself watching and wondering, why are people &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; into this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;135&quot; readability=&quot;8.6175115207373&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those seeds of doubt grew into a hearty techno-skepticism that inspired both his hit 2016 book &lt;em&gt;Deep Work&lt;/em&gt; (about the merits of mono-tasking and deep concentration in a world of constant distraction) and his newest release: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Digital-Minimalism-Choosing-Focused-Noisy/dp/0525536515&quot;&gt;Digital Minimalism: Choosing a Focused Life in a Noisy World&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. It presents a “philosophy of technology use” rooted in reclaiming control and intention back from the devices and platforms that have hijacked it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;136&quot; readability=&quot;20&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Newport suggests beginning with a thirty-day detox during which you stop using any “optional technologies” that you can forgo without causing harm in your professional or personal life (you probably need email; you probably don't need Facebook). That seems like a lot to ask, but trust: beyond this initial cleanse, digital minimalism is actually much more accessible than many of the prevailing anti-tech approaches that tell you to throw your phone in a river and save your brain while you still can. Newport doesn’t deny that the technology we use is both useful and imperative. (He is, after all, a professor of computer science at Georgetown.) The problem in our current digital world, he argues, isn’t about utility, it’s about autonomy: tech greatly improves our life, right up until the point where you stop using it intentionally and unknowingly fall into manipulative black holes—on your phone, on Slack, in your inbox—that are specifically designed to be addicting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;137&quot; readability=&quot;18&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The theory is that with thirty days of abstinence, you’ll be able to figure out when tech stops being useful and starts being problematic. With that extra time, you’ll not only re-discover the meaningful leisure activities you left behind when scrolling through Instagram became a national pastime; you'll also get a better sense of the values and goals that matter to you. Then, you can intentionally add back the digital tools that’ll enhance, rather than distract from, the things you want. (For instance, maybe Facebook &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; the most effective way to keep in touch with far-off family, or Twitter &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; the best, most up-to-the-moment source of news—but you should at least press pause long enough to reevaluate if that’s true.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;138&quot; readability=&quot;24&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s more, Newport compares the burgeoning “attention resistance,” in which people enact these purposeful guidelines for how they engage with tech, to America’s current fitness obsession. If the explosion of CrossFit, boutique fitness, and hard-bodied Instagram influencers was a reaction to the increase in processed foods—and, subsequently, obesity, diabetes, and heart disease—in the 20th Century, then, Newport believes, we’re going to see a similar explosion of lifestyle trends that counter tech’s takeover of the early 21st Century. If that proves true, then movements like digital minimalism aren’t just some marginal fad. In the world of health and wellness, they might be the next frontier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;139&quot; readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;GQ&lt;/em&gt;: I want to jump right to one of the ideas at the core of your book: techno-maximalism. Digital minimalism is a response to it. How would you define techno-maximalism?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cal Newport&lt;/em&gt;: It arose in the 1990s. The basic idea is that technological innovations can bring value and convenience into your life. So, you assess new technological tools with respect to what value or convenience it can bring into your life. And if you can find one, then the conclusion is, &quot;If I can afford it, I should probably have this.&quot; It just looks at the positives. And it's view is &quot;more is better than less,&quot; because more things that bring you benefits means more total benefits. This is what maximalism is: &quot;If there's something that brings value, you should get it.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;140&quot; readability=&quot;17&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is so pernicious about that type of thinking?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;People have been writing about why this is a bad idea in different contexts for a really long time, actually. Thoreau was really on this, looking at economic maximalism, at fellow farmers in Concord in Massachusetts. He was saying, &quot;They have this mindset of, ‘If having this much land makes me this much profit, then having twice as much will make me twice as much profit, so that's twice as good. You want to get as much land as possible.’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;141&quot; readability=&quot;21&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He had this rhetoric that I think is still relevant today, even in the digital world, which is: there's a cost [to these additions]. You can't just say, &quot;Another hundred acres of land is gonna give me another hundred dollars a month of profit.&quot; You also have to say, &quot;Another hundred acres of land is gonna cost me another 30 hours a week of labor, and that's life that I'm losing.&quot; He had this great example: Consider the farmer who buys the new wagon and says, “It now takes me only 20 minutes to get to town, instead of an hour, so I've saved myself time. What a great investment!'&quot; Yeah, but if you do the numbers, you're having to work two extra hours a week to afford the wagon. So actually, you're worse off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;142&quot; readability=&quot;17&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digital minimalism is the same thing. We see these tools, and we have this narrative that, &quot;You can do this on Facebook,&quot; or &quot;This new feature on this device means you can do this, which would be convenient.&quot; What you don't factor in is, &quot;Okay, well what's the cost in terms of my time attention required to have this device in my life?&quot; Facebook might have some particular thing that's valuable, but then you have the average U.S. user spending something like 50 minutes a day on Facebook products. That's actually a pretty big [amount of life] that you're now trading in order to get whatever the potential small benefit is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;143&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Maximalism] ignores the opportunity cost. And as Thoreau pointed out hundreds of years ago, it's actually in the opportunity cost that all the interesting math happens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;144&quot; readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One of the problems here is a sort of digital FOMO. “If I don’t have that thing”—Facebook, Instagram, whatever—”what benefit might I be missing out on?” You’re pretty unplugged. How do you deal with that digital FOMO?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;There's a rarefied number of activities to invest time in that are really important and return a lot of value—the amount of value [in these activities] is way higher than, say, the little bit of value you get by seeing a funny Tweet or writing a comment on a friend’s Facebook post. Spreading your time and attention over these low value things takes your time and attention away from the things that are disproportionately higher value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;145&quot; readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to maximize the amount of value you feel in your life, the mathematics are clear: You want to put as much of your time and effort as possible into the small number of things to give you these huge rewards. When you think about it that way, fear of missing out looks like, just mathematically speaking, a really bad strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed callout&quot; data-reactid=&quot;146&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed callout-embed-component inline-pullquote&quot; data-type=&quot;callout&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed pullquote&quot; data-type=&quot;pullquote&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pullquote-content&quot;&gt;&quot;You're gonna look at allowing a 13-year-old to have a smartphone the same way that you would look at allowing your 13-year-old to smoke a cigarette.&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;147&quot; readability=&quot;24&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most people value their social life, and connection, and community. When people take their energy, and, in a really focused manner, say, &quot;Here's how I'm going to connect with my family, my close friends, and have good standing in my community through these high-energy, real world, analog type interactions and commitments&quot;—people who do that frequently feel a much stronger value and sense of social connection than someone who is dissipating that energy to try to maintain one of these very large, weakly-connected, arbitrary social media friend contact groups [with] lots of comments, and Happy Birthday!’s, and likes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;148&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't fear missing out. I fear not giving enough attention to the things that I already know for sure are important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;149&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You talk about how we're always ceding our autonomy to these devices. I understand the immediate implications of that—you’re not being intentional with your time, you're not in control of how you use it—but what are some of the long-term ramifications of always craving that constant hit of stimuli and distraction?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;You get actual lasting changes to your brain chemistry. Now you have a brain that needs stimuli just to get back up to normal. Just like the drug addict: after a while it takes more and more drugs just get back to normal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;150&quot; readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you train your brain, &quot;I always have to have stimuli. I can't be bored for a moment,&quot; you're gonna have both professional and social ramifications. Professionally, it makes it very difficult to concentrate without distraction. I wrote a whole book about this called &lt;em&gt;Deep Work&lt;/em&gt; that makes us log arguments for why it’s really valuable in our current economy to be able to focus very intensely. So to train yourself out of your ability to do that is sort of like economic self-sabotage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;151&quot; readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, it can be impoverishing. Not just in a way that it takes time away from things that are more important, but when you're doing things in your personal life, you extract much less value out of them, because you can't sustain presence or attention. Going out for a drink with a friend is not as satisfying as it might have been 10 years ago, because you just have this itch the whole time, &quot;I gotta check [my phone].&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;152&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You float the idea that the freshness of devices will wear off and we'll be left to re-evaluate how we engage with this technology. What do you think might happen in the next five to ten years?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;My prediction is things like digital minimalism are going to become much more popular. When I say “things like digital minimalism,” I mean named philosophies of technology use. I think the right analogy is food and fitness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;153&quot; readability=&quot;24&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you look at the 20th century, we had this influx of highly processed food and fast food, and, as a result, we had a large increase in obesity, diabetes, heart disease, metabolic syndrome. At first, the way we tried to deal with these was with tips and good intentions: &quot;Try to eat better, try to move more. Here's a food pyramid, look at this. This will tell you what to do.&quot; But it was really ineffective. As people got more and more fed up with being less healthy, now we're starting to see changes. But if you ask yourself who's the healthiest person you know, almost certainly they subscribe to some sort of named philosophy that helps them make consistent and value-driven decisions about what they eat and how they move. Maybe they're vegan or paleo. These named philosophies emerged as a response to, &quot;There's a real health issue, and the forces behind it are too strong for just good intentions and advice to solve it.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;154&quot; readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The transition we're going through now with digital technology is like that transition. People are shifting from self-deprecating jokes, like, &quot;Ah, I spend too much time on my phone,&quot; to actually being concerned. They've already read the article about turning off your notifications. They've already heard about digital Shabbat, that you should put your phone away for a night, or that you shouldn't have your phone in the room before you go to bed. They've heard these tips; it's not making a difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed callout&quot; data-reactid=&quot;155&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed callout-embed-component inline-pullquote&quot; data-type=&quot;callout&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed pullquote&quot; data-type=&quot;pullquote&quot; readability=&quot;7.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pullquote-content&quot;&gt;&quot;Like 99% of the value that people actually get out of Facebook, if you put distraction aside, probably requires 20 minutes on Sunday.&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;156&quot; readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digital minimalism is a clear philosophy: you figure out what's valuable to you. For each of these things you say, &quot;What's the best way I need to use technology to support that value?&quot; And then you happily miss out on everything else. It's about additively building up a digital life from scratch to be very specifically, intentionally designed to make your life much better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;157&quot; readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There might be other philosophies, just like in health in fitness. More important to me than everyone becoming a digital minimalist, is people in general getting used to this idea that, &quot;I have a philosophy that's really clear and grounded in my values that tells me how I approach technology.&quot; Moving past this ad-hoc stage of like, &quot;Whatever, I just kind of signed up for maximalist stage,” and into something a little bit more intentional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;158&quot; readability=&quot;16.301369863014&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I feel like we're at an inflection point, where we &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; go that way. But I can also see the other way, where we just keep using these devices without thinking about it and we all become digital zombies.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;As someone that's been pounding the drum for a while, I noticed a real big shift about two years ago. Something is different now than it was then. Clearly there's a fulcrum right around the presidential election. The week after, I had an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2016/11/20/jobs/quit-social-media-your-career-may-depend-on-it.html&quot;&gt;Op-Ed in the New York Times&lt;/a&gt;, in which I was saying critical things about social media. And I got the standard response to that: a lot of pushback, a lot of, &quot;This is crazy. Here's all these benefits. You're a loon.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;159&quot; readability=&quot;18.68&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But by, let's say, December of that year, or January of the next year, this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ted.com/talks/cal_newport_why_you_should_quit_social_media?language=en&quot;&gt;TED Talk&lt;/a&gt; I had done on quitting social media had jumped from a small number of views to millions of views. Somewhere right around there, there was this inflection point. Pre-Trump election, many people still had the model of technology that Silicon Valley had been pitching, which is this idea that, to quote Bill Maher, these are just gifts being handed down by the nerd gods. Just purely positive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;160&quot; readability=&quot;25&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The election really shook things up, because for just about everyone, on all sides of the political spectrum, it introduced at least one negative narrative about social media. If you're on the left, there were these sort of narratives about, &quot;Wait a second, Facebook has some involvement in Donald Trump, and the Russians were using it.&quot; If you're on the right, there were these narratives about censorship, like, &quot;Well, maybe they're censoring what we're allowed to post or not post&quot;… [And that] changed the way that people categorize social media in their minds. This went from something like, &quot;The notion of it having flaws is something that doesn't makes sense to me,&quot; to &quot;Now that I see that it could have flaws, all of the sudden, I'm seeing all these cracks.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;161&quot; readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the other thing that's happening is that the psychological data on young people is just incredibly distressing. Hospitalizations for self-harm, for example, among young women of Gen Z, so the first generation to grow up with smartphones and social media from their very earliest pre-teen years, it's like a hockey stick. This isn't curmudgeonly stuff. This is 13-year-olds who are going to the hospital at unprecedented levels. It's social media. Nothing else fits the timing. This starts right around the time that about 50% of people that age had access to a smartphone. And I think that's going to significantly change the way we think about use in these technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;162&quot; readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's just like with smoking, where we started by making it illegal for people under 18. That was the beginning of, &quot;Well, wait a second, if it's so dangerous for them, why am I doing it so much?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;163&quot; readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you see this playing out in the political realm? Do you think there will be regulations?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I don't know if there's gonna be regulations or not. I'm convinced that within a five-year window, the culture's gonna shift on young people and smartphones. You're gonna look at allowing a 13-year-old to have a smartphone the same way that you would look at allowing your 13-year-old to smoke a cigarette. The data is so stark—and a lot of this is really recent—that it's gonna shift. No responsible parent's going to want to do it… I think that's gonna be a cultural shift that's probably gonna happen, maybe even before regulation is needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;164&quot; readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm a skeptic on a lot of privacy legislation, just because I'm a computer scientist who knows it's very, very hard to even get a sensible definition of what privacy means. So, I personally don't see the regulatory arena as being what's gonna save us here. I think what's gonna save us is this idea that we don't need the giant walled garden platforms to attract the value of the internet. We would be fine if Facebook went away. A lot of the problems that we're facing—almost all the problems I write about—are an artifact of trying to consolidate the internet behind the walled gardens of one private company. You go back to the wild, decentralized social internet, and most of the issues that people worry about go away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed callout&quot; data-reactid=&quot;165&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed callout-embed-component inline-pullquote&quot; data-type=&quot;callout&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed pullquote&quot; data-type=&quot;pullquote&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pullquote-content&quot;&gt;&quot;We're not properly valuing attention capital. We're not properly valuing how to get the right return out of human brains.&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;166&quot; readability=&quot;17&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like we went through the AOL phase before people were comfortable with web browsers. The whole pitch of AOL was, &quot;We're easier. It's a walled garden we control. The internet's scary. You have to download a web browser. The web is weird, you want to be on AOL.&quot; And then people left, like, &quot;Actually, I'm okay with the internet&quot;—only old people were left on AOL. I think we'll see the same thing with these walled gardens. I don't need a Facebook account in order to meet interesting people, encounter interesting ideas, and express myself using the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;167&quot; readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sometimes a sense of morality can get inserted into this. It’s like when people first went gluten-free—when someone said they were gluten-free, you felt like it was kind of an implicit attack on everyone who wasn't gluten-free. I'm curious if you've encountered any resistance of that sort when you're telling people about this digital minimalism plan.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;That's like the last five years of my life. I'm like the first gluten-free person, or the first person to do yoga. Like, &quot;You gotta do yoga!&quot; There is a lot defensiveness. I'm seeing a lot of that changing as more and more people accept this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;168&quot; readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the other thing I'm seeing that's effective is this minimalist’s additive message: &quot;How can you make your life better? Here's how to put technology to work in a more intentional way, and you'll get much bigger return.&quot; What you're selling is this sort of better life. That's different than focusing on the reductive approach, and saying, &quot;Here's why this thing is bad, and you're stupid to be using it.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;169&quot; readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minimalism is much more positive. This is why a big focus of the book is this 30-day declutter process, which is actually a bit unusual for my writing. I don't usually have processes like that. But I thought this was really important, because it was a way for people to actually go through a ritual and come out the other side with a different type of life… This additive of, &quot;I'm rebuilding my life better,&quot; as opposed to, &quot;I'm just trying to identify what's bad,&quot; does reduce defensiveness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;170&quot; readability=&quot;26&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can make a career now just by being a micro influencer on Instagram. Those things make me think maybe we’re trending towards more, not less, social media use.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This whole edifice depends on this really arbitrary cultural decision that we're all gonna look at these screens, and feed them demographic data, and look at ads all day. That's what makes it so valuable. And this was a shift. You can go back and trace this. Essentially, Facebook made its shift to mobile [when] its investors were like, &quot;Okay, we want our 100x return. Figure out how we can get that.&quot; [Facebook] had to significantly boost their numbers. And that's when they they shifted to mobile: &quot;Let's change this experience from this much more slow-moving, browser-based experience where you come in, you check to see what your friends are up to, but there's no reason you'd check back the same day, because your friends aren't gonna change something on their Facebook profile that day.&quot; So they had all these innovations—adding likes, comments, re-Tweets, auto-tagging in photos—so they could create these rich streams of social approval indicators that get delivered in an addictive, intermittent fashion. They created this arbitrary behavior of, &quot;I have to keep tapping this thing throughout the day.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;171&quot; readability=&quot;26&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, that allowed them to build this whole edifice: &quot;Now we know everything about you, and can sell things to you all day long.&quot; I think that's way more shaky than they'd probably like to admit. It took this careful attention engineering, and cultural engineering, to try to make this seem innovative, and high-tech, and like you had to be doing this. If that falls apart, the whole thing goes. They need you using this a lot, all day long. If you go back, and say, &quot;Yeah, I use Facebook groups, and I check in on my daily pictures, and I do it on my browser—that takes me 20 minutes on Sunday,&quot; they're out of business. Like 99% of the value that people actually get out of Facebook, if you put distraction aside, probably requires 20 minutes on Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;172&quot; readability=&quot;18&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I know you're working on a book called &lt;em&gt;A World Without Email&lt;/em&gt;. I'm curious how realistic you think that is, and how you think the role of email will change.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Basically what we've done is we've taken this sort of paleolithic tribal model of communication: &quot;Hey, there's three or four of us hunting the mastodon, we just have this unstructured back and forth conversation, and we just attack. You go over there, I'll go over here. Did you see this? You, circle around.&quot; We've taken this and tried to scale it up the large companies. We talk over email messages, or Slack. It’s this ongoing, unstructured conversation. We've decided this is the right way to run an organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;173&quot; readability=&quot;18&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turns out, this is a huge failed experiment. Partially because we know from the research, that this type of ad-hoc, unstructured conversation, once you get above about five people, it doesn't work. As we shift towards knowledge work, where we're trying to create value with our brains, maintaining that conversation requires topic context switching, which is like poison to cognitive performance. We've invented an approach to organizing our work that makes us really terrible at what we do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed callout&quot; data-reactid=&quot;174&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed callout-embed-component inline-pullquote&quot; data-type=&quot;callout&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed pullquote&quot; data-type=&quot;pullquote&quot; readability=&quot;8.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pullquote-content&quot;&gt;&quot;Yes, it's scary not to be distracted, but I think it's even more scary to avoid all of the deep good that comes from having to just be there with yourself, and confront all of those difficulties and opportunities that entails.&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;175&quot; readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're gonna see the role of knowledge work evolve past a workflow in which we just say, &quot;Everybody has an email address, let's rock and roll.&quot; We're gonna move past that into much more structured approaches to work that are heavily dependent on what you do for the company, and how we can actually help you produce the most value from your brain in the most sustainable manner…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;176&quot; readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're leaving a lot of money on the table. It's like the way they used to build cars before the assembly line. It's just a terrible way to work. No one really designed it, it emerged haphazardly once these communication technologies were introduced. And we're getting to a point where people are gonna step back and say, &quot;I could make a lot more profit if I was willing to step away from this really easy but terribly ineffective way of organizing work.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;177&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're not properly valuing attention capital. We're not properly valuing how to get the right return out of human brains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;178&quot; readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You write about digital distraction as a way we can avoid ever having to be with ourselves. What's the value in having to turn inward?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;You have to actually confront yourself and engage in self-reflection: thinking about your life, what's important, what's working, and what's not working. And this process of self-shaping is absolutely crucial to building an impactful and flourishing life. That's when you shape yourself. That's when a life of focus and value is built.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;179&quot; readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second thing, and maybe this sounds a bit more trivial, is that through time immemorial, the way that people dealt with this void—whenever they were lucky enough to be in a time and place where they had some leisure time—was to seek out high quality leisure activities.... usually highly social, highly skilled activities. As Aristotle used to write, these activities you do just for the sake of the activities—just for the quality and joy of it—gives you this resilience that makes it much easier to deal with all the other hardships of life. Your life is not just all hardships, there's these things that we do that are intrinsically full and joyful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;180&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can taper over the void with a constant stream of distractions—make it just comfortable enough that you don't have to confront it—you're in a really bad situation. Now you're avoiding that self-reflection that you need to actually grow up and to build a life worth living. Also, you can distract yourself enough that you never have to answer that drive to actually fill your life with the quality activities: getting engaged with your community; picking up a skilled hobby; art and poetry; these type of things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;181&quot; readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it's actually pretty dire. Yes, it's scary not to be distracted, but I think it's even more scary to avoid all of the deep good that comes from having to just be there with yourself, and confront all of those difficulties and opportunities that entails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed p&quot; data-reactid=&quot;182&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This interview has been edited and condensed.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 12:56:19 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dhh2106</dc:creator>
<og:title>Cal Newport on Why We'll Look Back at Our Smartphones Like Cigarettes</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.gq.com/story/cal-newport-digital-minimalism</og:url>
<og:description>The computer scientist on his new book &quot;Digital Minimalism,&quot; why workplaces may go email-free, and why the tech backlash is about to go mainstream.</og:description>
<og:image>https://media.gq.com/photos/5c48a189c6e40853b4876343/16:9/pass/cal-newport-on-why-we'll-look-back-at-our-smartphones-like-cigarettes-gq-1.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.gq.com/story/cal-newport-digital-minimalism</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Skirting U.S. sanctions, Europeans launch trade mechanism for Iran</title>
<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-iran-usa-sanctions-eu/germany-france-britain-to-launch-mechanism-for-trade-with-iran-idUSKCN1PP0K3</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.reuters.com/article/us-iran-usa-sanctions-eu/germany-france-britain-to-launch-mechanism-for-trade-with-iran-idUSKCN1PP0K3</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;PARIS/BERLIN (Reuters) - France, Germany and Britain have opened a new channel for non-dollar trade with Iran to avert U.S. sanctions, although diplomats say it is unlikely to allow for the big transactions that Tehran says it needs to keep a nuclear deal afloat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Washington’s major European allies opposed last year’s decision by U.S. President Donald Trump to abandon the 2015 deal, under which international sanctions on Iran were lifted in return for Tehran accepting curbs on its nuclear program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iran has threatened to pull out of the deal unless the European powers enable it to receive economic benefits. The Europeans have promised to help companies do business with Iran as long as it abides by the deal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It is a political act,” French Foreign Minister Jean-Yves Le Drian told reporters after a meeting of EU counterparts in Bucharest. “It is a gesture to protect European companies.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Washington says that, although Iran has met the terms, the accord was too generous, failing to rein in Iran’s ballistic missile program or curb its regional meddling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New U.S. sanctions have largely succeeded in persuading European companies to abandon business with Iran, and Washington said on Thursday that it did not expect the EU effort, known as the Special Purpose Vehicle (SPV), to change that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We do not expect the SPV will in any way impact our maximum economic pressure campaign,” a U.S. State Department spokeswoman said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The United States questions the efficacy of the SPV and remains committed to fully enforcing its sanctions,” said a senior Trump administration who spoke on condition of anonymity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The European trade vehicle was conceived as a way to help match Iranian oil and gas exports against purchases of EU goods. However, those ambitions have been toned down, with diplomats saying that, realistically, it will be used only for smaller trade, for example of humanitarian products or food.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It won’t change things dramatically, but it’s an important political message to Iran to show that we are determined to save the JCPOA (Iran deal) and also to the United States to show we defend our interests despite their extraterritorial sanctions,” one European diplomat said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The EU has spent months preparing the system and it will take several months more to become operational.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Britain’s Jeremy Hunt said the three countries were working closely with Tehran to finalize arrangements: “Registration is a big step, but there is still more work to be done,” Hunt said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;RELATIONS WORSENING&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Instrument In Support Of Trade Exchanges, or INSTEX, is registered in France and will be headed by German banker Per Fischer, a former Commerzbank director. The three European powers are shareholders and hope other states will join later, although a senior German official said this was not imminent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iranian Deputy Foreign Minister Abbas Araqchi said the mechanism was a good first step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The European powers must now establish a budget for INSTEX and define its rules. Iran must also set up a mirror company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It seems that Iran should set up the same system inside Iran to organize rial transactions for Iranian companies,” Araqchi was quoted as saying by the semi-official Tasnim news agency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Embassy in Germany said it did not expect INSTEX to blunt its effort to pile economic pressure on Tehran.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even as European powers and the European Union have worked to preserve the nuclear deal, relations with Tehran have been worsening. The EU this month imposed its first sanctions on Iran since the nuclear pact, in response to the ballistic missile tests and assassination plots on European soil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Image_container&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;LazyImage_container LazyImage_dark&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s2.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;amp;d=20190131&amp;amp;t=2&amp;amp;i=1351754833&amp;amp;r=LYNXNPEF0U0LE&amp;amp;w=20&quot; aria-label=&quot;Iran's President Hassan Rouhani speaks during his visit to the shrine of the founder of the Islamic Republic, Ayatollah Ruhollah Khomeini, south of Tehran, Iran, January 30, 2019. Official President website/Handout via REUTERS&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;Image_caption&quot;&gt;

&lt;span&gt;Iran's President Hassan Rouhani speaks during his visit to the shrine of the founder of the Islamic Republic, Ayatollah Ruhollah Khomeini, south of Tehran, Iran, January 30, 2019. Official President website/Handout via REUTERS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a symbolic move, the EU added two Iranian individuals and an Iranian intelligence unit to its terrorist list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The three big European powers are also assessing whether to push for new sanctions on Iran over its missile program, diplomats have told Reuters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We are clear; this commitment does not in any way preclude us from addressing Iran’s hostile and destabilizing activities,” Hunt said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Attribution_container&quot; readability=&quot;7.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Attribution_attribution&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Attribution_content&quot;&gt;Additional reporting by Andrea Shalal and Paul Carrel in Berlin, Robin Emmott and Alissa de Carbonel in Brussels and Parisa Hafezi in Dubai and Arshad Mohammed in Washington; writing by Madeline Chambers and John Irish; editing by Kevin Liffey and James Dalgleish&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;StandardArticleBody_trustBadgeContainer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;StandardArticleBody_trustBadgeTitle&quot;&gt;Our Standards:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;trustBadgeUrl&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thomsonreuters.com/en/about-us/trust-principles.html&quot;&gt;The Thomson Reuters Trust Principles.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 11:26:51 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>betahiker</dc:creator>
<og:title>Skirting U.S. sanctions, Europeans open new trade channel to Iran</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-iran-usa-sanctions-eu-idUSKCN1PP0K3</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>France, Germany and Britain have opened a new channel for non-dollar trade with ...</og:description>
<og:image>https://s2.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;d=20190131&amp;t=2&amp;i=1351754833&amp;w=1200&amp;r=LYNXNPEF0U0LE</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-iran-usa-sanctions-eu/germany-france-britain-to-launch-mechanism-for-trade-with-iran-idUSKCN1PP0K3</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Racket v7.2</title>
<link>https://blog.racket-lang.org/2019/01/racket-v7-2.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.racket-lang.org/2019/01/racket-v7-2.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;date-and-tags&quot;&gt;30 Jan 2019&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;/header&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;posted by Vincent St-Amour&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Racket version 7.2 is now available from &lt;a href=&quot;http://racket-lang.org/&quot;&gt;http://racket-lang.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Racket-on-Chez is done in a useful sense, but we’ll wait until it gets better before making it the default Racket implementation. For more information, see &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.racket-lang.org/2019/01/racket-on-chez-status.html&quot;&gt;http://blog.racket-lang.org/2019/01/racket-on-chez-status.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, the Racket 7.2 release includes the following improvements, which apply to both implementations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;10.5&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The contract system supports collapsible contracts, which avoid repeated wrappers in certain pathological situations. Thanks to Daniel Feltey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quickscript, a scripting tool for DrRacket, has become part of the standard distribution. Thanks to Laurent Orseau.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The web server’s built-in configuration for serving static files recognizes the &quot;.mjs&quot; extension for JavaScript modules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;data/enumerate&lt;/code&gt; library supports an additional form of subtraction via &lt;code&gt;but-not/e&lt;/code&gt;, following Yorgey and Foner’s ICFP’18 paper. Thanks to Max New.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;letrec.rkt&lt;/code&gt; example model in Redex has been changed to more closely match Racket, which led to some bug fixes in Racket’s implementation of &lt;code&gt;letrec&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;set!&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The racklog library has seen a number of improvements, including fixes to logic variable binding, logic variables containing predicates being applicable, and the introduction of an &lt;code&gt;%andmap&lt;/code&gt; higher-order predicate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following people contributed to this release: Akihide Nano, Alex Feldman-Crough, Alexander McLin, Alexander Shopov, Alexis King, Alex Knauth, Andrew Kent, Asumu Takikawa, Ben Greenman, Bogdan Popa, Caner Derici, Chongkai Zhu, Dan Feltey, Darren Newton, Gan Shen, Greg Hendershott, Gustavo Massaccesi, Jay McCarthy, Jens Axel Søgaard, John Clements, Jordan Johnson, Kevin Robert Stravers, Leif Andersen, Leo Uino, Matt Kraai, Matthew Butterick, Matthew Flatt, Matthias Felleisen, Max New, Michael Burge, Mike Sperber, Paul C. Anagnostopoulos, Paulo Matos, Philip McGrath, Robby Findler, Ronald Garcia, Ryan Culpepper, Ryan Kramer, Sam Tobin-Hochstadt, Shu-Hung You, Sorawee Porncharoenwase, Spencer Florence, Stephen Chang, and Vincent St-Amour&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feedback Welcome&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;footer&gt;
&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Made with &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/greghendershott/frog&quot;&gt;Frog&lt;/a&gt;, a static-blog generator written in Racket.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/racket/racket-lang-org&quot;&gt;Source code&lt;/a&gt; for this blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 10:32:10 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ethelward</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.racket-lang.org/2019/01/racket-v7-2.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A KGB agent shipped a Sidewinder missile by mail to Moscow (2017)</title>
<link>https://nationalinterest.org/blog/the-buzz/fact-the-kgb-shipped-sidewinder-missile-by-mail-moscow-21673</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://nationalinterest.org/blog/the-buzz/fact-the-kgb-shipped-sidewinder-missile-by-mail-moscow-21673</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;That the Soviet-made R-3S air-to-air missile — better known in the West by its NATO-designation AA-2 Atoll — is a copy of the AIM-9B Sidewinder, originally developed and manufactured in the USA, is relatively well-known.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How it came to be … isn’t so well-known. It involved the mail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story began back in summer of 1958. The communist People’s Republic of China was preparing to invade the U.S.-backed Republic of China, a.k.a. Taiwan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the course of related operations, the People’s Liberation Army Air Force received the order to establish air superiority over several islands close to mainland China still held by Taiwan’s Nationalists, specifically Quemoy and Matsu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the People’s Liberation Army began shelling Quemoy and Matsu, in August 1958, the United States helped re-equip several squadrons of the Republic of China Air Force with North American F-86F Saber fighter jets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the PLAAF took the skies, the Nationalist scrambled their own interceptors. Fierce clashes resulted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although outnumbered, the Taiwanese pilots achieved a positive kill-to-loss ratio. However, they found no solution for reaching the PLAAF’s MiG-15s when these operated at their maximum ceiling, several thousand feet higher than that of the Sabers.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 06:27:09 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rishabhd</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>FACT: The KGB Shipped a Sidewinder Missile by Mail to Moscow</og:title>
<og:url>https://nationalinterest.org/blog/the-buzz/fact-the-kgb-shipped-sidewinder-missile-by-mail-moscow-21673</og:url>
<og:description>It cost $79.25.</og:description>
<og:image>https://nationalinterest.org/sites/default/files/main_images/mig-23-red12.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://nationalinterest.org/blog/the-buzz/fact-the-kgb-shipped-sidewinder-missile-by-mail-moscow-21673</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>