<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Google Ends Forced Arbitration for Employees</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/21/google-ends-forced-arbitration-for-employees/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/21/google-ends-forced-arbitration-for-employees/</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/google&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;google&quot;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt; is finally ending forced arbitration for its employees. These changes will go into effect for both current and future Google employees on March 21.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Google won’t reopen settled claims, current employees can litigate past claims starting March 21.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the contractors Google works with directly, it will remove mandatory arbitration from their contracts. The caveat, however, is that it won’t require outside firms that employ contractors to do the same. Still, Google says it will notify suppliers so that they can see if that approach would work for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a direct response to a group of outspoken Google employees protesting the company’s arbitration practices. Last month, a group of &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/google&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;google&quot;&gt;Google &lt;/a&gt;employees took to Twitter and Instagram in an attempt to educate the public about forced arbitration. That came about &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/12/10/google-employees-demand-the-end-of-forced-arbitration-across-the-tech-industry/&quot;&gt;one month after this same group of 35 employees&lt;/a&gt; banded together to demand Google end forced arbitration as it relates to any case of discrimination. The group also called on other tech workers to join them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forced arbitration ensures workplace disputes are settled behind closed doors and without any right to an appeal. These types of agreements effectively prevent employees from suing companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the massive, 20,000-person walkout at Google in November, &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/11/08/google-walkout-organizers-response-sundar-pichai/&quot;&gt;Google got &lt;/a&gt;rid of forced arbitration for sexual harassment and sexual assault claims, offering more transparency around those investigations and more. &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/11/12/airbnb-ends-forced-arbitration-days-after-google-facebook-did-the-same/&quot;&gt;Airbnb, eBay &lt;/a&gt;and&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/11/12/airbnb-ends-forced-arbitration-days-after-google-facebook-did-the-same/&quot;&gt; Facebook &lt;/a&gt;quickly followed suit. Despite some progress across the industry, the end of forced arbitration across all workplace disputes is not widespread.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since getting rid of forced arbitration for cases relating to sexual harassment and assault, Google said it has been exploring the issue and ultimately decided on implementing a blanket change.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 21:52:42 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mayneack</dc:creator>
<og:title>Google ends forced arbitration for employees</og:title>
<og:description>Google is finally ending forced arbitration for its employees. These changes will go into effect for both current and future Google employees on March 21. While Google won’t reopen settled claims, current employees can litigate past claims starting March 21. For the contractors Google works w…</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/AP_18305598285182.jpg?w=657</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2019/02/21/google-ends-forced-arbitration-for-employees/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/21/google-ends-forced-arbitration-for-employees/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>America’s Professional Elite: Wealthy, Successful and Miserable</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2019/02/21/magazine/elite-professionals-jobs-happiness.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2019/02/21/magazine/elite-professionals-jobs-happiness.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My first, charmed&lt;/strong&gt; week as a student at Harvard Business School, late in the summer of 2001, felt like a halcyon time for capitalism. AOL Time Warner, Yahoo and Napster were benevolently connecting the world. Enron and WorldCom were bringing innovation to hidebound industries. President George W. Bush — an H.B.S. graduate himself — had promised to deliver progress and prosperity with businesslike efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;The next few years would prove how little we (and Washington and much of corporate America) really understood about the economy and the world. But at the time, for the 895 first-years preparing ourselves for business moguldom, what really excited us was our good luck. A Harvard M.B.A. seemed like a winning lottery ticket, a gilded highway to world-changing influence, fantastic wealth and — if those self-satisfied portraits that lined the hallways were any indication — a lifetime of deeply meaningful work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;So it came as a bit of a shock, when I attended my 15th reunion last summer, to learn how many of my former classmates weren’t overjoyed by their professional lives — in fact, they were miserable. I heard about one fellow alum who had run a large hedge fund until being sued by investors (who also happened to be the fund manager’s relatives). Another person had risen to a senior role inside one of the nation’s most prestigious companies before being savagely pushed out by corporate politics. Another had learned in the maternity ward that her firm was being stolen by a conniving partner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;Those were extreme examples, of course. Most of us were living relatively normal, basically content lives. But even among my more sanguine classmates, there was a lingering sense of professional disappointment. They talked about missed promotions, disaffected children and billable hours in divorce court. They complained about jobs that were unfulfilling, tedious or just plain bad. One classmate described having to invest $5 million a day — which didn’t sound terrible, until he explained that if he put only $4 million to work on Monday, he had to scramble to place $6 million on Tuesday, and his co-workers were constantly undermining one another in search of the next promotion. It was insanely stressful work, done among people he didn’t particularly like. He earned about $1.2 million a year and hated going to the office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;“I feel like I’m wasting my life,” he told me. “When I die, is anyone going to care that I earned an extra percentage point of return? My work feels totally meaningless.” He recognized the incredible privilege of his pay and status, but his anguish seemed genuine. “If you spend 12 hours a day doing work you hate, at some point it doesn’t matter what your paycheck says,” he told me. There’s no magic salary at which a bad job becomes good. He had received an offer at a start-up, and he would have loved to take it, but it paid half as much, and he felt locked into a lifestyle that made this pay cut impossible. “My wife laughed when I told her about it,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;rad-interactive full_bleed&quot; id=&quot;interactive-24mag-happiness-pq1&quot; data-id=&quot;100000006370079&quot; data-slug=&quot;24mag-happiness-pq1&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;rad-interactive-wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;interactive-headline&quot;/&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;‘When I die, is anyone going to care that I earned an extra percentage point of return? My work feels totally meaningless.’&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;After our reunion, I wondered if my Harvard class — or even just my own friends there — were an anomaly. So I began looking for data about the nation’s professional psyche. What I found was that my classmates were hardly unique in their dissatisfaction; even in a boom economy, a surprising portion of Americans are professionally miserable right now. In the mid-1980s, roughly 61 percent of workers told pollsters they were satisfied with their jobs. Since then, that number has declined substantially, hovering around half; the low point was in 2010, when only 43 percent of workers were satisfied, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.conference-board.org/blog/postdetail.cfm?post=6391&quot;&gt;according to data collected by the Conference Board&lt;/a&gt;, a nonprofit research organization. The rest said they were unhappy, or at best neutral, about how they spent the bulk of their days. Even among professionals given to lofty self-images, like those in medicine and law, other studies have noted a rise in discontent. Why? Based on my own conversations with classmates and the research I began reviewing, the answer comes down to oppressive hours, political infighting, increased competition sparked by globalization, an “always-on culture” bred by the internet — but also something that’s hard for these professionals to put their finger on, an underlying sense that their work isn’t worth the grueling effort they’re putting into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;This wave of dissatisfaction is especially perverse because corporations now have access to decades of scientific research about how to make jobs better. “We have so much evidence about what people need,” says Adam Grant, a professor of management and psychology at the University of Pennsylvania (and a contributing opinion writer at The Times). Basic financial security, of course, is critical — as is a sense that your job won’t disappear unexpectedly. What’s interesting, however, is that once you can provide financially for yourself and your family, according to studies, additional salary and benefits don’t reliably contribute to worker satisfaction. Much more important are things like whether a job provides a sense of autonomy — the ability to control your time and the authority to act on your unique expertise. People want to work alongside others whom they respect (and, optimally, enjoy spending time with) and who seem to respect them in return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;And finally, workers want to feel that their labors are meaningful. “You don’t have to be curing cancer,” says Barry Schwartz, a visiting professor of management at the University of California, Berkeley. We want to feel that we’re making the world better, even if it’s as small a matter as helping a shopper find the right product at the grocery store. “You can be a salesperson, or a toll collector, but if you see your goal as solving people’s problems, then each day presents 100 opportunities to improve someone’s life, and your satisfaction increases dramatically,” Schwartz says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;One of the more significant examples of how meaningfulness influences job satisfaction comes from &lt;a href=&quot;http://faculty.som.yale.edu/amywrzesniewski/documents/Craftingajob_Revisioningemployees_000.pdf&quot;&gt;a study published in 2001.&lt;/a&gt; Two researchers — Amy Wrzesniewski of Yale and Jane Dutton, now a distinguished emeritus professor at the University of Michigan — wanted to figure out why particular janitors at a large hospital were so much more enthusiastic than others. So they began conducting interviews and found that, by design and habit, some members of the janitorial staff saw their jobs not as just tidying up but as a form of healing. One woman, for instance, mopped rooms inside a brain-injury unit where many residents were comatose. The woman’s duties were basic: change bedpans, pick up trash. But she also sometimes took the initiative to swap around the pictures on the walls, because she believed a subtle stimulation change in the unconscious patients’ environment might speed their recovery. She talked to other convalescents about their lives. “I enjoy entertaining the patients,” she told the researchers. “That is not really part of my job description, but I like putting on a show for them.” She would dance around, tell jokes to families sitting vigil at bedsides, try to cheer up or distract everyone from the pain and uncertainty that otherwise surrounded them. &lt;a href=&quot;http://webuser.bus.umich.edu/janedut/High%20Quality%20Connections/Interpersonal%20Sensemaking.pdf&quot;&gt;In a 2003 study&lt;/a&gt; led by the researchers, another custodian described cleaning the same room two times in order to ease the mind of a stressed-out father.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;To some, the moral might seem obvious: If you see your job as healing the sick, rather than just swabbing up messes, you’re likely to have a deeper sense of purpose whenever you grab the mop. But what’s remarkable is how few workplaces seem to have internalized this simple lesson. “There are so many jobs where people feel like what they do is relatively meaningless,” Wrzesniewski says. “Even for well-paid positions, or jobs where you assume workers feel a sense of meaning, people feel like what they’re doing doesn’t matter.” That’s certainly true for my miserable classmate earning $1.2 million a year. Even though, in theory, the investments he makes each day help fund pensions — and thus the lives of retirees — it’s pretty hard to see that altruism from his window office in a Manhattan skyscraper. “It’s just numbers on a screen to me,” he told me. “I’ve never met a retiree who enjoyed a vacation because of what I do. It’s so theoretical it hardly seems real.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There is a&lt;/strong&gt; raging debate — on newspaper pages, inside Silicon Valley, among presidential hopefuls — as to what constitutes a “good job.” I’m an investigative business reporter, and so I have a strange perspective on this question. When I speak to employees at a company, it’s usually because something has gone wrong. My stock-in-trade are sources who feel their employers are acting unethically or ignoring sound advice. The workers who speak to me are willing to describe both the good and the bad in the places where they work, in the hope that we will all benefit from their insights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;rad-interactive full_bleed&quot; id=&quot;interactive-24mag-happiness-pq2&quot; data-id=&quot;100000006370329&quot; data-slug=&quot;24mag-happiness-pq2&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;rad-interactive-wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;interactive-headline&quot;/&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;The smoothest life paths sometimes fail to teach us about what really brings us satisfaction day to day.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;What’s interesting to me, though, is that these workers usually don’t come across as unhappy. When they agree to talk to a journalist — to share confidential documents or help readers understand how things went awry — it’s not because they hate their employers or are overwhelmingly disgruntled. They often seem to love their jobs and admire the companies they work for. They admire them enough, in fact, to want to help them improve. They are engaged and content. They believe what they are doing matters — both in coming to work every day and in blowing the whistle on problems they see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;Do these people have “good jobs”? Are they luckier or less fortunate than my $1.2 million friend, who couldn’t care less about his firm? Are Google employees who work 60 hours a week but who can eat many of their meals (or freeze their eggs) on the company’s dime more satisfied than a start-up founder in Des Moines who cleans the office herself but sees her dream become reality?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;As the airwaves heat up in anticipation of the 2020 election, Americans are likely to hear a lot of competing views about what a “good job” entails. Some will celebrate billionaires as examples of this nation’s greatness, while others will pillory them as evidence of an economy gone astray. Through all of that, it’s worth keeping in mind that the concept of a “good job” is inherently complicated, because ultimately it’s a conversation about what we value, whether individually or collectively. Even for Americans who live frighteningly close to the bone, like the janitors studied by Wrzesniewski and Dutton, a job is usually more than just a means to a paycheck. It’s a source of purpose and meaning, a place in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;There’s a possibility, when it comes to understanding good jobs, that we have it all wrong. When I was speaking to my H.B.S. classmates, one of them reminded me about some people at our reunion who seemed wholly unmiserable — who seemed, somewhat to their own surprise, to have wound up with jobs that were both financially and emotionally rewarding. I knew of one person who had become a prominent venture capitalist; another friend had started a retail empire that expanded to five states; yet another was selling goods all over the world. There were some who had become investors running their own funds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;And many of them had something in common: They tended to be the also-rans of the class, the ones who failed to get the jobs they wanted when they graduated. They had been passed over by McKinsey &amp;amp; Company and Google, Goldman Sachs and Apple, the big venture-capital firms and prestigious investment houses. Instead, they were forced to scramble for work — and thus to grapple, earlier in their careers, with the trade-offs that life inevitably demands. These late bloomers seemed to have learned the lessons about workplace meaning preached by people like Barry Schwartz. It wasn’t that their workplaces were enlightened or (as far as I could tell) that H.B.S. had taught them anything special. Rather, they had learned from their own setbacks. And often they wound up richer, more powerful and more content than everyone else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;That’s not to wish genuine hardship on any American worker, given that a setback for a poor or working-class person can lead to bankruptcy, hunger or worse. But for those who do find themselves miserable at work, it’s an important reminder that the smoothest life paths sometimes fail to teach us about what really brings us satisfaction day to day. A core goal of capitalism is evaluating and putting a price on risk. In our professional lives, we hedge against misfortune by taking out insurance policies in the form of fancy degrees, saving against rainy days by pursuing careers that promise stability. Nowadays, however, stability is increasingly scarce, and risk is harder to measure. Many of our insurance policies have turned out to be worth as much as Enron.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;“I’m jealous of everyone who had the balls to do something that made them happy,” my $1.2 million friend told me. “It seemed like too big a risk for me to take when we were at school.” But as one of the also-rans myself — I applied to McKinsey, to private-equity firms and to a real estate conglomerate and was rejected by them all — I didn’t need any courage in making the decision to go into the modest-paying (by H.B.S. standards) field of journalism. Some of my classmates thought I was making a huge mistake by ignoring all the doors H.B.S. had opened for me in high finance and Silicon Valley. What they didn’t know was that those doors, in fact, had stayed shut — and that as a result, I was saved from the temptation of easy riches. I’ve been thankful ever since, grateful that my bad luck made it easier to choose a profession that I’ve loved. Finding meaning, whether as a banker or a janitor, is difficult work. Usually life, rather than a business-school classroom, is the place to learn how to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 17:07:03 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ojbyrne</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2019/02/21/magazine/elite-professionals-jobs-happiness.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>America’s Professional Elite: Wealthy, Successful and Miserable</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/02/24/magazine/24Mag-Happiness-Image1/24Mag-Happiness-Image1-facebookJumbo-v2.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>The upper echelon is hoarding money and privilege to a degree not seen in decades. But that doesn’t make them happy at work.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2019/02/21/magazine/elite-professionals-jobs-happiness.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Practical Go: Real-world advice for writing maintainable Go programs</title>
<link>https://dave.cheney.net/practical-go/presentations/qcon-china.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://dave.cheney.net/practical-go/presentations/qcon-china.html</guid>
<description>&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-go&quot; data-lang=&quot;go&quot;&gt;type Header struct {
        Key, Value string
}

type Status struct {
        Code   int
        Reason string
}

func WriteResponse(w io.Writer, st Status, headers []Header, body io.Reader) error {
        _, err := fmt.Fprintf(w, &quot;HTTP/1.1 %d %s\r\n&quot;, st.Code, st.Reason)
        if err != nil {
                return err
        }

        for _, h := range headers {
                _, err := fmt.Fprintf(w, &quot;%s: %s\r\n&quot;, h.Key, h.Value)
                if err != nil {
                        return err
                }
        }

        if _, err := fmt.Fprint(w, &quot;\r\n&quot;); err != nil {
                return err
        }

        _, err = io.Copy(w, body)
        return err
}&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 16:43:50 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ra7</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://dave.cheney.net/practical-go/presentations/qcon-china.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Travis CI Is Laying Off Senior Engineer Staff</title>
<link>https://twitter.com/alicegoldfuss/status/1098604563664420865</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://twitter.com/alicegoldfuss/status/1098604563664420865</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alicegoldfuss/status/1098604563664420865&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/alicegoldfuss/status/1098604563664420865&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19218036&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19218036&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 254&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 83&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 16:39:34 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kaycebasques</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mobile.twitter.com/alicegoldfuss/status/1098604563664420865</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>We&amp;#039;re Entering a Golden Age of Podcasts</title>
<link>https://chartable.com/blog/golden-age-of-podcasts</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://chartable.com/blog/golden-age-of-podcasts</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Podcasts have been around since &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/media/2004/feb/12/broadcasting.digitalmedia&quot;&gt;at least 2004&lt;/a&gt;. But unlike text-based news and blogs, which have gone through waves of centralization and disruption thanks to Facebook and Google, the podcast industry has remained stubbornly decentralized. There are dozens of popular podcast players, and no single gatekeeper in the industry. Despite many attempts, there has never been a “Netflix of podcasts.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That may change soon: Spotify bought &lt;a href=&quot;http://gimletmedia.com&quot;&gt;Gimlet Media&lt;/a&gt;, a premium podcast studio, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://anchor.fm&quot;&gt;Anchor&lt;/a&gt;, a podcast hosting platform, for &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/14/spotify-gimlet-anchor-340-million/&quot;&gt;$340 million earlier this month&lt;/a&gt;. That's a lot of money for an industry that was sized at just &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iab.com/news/us-podcast-ad-revenues-2017&quot;&gt;$314 million in 2017&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spotify CEO Daniel Ek &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2019/02/06/music-streaming-service-spotify-to-buy-podcast-producers-gimlet-media-and-anchor.html&quot;&gt;explicitly referenced Netflix's strategy&lt;/a&gt; as part of their motivation, saying that Spotify will spend hundreds of millions of dollars acquiring podcasts. When Netflix moved into streaming, they invested billions of dollars into original programming, helping usher in the “&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Golden_Age_of_Television_(2000s%E2%80%93present)&quot;&gt;New Golden Age of Television&lt;/a&gt;”—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statista.com/chart/12493/number-of-tv-series-aired-in-the-united-states/&quot;&gt;a sharp increase in the number and quality of new scripted shows&lt;/a&gt;—alongside HBO, Hulu, and Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spotify's acquisition spree won't change the podcast industry on its own. But it's another signal that we're on the cusp of a similar change for podcasting. Let's call it the beginning of the Golden Age of Podcasts—a marked increase in the amount and quality of original audio programming. To understand the Golden Age, let's look at what's happening, why it's happening now, and what's coming next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What's happening&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2018: An exceptional year&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Apple included the Apple Podcasts app on every iPhone back in 2014, Edison Research's &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.shareofear.com/&quot;&gt;Share of Ear report&lt;/a&gt; has shown slow but steady growth. But 2018 looks like it was an exceptional year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CBS News conducted &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbsnews.com/news/cbs-news-poll-the-jump-in-popularity-in-podcasts/&quot;&gt;a survey of US listeners in January 2019&lt;/a&gt; showing an increase of people listening to podcasts daily or a few times a week from 15% to 23%. That represents &lt;strong&gt;20 million more frequent podcast listeners in the US alone&lt;/strong&gt;—a 50% relative jump over the previous year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Such a huge jump seemed unusual, so Chartable commissioned a survey to double-check. The results we got confirmed that 2018 was a big year for podcasts: &lt;a href=&quot;https://chartable.com/blog/golden-age-of-podcasts#footnote1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.buttercms.com/ffN8PKpVQiK91kSLjeAb&quot; alt=&quot;How-often-do-you-listen-to-podcasts_-...&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The survey confirmed that 23-25% of US adults listen to podcasts daily or a few times a week. Using the latest US Census data, that represents an audience of around &lt;strong&gt;60 million people&lt;/strong&gt; listening a few times a week or more, and &lt;strong&gt;91 million people listening at least once a week&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Podcast listeners make time for a lot of podcasts during their week: The Share of Ear report shows that the average listener consumes &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.slideshare.net/webby2001/the-podcast-consumer-2018/15&quot;&gt;seven podcast episodes a week&lt;/a&gt;, which is also increasing over time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Multiply more listeners by more episodes per listener, and you get a massive increase in the number of downloads and the amount of attention paid to podcasts overall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Content explosion&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All those new listeners are listening to a record number of new podcasts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2018, an average of 575 podcasts were started every day—that's about one podcast every three minutes. Chartable now tracks over 670,000 podcasts in the Apple Podcasts directory, and over 210,000 of those published their first episode in 2018. &lt;a href=&quot;https://chartable.com/blog/golden-age-of-podcasts#footnote2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.buttercms.com/cVVyrCUMSBuokB0YfheH&quot; alt=&quot;undefined&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While that might seem like a lot of podcasts—surely everything has been done?—Justin Jackson &lt;a href=&quot;https://chartable.com/podcasts/chartable-radio/episodes/30852152-justin-jackson-cofounder-transistorfm&quot;&gt;pointed out on Chartable Radio&lt;/a&gt; that there are over 35 million YouTube channels. There's still plenty of room for new entrants in the audio world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So many people are creating podcasts for the same reason journalists and others are starting newsletters: podcasts are a great way to connect directly to an audience. There's no single gatekeeper, or gatekeeping algorithm, that will prevent you from reaching your audience—if someone subscribes to your podcast, they'll see all your new episodes. That's why there are many more shows from diverse and marginalized creators than you'd find on broadcast radio.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://anchor.fm&quot;&gt;Anchor&lt;/a&gt;, which creates easy-to-use podcasting tools, certainly accelerated this trend. As we wrote last year, &lt;a href=&quot;https://chartable.com/blog/whats-really-the-top-podcast-hosting-service&quot;&gt;Anchor hosts over a third of new podcasts&lt;/a&gt;, because they make starting a new podcast much easier. They've brought a whole new set of creators to the medium that would otherwise have found it too challenging to get started—like what Blogger and Wordpress did for blogging.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There have also been many more professionally-produced podcasts in recent years. Many early shows were simply repackaged radio programs, but since Serial launched in 2014&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; startups, independent producers, and even big media companies have been finding success with shows designed from the start as podcasts. &lt;a href=&quot;https://chartable.com/blog/golden-age-of-podcasts#footnote3&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Daily podcasts build habits&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just three years ago, there were no daily news podcasts that weren't borrowed from radio.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;USA Today launched the first daily news podcast in the US in October of 2016. But the genre really took off when The New York Times launched The Daily, the most popular daily podcast, on February 1st, 2017. Since then, many media companies have started daily podcasts of their own, like Slate, The Washington Post, and The Economist. &lt;a href=&quot;https://chartable.com/blog/golden-age-of-podcasts#footnote4&quot;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.buttercms.com/z8M11k1HTLKuZATCChYB&quot; alt=&quot;Number-of-daily-news-podcasts-(1).png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chartable now counts 11 general-audience daily shows, most of which were launched in the last year. These shows, like &lt;em&gt;Serial&lt;/em&gt;, were meant to be podcasts from the outset, meaning they weren't tied to the rhythms or rules of broadcast radio.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Besides the obvious benefit to publishers—five episodes per week means more ad inventory—daily podcasts offer listeners a consistent way to integrate podcasts into their routines.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Daily news podcasts help turn occasional listeners into more frequent listeners. While “at home” is the most popular place to listen to podcasts, many people listen on their commute, and daily podcasts offer a predictable way to keep up with the news and build a habit of podcast listening. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.slideshare.net/webby2001/the-podcast-consumer-2018/17&quot;&gt;And once someone starts listening to podcasts, they tend to listen to even more podcasts over time&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Binge-worthy audio&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some sources claim that our average attention span is down to &lt;a href=&quot;http://time.com/3858309/attention-spans-goldfish/&quot;&gt;8 seconds&lt;/a&gt;. People view Facebook Watch videos for an average of 23 seconds. A “good” YouTube consumption rate is somewhere around 50%.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But podcasts are different: Edison Research data shows that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.slideshare.net/webby2001/the-podcast-consumer-2018/20&quot;&gt;87% of podcast listeners listen to most or all of each podcast they listen to&lt;/a&gt;. This is despite the fact that many podcasts can run for hours. No wonder that podcasts have been called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.niemanlab.org/2018/12/podcasting-is-medias-slow-food-movement/&quot;&gt;“the slow food movement of the media world&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Listeners are binging on podcasts the same way they binge a new Netflix season. That's incredibly valuable to a company like Spotify that depends on building and maintaining its users' attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.buttercms.com/7h2EDPQ9RgewFw9Ns8gj&quot; alt=&quot;Amount-of-podcast-episode-listened-to...&quot; class=&quot;w-80-ns db center&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why now?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is there such a boom &lt;em&gt;now&lt;/em&gt;, given that podcasts have been around for 15 years? One could ask the same question about streaming video's growth in the 2010s—and as the head of Amazon Studios said in 2017: “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ft.com/content/68309b3a-1f02-11e7-a454-ab04428977f9&quot;&gt;Streaming is the culmination of a change that has been coming for decades&lt;/a&gt;”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, the podcast boom has deep roots—as James Cridland &lt;a href=&quot;https://podnews.net/article/spotify-gimlet&quot;&gt;has written&lt;/a&gt;, “podcasting has been taken seriously for a long, long time by anyone that cares about well-produced audio.” There are several broad trends converging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spotify and Google get serious&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple is so integral to the podcast ecosystem that up to two-thirds of all podcast listening globally happens on iPhones and other Apple devices—despite the fact that Android has a greater market share, especially outside of the US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.buttercms.com/Knhjv6HQTyeTxgneduSA&quot; alt=&quot;Apple market share&quot; class=&quot;w-80-ns db center&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spotify and Google both increased their investment in podcasting in 2018, reducing Apple's dominance and bringing more listeners to podcasts for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Google launched a native Google Podcasts app for Android, after multiple attempts at integrating podcasts with other services like Google Play. Although Google's new app is only responsible for about 1% of downloads according to Libsyn, it has the advantage of working on any Android device &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@JamesCridland/how-to-link-to-your-podcast-most-effectively-e15ecb1e1105&quot;&gt;without requiring an app installation,&lt;/a&gt; which means the hundreds of millions of Android users out there now have a “universal link” for podcast listening.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Spotify has allowed podcast listening in their desktop and mobile for over two years, but they significantly increased the prominence of podcasts in 2018 and opened the platform to all podcasters. Their increased emphasis on podcasts shows in download stats: Spotify's percentage of downloads doubled last year, from 4.4% in December 2017 to 8.5% in December 2018 &lt;a href=&quot;https://chartable.com/blog/golden-age-of-podcasts#footnote5&quot;&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.buttercms.com/zVaKuYwrT0KmgY4bCsJy&quot; alt=&quot;Spotify-market-share-(1).png&quot; class=&quot;w-80-ns db center&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of these listeners are new to podcasts. In other words, Spotify didn't “steal” listeners who were already listening to podcasts on Apple Podcasts, they created new listeners by exposing them to podcasts for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mobile everywhere&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smartphone penetration in the US started peaking just a few years ago. Because smartphones are by far the most popular devices for listening to podcasts, near-complete adoption of smartphones was a prerequisite for the podcast boom. Streaming media &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.tmcnet.com/next-generation-communications/2013/08/six-degrees-of-mobile-data-plan-innovation-capacity-based-plans.html&quot;&gt;make up the majority of mobile data usage&lt;/a&gt;—and that share is still growing. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statista.com/statistics/201182/forecast-of-smartphone-users-in-the-us/&quot; class=&quot;link gray&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.buttercms.com/UPS88hTxSuKKHUNZMOzg&quot; alt=&quot;Number-of-US-smartphone-users.png&quot; class=&quot;w-80-ns db center&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connected cars&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.slideshare.net/webby2001/the-podcast-consumer-2018/19&quot;&gt;A quarter of all listeners do the majority of their podcast listening in their car&lt;/a&gt;. As more cars adopt Apple's CarPlay and Android Auto, people are choosing to listen to podcasts or streaming services like Spotify or Apple Music rather than AM/FM radio. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@SoftClouds/crm-telematics-iot-the-emerging-landscape-1b7cdb17e205&quot; class=&quot;link gray&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.buttercms.com/xj0smxjkSBu3mj5IxGT6&quot; alt=&quot;Connected-car-adoption.png&quot; class=&quot;w-80-ns db center&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More audio, everywhere&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's not just podcasts that are booming—smartphones have brought many more listening options to consumers, from streaming music services (Apple Music, Spotify), to meditation apps (Calm, Headspace) to audiobooks (Audible, Libby). Calm alone has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.calm.com/about&quot;&gt;over 40 million downloads&lt;/a&gt;, and 18% of US adults have listened to an audiobook in the last year, up from 11% in 2011. (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pewresearch.org/fact-tank/2018/03/08/nearly-one-in-five-americans-now-listen-to-audiobooks/&quot; class=&quot;link gray&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.buttercms.com/1vMckx1zQbCKx0RqVv1q&quot; alt=&quot;Audiobook adoption&quot; class=&quot;w-80-ns db center&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smart speakers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alexa, Google Assistant, and HomePod have been adopted by consumers more quickly than almost any other consumer platform in history. These speakers still represent a small percentage of overall podcast listening—and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.slideshare.net/webby2001/the-podcast-consumer-2018/30&quot;&gt;only 17% of smart speaker owners use them to listen to podcasts&lt;/a&gt;— but as more consumers get a speaker in their home and build a habit of using it, expect to see those numbers climb. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://files.constantcontact.com/150f9af2201/5c84cae5-7ff0-403d-acd5-9065db944222.pdf&quot; class=&quot;link gray&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.buttercms.com/jRGe7UJCS8qsiywnECrT&quot; alt=&quot;US-Smart-Speaker-Units.png&quot; class=&quot;w-80-ns db center&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What's next?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Golden Age of Podcasts is happening now because of more listeners, more content, more binge-worthy and daily content plus the convergence of tech adoption curves. So what can we expect in the near future?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For listeners, there will be more amazing shows of all kinds&lt;/strong&gt;. More media companies will invest in creating quality long-form audio. We'll see many more high-quality shows like &lt;a href=&quot;https://chartable.com/blog/the-best-podcasts-of-2018&quot;&gt;the best podcasts of 2018&lt;/a&gt; that are binge-worthy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Podcasts will continue to grow their share of overall attention&lt;/strong&gt;. The more people listen to podcasts, the more podcasts they listen to. And quality audio is a great way to learn something new or entertain yourself while reducing screen time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For creators, new models for funding the production for a show will emerge&lt;/strong&gt;, much as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2018/08/15/netflix-cost-plus-model-tv-shows-revenue-upside.html&quot;&gt;Netflix has changed the TV production model&lt;/a&gt;. And we'll see more ways for creators to monetize their shows, in addition to than the current methods (ads, live shows, subscriptions). After all, &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:5555/blog/golden-age-of-podcasts&quot;&gt;podcasts are a $7 billion industry in China&lt;/a&gt;—surely we haven't explored all paths towards monetization in the US.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More transparency.&lt;/strong&gt; The accepted measurement in the podcast industry is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iab.com/guidelines/podcast-measurement-guidelines/&quot;&gt;download&lt;/a&gt;, which doesn't say much about whether anyone's actually listening. I previously wrote about &lt;a href=&quot;https://chartable.com/blog/chartbreakers&quot;&gt;fraud on the podcast charts&lt;/a&gt;—I expect download fraud to become more common. As the industry grows, advertisers and other funders will expect more precise and transparent measurement of audience engagement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spotify will create more exclusive content to aggregate and retain listeners.&lt;/strong&gt; This is a strategic move straight out of Ben Thompson's &lt;a href=&quot;https://stratechery.com/2015/aggregation-theory/&quot;&gt;Aggregation Theory&lt;/a&gt;. When users listen to podcasts, Spotify doesn't have to pay out the major labels. And Spotify can also leverage their listener base to aggregate advertiser demand for podcast ad space.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Despite Spotify's strong moves, Apple will maintain a strong position.&lt;/strong&gt; Because the iPhone is such a powerful platform and the Apple Podcasts app is installed by default, Apple will always command the attention of some (large) percentage of listeners. Even if Spotify and Gimlet create exceptional exclusive content, there will always be a big pool of free, high-quality shows—many podcasts are the product of public media (e.g. NPR, CBC, BBC), and many creators won't want to lose the direct relationship with their listeners that the open podcast ecosystem provides.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;We founded &lt;a href=&quot;https://chartable.com&quot;&gt;Chartable&lt;/a&gt; last year with the goal of helping podcasters understand and grow their audiences, and I couldn't be more excited to be working in this creative industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our current Golden Age of Television started eighty years after the invention of TV, and a decade after the invention of the Web. And despite some dire warnings, the trend in more and better TV programming has yet to slow. In comparison, the Golden Age of Podcasts only took 15 years since the invention of the medium, and it's just getting started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;pa3 bg-washed-green f5&quot;&gt;If you liked this post, please consider sharing it on:  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/sharer/sharer.php?u=https%3A%2F%2Fchartable.com%2Fblog%2Fgolden-age-of-podcasts&amp;amp;quote=Why%20we%27re%20entering%20the%20Golden%20Age%20of%20Podcasts%20%28in%2010%20graphs%29&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Share on Facebook&quot; class=&quot;link blue&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; · &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?source=https%3A%2F%2Fchartable.com%2Fblog%2Fgolden-age-of-podcasts&amp;amp;text=Why%20we%27re%20entering%20the%20Golden%20Age%20of%20Podcasts%20%28in%2010%20graphs%29:%20https%3A%2F%2Fchartable.com%2Fblog%2Fgolden-age-of-podcasts&amp;amp;via=ChartableDotCom&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Tweet&quot; class=&quot;link blue&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; · &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.linkedin.com/shareArticle?mini=true&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fchartable.com%2Fblog%2Fgolden-age-of-podcasts&amp;amp;title=Why%20we%27re%20entering%20the%20Golden%20Age%20of%20Podcasts%20%28in%2010%20graphs%29&amp;amp;summary=Podcasts%20have%20been%20around%20in%20some%20form%20since%20at%20least%202004%2C%20but%20many%20trends%20point%20to%20the%20beginning%20of%20a%20Golden%20Age.%20Spotify%27s%20recent%20%24340%20million%20acquisition%20is%20just%20one%20of%20many%20signals%20that%20things%20are%20changing.&amp;amp;source=https%3A%2F%2Fchartable.com%2Fblog%2Fgolden-age-of-podcasts&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Share on LinkedIn&quot; class=&quot;link blue&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt; · &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:?subject=Why%20we%27re%20entering%20the%20Golden%20Age%20of%20Podcasts%20%28in%2010%20graphs%29&amp;amp;body=Podcasts%20have%20been%20around%20in%20some%20form%20since%20at%20least%202004%2C%20but%20many%20trends%20point%20to%20the%20beginning%20of%20a%20Golden%20Age.%20Spotify%27s%20recent%20%24340%20million%20acquisition%20is%20just%20one%20of%20many%20signals%20that%20things%20are%20changing:%20https%3A%2F%2Fchartable.com%2Fblog%2Fgolden-age-of-podcasts&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Send email&quot; class=&quot;link blue&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Via email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Or join the discussion on &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19217575&quot;&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;pa3 mt4 bg-almost-white f6-ns f5&quot; readability=&quot;61.14034725093&quot;&gt;

&lt;strong class=&quot;db mb3&quot;&gt;Notes&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] There is a survivorship bias towards recent podcasts in our data — podcasts that started and then disappeared from the iTunes directory prior to June 2018 are not included in our dataset. It's difficult to estimate the size of this effect.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[2] Our sample was conducted online, so there may be a bias towards more podcast listening given that respondents already comfortable using the Internet may be more familiar with newer media like podcasts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[3] Here are just a few: Gimlet Media and Radiotopia started in 2014; Parcast (Conspiracy Theories, Serial Killers), Wondery (Dr. Death, Dirty John), and The Ringer started in 2016. MSNBC (The Bag Man) and ABC (The Drop Out) launched major new documentaries in the last few months, and ESPN has been releasing its “30 For 30” documentaries as podcasts for several years now.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[4] Here are the daily podcasts and their launch dates I collected. I'm sure I'm missing some, so if you know of a podcast-native daily show, please let me know. 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;USA Today: 5 Things (10/2016), The Daily (2/2017), NPR: Up First (4/2017), NPR: The Indicator from Planet Money (12/2017), Vox: Today, Explained (2/2018), ABC (US): Start Here (3/2018), Washington Post: Post Reports (10/2018), Financial Times: FT News Briefing (10/2018), The Guardian: Today in Focus (11/2018), Slate: What's Next (1/2019), The Economist: The Intelligence (1/2019)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[5] Spotify likely represents more listening than download statistics suggest because a stream isn't equivalent to a donwload. When you subscribe to a show on Apple Podcasts, the app will download every episode as long as you occasionally listen—which means many if not most of the episodes on your phone go unlistened. Spotify just counts a stream after you press “play”, which means there's more intent to listen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;strong class=&quot;db mb3&quot;&gt;Thanks&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://edisonresearch.com&quot;&gt;Edison Research&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://thefeed.libsyn.com/&quot;&gt;Libsyn&lt;/a&gt; for making their numbers freely accessible. Additional thanks to Lukas Biewald, Jim Young, Andrew Cove and Rosy Kalfus for reading drafts of this article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 15:42:10 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>andrewacove</dc:creator>
<og:title>Here's why we're entering the Golden Age of Podcasts (in 10 graphs)</og:title>
<og:description>Spotify's acquisition of Gimlet Media and Anchor signals the beginning of the Golden Age of Podcasts. It's the culmination of many trends: More listeners, more content, more kinds of content, more ways to listen, and the convergence of larger tech adoption curves.</og:description>
<og:image>https://cdn.buttercms.com/ejvlmtJiTnKMXmuZgEwF</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://chartable.com/blog/golden-age-of-podcasts</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>PostgreSQL&amp;#039;s Explain Analyze Made Readable</title>
<link>http://explain.depesz.com</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://explain.depesz.com</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;http://explain.depesz.com&quot;&gt;http://explain.depesz.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19216315&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19216315&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 253&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 48&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 12:23:42 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>GordonS</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://explain.depesz.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>COI – Chat Over IMAP</title>
<link>https://www.coi-dev.org/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.coi-dev.org/</guid>
<description>&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Others do not Solve this Problem?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;Maybe you are thinking “&lt;strong&gt;I thought this is why we have Signal, Telegram and the other privacy-centric apps?&lt;/strong&gt;” – they might very well be better than some of the more popular networks, but in the end, they control the network and other providers are locked out. Basically, you are exchanging one silo with another. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;“&lt;strong&gt;What about &lt;a href=&quot;https://xmpp.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;XMPP&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://matrix.org/blog/home/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Matrix.org&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt;” – glad you asked! We love XMPP and Matrix.org, because they provide a great solution, but this only solves the problem in theory though. With XMPP and Matrix.org -based services you would still need to convince everyone to join your new network. Easy in theory, very complex in practice! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;“&lt;strong&gt;What about RCS?&lt;/strong&gt;“ – Most notably, RCS requires a device to have a phone number (MSISDN). As communication is quickly migrating towards pure IP based solutions, MSISDNs become a relics of the past. Most new innovative devices come without MSISDNs, e.g. voice enabled devices such as smart speakers, VR and AR devices, portable game consoles, etc. With this dependency on MSISDNs, RCS’ future is uncertain. Additionally, operators already have wasted millions with RCS, so they are hesitant when being asked to spend further millions on this technology. Last but not least, Apple does not support RCS out of the box at the moment, as they successfully operate a proprietary messaging service.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 11:28:03 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>smartmic</dc:creator>
<og:title>COI - Chat Over IMAP</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.coi-dev.org/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Indonesia reports reduced deforestation, triggering carbon payment from Norway</title>
<link>https://www.norway.no/en/indonesia/norway-indonesia/news-events/news2/indonesia-reports-reduced-deforestation-triggering-first-carbon-payment-from-norway/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.norway.no/en/indonesia/norway-indonesia/news-events/news2/indonesia-reports-reduced-deforestation-triggering-first-carbon-payment-from-norway/</guid>
<description>&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Indonesia confirms that carbon emissions from deforestation declined in 2017.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When the emission figures are independently verified, Norway will guarantee payments to Indonesia for approximately 4.8 millions tons of CO2.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This will be the first payment for reduced emissions during the climate and forest partnership between the two countries that started in 2010.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Halting deforestation is essential for the world to meet the Paris Climate Goals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meeting in Jakarta on Saturday, the Minister of Environment and Forests of Indonesia, Ms. Siti Nurbaya Bakar and the Minister of Climate and Environment of Norway, Mr. Ola Elvestuen, announced that the two countries were launching a new phase of their landmark bilateral climate and forest partnership that started in 2010. The two countries have agreed to the rules for results-based payments from Norway to Indonesia for reduced emissions. With that, Indonesia will be the largest rainforest nation to receive payments for reduced deforestation at the national level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- I am glad during the last four years, the Indonesian government led by President Joko Widodo has managed to undertake a series of corrective measures in the forest and land use sector. The bold measures have resulted in significant reduction of deforestation, forest degradation, as well as GHG emissions, said Minister Siti Nurbaya.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She added &quot;I'm also pleased that Indonesia and Norway have agreed on the rules for results-based payments. With these developments, we are ready to step into the third phase of the partnership, in which emission reductions on the field is rewarded by Norway.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Indonesia has embarked on bold regulatory reforms, and it is showing results, said Minister Elvestuen. - It may be too early to see a clear trend, but if deforestation continues to drop we stand ready to increase our annual payments to reward Indonesia's results and support its efforts. The minister's remarks came at the end of a successful weeklong visit to Jakarta and a West-Papua, where he met Governor Dominguus Mandacan and visited mangrove forests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indonesia has implemented a number of critical reforms and actions in the forest and land use sectors over the last few years. The government has introduced new measures to protect forests, including a ban on destroying primary forests and peatlands. In 2018, president Jokowi announced a policy to drive future increases in palm oil production from existing plantations instead of opening new forest areas. Indonesia has embarked on a comprehensive legal review of existing forestry and agriculture concessions, and increased law enforcement efforts against forest crimes. Importantly, the adat and other local communities have gained rights to land.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following an independent third-party verification of the annual emission reduction numbers Indonesia presented today, Norway will guarantee payment for a portion of the result. Assuming the verified result matches the reported result for 2016-17, the first payment would be for approximately 4.8 million tons CO2. In 2010, Norway pledged to support Indonesia with up to 1 billion USD depending on results. So far, about 13% of this pledge has been spent to support the efforts of the Indonesian government to address deforestation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indonesia has the world's third largest tropical rainforest. The total emissions from deforestation and peatland destruction has put Indonesia amongst the world's top emitters, but Indonesia has set ambitious targets for reducing its emissions from deforestation. It has called for international partnerships to increase its ambitious contributions to the Paris Climate Agreement and reduce emissions by up to 41% by 2030.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forests are critical for meeting both the Paris Climate Agreement and many of the Sustainable Development Goals. Substantial actions on reducing emissions from deforestation are necessary if the world is to keep global temperature increase below 1,5–2 degrees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;About the new results protocol&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Starting from the forest year 2016-17, results are estimated for reduced deforestation and forest degradation at the national level.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Results are measured against a 10-year historical average emissions level. For the period 2006- 16 that was estimated at approx. 237 mill tons CO2 per year from deforestation and approx. 42 mill tons for forest degradation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Emission reductions from peat degradation and peat fires will be included in the results protocol in the near future, as estimates improve.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Indonesia will set aside 20% of the results to account for uncertainty, and another 15% to reflect its own ambition in reducing emissions. The remaining 65% of the results can be rewarded by Norway or other financiers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Norway will guarantee payment for a portion of the available tons. Norway will not use emission reductions from Indonesia to offset its climate commitments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norway.no/contentassets/8b319959d6e5489483f0d924281fdf55/mrv_protocol_final.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;The details of the payment model (&quot;MRV Protocol&quot;) can be downloaded here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For further information please contact:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;From Indonesia: Ms. Nining Ngudi, KLN, Ministry of Environment and Forestry (nining.ngudi@gmail.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From Norway: Mr Snorre Tønset, Ministry of Climate and the Environment, (snorre.tonset@kld.dep.no)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 10:45:58 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ammaristotle</dc:creator>
<og:title>Indonesia reports reduced deforestation, triggering first carbon payment from Norway</og:title>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:image>https://www.norway.no/static/images/meta/opengraph_200x200.png</og:image>
<og:url>https://www.norway.no/en/indonesia/norway-indonesia/news-events/news2/indonesia-reports-reduced-deforestation-triggering-first-carbon-payment-from-norway/</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.norway.no/en/indonesia/norway-indonesia/news-events/news2/indonesia-reports-reduced-deforestation-triggering-first-carbon-payment-from-norway/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Stop Saying, ‘We Take Your Privacy and Security Seriously’</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/17/we-take-your-privacy-and-security-seriously/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/17/we-take-your-privacy-and-security-seriously/</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot;&gt;In my years covering cybersecurity, there’s one variation of the same lie that floats above the rest. “We take your privacy and security seriously.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might have heard the phrase here and there. It’s a common trope used by companies in the wake of a data breach — either in a &lt;em&gt;“mea culpa”&lt;/em&gt; email to their customers or a statement on their website to tell you that they care about your data, even though in the next sentence they all too often admit to misusing or losing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The truth is, most companies don’t care about the privacy or security of your data. They care about having to explain to their customers that their data was stolen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve never understood exactly what it means when a company says it values my privacy. If that were the case, data hungry companies like Google and Facebook, which sell data about you to advertisers, wouldn’t even exist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was curious how often this go-to one liner was used. I scraped every reported notification to the California attorney general, a requirement under state law in the event of a breach or security lapse, stitched them together, and converted it into machine-readable text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About one-third of all 285 data breach notifications had some variation of the line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t show that companies care about your data. It shows that they don’t know what to do next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A perfect example of a company not caring: Last week, we reported several OkCupid users had complained &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/10/okcupid-account-hacks/&quot;&gt;their accounts were hacked&lt;/a&gt;. More likely than not, the accounts were hit by credential stuffing, where hackers take lists of usernames and passwords and try to brute-force their way into people’s accounts. Other companies have learned from such attacks and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zdnet.com/article/adguard-resets-all-user-passwords-after-credential-stuffing-attack/&quot;&gt;took the time to improve account security&lt;/a&gt;, like rolling out two-factor authentication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, OkCupid’s response was to deflect, defend and deny, a common way for companies to get ahead of a negative story. It looked like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Deflect: “All websites constantly experience account takeover attempts,” the company said.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Defend: “There’s no story here,” the company later told &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infosecurity-magazine.com/news/okcupid-users-victims-of/&quot;&gt;another publication&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deny: “No further comment,” when asked what the company will do about it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;It would’ve been great to hear OkCupid say it cared about the matter and what it was going to do about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every industry has long neglected security. Most of the breaches today are the result of shoddy security over years or sometimes decades, coming back to haunt them. Nowadays, every company has to be a security company, whether it’s a bank, a toymaker or a single app developer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Companies can start off small: tell people how to reach contact them &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.michalspacek.com/what-is-security.txt-and-why-you-should-have-one&quot;&gt;with security flaws&lt;/a&gt;, roll out a bug bounty to &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2017/02/08/hackerone-scores-40-million-investment-as-bug-bounty-programs-mainstream/&quot;&gt;encourage bug submissions&lt;/a&gt; and grant good-faith researchers safe harbor by &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/06/teslas-new-bug-bounty-protects-hackers-and-your-warranty/&quot;&gt;promising not to sue&lt;/a&gt;. Startup founders can also fill their executive suite with a chief security officer from the very beginning. They’d be better off than 95 percent of &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/2018/12/a-chief-security-concern-for-executive-teams/&quot;&gt;the world’s richest companies that haven’t even bothered&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But this isn’t what happens. Instead, companies would rather just pay the fines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Target &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usatoday.com/story/money/2017/05/23/target-pay-185m-2013-data-breach-affected-consumers/102063932/&quot;&gt;paid $18.5 million for a data breach&lt;/a&gt; that ensnared 41 million credit cards, compared to full-year revenues of $72 billion. Anthem &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/article/us-anthem-cyber-settlement/anthem-to-pay-record-115-million-to-settle-u-s-lawsuits-over-data-breach-idUSKBN19E2ML&quot;&gt;paid $115 million in fines&lt;/a&gt; after a data breach put 79 million insurance holders’ data at risk, on revenues that year of $79 billion. And, remember Equifax? The biggest breach of 2017 &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/08/equifax-one-year-later-unscathed/&quot;&gt;led to all talk but no action&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With no incentive to change, companies will continue to parrot their usual hollow remarks. Instead, they should do something about it.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 07:43:48 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>samaysharma</dc:creator>
<og:title>Stop saying, ‘We take your privacy and security seriously’</og:title>
<og:description>In my years covering cybersecurity, there’s one variation of the same lie that floats above the rest. “We take your privacy and security seriously.” You might have heard the phrase here and there. It’s a common trope used by companies in the wake of a data breach — eit…</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/seriously.jpg?w=600</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2019/02/17/we-take-your-privacy-and-security-seriously/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/17/we-take-your-privacy-and-security-seriously/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Introduction to Algotrading (2011) [pdf]</title>
<link>http://isomorphisms.sdf.org/maxdama.pdf</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://isomorphisms.sdf.org/maxdama.pdf</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;http://isomorphisms.sdf.org/maxdama.pdf&quot;&gt;http://isomorphisms.sdf.org/maxdama.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19215026&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19215026&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 342&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 93&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 06:43:29 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>steventhedev</dc:creator>
<dc:identifier>http://isomorphisms.sdf.org/maxdama.pdf</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>