<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>U.S. Supreme Court to hear civil forfeiture case</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/06/25/us/politics/supreme-court-civil-asset-forfeiture.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2018/06/25/us/politics/supreme-court-civil-asset-forfeiture.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;45&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;35&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;WASHINGTON — Tyson Timbs would like his Land Rover back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The State of Indiana took it, using a law that lets it seize vehicles used to transport illegal drugs. Last week, the Supreme Court agreed to decide whether the Constitution has anything to say about such civil forfeiture laws, which allow states and localities to take and keep private property used to commit crimes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Timbs bought the Land Rover after his father died. The life insurance money amounted to around $73,000, and he spent $42,000 of it on the vehicle. He blew most of the rest on drugs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“Unfortunately, I had a whole bunch of money, which isn’t a good idea for a drug addict to have,” Mr. Timbs recalled the other day. “I used a lot, and eventually the money ran out. It was an addict’s life.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Timbs’s habit started with an opioid addiction and progressed to heroin. He used his Land Rover to get drugs and, on at least two occasions, to sell them. The buyers were undercover police officers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;49.176062445794&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;44.258456201214&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Timbs pleaded guilty to one of the drug sales, in which $225 had changed hands, and he was sentenced to a year of house arrest followed by five years of probation. He also agreed to pay an array of fees and fines adding up to about $1,200.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;But Indiana wanted more. Using the civil forfeiture law, it took the Land Rover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Timbs, 37, has put his life back together, but it has not been easy. “I have to go to meetings, to counseling, to probation appointments,” he said, making clear that he was not complaining.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“They want you to get a job,” he said. “It’s hard to do without a vehicle. Plus, I was a felon, which makes it even harder to find a job.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;He found work as a machinist in a factory some 40 minutes from his home in Marion, Ind., where he lives with his aunt. He borrows her car to get to work, and he feels guilty about that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“She has to take a bus back and forth to her kidney dialysis appointments,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;As Justice Clarence Thomas &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.supremecourt.gov/opinions/16pdf/16-122_1b7d.pdf&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;explained last year&lt;/a&gt; in an opinion urging the Supreme Court to examine civil forfeiture laws, government seizures of property used to commit crimes have become worrisomely popular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“Forfeiture has in recent decades become widespread and highly profitable,” Justice Thomas wrote. “And because the law enforcement entity responsible for seizing the property often keeps it, these entities have strong incentives to pursue forfeiture.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;45.464337700146&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;39.371179039301&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“This system — where police can seize property with limited judicial oversight and retain it for their own use — has led to egregious and well-chronicled abuses,” he wrote, citing excellent reporting from &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/sf/investigative/2014/09/06/stop-and-seize/?utm_term=.3476f50ca105&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2013/08/12/taken&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The New Yorker&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The burdens of civil forfeiture fall disproportionately on the poor, said &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://ij.org/staff/whottot/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Wesley P. Hottot&lt;/a&gt;, a lawyer with the &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://ij.org/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Institute for Justice&lt;/a&gt;, which represents Mr. Timbs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“Tyson’s case illustrates how civil forfeiture makes it harder for people who have made mistakes to correct those mistakes and re-enter society,” Mr. Hottot said. “It shouldn’t take the United States Supreme Court to make clear that you don’t take everything from a person who’s facing the kinds of challenges Tyson is.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Timbs won the early rounds in Indiana’s lawsuit seeking to take his vehicle, based on the &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.law.cornell.edu/constitution/eighth_amendment&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Eighth Amendment&lt;/a&gt;, which says that “excessive bail shall not be required, nor excessive fines imposed, nor cruel and unusual punishments inflicted.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Judge Jeffrey D. Todd, of the Grant County Superior Court, said the amendment’s second clause — the one barring “excessive fines” — protected Mr. Timbs. The Land Rover, the judge wrote, was worth about four times the maximum fine Mr. Timbs could have been ordered to pay, which was $10,000. It was also worth more than 30 times the fines that were actually imposed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;50.227272727273&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;47.329545454545&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“The amount of the forfeiture sought is excessive and is grossly disproportional to the gravity of the defendant’s offense,” Judge Todd wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.in.gov/judiciary/opinions/pdf/10201602pdm.pdf&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;An appeals court agreed&lt;/a&gt;. In dissent, Judge Michael P. Barnes wrote that civil forfeiture laws can be abused but that Mr. Timbs should lose the vehicle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“I am keenly aware of the overreach some law enforcement agencies have exercised in some of these cases,” Judge Barnes wrote. “Entire family farms are sometimes forfeited based on one family member’s conduct, or exorbitant amounts of money are seized. However, it seems to me that one who deals heroin, and there is no doubt from the record we are talking about a dealer, must and should suffer the legal consequences to which he exposes himself.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The Indiana Supreme Court &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://www.scotusblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/17-1091-opinion-below.pdf&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ruled against Mr. Timbs&lt;/a&gt;, on interesting grounds. It said the Eighth Amendment’s prohibition of excessive fines did not apply to ones imposed by states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;This is, surprisingly, an open question. The Bill of Rights originally restricted the power of only the federal government, but the Supreme Court has ruled that most of its protections apply to the states under the due process clause of the &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://www.senate.gov/civics/constitution_item/constitution.htm#amdt_14_(1868)&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;14th Amendment&lt;/a&gt;, one of the post-Civil War amendments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;But there are a few exceptions, and the Supreme Court has been inconsistent about where it stands on the excessive fines clause. Mr. Timbs’s case is poised to resolve the question. It will be argued in the fall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;In the meantime, Mr. Timbs sometimes lapses into frustration and bitterness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“I don’t deserve this,” he said. “Nobody does. It’s an unnecessary stressor. I struggle with more than addiction. I struggle with anxiety and depression. I don’t feel like much of a man, because I don’t have a vehicle.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 20:48:59 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>wcbeard10</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/06/25/us/politics/supreme-court-civil-asset-forfeiture.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>He Sold Drugs for $225. Indiana Took His $42,000 Land Rover.</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/06/26/us/26dc-bar1/26dc-bar1-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>The Supreme Court has agreed to decide whether the Constitution has anything to say about civil forfeiture laws that let states take property used in crimes.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/06/25/us/politics/supreme-court-civil-asset-forfeiture.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Introducing A16Z Crypto</title>
<link>https://a16zcrypto.com/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://a16zcrypto.com/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Historically, new models of computing have tended to &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/software-is-eating-the-world/what-s-next-in-computing-e54b870b80cc&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;emerge&lt;/a&gt; every 10-15 years: mainframes in the 60s, PCs in the late 70s, the internet in the early 90s, and smartphones in the late 2000s. Each computing model enabled new classes of applications that built on the unique strengths of the platform. For example, smartphones were the first truly personal computers with built-in sensors like GPS and high-resolution cameras. Applications like Instagram, Snapchat, and Uber/Lyft took advantage of these unique capabilities and are now used by billions of people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blockchain computers were first proposed in 2008 by Satoshi Nakamoto in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitcoin.org/bitcoin.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Bitcoin whitepaper&lt;/a&gt;. Those original ideas have since been dramatically expanded by developers and researchers around the world. Blockchain computers are new types of computers where the unique capability is &lt;em&gt;trust&lt;/em&gt; between users, developers, and the platform itself. This trust &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cdixon/status/563223999543382017&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;emerges&lt;/a&gt; from the mathematical and game-theoretic properties of the system, without depending on the trustworthiness of individual network participants. In exchange for these new capabilities, blockchain computers trade off other capabilities such as transaction scalability. This can lead people to dismiss them, in the same way people dismissed early smartphones because they traded off computing power and screen size for portability and new sensors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trust is a new software primitive from which other components can be constructed. The first and most prominent example is digital money, made famous by Bitcoin. But, as we’ve discovered over the past few years, many other software components can be constructed using the building blocks of trust. Smart contract platforms like Ethereum enable the creation of, among other things, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ERC20&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;application-specific currencies&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ethereum/eips/issues/721&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;digital property rights&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ethereum/EIPs/issues/1068&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;open financial instruments&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/davesag/ERC884-reference-implementation&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;software-based organizations&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From these components, in turn, new infrastructure and applications can be constructed. For example, developers are working on upgrading the core infrastructure of the internet, including storage, networking, &lt;a href=&quot;https://ens.domains/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;identity&lt;/a&gt;, and distributed &lt;a href=&quot;https://truebit.io/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;computation&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://hackernoon.com/stablecoins-designing-a-price-stable-cryptocurrency-6bf24e2689e5&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Stablecoins&lt;/a&gt; can enable more mainstream user experiences for digital payments and financial services. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ethereum/eips/issues/721&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Cryptogoods&lt;/a&gt; can unlock new experiences and business models for games and other forms of media. Entrepreneurs are developing crypto-powered financial services like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://hackernoon.com/traditional-asset-tokenization-b8a59585a7e0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;tokenization&lt;/a&gt; of traditional assets, and payment services for the unbanked. We expect many other applications to emerge in the coming years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new primitive of trust also means that 3rd-party developers, entrepreneurs, and creators can build on top of crypto-powered platforms &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@cdixon/why-decentralization-matters-5e3f79f7638e&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;without worrying&lt;/a&gt; about whether the rules of the game will change later on. In an era in which the internet is increasingly &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@cdixon/crypto-tokens-a-breakthrough-in-open-network-design-e600975be2ef&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;controlled&lt;/a&gt; by a handful of large tech incumbents, it’s more important than ever to create the right economic conditions for developers, creators, and entrepreneurs. Trust also enables new kinds of governance where communities collectively make important decisions about how networks evolve, what behaviors are permitted, and how economic benefits are distributed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are other important trends happening in computing, including the emergence of next-gen computing devices like VR &amp;amp; AR, self-driving cars, drones, and IoT devices. Recent developments in artificial intelligence are extremely exciting and will enable computers to more intelligently interact with the world. We believe that just as the last three megatrends -- mobile, social, and cloud -- intersected and reinforced each other, so will the next three megatrends -- next-gen computing devices, AI, and crypto.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the Bitcoin whitepaper is now almost 10 years old, we believe we are still early in the crypto movement. The infrastructure needs to be improved and the applications are difficult for non-early adopters to use. Many crypto applications still get &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdixon.org/2010/01/03/the-next-big-thing-will-start-out-looking-like-a-toy/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;dismissed as toys&lt;/a&gt;. We believe this will change quickly. For one, crypto is purely a software movement and doesn’t depend on a hardware buildout, in contrast to, say, the internet, which required laying cables and building cell towers. Second, the space is developing extremely rapidly, partly because the code, data, and knowledge is largely open source, and partly because of the increasing inflow of talent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we are optimistic because we are deep believers in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://a16z.com/2016/08/20/why-software-is-eating-the-world/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;power of software&lt;/a&gt;. Software is simply &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@cdixon/why-decentralization-matters-5e3f79f7638e&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;the encoding of human thought&lt;/a&gt;, and as such has an almost unbounded design space. We find ourselves consistently surprised and excited by the wide variety of creative crypto ideas we encounter. For those of us who have been involved in software for a long time, it feels like the early days of the internet, web 2.0, or smartphones all over again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The a16z crypto fund&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today we are announcing the launch of a16z crypto, a $300M venture fund that will invest in crypto companies and protocols. Our fund is designed to include the best features of traditional venture capital, updated to the modern crypto world:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;We are long-term, patient investors&lt;/em&gt;. We’ve been investing in crypto assets for 5+ years. We’ve never sold any of those investments, and don’t plan to any time soon. We structured the a16z crypto fund to be able to hold investments for 10+ years.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;We have an “all weather” fund&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; We plan to invest consistently over time, regardless of market conditions. If there is another “crypto winter,” we’ll keep investing aggressively.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;We provide operational support to entrepreneurs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; Our crypto investments have access to the same 80+ person a16z &lt;a href=&quot;https://a16z.com/about/team/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;operating teams&lt;/a&gt; as do our non-crypto investments. Our operating teams have deep expertise in executive and technical recruiting, regulatory affairs, communications and marketing, and general startup management. We are responsible participants in the governance of companies and the governance of networks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;We are flexible with respect to stage, asset type, and geography&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; One reason we created a new fund is to have maximum flexibility. We invest at all stages, from seed stage pre-launch projects to fully developed later-stage networks like Bitcoin and Ethereum. We’ll invest in traditional financial instruments like equity or convertible notes, and new instruments including the direct purchase of coins/tokens. Crypto is a global phenomenon, with great projects all around the world, and we’ll invest accordingly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;We are focused on non-speculative use case&lt;/em&gt;. We want services powered by crypto protocols to be used by hundreds of millions and eventually billions of people. Crypto tokens are the native asset class of digital networks, but their value is driven by the underlying, practical uses cases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;We’ve assembled a team of crypto specialists to lead our investment effort: &lt;a href=&quot;https://a16zcrypto.com/author/chris-dixon/&quot;&gt;myself&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://a16zcrypto.com/author/ali-yahya/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Ali&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://a16zcrypto.com/author/hilary-kivitz/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Hilary&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://a16zcrypto.com/author/jesse-walden/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Jesse&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://a16zcrypto.com/author/denis-nazarov/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Denis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://a16zcrypto.com/author/corban-bell/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Corban&lt;/a&gt;, Michelle, and our newest General Partner, &lt;a href=&quot;https://a16zcrypto.com/author/kathryn-haun/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Katie Haun&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are an entrepreneur working on a crypto project, we’d love to talk to you -- please &lt;a href=&quot;https://a16zcrypto.com/contact/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;send&lt;/a&gt; us a note.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For important additional information regarding statements on this page, please go &lt;a href=&quot;https://a16zcrypto.com/disclosures/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 20:24:13 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mdelias</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:title>a16zcrypto</og:title>
<og:url>https://a16zcrypto.com/</og:url>
<og:image>https://a16zcrypto.com/wp-content/themes/a16z-crypto/client/images/a16z-logo.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://a16zcrypto.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Layoffs at Watson Health Reveal IBM’s Problem with AI</title>
<link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/the-human-os/robotics/artificial-intelligence/layoffs-at-watson-health-reveal-ibms-problem-with-ai</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://spectrum.ieee.org/the-human-os/robotics/artificial-intelligence/layoffs-at-watson-health-reveal-ibms-problem-with-ai</guid>
<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://spectrum.ieee.org/image/MzA4MDQ5Nw.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Illustration of IBM logo with stethoscope.&quot;/&gt; Illustration: IEEE Spectrum; Images: IBM; iStockphoto
&lt;section id=&quot;side-module&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;medium-top-ad&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-module&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advertisement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;recommended-side&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Editor’s Picks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;article-rec&quot; readability=&quot;36&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-column&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://spectrum.ieee.org/image/MjkzOTk3Mg.jpg&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; height=&quot;140&quot; alt=&quot;An illustration shows a transparent human head in profile with a brain tumor highlighted in red.&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;IBM Watson Makes a Treatment Plan for Brain-Cancer Patient in 10 Minutes; Doctors Take 160 Hours&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;image-column&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://spectrum.ieee.org/image/MjYzMzA0NA.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; height=&quot;140&quot; alt=&quot;Illustration by Tavis Coburn&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;IBM’s Dr. Watson Will See You...Someday&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;image-column&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://spectrum.ieee.org/image/MjQ0MTEyMg.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; height=&quot;140&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;IBM Invests $1 Billion to Grow Watson Supercomputer's Struggling Business&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;p&gt;IBM, a venerable tech company on a mission to stay relevant, has staked much of its future on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ibm.com/watson/&quot;&gt;IBM Watson&lt;/a&gt;. The company has touted Watson, its flagship artificial intelligence, as the premier product for turning our data-rich but disorganized world into a smart and tidy planet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just last month, IBM CEO Ginni Rometty &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ibm.com/events/vivatech?social_post=1552907884&amp;amp;linkId=52107359&quot;&gt;told a convention audience&lt;/a&gt; that we’re at an inflection point in history. Putting AI into everything will enable businesses to improve on “an exponential curve,” she said—a phenomenon that might one day be referred to as “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.channelweb.co.uk/crn-uk/news/3032963/watsons-law-will-rival-moores-law-claims-ginni-rometty-in-ai-keynote&quot;&gt;Watson’s Law&lt;/a&gt;.”   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But according to engineers swept up in a major round of layoffs within IBM’s Watson division last month, the company’s promotions of its “cognitive computing” platform mask its own real difficulties in turning its AI into a profitable business. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“IBM Watson has great AI,” one engineer said, who asked to remain anonymous so he wouldn’t lose his severance package. “It’s like having great shoes, but not knowing how to walk—they have to figure out how to use it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The layoffs at the end of May cut a swath through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ibm.com/watson/health/&quot;&gt;Watson Health&lt;/a&gt; division. According to anonymous accounts submitted to the site &lt;a href=&quot;https://watchingibm.com/ibm-job-cuts/&quot;&gt;Watching IBM&lt;/a&gt;, the cuts primarily affecting workers from three acquired companies: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ibm.com/watson/health/phytel/&quot;&gt;Phytel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ibm.com/watson/health/explorys/&quot;&gt;Explorys&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://truvenhealth.com/&quot;&gt;Truven&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All three companies, acquired in 2015 and 2016, brought with them hefty troves of healthcare data as well as proprietary analytics systems to mine the data for insights. The companies also brought existing customers: healthcare providers that used the analytics to improve both their care and their finances. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;inlay pullquote rt med&quot;&gt;“We thought IBM would take our company to the next level—not destroy it within three years.” &lt;span class=&quot;pq-attrib&quot;&gt;—laid-off worker from Phytel&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two laid-off engineers from Phytel spoke to &lt;em&gt;IEEE Spectrum&lt;/em&gt; in depth. They allege that IBM’s leadership mismanaged their company since its acquisition, and say the problems at Phytel are emblematic of IBM’s struggles to make Watson profitable. Several other Phytel employees corroborated the basic facts of their accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both engineers worked for Phytel since before &lt;a href=&quot;https://www-03.ibm.com/press/us/en/pressrelease/46767.wss&quot;&gt;its 2015 acquisition&lt;/a&gt;, and say they were excited to become part of Big Blue. “Everyone expected that we would join IBM and be propelled by their support, that it would be the beginning of great things,” says the first engineer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Phytel was a really good company, it was really strong,” says the second, who also asked for anonymity to preserve his severance package. “Many people who got laid off are disappointed because they helped build this company and they really thought IBM would take it to the next level—not destroy it within three years.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phytel had more than 150 clients when it was acquired by IBM, the engineers say. Today it has about 80. “Smaller companies are eating us alive,” says the first engineer. “They’re better, faster, cheaper. They’re winning our contracts, taking our customers, doing better at AI.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“A small percentage of the workforce”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IBM spokesman Ian Colley has declined to answer &lt;em&gt;IEEE Spectrum&lt;/em&gt;’s questions about Phytel, and won’t comment specifically on the engineers’ allegations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead Colley provided the following statement about the layoffs: “This activity affects a small percentage of our Watson Health workforce, as we move to more technology-intensive offerings, simplified processes, and automation to drive speed. IBM is continuing to reposition our team to focus on the high-value segments of the IT market, and we continue to hire aggressively in critical new areas that deliver value for our clients and IBM.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colley also references a &lt;a href=&quot;https://thefly.com/landingPageNews.php?id=2738971&amp;amp;headline=IBM-Morgan-Stanley-says-report-on-mass-layoffs-in-IBMs-Watson-Health-misleading&quot;&gt;Morgan Stanley analyst’s note&lt;/a&gt;, which argues that the layoffs represent restructuring that typically follows an acquisition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;inlay pullquote rt med&quot;&gt;Are you an IBM employee with something to say about Watson Health? Write to e.strickland@ieee.org &lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;But not all financial analysts have been bullish on IBM Watson. Last July, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://javatar.bluematrix.com/pdf/fO5xcWjc&quot;&gt;report from Jefferies LLC&lt;/a&gt; argued that despite IBM’s heavy investment in Watson (which the analyst estimated at $15 billion from 2010 to 2015 alone), the division won’t be profitable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though IBM Watson “remains one of the most complete off-the-shelf [AI] platforms available on the marketplace,” the analyst wrote, customers face serious difficulties in integrating Watson with their existing data and analytics systems. As an example, he cited the MD Anderson Cancer Center in Texas, which &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.beckershospitalreview.com/healthcare-information-technology/5-things-to-know-about-the-md-anderson-ibm-watson-breakup.html&quot;&gt;suspended its Watson project&lt;/a&gt; after spending $62 million on it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Jefferies analyst also argued that IBM is “outgunned in the war for AI talent and will likely see increasing competition”—a situation that probably won’t be helped as disgruntled engineers leave IBM Watson with tales of mismanagement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Healthcare: the killer app? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IBM Watson first wowed the public in 2011 with its &lt;a href=&quot;https://spectrum.ieee.org/automaton/robotics/artificial-intelligence/ibm-watson-jeopardy-computer-shuts-down-humans&quot;&gt;triumphant performance&lt;/a&gt; on the game show &lt;em&gt;Jeopardy!&lt;/em&gt;. The AI owed its victory to its natural language processing abilities, which enabled it to parse the show’s complicated and pun-filled clues, then scan its vast library for the solution. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&amp;quot;Jeopardy!&amp;quot; champions Ken Jennings, left, looks on as &amp;quot;Watson&amp;quot; beats him to the buzzer.&quot; src=&quot;https://spectrum.ieee.org/image/MzA4MDQ0MA.jpeg&quot;/&gt; Photo: Seth Wenig/AP IBM’s Watson beats champion Ken Jennings to the buzzer during a 2011 episode of the game show Jeopardy!.
&lt;p&gt;Two years after that televised tour de force, IBM declared that Watson would find its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/bruceupbin/2013/02/08/ibms-watson-gets-its-first-piece-of-business-in-healthcare/#6860d0b54028&quot;&gt;first killer app in healthcare&lt;/a&gt;. It seemed a natural fit: With hospitals and doctors switching to electronic health records for their patients, data troves were becoming available to machines like Watson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For its first job, Watson was supposed to go to work at &lt;a href=&quot;https://spectrum.ieee.org/computing/software/ibms-watson-goes-to-med-school&quot;&gt;cancer treatment centers&lt;/a&gt;, scanning the medical literature and patient records to advise doctors on treatment plans. Three years later, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statnews.com/2017/09/05/watson-ibm-cancer/&quot;&gt;an investigation&lt;/a&gt; by the publication &lt;em&gt;Stat&lt;/em&gt; alleged that Watson Oncology hadn’t lived up to expectations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the years, &lt;em&gt;IEEE Spectrum&lt;/em&gt; has reported that IBM was &lt;a href=&quot;https://spectrum.ieee.org/tech-talk/computing/software/ibm-invests-1-billion-to-grow-watson-supercomputer-struggling-business&quot;&gt;investing billions&lt;/a&gt; in the Watson business, but that “Doctor Watson” &lt;a href=&quot;https://spectrum.ieee.org/biomedical/diagnostics/ibms-dr-watson-will-see-yousomeday&quot;&gt;wasn’t yet revolutionizing medicine&lt;/a&gt;. We didn’t neglect its significant achievements, though, also reporting on a study in which Watson &lt;a href=&quot;https://spectrum.ieee.org/the-human-os/biomedical/diagnostics/ibm-watson-makes-treatment-plan-for-brain-cancer-patient-in-10-minutes-doctors-take-160-hours&quot;&gt;came up with a treatment plan&lt;/a&gt; for a brain cancer patient in 10 minutes—as compared to the human experts’ 160 hours of deliberation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Everything stopped”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IBM acquired the three companies Phytel, Explorys, and Truven for their databases of patient information and their data analytics that helped physicians and insurance companies provide more effective care. (A fourth acquisition, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.merge.com/&quot;&gt;Merge&lt;/a&gt;, brought in analytics relating to medical imaging, a very promising field for AI.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watson Health hoped to use these assets to help healthcare systems switch over from the traditional &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.insight-txcin.org/post/value-based-care-vs-fee-for-service&quot;&gt;fee-for-service model to the new value-based model&lt;/a&gt; emphasized under Obamacare. In the new model, healthcare systems aren’t paid for each procedure and visit, but are instead rewarded for keeping patients healthy and achieving better outcomes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phytel’s contribution was analytics paired with an automated patient communication system. A clinic could use the system to search its patient records and find, for example, all the men over age 45 who were overdue for a colonoscopy, and then use an autocall to remind them to schedule the dreaded appointment. Finding these patients who are “out of compliance” is a key part of preventative care, in which regular checkups can catch problems early, before they’re difficult (and expensive) to treat. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phytel came to IBM as a sucessful business with a great reputation. In a 2014 survey of companies working on population health management, the research firm KLAS &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/klas-ranks-phytel-highest-among-population-health-management-vendors-300008156.html&quot;&gt;ranked Phytel as #1&lt;/a&gt; and called it the “clear leader” in the market. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a 2015 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www-03.ibm.com/press/us/en/pressrelease/46584.wss&quot;&gt;press release&lt;/a&gt; announcing the acquisition, IBM announced that Phytel would be part of its brand new Watson Health division, which would augment Phytel’s offerings with IBM’s “powerful cognitive computing.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the acquisition, IBM management started the process known internally as “bluewashing,” in which an acquired company’s branding and operations are brought into alignment with IBM’s way of doing things. During this bluewashing, “everything stopped,” the first Phytel engineer says, and the workers were told not to focus on improving their existing product for current clients. “People were sitting around doing nothing for almost a year,” the second engineer says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, they were instructed to work on a grand project of merging Phytel’s databases and analytics with those of Explorys. The integration was a massive task, the engineers say, which required a huge investment of time and money from IBM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coding without a map&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both engineers lay the blame squarely on IBM’s “offering management” department, which is responsible for coming up with the products that IBM sells to customers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;A University of Texas MD uses IBM's Watson cognitive system while consulting with patient.&quot; src=&quot;https://spectrum.ieee.org/image/MzA4MDU0OA.jpeg&quot;/&gt; Photo: IBM Courtney DiNardo, a clinical researcher at MD Anderson Cancer Center in Texas, consults IBM Watson while speaking with a patient.
&lt;p&gt;IBM’s goal, the Phytel employees said, was to create a fancy new product that combined the capabilities of Phytel and Explorys. However, the offering managers didn’t have a clear idea of what that product would be. “They couldn’t decide on a roadmap,” says the second engineer. “We pivoted so many times.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both Phytel engineers say the offering managers didn’t have technical backgrounds and sometimes came up with ideas for new products that were simply impossible. While the engineers tried to follow the shifting directions from above, Phytel didn’t deliver anything new to the market. “And we were burning through money,” the second engineer says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually, the engineers say, the offering managers did come up with a plan for a new product that would utilize both the Phytel and Explorys resources. But they note that there was no talk of bringing real artificial intelligence into the product. Watson, in other words, was absent. “They’re not anywhere close to injecting AI into the provider space,” says the second engineer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IBM recently began demoing its new product for patient communication with potential international customers, the engineers say—but these potential customers weren’t impressed. Instead they asked for something resembling Phytel’s old system. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Layoffs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IBM hasn't released the total number of Watson Health employees laid off in May, but the Phytel workers estimate that at least 300 people were given notice at their company, Explorys, and Truven. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Phytel, the engineers estimate that IBM laid off about 80 percent of employees—upward of 120 people from engineering, sales, and project management. “These are key technical people, and people working hands-on with the clients,” the first engineer says. “It’s not that they’re trimming down administrative staff or getting rid of non-essential workers.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The engineers say that Phytel’s office, in Dallas, will soon have only a skeleton crew to support the existing products. How effectively that crew will perform, however, is an open question. The engineers say they were trying to help several major customers meet government-defined deadlines, such as starting with a value-based care model in July. “Now, it will be a big surprise to me if this goes as planned,” the first engineers says. “These layoffs will heavily undermine these efforts. If you cut all these people out, who will build the products? Who will deliver in the end?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The engineers see these cuts as IBM’s retreat from making products for healthcare providers such as hospitals, clinics, and doctors’ offices. They say that the employees who escaped the layoffs at the three companies work on products intended instead for insurance companies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The laid-off employees say they aren’t too worried about finding new jobs. Hiring season is coming in August and September, they say, when companies plan their budgets. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While an AI revolution in healthcare may be inevitable, they don’t believe that IBM will lead the charge. While Watson Health was floundering, they say, competitors have been racing ahead. “IBM has great potential, but in modern business, you adapt or go away. Workers will go to other companies,” says the first engineer. “The winner will not be IBM.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 16:15:41 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>amynordrum</dc:creator>
<og:title>Layoffs at Watson Health Reveal IBM’s Problem with AI</og:title>
<og:url>https://spectrum.ieee.org/the-human-os/robotics/artificial-intelligence/layoffs-at-watson-health-reveal-ibms-problem-with-ai</og:url>
<og:description>Axed engineers say IBM isn't always smart about artificial intelligence</og:description>
<og:image>https://spectrum.ieee.org/image/MzA4MDUzNQ.jpeg</og:image>
<og:type>blog-the-human-os</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://spectrum.ieee.org/the-human-os/robotics/artificial-intelligence/layoffs-at-watson-health-reveal-ibms-problem-with-ai</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>OpenAI Five</title>
<link>https://blog.openai.com/openai-five/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.openai.com/openai-five/</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;content&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our team of five neural networks, OpenAI Five, has started to &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.openai.com/openai-five/#thegames&quot;&gt;defeat&lt;/a&gt; amateur human teams at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dota2.com/play/&quot;&gt;Dota 2&lt;/a&gt;. While today we play with &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.openai.com/openai-five/#restricted&quot;&gt;restrictions&lt;/a&gt;, we aim to beat a team of top professionals at &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_International_(Dota_2)&quot;&gt;The International&lt;/a&gt; in August subject only to a limited set of heroes. We may not succeed: Dota 2 is one of the most popular and &lt;a href=&quot;https://purgegamers.true.io/g/dota-2-guide&quot;&gt;complex&lt;/a&gt; esports games in the world, with creative and motivated professionals who &lt;a href=&quot;https://venturebeat.com/2017/02/12/dota-evil-geniuses/&quot;&gt;train&lt;/a&gt; year-round to earn part of Dota's annual $40M &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.esportsearnings.com/history/2017/games&quot;&gt;prize pool&lt;/a&gt; (the largest of any esports game).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OpenAI Five plays 180 years worth of games against itself every day, learning via self-play. It trains using a scaled-up version of &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.openai.com/openai-baselines-ppo/&quot;&gt;Proximal Policy Optimization&lt;/a&gt; running on 256 GPUs and 128,000 CPU cores — a larger-scale version of the system we built to play the much-simpler &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.openai.com/dota-2/&quot;&gt;solo variant&lt;/a&gt; of the game last year. Using a separate &lt;a href=&quot;http://colah.github.io/posts/2015-08-Understanding-LSTMs/#lstm-networks&quot;&gt;LSTM&lt;/a&gt; for each hero and no human data, it learns recognizable strategies. This indicates that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.technologyreview.com/s/603501/10-breakthrough-technologies-2017-reinforcement-learning/&quot;&gt;reinforcement learning&lt;/a&gt; can yield long-term planning with large but achievable scale — without fundamental advances, contrary to our own expectations upon starting the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To benchmark our progress, we'll host a match versus top players on July 28th. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.twitch.tv/openai&quot;&gt;Follow&lt;/a&gt; us on Twitch to view the live broadcast, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/openai-five-benchmark-tickets-47144438284&quot;&gt;request&lt;/a&gt; an invite to attend in person!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.openai.com/content/images/2018/06/H0A3837.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Players and audience of the bot playing against our human test team&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;OpenAI Five playing the best OpenAI employee team. The match was commentated by professional commentator &lt;a href=&quot;https://liquipedia.net/dota2/Blitz&quot;&gt;Blitz&lt;/a&gt; and OpenAI Dota team member Christy Dennison, and observed by a crowd from the community.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One AI milestone is to exceed human capabilities in a complex video game like &lt;a href=&quot;https://qz.com/1051052/deepmind-goog-and-facebook-fb-have-started-the-global-sprint-for-ai-to-beat-starcraft-ii/&quot;&gt;StarCraft&lt;/a&gt; or Dota. Relative to previous AI milestones like &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Deep_Blue_(chess_computer)&quot;&gt;Chess&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://deepmind.com/research/alphago/&quot;&gt;Go&lt;/a&gt;, complex video games start to capture the messiness and continuous nature of the real world. The hope is that systems which solve complex video games will be highly general, with applications outside of games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dota 2 is a real-time strategy game played between two teams of five players, with each player controlling a character called a &quot;hero&quot;. A Dota-playing AI must master the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Long time horizons.&lt;/strong&gt; Dota games run at 30 frames per second for an average of 45 minutes, resulting in 80,000 ticks per game. Most actions (like ordering a hero to &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.valvesoftware.com/wiki/Dota_Bot_Scripting#UNIT_SCOPED_FUNCTIONS&quot;&gt;move&lt;/a&gt; to a location) have minor impact individually, but some individual actions like &lt;a href=&quot;https://dota2.gamepedia.com/Town_Portal_Scroll&quot;&gt;town portal&lt;/a&gt; usage can affect the game strategically; some &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.liquiddota.com/forum/dota-2-strategy/454744-a-small-primer-on-dota-2-strategy&quot;&gt;strategies&lt;/a&gt; can play out over an entire game. OpenAI Five observes every fourth frame, yielding 20,000 moves. &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.ebemunk.com/a-visual-look-at-2-million-chess-games/&quot;&gt;Chess&lt;/a&gt; usually ends before 40 moves, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Go_and_mathematics#Game_tree_complexity&quot;&gt;Go&lt;/a&gt; before 150 moves, with almost every move being strategic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Partially-observed state.&lt;/strong&gt; Units and buildings can only see the area around them. The rest of the map is covered in a fog hiding enemies and their strategies. Strong play requires making inferences based on incomplete data, as well as modeling what one's opponent might be up to. Both chess and Go are full-information games.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;High-dimensional, continuous action space.&lt;/strong&gt; In Dota, each hero can take dozens of actions, and many actions target either another unit or a position on the ground. We discretize the space into 170,000 possible actions per hero (not all valid each tick, such as using a spell on &lt;a href=&quot;https://dota2.gamepedia.com/Cooldown&quot;&gt;cooldown&lt;/a&gt;); not counting the continuous parts, there are an average of ~1,000 valid actions each tick. The average &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Branching_factor&quot;&gt;number of actions&lt;/a&gt; in chess is 35; in Go, 250.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;High-dimensional, continuous observation space.&lt;/strong&gt; Dota is played on a large continuous &lt;a href=&quot;https://devilesk.com/dota2/apps/interactivemap/&quot;&gt;map&lt;/a&gt; containing ten heroes, dozens of buildings, dozens of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Non-player_character&quot;&gt;NPC&lt;/a&gt; units, and a long tail of game features such as runes, trees, and wards. Our model observes the state of a Dota game via Valve's &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.valvesoftware.com/wiki/Dota_Bot_Scripting&quot;&gt;Bot API&lt;/a&gt; as 20,000 (mostly floating-point) numbers representing all information a human is allowed to access. A chess board is naturally represented as about 70 enumeration values (a 8x8 board of 6 piece types and minor &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Threefold_repetition&quot;&gt;historical&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Castling&quot;&gt;info&lt;/a&gt;); a Go board as about 400 enumeration values (a 19x19 board of 2 piece types plus &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Go_(game)#Ko_rule&quot;&gt;Ko&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Dota rules are also very complex — the game has been actively developed for over a decade, with game logic implemented in hundreds of thousands of lines of code. This logic takes milliseconds per tick to execute, versus nanoseconds for Chess or Go engines. The game also gets an update about once every two weeks, constantly changing the environment semantics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our system learns using a massively-scaled version of &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.openai.com/openai-baselines-ppo/&quot;&gt;Proximal Policy Optimization&lt;/a&gt;. Both OpenAI Five and our earlier &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.openai.com/dota-2/&quot;&gt;1v1 bot&lt;/a&gt; learn entirely from self-play. They start with random parameters and do not use &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/DotA2/comments/87up8k/will_open_ai_play_real_5v5_dota_at_ti_8/dwg12om/&quot;&gt;search&lt;/a&gt; or bootstrap from human replays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th/&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OpenAI 1v1 bot&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OpenAI Five&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody readability=&quot;4.8586118251928&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.0149253731343&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CPUs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;60,000 CPU cores on Azure&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;128,000 &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/preemptible-vms/&quot;&gt;preemptible&lt;/a&gt; CPU cores on GCP&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GPUs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;256 K80 GPUs on Azure&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;256 P100 GPUs on GCP&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Experience collected&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;~300 years per day&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;~180 years per day (~900 years per day counting each hero separately)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Size of observation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;~3.3 kB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;~36.8 kB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Observations per second of gameplay&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7.5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Batch size&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8,388,608 observations&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1,048,576 observations&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Batches per minute&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;~20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;~60&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;RL researchers (including ourselves) have generally &lt;a href=&quot;https://himanshusahni.github.io/2018/02/23/reinforcement-learning-never-worked.html&quot;&gt;believed&lt;/a&gt; that long time horizons would require fundamentally new advances, such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cs.toronto.edu/~fritz/absps/dh93.pdf&quot;&gt;hierarchical&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.openai.com/learning-a-hierarchy/&quot;&gt;reinforcement&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://einstein.ai/research/hierarchical-reinforcement-learning&quot;&gt;learning&lt;/a&gt;. Our results suggest that we haven't been giving today's algorithms enough credit — at least when they're run at sufficient scale and with a reasonable way of &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.openai.com/openai-five/#exploration&quot;&gt;exploring&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our agent is trained to maximize the exponentially decayed sum of future rewards, weighted by an exponential decay factor called &lt;code&gt;γ&lt;/code&gt;. During the latest training run of OpenAI Five, we annealed &lt;code&gt;γ&lt;/code&gt; from &lt;code&gt;0.998&lt;/code&gt; (valuing future rewards with a half-life of 46 seconds) to &lt;code&gt;0.9997&lt;/code&gt; (valuing future rewards with a half-life of five minutes). For comparison, the longest horizon in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1707.06347&quot;&gt;PPO&lt;/a&gt; paper was a half-life of 0.5 seconds, the longest in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1710.02298&quot;&gt;Rainbow&lt;/a&gt; paper was a half-life of 4.4 seconds, and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1805.11593&quot;&gt;Observe and Look Further&lt;/a&gt; paper used a half-life of 46 seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the current version of OpenAI Five is weak at &lt;a href=&quot;https://dota2.gamepedia.com/Creep_control_techniques#Last-hitting&quot;&gt;last-hitting&lt;/a&gt; (observing our test matches, the professional Dota commentator &lt;a href=&quot;https://liquipedia.net/dota2/Blitz&quot;&gt;Blitz&lt;/a&gt; estimated it around median for Dota players), its &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.openai.com/openai-five/#observations&quot;&gt;objective prioritization&lt;/a&gt; matches a common professional strategy. Gaining long-term rewards such as strategic map control often requires sacrificing short-term rewards such as gold gained from &lt;a href=&quot;https://dota2.gamepedia.com/Farming&quot;&gt;farming&lt;/a&gt;, since grouping up to attack towers takes time. This observation reinforces our belief that the system is truly optimizing over a long horizon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/UZHTNBMAfAA&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;modelstructure&quot;&gt;Model structure&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each of &lt;a href=&quot;https://d4mucfpksywv.cloudfront.net/research-covers/openai-five/network-architecture.pdf&quot;&gt;OpenAI Five's networks&lt;/a&gt; contain a single-layer, 1024-unit &lt;a href=&quot;http://colah.github.io/posts/2015-08-Understanding-LSTMs/#lstm-networks&quot;&gt;LSTM&lt;/a&gt; that sees the current game state (extracted from Valve's &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.valvesoftware.com/wiki/Dota_Bot_Scripting&quot;&gt;Bot API&lt;/a&gt;) and emits actions through several possible action heads. Each head has semantic meaning, for example, the number of ticks to delay this action, which action to select, the X or Y coordinate of this action in a grid around the unit, etc. Action heads are computed independently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Interactive demonstration of the observation space and action space used by OpenAI Five. OpenAI Five views the world as a list of 20,000 numbers, and takes an action by emitting a list of 8 enumeration values. Select different actions and targets to understand how OpenAI Five encodes each action, and how it observes the world. The image shows the scene as a human would see it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;content&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;OpenAI Five can react to missing pieces of state that correlate with what it does see. For example, until recently OpenAI Five's observations did not include &lt;a href=&quot;https://dota2.gamepedia.com/Sniper#Abilities&quot;&gt;shrapnel&lt;/a&gt; zones (areas where projectiles rain down on enemies), which humans see on screen. However, we observed OpenAI Five learning to walk out of (though not avoid entering) active shrapnel zones, since it could see its health decreasing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;exploration&quot;&gt;Exploration&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given a learning algorithm capable of handling long horizons, we still need to explore the environment. Even with our &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.openai.com/openai-five/#restricted&quot;&gt;restrictions&lt;/a&gt;, there are hundreds of items, dozens of buildings, spells, and unit types, and a long tail of game mechanics to learn about — many of which yield powerful combinations. It's not easy to explore this combinatorially-vast space efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OpenAI Five learns from self-play (starting from random weights), which provides a natural curriculum for exploring the environment. To avoid &quot;strategy collapse&quot;, the agent trains 80% of its games against itself and the other 20% against its past selves. In the first games, the heroes walk aimlessly around the map. After several hours of training, concepts such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/DotA2/comments/17fj2y/laning_101/&quot;&gt;laning&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://dota2.gamepedia.com/Farming&quot;&gt;farming&lt;/a&gt;, or fighting over &lt;a href=&quot;https://pvgna.com/dota2/paths/how-to-master-mid-lane&quot;&gt;mid&lt;/a&gt; emerge. After several days, they consistently adopt basic human strategies: attempt to steal &lt;a href=&quot;https://dota2.gamepedia.com/Bounty_Rune&quot;&gt;Bounty&lt;/a&gt; runes from their opponents, walk to their &lt;a href=&quot;https://dota2.gamepedia.com/Buildings#Towers&quot;&gt;tier one&lt;/a&gt; towers to farm, and rotate heroes around the map to gain lane advantage. And with further training, they become proficient at high-level strategies like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/DotA2/comments/4iyr00/how_do_you_counter_a_5man_early_game_push_strat/&quot;&gt;5-hero push&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In March 2017, our first &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5Fv2c4aNS2w&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&quot;&gt;agent&lt;/a&gt; defeated bots but got confused against humans. To force exploration in strategy space, during training (and only during training) we randomized the properties (health, speed, start level, etc.) of the units, and it began beating humans. Later on, when a test player was consistently beating our 1v1 bot, we increased our training randomizations and the test player started to lose. (Our robotics team concurrently applied similar randomization techniques to &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.openai.com/generalizing-from-simulation/&quot;&gt;physical&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.openai.com/spam-detection-in-the-physical-world/&quot;&gt;robots&lt;/a&gt; to transfer from simulation to the real world.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OpenAI Five uses the randomizations we wrote for our 1v1 bot. It also uses a new &quot;lane assignment&quot; one. At the beginning of each training game, we randomly &quot;assign&quot; each hero to some subset of &lt;a href=&quot;https://dota2.gamepedia.com/Lane&quot;&gt;lanes&lt;/a&gt; and penalize it for straying from those lanes until a randomly-chosen time in the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exploration is also helped by a good reward. &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/dfarhi/66ec9d760ae0c49a5c492c9fae93984a&quot;&gt;Our reward&lt;/a&gt; consists mostly of metrics humans track to decide how they're doing in the game: net worth, kills, deaths, assists, last hits, and the like. We postprocess each agent's reward by subtracting the other team's average reward to prevent the agents from finding positive-sum situations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hardcode item and skill builds (originally written for our &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.openai.com/more-on-dota-2/#infrastructure&quot;&gt;scripted&lt;/a&gt; baseline), and choose which of the builds to use at random. &lt;a href=&quot;https://dota2.gamepedia.com/Courier&quot;&gt;Courier&lt;/a&gt; management is also imported from the scripted baseline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;coordination&quot;&gt;Coordination&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OpenAI Five does not contain an explicit communication channel between the heroes' neural networks. Teamwork is controlled by a hyperparameter we dubbed &quot;team spirit&quot;. Team spirit ranges from 0 to 1, putting a weight on how much each of OpenAI Five's heroes should care about its individual reward function versus the average of the team's reward functions. We anneal its value from 0 to 1 over training.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;rapid&quot;&gt;Rapid&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;Dota-Minigraph&quot; src=&quot;https://blog.openai.com/content/images/2018/06/rapid@2x.png&quot; alt=&quot;OpenAI Rapid&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our system is implemented as a general-purpose RL training system called Rapid, which can be applied to any &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/openai/gym&quot;&gt;Gym&lt;/a&gt; environment. We've used Rapid to solve other problems at OpenAI, including &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.openai.com/competitive-self-play/&quot;&gt;Competitive Self-Play&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.openai.com/content/images/2018/06/rapid-architecture@2x--1-.png&quot; alt=&quot;rapid-architecture@2x--1-&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The training system is separated into &lt;em&gt;rollout&lt;/em&gt; workers, which run a copy of the game and an agent gathering experience, and &lt;em&gt;optimizer&lt;/em&gt; nodes, which perform synchronous gradient descent across a fleet of GPUs. The rollout workers sync their experience through Redis to the optimizers. Each experiment also contains workers evaluating the trained agent versus reference agents, as well as monitoring software such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tensorflow.org/programmers_guide/summaries_and_tensorboard&quot;&gt;TensorBoard&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://sentry.io/welcome/&quot;&gt;Sentry&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://grafana.com/&quot;&gt;Grafana&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;Dota-Minigraph&quot; src=&quot;https://blog.openai.com/content/images/2018/06/gpu-synchronization-time-small@2x.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;During synchronous gradient descent, each GPU computes a gradient on its part of the batch, and then the gradients are globally averaged. We originally used &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Message_Passing_Interface&quot;&gt;MPI's&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mcs.anl.gov/research/projects/mpi/mpi-standard/mpi-report-1.1/node82.htm&quot;&gt;allreduce&lt;/a&gt; for averaging, but now use our own &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.nvidia.com/nccl&quot;&gt;NCCL2&lt;/a&gt; wrappers that parallelize GPU computations and network data transfer.&lt;br/&gt;The latencies for synchronizing 58MB of data (size of OpenAI Five's parameters) across different numbers of GPUs are shown on the right. The latency is low enough to be largely masked by GPU computation which runs in parallel with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've implemented Kubernetes, Azure, and GCP backends for Rapid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus far OpenAI Five has played (with our &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.openai.com/openai-five/#restricted&quot;&gt;restrictions&lt;/a&gt;) versus each of these teams:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Best OpenAI employee team: 2.5k &lt;a href=&quot;https://dota2.gamepedia.com/Matchmaking_Rating&quot;&gt;MMR&lt;/a&gt; (46th percentile)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Best audience players watching OpenAI employee match (including Blitz, who commentated the first OpenAI employee match): 4-6k MMR (90th-99th percentile), though they'd never played as a team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Valve employee team: 2.5-4k MMR (46th-90th percentile).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amateur team: 4.2k MMR (93rd percentile), trains as a team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Semi-pro team: 5.5k MMR (99th percentile), trains as a team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;The April 23rd version of OpenAI Five was the first to beat our scripted baseline. The May 15th version of OpenAI Five was evenly matched versus team 1, winning one game and losing another. The June 6th version of OpenAI Five decisively won all its games versus teams 1-3. We set up informal &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/DotA2/comments/3s9zet/what_is_a_scrim/&quot;&gt;scrims&lt;/a&gt; with teams 4 &amp;amp; 5, expecting to lose soundly, but OpenAI Five won two of its first three games versus both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.openai.com/content/images/2018/06/195A8963_cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;195A8963_cropped&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The teamwork aspect of the bot was just overwhelming. It feels like five selfless players that know a good general strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Blitz&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We observed that OpenAI Five:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Repeatedly sacrificed its own &lt;a href=&quot;https://dota2.gamepedia.com/Lane&quot;&gt;safe lane&lt;/a&gt; (top lane for dire; bottom lane for radiant) in exchange for controlling the enemy's safe lane, forcing the fight onto the side that is harder for their opponent to defend. This strategy emerged in the professional scene in the last few years, and is now considered to be the prevailing tactic. Blitz commented that he only learned this after eight years of play, when &lt;a href=&quot;https://liquipedia.net/dota2/Team_Liquid&quot;&gt;Team Liquid&lt;/a&gt; told him about it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;Dota-Minigraph&quot; src=&quot;https://blog.openai.com/content/images/2018/06/ganking-2.gif&quot;/&gt;Pushed the &lt;a href=&quot;https://purgegamers.true.io/purge/phases-of-the-game/&quot;&gt;transitions&lt;/a&gt; from early- to mid-game faster than its opponents. It did this by: (1) setting up successful &lt;a href=&quot;https://dota2.gamepedia.com/Ganking&quot;&gt;ganks&lt;/a&gt; (when players move around the map to ambush an enemy hero — see animation) when players overextended in their lane, and (2) by grouping up to take towers before the opponents could organize a counterplay.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deviated from current &lt;a href=&quot;https://liquipedia.net/dota2/Metagame&quot;&gt;playstyle&lt;/a&gt; in a few areas, such as giving &lt;a href=&quot;https://dota2.gamepedia.com/Role#Support&quot;&gt;support&lt;/a&gt; heroes (which usually do not take priority for resources) lots of early experience and gold. OpenAI Five's prioritization allows for its damage to peak sooner and push its advantage harder, winning team fights and capitalizing on mistakes to ensure a fast win.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.openai.com/content/images/2018/06/_H0A3928.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;_H0A3928&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Trophies awarded after the match between the best players at OpenAI and our bot team. One trophy for the humans, one trophy for the bots (represented by Susan Zhang from our team!)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenAI Five is given access to the same information as humans, but instantly sees data like positions, healths, and item inventories that humans have to check manually. Our method isn't fundamentally tied to observing state, but just rendering pixels from the game would require thousands of GPUs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OpenAI Five averages around 150-170 actions per minute (and has a theoretical maximum of 450 due to observing every 4th frame). Frame-perfect timing, while &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/DotA2/comments/493wib/frameperfect_stun_by_swindle_on_enchantress_in_eg/&quot;&gt;possible&lt;/a&gt; for skilled players, is trivial for OpenAI Five. OpenAI Five has an average reaction time of 80ms, which is faster than humans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These differences matter most in 1v1 (where our bot had a reaction time of 67ms), but the playing field is relatively equitable as we've seen humans learn from and adapt to the bot. Dozens of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/DotA2/comments/6yp5ug/black_just_killed_open_ai/&quot;&gt;professionals&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/DotA2/comments/6wqf5x/bulldog_gets_jebaited_hard_by_openai_bot/&quot;&gt;used&lt;/a&gt; our 1v1 bot for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DQ3fPS9345A&quot;&gt;training&lt;/a&gt; in the months after last year's &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_International_(Dota_2)&quot;&gt;TI&lt;/a&gt;. According to Blitz, the 1v1 bot has changed the way people think about 1v1s (the bot adopted a fast-paced playstyle, and everyone has now adapted to keep up).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;Dota-Minigraph&quot; src=&quot;https://blog.openai.com/content/images/2018/06/sparse-vs-dense-small@2x.png&quot; alt=&quot;Sparse vs Dense rewards learning curves, showing dense reaching an equivalent level of performance faster.&quot;/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Binary rewards can give good performance.&lt;/strong&gt; Our 1v1 model had a shaped reward, including rewards for last hits, kills, and the like. We ran an experiment where we only rewarded the agent for winning or losing, and it trained an order of magnitude slower and somewhat plateaued in the middle, in contrast to the smooth learning curves we usually see. The experiment ran on 4,500 cores and 16 k80 GPUs, training to the level of semi-pros (70 &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/TrueSkill&quot;&gt;TrueSkill&lt;/a&gt;) rather than 90 TrueSkill of our best 1v1 bot).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creep blocking can be learned from scratch.&lt;/strong&gt; For 1v1, we learned &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.openai.com/more-on-dota-2/#thetask&quot;&gt;creep blocking&lt;/a&gt; using traditional RL with a &quot;creep block&quot; reward. One of our team members left a 2v2 model training when he went on vacation (proposing to his now wife!), intending to see how much longer training would boost performance. To his surprise, the model had &lt;a href=&quot;https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/openai-assets/dota_2018/cm_creepblock.mp4&quot;&gt;learned to creep block&lt;/a&gt; without any special guidance or reward.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;Dota-Minigraph&quot; src=&quot;https://blog.openai.com/content/images/2018/06/bug-comparison-small@2x.png&quot; alt=&quot;Comparison of learning curves before and after bugfixes, showing how fixing bugs increases learning speed.&quot;/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We're still fixing bugs.&lt;/strong&gt; The chart shows a training run of the code that defeated amateur players, compared to a version where we simply fixed a number of bugs, such as rare crashes during training, or a bug which resulted in a large negative reward for reaching level 25. It turns out it's possible to beat good humans while still hiding serious bugs!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.openai.com/content/images/2018/06/group-laptop.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;group-laptop&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;A subset of the OpenAI Dota team, holding the laptop that &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.openai.com/dota-2/&quot;&gt;defeated&lt;/a&gt; the world's top professionals at Dota 1v1 at The International last year.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our team is focused on making our August goal. We don't know if it will be achievable, but we believe that with hard work (and some luck) we have a real shot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post described a snapshot of our system as of June 6th. We'll release updates along the way to surpassing human performance and write a report on our final system once we complete the project. Please join us on July 28th &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.twitch.tv/openai&quot;&gt;virtually&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/openai-dota-5v5-match-tickets-47144438284&quot;&gt;in person&lt;/a&gt;, when we'll play a team of top players!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our underlying motivation reaches beyond Dota. Real-world AI deployments will need to deal with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.openai.com/openai-five/#theproblem&quot;&gt;challenges&lt;/a&gt; raised by Dota which are not reflected in Chess, Go, Atari games, or Mujoco benchmark tasks. Ultimately, we will measure the success of our Dota system in its application to real-world tasks. If you'd like to be part of what comes next, we're &lt;a href=&quot;https://openai.com/jobs/&quot;&gt;hiring&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;37.850806451613&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] Current set of restrictions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mirror match of &lt;a href=&quot;https://dota2.gamepedia.com/Necrophos&quot;&gt;Necrophos&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://dota2.gamepedia.com/Sniper&quot;&gt;Sniper&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://dota2.gamepedia.com/Viper&quot;&gt;Viper&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://dota2.gamepedia.com/Crystal_Maiden&quot;&gt;Crystal Maiden&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://dota2.gamepedia.com/Lich&quot;&gt;Lich&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;No &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thescoreesports.com/dota2/news/13481-a-basic-guide-to-warding-in-dota-2&quot;&gt;warding&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;No &lt;a href=&quot;https://dota2.gamepedia.com/Roshan&quot;&gt;Roshan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;No &lt;a href=&quot;https://dota2.gamepedia.com/Invisibility&quot;&gt;invisibility&lt;/a&gt; (consumables and relevant items)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;No &lt;a href=&quot;https://dota2.gamepedia.com/Summons&quot;&gt;summons&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://dota2.gamepedia.com/Illusions&quot;&gt;illusions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;No &lt;a href=&quot;https://dota2.gamepedia.com/Divine_Rapier&quot;&gt;Divine Rapier&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://dota2.gamepedia.com/Bottle&quot;&gt;Bottle&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://dota2.gamepedia.com/Quelling_Blade&quot;&gt;Quelling Blade&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://dota2.gamepedia.com/Boots_of_Travel&quot;&gt;Boots of Travel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://dota2.gamepedia.com/Tome_of_Knowledge&quot;&gt;Tome of Knowledge&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://dota2.gamepedia.com/Infused_Raindrop&quot;&gt;Infused Raindrop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;5 invulnerable couriers, no exploiting them by scouting or tanking&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;No &lt;a href=&quot;https://dota2.gamepedia.com/Scan&quot;&gt;Scan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The hero set restriction makes the game very different from how Dota is played at world-elite level (i.e. &lt;a href=&quot;https://dota2.gamepedia.com/Game_modes#Captains_Mode&quot;&gt;Captains Mode&lt;/a&gt; drafting from all 100+ heroes). However, the difference from regular &quot;public&quot; games (&lt;a href=&quot;https://dota2.gamepedia.com/Game_modes#All_Pick&quot;&gt;All Pick&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&quot;https://dota2.gamepedia.com/Game_modes#Random_Draft&quot;&gt;Random Draft&lt;/a&gt;) is smaller.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the restrictions come from remaining aspects of the game we haven't integrated yet. Some restrictions, in particular wards and Roshan, are central components of professional-level play. We're working to add these as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[2] Thanks to the following for feedback on drafts of this post: Alexander Lavin, Andrew Gibiansky, Anna Goldie, Azalia Mirhoseini, Catherine Olsson, David Dohan, David Ha, Denny Britz, Erich Elsen, James Bradbury, John Miller, Luke Metz, Maddie Hall, Miles Brundage, Nelson Elhage, Ofir Nachum, Pieter Abbeel, Rumen Hristov, Shubho Sengupta, Solomon Boulos, Stephen Merity, Tom Brown, Zak Stone&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 14:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>gdb</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>OpenAI Five</og:title>
<og:description>Our team of five neural networks, OpenAI Five, has started to defeat amateur human teams at Dota 2.</og:description>
<og:url>https://blog.openai.com/openai-five/</og:url>
<og:image>https://blog.openai.com/content/images/2018/06/dota-card-2.jpg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.openai.com/openai-five/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Wendelstein 7-X achieves world record</title>
<link>http://www.ipp.mpg.de/4413312/04_18</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.ipp.mpg.de/4413312/04_18</guid>
<description>&lt;h3 class=&quot;subtitle serif&quot;&gt;Stellarator record for fusion product / First confirmation for optimisation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;date&quot;&gt;June 25, 2018&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;summary&quot; readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;In the past experimentation round Wendelstein 7-X achieved higher temperatures and densities of the plasma, longer pulses and the stellarator world record for the fusion product. Moreover, first confirmation for the optimisation concept on which Wendelstein 7-X is based, was obtained. Wendelstein 7-X at Max Planck Institute for Plasma Physics (IPP) in Greifswald, the world’s largest fusion device of the stellarator type, is investigating the suitability of this concept for application in power plants.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;box_image float_left&quot; readability=&quot;7.1010638297872&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;extension_fancybox&quot; href=&quot;http://www.ipp.mpg.de/4411473/original-1529924951.jpg?t=eyJ3aWR0aCI6ODAwLCJoZWlnaHQiOjYwMCwib2JqX2lkIjo0NDExNDczfQ==--19c73166a62651f1cfdefa4a695874fe6d50c2d1&quot; title=&quot; Photo: IPP, Jan Michael Hosan&quot; data-fancybox-group=&quot;extension_image&quot; data-description-id=&quot;extension_image_4411460&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;standard&quot; alt=&quot;View inside the plasma vessel with graphite tile cladding.&quot; src=&quot;http://www.ipp.mpg.de/4411473/original-1529924951.jpg?t=eyJ3aWR0aCI6MjQ2LCJvYmpfaWQiOjQ0MTE0NzN9--7a1571806f0d91ff878fbfe2b325f4daff06b1e7&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;extension_fancybox&quot; href=&quot;http://www.ipp.mpg.de/4411473/original-1529924951.jpg?t=eyJ3aWR0aCI6ODAwLCJoZWlnaHQiOjYwMCwib2JqX2lkIjo0NDExNDczfQ==--19c73166a62651f1cfdefa4a695874fe6d50c2d1&quot; title=&quot; Photo: IPP, Jan Michael Hosan&quot; data-fancybox-group=&quot;extension_image_zoom_icon&quot; data-description-id=&quot;extension_image_4411460&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lens&quot;&gt;Zoom Image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image_description&quot; readability=&quot;12.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;View inside the plasma vessel with graphite tile cladding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;hidden text_for_zoom_and_print&quot; id=&quot;extension_image_4411460&quot; readability=&quot;35&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;View inside the plasma vessel with graphite tile cladding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo: IPP, Jan Michael Hosan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo: IPP, Jan Michael Hosan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike in the first experimentation phase 2015/16, the plasma vessel of Wendelstein 7-X has been fitted with interior cladding since September last year (see &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ipp.mpg.de/4254576/08_17&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PI 8/2017&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). The vessel walls are now covered with graphite tiles, thus allowing higher temperatures and longer plasma discharges. With the so-called divertor it is also possible to control the purity and density of the plasma: The divertor tiles follow the twisted contour of the plasma edge in the form of ten broad strips along the wall of the plasma vessel. In this way, they protect particularly the wall areas onto which the particles escaping from the edge of the plasma ring are made to impinge. Along with impurities, the impinging particles are here neutralised and pumped off.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“First experience with the new wall elements are highly positive”, states Professor Dr. Thomas Sunn Pedersen. While by the end of the first campaign pulse lengths of six seconds were being attained, plasmas lasting up to 26 seconds are now being produced. A heating energy of up to 75 megajoules could be fed into the plasma, this being 18 times as much as in the first operation phase without divertor. The heating power could also be increased, this being a prerequisite to high plasma density.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;box_image float_right&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;extension_fancybox&quot; href=&quot;http://www.ipp.mpg.de/4413357/original-1529924951.jpg?t=eyJ3aWR0aCI6ODAwLCJoZWlnaHQiOjYwMCwib2JqX2lkIjo0NDEzMzU3fQ==--c41587dba2c28e26389d06edf33a8d7b40e78a4a&quot; title=&quot; Graphic: IPP&quot; data-fancybox-group=&quot;extension_image&quot; data-description-id=&quot;extension_image_4413343&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;standard&quot; alt=&quot;Wendelstein 7-X attained the Stellarator world record for the fusion product. This product of the ion temperature, plasma density and energy confinement time specifies how close one is getting to the reactor values needed to ignite a plasma&quot; src=&quot;http://www.ipp.mpg.de/4413357/original-1529924951.jpg?t=eyJ3aWR0aCI6MjQ2LCJvYmpfaWQiOjQ0MTMzNTd9--d4fec2b3dfe9538abd5dd26808f413559c330fd7&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;extension_fancybox&quot; href=&quot;http://www.ipp.mpg.de/4413357/original-1529924951.jpg?t=eyJ3aWR0aCI6ODAwLCJoZWlnaHQiOjYwMCwib2JqX2lkIjo0NDEzMzU3fQ==--c41587dba2c28e26389d06edf33a8d7b40e78a4a&quot; title=&quot; Graphic: IPP&quot; data-fancybox-group=&quot;extension_image_zoom_icon&quot; data-description-id=&quot;extension_image_4413343&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lens&quot;&gt;Zoom Image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image_description&quot; readability=&quot;7.4124513618677&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;hide_in_print&quot; readability=&quot;7.3178137651822&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;toggle hide_with_js&quot; readability=&quot;9.7570850202429&quot;&gt;Wendelstein 7-X attained the Stellarator world record for the fusion product. This product of the ion temperature, plasma density and energy confinement time specifies how close one is getting to the reactor values needed to ignite a plasma &lt;a class=&quot;toggle_description&quot; href=&quot;http://www.ipp.mpg.de/4413312/04_18#&quot;&gt;[less]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;hidden text_for_zoom_and_print&quot; id=&quot;extension_image_4413343&quot; readability=&quot;35&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wendelstein 7-X attained the Stellarator world record for the fusion product. This product of the ion temperature, plasma density and energy confinement time specifies how close one is getting to the reactor values needed to ignite a plasma&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Graphic: IPP&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Graphic: IPP&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this way a record value for the fusion product was attained. This product of the ion temperature, plasma density and energy confinement time specifies how close one is getting to the reactor values needed to ignite a plasma. At an ion temperature of about 40 million degrees and a density of 0.8 x 10&lt;sup&gt;20&lt;/sup&gt; particles per cubic metre Wendelstein 7-X has attained a fusion product affording a good 6 x 10&lt;sup&gt;26&lt;/sup&gt; degrees x second per cubic metre, the world’s stellarator record. “This is an excellent value for a device of this size, achieved, moreover, under realistic conditions, i.e. at a high temperature of the plasma ions”, says Professor Sunn Pedersen. The energy confinement time attained, this being a measure of the quality of the thermal insulation of the magnetically confined plasma, indicates with an imposing 200 milliseconds that the numerical optimisation on which Wendelstein 7-X is based might work: “This makes us optimistic for our further work.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The fact that optimisation is taking effect not only in respect of the thermal insulation is testified to by the now completed evaluation of experimental data from the first experimentation phase from December 2015 to March 2016, which has just been reported in Nature Physics (see below). This shows that also the bootstrap current behaves as expected. This electric current is induced by pressure differences in the plasma and could distort the tailored magnetic field. Particles from the plasma edge would then no longer impinge on the right area of the divertor. The bootstrap current in stellarators should therefore be kept as low as possible. Analysis has now confirmed that this has actually been accomplished in the optimised field geometry. “Thus, already during the first experimentation phase important aspects of the optimisation could be verified”, states first author Dr. Andreas Dinklage. “More exact and systematic evaluation will ensue in further experiments at much higher heating power and higher plasma pressure.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since the end of 2017 Wendelstein 7-X has undergone further extensions: These include new measuring equipment and heating systems. Plasma experiments are to be resumed in July. Major extension is planned as of autumn 2018: The present graphite tiles of the divertor are to be replaced by carbon-reinforced carbon components that are additionally water-cooled. They are to make discharges lasting up to 30 minutes possible, during which it can be checked whether Wendelstein 7-X permanently meets its optimisation objectives as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The objective of fusion research is to develop a power plant favourable to the climate and environment. Like the sun, it is to derive energy from fusion of atomic nuclei. Because the fusion fire needs temperatures exceeding 100 million degrees to ignite, the fuel, viz. a low-density hydrogen plasma, ought not to come into contact with cold vessel walls. Confined by magnetic fields, it is suspended inside a vacuum chamber with almost no contact.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The magnetic cage of Wendelstein 7-X is produced by a ring of 50 superconducting magnet coils about 3.5 metres high. Their special shapes are the result of elaborate optimisation calculations. Although Wendelstein 7-X will not produce energy, it hopes to prove that stellarators are suitable for application in power plants.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Its aim is to achieve for the first time in a stellarator the quality of confinement afforded by competing devices of the tokamak type. In particular, the device is to demonstrate the essential advantage of stellarators, viz. their capability to operate in continuous mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isabella Milch&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Publication:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andreas Dinklage et al.&lt;br /&gt;Magnetic configuration effects on the Wendelstein 7-X stellarator.&lt;br /&gt;In: Nature Physics, 21 May 2018, &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41567-018-0141-9&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;external&quot;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41567-018-0141-9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 13:49:59 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>_fizz_buzz_</dc:creator>
<og:title>Wendelstein 7-X achieves world record</og:title>
<og:description></og:description>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>http://www.ipp.mpg.de/4413312/04_18</og:url>
<og:image>http://www.ipp.mpg.de/4413357/original-1529924951.jpg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.ipp.mpg.de/4413312/04_18</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The NSA’s Hidden Spy Hubs in Eight U.S. Cities</title>
<link>https://theintercept.com/2018/06/25/att-internet-nsa-spy-hubs/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://theintercept.com/2018/06/25/att-internet-nsa-spy-hubs/</guid>
<description>&lt;div data-reactid=&quot;203&quot; readability=&quot;40.797808219178&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-shortcode-type=&quot;dropcap&quot; class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;&lt;u class=&quot;project-y&quot;&gt;he secrets are&lt;/u&gt; hidden behind fortified walls in cities across the United States, inside towering, windowless skyscrapers and fortress-like concrete structures that were built to withstand earthquakes and even nuclear attack. Thousands of people pass by the buildings each day and rarely give them a second glance, because their function is not publicly known. They are an integral part of one of the world’s largest telecommunications networks – and they are also linked to a controversial National Security Agency surveillance program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Atlanta, Chicago, Dallas, Los Angeles, New York City, San Francisco, Seattle, and Washington, D.C. In each of these cities, The Intercept has identified an AT&amp;amp;T facility containing networking equipment that transports large quantities of internet traffic across the United States and the world. A body of evidence – including classified NSA documents, public records, and interviews with several former AT&amp;amp;T employees – indicates that the buildings are central to an NSA spying initiative that has for years monitored billions of emails, phone calls, and online chats passing across U.S. territory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The NSA considers AT&amp;amp;T to be one of its most trusted partners and has lauded the company’s “extreme willingness to help.” It is a collaboration that dates back decades. Little known, however, is that its scope is not restricted to AT&amp;amp;T’s customers. According to the NSA’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.com/document/2018/06/25/fairview-overview-with-notes&quot;&gt;documents&lt;/a&gt;, it values AT&amp;amp;T not only because it “has access to information that transits the nation,” but also because it maintains unique relationships with other phone and internet providers. The NSA exploits these relationships for surveillance purposes, commandeering AT&amp;amp;T’s massive infrastructure and using it as a platform to covertly tap into communications processed by other companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ProjectY-Map&quot; data-reactid=&quot;204&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap align-bleed xtra-large-bleed width-auto ProjectY-Map--map section section--with-background&quot; data-reactid=&quot;254&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;ProjectY-Map--background aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn01.theintercept.com/static/project-y/map.png&quot; data-reactid=&quot;255&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div data-reactid=&quot;256&quot; readability=&quot;201.73358770059&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much has previously been reported about the NSA’s surveillance programs. But few details have been disclosed about the physical infrastructure that enables the spying. Last year, The Intercept &lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.com/2016/11/16/the-nsas-spy-hub-in-new-york-hidden-in-plain-sight/&quot;&gt;highlighted&lt;/a&gt; a likely NSA facility in New York City’s Lower Manhattan. Now, we are revealing for the first time a series of other buildings across the U.S. that appear to serve a similar function, as critical parts of one of the world’s most powerful electronic eavesdropping systems, hidden in plain sight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s eye-opening and ominous the extent to which this is happening right here on American soil,” said Elizabeth Goitein, co-director of the Liberty and National Security Program at the Brennan Center for Justice. “It puts a face on surveillance that we could never think of before in terms of actual buildings and actual facilities in our own cities, in our own backyards.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are hundreds of AT&amp;amp;T-owned properties scattered across the U.S. The eight identified by The Intercept serve a specific function, processing AT&amp;amp;T customers’ data and also carrying large quantities of data from other internet providers. They are known as “backbone” and “peering” facilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;alignnone&quot;&gt;While network operators would usually prefer to send data through their own networks, often a more direct and cost-efficient path is provided by other providers’ infrastructure. If one network in a specific area of the country is overloaded with data traffic, another operator with capacity to spare can sell or exchange bandwidth, reducing the strain on the congested region. This exchange of traffic is called “peering” and is an essential feature of the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of AT&amp;amp;T’s position as one of the U.S.’s leading telecommunications companies, it has a large network that is frequently used by other providers to transport their customers’ data. Companies that “peer” with AT&amp;amp;T include the American telecommunications giants Sprint, Cogent Communications, and Level 3, as well as foreign companies such as Sweden’s Telia, India’s Tata Communications, Italy’s Telecom Italia, and Germany’s Deutsche Telekom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AT&amp;amp;T currently boasts 19,500 &lt;a class=&quot;project-y&quot; data-tooltip=&quot;An access point that connects to the internet, located inside a facility that contains routers, servers, and other networking equipment.&quot;&gt;“points of presence”&lt;/a&gt; in 149 countries where internet traffic is exchanged. But only eight of the company’s facilities in the U.S. offer direct access to its “common backbone” – key data routes that carry vast amounts of emails, internet chats, social media updates, and internet browsing sessions. These eight locations are among the most important in AT&amp;amp;T’s global network. They are also highly valued by the NSA, documents indicate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data exchange between AT&amp;amp;T and other networks initially takes place outside AT&amp;amp;T’s control, sources said, at third-party data centers that are owned and operated by companies such as California’s Equinix. But the data is then routed – in whole or in part – through the eight AT&amp;amp;T buildings, where the NSA taps into it. By monitoring what it calls the “peering circuits” at the eight sites, the spy agency can collect “not only AT&amp;amp;T’s data, they get all the data that’s interchanged between AT&amp;amp;T’s network and other companies,” according to Mark Klein, a former AT&amp;amp;T technician who worked with the company for 22 years. It is an efficient point to conduct internet surveillance, Klein said, “because the peering links, by the nature of the connections, are liable to carry everybody’s traffic at one point or another during the day, or the week, or the year.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christopher Augustine, a spokesperson for the NSA, said in a statement that the agency could “neither confirm nor deny its role in alleged classified intelligence activities.” Augustine declined to answer questions about the AT&amp;amp;T facilities, but said that the NSA “conducts its foreign signals intelligence mission under the legal authorities established by Congress and is bound by both policy and law to protect U.S. persons’ privacy and civil liberties.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jim Greer, an AT&amp;amp;T spokesperson, said that AT&amp;amp;T was “required by law to provide information to government and law enforcement entities by complying with court orders, subpoenas, lawful discovery requests, and other legal requirements.” He added that the company provides “voluntary assistance to law enforcement when a person’s life is in danger and in other immediate, emergency situations. In all cases, we ensure that requests for assistance are valid and that we act in compliance with the law.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dave Schaeffer, CEO of Cogent Communications, told The Intercept that he had no knowledge of the surveillance at the eight AT&amp;amp;T buildings, but said he believed “the core premise that the NSA or some other agency would like to look at traffic … at an AT&amp;amp;T facility.” He said he suspected that the surveillance is likely carried out on “a limited basis,” due to technical and cost constraints. If the NSA were trying to “ubiquitously monitor” data passing across AT&amp;amp;T’s networks, Schaeffer added, he would be “extremely concerned.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sprint, Telia, Tata Communications, Telecom Italia, and Deutsche Telekom did not respond to requests for comment. CenturyLink, which owns Level 3, said it would not discuss “matters of national security.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap align-bleed xtra-large-bleed width-auto&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-194677&quot; src=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/06/map-gifs-4-1529435205.gif?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&quot; alt=&quot;map-gifs-4-1529435205&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;caption overlayed&quot;&gt;The maps The Intercept used to identify the internet surveillance hubs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption source pullright&quot;&gt;Maps: NSA/AT&amp;amp;T&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-shortcode-type=&quot;dropcap&quot; class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;&lt;u class=&quot;project-y&quot;&gt;he eight locations&lt;/u&gt; are featured on a top-secret NSA map, which depicts U.S. facilities that the agency relies upon for one of its largest surveillance programs, code-named &lt;a class=&quot;project-y&quot; data-tooltip=&quot;An NSA surveillance program that collects communications from AT&amp;amp;T's networks.&quot;&gt;FAIRVIEW&lt;/a&gt;. AT&amp;amp;T is the only company involved in FAIRVIEW, which was first established in 1985, according to NSA documents, and involves tapping into international telecommunications cables, routers, and switches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2003, the NSA launched new internet mass surveillance methods, which were pioneered under the FAIRVIEW program. The methods were used by the agency to collect – within a few months – some 400 billion records about people’s internet communications and activity, the New York Times &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2015/08/16/us/politics/att-helped-nsa-spy-on-an-array-of-internet-traffic.html&quot;&gt;previously reported&lt;/a&gt;. FAIRVIEW was also forwarding more than 1 million emails every day to a “keyword selection system” at the NSA’s Fort Meade headquarters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Central to the internet spying are eight “peering link router complex” sites, which are pinpointed on the top-secret NSA map. The locations of the sites mirror maps of AT&amp;amp;T’s networks, obtained by The Intercept from public records, which show “backbone node with peering” facilities in Atlanta, Chicago, Dallas, Los Angeles, New York City, San Francisco, Seattle, and Washington, D.C.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the AT&amp;amp;T maps contains unique codes individually identifying the addresses of the facilities in each of the cities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the pinpointed buildings, there is a nuclear blast-resistant, windowless facility in New York City’s Hell’s Kitchen neighborhood; in Washington, D.C., a fortress-like, concrete structure less than half a mile south of the U.S. Capitol; in Chicago, an earthquake-resistant skyscraper in the West Loop Gate area; in Atlanta, a 429-foot art deco structure in the heart of the city’s downtown district; and in Dallas, a cube-like building with narrow windows and large vents on its exterior, located in the Old East district.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elsewhere, on the west coast of the U.S., there are three more facilities: in downtown Los Angeles, a striking concrete tower near the Walt Disney Concert Hall and the Staples Center, two blocks from the most important internet exchange in the region; in Seattle, a 15-story building with blacked-out windows and reinforced concrete foundations, near the city’s waterfront; and in San Francisco’s South of Market neighborhood, a building where it was previously claimed that the NSA was monitoring internet traffic from a secure room on the sixth floor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The peering sites – otherwise known in AT&amp;amp;T parlance as &lt;a class=&quot;project-y&quot; data-tooltip=&quot;Major AT&amp;amp;T internet hubs.&quot;&gt;“Service Node Routing Complexes,”&lt;/a&gt; or SNRCs – were developed following the internet boom in the mid- to late 1990s. By March 2009, the NSA’s documents say it was tapping into “peering circuits at the eight SNRCs.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The facilities’ purpose was to bolster AT&amp;amp;T’s network, improving its reliability and enabling future growth. They were developed under the leadership of an Iranian-American innovator and engineer named Hossein Eslambolchi, who was formerly AT&amp;amp;T’s chief technology officer and president of AT&amp;amp;T Labs, a division of the company that focuses on research and development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eslambolchi told The Intercept that the project to set up the facilities began after AT&amp;amp;T asked him to help create “the largest internet protocol network in the world.” He obliged and began implementing his network design by placing large Cisco routers inside former AT&amp;amp;T phone switching facilities across the U.S. When planning the project, he said he divided AT&amp;amp;T’s network into different regions, “and in every quadrant I will have what I will call an SNRC.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div data-reactid=&quot;263&quot; readability=&quot;194.31941881919&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During his employment with AT&amp;amp;T, Eslambolchi said he had to take a polygraph test, and he obtained a government security clearance. “I was involved in very, very top, heavy-duty projects for a few of these three-letter agencies,” he said, in an apparent reference to U.S. intelligence agencies. “They all loved me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He would not confirm or deny the exact locations of the eight peering sites identified by The Intercept or discuss the classified work he carried out while with the company. “You put a gun to my head,” he said, “I’m not going to tell you.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other former AT&amp;amp;T employees, however, were more forthcoming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A former senior member of AT&amp;amp;T’s technical staff, who spoke on condition of anonymity due to the sensitivity of the subject, confirmed with “100 percent” certainty the locations of six of the eight peering facilities identified by The Intercept. The source, citing direct knowledge of the facilities and their function, verified the addresses of the buildings in Atlanta, Dallas, Los Angeles, New York City, Seattle, and Washington, D.C.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A second former AT&amp;amp;T employee confirmed the locations of the remaining two sites, in Chicago and San Francisco. “I worked with all of them,” said Philip Long, who was employed by AT&amp;amp;T for more than two decades as a technician servicing its networks. Long’s work with AT&amp;amp;T was carried out mostly in California, but he said his job required him to be in contact with the company’s other facilities across the U.S. In about 2005, Long recalled, he received orders to move “every internet backbone circuit I had in northern California” through the San Francisco AT&amp;amp;T building identified by The Intercept as one of the eight NSA spy hubs. Long said that, at the time, he felt suspicious of the changes, because they were unusual and unnecessary. “We thought we were routing our circuits so that they could grab all the data,” he said. “We thought it was the government listening.” He retired from his job with AT&amp;amp;T in 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A third former AT&amp;amp;T employee reviewed The Intercept’s research and said he believed it accurately identified all eight of the facilities. “The site data certainly seems correct,” said Thomas Saunders, who worked as a data networking consultant for AT&amp;amp;T in New York City between 1995 and 2004. “Those nodes aren’t going to move.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap align-bleed full-bleed width-auto&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-193722&quot; src=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/06/building-5-1528987907.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&quot; alt=&quot;building-5-1528987907&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;caption source pullright&quot;&gt;Photo: Henrik Moltke&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span data-shortcode-type=&quot;dropcap&quot; class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;A&lt;/span&gt;&lt;u class=&quot;project-y&quot;&gt;n estimated 99 percent&lt;/u&gt; of the world’s intercontinental internet traffic is transported through hundreds of giant fiber optic cables hidden beneath the world’s oceans. A large portion of the data and communications that pass across the cables is routed at one point through the U.S., partly because of the country’s location – situated between Europe, the Middle East, and Asia – and partly because of the pre-eminence of American internet companies, which provide services to people globally.
&lt;p&gt;The NSA calls this predicament “home field advantage” – a kind of geographic good fortune. “A target’s phone call, email, or chat will take the cheapest path, not the physically most direct path,” one agency document &lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/06/direct-path-1529876697.png?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&quot;&gt;explains&lt;/a&gt;. “Your target’s communications could easily be flowing into and through the U.S.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the internet traffic arrives on U.S. soil, it is processed by American companies. And that is why, for the NSA, AT&amp;amp;T is so indispensable. The company claims it has one of the world’s most powerful networks, the largest of its kind in the U.S. AT&amp;amp;T routinely handles masses of emails, phone calls, and internet chats. As of March 2018, some 197 petabytes of data – the equivalent of more than 49 trillion pages of text, or 60 billion average-sized mp3 files – traveled across its networks every business day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The NSA documents, which come from the trove provided to The Intercept by the whistleblower Edward Snowden, describe AT&amp;amp;T as having been “aggressively involved” in aiding the agency’s surveillance programs. One example of this appears to have taken place at the eight facilities under a classified initiative called &lt;a class=&quot;project-y&quot; data-tooltip=&quot;An NSA surveillance operation that monitors internet data inside AT&amp;amp;T facilities.&quot;&gt;SAGUARO&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of SAGUARO, AT&amp;amp;T developed a strategy to help the NSA electronically eavesdrop on internet data from the “peering circuits” at the eight sites, which were said to connect to the “common backbone,” major data routes carrying internet traffic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company worked with the NSA to rank communications flowing through its networks on the basis of intelligence value, prioritizing data depending on which country it was derived from, according to a top-secret &lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.com/document/2018/06/25/sso-dictionary-relevant-entries&quot;&gt;agency document&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap align-center width-fixed&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-article-large wp-image-192005&quot; src=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/06/diagram-5-1528310650.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&amp;amp;w=1000&amp;amp;h=758&quot; alt=&quot;diagram-5-1528310650&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;caption source&quot;&gt;Graphic: NSA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NSA &lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.com/document/2016/11/16/fairview-dataflow-charts-apr-2012/&quot;&gt;diagrams&lt;/a&gt; reveal that after it collects data from AT&amp;amp;T’s “access links” and “peering partners,” it is sent to a “centralized processing facility” code-named &lt;a class=&quot;project-y&quot; data-tooltip=&quot;A New Jersey facility where AT&amp;amp;T data is processed and sent to the NSA.&quot;&gt;PINECONE&lt;/a&gt;, located somewhere in New Jersey. Inside the PINECONE facility, there is a secure space in which there is both NSA-controlled and AT&amp;amp;T-controlled equipment. Internet traffic passes through an AT&amp;amp;T “distribution box” to two NSA systems. From there, the data is then transferred about 200 miles southwest to its final destination: NSA headquarters at Fort Meade in Maryland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the Maryland compound, the communications collected from AT&amp;amp;T’s networks are integrated into powerful systems called &lt;a class=&quot;project-y&quot; data-tooltip=&quot;An NSA database used to store and analyze records of phone communications, including cellphone, landline and internet-based Voice Over IP calls.&quot;&gt;MAINWAY&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&quot;project-y&quot; data-tooltip=&quot;An NSA database used to store and analyze internet metadata, including records about email correspondence.&quot;&gt;MARINA&lt;/a&gt;, which the NSA uses to analyze metadata – such as the “to” and “from” parts of emails, and the times and dates they were sent. The communications obtained from AT&amp;amp;T are also made accessible through a tool named &lt;a class=&quot;project-y&quot; data-tooltip=&quot;A Google-like system NSA uses to search through the full written contents of internet communications, such as the bodies of emails.&quot;&gt;XKEYSCORE&lt;/a&gt;, which NSA employees use to search through the full contents of emails, instant messenger chats, web-browsing histories, webcam photos, information about downloads from online services, and Skype sessions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap align-bleed full-bleed width-auto&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-195641&quot; src=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/06/grid-combine-01-1529695390.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&amp;amp;w=1024&amp;amp;h=647&quot; alt=&quot;grid-combine-01-1529695390&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;caption source pullright&quot;&gt;Top left / right: Mike Osborne. Bottom left: Henrik Moltke. Bottom right: Frank Heath.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-shortcode-type=&quot;dropcap&quot; class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;&lt;u class=&quot;project-y&quot;&gt;he NSA’s primary&lt;/u&gt; mission is to gather foreign intelligence. The agency has broad legal powers to monitor emails, phone calls, and other forms of correspondence as they are being transported across the U.S., and it can compel companies such as AT&amp;amp;T to install surveillance equipment within their networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under a Ronald Reagan-era presidential directive – &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dni.gov/index.php/ic-legal-reference-book/executive-order-12333&quot;&gt;Executive Order 12333&lt;/a&gt; – the NSA has what it calls “transit authority,” which it says enables it to eavesdrop on “communications which originate and terminate in foreign countries, but traverse U.S. territory.” That could include, for example, an email sent by a person in France to a person in Mexico, which on its way to its destination was routed through a server in California. According to the NSA’s documents, it was using AT&amp;amp;T’s networks as of March 2013 to gather some 60 million foreign-to-foreign emails every day, 1.8 billion per month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without an individualized court order, it is illegal for the NSA to spy on communications that are wholly domestic, such as emails sent back and forth between two Americans living in Texas. However, in the aftermath of the 9/11 attacks, the agency began eavesdropping on Americans’ international calls and emails that were passing between the U.S. and other countries. That practice was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2005/12/16/politics/bush-lets-us-spy-on-callers-without-courts.html&quot;&gt;exposed by the New York Times&lt;/a&gt; in 2005 and triggered what became known as the “warrantless wiretapping” scandal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Critics argued that the surveillance of Americans’ international communications was illegal, because the NSA had carried it out without obtaining warrants from a judge and had instead acted on the orders of President George W. Bush. In 2008, Congress weighed into the dispute and controversially authorized elements of the warrantless wiretapping program by enacting Section 702 of the Foreign Intelligence and Surveillance Act, or FISA. The new law allowed the NSA to continue sweeping up Americans’ international communications without a warrant, so long as it did so “incidentally” while it was targeting foreigners overseas – for instance, if it was monitoring people in Pakistan, and they were talking with Americans in the U.S. by phone, email, or through an internet chat service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within AT&amp;amp;T’s networks, there is filtering equipment designed to separate foreign and domestic internet data before it is passed to the NSA, the agency’s documents show. Filtering technology is often used by internet providers for security reasons, enabling them to keep tabs on problems with their networks, block out spam, or monitor hacking attacks. But the same tools can be used for government surveillance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You can essentially trick the routers into redirecting a small subset of traffic you really care about, which you can monitor in more detail,” said Jennifer Rexford, a computer scientist who worked for AT&amp;amp;T Labs between 1996 and 2005.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div data-reactid=&quot;270&quot; readability=&quot;79.123433345993&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the NSA’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.com/document/2018/06/25/sso-news-relevant-entries/&quot;&gt;documents&lt;/a&gt;, it programs its surveillance systems to focus on particular IP addresses – a set of numbers that identify a computer – associated with foreign countries. A classified 2012 memo describes the agency’s efforts to use IP addresses to home in on internet data passing between the U.S. and particular “regions of interest,” including Iran, Afghanistan, Israel, Nigeria, Pakistan, Yemen, Sudan, Tunisia, Libya, and Egypt. But this process is not an exact science, as people can use privacy or anonymity tools to change or spoof their IP addresses. A person in Israel could use privacy software to masquerade as if they were accessing the internet in the U.S. Likewise, an internet user in the U.S. could make it appear as if they were online in Israel. It is unclear how effective the NSA’s systems are at detecting such anomalies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In October 2011, the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court, which approves the surveillance operations carried out under Section 702 of FISA, found that there were “technological limitations” with the agency’s internet eavesdropping equipment. It was “generally incapable of distinguishing” between some kinds of data, the court stated. As a consequence, Judge John D. Bates &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/4522989-Fisc-Opinion-Oct-2011.html&quot;&gt;ruled&lt;/a&gt;, the NSA had been intercepting the communications of “non-target United States persons and persons in the United States,” violating Fourth Amendment protections against unreasonable searches and seizures. The ruling, which was declassified in August 2013, concluded that the agency had acquired some 13 million “internet transactions” during one six-month period, and had unlawfully gathered “tens of thousands of wholly domestic communications” each year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The root of the issue was that the NSA’s technology was not only targeting communications sent to and from specific surveillance targets. Instead, the agency was sweeping up people’s emails if they had merely mentioned particular information &lt;em&gt;about&lt;/em&gt; surveillance targets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.com/document/2018/06/25/faa702-comms-memo&quot;&gt;top-secret NSA memo&lt;/a&gt; about the court’s ruling, which has not been disclosed before, explained that the agency was collecting people’s messages en masse if a single one were found to contain a “selector” – like an email address or phone number – that featured on a target list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“One example of this is when a user of a webmail service accesses her inbox; if the inbox contains one email message that contains an NSA tasked selector, NSA will acquire a copy of the entire inbox, not just the individual email message that contains the tasked selector,” the memo stated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The court’s ruling left the agency with two options: shut down the spying based on mentions of targets completely, or ensure that protections were put in place to stop the unlawfully collected communications from being reviewed. The NSA chose the latter option, and created a “cautionary banner” that warned its analysts not to read particular messages unless they could confirm that they had been lawfully obtained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the cautionary banner did not solve the problem. The NSA’s analysts continued to access the same data repositories to search, unlawfully, for information on Americans. In April 2017, the agency &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nsa.gov/news-features/press-room/statements/2017-04-28-702-statement.shtml&quot;&gt;publicly acknowledged&lt;/a&gt; these violations, which it described as “inadvertent compliance incidents.” It said that it would no longer use surveillance programs authorized under Section 702 of FISA to harvest messages that mentioned its targets, citing “technological constraints, United States person privacy interests, and certain difficulties in implementation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The messages that the NSA had unlawfully collected were swept up using a method of surveillance known as “upstream,” which the agency still deploys for other surveillance programs authorized under both Section 702 of FISA and Executive Order 12333. The upstream method involves tapping into communications as they are passing across internet networks – precisely the kind of electronic eavesdropping that appears to have taken place at the eight locations identified by The Intercept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;section section--with-background&quot; data-shortcode-type=&quot;section&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap align-bleed full-bleed width-auto&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-195107&quot; src=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/06/DSC5709-SH-edit-1529525114.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&quot; alt=&quot;DSC5709-SH-edit-1529525114&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;caption source pullright&quot;&gt;Photo: Frank Heath&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;columns columns--2-to-3&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;columns&quot; data-style=&quot;2:3&quot; readability=&quot;12.565406976744&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;column&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;atlanta&quot; class=&quot;chapter project-y&quot;&gt;Atlanta 51 Peachtree Center Avenue&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap align-center width-fixed&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-pez-640 wp-image-192011&quot; src=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/06/atlanta-1528311471.png?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;column&quot; readability=&quot;20.260336906585&quot;&gt;The AT&amp;amp;T building in Atlanta was originally constructed in the 1920s as the main telephone exchange for the city’s downtown area. The art deco structure, made of limestone, was designed to be the largest in the city at the time at 25 stories tall. However, due to the Great Depression, plans were scaled back and at first, it only had six stories. Between 1947 and 1963, the building was upgraded to host 14 stories, and a large brown microwave tower – visible for miles – was also added. A profile of the building on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://historyatlanta.com/southern-bell-telephone-company-building&quot;&gt;History Atlanta website&lt;/a&gt; notes that it contains “operations, phone exchanges and other communications equipment for AT&amp;amp;T.”&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap align-center width-fixed&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/06/building-2-1528303742.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-191908&quot; src=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/06/building-2-1528303742.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&amp;amp;w=1024&amp;amp;h=683&quot; alt=&quot;building-2-1528303742&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption source&quot;&gt;Photo: Frank Heath&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;columns columns--2-to-3&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;columns&quot; data-style=&quot;2:3&quot; readability=&quot;9.010989010989&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;column&quot; readability=&quot;13.516483516484&quot;&gt;NSA and AT&amp;amp;T maps point to the Atlanta facility as being one of eight “peering” hubs that process internet traffic as part of the NSA surveillance program code-named &lt;a class=&quot;project-y&quot; data-tooltip=&quot;An NSA surveillance program that collects communications from AT&amp;amp;T's networks.&quot;&gt;FAIRVIEW&lt;/a&gt;. One former AT&amp;amp;T employee – who spoke on condition of anonymity – confirmed that the site was one of eight primary AT&amp;amp;T &lt;a class=&quot;project-y&quot; data-tooltip=&quot;Major AT&amp;amp;T internet hubs.&quot;&gt;“Service Node Routing Complexes,”&lt;/a&gt; or SNRCs, in the U.S. NSA documents explicitly describe tapping into flows of data at all eight of these sites.

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div data-reactid=&quot;277&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section section--with-background&quot; data-shortcode-type=&quot;section&quot; readability=&quot;7.3394077448747&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;columns columns--2-to-3&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;columns&quot; data-style=&quot;2:3&quot; readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;column&quot; readability=&quot;25&quot;&gt;Information provided by a second former AT&amp;amp;T employee adds to the evidence linking the Atlanta building to NSA surveillance. Mark Klein, a former AT&amp;amp;T technician, alleged in 2006 that the company had allowed the NSA to install surveillance equipment in some of its network hubs. An AT&amp;amp;T facility in Atlanta was one of the spy sites, according to documents Klein presented in a court case over the alleged spying. The Atlanta facility was equipped with “splitter” equipment, which was used to make copies of internet traffic as AT&amp;amp;T’s networks processed it. The copied data would then be diverted to “SG3” equipment – a reference to “Study Group 3” – which was a code name AT&amp;amp;T used for activities related to NSA surveillance, according to evidence in the Klein case.
&lt;p&gt;The Atlanta facility is likely of strategic importance for the NSA. The site is the closest major AT&amp;amp;T internet routing center to Miami, according to the NSA and AT&amp;amp;T maps. From undersea cables that come aground at Miami, huge flows of data pass between the U.S. and South America. It is probable that much of that data is routed through the Atlanta facility as it is being sent to and from the U.S. In recent years, the NSA has extensively targeted several Latin American countries – such as Mexico, Brazil, and Venezuela – for surveillance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap align-bleed full-bleed width-auto&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-194129&quot; src=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/06/026V2098-1529092644.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&quot; alt=&quot;026V2098-1529092644&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;caption source pullright&quot;&gt;Photo: Henrik Moltke&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;columns columns--reverse columns--3-to-2&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;columns&quot; data-style=&quot;3:2&quot; readability=&quot;14.916897506925&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;column&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;chicago&quot; class=&quot;chapter project-y&quot;&gt;Chicago 10 South Canal Street&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap align-center width-fixed&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-pez-640 wp-image-192050&quot; src=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/06/chicago-1528315510.png?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;column&quot; readability=&quot;24.85549132948&quot;&gt;Like many other major telecommunications hubs built during the late 1960s and early 1970s, the Chicago AT&amp;amp;T building was designed amid the Cold War to withstand a nuclear attack. The 538-foot skyscraper, located in the West Loop Gate area of the city, was completed in 1971. There are windows at both the top and bottom of the vast concrete structure, but 18 of its 28 floors are windowless.
&lt;p&gt;According to the Chicago Sun-Times, the facility handles much of the city’s phone and internet traffic and is equipped with banks of routers, servers, and switching systems. “This building touches every single resident of the city,” Jim Wilson, an AT&amp;amp;T area manager, &lt;a href=&quot;https://chicago.suntimes.com/columnists/steinberg-the-technology-has-changed-quite-a-bit/&quot;&gt;told&lt;/a&gt; the newspaper in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap align-center width-fixed&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-194130&quot; src=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/06/026V2228-1529092700.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&amp;amp;w=1024&amp;amp;h=682&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;caption source&quot;&gt;Photo: Henrik Moltke&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;columns columns--reverse columns--3-to-2&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;columns&quot; data-style=&quot;3:2&quot; readability=&quot;15.25429326288&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;column&quot; readability=&quot;25.58784676354&quot;&gt;One of the building’s architects, John Augur Holabird, &lt;a href=&quot;http://digital-libraries.saic.edu/cdm/singleitem/collection/caohp/id/26362/rec/1&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; in a 1998 interview that it housed “a big switchboard.” He added: “In case the atomic bomb hits Milwaukee, you’ll be happy to know your telephone line will still go through even though the rest of us are wiped out. And that’s what that building was for.”
&lt;p&gt;10 South Canal Street originally contained a million-gallon oil tank, turbine generators, and a water well, so that it could continue to function for more than two weeks without electricity or water from the city, according to Illinois broadcaster WBEZ. The building is “anchored in bedrock, which helps support the weight of the equipment inside, and gives it extra resistance to bomb blasts or earthquakes,” WBEZ &lt;a href=&quot;http://wglt.org/post/hidden-plain-sight-inside-downtown-chicagos-windowless-doorless-buildings&quot;&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;columns columns--reverse columns--3-to-2&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;columns&quot; data-style=&quot;3:2&quot; readability=&quot;14.437817258883&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;column&quot; readability=&quot;24.218274111675&quot;&gt;Today, the facility contains six large V-16 yellow Caterpillar generators that can provide backup electricity in the event of a power failure, &lt;a href=&quot;https://chicago.suntimes.com/columnists/steinberg-the-technology-has-changed-quite-a-bit/&quot;&gt;according&lt;/a&gt; to the Chicago Sun Times. Inside the skyscraper, AT&amp;amp;T stores some 200,000 gallons of diesel fuel, enough to run the generators for 40 days.
&lt;p&gt;NSA and AT&amp;amp;T maps point to the Chicago facility as being one of the “peering” hubs, which process internet traffic as part of the NSA surveillance program code-named &lt;a class=&quot;project-y&quot; data-tooltip=&quot;an NSA surveillance program that collects communications from AT&amp;amp;T's networks.&quot;&gt;FAIRVIEW&lt;/a&gt;. Philip Long, who was employed by AT&amp;amp;T for more than two decades as a technician servicing its networks, confirmed that the Chicago site was one of eight primary AT&amp;amp;T &lt;a class=&quot;project-y&quot; data-tooltip=&quot;Major AT&amp;amp;T internet hubs.&quot;&gt;“Service Node Routing Complexes,”&lt;/a&gt; or SNRCs, in the U.S. NSA documents explicitly describe tapping into flows of data at all eight of these sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap align-bleed full-bleed width-fixed&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/06/building-6-1528303991.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-191914&quot; src=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/06/building-6-1528303991.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&quot; alt=&quot;building-6-1528303991&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption source pullright&quot;&gt;Photo: Mike Osborne&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;columns columns--2-to-3&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;columns&quot; data-style=&quot;2:3&quot; readability=&quot;13.905787348587&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;column&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;dallas&quot; class=&quot;chapter project-y&quot;&gt;Dallas 4211 Bryan Street&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap align-center width-fixed&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-pez-640 wp-image-192051&quot; src=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/06/dallas-1528315541.png?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;column&quot; readability=&quot;22.839832869081&quot;&gt;This AT&amp;amp;T building is a fortified, cube-like structure, located in the Old East area of Dallas, not far from Baylor University Medical Center. Built in 1961, it is a light yellow-brown color with a granite foundation. Large vents are visible on the exterior of the building, as are several narrow windows, many of which appear to have been blacked out or covered in a reflective privacy glass.
&lt;p&gt;The 4211 Bryan Street facility is located next to other AT&amp;amp;T-owned buildings, including a towering telephone routing complex that was first built in 1904. A &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dallasobserver.com/arts/is-this-the-fugliest-building-in-dallas-7087129&quot;&gt;piece&lt;/a&gt; about the telephone hub in the Dallas Observer described it as “an imposing, creepy building” that is “known in some circles as The Great Wall of Beige.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap align-center width-fixed&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/06/building-7-1528304068.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-191915&quot; src=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/06/building-7-1528304068.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&amp;amp;w=1024&amp;amp;h=640&quot; alt=&quot;building-7-1528304068&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption source&quot;&gt;Photo: Mike Osborne&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;columns columns--2-to-3&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;columns&quot; data-style=&quot;2:3&quot; readability=&quot;16.372366790582&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;column&quot; readability=&quot;28.066914498141&quot;&gt;According to the Central Office &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thecentraloffice.com/texas/dallas%20tandem/dalltandem.htm&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;, which profiles telecommunications buildings across the U.S., the Dallas telephone hub is “the main regional tandem and AT&amp;amp;T for long distance and toll services in the Dallas Texas region.” Today, the building also has “major fiber connections to Plano, Irving, Tulsa, Oklahoma City, Ft. Worth, Abilene, Houston and Austin,” the website adds.
&lt;p&gt;NSA and AT&amp;amp;T maps point to the 4211 Bryan Street facility as being one of the “peering” hubs, which process internet traffic as part of the NSA surveillance program code-named &lt;a class=&quot;project-y&quot; data-tooltip=&quot;An NSA surveillance program that collects communications from AT&amp;amp;T's networks.&quot;&gt;FAIRVIEW&lt;/a&gt;. A former AT&amp;amp;T employee confirmed that the site was one of eight primary AT&amp;amp;T &lt;a class=&quot;project-y&quot; data-tooltip=&quot;Major AT&amp;amp;T internet hubs.&quot;&gt;“Service Node Routing Complexes,”&lt;/a&gt; or SNRCs, in the U.S. NSA documents explicitly describe tapping into flows of data at all eight of these sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap align-bleed full-bleed width-auto&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/06/building-8-1528304243.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-191917&quot; src=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/06/building-8-1528304243.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&quot; alt=&quot;building-8-1528304243&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption source pullright&quot;&gt;Photo: Henrik Moltke&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;columns columns--reverse columns--3-to-2&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;columns&quot; data-style=&quot;3:2&quot; readability=&quot;11.267004341534&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;column&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;losangeles&quot; class=&quot;chapter project-y&quot;&gt;Los Angeles 420 South Grand Avenue&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap align-center width-fixed&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-pez-640 wp-image-192052&quot; src=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/06/la-1528315561.png?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;column&quot; readability=&quot;17.615853658537&quot;&gt;At the time of its construction in 1961, the AT&amp;amp;T building known as the Madison Complex was the tallest building in downtown Los Angeles. It has since been dwarfed by a number of corporate office skyscrapers in the surrounding Financial District.
&lt;p&gt;Located between Chinatown and the Staples Center, the fortress-like structure is one of the largest telephone central offices in the U.S. “The theoretical number of telephone lines that can be served from this office are 1.3 million and this office also serves as a foreign exchange carrier to neighboring area codes,” according to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thecentraloffice.com/calif/la/madison/lamadison.htm&quot;&gt;Central Office&lt;/a&gt;, a website that profiles U.S. telecommunications hubs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap align-center width-fixed&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/06/building-9-1528304318.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-191919&quot; src=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/06/building-9-1528304318.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&amp;amp;w=1024&amp;amp;h=682&quot; alt=&quot;building-9-1528304318&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;“Untitled, or Bell Communications Around the Globe”. Mural by Anthony Heinsbergen (1961) on the West side of 420 South Grand Ave, La.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption source&quot;&gt;Photo: Henrik Moltke&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;columns columns--reverse columns--3-to-2&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;columns&quot; data-style=&quot;3:2&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;column&quot; readability=&quot;17&quot;&gt;The 448-foot, 17-story building is beige, rectangular, and mostly windowless. On its roof, there is a large microwave tower, which was originally used to transmit phone calls across a network of antennae. The tower’s technology became obsolete in the early 1990s, and it ceased to operate. It remains in place today as a sort of monument to outdated methods of communication and stands in contrast to the more modern buildings in the vicinity, many of them owned by banks.

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div data-reactid=&quot;284&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section section--with-background&quot; data-shortcode-type=&quot;section&quot; readability=&quot;8.1535662299854&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;columns columns--3-to-2&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;columns&quot; data-style=&quot;3:2&quot; readability=&quot;16.608173076923&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;column&quot; readability=&quot;28.471153846154&quot;&gt;The Madison Complex is located just two blocks from One Wilshire, which houses what is reportedly the most important internet exchange on the U.S. west coast. “Billions of phone calls, emails and internet pages pass through One Wilshire every week,” the Los Angeles Times &lt;a href=&quot;http://articles.latimes.com/2013/jul/18/business/la-fi-0718-property-report-20130718&quot;&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; in 2013, “because it is the primary terminus for major fiber-optic cable routes between Asia and North America.”
&lt;p&gt;Due to the close proximity of the Madison Complex and One Wilshire, and their shared role as telecommunications hubs, it is likely that the buildings process some of the same data as it is being routed across U.S. networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NSA and AT&amp;amp;T maps point to the Madison Complex facility as being one of the “peering” hubs, which process internet traffic as part of the NSA surveillance program code-named &lt;a class=&quot;project-y&quot; data-tooltip=&quot;An NSA surveillance program that collects communications from AT&amp;amp;T's networks.&quot;&gt;FAIRVIEW&lt;/a&gt;. A former AT&amp;amp;T employee confirmed that the site was one of eight primary AT&amp;amp;T &lt;a class=&quot;project-y&quot; data-tooltip=&quot;Major AT&amp;amp;T internet hubs.&quot;&gt;“Service Node Routing Complexes,”&lt;/a&gt; or SNRCs, in the U.S. NSA documents explicitly describe tapping into flows of data at all eight of these sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap align-bleed full-bleed width-auto&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/06/building-10-1528304345.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-191920&quot; src=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/06/building-10-1528304345.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&quot; alt=&quot;building-10-1528304345&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption source pullright&quot;&gt;Photo: Henrik Moltke&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;columns columns--2-to-3&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;columns&quot; data-style=&quot;2:3&quot; readability=&quot;10.868376068376&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;column&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;nyc&quot; class=&quot;chapter project-y&quot;&gt;New York City 811 10th Avenue&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap align-center width-fixed&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-pez-640 wp-image-192053&quot; src=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/06/nyc-1528315583.png?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;column&quot; readability=&quot;16.785585585586&quot;&gt;It was built in 1964 as New York City’s first major telecommunications fortress. The striking concrete and granite AT&amp;amp;T building – located in the Hell’s Kitchen area about a 15-minute walk from Central Park – is 134 meters tall, with 21 floors, each one of them windowless and built to resist a nuclear blast.
&lt;p&gt;A New York Times &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/1975/12/06/archives/when-building-for-future-means-a-step-backward.html&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; published in 1975 noted that 811 10th Avenue was “the first of several windowless equipment buildings to be constructed” in the city, and added that its design initially “caused considerable controversy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap align-center width-fixed&quot; readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/06/building-11-1528304373.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-191921&quot; src=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/06/building-11-1528304373.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&amp;amp;w=1024&amp;amp;h=682&quot; alt=&quot;building-11-1528304373&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Aerial shot of 811 10th street, NYC, ca. 1965.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption source&quot;&gt;Photo: courtesy of Avery Architectural &amp;amp; Fine Arts Library, Columbia University&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;columns columns--2-to-3&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;columns&quot; data-style=&quot;2:3&quot; readability=&quot;11.349813432836&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;column&quot; readability=&quot;17.764925373134&quot;&gt;According to AT&amp;amp;T &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20150226030013/http:/telehouse.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/NY-City-Midtown-Spec-sheet.pdf&quot;&gt;records&lt;/a&gt;, the building is a “hardened telco data center” and was upgraded in 2000 to become an internet data center. Thomas Saunders, a former AT&amp;amp;T engineer, told The Intercept that, in the 1970s, the building was considered to be “the biggest hub for transmission [of communications] in the country.” Saunders also claimed that, had Bush been in Manhattan during the 9/11 attacks, the Secret Service would have taken him to safety inside the AT&amp;amp;T facility. “It’s the strongest building in town,” he said.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap align-center width-fixed&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-194142&quot; src=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/06/026V2356-1529093799.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&amp;amp;w=1024&amp;amp;h=572&quot; alt=&quot;026V2356-1529093799&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;caption source&quot;&gt;Photo: Henrik Moltke&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;columns columns--2-to-3&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;columns&quot; data-style=&quot;2:3&quot; readability=&quot;8.4698795180723&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;column&quot; readability=&quot;12.481927710843&quot;&gt;NSA and AT&amp;amp;T maps indicate that the 10th Avenue facility is one of eight “peering” hubs that process internet traffic as part of the NSA surveillance program code-named &lt;a class=&quot;project-y&quot; data-tooltip=&quot;An NSA surveillance program that collects communications from AT&amp;amp;T's networks.&quot;&gt;FAIRVIEW&lt;/a&gt;. Two former AT&amp;amp;T employees confirmed that the site was one of eight primary AT&amp;amp;T &lt;a class=&quot;project-y&quot; data-tooltip=&quot;Major AT&amp;amp;T internet hubs.&quot;&gt;“Service Node Routing Complexes,”&lt;/a&gt; or SNRCs, in the U.S. NSA documents explicitly describe tapping into flows of data at all eight of these sites.

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div data-reactid=&quot;291&quot; readability=&quot;6.7452926208651&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section section--with-background&quot; data-shortcode-type=&quot;section&quot; readability=&quot;14.683676126009&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;columns columns--2-to-3&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;columns&quot; data-style=&quot;2:3&quot; readability=&quot;12.871287128713&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;column&quot; readability=&quot;20.792079207921&quot;&gt;The design of the building bears some resemblance to another windowless building in New York City – AT&amp;amp;T’s towering skyscraper at 33 Thomas Street in lower Manhattan. As The Intercept &lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.com/2016/11/16/the-nsas-spy-hub-in-new-york-hidden-in-plain-sight/&quot;&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; in 2016, 33 Thomas Street is a major hub for routing international phone calls and appears to contain a secure NSA surveillance room – code-named TITANPOINTE – that has been used to tap into faxes and phone calls.
&lt;p&gt;NSA and AT&amp;amp;T documents indicate that 10th Avenue building serves as the NSA’s internet equivalent of 33 Thomas Street. While the NSA’s surveillance at 33 Thomas Street mainly targets phone calls that pass through the building’s international switching points, at the 10th Avenue site the agency appears to primarily collect emails, online chats, and data from internet browsing sessions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap align-bleed full-bleed width-auto&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-191920&quot; src=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/06/building-13-1528304435.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&quot; alt=&quot;building-13-1528304435&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;caption source pullright&quot;&gt;Photo: Henrik Moltke&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;columns columns--reverse columns--3-to-2&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;columns&quot; data-style=&quot;3:2&quot; readability=&quot;12.322916666667&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;column&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;sanfrancisco&quot; class=&quot;chapter project-y&quot;&gt;San Francisco 611 Folsom Street&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap align-center width-fixed&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-pez-640 wp-image-192054&quot; src=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/06/sf-1528315600.png?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;column&quot; readability=&quot;19.864182692308&quot;&gt;This San Francisco AT&amp;amp;T building has been described as the city’s telecommunications “nerve center.” It is about 256 feet tall, has nine floors, and its exterior is covered in silver-colored panels; there are a series of vents that can be seen at street level, but there are few windows.
&lt;p&gt;NSA and AT&amp;amp;T maps obtained by The Intercept indicate that 611 Folsom Street is one of the eight “peering” hubs in the U.S. that process internet traffic as part of the NSA surveillance program code-named &lt;a class=&quot;project-y&quot; data-tooltip=&quot;An NSA surveillance program that collects communications from AT&amp;amp;T's networks.&quot;&gt;FAIRVIEW&lt;/a&gt;. Philip Long, who was employed by AT&amp;amp;T for more than two decades as a technician servicing its networks, confirmed that the San Francisco site is one of eight primary AT&amp;amp;T &lt;a class=&quot;project-y&quot; data-tooltip=&quot;Major AT&amp;amp;T internet hubs.&quot;&gt;“Service Node Routing Complexes,”&lt;/a&gt; or SNRCs, in the U.S. NSA documents explicitly describe tapping into flows of data at all eight of these sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap align-center width-fixed&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/06/building-14-1528304462.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-191927&quot; src=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/06/building-14-1528304462.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&amp;amp;w=1024&amp;amp;h=682&quot; alt=&quot;building-14-1528304462&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption source&quot;&gt;Photo: Henrik Moltke&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;columns columns--reverse columns--3-to-2&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;columns&quot; data-style=&quot;3:2&quot; readability=&quot;19.5&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;column&quot; readability=&quot;34&quot;&gt;Long recalled that, in the early 2000s, he “moved every internet backbone circuit I had in northern California” through the Folsom Street office. At the time, he said, he and his colleagues found it strange that they were asked to suddenly reroute all of the traffic, because “there was nothing wrong with the services, no facility problems.”
&lt;p&gt;“We were getting orders to move backbones … and it just grabbed me,” said Long. “We thought it was government stuff and that they were being intrusive. We thought we were routing our circuits so that they could grab all the data.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is not the first time the building has been implicated in revelations about electronic eavesdropping. In 2006, an AT&amp;amp;T technician named Mark Klein alleged in a sworn court declaration that the NSA was tapping into internet traffic from a secure room on the sixth floor of the facility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Klein, who worked at 611 Folsom Street between October 2003 and May 2004, stated that employees from the agency had visited the building and recruited one of AT&amp;amp;T’s management level technicians to carry out a “special job.” The job involved installing a “splitter cabinet” that copied internet data as it was flowing into the building, before diverting it into the secure room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap align-center width-fixed&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/06/building-15-1528304523.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-article-large wp-image-191928&quot; src=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/06/building-15-1528304523.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&amp;amp;w=1000&amp;amp;h=750&quot; alt=&quot;building-15-1528304523&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;The room at AT&amp;amp;T’s Folsom St. facility that allegedly contained NSA surveillance equipment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption source&quot;&gt;Photo: Mark Klein&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;columns columns--reverse columns--3-to-2&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;columns&quot; data-style=&quot;3:2&quot; readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said equipment in the secure room included a “semantic traffic analyzer” – a tool that can be used to search large quantities of data for particular words or phrases contained in emails or online chats. Notably, Klein discovered that the NSA appeared to be specifically targeting internet “peering links,” which is corroborated by the NSA and AT&amp;amp;T documents obtained by The Intercept.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;columns columns--reverse columns--3-to-2&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;columns&quot; data-style=&quot;3:2&quot; readability=&quot;18&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;column&quot; readability=&quot;31&quot;&gt;“By cutting into the peering links, they get not only AT&amp;amp;T’s data, they get all the data that’s interchanged between AT&amp;amp;T’s network and other companies,” Klein told The Intercept in a recent interview.
&lt;p&gt;According to documents provided by Klein, AT&amp;amp;T’s network at Folsom Street “peered” with other companies like Sprint, Cable &amp;amp; Wireless, and Qwest. It was also linked, he said, to an internet exchange named MAE West, a major data hub in San Jose, California, where other companies connect their networks together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sprint did not respond to a request for comment. A spokesperson for Cable &amp;amp; Wireless said the company only discloses data “when legally required to do so as a result of a valid warrant or other legal process.” In 2011, CenturyLink acquired Qwest as part of a $12.2 billion merger deal. A CenturyLink spokesperson said he could not discuss “matters of national security.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap align-bleed full-bleed width-auto&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-192488&quot; src=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/06/seattle-1-1528469085.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&quot; alt=&quot;The National Security Agency’s Seattle facility, located in the city’s downtown area, photographed on Wednesday, May 2, 2018, in Seattle, Wash. The 15-story gray building hosts the NSA, AT&amp;amp;T and Qwest Corporation communications. NSA and AT&amp;amp;T maps point to the Seattle facility as being of eight peering hubs that process internet traffic as part of the NSA surveillance program code-named FAIRVIEW. (Jovelle Tamayo for The Intercept)&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;caption source pullright&quot;&gt;Photo: Jovelle Tamayo for The Intercept&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;columns columns--2-to-3&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;columns&quot; data-style=&quot;2:3&quot; readability=&quot;15.764127764128&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;column&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;seattle&quot; class=&quot;chapter project-y&quot;&gt;Seattle 1122 3rd Avenue&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap align-center width-fixed&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-pez-640 wp-image-192055&quot; src=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/06/seattle-1528315622.png?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;column&quot; readability=&quot;26.589873417722&quot;&gt;The Seattle facility is located in the city’s downtown area, not far from the waterfront. The gray building is 15 stories tall, with a dozen rows of narrow, blacked-out windows and vents that rise to its peak. According to public &lt;a href=&quot;http://pcad.lib.washington.edu/building/8826/&quot;&gt;records&lt;/a&gt;, it was first constructed in 1955 and has reinforced concrete foundations and exterior walls that are supported by a steel frame.
&lt;p&gt;Historically, the facility was an important communications switching point in the northwest of the U.S., routing calls between places like Bellingham, Spokane, Yakima, and north to Canada and Alaska. Today, the building appears to be primarily &lt;a href=&quot;http://blue.kingcounty.com/Assessor/eRealProperty/Detail.aspx?ParcelNbr=2302700000&quot;&gt;owned&lt;/a&gt; by the Qwest Corporation – a subsidiary of CenturyLink – but AT&amp;amp;T has a presence within it. AT&amp;amp;T’s logo is emblazoned on a plaque outside the building’s entrance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;columns columns--2-to-3&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;columns&quot; data-style=&quot;2:3&quot; readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twenty-five miles north of Seattle, there is a major intercontinental undersea cable called Pacific Crossing-1, which routes communications between the U.S. and Japan; it is possible that the Seattle building processes some of these communications and others that pass between the U.S. west coast and Asia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap align-center width-fixed&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-192489&quot; src=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/06/seattle-2-1528469087.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&amp;amp;w=1024&amp;amp;h=682&quot; alt=&quot;The National Security Agency’s Seattle facility, located in the city’s downtown area, photographed on Wednesday, May 2, 2018, in Seattle, Wash. The 15-story gray building hosts the NSA, AT&amp;amp;T and Qwest Corporation communications. NSA and AT&amp;amp;T maps point to the Seattle facility as being of eight peering hubs that process internet traffic as part of the NSA surveillance program code-named FAIRVIEW. (Jovelle Tamayo for The Intercept)&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;caption source&quot;&gt;Photo: Jovelle Tamayo for The Intercept&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;columns columns--2-to-3&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;columns&quot; data-style=&quot;2:3&quot; readability=&quot;8.4365671641791&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;column&quot; readability=&quot;12.432835820896&quot;&gt;NSA and AT&amp;amp;T maps point to the Seattle facility as being of eight “peering” hubs that process internet traffic as part of the NSA surveillance program code-named &lt;a class=&quot;project-y&quot; data-tooltip=&quot;An NSA surveillance program that collects communications from AT&amp;amp;T's networks.&quot;&gt;FAIRVIEW&lt;/a&gt;. A former AT&amp;amp;T employee confirmed that the site was one of eight primary AT&amp;amp;T &lt;a class=&quot;project-y&quot; data-tooltip=&quot;Major AT&amp;amp;T internet hubs.&quot;&gt;“Service Node Routing Complexes,”&lt;/a&gt; or SNRCs, in the U.S. NSA documents explicitly describe tapping into flows of data at all eight of these sites.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap align-bleed full-bleed width-auto&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-191920&quot; src=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/06/building-18-1528304953.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&quot; alt=&quot;building-18-1528304953&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;caption source pullright&quot;&gt;Photo: Henrik Moltke&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;columns columns--reverse columns--3-to-2&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;columns&quot; data-style=&quot;3:2&quot; readability=&quot;14.866920152091&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;column&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;washingtondc&quot; class=&quot;chapter project-y&quot;&gt;Washington, D.C. 30 E Street Southwest&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap align-center width-fixed&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-pez-640 wp-image-192056&quot; src=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/06/washington-1528315638.png?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;column&quot; readability=&quot;24.766666666667&quot;&gt;The building is a large, concrete, rectangular-shaped facility with few windows, located less than a mile south of the U.S. Capitol. Property tax records show that Verizon owns the majority of the property (worth $26 million), while AT&amp;amp;T owns a smaller part (worth $8.8 million). Plans of the building’s internal layout show that AT&amp;amp;T has space on the fourth, fifth, and sixth floors.
&lt;p&gt;Central Office Buildings, a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.co-buildings.com/dc/202/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; that profiles telecommunications hubs in North America, describes the 30 E Street South West facility as “the granddaddy HQ of Verizon landline in Washington, DC.” It adds that the building contains a “a slew of switches of various types,” including AT&amp;amp;T equipment for routing long distance phone calls across networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap align-center width-fixed&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/06/building-19-1528305177.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-191940&quot; src=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/06/building-19-1528305177.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&amp;amp;w=1024&amp;amp;h=574&quot; alt=&quot;building-19-1528305177&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption source&quot;&gt;Photo: Mike Osborne&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;columns columns--reverse columns--3-to-2&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;columns&quot; data-style=&quot;3:2&quot; readability=&quot;13.251781472684&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;column&quot; readability=&quot;21.770783847981&quot;&gt;Capitol Police has an office located opposite the telecommunications hub, and a large number of police vehicles are usually located around the site. When The Intercept visited the facility to take photographs earlier this year, within a few minutes, several armed police officers arrived on the scene with dogs. They questioned our reporter, searched his car, and said that the building was considered critical infrastructure.
&lt;p&gt;NSA and AT&amp;amp;T maps point to the Washington, D.C. facility as being one of eight “peering” hubs that process internet traffic as part of the NSA surveillance program code-named &lt;a class=&quot;project-y&quot; data-tooltip=&quot;An NSA surveillance program that collects communications from AT&amp;amp;T's networks.&quot;&gt;FAIRVIEW&lt;/a&gt;. A former AT&amp;amp;T employee confirmed that the site was one of eight primary AT&amp;amp;T &lt;a class=&quot;project-y&quot; data-tooltip=&quot;Major AT&amp;amp;T internet hubs.&quot;&gt;“Service Node Routing Complexes,”&lt;/a&gt; or SNRCs, in the U.S. NSA documents explicitly describe tapping into flows of data at all eight of these sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Documents&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Documents published with this article:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 12:50:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>BerislavLopac</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://theintercept.com/2018/06/25/att-internet-nsa-spy-hubs/</og:url>
<og:description>These fortress-like AT&amp;amp;T buildings are central to a secret NSA program that has monitored billions of communications, documents and sources reveal.</og:description>
<og:image>https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/06/NSA-building-feature-02-1529697466.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;q=90&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=1200&amp;h=800</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>The NSA’s Hidden Spy Hubs in Eight U.S. Cities</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://theintercept.com/2018/06/25/att-internet-nsa-spy-hubs/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Firefox Developer Tools: Accessibility inspector</title>
<link>https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Tools/Accessibility_inspector</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Tools/Accessibility_inspector</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;The accessibility inspector provides a means to access important information exposed to assistive technologies on the current page via the accessibility tree, allowing you to check what's missing or otherwise needs attention. This article takes you through the main features of the accessibility inspector and how to use it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;A_(very)_brief_guide_to_accessibility&quot;&gt;A (very) brief guide to accessibility&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accessibility is the practice of making your websites usable by as many people as possible. This means trying your best to not lock anyone out of accessing information because of any disability they may have, or any other personal circumstances such as the device they are using, the speed of their network connection, or their geographic location or locale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we are mainly talking about about exposing information to people with visual disabilities — this is done via the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2015/03/web-accessibility-with-accessibility-api/&quot; class=&quot;external&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;accessibility APIs&lt;/a&gt; available inside web browsers, which expose information on what roles the different elements on your page play (e.g., are they just text, or are they buttons, links, form elements, etc.?).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Semantic DOM elements have roles assigned to them by default that hint at what their purpose is. Sometimes, however, you need to use some non-semantic markup (e.g., &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTML/Element/div&quot; title=&quot;The HTML Content Division element (&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;) is the generic container for flow content. It has no effect on the content or layout until styled using CSS.&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;s) to build a complex custom control, and the control won't have a default role that reflects its purpose. In such a situation, you can use &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Learn/Accessibility/WAI-ARIA_basics&quot;&gt;WAI-ARIA&lt;/a&gt; role attributes to provide your own roles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roles and other information exposed by browser accessibility APIs is presented in a hierarchical structure called the accessibility tree. This is a bit like the DOM tree, except that it contains a more limited set of elements and slightly different information about them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assistive technologies like screenreaders use this information to find out what's on a web page, tell their users what's there, and enable them to interact with the page. The accessibility inspector also uses this information to provide valuable accessibility debugging capabilities in the DevTools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;Accessing_the_accessibility_inspector&quot;&gt;Accessing the accessibility inspector&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The accessibility inspector (available since Firefox 61) is not shown by default in the DevTools. To turn it on, you need to go to DevTools Settings (press &lt;kbd&gt;F1&lt;/kbd&gt;, or go to the &quot;three dots&quot; menu and choose &lt;em&gt;Settings&lt;/em&gt;) and check the &lt;em&gt;Accessibility&lt;/em&gt; checkbox under the &lt;em&gt;Default Developer Tools&lt;/em&gt; heading. This will cause the &lt;em&gt;Accessibility&lt;/em&gt; tab to appear in the main DevTools display, which can be clicked on to display the accessibility panel:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mdn.mozillademos.org/files/16021/accessibility-inspector-panel-off.png&quot; alt=&quot;Accessibility tab in firefox devtools, turned off, with a button labeled Turn On Accessibility Features&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially the DevTools accessibility features are turned off (unless you've already got them turned on in another browser tab, or got the Firefox accessibility engine started already, e.g., you might be a screenreader user or tester). This is because the accessibility engine runs in the background when the accessibility features are turned on. While it’s running, it slows performance and takes up memory; therefore it interferes with the metrics from other panels such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Tools/Memory&quot;&gt;Memory&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Tools/Performance&quot;&gt;Performance&lt;/a&gt; as well as overall browser performance. For this reason you should keep it turned off when you aren't specifically using it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can turn the features on using the &lt;em&gt;Turn On Accessibility Features&lt;/em&gt; button.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the panel content loads, you can then turn it off again using the &lt;em&gt;Turn Off Accessibility Features&lt;/em&gt; button available in the top-left corner, unless you have the accessibility engine running previously to operate a screenreader, in which case this button will be disabed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;note&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: If are using the accessibility features in multiple tabs, turning them off in one tab turns them off in all tabs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;Features_of_the_Accessibility_panel&quot;&gt;Features of the Accessibility panel&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The enabled accessibility panel looks like so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mdn.mozillademos.org/files/16022/accessibility-inspector-panel-on.png&quot; alt=&quot;Accessibility tab in firefox devtools, turned on, showing two information panels plus a button labeled Turn Off Accessibility Features&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the left-hand side, there is a tree diagram representing all the items in the accessibility tree for the current page. Items with nested children have arrows that can be clicked to reveal the children, so you can move deeper into the hierarchy. Each item has two properties listed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Role&lt;/em&gt; — the role this item has on the page (e.g., &lt;code&gt;pushbutton&lt;/code&gt;, or &lt;code&gt;footer&lt;/code&gt;). This can be either a default role provided by the browser, or a role given to it via a WAI-ARIA &lt;code&gt;role&lt;/code&gt; attribute.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Name&lt;/em&gt; — the name this item has on the page. Where this comes from depends on the element; for example, the name of most text elements is simply their &lt;code&gt;textContent&lt;/code&gt;, whereas form elements' names are the contents of their associated &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTML/Element/label&quot; title=&quot;The HTML &amp;lt;label&amp;gt; element represents a caption for an item in a user interface.&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;label&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the right-hand side, you can see further information about the currently selected item. The listed properties are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;name&lt;/em&gt; — the item's name, as described above.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;role&lt;/em&gt; — the item's role, as described above.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;actions&lt;/em&gt; — a list of the actions that can be performed on the item, for example a pushbutton would have &quot;Press&quot; listed, while a link would have &quot;Jump&quot; listed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;value&lt;/em&gt; — the value of the item. This can mean different things depending on the type of item; for example, a form input (role: entry) would have a value of whatever is entered in the input, whereas a link's value would be the URL in the corresponding &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;a&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; element's &lt;code&gt;href&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;DOMNode&lt;/em&gt; — the type of DOM node that the item in the accessibility tree represents. You can click on the &quot;target&quot; icon that comes after it to select the node in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Tools/Page_Inspector&quot;&gt;Page Inspector&lt;/a&gt;. Hovering over the &quot;target&quot; icon highlights the DOM node in the page content.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mdn.mozillademos.org/files/16025/dom-node-target-icon.png&quot; alt=&quot;DOMNode property in accessibility inspector with target icon highlighted&quot;/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;description&lt;/em&gt; — any further description provided on the element, usually by the content of a title attribute.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;help&lt;/em&gt; — this is not implemented in Gecko, so it always returns an empty string. This will be removed from the inspector in Firefox 62 (&lt;a href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1467643&quot; title=&quot;FIXED: Don't expose help property in A11y Inspector&quot; class=&quot;external&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;bug 1467643&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;keyboardShortcut&lt;/em&gt; — any keyboard shortcut that is available to activate the element, as specified in an &lt;code&gt;accessKey&lt;/code&gt; attribute. Note that this works correctly as of Firefox 62 (&lt;a href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1467381&quot; title=&quot;FIXED: Keyboard shortcut empty for element with accesskey&quot; class=&quot;external&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;bug 1467381&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;childCount&lt;/em&gt; — the number of child items the current item has in the accessibility tree hierarchy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;indexInParent&lt;/em&gt; — an index value indicating what number child the item is, inside its parent. If the item is the first item inside its parent, it has a value of 0. If it is the second, it has a value of 1. And so on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;states&lt;/em&gt; — a list of the different accessibility-relevant states that can apply to the current item. For example, one of the links in one demo has states of focusable, linked, selectable text, opaque, enabled, and sensitive. For a full list of internal states, see &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/Accessibility/AT-APIs/Gecko/States&quot;&gt;Gecko states&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;attributes&lt;/em&gt; — a list of all the accessibility-relevant attributes that are applied to the item. This can include style-related attributes such as margin-left and text-indent, and other useful states for accessibility information, such as draggable and level (e.g., what heading level is it, in the case of headings). For a full list of possible attributes, see &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/Accessibility/AT-APIs/Gecko/Attrs&quot;&gt;Gecko object attributes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;note&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: The exposed information is the same across all platforms — the inspector exposes Gecko's accessibility tree, rather than information from the platform accessibility layer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;Keyboard_controls&quot;&gt;Keyboard controls&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Accessibility&lt;/em&gt; tab is fully keyboard-accessible:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;You can tab between the &lt;em&gt;Turn Off Accessibility Features&lt;/em&gt; button and left and right panels.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When one of the panels is focused, you can move the focus up and down items using the up and down arrow keys, and use the left and right arrow keys to expand and collapse expandable rows (e.g., different hierarchy levels of the accessibility tree).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the accessibility features are turned on, there are a number of useful additional features available in the DevTools, which are detailed below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An extra context menu option is added, both for the general context menu on the web page when right/&lt;kbd&gt;Ctrl&lt;/kbd&gt; + clicking a UI feature, and the HTML pane of the page inspector when right/&lt;kbd&gt;Ctrl&lt;/kbd&gt; + clicking a DOM element:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mdn.mozillademos.org/files/16028/web-page-context-menu.png&quot; alt=&quot;context menu in the browser viewport, with a highlighted option: Inspect Accessibility Properties&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mdn.mozillademos.org/files/16020/dom-inspector-context-menu.png&quot; alt=&quot;context menu in the DOM inspector, with a highlighted option: Show Accessibility Properties&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you choose the &lt;em&gt;Inspect Accessibility Properties&lt;/em&gt;/&lt;em&gt;Show Accessibility Properties&lt;/em&gt; context menu options, the &lt;em&gt;Accessibility&lt;/em&gt; tab is immediately opened to show the corresponding accessibility tree item and its properties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;note&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: Some DOM elements do not have accessibility properties — in such a case, the &lt;em&gt;Inspect Accessibility Properties&lt;/em&gt;/&lt;em&gt;Show Accessibility Properties&lt;/em&gt; context menu item is grayed out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;Highlighting_of_UI_items&quot;&gt;Highlighting of UI items&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Accessibility tab, when the mouse hovers over accessibility items, you can see a semi-transparent highlight appear over the UI items they relate to, if appropriate. This is useful for determining how the items in the accessibility tree relate to the UI items on the actual page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;Accessibility_picker&quot;&gt;Accessibility picker&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a similar way to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Tools/Page_Inspector/How_to/Select_an_element#With_the_node_picker&quot;&gt;Page Inspector HTML pane picker&lt;/a&gt;, when the &lt;em&gt;Accessibility&lt;/em&gt; tab's picker button is pressed you can then hover and select UI items in the current page, and the corresponding accessible object is highlighted in the accessibility tree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The accessibility tab picker differs in look slightly from the Page Inspector HTML pane picker, as shown below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mdn.mozillademos.org/files/16024/dom-inspector-picker.png&quot; alt=&quot;highlighted dom inspector picker button, with a tooltip saying Pick an element from the page&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mdn.mozillademos.org/files/16023/accessibility-inspector-picker.png&quot; alt=&quot;highlighted accessibility inspector button, with a tooltip saying Pick accessible object from the page&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you &quot;perform a pick&quot;, you see the accessibility object highlighted in the accessibility tree, and the picker is then deactivated. Note, however, that if you hold the &lt;kbd&gt;Shift&lt;/kbd&gt; key down when &quot;performing a pick&quot;, you can &quot;preview&quot; the accessibility object in the tree (and its properties in the right-hand pane), but then continue picking as many times as you like (the picker does not get cancelled) until you release the &lt;kbd&gt;Shift&lt;/kbd&gt; key.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the picker is activated, you can also deactivate it by pressing the picker button a second time, or pressing the &lt;kbd&gt;Esc&lt;/kbd&gt; key.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;Typical_use_cases&quot;&gt;Typical use cases&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The accessibility inspector is very useful for spotting accessibility problems at a glance. For a start, you can investigate items that don't have a proper text equivalent — images without &lt;code&gt;alt&lt;/code&gt; text and form elements without proper labels have a &lt;code&gt;name&lt;/code&gt; property of &lt;code&gt;null&lt;/code&gt;, for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mdn.mozillademos.org/files/16027/use-case-no-label.png&quot; alt=&quot;A form input highlighted in the UI, with information about it shown in the accessibility inspector to reveal that it has no label — it has a name property of null&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is also very handy for verifying semantics — you can use the &lt;em&gt;Inspect Accessibility Properties&lt;/em&gt; context menu option to quickly see whether an item has the correct role set on it (e.g., whether a button is really a button, or whether a link is really a link).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mdn.mozillademos.org/files/16026/use-case-fake-button.png&quot; alt=&quot;A UI element that looks like a button, with information about it shown in the accessibility inspector to reveal that it isn't a button, it is a section element. It has a name property of null&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;See_also&quot;&gt;See also&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 12:06:23 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>teamhappy</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:image>https://developer.mozilla.org/static/img/opengraph-logo.72382e605ce3.png</og:image>
<og:title>Accessibility inspector</og:title>
<og:url>https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Tools/Accessibility_inspector</og:url>
<og:description>The accessibility inspector provides a means to access important information exposed to assistive technologies on the current page via the accessibility tree, allowing you to check what's missing or otherwise needs attention. This article takes you through the main features of the accessibility inspector and how to use it.</og:description>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Tools/Accessibility_inspector</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Notes on Discrete Mathematics (2017) [pdf]</title>
<link>http://www.cs.yale.edu/homes/aspnes/classes/202/notes.pdf</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.cs.yale.edu/homes/aspnes/classes/202/notes.pdf</guid>
<description>&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cs.yale.edu/homes/aspnes/classes/202/notes.pdf&quot;&gt;Download PDF&lt;/a&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 11:54:28 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>alokrai</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:image>https://developer.mozilla.org/static/img/opengraph-logo.72382e605ce3.png</og:image>
<og:title>Accessibility inspector</og:title>
<og:url>https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Tools/Accessibility_inspector</og:url>
<og:description>The accessibility inspector provides a means to access important information exposed to assistive technologies on the current page via the accessibility tree, allowing you to check what's missing or otherwise needs attention. This article takes you through the main features of the accessibility inspector and how to use it.</og:description>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.cs.yale.edu/homes/aspnes/classes/202/notes.pdf</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Losing 100 pounds in 276 days</title>
<link>https://posts.alexgr.in/losing-100-pounds-in-276-days/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://posts.alexgr.in/losing-100-pounds-in-276-days/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;On August 2nd, 2017, per the suggestion of my doctor, I decided to pickup a free download of &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/myfitnesspal/id341232718?mt=8&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;MyFitnessPal&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Etekcity-Digital-Bathroom-Measure-Tempered/dp/B01HI1W1V4/ref=sr_1_2_sspa?s=hpc&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1529785382&amp;amp;sr=1-2-spons&amp;amp;keywords=scale&amp;amp;psc=1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;$20 digital scale&lt;/a&gt;. I had never used the first and barely ever used the second.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I received my scale, I weighed in at &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;276.8 lbs&lt;/code&gt;. I’m only &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;5'9&lt;/code&gt;, so this put me at a shocking BMI of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bmi-calculator.net/bmi-classification/bmi-obesity-class-3-information.php&quot;&gt;40.9&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;I had been overweight for most of my life, but this was a new extreme even for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;276&lt;/code&gt; days later, I weighed in at &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;176.6 lbs&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;Today, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;326&lt;/code&gt; days later, I weighed in at &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;163.2 lbs&lt;/code&gt; – a whopping &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;113 lbs&lt;/code&gt; lost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is how I did it, along with the data I collected along the way (calories, steps, fitness).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;data&quot;&gt;Data&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;weight-interactive&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;tabs&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weight&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calories&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steps&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;caloric-deficit--weight-loss&quot;&gt;Caloric Deficit &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;==&lt;/code&gt; Weight Loss&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only thing you really need to know is that you should be eating fewer calories than your body burns everyday. If you do this, you will lose weight – it’s science. Nothing else matters for weight loss. The magnitude of the caloric difference will regulate how quickly or slowly you lose the weight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On average, it takes about &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;3,500&lt;/code&gt; calories to burn &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;1&lt;/code&gt; pound of fat. Suppose you eat &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;1,000&lt;/code&gt; fewer calories than your &lt;a href=&quot;https://manytools.org/handy/bmr-calculator/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Basal Metabolic Rate (BMR)&lt;/a&gt;. After a week your body will burn &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;7,000&lt;/code&gt; calories or &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;2 lbs&lt;/code&gt; of fat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I never understood how simple it was before starting this. I found &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mayoclinic.org/healthy-lifestyle/weight-loss/in-depth/calories/art-20048065&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; to be quite helpful for learning the basics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-single-most-important-tool-for-my-weight-loss-was-the-myfitnesspal-app&quot;&gt;The single most important tool for my weight loss was the MyFitnessPal app&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;greatest&lt;/em&gt; feature of the app is that it tells you how many calories to eat. You put in your height, weight, and goal weight and it outputs your daily calorie intake limit. You can also specify how fast you want to lose the weight – I chose the max option of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;-2 lbs/week&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;second greatest&lt;/em&gt; feature is the food database. MyFitnessPal has fairly accurate calorie estimates for almost anything you’d ever eat. I recorded what I ate, every single meal and snack, every single day, and even now I still do it. I’ll probably do it for many years to come. It’s amazingly helpful to stay on track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;fun-stats&quot;&gt;Fun Stats&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fun-stats&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;stat&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daily Calories&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;average per day&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;stat&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall Calories&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in 276 days&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;stat&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Weight (lbs) Lost&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in 276 days&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;stat&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Average Steps&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;per day&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;8/2/2017&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;5/6/2018&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-tv-ad-photo&quot;&gt;The TV-ad photo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;photo-proof&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;images&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://posts.alexgr.in/img/weightloss/before.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://posts.alexgr.in/img/weightloss/after2.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Left: &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;~250 lbs&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;Right: &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;~170 lbs&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;tips&quot;&gt;Tips&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;data-is-king&quot;&gt;Data is king&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Record everything you eat, even if you go over your limit. The accountability is helpful and it becomes addictive. MyFitnessPal reminds you a few times a day to record things so you won’t forget.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;fewer-calories-over-time&quot;&gt;Fewer calories over Time&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you lose weight (depending on how much you want to lose) your calorie goal should decrease. MyFitnessPal has a huge bug – it doesn’t do this automatically, you have to periodically “adjust” your goal weight so it recomputes the daily caloric intake goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;exercise-or-dont&quot;&gt;Exercise or don’t&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don’t have to exercise. If you like to exercise that’s great – you’ll burn more calories which means you will lose the weight faster (as long as you don’t eat those calories back). I tried running – about 30m, every morning, for 3 months. At times it felt great, but in the end I didn’t like it enough to stick with it. If you’re just trying to cut weight, you can do that with calorie restriction alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;diet-plans-are-not-necessary&quot;&gt;“Diet plans” are not necessary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the diet plans that I’ve seen really do one thing – they employ fancy tricks to get you to eat fewer calories without actually counting. Skip the gimmicks and just count calories. It’s easier to deal with just one restriction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;healthy-food-only&quot;&gt;Healthy food only?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I naturally started eating healthy foods because I could eat more of them. If you eat a chocolate bar, you will still be hungry. For the same amount of calories, you could eat a few bowls of vegetables and be full. That said, the best part about this overall approach is that you can still eat whatever you want – just count the calories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;intermittent-fasting&quot;&gt;Intermittent fasting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somewhere along the journey I picked up intermittent fasting. I like it but it’s also not necessary. I found that it helped reduce my appetite which means I can eat fewer calories. The principal is that you have a feeding period of 8 hours and a fasting period of 16 hours. I eat from 12pm to 8pm, and fast from 8pm - 12pm. This means I always skip breakfast. There’s a lot of “science” that say low insulin levels in the fasted state lead to more fat burning. If you’re in a caloric deficit this will happen anyways. This might fall into the category of “fancy diet plans” that just get you to eat fewer calories without realizing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Everything I wrote above is what worked for me – that is not to say it will work for everyone. I am also not a doctor, I’m an engineer, so none of this is medical advice – please consult your doctor.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 11:51:06 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>agrinman</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://posts.alexgr.in/losing-100-pounds-in-276-days/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Intel and the Danger of Integration</title>
<link>https://stratechery.com/2018/intel-and-the-danger-of-integration/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://stratechery.com/2018/intel-and-the-danger-of-integration/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Last week &lt;a href=&quot;https://newsroom.intel.com/news-releases/intel-ceo-brian-krzanich-resigns-board-appoints-bob-swan-interim-ceo/&quot;&gt;Brian Krzanich resigned as the CEO of Intel&lt;/a&gt; after violating the company’s non-fraternization policy. The details of Krzanich’s departure, though, ultimately don’t matter: his tenure was an abject failure, the extent of which is only now coming into view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Intel’s Obsolete Opportunity&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Krzanich was appointed CEO in 2013 it was already clear that arguably the most important company in Silicon Valley’s history was in trouble: PCs, long Intel’s chief money-maker, were in decline, leaving the company ever more reliant on the sale of high-end chips to data centers; Intel had effectively zero presence in mobile, the industry’s other major growth area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, &lt;a href=&quot;https://stratechery.com/2013/the-intel-opportunity/&quot;&gt;I framed the situation that faced Krzanich as an opportunity&lt;/a&gt;, and drew a comparison to the challenges that faced &lt;a href=&quot;https://stratechery.com/2016/andy-grove-and-the-iphone-se/&quot;&gt;the legendary Andy Grove&lt;/a&gt; three decades ago:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the 1980s, though, it was the microprocessor business, fueled by the IBM PC, that was driving growth, while the DRAM business was fully commoditized and dominated by Japanese manufacturers. Yet Intel still fashioned itself a memory company. That was their identity, come hell or high water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By 1986, said high water was rapidly threatening to drag Intel under. In fact, 1986 remains the only year in Intel’s history that they made a loss. Global overcapacity had caused DRAM prices to plummet, and Intel, rapidly becoming one of the smallest players in DRAM, felt the pain severely. It was in this climate of doom and gloom that Grove took over as CEO. And, in a highly emotional yet patently obvious decision, he once and for all got Intel out of the memory manufacturing business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intel was already the best microprocessor design company in the world. They just needed to accept and embrace their destiny.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to the challenge that faced Krzanich:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is into a climate of doom and gloom that Krzanich is taking over as CEO. And, in what will be a highly emotional yet increasingly obvious decision, he ought to commit Intel to the chip manufacturing business, i.e. manufacturing chips according to other companies’ designs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intel is already the best microprocessor manufacturing company in the world. They need to accept and embrace their destiny.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That article is now out of date: in a remarkable turn of events, Intel has lost its manufacturing lead. Ben Bajarin wrote last week in &lt;a href=&quot;https://techpinions.com/intels-moment-of-truth/53135&quot;&gt;Intel’s Moment of Truth&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only has the competition caught Intel they have surpassed them. TSMC is now sampling on 7nm and AMD will ship their architecture on 7nm technology in both servers and client PCs ahead of Intel. For those who know their history, this is the first time AMD has ever beat Intel to a process node. Not only that, but AMD will likely have at least an 18 month lead on Intel with 7nm, and I view that as conservative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Bajarin notes, 7nm for TSMC (or Samsung or Global Foundries) isn’t necessarily better than Intel’s 10nm; chip-labeling isn’t what it used to be. The problem is that Intel’s 10nm process isn’t close to shipping at volume, and the competition’s 7nm processes are. Intel is behind, and its insistence on integration bears a large part of the blame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Intel’s Integrated Model&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intel, like Microsoft, had its fortunes made by IBM: eager to get the PC an increasingly vocal section of its customer base demanded out the door, the mainframe maker outsourced much of the technology to third party vendors, the most important being an operating system from Microsoft and a processor from Intel. The impact of the former decision was the formation of an entire ecosystem centered around MS-DOS, and eventually Windows, cementing Microsoft’s dominance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intel was a slightly different story; while an operating system was simply bits on a disk, and thus easily duplicated for all of the PCs IBM would go on to sell, a processor was a physical device that needed to be manufactured. To that end IBM insisted on having a “second source”, that is, a second non-Intel manufacturer for Intel’s chips. Intel chose AMD, and licensed first the 8086 and 8088 designs that were in the original IBM PC, and later, again under pressure from IBM, the 80286 design; the latter was particularly important because it was designed to be upward compatible with everything that followed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This laid the groundwork for Intel’s strategy — and immense profitability — for the next 35 years. First off, the dominance of Intel’s x86 design was assured thanks to its integration with DOS/Windows: specifically, DOS/Windows created a two-sided market of developers and PC users, and DOS/Windows ran on x86.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Paper.stratechery-Year-One.354-2-1024x699.png&quot; alt=&quot;Microsoft and Intel were integrated in the PC value chain&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;437&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-3571&quot; srcset=&quot;https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Paper.stratechery-Year-One.354-2-1024x699.png 1024w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Paper.stratechery-Year-One.354-2-300x205.png 300w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Paper.stratechery-Year-One.354-2-768x525.png 768w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Paper.stratechery-Year-One.354-2-922x630.png 922w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Paper.stratechery-Year-One.354-2.png 1300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, thanks to its licensing deal with AMD, Intel wasn’t automatically entitled to all of the profits that would result from that integration; thus Intel doubled-down on an integration of its own: the design and manufacture of x86 chips. That is, Intel would invest huge sums of money into creating new and faster designs (the 386, the 486, the Pentium, etc.), and also invest huge sums of money into ever smaller and more efficient manufacturing processes that would push the limits of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Moore%27s_law&quot;&gt;Moore’s Law&lt;/a&gt;. This one-two punch would ensure that, despite AMD’s license, Intel’s chips would be the only realistic choice for PC makers, allowing the company to capture the vast majority of the profits created by the x86’s integration with DOS/Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intel was largely successful. AMD did take the performance crown around the turn of the century with the Athlon 64, but the company was unable to keep up with Intel financially when it came to fabs, and Intel illegally leveraged its dominant position with OEMs to keep them buying mostly Intel parts; then, a few years later, Intel not only took back the performance lead with its Core architecture, but settled into the “tick-tock” strategy where it alternated new designs and new manufacturing processes on a regular schedule. The integration advantage was real.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;TSMC’s Modular Approach&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime there was a revolution brewing in Taiwan. In 1987, Morris Chang founded Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Company (TSMC) promising “Integrity, commitment, innovation, and customer trust”. Integrity and customer trust referred to Chang’s commitment that TSMC would never compete with its customers with its own designs: the company would focus on nothing but manufacturing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a completely novel idea: at that time all chip manufacturing was integrated a la Intel; the few firms that were only focused on chip design had to scrap for excess capacity at Integrated Device Manufacturers (IDMs) who were liable to steal designs and cut off production in favor of their own chips if demand rose. Now TSMC offered a much more attractive alternative, even if their manufacturing capabilities were behind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In time, though, TSMC got better, in large part because it had no choice: soon its manufacturing capabilities were only one step behind industry standards, and within a decade had caught-up (although Intel remained ahead of everyone). Meanwhile, the fact that TSMC existed created the conditions for an explosion in “fabless” chip companies that focused on nothing but design. For example, in the late 1990s there was an explosion in companies focused on dedicated graphics chips: nearly all of them were manufactured by TSMC. And, all along, the increased business let TSMC invest even more in its manufacturing capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Paper.stratechery-Year-One.371-2-1024x679.png&quot; alt=&quot;Integrated intel was competing with a competitive modular ecosystem&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;424&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-3572&quot; srcset=&quot;https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Paper.stratechery-Year-One.371-2-1024x679.png 1024w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Paper.stratechery-Year-One.371-2-300x199.png 300w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Paper.stratechery-Year-One.371-2-768x509.png 768w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Paper.stratechery-Year-One.371-2-950x630.png 950w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Paper.stratechery-Year-One.371-2.png 1300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This represented into a three-pronged assault on Intel’s dominance:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Many of those new fabless design companies were creating products that were direct alternatives to Intel chips for general purpose computing. The vast majority of these were based on the ARM architecture, but also AMD in 2008 spun off its fab operations (christened GlobalFoundries) and became a fabless designer of x86 chips.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Specialized chips, designed by fabless design companies, were increasingly used for operations that had previously been the domain of general purpose processors. Graphics chips in particular &lt;a href=&quot;https://stratechery.com/2017/apple-to-build-own-gpu-the-evolution-of-gpus-apple-and-the-general-purpose-gpu/&quot;&gt;were well-suited to machine learning&lt;/a&gt;, cryptocurrency mining, and other highly “embarrassingly parallel” operations; many of those applications have spawned specialized chips of their own. There are dedicated bitcoin chips, for example, or Google’s Tensor Processing Units: all are manufactured by TSMC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meanwhile TSMC, joined by competitors like GlobalFoundries and Samsung, were investing ever more in new manufacturing processes, fueled by the revenue from the previous two factors in a virtuous cycle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Intel’s Straitjacket&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intel, meanwhile, was hemmed in by its integrated approach. The first major miss was mobile: &lt;a href=&quot;https://stratechery.com/2016/andy-grove-and-the-iphone-se/&quot;&gt;instead of simply manufacturing ARM chips for the iPhone&lt;/a&gt; the company presumed it could win by leveraging its manufacturing to create a more-efficient x86 chip; it was a decision that evinced too much knowledge of Intel’s margins and not nearly enough reflection on the importance of the integration between DOS/Windows and x86.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intel took the same mistaken approach to non general-purpose processors, particularly graphics: the company’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Larrabee_(microarchitecture)&quot;&gt;Larrabee architecture&lt;/a&gt; was a graphics chip based on — you guessed it — x86; it was predicated on leveraging Intel’s integration, instead of actually meeting a market need. Once the project predictably failed Intel limped along with graphics that were barely passable for general purpose displays, and worthless for all of the new use cases that were emerging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The latest crisis, though, is in design: AMD is genuinely innovating with its Ryzen processors (manufactured by both GlobalFoundries and TSMC), while Intel is still selling varations on Skylake, a three year-old design. Ashraf Eassa, with assistance from a since-deleted tweet from a former Intel engineer, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fool.com/investing/2018/05/10/ex-intel-engineer-explains-the-companys-biggest-mi.aspx&quot;&gt;explains what happened&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to a tweet from ex-Intel engineer Francois Piednoel, the company had the opportunity to bring all-new processor technology designs to its currently shipping 14nm technology, but management decided against it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;my post was actually pointing out that market stalling is more troublesome than Ryzen, It is not a good news. 2 years ago, I said that ICL should be taken to 14nm++, everybody looked at me like I was the craziest guy on the block, it was just in case … well … now, they know&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— François Piednoël (@FPiednoel) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/FPiednoel/status/989617508289208320&quot;&gt;April 26, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem in recent years is that Intel has been unable to bring its major new manufacturing technology, known as 10nm, into mass production. At the same time, the issues with 10nm seemed to catch Intel off-guard. So, by the time it became clear that 10nm wouldn’t go into production as planned, it was too late for Intel to do the work to bring one of the new processor designs that was originally developed to be built on the 10nm technology to its older 14nm technology…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What Piednoel is saying in the tweet I quoted above is that when management had the opportunity to start doing the work to bring their latest processor design, known as Ice Lake (abbreviated “ICL” in the tweet), [to the 14nm process] they decided against doing so. That was likely because management truly believed two years ago that Intel’s 10nm manufacturing technology would be ready for production today. Management bet incorrectly, and Intel’s product portfolio is set to suffer as a result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To put it another way, Intel’s management did not break out of the integration mindset: design and manufacturing were assumed to be in lockstep forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Integration and Disruption&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is perhaps simpler to say that Intel, like Microsoft, has been disrupted. The company’s integrated model resulted in incredible margins for years, and every time there was the possibility of a change in approach Intel’s executives chose to keep those margins. In fact, Intel has followed the script of the disrupted even more than Microsoft: while the decline of the PC finally led to &lt;a href=&quot;https://stratechery.com/2018/the-end-of-windows/&quot;&gt;The End of Windows&lt;/a&gt;, Intel has spent the last several years propping up its earnings by focusing more and more on the high-end, selling Xeon processors to cloud providers. That approach was certainly good for quarterly earnings, but it meant the company was only deepening the hole it was in with regards to basically everything else. And now, most distressingly of all, the company looks to be on the verge of losing its performance advantage even in high-end applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is all certainly on Krzanich, and his predecessor Paul Otellini. Then again, perhaps neither had a choice: what makes disruption so devastating is the fact that, absent a crisis, it is almost impossible to avoid. Managers are paid to leverage their advantages, not destroy them; to increase margins, not obliterate them. Culture more broadly is &lt;a href=&quot;https://stratechery.com/2016/the-curse-of-culture/&quot;&gt;an organization’s greatest asset right up until it becomes a curse&lt;/a&gt;. To demand that Intel apologize for its integrated model is satisfying in 2018, but all too dismissive of the 35 years of success and profits that preceded it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it goes.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 08:32:30 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ingve</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Intel and the Danger of Integration</og:title>
<og:url>https://stratechery.com/2018/intel-and-the-danger-of-integration/</og:url>
<og:description>Intel is in an increasingly bad position in part because it has been captive to its integrated model. Or, you could simply say they were disrupted.</og:description>
<og:image>https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Paper.stratechery-Year-One.371-2.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://stratechery.com/2018/intel-and-the-danger-of-integration/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>