<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>“Intel Core 2 bugs will assuredly be exploitable from userland code” (2007)</title>
<link>https://marc.info/?l=openbsd-misc&amp;m=118296441702631&amp;w=2</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://marc.info/?l=openbsd-misc&amp;m=118296441702631&amp;w=2</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;Content-Type&quot; content=&quot;text/html&quot; /&gt;&lt;title&gt;'Intel Core 2' - MARC&lt;/title&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot; href=&quot;/style.css&quot; /&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body bgcolor=&quot;#FFFFFF&quot; text=&quot;#000000&quot; link=&quot;#0000C0&quot; vlink=&quot;#800080&quot; id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;42.55789143395&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;[&lt;a href=&quot;https://marc.info/?l=openbsd-misc&amp;amp;m=118296701919577&amp;amp;w=2&quot;&gt;prev in list&lt;/a&gt;] [&lt;a href=&quot;https://marc.info/?l=openbsd-misc&amp;amp;m=118297555807876&amp;amp;w=2&quot;&gt;next in list&lt;/a&gt;] [&lt;span&gt;prev in thread&lt;/span&gt;] [&lt;a href=&quot;https://marc.info/?l=openbsd-misc&amp;amp;m=118297555807876&amp;amp;w=2&quot;&gt;next in thread&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;
List:       &lt;a href=&quot;https://marc.info/?l=openbsd-misc&amp;amp;r=1&amp;amp;w=2&quot;&gt;openbsd-misc&lt;/a&gt;
Subject:    &lt;a href=&quot;https://marc.info/?t=118296457100003&amp;amp;r=1&amp;amp;w=2&quot;&gt;Intel Core 2&lt;/a&gt;
From:       &lt;a href=&quot;https://marc.info/?a=90366097200024&amp;amp;r=1&amp;amp;w=2&quot;&gt;Theo de Raadt &amp;lt;deraadt () cvs ! openbsd ! org&amp;gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Date:       &lt;a href=&quot;https://marc.info/?l=openbsd-misc&amp;amp;r=1&amp;amp;w=2&amp;amp;b=200706&quot;&gt;2007-06-27 17:08:16&lt;/a&gt;
Message-ID: &lt;a href=&quot;https://marc.info/?i=200706271708.l5RH8GkK024621%20()%20cvs%20!%20openbsd%20!%20org&quot;&gt;200706271708.l5RH8GkK024621 () cvs ! openbsd ! org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
[&lt;a href=&quot;https://marc.info/?l=openbsd-misc&amp;amp;m=118296441702631&amp;amp;q=raw&quot;&gt;Download message RAW&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/strong&gt;

Various developers are busy implimenting workarounds for serious bugs
in Intel's Core 2 cpu.

These processors are buggy as hell, and some of these bugs don't just
cause development/debugging problems, but will *ASSUREDLY* be
exploitable from userland code.

As is typical, BIOS vendors will be very late providing workarounds /
fixes for these processors bugs.  Some bugs are unfixable and cannot
be worked around.  Intel only provides detailed fixes to BIOS vendors
and large operating system groups.  Open Source operating systems are
largely left in the cold.

Full (current) errata from Intel:

  &lt;a href=&quot;http://download.intel.com/design/processor/specupdt/31327914.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://download.intel.com/design/processor/specupdt/31327914.pdf&lt;/a&gt;

  - We bet there are many more errata not yet announced -- every month
    this file gets larger.
  - Intel understates the impact of these erraata very significantly.
    Almost all operating systems will run into these bugs.
  - Basically the MMU simply does not operate as specified/implimented
    in previous generations of x86 hardware.  It is not just buggy, but
    Intel has gone further and defined &quot;new ways to handle page tables&quot;
    (see page 58).
  - Some of these bugs are along the lines of &quot;buffer overflow&quot;; where
    a write-protect or non-execute bit for a page table entry is ignored.
    Others are floating point instruction non-coherencies, or memory
    corruptions -- outside of the range of permitted writing for the
    process -- running common instruction sequences.
  - All of this is just unbelievable to many of us.

An easier summary document for some people to read:

  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.geek.com/images/geeknews/2006Jan/core_duo_errata__2006_01_21__full.gif&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://www.geek.com/images/geeknews/2006Jan/core_duo_errata__2006_01_21__full.gif&lt;/a&gt;

Note that some errata like AI65, AI79, AI43, AI39, AI90, AI99 scare
the hell out of us.  Some of these are things that cannot be fixed in
running code, and some are things that every operating system will do
until about mid-2008, because that is how the MMU has always been
managed on all generations of Intel/AMD/whoeverelse hardware.  Now
Intel is telling people to manage the MMU's TLB flushes in a new and
different way.  Yet even if we do so, some of the errata listed are
unaffected by doing so.

As I said before, hiding in this list are 20-30 bugs that cannot be
worked around by operating systems, and will be potentially
exploitable.  I would bet a lot of money that at least 2-3 of them
are.

For instance, AI90 is exploitable on some operating systems (but not
OpenBSD running default binaries).

At this time, I cannot recommend purchase of any machines based on the
Intel Core 2 until these issues are dealt with (which I suspect will
take more than a year).  Intel must be come more transparent.

(While here, I would like to say that AMD is becoming less helpful day
by day towards open source operating systems too, perhaps because
their serious errata lists are growing rapidly too).

&lt;strong&gt;[&lt;a href=&quot;https://marc.info/?l=openbsd-misc&amp;amp;m=118296701919577&amp;amp;w=2&quot;&gt;prev in list&lt;/a&gt;] [&lt;a href=&quot;https://marc.info/?l=openbsd-misc&amp;amp;m=118297555807876&amp;amp;w=2&quot;&gt;next in list&lt;/a&gt;] [&lt;span&gt;prev in thread&lt;/span&gt;] [&lt;a href=&quot;https://marc.info/?l=openbsd-misc&amp;amp;m=118297555807876&amp;amp;w=2&quot;&gt;next in thread&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://marc.info/?q=configure&quot;&gt;Configure&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://marc.info/?q=about&quot;&gt;About&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://marc.info/?q=news&quot;&gt;News&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:webguy@marc.info?subject=Add%20a%20list%20to%20MARC&quot;&gt;Add a list&lt;/a&gt; | Sponsored by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.korelogic.com/&quot;&gt;KoreLogic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2018 01:29:06 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pixelmonkey</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://marc.info/?l=openbsd-misc&amp;m=118296441702631&amp;w=2</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>About speculative execution vulnerabilities in ARM-based and Intel CPUs</title>
<link>https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT208394</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT208394</guid>
<description>&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Security researchers have recently uncovered security issues known by two names, Meltdown and Spectre. These issues apply to all modern processors and affect nearly all computing devices and operating systems. All Mac systems and iOS devices are affected, but there are no known exploits impacting customers at this time. Since exploiting many of these issues requires a malicious app to be loaded on your Mac or iOS device, we recommend downloading software only from trusted sources such as the App Store. Apple has already released mitigations in iOS 11.2, macOS 10.13.2, and tvOS 11.2 to help defend against Meltdown. Apple Watch is not affected by Meltdown. In the coming days we plan to release mitigations in Safari to help defend against Spectre. We continue to develop and test further mitigations for these issues and will release them in upcoming updates of iOS, macOS, tvOS, and watchOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Meltdown and Spectre issues take advantage of a modern CPU performance feature called speculative execution. Speculative execution improves speed by operating on multiple instructions at once—possibly in a different order than when they entered the CPU. To increase performance, the CPU predicts which path of a branch is most likely to be taken, and will speculatively continue execution down that path even before the branch is completed. If the prediction was wrong, this speculative execution is rolled back in a way that is intended to be invisible to software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Meltdown and Spectre exploitation techniques abuse speculative execution to access privileged memory—including that of the kernel—from a less-privileged user process such as a malicious app running on a device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Meltdown&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meltdown is a name given to an exploitation technique known as CVE-2017-5754 or &quot;rogue data cache load.&quot; The Meltdown technique can enable a user process to read kernel memory. Our analysis suggests that it has the most potential to be exploited. Apple released mitigations for Meltdown in iOS 11.2, macOS 10.13.2, and tvOS 11.2. watchOS did not require mitigation. Our testing with public benchmarks has shown that the changes in the December 2017 updates resulted in no measurable reduction in the performance of macOS and iOS as measured by the GeekBench 4 benchmark, or in common Web browsing benchmarks such as Speedometer, JetStream, and ARES-6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Spectre&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spectre is a name covering two different exploitation techniques known as CVE-2017-5753 or &quot;bounds check bypass,&quot; and CVE-2017-5715 or &quot;branch target injection.&quot; These techniques potentially make items in kernel memory available to user processes by taking advantage of a delay in the time it may take the CPU to check the validity of a memory access call.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Analysis of these techniques revealed that while they are extremely difficult to exploit, even by an app running locally on a Mac or iOS device, they can be potentially exploited in JavaScript running in a web browser. Apple will release an update for Safari on macOS and iOS in the coming days to mitigate these exploit techniques. Our current testing indicates that the upcoming Safari mitigations will have no measurable impact on the Speedometer and ARES-6 tests and an impact of less than 2.5% on the JetStream benchmark. We continue to develop and test further mitigations within the operating system for the Spectre techniques, and will release them in upcoming updates of iOS, macOS, tvOS, and watchOS. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2018 00:11:09 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>gok</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT208394</og:url>
<og:title>About speculative execution vulnerabilities in ARM-based and Intel CPUs</og:title>
<og:description>  </og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT208394</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>“My ten hour white noise video now has five copyright claims”</title>
<link>https://twitter.com/littlescale/status/949032404206870528</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://twitter.com/littlescale/status/949032404206870528</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/littlescale/status/949032404206870528&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/littlescale/status/949032404206870528&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16075325&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16075325&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Points: 763&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 193&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2018 00:07:28 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ryanlol</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mobile.twitter.com/littlescale/status/949032404206870528</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Announcing the OpenWrt/LEDE merge</title>
<link>https://forum.lede-project.org/t/announcing-the-openwrt-lede-merge/10217</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://forum.lede-project.org/t/announcing-the-openwrt-lede-merge/10217</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both the OpenWrt and LEDE projects are happy to announce their unification under the OpenWrt name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After long and sometimes slowly moving discussions about the specifics of the re-merge, with multiple similar proposals but little subsequent action, we’re happy to announce that both projects are about to execute the final steps of the merger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://forum.lede-project.org/uploads/default/original/2X/e/ec719677c944f10dbeb234b2dcdf86ad118e15bf.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;svg&quot; width=&quot;250&quot; height=&quot;175&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new, unified OpenWrt project will be governed under the &lt;a href=&quot;https://lede-project.org/rules&quot;&gt;rules established by the LEDE project&lt;/a&gt;. Active members of both the former LEDE and OpenWrt projects will continue working on the unified OpenWrt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LEDE’s fork and subsequent re-merge into OpenWrt will not alter the overall technical direction taken by the unified project. We will continue to work on improving stability and release maintenance while aiming for frequent minor releases to address critical bugs and security issues like we did with LEDE 17.01 and its four point releases until now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Old pre-15.05 OpenWrt CC releases will not be supported by the merged project anymore, leaving these releases without any future security or bug fixes. The OpenWrt CC 15.05 release series will receive a limited amount of security and bug fixes, but is not yet fully integrated in our release automation, so binary releases are lacking behind for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The LEDE 17.01 release will continue to get full security and bug fix support for both source code and binary releases.&lt;br/&gt;We are planning a new major release under the new name in the next few months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The merged project will use the code base of the former LEDE project. OpenWrt specific patches not present in the LEDE repository but meeting LEDEs code quality requirements got integrated into the new tree. The source code will be hosted at &lt;a href=&quot;https://git.openwrt.org/&quot;&gt;git.openwrt.org&lt;/a&gt; with a continuously synchronized mirror hosted at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/openwrt/openwrt&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;. The original OpenWrt codebase has been &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/openwrt/archive&quot;&gt;archived on Github&lt;/a&gt; for future reference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet open pull requests to both the old OpenWrt and LEDE repositories will be closed after a 30 day grace period. We encourage people to open new pull requests at the new repository or re-send still unmerged patches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The remerged OpenWrt project is legally represented by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.spi-inc.org/&quot;&gt;Software in the Public Interest (SPI)&lt;/a&gt; - an US 501(c)(3) non-profit organization which is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.spi-inc.org/projects/openwrt/&quot;&gt;managing our OpenWrt trademark&lt;/a&gt;, handling our donations and helping us with legal problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Infrastructure currently available under the &lt;a href=&quot;http://lede-project.org&quot;&gt;lede-project.org&lt;/a&gt; domain will be moved to corresponding &lt;a href=&quot;http://openwrt.org&quot;&gt;openwrt.org&lt;/a&gt; subdomains and redirects will be put in place where appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The merger of the OpenWrt and LEDE forums and wikis is not yet fully decided, so all portals will continue to be available under their respective domains until a definite consensus is reached.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 23:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kylegordon</dc:creator>
<og:image>http://forum.lede-project.org/uploads/default/original/2X/e/ec719677c944f10dbeb234b2dcdf86ad118e15bf.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>http://forum.lede-project.org/t/announcing-the-openwrt-lede-merge/10217?_escaped_fragment_=</og:url>
<og:title>Announcing the OpenWrt/LEDE merge</og:title>
<og:description>Both the OpenWrt and LEDE projects are happy to announce their unification under the OpenWrt name. After long and sometimes slowly moving discussions about the specifics of the re-merge, with multiple similar proposals but little subsequent action, we’re happy to announce that both projects are about to execute the final steps of the merger. The new, unified OpenWrt project will be governed under the rules established by the LEDE project. Active members of both the former LEDE and OpenWrt pr...</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://forum.lede-project.org/t/announcing-the-openwrt-lede-merge/10217?_escaped_fragment_=</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Texttop – An interactive X Linux desktop rendered in TTY and streamable over SSH</title>
<link>https://github.com/tombh/texttop</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/tombh/texttop</guid>
<description>&lt;h3&gt;README.md&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hello newcomers. This has suddenly got some unplanned exposure. I'm actually in the middle of a complete rewrite on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tombh/texttop/tree/webext-rewrite&quot;&gt;webext-rewrite branch&lt;/a&gt;. You can get an idea of my approach with this function: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tombh/texttop/blob/webext-rewrite/webext/src/text_builder.js#L165&quot;&gt;https://github.com/tombh/texttop/blob/webext-rewrite/webext/src/text_builder.js#L165&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the success of hitting the front page of Hacker News last year, I really wanted to sit down and turn this proof of concept into something solid. So not only am I working on real text support (that you can of course copy and paste without even zooming). But I've removed the dependencies on &lt;code&gt;ffmpeg&lt;/code&gt;, Xorg (for Firefox at least - Chrome strangely doesn't support webextensions in headless mode), &lt;code&gt;docker&lt;/code&gt; AND it will work on all webextension-compatible browsers. It's going to be a single cross-platform, static Go binary, that launches your preferred browser in the background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generally it's bad luck to talk about something before it's finished, but seeing as it's suddenly getting attention again I wanted to let all those interested know that I'm making this 10 times better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A fully interactive X Linux desktop rendered to TTY and streamed over SSH&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;or Firefox in your terminal 😲&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/632c0f3d4d2aeb65162ab501bcec53fe6363db15/68747470733a2f2f692e696d6775722e636f6d2f6a583376684f342e676966&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/632c0f3d4d2aeb65162ab501bcec53fe6363db15/68747470733a2f2f692e696d6775722e636f6d2f6a583376684f342e676966&quot; alt=&quot;Alt Text&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/jX3vhO4.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TE_D_fx_ut8&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Youtube video&lt;/a&gt; gives a more faithful rendition of the experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm travelling around the world and sometimes I don't have very good Internet. If all I have is a 3kbps connection tethered from my phone then it's good to SSH into my server and browse the web through &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.xteddy.org/elinks/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;elinks&lt;/a&gt;. That way my &lt;em&gt;server&lt;/em&gt; downloads the web pages and uses the limited bandwidth of my SSH connection to display the result. But it lacks JS support and all that other modern HTML5 goodness. Texttop is simply a way to have the power of a remote server running a desktop, but interfaced through the simplicity of a terminal and very low bandwidth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why not VNC? Well VNC is certainly one solution but it doesn't quite have the same ability to deal with extremely bad Internet. Texttop uses MoSH to further reduce the bandwidth and stability requirements of the connection. Mosh offers features like automatic reconnection of dropped connections and diff-only screen updates. Also, other than SSH or MoSH, Texttop doesn't require a client like VNC. But of course another big reason for Texttop is that it's just very cool geekery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Quickstart&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you just want to have a play on your local machine:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;docker run --rm -it tombh/texttop sh
./run.sh
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can either pull from the Docker Registry: &lt;code&gt;docker pull tombh/texttop&lt;/code&gt; or, build yourself:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;git clone https://github.com/tombh/texttop.git
cd texttop
docker build -t texttop .
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The docker image is only ~275MB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On your remote server (this will pull the docker image the first time you issue it):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;docker run -d \
  -p 7777:7777 -p 60000-60020:60000-60020/udp \
  -v ${HOME}/.ssh:/root/.ssh:ro \
  tombh/texttop
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that this assumes you already have SSH setup on your server and that you have your public key there. Password logins work fine too. The &lt;code&gt;60000-60020&lt;/code&gt; port range is for MoSH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then on your local machine:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;mosh user@yourserver:7777
./run.sh
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MoSH is available through most system package managers. SSH can be used exactly the same, just replace &lt;code&gt;mosh&lt;/code&gt; with &lt;code&gt;ssh&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;user@yourserver&lt;/code&gt; is the normal URI you would use to connect via SSH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exiting&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;code&gt;CTRL+ALT+Q&lt;/code&gt; will drop you back to the docker container's CLI. You can start again with &lt;code&gt;./run.sh&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If MoSH or SSH become unresponsive you can exit MoSH with &lt;code&gt;CTRL+^ .&lt;/code&gt; or SSH with &lt;code&gt;ENTER ~ .&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Interaction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;CTRL + mousewheel&lt;/code&gt; to zoom&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;CTRL + click/drag&lt;/code&gt; to pan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most mouse and keyboard input is exactly the same as a normal desktop. If your terminal is active then you can click, type, scroll, use arrow keys and drag things around. However there are still some things not available, like copy and paste. The main difference from a normal desktop is that you can zoom and pan the desktop by using &lt;code&gt;CTRL + mousewheel&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;CTRL + drag&lt;/code&gt;. This is very handy as it's hard to see what's what when you're zoomed right out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Keyboard Mode&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your terminal doesn't support mouse input then you can switch in and out of keyboard mode with &lt;code&gt;CTRL+ALT+M&lt;/code&gt;. This will give you the following shortcuts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;u&lt;/code&gt; mouse up&lt;br/&gt;&lt;code&gt;n&lt;/code&gt; mouse down&lt;br/&gt;&lt;code&gt;h&lt;/code&gt; mouse left&lt;br/&gt;&lt;code&gt;k&lt;/code&gt; mouse right&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;SHIFT+u&lt;/code&gt; pan up&lt;br/&gt;&lt;code&gt;SHIFT+n&lt;/code&gt; pan down&lt;br/&gt;&lt;code&gt;SHIFT+h&lt;/code&gt; pan left&lt;br/&gt;&lt;code&gt;SHIFT+k&lt;/code&gt; pan right&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;CTRL+u&lt;/code&gt; zoom in&lt;br/&gt;&lt;code&gt;CTRL+n&lt;/code&gt; zoom out&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;j&lt;/code&gt; left-click&lt;br/&gt;&lt;code&gt;r&lt;/code&gt; right-click&lt;br/&gt;&lt;code&gt;t&lt;/code&gt; middle-click&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Adding new applications&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, only Firefox is installed on this extremely minimal Alpine Linux distro. However you can add new packages with &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.alpinelinux.org/wiki/Alpine_Linux_package_management&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;apk&lt;/a&gt;. Example;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;# Login with a seperate session
apk --no-cache add xterm
export DISPLAY=:0
xterm &amp;amp;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just remember that you will lose any system changes once you restart the docker container. I'm thinking about ways to save state. You may experiment with mounting certain system directories. Eg;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;docker run -d \
  -p 7777:7777 -p 60000-60020:60000-60020/udp \
  -v ${HOME}/.ssh:/root/.ssh:ro \
  -v ${HOME}/.texttop/var:/var \
  tombh/texttop
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Known Issues&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Docker Hub version is built against Intel CPU architectures, this causes hiptext to fail on AMD chips. In which case you will need to build texttop yourself:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;git clone https://github.com/tombh/texttop.git
cd texttop
docker build -t texttop .
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Working terminals&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Problematic terminals&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;konsole: neither &lt;code&gt;CTRL+click/drag&lt;/code&gt; nor &lt;code&gt;CTRL+mousewheel&lt;/code&gt; are forwarded (perhaps mouse reporting is disabled by default)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;xterm: &lt;code&gt;CTRL+click/drag&lt;/code&gt; is intercepted by the GUI menu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rxvt: rendering issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Contributions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes please.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GNU General Public License v3.0&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 21:08:11 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>sandebert</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars0.githubusercontent.com/u/160835?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>tombh/texttop</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/tombh/texttop</og:url>
<og:description>texttop - A fully interactive X Linux desktop rendered in TTY and streamable over SSH</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/tombh/texttop</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>More details about mitigations for the CPU Speculative Execution issue</title>
<link>https://security.googleblog.com/2018/01/more-details-about-mitigations-for-cpu_4.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://security.googleblog.com/2018/01/more-details-about-mitigations-for-cpu_4.html</guid>
<description></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 20:40:25 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>el_duderino</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>More details about mitigations for the CPU Speculative Execution issue</og:title>
<og:image>http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-7bZ5EziliZQ/VynIS9F7OAI/AAAAAAAASQ0/BJFntXCAntstZe6hQuo5KTrhi5Dyz9yHgCK4B/s1600/googlelogo_color_200x200.png</og:image>
<og:url>https://security.googleblog.com/2018/01/more-details-about-mitigations-for-cpu_4.html</og:url>
<og:description>Posted by Matt Linton, Senior Security Engineer and Pat Parseghian, Technical Program Manager Yesterday, Google’s Project Zero team posted...</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://security.googleblog.com/2018/01/more-details-about-mitigations-for-cpu_4.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Productivity in 2017: analyzing 225 million hours of work time</title>
<link>http://blog.rescuetime.com/225-million-hours-productivity/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://blog.rescuetime.com/225-million-hours-productivity/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;When &lt;em&gt;exactly&lt;/em&gt; are we the most productive?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thinking back on your last year, you probably have no idea. Days blend together. Months fly by. And another year turns over without any real understanding of how we actually spent our time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But our mission at RescueTime has always been to help you do more meaningful work. And this starts with understanding how you spend your days, when you’re most productive, and what’s getting in your way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2017, we logged &lt;strong&gt;over 225 million hours of digital time&lt;/strong&gt; from hundreds of thousands of RescueTime users around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By studying the anonymized data of how people spent their time on their computers and phones over the past 12 months, we’ve pinpointed exactly what days and times we do the most productive work, how often we’re getting distracted by emails or social media, and how much time a week we actually have to do meaningful work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Takeaways:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;5844&quot; data-permalink=&quot;http://blog.rescuetime.com/225-million-hours-productivity/key-takeaways/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/blog.rescuetime.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/key-takeaways.png?fit=5224%2C3670&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;5224,3670&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;key-takeaways&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/blog.rescuetime.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/key-takeaways.png?fit=300%2C211&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/blog.rescuetime.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/key-takeaways.png?fit=640%2C449&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-5844&quot; src=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/blog.rescuetime.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/key-takeaways.png?resize=640%2C450&quot; alt=&quot;RescueTime key takeaways productivity in 2017&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; srcset=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/blog.rescuetime.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/key-takeaways.png?w=5224 5224w, https://i2.wp.com/blog.rescuetime.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/key-takeaways.png?resize=300%2C211 300w, https://i2.wp.com/blog.rescuetime.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/key-takeaways.png?resize=768%2C540 768w, https://i2.wp.com/blog.rescuetime.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/key-takeaways.png?resize=1024%2C719 1024w, https://i2.wp.com/blog.rescuetime.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/key-takeaways.png?w=1280 1280w, https://i2.wp.com/blog.rescuetime.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/key-takeaways.png?w=1920 1920w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 900px) 700px, 900px&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simply put, our data shows that &lt;strong&gt;people were the most productive on November 14th.&lt;/strong&gt; In fact, that entire week ranked as the most productive of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which makes sense. With American Thanksgiving the next week and the mad holiday rush shortly after, mid-November is a great time for people to cram in a few extra work hours and get caught up before gorging on Turkey dinner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other side of the spectrum, we didn’t get a good start to the year. &lt;strong&gt;January 6th—the first Friday of the year—was the least productive day of 2017.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, what do we mean when we talk about the “most” or “least” productive days?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rescuetime.com/&quot;&gt;RescueTime&lt;/a&gt; is a tool that tracks how you spend your time on your computer and phone and let’s you categorize activities on a scale from very distracting to very productive. So for example, if you’re a writer, time spent in Microsoft Word or Google Docs is categorized as very productive while social media is very distracting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;5816&quot; data-permalink=&quot;http://blog.rescuetime.com/225-million-hours-productivity/screen-shot-2018-01-03-at-11-04-48-am/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/blog.rescuetime.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/Screen-Shot-2018-01-03-at-11.04.48-AM.png?fit=2066%2C696&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2066,696&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Screen Shot 2018-01-03 at 11.04.48 AM&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/blog.rescuetime.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/Screen-Shot-2018-01-03-at-11.04.48-AM.png?fit=300%2C101&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/blog.rescuetime.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/Screen-Shot-2018-01-03-at-11.04.48-AM.png?fit=640%2C216&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-5816&quot; src=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/blog.rescuetime.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/Screen-Shot-2018-01-03-at-11.04.48-AM.png?resize=640%2C216&quot; alt=&quot;Productivity Pulse&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;216&quot; srcset=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/blog.rescuetime.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/Screen-Shot-2018-01-03-at-11.04.48-AM.png?w=2066 2066w, https://i2.wp.com/blog.rescuetime.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/Screen-Shot-2018-01-03-at-11.04.48-AM.png?resize=300%2C101 300w, https://i2.wp.com/blog.rescuetime.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/Screen-Shot-2018-01-03-at-11.04.48-AM.png?resize=768%2C259 768w, https://i2.wp.com/blog.rescuetime.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/Screen-Shot-2018-01-03-at-11.04.48-AM.png?resize=1024%2C345 1024w, https://i2.wp.com/blog.rescuetime.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/Screen-Shot-2018-01-03-at-11.04.48-AM.png?w=1280 1280w, https://i2.wp.com/blog.rescuetime.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/Screen-Shot-2018-01-03-at-11.04.48-AM.png?w=1920 1920w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 900px) 700px, 900px&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From that data, we calculate your &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.rescuetime.com/breaking-down-the-rescuetime-productivity-score/&quot;&gt;productivity pulse&lt;/a&gt;—a score out of 100 for how much of your time you spent on activities that you deem productive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On November 14th, the average productivity pulse across all RescueTime users was a not-so-shabby 60.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest mistakes so many of us make when planning out our days is to assume we have 8+ hours to do productive work. This couldn’t be further from the truth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What we found is that, on average, &lt;strong&gt;we only spend 5 hours a day working on a digital device&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And with an average productivity pulse of 53% for the year, that means &lt;strong&gt;we only have 12.5 hours a week to do productive work.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understanding our overall productivity is a fun exercise, but our data lets us go even deeper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at the workday (from 8am–6pm, Monday to Friday), how are we spending our time? When do we do our best work? Do different tasks normally get done at different times?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s what we found out:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Our most productive work happens on Wednesdays at 3pm&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our data showed that we do our most productive work (represented by the light blue blocks) between 10 and noon and then again from 2-5pm each day. However, breaking it down to the hour, &lt;strong&gt;we do our most productive work on Wednesdays at 3pm. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;5818&quot; data-permalink=&quot;http://blog.rescuetime.com/225-million-hours-productivity/image7/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/blog.rescuetime.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/image7.png?fit=500%2C350&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;500,350&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;image7&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/blog.rescuetime.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/image7.png?fit=300%2C210&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/blog.rescuetime.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/image7.png?fit=500%2C350&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-5818&quot; src=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/blog.rescuetime.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/image7.png?resize=500%2C350&quot; alt=&quot;Very productive time&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; srcset=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/blog.rescuetime.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/image7.png?w=500 500w, https://i0.wp.com/blog.rescuetime.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/image7.png?resize=300%2C210 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;Very productive time (light blue)
&lt;h3&gt;Email rules our mornings, but never really leaves us alone&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our days start with email, with &lt;strong&gt;Monday morning at 9am being the clear winner for most time spent on email during the week.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;5819&quot; data-permalink=&quot;http://blog.rescuetime.com/225-million-hours-productivity/image2/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/blog.rescuetime.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/image2.png?fit=500%2C350&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;500,350&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;image2&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/blog.rescuetime.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/image2.png?fit=300%2C210&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/blog.rescuetime.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/image2.png?fit=500%2C350&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-5819&quot; src=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/blog.rescuetime.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/image2.png?resize=500%2C350&quot; alt=&quot;Time spent on email&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; srcset=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/blog.rescuetime.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/image2.png?w=500 500w, https://i0.wp.com/blog.rescuetime.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/image2.png?resize=300%2C210 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;Time spent on email (light blue)
&lt;h3&gt;Software developers don’t hit peak productivity until 2pm each day&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What about how specific digital workers spend their days?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at the time spent in software development tools, our data paints a picture of a workday that doesn’t get going until the late morning and peaks between 2–6pm daily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;5820&quot; data-permalink=&quot;http://blog.rescuetime.com/225-million-hours-productivity/image8/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/blog.rescuetime.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/image8.png?fit=500%2C350&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;500,350&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;image8&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/blog.rescuetime.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/image8.png?fit=300%2C210&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/blog.rescuetime.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/image8.png?fit=500%2C350&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-5820&quot; src=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/blog.rescuetime.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/image8.png?resize=500%2C350&quot; alt=&quot;Time spent in Software development&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; srcset=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/blog.rescuetime.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/image8.png?w=500 500w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.rescuetime.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/image8.png?resize=300%2C210 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;Time spent in Software Development tools (light blue)
&lt;h3&gt;While writers are more likely to be early birds&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those who spend their time writing, it’s a different story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing apps were used more evenly throughout each day with &lt;strong&gt;the most productive writing time happening on Tuesdays at 10am&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;5821&quot; data-permalink=&quot;http://blog.rescuetime.com/225-million-hours-productivity/image4/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/blog.rescuetime.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/image4.png?fit=500%2C350&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;500,350&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;image4&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/blog.rescuetime.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/image4.png?fit=300%2C210&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/blog.rescuetime.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/image4.png?fit=500%2C350&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-5821&quot; src=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/blog.rescuetime.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/image4.png?resize=500%2C350&quot; alt=&quot;Time spent writing&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; srcset=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/blog.rescuetime.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/image4.png?w=500 500w, https://i2.wp.com/blog.rescuetime.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/image4.png?resize=300%2C210 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;Time spent in writing tools (light blue)


&lt;p&gt;It’s great to pat ourselves on the back about how productive we were in 2017. But we live in a distracted world and one of our greatest challenges is to stay focused and on task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s what our research discovered about the biggest time wasters of last year:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On an average day we use 56 different apps and websites&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on what you do, this number might not seem that bad. However, when we look at &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; we use those different apps and websites, things get a bit hairier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to switching between different apps and websites (i.e. &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.rescuetime.com/multitasking/&quot;&gt;multitasking&lt;/a&gt;), &lt;strong&gt;we jump from one task to another nearly 300 times per day &lt;/strong&gt;and switch between documents and pages within a site 1,300 times per day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;For Slack users, 8.8% of our day is spent in the app&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s been a lot of talk about how much email and communication eats into our days. But what do the numbers look like?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What we found is that for people who use Slack as their work communication tool, they spend almost 10% of their workday in the app (8.8% to be exact).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;We check email or IM 40 times every day&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s more telling is how often we check our communication tools, whether email or instant messengers like Slack or HipChat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On average, &lt;strong&gt;we check our communication apps 40 times a day,&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;once every 7.5 minutes&lt;/strong&gt; during our 5 hours of daily digital work time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Almost 7% of every workday is spent on social media&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m sure most of us try not to spend time on social media while at work. But our data showed that &lt;strong&gt;almost 7% of every workday was spent on social media&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not only time spent that’s the issue, however. On average, &lt;strong&gt;we check in on social media sites 14 times per workday&lt;/strong&gt;, or nearly 3 times an hour during our 5-hour digital day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, what does all this tell us about how we spend our days?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, first off, we need to remember that averages shouldn’t be treated as universal truths. Everyone works differently. But having a high-level look at productivity and the things that get in its way is a powerful tool in improving how you work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest piece of advice we can pull from all this data is to be aware of the limited time you have each day for meaningful work, and spend it wisely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our days are filled with distractions, and it’s up to us to protect what time we have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;A note about this data…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rescuetime.com&quot;&gt;RescueTime&lt;/a&gt; is used by everyone from students to software developers to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rescuetime.com/orgs&quot;&gt;full organizations&lt;/a&gt; to track and understand how they use their time on digital devices.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;These stats were pulled using data from hundreds of thousands of users from around the world, looking at how they spend their digital time Monday to Friday between 8am and 6pm.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 20:25:23 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jorymackay</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Productivity in 2017: What we learned from analyzing 225 million hours - rescueTime</og:title>
<og:description>What was the most productive day of 2017? How often do we get distracted by emails or IM? By analyzing millions of hours of anonymized data, we found out.</og:description>
<og:url>http://blog.rescuetime.com/225-million-hours-productivity/</og:url>
<og:image>http://blog.rescuetime.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/ben-kolde-403278-copy.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://blog.rescuetime.com/225-million-hours-productivity/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Xerox Alto zero-day: cracking disk password protection on a 45 year old system</title>
<link>http://www.righto.com/2018/01/xerox-alto-zero-day-cracking-disk.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.righto.com/2018/01/xerox-alto-zero-day-cracking-disk.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;We've been archiving a bunch of old Xerox Alto disk packs from the 1970s. A few of them turned out to be password-protected, so I needed to figure out how to get around the password protection. I've developed a way to disable password protection, as well as a program to find the password instantly. (This attack is called &lt;em&gt;XeroDay&lt;/em&gt;, based on a suggestion by &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16073896&quot;&gt;msla&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-wkh_wZG0zO8/Wk5rCH-VaOI/AAAAAAABH8A/ingPw6ASMOAM2rj8vGDqo_GKeb_cJDWwwCHMYBhgL/w9999/alto-mandelbrot-full.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;The Xerox Alto. The disk drive is the black unit below the keyboard. The processor is behind the grill. The Mandelbrot set has nothing to do with this article.&quot; class=&quot;hilite&quot; height=&quot;413&quot; src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-wkh_wZG0zO8/Wk5rCH-VaOI/AAAAAAABH8A/ingPw6ASMOAM2rj8vGDqo_GKeb_cJDWwwCHMYBhgL/w200/alto-mandelbrot-full.jpg&quot; title=&quot;The Xerox Alto. The disk drive is the black unit below the keyboard. The processor is behind the grill. The Mandelbrot set has nothing to do with this article.&quot; width=&quot;200&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cite&quot;&gt;The Xerox Alto. The disk drive is the black unit below the keyboard. The processor is behind the grill. The Mandelbrot set has nothing to do with this article.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Alto was a revolutionary computer designed at Xerox PARC in 1973 to investigate personal computing. In the photo above, the Alto computer itself is in the lower cabinet. The Diablo disk drive (in 1970s orange, below the keyboard) takes a removable 14 inch disk pack that stores 2.5 megabytes of data. (A bunch of disk packs are visible behind the Alto and in the photo below.) I've been restoring a Xerox Alto, along with Marc Verdiell, Luca Severini and &lt;a href=&quot;http://rescue1130.blogspot.com/&quot;&gt;Carl Claunch&lt;/a&gt;. (The full set of Alto posts is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.righto.com/search/label/alto&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and Marc's videos are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/mverdiell/videos&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-n5bs7HfCIgc/Wk5rCAFMLgI/AAAAAAABH8A/v9B2nKJanbIcP70gvmdi1MV0CCEwW_t_ACHMYBhgL/w9999/parc-disks.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Some of the disks from Xerox PARC that we're archiving.&quot; class=&quot;hilite&quot; height=&quot;309&quot; src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-n5bs7HfCIgc/Wk5rCAFMLgI/AAAAAAABH8A/v9B2nKJanbIcP70gvmdi1MV0CCEwW_t_ACHMYBhgL/w400/parc-disks.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Some of the disks from Xerox PARC that we're archiving.&quot; width=&quot;400&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cite&quot;&gt;Some of the disks from Xerox PARC that we're archiving.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we have the Alto running, one project is to archive a bunch of disks that have been sitting at Xerox PARC for decades, and find out if there are any interesting treasures among the disks. We can archive disks by running the &lt;em&gt;Copydisk&lt;/em&gt; program on the Alto, and copying them over Ethernet to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/livingcomputermuseum/IFS&quot;&gt;PC server&lt;/a&gt;. (Ethernet was invented by Xerox for the Alto.) However, it's considerably faster to read the data directly off the disk drive, bypassing the computer. Carl created an FPGA-based disk controller (below) that connects to the Diablo disk drive, speeding up the archiving process.&lt;span id=&quot;fnref:carl&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;ref&quot; href=&quot;http://www.righto.com/2018/01/xerox-alto-zero-day-cracking-disk.html#fn:carl&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-ltkcnKBOM_0/Wk5rCPDVJGI/AAAAAAABH8A/6ZnXOBzWznMEkEStGx6rtbcKY-4-ToQDgCHMYBhgL/w9999/disk-tool.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Diablo disk tool, built by Carl Claunch using an FPGA.&quot; class=&quot;hilite&quot; height=&quot;171&quot; src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-ltkcnKBOM_0/Wk5rCPDVJGI/AAAAAAABH8A/6ZnXOBzWznMEkEStGx6rtbcKY-4-ToQDgCHMYBhgL/w400/disk-tool.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Diablo disk tool, built by Carl Claunch using an FPGA.&quot; width=&quot;400&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cite&quot;&gt;Diablo disk tool, built by Carl Claunch using an FPGA.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before reading each disk, we open up the pack and carefully clean the surface. After storage for decades, these disks have some grime, dust, and the occasional bug (of the dead insect variety), so we need to clean them to reduce the chance of a head crash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-Z6JCniMSnHI/Wk5rCNElU6I/AAAAAAABH8A/MLNkmLk91XsloNczWBLU27CDGolL5kBcQCHMYBhgL/w9999/opened-disk.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;A Xerox Alto disk pack, opened for cleaning. The &amp;quot;flaws&amp;quot; on the surface are just reflections.&quot; class=&quot;hilite&quot; height=&quot;285&quot; src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-Z6JCniMSnHI/Wk5rCNElU6I/AAAAAAABH8A/MLNkmLk91XsloNczWBLU27CDGolL5kBcQCHMYBhgL/w400/opened-disk.jpg&quot; title=&quot;A Xerox Alto disk pack, opened for cleaning. The &amp;quot;flaws&amp;quot; on the surface are just reflections.&quot; width=&quot;400&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cite&quot;&gt;A Xerox Alto disk pack, opened for cleaning. The &quot;flaws&quot; on the surface are just reflections.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the archived disks can be booted on the Alto or the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/livingcomputermuseum/ContrAlto&quot;&gt;ContrAlto simulator&lt;/a&gt;. But a few disks only booted to a password prompt (see below), and we couldn't use the disk without the password. So I decided to hack my way into the password-protected disks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-iIFdKzxO9QQ/Wk5rCIediNI/AAAAAAABH8A/Xzi8-P8ybFUMEy_-3M8REr573X0bj9PSACHMYBhgL/w9999/password-screen.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Booting a password-protected disk results in a request for the password.&quot; class=&quot;hilite&quot; height=&quot;36&quot; src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-iIFdKzxO9QQ/Wk5rCIediNI/AAAAAAABH8A/Xzi8-P8ybFUMEy_-3M8REr573X0bj9PSACHMYBhgL/w442/password-screen.png&quot; title=&quot;Booting a password-protected disk results in a request for the password.&quot; width=&quot;442&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cite&quot;&gt;Booting a password-protected disk results in a request for the password.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Alto documentation discusses password protection, explaining how a password can be associated with a disk. It only promises &quot;a modest level of security&quot;, which turns out to be true. It also says if you forget the password, &quot;you will need an expert to get access to anything on your disk.&quot; But could I break in without finding an expert?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-DJWx8sgLaZ8/Wk5rCNwc0LI/AAAAAAABH8A/9M6VkBHeAxcBOjFP4b9CbROFqe9gzRgBgCHMYBhgL/w9999/users-manual.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Password protection is described in the Alto User's Handbook page 5.&quot; class=&quot;hilite&quot; height=&quot;91&quot; src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-DJWx8sgLaZ8/Wk5rCNwc0LI/AAAAAAABH8A/9M6VkBHeAxcBOjFP4b9CbROFqe9gzRgBgCHMYBhgL/w650/users-manual.png&quot; title=&quot;Password protection is described in the Alto User's Handbook page 5.&quot; width=&quot;650&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;A bit about passwords&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Storing passwords in plain text is a very bad idea, since anyone who can access the file can see the password.&lt;span id=&quot;fnref:zero&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;ref&quot; href=&quot;http://www.righto.com/2018/01/xerox-alto-zero-day-cracking-disk.html#fn:zero&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Most systems use a solution invented by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roger_Needham&quot;&gt;Roger Needham&lt;/a&gt; in 1967. Instead of storing the password, you hash the password through a cryptographic one-way function and store the hash. When the user inputs a password, you hash it through the same function and compare the hashes. If they match, the passwords match. And if anyone sees the hash, there's no easy way to get the password back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One problem with hashed passwords is if two users have the same hash, then you know they have the same password. A solution (invented in Unix) is to hash some random bytes (called &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Salt_(cryptography)&quot;&gt;salt&lt;/a&gt;) along with the password to yield the stored hash. Since different users will have different salt, the hashes will be different even if the passwords are the same. (Of course you need to store the salt along with the hash in order to check passwords.)&lt;span id=&quot;fnref:rainbow&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;ref&quot; href=&quot;http://www.righto.com/2018/01/xerox-alto-zero-day-cracking-disk.html#fn:rainbow&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Like Unix, the Alto used salted and hashed passwords.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Alto's hash algorithm&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The source code for the Alto's password algorithm reveals how the password hashing is implemented.&lt;span id=&quot;fnref:passwordCode&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;ref&quot; href=&quot;http://www.righto.com/2018/01/xerox-alto-zero-day-cracking-disk.html#fn:passwordCode&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; The Alto uses four words of salt with the password (two words based on the password creation time and two words based on the user name). The password hash is 4 words (64 bits) long. The Alto's password hash algorithm is pretty simple:&lt;span id=&quot;fnref:negate&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;ref&quot; href=&quot;http://www.righto.com/2018/01/xerox-alto-zero-day-cracking-disk.html#fn:negate&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Hash c = -a*x*x + b*y&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;where &lt;code&gt;a&lt;/code&gt; is the time salt and &lt;code&gt;b&lt;/code&gt; is the user name salt. &lt;code&gt;x&lt;/code&gt; is a one-word value generated from the password string and &lt;code&gt;y&lt;/code&gt; is a two-word value from the password string, both generated by concatenating characters from the password.&lt;span id=&quot;fnref:concat&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;ref&quot; href=&quot;http://www.righto.com/2018/01/xerox-alto-zero-day-cracking-disk.html#fn:concat&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Disabling the password&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's a way to disable the password on disk, gaining access to the file system.&lt;span id=&quot;fnref:neptune&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;ref&quot; href=&quot;http://www.righto.com/2018/01/xerox-alto-zero-day-cracking-disk.html#fn:neptune&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; The Alto boots from disk by running the file &lt;code&gt;sys.boot&lt;/code&gt;; this file decides if a password is required for boot, based on the 9-word password vector stored inside the file. The first word is a flag indicating if the disk is password protected. If the password flag is set, the boot program requires a password before proceeding. The next four words are the salt, and the final four words are the password hash itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The password protection can be disabled by clearing the flag word inside &lt;code&gt;sys.boot&lt;/code&gt;, which is the 128th word in the second block of &lt;code&gt;sys.boot&lt;/code&gt;. The tricky part is finding where this word is on disk. The file system stores a directory as the name of each file along with the disk address of the file's first block. By reading the directory as raw data and interpreting it, we can find the location of &lt;code&gt;sys.boot&lt;/code&gt;. In the Alto file system, each disk block has pointers to the previous and next block. So once we've found the first block, we can follow the pointer to find the second block. (Basically I re-implemented a subset of the Alto file system using the raw disk.) Erasing the password flag in this block makes the disk bootable without the password.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After implementing this, I realized there's a short cut. The writers of the disk bootstrap code didn't want to re-implement the file system either, so the Alto simply copies the first block of &lt;code&gt;sys.boot&lt;/code&gt; to the first disk sector. This makes it trivial to find the file, without needing to scan the directory. Once I have the first block, I can find the second block from the pointer, access the block, and clear the password flag, disabling the security.&lt;span id=&quot;fnref:filesystem&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;ref&quot; href=&quot;http://www.righto.com/2018/01/xerox-alto-zero-day-cracking-disk.html#fn:filesystem&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made a simple Python program to update the disk image file and clear the password flag (&lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/shirriff/0faa98f7c0740583f04bbf8425c544ce&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;). After running this program, I was able to access the protected disks. The password-protected disks didn't have any super-secret treasures. However, one disk contained an implementation of APL in Mesa, which was interesting. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/APL_(programming_language)&quot;&gt;APL&lt;/a&gt; is a cool programming language known for its extremely terse notation and strange character set. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mesa_(programming_language)&quot;&gt;Mesa&lt;/a&gt; is a high-level language developed at Xerox PARC; it influenced Java.) We haven't gotten Mesa running on the Alto yet, but this looks like an interesting thing to try out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-TLDTzw5jcCM/Wk5rCMuAJgI/AAAAAAABH8A/w4m52WNUOz8t7KE17-AMxy2bAem0vuLzgCHMYBhgL/w9999/apl.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;After defeating the password, I can view the disk contents. These files implement APL in Mesa.&quot; class=&quot;hilite&quot; height=&quot;271&quot; src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-TLDTzw5jcCM/Wk5rCMuAJgI/AAAAAAABH8A/w4m52WNUOz8t7KE17-AMxy2bAem0vuLzgCHMYBhgL/w606/apl.png&quot; title=&quot;After defeating the password, I can view the disk contents. These files implement APL in Mesa.&quot; width=&quot;606&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cite&quot;&gt;After defeating the password, I can view the disk contents. These files implement APL in Mesa.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Brute-forcing the password&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I could access the disk simply by clearing the password flag, I wondered what the original passwords were. I implemented the password algorithm in C (&lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/shirriff/e333b99b521bd8dbddbbd40868245011&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;), so I could rapidly test passwords. My hope was that testing against a list of &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/danielmiessler/SecLists/tree/master/Passwords&quot;&gt;top 100,000 passwords&lt;/a&gt; would find the passwords, since I didn't expect much in the way of 1970s password security practices. Surprisingly, there were no hits so the passwords weren't common words. My next step was brute-forcing the password by generating all strings of length 1, 2, 3 and so forth.&lt;span id=&quot;fnref:lowercase&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;ref&quot; href=&quot;http://www.righto.com/2018/01/xerox-alto-zero-day-cracking-disk.html#fn:lowercase&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Finally at length 8, I cracked the first password with &quot;AATFDAFD&quot;. The second disk had password &quot;HGFIHD&quot; and the third had &quot;AAJMAKAY&quot;. Apparently random strings were popular passwords back then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was a bit suspicious when I saw that both 8-character passwords started with &quot;AA&quot; so I investigated a bit more. It turned out that using &quot;AB&quot; in place of &quot;AA&quot; also worked, as did starting with anything in &quot;{A-Z}{A-G}&quot;. Studying the algorithm more closely, I realized that when &lt;code&gt;x&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;y&lt;/code&gt; get too long, the old character bits were just dropped. Thus, when you use a password longer than 6 characters, most of the bits from the first characters are lost. This is a pretty big flaw in the algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Finding the password with math&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It takes half an hour or so to brute force the password; can we do better? Yes, by doing some algebra on the password formula yielding:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;y = (c + a*x*x) / b&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;where &lt;code&gt;x&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;y&lt;/code&gt; are generated from the password string, &lt;code&gt;a&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;b&lt;/code&gt; are salt, and &lt;code&gt;c&lt;/code&gt; is the stored password hash. Since &lt;code&gt;x&lt;/code&gt; is only 16 bits, we can easily try all the values, finding ones for which the division works. When we find a solution for &lt;code&gt;y&lt;/code&gt;, we can recover the original password by chopping &lt;code&gt;x&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;y&lt;/code&gt; into 7-bit characters. Using this technique, the password can be recovered almost instantly. I implemented this in Python &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/shirriff/978cd9a345870f7aa96234a2884c6321&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Xerox Alto's disk passwords can be trivially bypassed, and the password can be easily recovered. The password algorithm has multiple flaws that make it weaker than you'd expect (dropping password characters) and easily reversed. Since the system is almost 45 years old, they had to keep the code small and they weren't facing modern threats. After all, Xerox only promised &quot;modest&quot; security with the passwords, and that's what it provided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Notes and references&lt;/h2&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 19:18:42 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jjwiseman</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://www.righto.com/2018/01/xerox-alto-zero-day-cracking-disk.html</og:url>
<og:title>Xerox Alto zero-day: cracking disk password protection on a 45 year old system</og:title>
<og:description>We've been archiving a bunch of old Xerox Alto disk packs from the 1970s. A few of them turned out to be password-protected, so I needed ...</og:description>
<og:image>https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-wkh_wZG0zO8/Wk5rCH-VaOI/AAAAAAABH8A/ingPw6ASMOAM2rj8vGDqo_GKeb_cJDWwwCHMYBhgL/w1200-h630-p-k-no-nu/alto-mandelbrot-full.jpg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.righto.com/2018/01/xerox-alto-zero-day-cracking-disk.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>XPS 13 developer edition 7th generation available</title>
<link>https://bartongeorge.io/2018/01/04/xps-13-developer-edition-the-7th-gen-is-here/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://bartongeorge.io/2018/01/04/xps-13-developer-edition-the-7th-gen-is-here/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Today I am excited to announce the availability of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dell.com/en-us/work/shop/dell-laptops-and-notebooks/xps-13-developer-edition/spd/xps-13-9370-laptop?appliedRefinements=301&quot;&gt;7th generat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dell.com/en-us/work/shop/dell-laptops-and-notebooks/xps-13-developer-edition/spd/xps-13-9370-laptop?appliedRefinements=301&quot;&gt;ion&lt;/a&gt; of the Ubuntu-based XPS 13 developer edition.  Project Sputnik’s latest and greatest system is now simultaneously available in Europe, Canada and the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dell.com/en-us/work/shop/dell-laptops-and-notebooks/xps-13-developer-edition/spd/xps-13-9370-laptop?appliedRefinements=301&quot;&gt;XPS 13 developer edition (9370)&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://bartongeorge.io/2018/01/04/xps-13-developer-edition-the-7th-gen-is-here/italia-with-screenfill-transparent/&quot; rel=&quot;attachment wp-att-9855&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;9855&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://bartongeorge.io/2018/01/04/xps-13-developer-edition-the-7th-gen-is-here/italia-with-screenfill-transparent/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://barton808.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/italia-with-screenfill-transparent.png&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2000,1084&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Italia – with screenfill -transparent&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://barton808.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/italia-with-screenfill-transparent.png?w=300&amp;amp;h=163&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://barton808.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/italia-with-screenfill-transparent.png?w=450&quot; class=&quot;alignright size-medium wp-image-9855&quot; src=&quot;https://barton808.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/italia-with-screenfill-transparent.png?w=300&amp;amp;h=163&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;163&quot; srcset=&quot;https://barton808.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/italia-with-screenfill-transparent.png?w=300&amp;amp;h=163 300w, https://barton808.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/italia-with-screenfill-transparent.png?w=600&amp;amp;h=326 600w, https://barton808.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/italia-with-screenfill-transparent.png?w=150&amp;amp;h=81 150w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;features the 8th Generation Intel Quad Core, a brand new chassis, an improved display and smaller borders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 9370 is even thinner, lighter and smaller than its already svelte predecessor, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dell.com/en-us/work/shop/cty/pdp/spd/xps-13-9360-laptop?3x_nav=OS_BRAND%3DUBUNT&amp;amp;3x_page=1&amp;amp;filterCollapsed=true&amp;amp;appliedRefinements=302&quot;&gt;9360&lt;/a&gt;. (Note, the 9370 does not replace the 9360, as the two will coexist.)  If you want more detailed specs, please scroll down dear reader. Before we get to the product details however, here’s a quick Project Sputnik backgrounder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project Sputnik, a recap&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It all started back in 2012 with the wacky idea of creating a high-end Linux laptop targeted at developers.   An internal innovation fund gave the scrapp&lt;a href=&quot;https://bartongeorge.io/2018/01/04/xps-13-developer-edition-the-7th-gen-is-here/sputnik_tshirt-5th-print-rev-nov-2017/&quot; rel=&quot;attachment wp-att-9807&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;9807&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://bartongeorge.io/2018/01/04/xps-13-developer-edition-the-7th-gen-is-here/sputnik_tshirt-5th-print-rev-nov-2017/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://barton808.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/sputnik_tshirt-5th-print-rev-nov-2017.jpg&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;800,1000&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Sputnik_tshirt-5th-print-rev – Nov 2017&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://barton808.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/sputnik_tshirt-5th-print-rev-nov-2017.jpg?w=240&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://barton808.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/sputnik_tshirt-5th-print-rev-nov-2017.jpg?w=450&quot; class=&quot;size-thumbnail wp-image-9807 alignleft&quot; src=&quot;https://barton808.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/sputnik_tshirt-5th-print-rev-nov-2017.jpg?w=120&amp;amp;h=150&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;120&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; srcset=&quot;https://barton808.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/sputnik_tshirt-5th-print-rev-nov-2017.jpg?w=120&amp;amp;h=150 120w, https://barton808.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/sputnik_tshirt-5th-print-rev-nov-2017.jpg?w=240&amp;amp;h=300 240w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 120px) 100vw, 120px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;y project team a little bit of money and six months to see if this idea would fly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From day one, project Sputnik publically solicited input from the developer community.  It was this input and the tremendous community support that pushed the effort from project to a product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The initial XPS 13 developer edition, available only as one configuration, debuted on November 29, 2012.  Fast forward five years and not only are we announcing the 7th generation of that initial product but the project itself has now expanded to become a full line of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dell.com/learn/us/en/555/campaigns/xps-linux-laptop_us&quot;&gt;developer-targeted systems&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;US and Canadian configurations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In North America, as mentioned above, the new XPS 13 developer edition is available in both the US and Canada.  The following are the available configurations in the two countries (Note: the links below point to the US configurations).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CPU | Memory | Storage | Display&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;European configurations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of today, the new XPS 13 developer edition is available online in Europe in the following countries:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UK, Ireland, Germany, Austria, France, Italy, Spain, Switzerland (French and German), Belgium, Netherlands, Sweden, Norway, Denmark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bartongeorge.io/2018/01/04/xps-13-developer-edition-the-7th-gen-is-here/italia-no-screen-visible/&quot; rel=&quot;attachment wp-att-9806&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;9806&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://bartongeorge.io/2018/01/04/xps-13-developer-edition-the-7th-gen-is-here/italia-no-screen-visible/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://barton808.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/italia-no-screen-visible.png&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1058,661&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Italia – No screen visible&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://barton808.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/italia-no-screen-visible.png?w=151&amp;amp;h=94&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://barton808.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/italia-no-screen-visible.png?w=450&quot; class=&quot; wp-image-9806 alignleft&quot; src=&quot;https://barton808.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/italia-no-screen-visible.png?w=151&amp;amp;h=94&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;151&quot; height=&quot;94&quot; srcset=&quot;https://barton808.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/italia-no-screen-visible.png?w=151&amp;amp;h=94 151w, https://barton808.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/italia-no-screen-visible.png?w=302&amp;amp;h=188 302w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 151px) 100vw, 151px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Beyond the thirteen countries above, there is a much longer list of countries where the 9370 is available offline.  (I’ll be posting this list in the next few days.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following configurations are available both online and offline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CPU | Memory | Storage | Display&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;i7 | 16GB |      1TB | UHD touch (3840 x 2160)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;i7 | 16GB | 512GB | UHD touch (3840 x 2160)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;i7 | 16GB | 512GB | FHD non-touch (1920 x 1080)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;i7 |  8GB | 256GB | FHD non-touch (1920 x 1080)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9370 Specifications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a bit more detail behind the system specs.  These options are available as noted above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;8th Generation Intel® Quad Core™, i5 (US and Canada only) and i7 versions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Memory options: 4GB, 8GB or 16GB Dual Channel SDRAM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Storage options: &lt;span&gt;128GB&lt;/span&gt;, 256GB, 512GB or 1TB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ports
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;2x Thunderbolt™ 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Noble lock slot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Headset jack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DC-In &amp;amp; DisplayPort 1x USB-C 3.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MicroSD card reader&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Display options
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;UltraSharp 4K Ultra HD (3840×2160) InfinityEdge touch display&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FHD (1920 x 1080) InfinityEdge display&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ubuntu 16.04 LTS preloaded&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 year ProSupport&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Who’d a thunk it&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I gotta admit that five years ago the team and I would never have thought that we would be posting a blog announcing the 7th generation of the XPS 13 developer edition.  The thought of even a third generation would have bogled our minds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Five years ago, thanks to the support of the community, Project Sputnik reached escape velocity.  This support, input and direction has not only continued but has grown over the last five years, enabling the Sputnik team to stop focusing on survival and instead focus on supporting a broader range of developer needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we go forward, please keep driving us by sharing your input and experiences, be they be good, bad or ugly. 🙂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Barton&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Extra-credit reading&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;entry-title&quot;&gt;Line up — New XPS 13 developer edition —  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dell.com/en-us/work/shop/dell-laptops-and-notebooks/xps-13-developer-edition/spd/xps-13-9370-laptop?appliedRefinements=301&quot;&gt;(9370)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Line up — XPS 13 developer edition — &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dell.com/en-us/work/shop/cty/pdp/spd/xps-13-9360-laptop?3x_nav=OS_BRAND%3DUBUNT&amp;amp;3x_page=1&amp;amp;filterCollapsed=true&amp;amp;appliedRefinements=302&quot;&gt;(9360)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Project Sputnik Turns Five! – &lt;a href=&quot;https://bartongeorge.io/2017/11/29/project-sputnik-turns-five/&quot;&gt;November 29, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2012 — year one
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pau for now…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wpcnt&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wpa wpmrec&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;wpa-about&quot;&gt;Advertisements&lt;/span&gt;



&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;jp-post-flair&quot; class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-rating-enabled sd-like-enabled sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;robots-nocontent sd-block sd-social sd-social-icon-text sd-sharing&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Share this:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-block sd-like jetpack-likes-widget-wrapper jetpack-likes-widget-unloaded&quot; id=&quot;like-post-wrapper-4695609-9801-5a4fa083a359a&quot; data-src=&quot;//widgets.wp.com/likes/#blog_id=4695609&amp;amp;post_id=9801&amp;amp;origin=barton808.wordpress.com&amp;amp;obj_id=4695609-9801-5a4fa083a359a&quot; data-name=&quot;like-post-frame-4695609-9801-5a4fa083a359a&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Like this:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;button&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Like&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;loading&quot;&gt;Loading...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;jp-relatedposts-headline&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Related&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;postmetadata alt&quot;&gt;&lt;small&gt;This entry was posted on Thursday, January 4th, 2018 at 10:54 am and is filed under &lt;a href=&quot;https://bartongeorge.io/category/uncategorized/&quot; rel=&quot;category tag&quot;&gt;Uncategorized&lt;/a&gt;. You can follow any responses to this entry through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://bartongeorge.io/2018/01/04/xps-13-developer-edition-the-7th-gen-is-here/feed/&quot;&gt;RSS 2.0&lt;/a&gt; feed. You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://bartongeorge.io/2018/01/04/xps-13-developer-edition-the-7th-gen-is-here/#respond&quot;&gt;leave a response&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://bartongeorge.io/2018/01/04/xps-13-developer-edition-the-7th-gen-is-here/trackback/&quot; rel=&quot;trackback&quot;&gt;trackback&lt;/a&gt; from your own site.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;nav id=&quot;nav-below&quot;&gt;&lt;h3 class=&quot;assistive-text&quot;&gt;Post navigation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nav-previous&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bartongeorge.io/2017/11/29/project-sputnik-turns-five/&quot; rel=&quot;prev&quot;&gt;« Previous Post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/nav&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 19:01:48 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>warp</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>XPS 13 Developer Edition — the 7th gen is here!</og:title>
<og:url>https://bartongeorge.io/2018/01/04/xps-13-developer-edition-the-7th-gen-is-here/</og:url>
<og:description>Today I am excited to announce the availability of the 7th generation of the Ubuntu-based XPS 13 developer edition.  Project Sputnik’s latest and greatest system is now simultaneously availab…</og:description>
<og:image>https://barton808.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/italia-no-screen-visible.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://bartongeorge.io/2018/01/04/xps-13-developer-edition-the-7th-gen-is-here/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Intel Issues Updates to Protect Systems from Security Exploits</title>
<link>https://newsroom.intel.com/news-releases/intel-issues-updates-protect-systems-security-exploits/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://newsroom.intel.com/news-releases/intel-issues-updates-protect-systems-security-exploits/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;SANTA CLARA, Calif., Jan. 4, 2018 — Intel has developed and is rapidly issuing updates for all types of Intel-based computer systems — including personal computers and servers — that render those systems immune from both exploits (referred to as “Spectre” and “Meltdown”) reported by Google Project Zero. Intel and its partners have made significant progress in deploying updates as both software patches and firmware updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MORE:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://newsroom.intel.com/news/intel-responds-to-security-research-findings/&quot;&gt;Intel Responds to Security Research Findings&lt;/a&gt; (Jan. 3, 2018) | &lt;a href=&quot;https://newsroom.intel.com/news-releases/industry-testing-shows-recently-released-security-updates-not-impacting-performance-real-world-deployments/&quot;&gt;Industry Testing Shows Recently Released Security Updates Not Impacting Performance in Real-World Deployments&lt;/a&gt; (Jan. 4, 2018) | &lt;a href=&quot;https://newsroom.intel.com/press-kits/security-exploits-intel-products/&quot;&gt;Security Exploits and Intel Products&lt;/a&gt; (Press Kit) | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.intel.com/content/www/us/en/architecture-and-technology/facts-about-side-channel-analysis-and-intel-products.html&quot;&gt;Facts about The New Security Research Findings and Intel Products&lt;/a&gt; (Intel.com)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intel has already issued updates for the majority of processor products introduced within the past five years. By the end of next week, Intel expects to have issued updates for more than 90 percent of processor products introduced within the past five years. In addition, many operating system vendors, public cloud service providers, device manufacturers and others have indicated that they have already updated their products and services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intel continues to believe that the performance impact of these updates is highly workload-dependent and, for the average computer user, should not be significant and will be mitigated over time. While on some discrete workloads the performance impact from the software updates may initially be higher, additional post-deployment identification, testing and improvement of the software updates should mitigate that impact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;System updates are made available by system manufacturers, operating system providers and others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intel will continue to work with its partners and others to address these issues, and Intel appreciates their support and assistance. Intel encourages computer users worldwide to utilize the automatic update functions of their operating systems and other computer software to ensure their systems are up-to-date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For information and links to useful resources, visit the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.intel.com/content/www/us/en/architecture-and-technology/facts-about-side-channel-analysis-and-intel-products.html&quot;&gt;security research findings page on Intel.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 17:53:36 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>runesoerensen</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Intel Issues Updates to Protect Systems from Security Exploits | Intel Newsroom</og:title>
<og:description>SANTA CLARA, Calif., Jan. 4, 2018 — Intel has developed and is rapidly issuing updates for all types of Intel-based computer systems — including personal computers and servers — that render those systems immune from both exploits (referred to as “Spectre” and “Meltdown”) reported by Google Project Zero. Intel and its partners have made significant … Continued</og:description>
<og:url>https://newsroom.intel.com/news-releases/intel-issues-updates-protect-systems-security-exploits/</og:url>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://newsroom.intel.com/news-releases/intel-issues-updates-protect-systems-security-exploits/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>