<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>iPhone 11 Pro and iPhone 11 Pro Max</title>
<link>https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2019/09/iphone-11-pro-and-iphone-11-pro-max-the-most-powerful-and-advanced-smartphones/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2019/09/iphone-11-pro-and-iphone-11-pro-max-the-most-powerful-and-advanced-smartphones/</guid>
<description>&lt;h3 class=&quot;pagebody-header&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pro Design and Display&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;iPhone 11 Pro and iPhone 11 Pro Max have a textured matte glass back and polished stainless steel band, and come in four stunning finishes including a beautiful new midnight green. The most powerful devices are also designed to be durable — iPhone 11 Pro and iPhone 11 Pro Max feature the toughest glass ever in a smartphone and are rated IP68 for water resistance up to 4 meters for up to 30 minutes, and are protected against everyday spills including coffee and soda.&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new Super Retina XDR display, a custom-designed OLED, provides users an immersive HDR viewing experience for movies and other high-definition video with up to 1,200 nits brightness. Super Retina XDR features wide color support with system-wide color management and True Tone to offer a more natural viewing experience. With a 2 million-to-one contrast ratio with true blacks, pro users can enjoy a more vivid viewing experience for HDR videos and photos, and the Super Retina XDR display is even more power efficient. Customers can interact with their favorite apps in a quick, seamless way with Haptic Touch deeply integrated across iOS 13 to provide app shortcuts for everyday tasks right from the Home screen, including taking a selfie in Camera, checking an appointment in Calendar or previewing email within Mail with just a simple press.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 18:39:58 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Zaheer</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>iPhone 11 Pro and iPhone 11 Pro Max: the most powerful and advanced smartphones</og:title>
<og:description>Apple today announced iPhone 11 Pro and iPhone 11 Pro Max, a new pro line for iPhone that delivers advanced performance.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2019/09/iphone-11-pro-and-iphone-11-pro-max-the-most-powerful-and-advanced-smartphones/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/iphone/standard/Apple_iPhone-11-Pro_Most-Powerful-Advanced_091019_LP_hero.jpg.og.jpg?201909102254</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2019/09/iphone-11-pro-and-iphone-11-pro-max-the-most-powerful-and-advanced-smartphones/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Uber lays off 435 people</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/10/uber-lays-off-435-people-across-engineering-and-product-teams/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/10/uber-lays-off-435-people-across-engineering-and-product-teams/</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/uber&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;uber&quot;&gt;Uber&lt;/a&gt; has laid off 435 employees across its product and engineering teams, the company announced today. Combined, the layoffs represent about 8% of the organization, with 170 people leaving the product team and 265 people leaving the engineering team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The layoffs had no effect on Eats, which is one of Uber’s top-performing products, and Freight, according to a source familiar with the situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the company is lifting the hiring freeze on the product and engineering teams that has been in effect since early August, according to the source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Our hope with these changes is to reset and improve how we work day to day — ruthlessly prioritizing, and always holding ourselves accountable to a high bar of performance and agility,” an Uber spokesperson told TechCrunch. “While certainly painful in the moment, especially for those directly affected, we believe that this will result in a much stronger technical organization, which going forward will continue to hire some of the very best talent around the world.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of those laid off, more than 85% are based in the U.S.; 10% are in Asia-Pacific and 5% are in Europe, the Middle East and Africa, according to the source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The layoffs came after Uber CEO Dara Khosrowshahi asked every member of his executive leadership team if they were to start from scratch, would their respective organizations look the way they do today?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“After careful consideration, our Engineering and Product leaders concluded the answer to this question in many respects was ‘no,’ ” the spokesperson said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those leaders are Chief Product Officer Manik Gupta and CTO Thuan Pham. They looked at team size, identified duplicate roles and overlapping work, as well as individual performance to determine who would be laid off, the source said. That’s how they landed on focusing more on the design and research teams from the product side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Previously, to meet the demands of a hyper-growth startup, we hired rapidly and in a decentralized way,” the spokesperson said. “While this worked for Uber in the past, now that we have over 27,000 full-time employees in cities around the world, we need to shift how we design our organizations: lean, exceptionally high-performing teams, with clear mandates and the ability to execute faster than our competitors.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These layoffs come shortly after &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/29/uber-lays-off-400-employees-as-part-of-marketing-team-restructuring/&quot;&gt;Uber laid off 400 people&lt;/a&gt; from its marketing team. In Q2 2019, Uber lost more than $5 billion — its biggest quarterly revenue loss to date — though a chunk of its losses were a result of stock-based compensation expenses for employees following the company’s IPO in May. While it may seem these layoffs are in response to those quarterly losses, Uber says the conversations have been ongoing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Uber lays off its W-2 employees, it’s simultaneously investing in ensuring its 1099 independent contractors remain classified in that way. In light of gig worker protection bill AB-5 advancing through the California legislature, &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/29/uber-and-lyft-are-putting-60-million-toward-keeping-drivers-independent-contractors/&quot;&gt;Uber, along with Lyft and DoorDash&lt;/a&gt;, put $30 million toward a 2020 ballot initiative that would enable them to keep their drivers as independent contractors. If AB-5 passes, Uber would see a significant uptick in costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uber is currently trading at $33.14 per share, well below its IPO pricing of $45.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s Uber’s full statement:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;39&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our CEO has asked everyone on our management team a simple but important question: if we started from scratch, would we design our organizations as they stand today? After careful consideration, our Engineering and Product leaders concluded the answer to this question in many respects was no. Previously, to meet the demands of a hyper-growth startup, we hired rapidly and in a decentralized way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this worked for Uber in the past, now that we have over 27,000 full-time employees in cities around the world, we need to shift how we design our organizations: lean, exceptionally high-performing teams, with clear mandates and the ability to execute faster than our competitors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, we’re making some changes to get us back on track, which include reducing the size of some teams to ensure we are staffed appropriately against our top priorities. These were incredibly difficult calls as it means some of our employees no longer have a role, specifically around 170 people in our Product group and 265 people in Engineering, which is roughly 8 percent of those two orgs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our hope with these changes is to reset and improve how we work day to day—ruthlessly prioritizing, and always holding ourselves accountable to a high bar of performance and agility. While certainly painful in the moment, especially for those directly affected, we believe that this will result in a much stronger technical organization, which going forward will continue to hire some of the very best talent around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 18:37:01 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>coloneltcb</dc:creator>
<og:title>Uber lays off 435 people across engineering and product teams – TechCrunch</og:title>
<og:description>Uber has laid off 435 employees across its product and engineering teams, the company announced today. Combined, the layoffs represent about 8% of the organization, with 170 people leaving the product team and 265 people leaving the engineering team. The layoffs had no effect on Eats, which is one …</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/disruptsf18_dara_khosrowshahi_uber-0943.jpg?w=600</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2019/09/10/uber-lays-off-435-people-across-engineering-and-product-teams/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/10/uber-lays-off-435-people-across-engineering-and-product-teams/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Bring Back the SE</title>
<link>https://avc.com/2019/09/bring-back-the-se/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://avc.com/2019/09/bring-back-the-se/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Today Apple is going to announce three new iPhones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of them should be a small form factor like the old SE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple discontinued the iPhone SE at the tail end of 2018 and has stated that the next iOS update will not run on the old SE hardware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a number of friends and family members who have the old SE, love the small form factor, and do not want a larger phone in their pockets, purses, and hands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result, these people have been holding onto phones that have gotten a bit old and badly in need of an upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But more importantly in my view, if Apple wants to tightly control the hardware that iOS can run on (which obviously they do), then they should put a wide enough variety of hardware into the market to support their user base.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is unlikely that any of my friends and family members are going to move to Android, where there is a wide variety of hardware form factors to choose from. The iOS lockin is very powerful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So Apple doesn’t need to do this so much for business reasons. But I do think they should do this for other reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 18:25:06 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>abhi3</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://avc.com/2019/09/bring-back-the-se/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Apple Watch Series 5</title>
<link>https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2019/09/apple-unveils-apple-watch-series-5/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2019/09/apple-unveils-apple-watch-series-5/</guid>
<description>Cupertino, California — Apple today announced &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/apple-watch-series-5/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Apple Watch Series 5&lt;/a&gt;, debuting an Always-On Retina display that never sleeps, so it’s easy to see the time and other important information, without raising or tapping the display. New location features, from a built-in compass to current elevation, help users better navigate their day, while international emergency calling&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; allows customers to call emergency services directly from Apple Watch in over 150 countries, even without iPhone nearby. Apple Watch Series 5 is available in a wider range of materials, including aluminum, stainless steel, ceramic and an all-new titanium. Combined with the power of watchOS 6, users are empowered to take charge of their health and fitness with new features like Cycle Tracking, the Noise app and Activity Trends.</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 17:50:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>UkiahSmith</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Apple unveils Apple Watch Series 5</og:title>
<og:description>Apple today announced Apple Watch Series 5, debuting an Always-On Retina display that never sleeps.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2019/09/apple-unveils-apple-watch-series-5/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/watch/standard/Apple_watch_series_5_introduces-always-on-retina-display_091019_LP_hero.jpg.og.jpg?201909102254</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2019/09/apple-unveils-apple-watch-series-5/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: Browse Reddit in 3D</title>
<link>https://3dforreddit.com/r/pics</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://3dforreddit.com/r/pics</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://3dforreddit.com/r/pics&quot;&gt;https://3dforreddit.com/r/pics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20929801&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20929801&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 540&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 135&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 16:13:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>masterspy7</dc:creator>
<og:title>3D for Reddit</og:title>
<og:description>Browse Reddit in 3D</og:description>
<og:image>https://3dforreddit.com/assets/images/example.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://3dforreddit.com/r/pics</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>It&amp;#039;s later than you think</title>
<link>https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/its-later-than-you-think-j-r-storment/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/its-later-than-you-think-j-r-storment/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Eight years ago, during the same month, I had twin boys and co-founded Cloudability. About three months ago Cloudability was acquired. About three weeks ago we lost one of our boys.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I got the call I was sitting in a conference room with 12 people at our Portland office talking about PTO policies. Minutes earlier, I had admitted to the group that in the last 8 years I’d not taken more than a contiguous week off.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My wife and I have an agreement that when one of us calls, the other answers. So when the phone rang I stood up and walked to the conference room door immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was still walking through the door when I answered with “Hey, what’s up?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her reply was icy and immediate: “J.R., Wiley is dead.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What?” I responded incredulously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Wiley has died.” she reiterated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What?! No.” I yelled out, “No!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I’m so sorry, I have to call 911.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was the entire conversation. The next thing I know I’m sprinting out the front door of the office with my car keys in hand, running ferociously across the street and muttering “oh Fuck. oh Fuck. oh Fuck.”. Half way down the block I realize I don’t have the opener to my parking garage. Running back into the lobby, I all but shout “Someone drive me! Somebody drive me!” Thankfully, a helpful colleague did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the time I got home twelve minutes later, our cul-de-sac was packed with emergency vehicles. I sprinted through our open front door and ran straight towards the bedroom that the boys share. One of a half-dozen police officers there stepped in front of me blocking the way. When a child dies suddenly, it becomes a potential crime scene. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was 2.5 painful hours before I could see my boy. After an hour of waiting in shock out front, I told the armed police officers guarding the doors that I couldn’t wait any longer. They allowed me to go out to the deck facing the kids room to peer through the sliding glass window. He lay in his bed, covers neatly on, looking peacefully asleep. I put my hand on the glass and lost it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the medical examiner finally finished his work, we were allowed in the room. An eerie calm came over me. I laid down next to him in the bed that he loved, held his hand and kept repeating, “What happened, buddy? What happened?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We stayed next to him for maybe 30 minutes and stroked his hair before they returned with a gurney to take him away. I walked him out, holding his hand and his forehead through the body bag as he was wheeled down our driveway. Then all the cars drove away. The last one to leave was the black minivan with Wiley in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;slate-resizable-image-embed slate-image-embed__resize-full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;No alt text provided for this image&quot; data-media-urn=&quot;&quot; data-li-src=&quot;https://media.licdn.com/dms/image/C4E12AQF9UnMZQY_djA/article-inline_image-shrink_1500_2232/0?e=1573689600&amp;amp;v=beta&amp;amp;t=B7hCaxJQKGr1BAa9C2vtJxIfTaJmZb1h8rr10DC_Fs8&quot; src=&quot;https://:0/&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A journal of Wiley’s we found the day after he died. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wiley was obsessed with starting a business. One day it was a smoothie stand, the next it would be a gallery, then a VR headset company, then a ‘coder’, then a spaceship building company. In each of these scenarios he was the boss. His brother (and sometimes us) were invited to work for—not with— him and were each assigned jobs. In the gallery scenario, Wiley informed Oliver that he would be manning the cash register.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around 5 years old, Wiley decided he was going to get married as an adult. By 6 he had identified the girl, holding her hand at recess on the first day of kindergarten. Over the next two years as we moved from Portland to London to Hawaii, he kept in touch with her by handwritten letter. Not long before we moved back to Portland, the two agreed (by letter) to marry. She beat him to the punch and asked him. He accepted. Happily, he got to see her twice after we moved back to Portland in June. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the countless difficult moments of this month was signing his death certificate. Seeing his name written on the top of it was hard. However, two fields further down the form crushed me. The first said: “Occupation: Never worked” and the next: “Marital Status: Never married”. He wanted so badly to do both of those things. I feel both fortunate and guilty to have had success in each. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the last three weeks I have come up with an endless stream of things I regret. They tend to fall into two categories: things I wish I had done differently and things I’m sad not to see him do. My wife is constantly reminding me of all the things he did do: Wiley went to 10 countries, drove a car on a farm road in Hawaii, hiked in Greece, snorkeled in Fiji, wore a suit to a fantastic British prep school every day for two years, got rescued from a shark on a jet ski, kissed multiple girls, got good enough at chess to beat me twice in a row, wrote short stories and drew comics obsessively. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then he died in his bed overnight. The evening before was normal. Wiley was healthy and engaged. We had friends with kids over for dinner. We all jumped on the giant trampoline that had been the first purchase for the house we had bought just a few weeks ago. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That evening Wiley got be bossy with the other kids (other than his mother, he was one of the most opinionated people I know) and started telling everyone they were playing the game wrong. I pulled him aside. I was stern with him. Too stern in hindsight. And I made him cry. It’s one of the last interactions we had and I’ve beaten myself up for it a dozen times. I can still see the tears rolling down his face and the protestations of “But you’re not listening to me. No one listens to me”. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few hours later, things had calmed down. We ordered take out and Wiley ate his favorite meal: rice with yellow dahl. Then we put the kids to bed. I had a very sweet interaction with Wiley at bedtime and apologized for making him cry. We had a good snuggle and I went to bed myself. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About 15 minutes later, I was laying in bed and through the darkened room saw his half naked form—always impossibly tall and lean for his age— walking up the stairs to our bedroom. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Papa, I can’t sleep.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was loud music playing outside from a neighbor’s party and it was keeping him awake. I walked him back to his room and shut all the windows. He said that was better. We had another quick snuggle and a sweet exchange. Then I went to bed for good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around 5:40am, the next morning I woke up for a series of back to back meetings. I did a Peloton ride, took an analyst call from my home office, one with a colleague on the drive to work, then the rest at the office. None seem that important now. I left that morning without saying goodbye or checking on the boys. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Late that morning, Jessica had thought Wiley was simply sleeping in. He loved to sleep, he loved his bed, and it had been a big week of late bedtimes and fun daytime activities with visiting friends. Eventually she got the sense it had been too long and went in to check on him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was cold. The Medical Examiner later estimated he had been dead for at least 8-10 hours by the time she found him, indicating he passed early in the night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year, Wiley was diagnosed with a typically mild form of epilepsy called Benign Rolandic Epilepsy that is most common in boys between 8-13. It’s called ‘benign’ because it typically resolves on its own by the teenage years. Wiley’s was light: we only saw a single confirmed seizure occur. It happened about 9 months ago while we were visiting Portland from the UK. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of the multiple pediatricians and neurologists with whom we discussed his condition said there was little to be concerned about. He had the “best” type of epilepsy and we should let it run his course. None mentioned what ultimately killed him. SUDEP is shorthand for Sudden Unexplained Death of Epilepsy. It’s rare enough that there is a philosophical debate in the neurology community about whether to proactively tell parents about it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SUDEP is generally seen to be unpredictable, unpreventable, and irreversible once it starts. It can be tied to a seizure but many times the brain just shuts down. Statistically, it was highly unlikely to hit our son: 1 out of 4,500 children with epilepsy are affected. Sometimes you end up the statistic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many have asked what they can do to help. Hug your kids. Don’t work too late. A lot of the things you are likely spending your time on you’ll regret once you no longer have the time. I’m guessing you have 1:1 meetings on the books with a lot of people you work with. Do you have them regularly scheduled with your kids? If there’s any lesson to take away from this, it’s to remind others (and myself) not to miss out on the things that matter. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven’t gone back to work yet. So, if you’ve emailed or messaged me, it’s likely I haven’t replied. When I do go back, I may end up declaring an &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Email_bankruptcy&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;email bankruptcy.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The big question is how to return to work in a way that won’t leave me again with the regrets I have now. To be honest, I’ve considered not going back. But I believe in the words of Kahlil Gibran who said, “Work is love made visible.'' To me, that line is a testament to how much we gain, grow and offer through the work we do. But that work needs to have a balance that I have rarely lived. It’s a balance that lets us offer our gifts to the world but not at the cost of self and family. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I sat writing this post, my living son, Oliver, came in to ask for screen time. Instead of saying the usual ‘no’, I stopped writing and asked if I could play with him. He was happily surprised by my answer and we connected in a way I would have formerly missed out on. Small things matter. One silver lining from this tragedy is the improving relationship I have with him. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our family has gone from having two units of two (the parents and the twins) to now being a triangle of three. That’s a big adjustment for a family that has always been four. Oliver’s brilliant reply when we discussed the shape of our new family: “But Papa, the triangle is the strongest shape.” By some sad and beautiful irony, Oliver has met three sets of 8-year-old twins in our new neighborhood since Wiley passed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve learned to stop waiting to do the things the kids ask for. When we sold the business I gave each of the boys a $100 dollar bill. They decided to pool their money to buy a tent for camping. But we didn’t make it happen before Wiley died. Another regret. So, after the first round of family visits after his death, I took Jessica and Oliver to REI to get gear and we left town quickly to camp near Mt. St. Helens. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somehow, we got to the wilderness without enough cash to cover the campground fee and had a slight panic. Jessica then realized that Wiley’s $100 bill was still in his seat pocket. He got to spend his money on camping after all. Collectively, the family said a big, “Thanks, buddy” out-loud to him. It was one of many bittersweet moments we will experience for the rest of our lives. Each happy time brings with it the sadness that he doesn’t get to experience it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of Wiley's happy times was listening to music and dancing. Damn, could that kid dance. He loved the Oregon Country Fair and the year before we left for London, we listened to a band there play a version of “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nFxjnUPRwx4&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Enjoy yourself (It’s later than you think)&lt;/a&gt;”. The words stuck with me that day three years ago and painfully so now:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“You work and work for years and years, you're always on the go&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You never take a minute off, too busy makin' dough&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Someday, you say, you'll have your fun, when you're a millionaire&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Imagine all the fun you'll have in your old rockin' chair&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Enjoy yourself, it's later than you think&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Enjoy yourself, while you're still in the pink&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The years go by, as quickly as a wink&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Enjoy yourself, enjoy yourself, it's later than you think”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As my wife writes in her beautiful post (she’s always more eloquent than I am), &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/all-remains-dr-jessica-brandes/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;All That Remains&lt;/a&gt;, “Please ask us about our son’s life and his death. We heal in small bits while talking about it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of these ashes have come many new and restored connections. Thank you for being one of mine. And I hope from this tragedy you consider how you prioritize your own time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 14:27:37 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>cloudytoday</dc:creator>
<og:title>It's later than you think</og:title>
<og:description>Eight years ago, during the same month, I had twin boys and co-founded Cloudability. About three months ago Cloudability was acquired.</og:description>
<og:image>https://media.licdn.com/dms/image/C4E12AQGep8inE3ZM6A/article-cover_image-shrink_720_1280/0?e=1573689600&amp;v=beta&amp;t=-sIsGSPnPdS2AaAVqZPW9m8oKzwmPxua1n0oNUHT6Hw</og:image>
<og:url>https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/its-later-than-you-think-j-r-storment</og:url>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/its-later-than-you-think-j-r-storment/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Stripe Corporate Card</title>
<link>https://stripe.com/corporate-card</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://stripe.com/corporate-card</guid>
<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://b.stripecdn.com/site-srv/assets/img/v3/card/moonlight_logo-29af4f4cfec5f6a83e444dd43bdf519cc4e20202.svg&quot; class=&quot;image Helm-Endorsement__logo&quot; alt=&quot;Moonlight logo&quot;/&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;Helm-Endorsement__quote&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;common-MediumBodyText Helm__text--slate3&quot;&gt;We’ve saved our employees hours of time on expense reporting and reimbursement processes. Now, all our expenses are automatically uploaded and tracked right in the Dashboard.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class-name=&quot;Helm-Endorsement__attributionName&quot; class=&quot;common-UppercaseText Helm__text--slate1 Helm-Endorsement__attributionName&quot;&gt;Philip Thomas&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class-name=&quot;Helm-Endorsement__attributionTitle&quot; class=&quot;common-BodyText Helm__text--slate1 Helm-Endorsement__attributionTitle&quot;&gt;Co-founder &amp;amp; CEO, Moonlight&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://b.stripecdn.com/site-srv/assets/img/v3/card/whimsical_logo-7ea19335056e5fef180d63da978f0b744ed2d090.svg&quot; class=&quot;image Helm-Endorsement__logo&quot; alt=&quot;Whimsical logo&quot;/&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;Helm-Endorsement__quote&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;common-MediumBodyText Helm__text--slate3&quot;&gt;Getting set up on our Stripe Corporate Card was so easy. We were able to link our bank account and provision cards in a matter of minutes.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class-name=&quot;Helm-Endorsement__attributionName&quot; class=&quot;common-UppercaseText Helm__text--slate1 Helm-Endorsement__attributionName&quot;&gt;Kaspars Dancis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class-name=&quot;Helm-Endorsement__attributionTitle&quot; class=&quot;common-BodyText Helm__text--slate1 Helm-Endorsement__attributionTitle&quot;&gt;Co-founder &amp;amp; CEO, Whimsical&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 14:12:22 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>eloycoto</dc:creator>
<og:title>Stripe Corporate Card: The corporate card for fast-growing businesses</og:title>
<og:url>https://stripe.com/corporate-card</og:url>
<og:description>Set custom spending controls, reconcile expenses automatically with software like Expensify, and earn extra cash back where you spend the most each month.</og:description>
<og:image>https://stripe.com/img/v3/card/social.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://stripe.com/corporate-card</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Firefox’s Test Pilot Program Returns</title>
<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/blog/2019/09/10/firefoxs-test-pilot-program-returns-with-firefox-private-network-beta/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.mozilla.org/blog/2019/09/10/firefoxs-test-pilot-program-returns-with-firefox-private-network-beta/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Like a cat, the Test Pilot program has had many lives. It originally started as &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/blog/2009/08/12/mozilla-labs-launches-test-pilot-add-on-for-firefox-3-5/&quot;&gt;an Add-on&lt;/a&gt; before &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/blog/2016/05/10/you-can-help-build-the-future-of-firefox-with-the-new-test-pilot-program/&quot;&gt;we relaunched it three years ago&lt;/a&gt;. Then in January, we announced that we were &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/blog/2019/01/15/evolving-firefoxs-culture-of-experimentation-a-thank-you-from-the-test-pilot-program/&quot;&gt;evolving our culture of experimentation&lt;/a&gt;, and as a result we closed the Test Pilot program to give us time to further explore what was next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/firefox-test-pilot/adios-amigo-51bec2a00072&quot;&gt;learned a lot from the Test Pilot program&lt;/a&gt;. First, we had a loyal group of users who provided us feedback on projects that weren’t polished or ready for general consumption. Based on that input we refined and revamped various features and services, and in some cases shelved projects altogether because they didn’t meet the needs of our users. The feedback we received helped us evaluate a variety of potential Firefox features, some of which are in the Firefox browser today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t heard, third time’s the charm. We’re turning to our loyal and faithful users, specifically &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/blog/2019/06/04/the-web-the-world-needs-can-be-ours-again-if-we-want-it/&quot;&gt;the ones who signed up for a Firefox account and opted-in to be in the know about new products testing&lt;/a&gt;, and are giving them a first crack to test-drive new, privacy-centric products as part of the relaunched Test Pilot program. The difference with the newly relaunched Test Pilot program is that these products and services may be outside the Firefox browser, and will be far more polished, and just one step shy of general public release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve already earmarked a couple of new products that we plan to fine-tune before their official release as part of the relaunched Test Pilot program. Because of how much we learned from our users through the Test Pilot program, and our ongoing commitment to build our products and services to meet people’s online needs, we’re kicking off our relaunch of the Test Pilot program by beta testing our project code named Firefox Private Network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Try our first beta – Firefox Private Network&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the key learnings from recent events is that there is growing demand for privacy features. The Firefox Private Network is an extension which provides a secure, encrypted path to the web to protect your connection and your personal information anywhere and everywhere you use your Firefox browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many ways that your personal information and data are exposed: online threats are everywhere, whether it’s through phishing emails or data breaches. You may often find yourself taking advantage of the free WiFi at the doctor’s office, airport or a cafe. There can be dozens of people using the same network — casually checking the web and getting social media updates. This leaves your personal information vulnerable to those who may be lurking, waiting to take advantage of this situation to gain access to your personal info. Using the Firefox Private Network helps protect you from hackers lurking in plain sight on public connections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://private-network.firefox.com/?utm_source=Blog&amp;amp;utm_medium=AnnouncementPost&amp;amp;utm_campaign=FPN_Beta&quot;&gt;Start testing the Firefox Private Network today&lt;/a&gt;, it’s currently available in the US on the Firefox desktop browser. A Firefox account allows you to be one of the first to test potential new products and services, you can sign up directly from the extension.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-12319 size-large&quot; src=&quot;https://ffp4g1ylyit3jdyti1hqcvtb-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/FPN-website-600x433.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;433&quot; srcset=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/FPN-website-600x433.png 600w, https://blog.mozilla.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/FPN-website-300x217.png 300w, https://blog.mozilla.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/FPN-website-768x554.png 768w, https://blog.mozilla.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/FPN-website-1000x722.png 1000w, https://blog.mozilla.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/FPN-website.png 1582w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Key features of Firefox Private Network are:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Protection when in public WiFi access points&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; – Whether you are waiting at your doctor’s office, the airport or working from your favorite coffee shop, your connection to the internet is protected when you use the Firefox browser thanks to a secure tunnel to the web, protecting all your sensitive information like the web addresses you visit, personal and financial information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Internet Protocol (IP) addresses are hidden so it’s harder to track you&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; – Your IP address is like a home address for your computer. One of the reasons why you may want to keep it hidden is to keep advertising networks from tracking your browsing history. Firefox Private Network will mask your IP address providing protection from third party trackers around the web.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Toggle the switch on at any time.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; By clicking in the browser extension, you will find an on/off toggle that shows you whether you are currently protected, which you can turn on at anytime if you’d like additional privacy protection, or off if not needed at that moment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Your feedback on Firefox Private Network beta is important&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the next several months you will see a number of variations on our testing of the Firefox Private Network. This iterative process will give us much-needed feedback to explore technical and possible pricing options for the different online needs that the Firefox Private Network meets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your feedback will be essential in making sure that we offer a full complement of services that address the problems you face online with the right-priced service solutions. We depend on your feedback and we will send a survey to follow up. We hope you can spend a few minutes to complete it and let us know what you think. Please note this first Firefox Private Network Beta test will only be available to start in the United States for Firefox account holders using desktop devices. We’ll keep you updated on our eventual beta test roll-outs in other locales and platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sign up now for a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/accounts/&quot;&gt;Firefox account&lt;/a&gt; and join the fight to keep the internet open and accessible to all.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 13:23:47 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jgrahamc</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://blog.mozilla.org/blog/2019/09/10/firefoxs-test-pilot-program-returns-with-firefox-private-network-beta</og:url>
<og:title>Firefox’s Test Pilot Program Returns with Firefox Private Network Beta – The Mozilla Blog</og:title>
<og:description>We’re kicking off our relaunch of the Test Pilot program by beta testing our project code named Firefox Private Network.</og:description>
<og:image>https://blog.mozilla.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/FFSP-blog-2.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.mozilla.org/blog/2019/09/10/firefoxs-test-pilot-program-returns-with-firefox-private-network-beta/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>American Phrase Book</title>
<link>http://alumni.media.mit.edu/~guy/american/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://alumni.media.mit.edu/~guy/american/</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;intro&quot; readability=&quot;26&quot;&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people moving to the U.S assume that they pretty much know English. After all, they have studied the language and watched many hours of American TV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon arrival it is therefore often to their surprise how many seemingly simple phrases actually turn out to mean something completely different in the US American variant of the English language. Interpreting these phrases literally, results in misunderstandings that can at times lead to severe complications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This phrase book is aimed to help newcomers to the U.S understand what some popular local idioms really mean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More generally, the immigrant should keep in mind a golden rule: US natives will usually phrase everything in a manner that creates the least social friction in any given interaction. In most cases this results in shying away from a negative description or opinion. Almost as often, it even means not saying &lt;em&gt;anything&lt;/em&gt; definite, and instead just stating possibilities and options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;update&quot;&gt;Last updated: 26 Aug 13&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;dict&quot; readability=&quot;126.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;heading&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phrase&quot;&gt;Phrase&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meaning&quot;&gt;Meaning&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;Example&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot; readability=&quot;38&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phrase&quot;&gt;Let's have lunch sometime!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meaning&quot;&gt;I don't want to see you again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;-&quot;There's still so much more I want to talk to you about!&quot;&lt;br /&gt;-&quot;Yeah, let's definitely have lunch sometime!&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot; readability=&quot;34&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phrase&quot;&gt;Thanks for reminding me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meaning&quot;&gt;Stop bugging me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;-&quot;Did you ever get a chance to look over that memo I sent you?&quot;&lt;br /&gt;-&quot;Oh, right! Thanks so much for reminding me! I'll get back to you on that soon.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot; readability=&quot;35&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phrase&quot;&gt;Some are better than others&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meaning&quot;&gt;Some are crap&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;-&quot;I do like my classes, but really I have to say that some are better than others.&quot;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot; readability=&quot;36&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phrase&quot;&gt;He/She is quite the character&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meaning&quot;&gt;He/She is scary and/or repulsive&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;-&quot;You know Jenny? She is quite the character. I don't know what to make of her.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phrase&quot;&gt;Thank you *so* much!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meaning&quot;&gt;Thanks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;-&quot;Can you pass me the milk?&quot;&lt;br /&gt;-&quot;There you go.&quot;&lt;br /&gt;-&quot;Thank you *so* much!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot; readability=&quot;35&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phrase&quot;&gt;Thanks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meaning&quot;&gt;[This phrase doesn't have a meaning per se]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;-&quot;Please send me the material by monday. Dave.&quot;&lt;br /&gt;-&quot;Here it is. Thanks, George.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot; readability=&quot;36&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phrase&quot;&gt;You would want to do X&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meaning&quot;&gt;Do X now! [Strong Imperative]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;-&quot;Sir, you would want to take your feet off this bench.&quot;&lt;br /&gt;-&quot;Of course, officer.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot; readability=&quot;36&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phrase&quot;&gt;You might want to consider to do X&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meaning&quot;&gt;I absolutely expect you to do X [Weak Imperative]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;-&quot;You might want to consider to postpone your trip until after the deadline.&quot;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot; readability=&quot;36&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phrase&quot;&gt;That's a great idea, but...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meaning&quot;&gt;That's a bad idea&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;-&quot;So I really think that's a great idea, but you might want to consider the opposite approach&quot;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phrase&quot;&gt;Would you like some gum/mint?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meaning&quot;&gt;You have bad breath&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;[Self-explanatory]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot; readability=&quot;36&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phrase&quot;&gt;Friend&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meaning&quot;&gt;Someone you've met at least once and didn't cause you any harm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;-&quot;Harvey, I'd like you to meet my friend, Je... Ji.... hmmm.. er... what was your name again?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phrase&quot;&gt;The most&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meaning&quot;&gt;A [Indefinite Article]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;-&quot;I just watched the most depressing movie&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phrase&quot;&gt;Good job!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meaning&quot;&gt;You didn't fail&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;-&quot;Please write down 5 names of people you know...Good job!&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot; readability=&quot;35&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phrase&quot;&gt;You did really great&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meaning&quot;&gt;[similar to 'Good Job!'] You didn't screw it up&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;-&quot;So we're done with your X-ray, you can get up now. You did really great.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot; readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phrase&quot;&gt;Fooling around&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meaning&quot;&gt;Having non-coital sex&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;For example, ex-US president clinton was merely &quot;fooling around&quot; with his intern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot; readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phrase&quot;&gt;Sounds great&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meaning&quot;&gt;Is fine&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;-&quot;Can we meet on Monday at 3?&quot;&lt;br /&gt;-&quot;Yeah, Monday at 3 sounds great!&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phrase&quot;&gt;How are you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meaning&quot;&gt;Hello [not a question]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;-&quot;How are you?&quot;&lt;br /&gt;-&quot;Hi! So good to see you!&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot; readability=&quot;38&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phrase&quot;&gt;I'll have to think about it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meaning&quot;&gt;I have thought about it, and the answer is no&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;-&quot;Would you be able to come pick me up before the game?&lt;br /&gt;-&quot;Hmm, I'll have to think about that one.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot; readability=&quot;34&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phrase&quot;&gt;A little&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meaning&quot;&gt;Way too&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;-&quot;We probably want to take a cab there. It's a little far&quot;&lt;br /&gt;-&quot;I don't want to go at all, it seems a little dangerous.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot; readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phrase&quot;&gt;Awesome&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meaning&quot;&gt;Very good&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;-&quot;Awesome. I think we have everything we need for the dinner&quot;&lt;br /&gt;-&quot;Yeah, it'll be an awesome event.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phrase&quot;&gt;Exciting / Excited&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meaning&quot;&gt;Good / Happy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;-&quot;I'm really excited about being done with my tax forms!&quot;&lt;br /&gt;-&quot;Really? That's so exciting to hear!&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot; readability=&quot;35&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phrase&quot;&gt;Let's just say&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meaning&quot;&gt;[Serious understatement following]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;-&quot;Let's just say, I'm a little unhappy with her work.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phrase&quot;&gt;Not great / not the best&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meaning&quot;&gt;Very bad&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;-&quot;We had to fire him because he wasn't the best programmer.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot; readability=&quot;37&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phrase&quot;&gt;Not a good / a great / the best fit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meaning&quot;&gt;[Stand in for any serious character flaw]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;-&quot;Unfortunately, a convicted arsonist is not the best fit for our warehouse.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot; readability=&quot;34&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phrase&quot;&gt;I wish I could&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meaning&quot;&gt;I have very little interest&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;-&quot;So are you coming over tonight?&quot;&lt;br /&gt;-&quot;Awwwww... I wish I could!&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot; readability=&quot;38&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phrase&quot;&gt;I love him/her, but&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meaning&quot;&gt;I have a serious problem with him/her&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;-&quot;I mean, don't get me wrong: I love my boss, he's awesome. But he keeps screwing me over behind my back, and he hasn't paid me in six months!&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot; readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phrase&quot;&gt;I'm not sure if/that &lt;em&gt;X&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meaning&quot;&gt;I'm sure that [not &lt;em&gt;X&lt;/em&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;-&quot;I'm not sure if I would agree with him on that matter.&quot;&lt;br /&gt;-&quot;You know what? I'm not sure that he really cares about your opinion.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot; readability=&quot;39&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phrase&quot;&gt;That's [really] interesting&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meaning&quot;&gt;I couldn't care less&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;-&quot;You work for 'Engage Music'? Oh my god! So my boyfriend, he has a band, and they're looking for an agent now. I mean, like, you know?&quot;&lt;br /&gt;-&quot;Really? That's really interesting.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot; readability=&quot;36&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phrase&quot;&gt;He/she is nice&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meaning&quot;&gt;I have nothing good to say about him/her&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;-&quot;So what did you think of Tony? We just started dating, and I think I really like him.&quot;&lt;br /&gt;-&quot;Yeah. He's nice. Totally. Totally nice.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot; readability=&quot;35&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phrase&quot;&gt;Keep/Stay in touch&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meaning&quot;&gt;Don't expect to ever hear from me again&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;-&quot;So yeah. Keep in touch, alright?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot; readability=&quot;38&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phrase&quot;&gt;How are you today Sir/Madam?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meaning&quot;&gt;I am paid to make conversation with you&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;-&quot;Welcome to Carpet Heaven, where the carpets are as good as their price. How are you today, Sir?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phrase&quot;&gt;Not bad&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meaning&quot;&gt;Bad&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;-&quot;So tell me honestly: what do you think of my new painting?&quot;&lt;br /&gt;-&quot;It's not bad.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot; readability=&quot;37&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phrase&quot;&gt;Still working on &lt;em&gt;X&lt;/em&gt; [Restaurant]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meaning&quot;&gt;Eating [too slowly]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;-&quot;Are you still working on that salad, Sir?&quot;&lt;br /&gt;-&quot;Yes, thanks.&quot;&lt;br /&gt;-&quot;I'll just leave this here then. Whenever you get a chance.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phrase&quot;&gt;Whenever you get a chance&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meaning&quot;&gt;As soon as possible&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;See above&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot; readability=&quot;37&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phrase&quot;&gt;I'm all over it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meaning&quot;&gt;Leave me alone. I'll get to it when I get to it, ok?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;-&quot;Did you start getting those reports ready, Nathan?&quot;&lt;br /&gt;-&quot;I'm all over it, boss!&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phrase&quot;&gt;Party [v.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meaning&quot;&gt;Drinking alcohol&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;-&quot;I partied so hard last night that I could hardly get up to work today.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot; readability=&quot;35&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phrase&quot;&gt;Party [n.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meaning&quot;&gt;An event in which people stand around in a well-lit room drinking and eating finger food. [Note: does not usually involve dancing.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;-&quot;You should come to my party on Saturday. There'll be olives!&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phrase&quot;&gt;Probably not&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meaning&quot;&gt;Definitely not&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;-&quot;I will probably not make it to the party tonight.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot; readability=&quot;34&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phrase&quot;&gt;A huge favor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meaning&quot;&gt;A small favor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;-&quot;Can you do me a &lt;em&gt;huge&lt;/em&gt; favor and pass me the salt?&quot;&lt;br /&gt;[usually followed by 'thank you &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; much, see above]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot; readability=&quot;39&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phrase&quot;&gt;It's not that &lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt;, it's just that...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meaning&quot;&gt;If it were acceptable, I would say &lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;-&quot;It's not that he's an idiot, it's just that I don't feel comfortable when he opens his mouth.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phrase&quot;&gt;Totally&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meaning&quot;&gt;Possibly&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;-&quot;I'm totally going to write her a letter.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot; readability=&quot;35&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phrase&quot;&gt;For you&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meaning&quot;&gt;[This phrase has no meaning per se]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;-&quot;Let me just have a look at this chart for you, sir.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot; readability=&quot;36&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phrase&quot;&gt;No offense, but&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meaning&quot;&gt;Prepare to get offended [Note: combines well with &quot;let's just say&quot;, see above]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;-&quot;No offense, but let's just say that your new book is not as great as your previous ones.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phrase&quot;&gt;Not necessarily&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meaning&quot;&gt;Definitely&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;-&quot;So do you think the board took my idea badly?&quot;&lt;br /&gt;-&quot;Not necessarily.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot; readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phrase&quot;&gt;Mixed success&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meaning&quot;&gt;Utter failure&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;-&quot;You know, bringing you to meet my parents was met with mixed success.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot; readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phrase&quot;&gt;Highly recommended&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meaning&quot;&gt;Mandatory&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;-&quot;It is highly recommended that you turn in your application in time to increase your odds at being considered.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot; readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phrase&quot;&gt;For your own safety&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meaning&quot;&gt;For the public order&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;-&quot;For your own safety, please do not congregate around this car crash victim.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot; readability=&quot;35&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phrase&quot;&gt;Cozy [about an apartment or room]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meaning&quot;&gt;Tiny&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;-&quot;I love my new East Village studio. I just don't know if two people can stand in it together. It's a bit cozy.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot; readability=&quot;35&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phrase&quot;&gt;That could be good&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meaning&quot;&gt;That's a terrible idea! Please, someone come up with a better one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;-&quot;How about we all go to Lasertag Karaoke?&quot;&lt;br /&gt;-&quot;Hmm. That could be good.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot; readability=&quot;36&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phrase&quot;&gt;Are you sure you want to do that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meaning&quot;&gt;Are you really stupid enough to consider that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;-&quot;I think I'll just call her and tell her how I really feel.&quot;&lt;br /&gt;-&quot;Are you sure you want to do that?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phrase&quot;&gt;That's a good question&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meaning&quot;&gt;I don't have an answer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;-&quot;When can you promise me the delivery of those components?&quot;&lt;br /&gt;-&quot;That's a good question.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot; readability=&quot;34&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phrase&quot;&gt;Do you mind [&lt;em&gt;X&lt;/em&gt;ing]?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meaning&quot;&gt;Do &lt;em&gt;X&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;br /&gt;[Implies a certain contempt for the listener not having thought about this themselves]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;-&quot;Do you mind using headphones?&quot;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;contact&quot;&gt;If you came across an additional American English phrase, or if you just like this page, please mail me at &lt;img src=&quot;http://alumni.media.mit.edu/~guy/hitme.gif&quot; /&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 04:28:13 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>troydavis</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://alumni.media.mit.edu/~guy/american/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Unencrypted patient medical information is being broadcast across Vancouver</title>
<link>https://openprivacy.ca/blog/2019/09/09/open-privacy-discovers-vancouver-patient-medical-data-breach/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://openprivacy.ca/blog/2019/09/09/open-privacy-discovers-vancouver-patient-medical-data-breach/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Vancouver, BC - The Open Privacy Research Society has discovered that the sensitive medical information of patients being admitted to certain hospitals across the Greater Vancouver Area is being broadcast, unencrypted, by hospital paging systems, and that these broadcasts are trivially interceptable by anyone in the Greater Vancouver Area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data being broadcast includes the patients name, age, gender marker, diagnosis, their attending doctor and room number. Other broadcasts regarding medical tests such as x-rays are often associated with a patients last name or medical number, exposing their progression through hospital departments. Some broadcasts appear to contain freeform text, allowing other sensitive information to be entered as well. We have been able to confirm the authenticity of this data by cross-referencing records with public obituaries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open Privacy immediately began responsible disclosure of this issue with Vancouver Coastal Health (VCH) in November 2018. After several attempts at contact we were informed in a brief email in December 2018 that the issue had been escalated. After several months with no follow up, and with the breach still ongoing, Open Privacy made the decision to contact journalists &amp;amp; begin public disclosure of the existence of this breach in an attempt to inform the public while minimizing the potential harm. We provide a full disclosure timeline along with this press release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-note-on-patient-safety--security&quot;&gt;A Note on Patient Safety &amp;amp; Security&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of the writing of this press release, the breach is still ongoing. Open Privacy has made the decision not to release specific details of the broadcast frequency and demodulation methods needed to exploit this breach, but we warn that such information is readily available online, and anyone with a $20 software-defined radio and some time would likely be able to rediscover what we have (and may have already done so).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;response-from-vancouver-coastal-health&quot;&gt;Response from Vancouver Coastal Health&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was only after Open Privacy disclosed details of this breach to a journalist who subsequently contacted Vancouver Coastal Health that we received responses &amp;amp; further questions about this breach from VCH. In addition we also contacted the Office of the Information &amp;amp; Privacy Commissioner in B.C. and have since co-operated in their investigation into this breach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VCH informed us that they had undertaken an investigation after our initial report, but that the system under investigation “was deemed secure as it was sent to specific pager devices and didn’t seem to rely on any radio connection” and that their “investigation findings leads us to believe that patient information is protected and not being intercepted.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two weeks ago, after Open Privacy clarified multiple misconceptions around pager operations, and provided heavily redacted samples to VCH, we received confirmation of this breach from the General Counsel / Chief Privacy Officer at Vancouver Coastal Health. This confirmation, however, was also coupled with a denial of the seriousness of the breach of patient privacy &amp;amp; security:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VCH takes patient privacy very seriously and is actively working to mitigate the privacy risks you have identified. Please note, however, that VCH has no information to suggest that patient information has been compromised or used for a malicious purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We wish to clarify that in our communications with VCH their privacy office has stated that VCH was &lt;em&gt;unaware of the radio broadcasting component of the pager system(s)&lt;/em&gt; in question until several weeks ago, indicating that the system’s opaqueness is an obstacle to understanding it. This opaqueness applies equally to the messages broadcast unencrypted over the airwaves: the system does not (and cannot) log access to the data by third parties, so any malicious interception would be passive and undetectable by nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where this impacts patient safety and security, it is simply impossible for anyone to state that no compromise has occurred. In a hypothetical scenario wherein multiple malicious actors accessed &lt;em&gt;every&lt;/em&gt; patient record ever broadcast, it would thus remain the case that VCH has “no information to suggest that patient information has been compromised or used for a malicious purpose.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;questions-that-vancouver-coastal-health-must-answer&quot;&gt;Questions that Vancouver Coastal Health must Answer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We cannot say for certain how many patients have been impacted by this breach. We suspect that this breach has likely been on going for several years. We have asked that VCH answer the following questions related to this breach:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;How many patients’ information has been broadcast to date in this breach?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When were the legacy pager systems installed?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can a patient determine if their individual information was broadcast in the breach? If so, how?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As some of the pager messages appeared to contain unstructured text data, is there any mechanism for patients to inquire what non-standard information in particular of theirs was broadcast unencrypted? If so, how?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How many VCH patients continue to have their personal information broadcast unencrypted on a daily basis?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have any mitigations, such as shutting down these systems or limiting what information is entered into the insecure paging system, been put in place?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How and when does VCH plan on notifying patients whose information was broadcast?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As you have indicated that this breach will not be remedied in the immediate future, will VCH be informing current &amp;amp; new/incoming patients that their personal information will be broadcast unencrypted by the legacy paging system(s)? If so, how, and will patients be given an option to opt out of having their information breached?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;disclosure-timeline&quot;&gt;Disclosure Timeline&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below we provide a timeline of emails, phone calls and in person meetings related to this data breach. As of the drafting of this press release the data breach is still active and ongoing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;2018-11-11: Open Privacy staff members discover the patient data broadcasts while working on an unrelated radio project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2018-11-12: Sarah Jamie Lewis reaches out to Vancouver Coastal Health Privacy Office (VCH-P) with information about the breach.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2018-11-19: Sarah Jamie Lewis reaches out again to VCH-P after receiving no response.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2018-11-19: VCH-P replies “The previous email has been received by VCH Privacy and earmarked for further review.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2018-11-29: Open Privacy staff confirm that sensitive medical information is still being broadcast and reaches out to VCH-P for further information on a mitigation timeline.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2018-11-30: VCH-P confirm that the issue “has been escalated to [their] Director of Client Relations and Risk Management to investigate”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2018-11-30: Sarah Jamie Lewis asks for clarification on who occupies the role of Director of Client Relations and Risk Management, this email goes unanswered.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2019-02-26: Open Privacy staff confirm that patient data is still being broadcast unencrypted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2019-02-27: Sarah Jamie Lewis arranges a meeting with a journalist regarding the breach.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2019-03-04: Sarah Jamie Lewis meets with two journalists and demonstrates the pager breach. This meeting was not recorded and this meeting is never followed up on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2019-07-23: During an interview with journalist Francesca Fionda, on Open Privacy’s research into Swiss election systems, Sarah Jamie Lewis discusses the pager breach.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2019-08-01: Sarah Jamie Lewis meets with Francesca Fionda for an interview about the pager breach. During this interview Sarah demonstrates the patient data breach (No information is recorded or transferred, and is discarded immediately).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2019-08-14: In response to a phone call from Francesca Fionda, VCH-P email Sarah Jamie Lewis, “We are committed to ensuring our clients’ privacy is upheld. At this time, we have not identified any paging system used at VGH that compromises client privacy. Our investigation findings leads us to believe that patient information is protected and not being intercepted.” In this email VCH-P also ask for more information to help determine the nature of the breach.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2019-08-14: Sarah Jamie Lewis discloses the full nature of the breach to the Open Privacy board of directors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2018-08-15: Open Privacy staff confirm that patient data is still being broadcast unencrypted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2019-08-15: Sarah Jamie Lewis responds to VCH-P with more information regarding the hardware &amp;amp; software that could be used to capture patient medical data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2019-08-15: Sarah Jamie Lewis reaches out to the Office of the Information and Privacy Commissioner for B.C. (OIPC), offering to help aid any investigation they wish to undertake in regards to this data breach.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2019-08-18: OIPC schedule a meeting with Sarah Jamie Lewis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2019-08-19: Sarah Jamie Lewis discloses details about the breach to OIPC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2019-08-20: Open Privacy is notified that OIPC has referred the case to their Investigations team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2019-08-20: VCH-P responds to Sarah Jamie Lewis and requests examples of interceptable messages and other additional details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2019-08-20: Sarah Jamie Lewis provides heavily redacted samples to VCH-P.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2019-08-23: Sarah Jamie Lewis speaks to an Investigator from OIPC regarding the breach.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2019-08-28: Sarah Jamie Lewis receives an email with a confirmation of the breach, and two questions from VCH General Counsel &amp;amp; Chief Privacy Officer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2019-09-04: Sarah Jamie Lewis responds to questions from VCH General Counsel &amp;amp; Chief Privacy Officer, and confirms that Open Privacy has securely deleted all logs that were found to contain patient health records.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2019-09-09: &lt;em&gt;Publication of this press release&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;further-information&quot;&gt;Further Information&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Media requests should be directed to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto://sarah@openprivacy.ca&quot;&gt;sarah@openprivacy.ca&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sarah Jamie Lewis&lt;br/&gt;Executive Director, Open Privacy Research Society&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 00:53:15 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>gregmac</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://openprivacy.ca</og:url>
<og:title>Press Release&amp;colon; Open Privacy discovers unencrypted patient medical information broadcast across Vancouver</og:title>
<og:description>The Open Privacy Research Society is a non-profit Canadian group based in Vancouver, British Columbia. We believe that moral systems enable consent. Our society exists to invent, create, build, test, publish, deploy, promote, and to encourage the development of such systems</og:description>
<og:image>https://openprivacy.ca/images/pager-breach.png</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://openprivacy.ca/blog/2019/09/09/open-privacy-discovers-vancouver-patient-medical-data-breach/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>