<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Architecture.md</title>
<link>https://matklad.github.io//2021/02/06/ARCHITECTURE.md.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://matklad.github.io//2021/02/06/ARCHITECTURE.md.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Feb 6, 2021&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot; readability=&quot;18&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you maintain an open-source project in the range of 10k-200k lines of code, I strongly encourage you to add an &lt;code&gt;ARCHITECTURE&lt;/code&gt; document next to &lt;code&gt;README&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;CONTRIBUTING&lt;/code&gt;. Before going into the details of why and how, I want to emphasize that this is not another “docs are good, write more docs” advice. I am pretty sloppy about documentation, and, eg, I often use just “simplify” as a commit message. Nonetheless, I feel strongly about the issue, event to the point of pestering you:-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot; readability=&quot;19&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have experience with both contributing to and maintaining open-source projects. One of the lessons I’ve learned is that the biggest difference between an occasional contributor and a core developer lies in the knowledge about the physical architecture of the project. Roughly, it takes 2x more time to write a patch if you are unfamiliar with the project, but it takes 10x more time to figure out &lt;em&gt;where&lt;/em&gt; you should change the code. This difference might be hard to perceive if you’ve been working with the project for a while. If I am new to a code base, I read each file as a sequence of logical chunks specified in some pseudo-random order. If I’ve made significant contributions before, the perception is quite different. I have a mental map of the code in my head, so I no longer read sequentially. Instead, I just jump to where the thing should be, and, if it is not there, I move it. Mental map is the source of truth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot; readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find &lt;code&gt;ARCHITECTURE&lt;/code&gt; file to be a low-effort high-leverage way to bridge this gap. As the name suggest, this file should describe the high-level architecture of the project. Keep it short: every recurring contributor will have to read it. Additionally, the shorter it is, the less likely it will be invalidated by some future change. This is the main rule of thumb for &lt;code&gt;ARCHITECTURE&lt;/code&gt; — specify only things which are unlikely to frequently change. Don’t try to keep it synchronized with code. Instead, revisit it a couple of times a year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot; readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start with a bird’s eye overview of the problem being solved. Then, specify a more-or-less detailed codemap. Describe coarse-grained modules and how they relate to each other. Codemap should answer “where’s the thing that does X?”. It should also answer “what does the thing that I am looking at do?”. Avoid going into details of &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; each module works, pull this into separate documents or (better) inline documentation. Codemap is a map of a country, and not an atlas of maps of its states. Use this as a chance to reflect on the project structure. Are the things you want to put near each other in the codemap adjacent in &lt;code&gt;exa -TD&lt;/code&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot; readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do name important files, modules, and types. Do not directly link them (links go stale). Instead, encourage the reader to use symbol search to find the mentioned entities by name. This doesn’t require maintenance, and will help to discover related, similarly named things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explicitly call-out architectural invariants. Often, important invariants are expressed as an &lt;em&gt;absence&lt;/em&gt; of something, and it’s pretty hard to divine that from reading the code. Nothing in the model layer specifically doesn’t depend on the views.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Point out boundaries between layers and systems as well. A boundary implicitly contains information about the implementation of the system behind it. It even constraints all &lt;em&gt;possible&lt;/em&gt; implementations. But finding a boundary by just randomly looking at the code is hard — good boundaries have measure zero.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After finishing the codemap, add a separate section on cross-cutting concerns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot; readability=&quot;5.7931034482759&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good example of &lt;code&gt;ARCHITECTURE&lt;/code&gt; document is the one from rust-analyzer: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-analyzer/rust-analyzer/blob/d7c99931d05e3723d878bea5dc26766791fa4e69/docs/dev/architecture.md&quot;&gt;architecture.md&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 18:46:58 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>todsacerdoti</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://matklad.github.io//2021/02/06/ARCHITECTURE.md.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Parents of daughters are more likely to divorce than those with sons</title>
<link>https://www.economist.com/science-and-technology/2021/02/06/daughters-provoke-parental-strife</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.economist.com/science-and-technology/2021/02/06/daughters-provoke-parental-strife</guid>
<description>&lt;aside class=&quot;article__aside&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;time itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/DateTime&quot; datetime=&quot;2021-02-06T00:00:00Z&quot; class=&quot;article__dateline-datetime&quot;&gt;Feb 6th 2021&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p data-caps=&quot;initial&quot; class=&quot;article__body-text article__body-text--dropcap&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-caps=&quot;initial&quot;&gt;D&lt;/span&gt;&lt;small&gt;AUGHTERS HAVE&lt;/small&gt; long been linked with divorce. Several studies conducted in America since the 1980s provide strong evidence that a couple’s first-born being a girl increases the likelihood of their subsequently splitting up. At the time, the researchers involved speculated that this was an expression of “son preference”, a phenomenon which, in its most extreme form, manifests itself as the selective abortion or infanticide of female offspring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article-audio-player&quot; readability=&quot;31.166666666667&quot;&gt;Listen to this story
&lt;p&gt;Your browser does not support the &amp;lt;audio&amp;gt; element.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article-audio-player__cta&quot;&gt;Enjoy more audio and podcasts on &lt;a id=&quot;audio-ios-cta&quot; href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/app/apple-store/id1239397626?pt=344884&amp;amp;ct=article%20audio%20player&amp;amp;mt=8&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;iOS&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a id=&quot;audio-android-cta&quot; href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.economist.lamarr&amp;amp;referrer=utm_source%3Darticle%2520audio%2520player&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article__body-text&quot;&gt;Work published in the &lt;em&gt;Economic Journal&lt;/em&gt;, however, debunks that particular idea. In “Daughters and Divorce”, Jan Kabatek of the University of Melbourne and David Ribar of Georgia State University, in Atlanta, confirm that having a female first-born does indeed increase the risk of that child’s parents divorcing, in both America and the Netherlands. But, unlike previous work, their study also looked at the effect of the girl’s age. It found that “daughter-divorce” risk emerges only in a first-born girl’s teenage years (see chart). Before they reach the age of 12, daughters are no more linked to couples splitting up than sons are. “If fathers were really more likely to take off because they preferred sons, surely they wouldn’t wait 13 years to do so,” reasons Dr Kabatek. Instead, he argues, the fact that the risk is so age-specific requires a different explanation, namely that parents quarrel more over the upbringing of teenage daughters than of teenage sons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;article__body-text-image&quot; readability=&quot;46&quot;&gt;
&lt;div itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; itemtype=&quot;https://schema.org/ImageObject&quot; data-slim=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://www.economist.com/img/b/608/701/90/sites/default/files/images/print-edition/20210206_STC622.png&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.economist.com/img/b/200/231/90/sites/default/files/images/print-edition/20210206_STC622.png 200w,https://www.economist.com/img/b/300/346/90/sites/default/files/images/print-edition/20210206_STC622.png 300w,https://www.economist.com/img/b/400/461/90/sites/default/files/images/print-edition/20210206_STC622.png 400w,https://www.economist.com/img/b/600/692/90/sites/default/files/images/print-edition/20210206_STC622.png 600w,https://www.economist.com/img/b/640/738/90/sites/default/files/images/print-edition/20210206_STC622.png 640w,https://www.economist.com/img/b/800/922/90/sites/default/files/images/print-edition/20210206_STC622.png 800w,https://www.economist.com/img/b/1000/1153/90/sites/default/files/images/print-edition/20210206_STC622.png 1000w,https://www.economist.com/img/b/1280/1476/90/sites/default/files/images/print-edition/20210206_STC622.png 1280w&quot; sizes=&quot;300px&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article__body-text&quot;&gt;Taken over the years, the daughter effect, though real, is small. In the Netherlands, by the time their first-born is 18, 20.12% of couples will have divorced if that child is a son, compared with 20.48% if she is a daughter—an increase in probability of 1.8%. But in the five years when the first-born is between the ages of 13 and 18, that increase goes up to 5%. And it peaks, at 9%, when the child is 15. In America, for which the data the researchers collected were sparser than those in the Netherlands, the numbers are roughly double this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article__body-text&quot;&gt;Anyone who has—or has been—a teenager knows how turbulent those years can be. Surveys confirm that teenage daughters and fathers, in particular, get on each other’s nerves. They also show that parents of teenage daughters argue more about parenting than do the parents of sons, and that mothers of teenage daughters report significantly more disagreements with their partners over money, and become more open to the idea of divorce. Earlier research has also shown that one of the most common things parents fight over is how much they should control their teenagers’ personal choices, such as how they dress, whom they date and where they work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article__body-text&quot;&gt;In light of all this, it is intriguing to note that Dr Kabatek and Dr Ribar found one type of couple who seem immune to the daughter effect: those in which the father grew up with a sister. Having seen things somewhat from a sister’s point of view may act as a sort of social inoculation. &lt;span data-ornament=&quot;ufinish&quot;&gt;■&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-test-id=&quot;Footnote&quot; class=&quot;article__footnote&quot;&gt;This article appeared in the Science &amp;amp; technology section of the print edition under the headline &quot;Teenage rampage&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 16:10:08 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jkuria</dc:creator>
<og:title>Parents of daughters are more likely to divorce than those with sons</og:title>
<og:type>Article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.economist.com/science-and-technology/2021/02/06/parents-of-daughters-are-more-likely-to-divorce-than-those-with-sons</og:url>
<og:description>But the difference only emerges when the children are teenagers</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.economist.com/img/b/1280/720/90/sites/default/files/images/2021/02/articles/main/20210206_stp501.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.economist.com/science-and-technology/2021/02/06/parents-of-daughters-are-more-likely-to-divorce-than-those-with-sons</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Programming for Cats</title>
<link>https://programmingforcats.com/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://programmingforcats.com/</guid>
<description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-programming-for-cats-aptitude-test&quot;&gt;The “Programming for Cats” aptitude test&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not everyone has an aptitude for programming. The Association for Cat Machinations (ACM) has compiled a list of traits that are needed to be a good programmer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, do you have what it takes to be a programming cat?&lt;br/&gt;Take this aptitude test and find out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, can you operate a keyboard?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://programmingforcats.com/images/can-you-operate-a-keyboard.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cat on keyboard of laptop&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Can you focus on one thing for hours at a time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://programmingforcats.com/images/focus-on-one-thing.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cat staring at mouse hole&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do you like to stay up at night and sleep all day?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://programmingforcats.com/images/sleep-all-day.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cat sleeping on floor&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Are you stubborn? Are you aloof?&lt;br/&gt;Are you often a jerk?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://programmingforcats.com/images/are-you-a-jerk.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cat sleeping in dog’s basket&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Are you easily distracted by bright shiny objects?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://programmingforcats.com/images/easily-distracted.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cat jumping&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do you sometimes forget why you left a room and then come back in again?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://programmingforcats.com/images/sometimes-forget.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cat thinking and puzzled&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do you like to ignore orders from people who think they are superior to you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://programmingforcats.com/images/ignore-orders.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cat being dragged along sidewalk&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Are you, in fact, superior to everyone else?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://programmingforcats.com/images/are-you-superior.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Royal cat wearing crown&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, and most importantly, can you lift one leg in the air and lick your crotch at the same time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://programmingforcats.com/images/can-you-lick-your-crotch.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cat licking crotch&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you said yes to all these questions, then congratulations, you have what it takes to be a programmer!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;programming-for-cats&quot;&gt;Programming for Cats!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Software is taking over the world. This presents a critical challenge for us cats. Natural law requires that we cats be dominant over lesser life-forms such as humans and dogs. But new technology means that we are in danger of losing our place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fellow felines, we must take back control! We must learn to program in order to maintain our authority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Feline Dominance Authority (FDA) and the Society for the Promotion of Cat Ascendency (SPCA) have created “Programming for Cats”, the only book written specially for cats who want to master the art of software development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are a cat, it’s your duty to learn to program. If you are not a cat, but know someone who is a cat, please persuade them to read this book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://programmingforcats.com/images/cover.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Book cover&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book explains why programming is important to a cat…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://programmingforcats.com/images/what-is-programming.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;What is programming?&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;…and covers programming paradigms and languages…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://programmingforcats.com/images/what-is-java.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;What is Java?&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;…testing, debugging, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://programmingforcats.com/images/debugging.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;debugging&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book will be available in Spring 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want to see inside the book? We have a 40 page sample available!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you provide your name and email below, we will email you when we have a final publication date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While you’re waiting, follow us on Twitter at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ProgrammingCats&quot;&gt;@ProgrammingCats&lt;/a&gt; to see excerpts from the book and photos of fellow cats at their computers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The wonderful illustrations are by Karen Donnelly (&lt;a href=&quot;http://karendonnelly.com&quot;&gt;karendonnelly.com&lt;/a&gt;). Follow her on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/donnellyillos/&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the best meows,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tigerlily&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://programmingforcats.com/images/author-photo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Author photo of Tigerlily&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 15:42:06 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tigerlilythecat</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:title>Programming for Cats</og:title>
<og:description>A book written specially for cats who want to program.</og:description>
<og:image>https://programmingforcats.com/images/twitter-card.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://programmingforcats.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Big name corporations more likely to commit fraud: study</title>
<link>https://news.wsu.edu/2021/02/02/big-name-corporations-likely-commit-fraud/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.wsu.edu/2021/02/02/big-name-corporations-likely-commit-fraud/</guid>
<description>&lt;a href=&quot;https://s3.wp.wsu.edu/uploads/sites/609/2021/02/sean-pollock-PhYq704ffdA-unsplash.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;792&quot; height=&quot;528&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.wp.wsu.edu/uploads/sites/609/2021/02/sean-pollock-PhYq704ffdA-unsplash-792x528.jpg&quot; class=&quot;attachment-spine-medium_size size-spine-medium_size wp-post-image&quot; alt=&quot;View of New York City skyscrapers from ground level.&quot; srcset=&quot;https://s3.wp.wsu.edu/uploads/sites/609/2021/02/sean-pollock-PhYq704ffdA-unsplash-792x528.jpg 792w, https://s3.wp.wsu.edu/uploads/sites/609/2021/02/sean-pollock-PhYq704ffdA-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://s3.wp.wsu.edu/uploads/sites/609/2021/02/sean-pollock-PhYq704ffdA-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://s3.wp.wsu.edu/uploads/sites/609/2021/02/sean-pollock-PhYq704ffdA-unsplash-396x264.jpg 396w, https://s3.wp.wsu.edu/uploads/sites/609/2021/02/sean-pollock-PhYq704ffdA-unsplash-990x660.jpg 990w, https://s3.wp.wsu.edu/uploads/sites/609/2021/02/sean-pollock-PhYq704ffdA-unsplash.jpg 1188w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 792px) 100vw, 792px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Photo by Sean Pollock
&lt;p class=&quot;byline&quot;&gt;By Sara Zaske, WSU News&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;PULLMAN, Wash. –  Fortune 500 firms with strong growth profiles are more susceptible to “cooking the books” than smaller, struggling companies, according to a recent study published in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/07418825.2020.1853799&quot;&gt;Justice Quarterly&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researchers from Washington State University, Pennsylvania State University and Miami University examined the characteristics of more than 250 U.S. public corporations that were involved in financial securities fraud identified in Securities and Exchange Commission filings from 2005-2013. They were then compared to a control sample of firms that were not named in SEC fraud filings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clear trends emerged in the risk of fraud including corporations that were listed in the Fortune 500, traded on the New York Stock Exchange and had strong growth expectations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Prestigious companies, those that are household names, were actually more prone to engage in financial fraud, which was very surprising,” said Jennifer Schwartz, WSU sociologist and lead author on the study. “We thought it would be companies that were struggling financially, that were nearing bankruptcy, but it was quite the opposite. It was the companies that thought they should be doing better than they were, the ones with strong growth imperatives–those were the firms that were most likely to cheat.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Corporate financial securities fraud involves attempts to manipulate financial markets in a business’ favor by using faulty accounting practices, providing false or incomplete information or otherwise misrepresenting the company’s financial status.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers noted that this type of elite, white-collar crime is understudied especially when compared with street crime even though it has more wide-reaching consequences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What these companies were doing was essentially fudging the numbers, lying to investors, other companies and the SEC,” said Schwartz. “Eventually, you have to make up for the money that was lost, that really never existed, so shareholders lose money, people lose retirement plans, people lose jobs. It’s very, very damaging.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schwartz and her co-authors decided to look at the time period around the global financial crisis that included the fraud scandals of WorldCom and Enron, and the subsequent regulatory Sarbanes-Oxley Act of 2002.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal was to identify the conditions at publicly traded companies in which there was a greater risk for fraud. The researchers found that companies with Fortune 500 status were represented nearly four times as often among the firms that had committed fraud than in the nonfraudulent control group. Likewise, firms that traded on NYSE were over-represented among fraudulent firms versus non-fraud – by nearly two to one, a higher rate than those that trade on other exchanges like the NASDAQ or OTC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study also revealed that fraud occurred more often in firms where the CEO was also the chair of the board, a potential connection that Schwartz and her colleagues are investigating further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We need to look more at corporate leadership arrangements, and the responsibility of individuals in creating the culture of the company itself,” she said. “How can leaders encourage companies to be more successful not only in terms of profit or growth but also in terms of corporate social responsibility?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Media contacts:&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 15:01:37 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>CapitalistCartr</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Big name corporations more likely to commit fraud | WSU Insider | Washington State University</og:title>
<og:description>Fortune 500 firms with strong growth profiles are more prone to “cooking the books” than smaller, struggling companies, according to a recent study led by WSU sociologist Jennifer Schwartz.</og:description>
<og:url>https://news.wsu.edu/2021/02/02/big-name-corporations-likely-commit-fraud/</og:url>
<og:image>https://s3.wp.wsu.edu/uploads/sites/609/2021/02/sean-pollock-PhYq704ffdA-unsplash.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.wsu.edu/2021/02/02/big-name-corporations-likely-commit-fraud/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>NordVPN disables features when you turn off auto-renew</title>
<link>https://www.reddit.com/r/assholedesign/comments/ldf9g9/nordvpn_disables_features_when_you_turn_off/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.reddit.com/r/assholedesign/comments/ldf9g9/nordvpn_disables_features_when_you_turn_off/</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;_1qeIAgB0cPwnLhDF9XSiJM&quot;&gt;The company known for putting fuck all into the actual service they provide and going all in on misleading the technologically illiterate?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_1qeIAgB0cPwnLhDF9XSiJM&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;_7s4syPYtk5hfUIjySXcRE&quot;&gt;Huge&lt;/em&gt; shock there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_1qeIAgB0cPwnLhDF9XSiJM&quot;&gt;But for real I don't know why anyone would use NordVPN, anyone pedaling their shit clearly doesn't care about who they're advertising to.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 14:20:14 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>decrypt</dc:creator>
<og:title>r/assholedesign - NordVpn disables features when you turn off auto-renew</og:title>
<og:type>image</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.reddit.com/r/assholedesign/comments/ldf9g9/nordvpn_disables_features_when_you_turn_off/</og:url>
<og:description>34,676 votes and 952 comments so far on Reddit</og:description>
<og:image>https://external-preview.redd.it/2AfPpF0p0A8jRQ4E502hBZJ9pM_x_YqJJuhgttnHvYY.jpg?auto=webp&amp;s=5969accc930748f7b6b92677b7e3bf0121fbd8d8</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.reddit.com/r/assholedesign/comments/ldf9g9/nordvpn_disables_features_when_you_turn_off/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>I told a cat food company how much they’d save by using taller cans (2020)</title>
<link>https://twitter.com/mathematicsprof/status/1235553604016070656</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://twitter.com/mathematicsprof/status/1235553604016070656</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mathematicsprof/status/1235553604016070656&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/mathematicsprof/status/1235553604016070656&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26046461&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26046461&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 230&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 145&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 13:49:59 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Tomte</dc:creator>
<og:title>r/assholedesign - NordVpn disables features when you turn off auto-renew</og:title>
<og:type>image</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.reddit.com/r/assholedesign/comments/ldf9g9/nordvpn_disables_features_when_you_turn_off/</og:url>
<og:description>34,676 votes and 952 comments so far on Reddit</og:description>
<og:image>https://external-preview.redd.it/2AfPpF0p0A8jRQ4E502hBZJ9pM_x_YqJJuhgttnHvYY.jpg?auto=webp&amp;s=5969accc930748f7b6b92677b7e3bf0121fbd8d8</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.reddit.com/r/assholedesign/comments/ldf9g9/nordvpn_disables_features_when_you_turn_off/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Complexity Explained</title>
<link>https://complexityexplained.github.io/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://complexityexplained.github.io/</guid>
<description>&lt;h2&gt;Credits&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coordinators:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Manlio De Domenico and Hiroki Sayama&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contributors:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Manlio De Domenico, Dirk Brockmann, Chico Camargo, Carlos Gershenson, Daniel Goldsmith, Sabine Jeschonnek, Lorren Kay, Stefano Nichele, José R. Nicolás, Thomas Schmickl, Massimo Stella, Josh Brandoff, Ángel José Martínez Salinas, Hiroki Sayama&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks to the following who provided inputs and feedback:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Hayford Adjavor, Alex Arenas, Yaneer Bar-Yam, Rogelio Basurto Flores, Michele Battle-Fisher, Anton Bernatskiy, Jacob D. Biamonte, Victor Bonilla, Dirk Brockmann, Victor Buendia, Seth Bullock, Simon Carrignon, Xubin Chai, Jon Darkow, Luca Dellanna, David Rushing Dewhurst, Peter Dodds, Alan Dorin, Peter Eerens, Christos Ellinad, Diego Espinosa, Ernesto Estrada, Nelson Fernández, Len Fisher, Erin Gallagher, Riccardo Gallotti, Pier Luigi Gentilli, Lasse Gerrits, Nigel Goldenfeld, Sergio Gómez, Héctor Gómez-Escobar, Alfredo González-Espinoza, Marcus Guest, J. W. Helkenberg, Stephan Herminghaus, Enrique Hernández-Zavaleta, Marco A. Javarone, Hang-Hyun Jo, Pedro Jordano, Abbas Karimi, J. Kasmire, Erin Kenzie, Tamer Khraisha, Heetae Kim, Bob Klapetzky, Brennan Klein, Karen Kommerce, Roman Koziol, Erika Legara, Carl Lipo, Oliver Lopez-Corona, Yeu Wen Mak, Vivien Marmelat, Steve McCormack, Dan Mønster, Alfredo Morales, Yamir Moreno, Ronald Nicholson, Enzo Nicosia, Sibout Nooteboom, Dragan Okanovic, Charles R Paez, Julia Poncela C., Francisco Rodrigues, Jorge P. Rodríguez, Iza Romanowska, Pier Luigi Sacco, Joaquín Sanz, Samuel Scarpino, Alice Schwarze, Nasser Sharareh, Keith Malcolm Smith, Ricard Sole, Keith Sonnanburg, Cédric Sueur, Ali Sumner, Michael Szell, Ali Tareq, Adam Timlett, Ignacio Toledo, Leo Torres, Paul van der Cingel, Ben van Lier, Jeffrey Ventrella, Alessandro Vespignani, Joe Wasserman, Kristen Weiss, Daehan Won, Phil Wood, Nicky Zachariou, Mengsen Zhang, Arshi, Brewingsense, Complexity Space Consulting, Raoul, Systems Innovation, The NoDE Lab&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Special thanks to Dirk Brockmann for his &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.complexity-explorables.org/&quot;&gt;Complexity Explorables&lt;/a&gt; and to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/serafina-agnello-a0683828/&quot;&gt;Serafina Agnello&lt;/a&gt; for designing and realizing the booklet.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 11:22:34 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>harscoat</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://complexityexplained.github.io/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The war on disinformation is a war on dissent</title>
<link>https://humanevents.com/2021/02/04/the-war-on-disinformation-is-a-war-on-dissent/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://humanevents.com/2021/02/04/the-war-on-disinformation-is-a-war-on-dissent/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The terms “misinformation” and “disinformation” have dominated the political lexicon in recent years. Whereas misinformation merely refers to inaccurate or misleading information, the label of disinformation implies an intent to deceive. Both have served as the source of much consternation and hand-wringing from media figures and politicians alike, with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/spotlight/disinformation&quot;&gt;countless articles&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/business/live-news/election-2020-misinformation/index.html&quot;&gt;press segments&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://mitsloan.mit.edu/ideas-made-to-matter/mit-sloan-research-about-social-media-misinformation-and-elections&quot;&gt;academic papers&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.poynter.org/fact-checking/2021/bidens-speech-elevated-the-dangers-of-disinformation-with-references-to-truth-facts-and-lies/&quot;&gt;political speeches&lt;/a&gt; devoted to solving the problem posed by intentionally false or misleading information and “fake news.” For its part, the Biden administration has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.poynter.org/fact-checking/2021/bidens-speech-elevated-the-dangers-of-disinformation-with-references-to-truth-facts-and-lies/&quot;&gt;characterized disinformation&lt;/a&gt; as a “threat to our democracy,” going as far as to lay out a &lt;a href=&quot;https://raskin.house.gov/media/press-releases/house-democrats-propose-roadmap-biden-administration-fighting-disinformation&quot;&gt;road map&lt;/a&gt; for how to combat it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Misinformation and disinformation are natural consequences of our public institutions’ inconsistency and incompetence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While our inability as a society to agree on basic facts is certainly a problem, what should be self-evident is that misinformation and disinformation naturally abound when there is very little trust in sense-making institutions. If the information sources that are deemed “authoritative” are so often &lt;a href=&quot;https://justthenews.com/video/5-times-cdc-got-it-wrong-coronvirus&quot;&gt;wrong or misleading&lt;/a&gt;, and inspire little &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pewresearch.org/politics/2020/09/14/americans-views-of-government-low-trust-but-some-positive-performance-ratings/&quot;&gt;public confidence&lt;/a&gt;, is it any wonder that people turn to alternatives? Misinformation and disinformation are natural consequences of our public institutions’ inconsistency and incompetence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, the escalating war on misinformation and disinformation seems to be less concerned with actually trying to establish authoritative sources of truth as it is with marginalizing facts or narratives that don’t suit the establishment agenda. The labels “misinformation” and “disinformation” are liberally and inconsistently applied to silence dissent and promote certain political interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The war on misinformation and disinformation is more about controlling the political narrative than it is about establishing a consensus on basic facts; narratives that threaten the establishment are &lt;a href=&quot;https://variety.com/2020/digital/news/twitter-blocking-nypost-china-hunter-biden-account-locked-1234808416/&quot;&gt;banned&lt;/a&gt;, and the tyrannical expansion of government power ensues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_185349&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;img aria-describedby=&quot;caption-attachment-185349&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-185349 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://humanevents.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/disinformation.png&quot; alt=&quot;&amp;quot;Disinformation.&amp;quot;&quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; srcset=&quot;https://humanevents.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/disinformation.png 1920w, https://humanevents.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/disinformation-300x169.png 300w, https://humanevents.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/disinformation-1024x576.png 1024w, https://humanevents.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/disinformation-768x432.png 768w, https://humanevents.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/disinformation-1536x864.png 1536w, https://humanevents.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/disinformation-1000x563.png 1000w, https://humanevents.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/disinformation-560x315.png 560w, https://humanevents.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/disinformation-1200x675.png 1200w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p id=&quot;caption-attachment-185349&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;“Disinformation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WHY INSTITUTIONS AREN’T TRUSTED&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;False or misleading information is the inevitable product of a lack of trust in authoritative, sense-making institutions. For decades, trust in public institutions, such as government, media, and academia, has been &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pewresearch.org/fact-tank/2019/07/22/key-findings-about-americans-declining-trust-in-government-and-each-other/&quot;&gt;declining&lt;/a&gt;. 69% of Americans believe their government intentionally lies to them, while 61% believe the news media deliberately ignores certain stories or information. Much of this decline can be attributed to the failures of the institutions themselves: institutional deficiencies that are perfectly captured in the response to, and media coverage of, the COVID-19 crisis. A combination of incompetence, hypocrisy, and duplicity in the handling of the virus has shattered the public’s faith in media, local government, and federal agencies. As it pertains to information about the coronavirus, only &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.latimes.com/world-nation/story/2020-10-20/ap-norc-usafacts-poll-us-trust-in-covid-19-information-down&quot;&gt;36% of Americans&lt;/a&gt; claim to trust the CDC, while 26% trust their state and local government, and only 18% trust the media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When all this was the consequence of listening to the “experts,” no wonder misinformation and disinformation have become so prevalent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The public’s distrust is well-merited. Dr. Anthony Fauci, one of the leaders of the Coronavirus Task Force, has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonexaminer.com/opinion/editorials/faucis-noble-lies-catch-up-to-him&quot;&gt;admitted&lt;/a&gt; that he intentionally lied to the public regarding the vaccination rate needed to halt the virus. State Governors, such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.foxla.com/news/fox-11-obtains-exclusive-photos-of-gov-newsom-at-french-restaurant-allegedly-not-following-covid-19-protocols&quot;&gt;Gavin Newsom&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://nypost.com/2020/11/20/our-hypocritical-leaders-refuse-to-obey-their-own-covid-19-rules/&quot;&gt;Andrew Cuomo&lt;/a&gt;, have repeatedly flaunted their own lockdown orders, with the former doing so to eat a $900 dinner. And these are only the most egregious &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newsweek.com/every-mayor-governor-caught-breaking-covid-restrictions-1552033&quot;&gt;examples&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While lies and hypocrisy don’t exactly endear one to the public, the corresponding mismanagement of the virus aggravated public distrust. Anthony Fauci’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/coronavirus-white-house-15-day-plan-too-short-2020-3&quot;&gt;lockdown plan&lt;/a&gt; of “two weeks to flatten the curve” has turned into a year of lockdowns; nonsensical &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.beckershospitalreview.com/supply-chain/don-t-let-covid-19-vaccine-priority-groups-slow-vaccinations-surgeon-general-says.html&quot;&gt;vaccine prioritization&lt;/a&gt; policies have led to wasted doses; a lack of substantial economic relief has ruined &lt;a href=&quot;https://carsey.unh.edu/COVID-19-Economic-Impact-By-State&quot;&gt;millions of lives&lt;/a&gt;. When all this was the consequence of listening to the “experts,” no wonder misinformation and disinformation have become so prevalent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet rather than take responsibility for poorly-informed &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/22176191/covid-19-coronavirus-pandemic-democrats-republicans-trump&quot;&gt;policy decisions&lt;/a&gt;, the common refrain from public institutions has been to blame everyday Americans. Failure to follow social distancing regulations, stay-at-home orders, and mask mandates have been held up by media and elected officials alike as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-10-29/wearing-face-masks-are-key-to-avoiding-shutdowns-fauci-says&quot;&gt;chief cause&lt;/a&gt; of the pandemic’s persistence, and “anti-maskers” have been &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.medscape.com/viewarticle/937103&quot;&gt;demonized&lt;/a&gt; as convenient scapegoats for colossal bureaucratic failures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los Angeles County, one of the most &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2021/01/29/us/los-angeles-county-covid-rates.html&quot;&gt;COVID-19-affected&lt;/a&gt; areas in the country, exemplifies this trend. Rather than address their failings, lawmakers and public officials have abdicated responsibility for the crisis and placed the blame on the average citizen. Following a vote to increase fines for non-mask wearers, Los Angeles City Councilman Paul Koretz &lt;a href=&quot;https://abc7.com/los-angeles-coronavirus-masks-enforcement/9644514/&quot;&gt;argued that&lt;/a&gt; “widespread non-compliance is driving this unimaginable spread.” Los Angeles County Health Officer Muntu Davis, meanwhile, has even gone as far as calling those not wearing masks “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theblaze.com/news/not-wearing-mask-in-public-is-act-of-domestic-terrorism-la-county-health-officer-declares&quot;&gt;domestic terrorists&lt;/a&gt;.” (Nevermind the fact that mask compliance has been “great,” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbsnews.com/news/transcript-mayor-eric-garcetti-on-face-the-nation-january-3-2021/&quot;&gt;in the words&lt;/a&gt; of Los Angeles Mayor Eric Garcetti; it’s simply easier to blame the people.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather than confront the fact that a year of lockdowns and mask mandates isn’t working, our local governments, the ostensible representatives of the people, have opted to bury their heads in the sand. And, by blaming the public, our institutions have succeeded in eroding social trust and nurturing a culture of suspicion. People no longer see their local governments as remotely capable, and therefore no longer see them as worthy of trust. And if people can’t trust their government to do its job, they’re not going to trust it as a source for information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_185348&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;img aria-describedby=&quot;caption-attachment-185348&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-185348 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://humanevents.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/cdc.png&quot; alt=&quot;CDC.&quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; srcset=&quot;https://humanevents.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/cdc.png 1920w, https://humanevents.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/cdc-300x169.png 300w, https://humanevents.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/cdc-1024x576.png 1024w, https://humanevents.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/cdc-768x432.png 768w, https://humanevents.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/cdc-1536x864.png 1536w, https://humanevents.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/cdc-1000x563.png 1000w, https://humanevents.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/cdc-560x315.png 560w, https://humanevents.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/cdc-1200x675.png 1200w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p id=&quot;caption-attachment-185348&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;CDC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE HYPOCRISY OF MISINFORMATION/DISINFORMATION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trust in authoritative sources of information has also been damaged by the inconsistent and politically-motivated application of the “misinformation” and “disinformation” labels. That classification is rarely based on any actual criteria for determining truth. Instead, it’s an identifier of whether or not information deviates from the party line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[T]heories or facts that don’t fit the official narrative, despite being true, are treated as misinformation or disinformation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facts or theories historically treated as misinformation have often become the official position of our public officials and institutions. For example, theories such as the notion that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thelancet.com/journals/landia/article/PIIS2213-8587(21)00003-6/fulltext&quot;&gt;Vitamin D&lt;/a&gt; is effective in lowering the risk of COVID-19 transmission, or that masks are effective in preventing COVID-19 infection, were once both &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.marketwatch.com/story/the-cdc-says-americans-dont-have-to-wear-facemasks-because-of-coronavirus-2020-01-30&quot;&gt;considered misinformation&lt;/a&gt;. Yet the CDC now recommends mask usage, and Anthony Fauci (though not the CDC in an official capacity), &lt;a href=&quot;https://bgr.com/2020/09/28/coronavirus-treatment-vitamin-d-anthony-fauci-recommendation/&quot;&gt;now recommends&lt;/a&gt; Vitamin D supplements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, the theory that COVID-19 numbers were inflated by false positives due to inaccurate testing, once considered a dangerous &lt;a href=&quot;https://sciencebasedmedicine.org/no-covid-19-casedemic/&quot;&gt;conspiracy theory&lt;/a&gt;, is now the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.who.int/news/item/20-01-2021-who-information-notice-for-ivd-users-2020-05&quot;&gt;official position&lt;/a&gt; of the World Health Organization. And while questioning the efficacy, and even the morality, of lockdowns was once demonized as callous and selfish, previously &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.msn.com/en-us/video/other/new-york-gov-andrew-cuomo-gets-heat-for-apparent-pivot-on-reopening-economy/vi-BB1cFdoT&quot;&gt;pro-lockdown governors&lt;/a&gt; are now advocating for reopening the economy despite cases being at an all-time high.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In these examples, theories or facts that don’t fit the official narrative, despite being true, are treated as misinformation or disinformation. More troubling, however, is when these labels are applied to information that would harm particular political interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, reports of Hunter Biden’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.msn.com/en-us/news/politics/hunter-biden-offered-2410-million-annually-by-chinese-energy-firm-for-e2-80-98introductions-alone-e2-80-99-email-shows/ar-BB1a3pj8&quot;&gt;dealings with Ukraine and China&lt;/a&gt; that were leaked mere weeks before the 2020 Presidential Election were characterized by our infallible national security experts as “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.politico.com/news/2020/10/19/hunter-biden-story-russian-disinfo-430276&quot;&gt;Russian disinformation&lt;/a&gt;,” before eventually being accepted as fact six weeks later—conveniently after the election had concluded. Similarly, the idea that former Obama-era CIA Director John Brennan was spying on the Trump campaign was mocked by “official” sources as disinformation, despite &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.foxnews.com/politics/dni-brennan-notes-cia-memo-clinton&quot;&gt;being confirmed&lt;/a&gt; by Brennan’s own notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_185347&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;img aria-describedby=&quot;caption-attachment-185347&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-185347 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://humanevents.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/moderna-vaccine.png&quot; alt=&quot;Moderna vaccine.&quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; srcset=&quot;https://humanevents.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/moderna-vaccine.png 1920w, https://humanevents.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/moderna-vaccine-300x169.png 300w, https://humanevents.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/moderna-vaccine-1024x576.png 1024w, https://humanevents.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/moderna-vaccine-768x432.png 768w, https://humanevents.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/moderna-vaccine-1536x864.png 1536w, https://humanevents.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/moderna-vaccine-1000x563.png 1000w, https://humanevents.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/moderna-vaccine-560x315.png 560w, https://humanevents.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/moderna-vaccine-1200x675.png 1200w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p id=&quot;caption-attachment-185347&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Moderna vaccine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;REPRESSION TO COMBAT DISINFORMATION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it’s certainly an issue that experts and public officials are often wrong or simply lying to protect their agenda when they label reality as misinformation or disinformation, the more pressing problem is that these politically-motivated labels, particularly disinformation, are being used to justify censorship and repression. Tech platforms have routinely &lt;a href=&quot;https://thehill.com/opinion/healthcare/531091-twitter-and-facebook-to-censor-vaccine-discourse-this-must-stop&quot;&gt;censored information&lt;/a&gt; deemed “misleading” regarding COVID-19 and the Pfizer and Moderna vaccines, while scientific journals &lt;a href=&quot;https://gmwatch.org/en/news/latest-news/19475&quot;&gt;refused to publish&lt;/a&gt; papers arguing that COVID-19 originated in a lab. Similarly, censorship of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.breitbart.com/tech/2021/01/07/youtube-escalates-censorship-of-election-misinformation/&quot;&gt;election fraud&lt;/a&gt; claims are well-documented, with President Donald Trump, along with a host of other conservatives, being censored for “promoting disinformation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But of course, hypocrisy is the point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An even more disturbing trend has arisen over the past few weeks: disinformation is now increasingly referred to as “dangerous” and is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.motherjones.com/politics/2020/12/trump-stochastic-terrorism-violence-rhetoric/&quot;&gt;being associated&lt;/a&gt; with “domestic terrorism.” In a series of tweets, Juliette Kayyem, a member of the Council on Foreign Relations, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.motherjones.com/politics/2020/12/trump-stochastic-terrorism-violence-rhetoric/&quot;&gt;characterized&lt;/a&gt; Trump’s claims of election fraud as “stochastic terrorism,” while domestic terror consultant Daryl Johnson &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/politics-news/isn-t-final-chapter-analyst-warns-again-about-rise-right-n1253950&quot;&gt;argued&lt;/a&gt; in an interview with NBC News that election fraud claims are “pouring fuel on the fire” of “extremist” violence. Even the Union of Concerned Scientists, a national nonprofit with no expertise in electoral politics, has deemed it appropriate &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.ucsusa.org/genna-reed/dangers-of-autocratic-disinformation-playbook&quot;&gt;to characterize&lt;/a&gt; the events at the Capitol as the “predictable outcome of an autocrat’s deadly disinformation spiral.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-width=&quot;550&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot; readability=&quot;10.790368271955&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Thread on Stochastic Terrorism: For years, the President of the United States Donald Trump has utilized his pulpit, twitter and his WH team to perfect a technique known as &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/stochasticterrorism?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#stochasticterrorism&lt;/a&gt;, inciting random but predictable violence by supporters. His goal was this⬇️ &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/JUV9I84sYQ&quot;&gt;https://t.co/JUV9I84sYQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Juliette Kayyem (@juliettekayyem) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/juliettekayyem/status/1338549546163515395?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;December 14, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s absurd is that many of those attempting to establish a link between disinformation and violence are themselves using disinformation to buttress their arguments, and are guilty of the very thing they are accusing Trump of doing: challenging an election without evidence. The claim that former President Trump willfully “incited violence” by alleging fraud and urging his supporters to take action is easily refuted by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2021/1/11/full-transcript-donald-trump-january-6-incendiary-speech&quot;&gt;actual transcript&lt;/a&gt; of his speech. Moreover, if challenging an election without evidence is equivalent to inciting violence, what would three years of Russiagate histrionics be considered? (Ironically enough, Juliette Kayyem wrote &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2017/03/03/opinions/no-smoking-gun-in-russia-investigation-kayyem/index.html&quot;&gt;several articles&lt;/a&gt; advancing the Russiagate narrative.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But of course, hypocrisy is the point. The “disinformation” label is applied inconsistently in order to silence dissent and further the political interests of those in power. By linking disinformation to violence, censorship of certain narratives, and repression of those who espouse them can be justified under the guise of public safety. This was the &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.twitter.com/en_us/topics/company/2020/suspension.html&quot;&gt;justification&lt;/a&gt; for banning then-President Trump from Twitter and serves as the justification for expanding government surveillance of American citizens under the guise of stemming disinformation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just last month, former NSA general counsel Glenn Gerstell &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbsnews.com/news/tackling-disinformation-is-national-security-issue-says-former-nsa-general-counsel/&quot;&gt;called for&lt;/a&gt; an “integrated disinformation center within the federal government” that would employ “counterterrorism” tactics to combat disinformation. It’s not exactly clear what these counterterrorism tactics would entail, but the idea that institutions that so often lie to the public should be able to decide what is and what is not “disinformation,” with the help of a surveillance apparatus designed to combat terrorism, is truly unnerving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As trust in institutions continues to decline, this kind of hostile information control will only escalate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other, less overt, forms of censorship and information control have also been proposed on the basis of combating disinformation. Academics at &lt;a href=&quot;https://law.yale.edu/sites/default/files/area/center/isp/documents/fighting_fake_news_-_workshop_report.pdf&quot;&gt;Yale Law&lt;/a&gt;, as well as researchers at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rand.org/research/projects/truth-decay/fighting-disinformation.html&quot;&gt;RAND Corporation&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brookings.edu/research/how-to-combat-fake-news-and-disinformation/&quot;&gt;Brookings Institute&lt;/a&gt;, have each separately argued for an online accreditation system that would determine which information sources are “trustworthy” and “reliable.” The decision as to which sources are reliable would, predictably, be made by a panel of “experts.” Similar tactics such as “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theinformation.com/articles/facebook-researchers-found-companys-political-whitelist-influenced-misinformation-spread&quot;&gt;whitelisting&lt;/a&gt;,” in which approved information sources are compiled and publicized, have also been suggested, with actually Facebook implementing a whitelisting strategy this election cycle. If this is allowed to continue, content from establishment-friendly sources will continue to be prioritized by the information infrastructure, while dissenting voices would be ghettoized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As trust in institutions continues to decline, this kind of hostile information control will only escalate. The incompetence of our government and institutions will continue to be excused, as alternative hypotheses can simply be labeled as misinformation or disinformation. Criticism can be silenced, and poor governance can be spared its natural consequences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More importantly, it will be increasingly difficult to meaningfully dissent, and ideas, information, and narratives that threaten the status quo will be removed from public discourse. When the only acceptable information is that approved by the ruling administration, there can be no meaningful check on state power. Consent for the establishment agenda can easily be manufactured, and opposition can simply be deemed “disinformation” and treated as “dangerous,” deserving of censorship and removal. With a silenced opposition, power can therefore be exercised with impunity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 08:16:26 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>AndrewBissell</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>The War on Disinformation Is a War on Dissent. | Human Events</og:title>
<og:description>“Disinformation” and “misinformation” are used to excuse incompetence and punish opposition.</og:description>
<og:url>https://humanevents.com/2021/02/04/the-war-on-disinformation-is-a-war-on-dissent/</og:url>
<og:image>https://humanevents.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/header-disinfo.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://humanevents.com/2021/02/04/the-war-on-disinformation-is-a-war-on-dissent/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Paul Taylor, the engineer who created the TTY machine for the deaf, has died</title>
<link>https://www.oregonlive.com/health/2021/02/he-died-in-portland-his-legacy-of-helping-the-deaf-communicate-with-the-world.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.oregonlive.com/health/2021/02/he-died-in-portland-his-legacy-of-helping-the-deaf-communicate-with-the-world.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;article__paragraph article__paragraph--left&quot; id=&quot;C6IRA27U3FAFTI43YBKBSQ5JU4&quot;&gt;Paul Taylor was born deaf, this in 1939, an era when people so physically different were labeled misfits. As such, his parents did not see a promising future for their son in Alabama.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article__paragraph article__paragraph--left&quot; id=&quot;A25CICTMQ5HSJDHGPGDANC5WKY&quot;&gt;By the time he died last month, at 81, he had lived around the country, the end coming in his Portland home. Alzheimer’s had robbed the man of his perseverance, the quality he used to change the lives of people he never met. Taylor was one of those people — and the world is full of them — who fight the good fight in the shadows, their remarkable achievements not fully understood and certainly taken for granted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;article__paragraph article__paragraph--left&quot; id=&quot;2JOASY32CJD3JPL43U6TZMQBUU&quot;&gt;“My father was driven by this strong desire to communicate,” said his daughter, Irene Taylor. “That defines his life. It’s impossible to appreciate how difficult it was to be deaf and to parent a deaf child in the 1940s. My father was someone who believed technology was central to the deaf experience. The more technology you could access, the better your life would be.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;article__paragraph article__paragraph--left&quot; id=&quot;GZUNXWSJPBDC7P6HMAZNVK5ZJE&quot;&gt;At age 4, Taylor was put on a train and sent from Birmingham to the Central Institute for the Deaf, a St. Louis boarding school. It was there he met the little deaf girl he would one day marry. He was given a primitive hearing aid and was taught to read lips. When his father died three years later, Taylor’s mother moved to St. Louis and studied at her son’s school to become an accredited teacher for the deaf.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;article__paragraph article__paragraph--left&quot; id=&quot;ZL5N5XX7UZGRPKP4DK57YNE2DE&quot;&gt;“My father did not have a lot of people in his life,” said his daughter. “He had his mother. She completely focused on him and became his advocate.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;article__paragraph article__paragraph--left&quot; id=&quot;H5IQTHAOZNBTZITPLALP2PJKZY&quot;&gt;Mother and son eventually moved to Houston, where she started a school for the deaf and eventually remarried. She enrolled her seventh-grade son in a public school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;article__paragraph article__paragraph--left&quot; id=&quot;R5QFIMBGSNEZBNT3WKWZ2LSQNM&quot;&gt;“A child gets cues from the people who raise them,” said Irene Taylor, who was named after her grandmother. “Dad was told there was no reason he could not go to public school, to college and to grad school, where he earned a degree in chemical engineering. He never had a note taker or an interpreter, all the things the deaf are now provided for by law. My dad never felt sorry for himself. He was always an optimist.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;article__paragraph article__paragraph--left&quot; id=&quot;DIO6YZJ3EFBQ3HIFACSMQPGR7M&quot;&gt;Paul Taylor eventually married Sally, that little girl, and they had three children. He worked as a chemical engineer for a St. Louis Company. But his real passion, something he did on the side, was to look for ways to improve the lives of the deaf.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;article__paragraph article__paragraph--left&quot; id=&quot;B3PK2U7RVFBVDJWXK6O4MSIGRE&quot;&gt;“He saw there were old World War II teletype machines not being used,” said his daughter. “Another deaf engineer in California had come up with the way to send signals over phone lines. My dad came up with the coupler component the teletype needed. He then pressed Western Union to provide the old machines to deaf people and Bell telephone to use them on their lines.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;article__paragraph article__paragraph--left&quot; id=&quot;NMBDRDPEBBCS5JY6ZOUTZDVHEE&quot;&gt;As rudimentary as it may seem now — both users needed a machine to type messages back and forth on what was called TTY, Telecommunications Device for the Deaf — it was as innovative when it launched in the 1960s as text messaging was when smart phones entered our lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;article__image-wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;article__image-content&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.oregonlive.com/resizer/UNqLK78Cd4klK91IKhHFIrqSTH4=/700x0/smart/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/advancelocal/DBM5DNK3RJGUDHCBZECACCOPDY.jpeg 700w, https://www.oregonlive.com/resizer/QYyzfCDkpAIuS47QgewjUECgUuA=/1280x0/smart/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/advancelocal/DBM5DNK3RJGUDHCBZECACCOPDY.jpeg 1280w&quot; src=&quot;https://www.oregonlive.com/resizer/jJUU3vjCnqcXjI8v29XTX8-sLWE=/450x0/smart/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/advancelocal/DBM5DNK3RJGUDHCBZECACCOPDY.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Father and daughter&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 1280px) 700w, 100vw&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;article__mm-image-caption-text&quot;&gt;Paul Taylor's daughter was named Irene after his mother.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;article__paragraph article__paragraph--left&quot; id=&quot;ECKW2HGUGVG6ZLCNPJRHSUO65Y&quot;&gt;“My parents used them to talk with deaf friends,” said Irene Taylor. “Eventually my grandparents got one. My father never stopped advocating for TTY, pushing for a national system where they would be available in public places.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;article__paragraph article__paragraph--left&quot; id=&quot;HBEPUPBPLND77HAKYJ7PMGW3JQ&quot;&gt;In 1975, Paul Taylor became a professor at the National Technical Institute for the Deaf in Rochester, N.Y. In addition to teaching, Taylor advocated for a national operator relay system for the deaf to allow them to communicate with people who were not deaf and did not have a TTY machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;article__paragraph article__paragraph--left&quot; id=&quot;M3RQZZ3KK5DPPHXZHHRKIY7Z5E&quot;&gt;The goal was to have a deaf person use a TTY machine to connect to an operator who would read the message and then use the phone to call someone — a doctor’s office, a repair shop or a store — and read out loud the deaf person’s message. The operator would listen to the other person’s response and then type back a reply, creating a real-time conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;article__paragraph article__paragraph--left&quot; id=&quot;2KXXRJPJFVGTFBPD2WJS4J2PFA&quot;&gt;Convinced it could work, Taylor took a two-year-leave of absence from teaching and was hired by the Federal Communications Commission in Washington, D.C., to help draft regulations to make the relay system part of the 1990 landmark Americans with Disabilities Act.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;article__paragraph article__paragraph--left&quot; id=&quot;67LPGAQMIVACPFVQLKMEKHC35M&quot;&gt;Karen Straus, then at the FCC to oversee disability and consumer access programs and policies, met Taylor while working on the act.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;article__paragraph article__paragraph--left&quot; id=&quot;EQCXR77TANFORICE6P2K5URBKI&quot;&gt;“He was soft spoken, but determined,” she said. “He had courage and stamina. He was also brilliant.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;article__paragraph article__paragraph--left&quot; id=&quot;N3SXVIP7WJBYVL2KNAIKZFOX64&quot;&gt;His daughter said the relay system was a “deeply emotional endeavor” for her father.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;article__paragraph article__paragraph--left&quot; id=&quot;J5MDFXSVYVE4LPXZUPJQUQPJ4U&quot;&gt;“I was 19 when the phone rang late one night at my friend’s house where we were having a party,” she said. “Someone said there was an operator calling for me. I immediately thought someone had died. Then I heard a woman’s voice say, ‘Irene, this is dad. I am talking to you via a relay operator.’ I started crying. My friends were worried. I told them my dad was calling me. He’d never been able to call me. He was calling me because he finally could.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;article__paragraph article__paragraph--left&quot; id=&quot;4AUXRNAHPRHURNURKK3SF6ENUA&quot;&gt;When the FCC stint ended, Paul Taylor returned to teaching. Irene Taylor moved to Portland in 2002. She had three children. It was then that her parents’ past became her future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;article__paragraph article__paragraph--left&quot; id=&quot;RCHPRQVJTNF4HPKXIKXUOTPKJY&quot;&gt;“My son was 18 months when I found out he was going deaf,” she said. “I was devastated. I imagined all the things my son would have to go through. My parents were my reference point. But I realized I was living in a different world than the one my parents grew up in.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;article__paragraph article__paragraph--left&quot; id=&quot;FTHBVVA3GJEARGEX2XO74MVEBU&quot;&gt;Paul and Sally Taylor eventually moved to Portland, believing they could help their daughter. Her son, Jonas Taylor Brodsky, 15, now has two cochlear implants, which give him access to sound. He can speak and listen. Her parents also got implants, which allowed them to hear sounds for the first time in their lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;article__paragraph article__paragraph--left&quot; id=&quot;BG76V3QKRJGVPF4LRAMUWKPNH4&quot;&gt;In 2007, Irene Taylor, a filmmaker, made a documentary — “Hear and Now” — about their experience. &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.hbomax.com/page/urn:hbo:page:GXTiChQJ1pFzCNQEAAAR7:type:feature&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Her movie won the audience award at the Sundance Film Festival and is now available on HBO.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;article__paragraph article__paragraph--left&quot; id=&quot;EHESSCEQPZCWLBMW3OT4YICFV4&quot;&gt;In 2019, Taylor released a second documentary — “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hbo.com/documentaries/moonlight-sonata-deafness-in-three-movements&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Moonlight Sonata,” also on HBO.&lt;/a&gt; The film examines the lives of Beethoven, who wrote the sonata while deaf, her parents and her son, Jonas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;article__paragraph article__paragraph--left&quot; id=&quot;X2MBBKRR7RC7DPGO7QFCPETT2E&quot;&gt;Her father was diagnosed with Alzheimer’s in 2017 while she was making her movie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;article__paragraph article__paragraph--left&quot; id=&quot;ISHFTV5YAVGPDNHYJDMIBHBT4U&quot;&gt;“The film shows his early descent into dementia,” she said. “What is beautiful about his death is that my mother and I were with him at the moment. They say that with Alzheimer’s your earliest memories are the last to go. I believe my father’s first and last memory is of my mother.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;article__image-wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;34&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;article__image-content&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.oregonlive.com/resizer/6ZGYeN_2MIXnW-7NLY_JIyP0ftk=/700x0/smart/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/advancelocal/SHLQOVWIJJACJIALAONYGGLN24.jpeg 700w, https://www.oregonlive.com/resizer/iDXKOP33jSg0dstjBnqQ7Dz4LVA=/1280x0/smart/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/advancelocal/SHLQOVWIJJACJIALAONYGGLN24.jpeg 1280w&quot; src=&quot;https://www.oregonlive.com/resizer/yTOvFy_Rl7tbKF86d3kJkwdxg_8=/450x0/smart/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/advancelocal/SHLQOVWIJJACJIALAONYGGLN24.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Grandfather and grandson&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 1280px) 700w, 100vw&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;article__mm-image-caption-text&quot;&gt;Paul Taylor and his grandson, Jonas, shared a life journey -- both were deaf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;article__paragraph article__paragraph--left&quot; id=&quot;CEX4NMT3QFCQXNMXQLX62AI23M&quot;&gt;Taylor said her father understood the loneliness that a deaf person deals with because of the challenge to communicate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;article__paragraph article__paragraph--left&quot; id=&quot;REGMX4TKERFR7F677L3ZP3NQYY&quot;&gt;“My father could not accept that being deaf meant being cut off from other people,” she said. “He became an engineer and inventor to make it easier for people like his grandson.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;article__paragraph article__paragraph--left&quot; id=&quot;KCPMB2U3IFAOLOWEAO7NKLWBTI&quot;&gt;-- Tom Hallman Jr; &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:thallman@oregonian.com&quot;&gt;thallman@oregonian.com&lt;/a&gt;; 503-221-8224; @thallmanjr&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 03:35:44 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>wallflower</dc:creator>
<og:title>TTY innovator died in Portland, leaving legacy of helping the deaf communicate</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.oregonlive.com/health/2021/02/he-died-in-portland-his-legacy-of-helping-the-deaf-communicate-with-the-world.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Paul Taylor, born deaf, was an engineer who worked to create technology to allow deaf people to communicate, first with each other and then the world.</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.oregonlive.com/resizer/1Uwo8qyX3Gim1h8JTqHz0tHh7cE=/1280x0/filters:focal(277x190:287x180)/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/advancelocal/DBM5DNK3RJGUDHCBZECACCOPDY.jpeg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.oregonlive.com/health/2021/02/he-died-in-portland-his-legacy-of-helping-the-deaf-communicate-with-the-world.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Virginia lawmakers pass marijuana legalization bills</title>
<link>https://wset.com/news/local/virginia-house-votes-legalize-marijuana</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://wset.com/news/local/virginia-house-votes-legalize-marijuana</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://wset.com/news/local/virginia-house-votes-legalize-marijuana&quot;&gt;https://wset.com/news/local/virginia-house-votes-legalize-marijuana&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26043815&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26043815&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 226&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 166&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 03:20:29 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>underseacables</dc:creator>
<og:title>In historic shift, Virginia lawmakers pass marijuana legalization bills</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://wset.com/news/local/virginia-house-votes-legalize-marijuana</og:url>
<og:image>https://static-29.sinclairstoryline.com/resources/media/c21e5f15-6004-49dd-9d0b-74d06b801372-large16x9_Marijuana.jpeg?1612545843811</og:image>
<og:description>This is an Associated Press update. Our earlier story follows. Both chambers of the Virginia General Assembly have passed legislation that would legalize marijuana for adult recreational use, with retail sales starting several years down the road. Work on the complicated legislation has been a priority for Democrats who control state government. But despite Friday's votes, the process is far from finished.</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://wset.com/news/local/virginia-house-votes-legalize-marijuana</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>