<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Agents raid home of fired Florida data scientist who built Covid-19 dashboard</title>
<link>https://www.tallahassee.com/story/news/2020/12/07/agents-raid-home-fired-florida-data-scientist-who-built-covid-19-dashboard-rebekah-jones/6482817002/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.tallahassee.com/story/news/2020/12/07/agents-raid-home-fired-florida-data-scientist-who-built-covid-19-dashboard-rebekah-jones/6482817002/</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tallahassee.com/story/news/2020/12/07/agents-raid-home-fired-florida-data-scientist-who-built-covid-19-dashboard-rebekah-jones/6482817002/&quot;&gt;https://www.tallahassee.com/story/news/2020/12/07/agents-raid-home-fired-florida-data-scientist-who-built-covid-19-dashboard-rebekah-jones/6482817002/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25339510&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25339510&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 343&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 88&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 23:59:57 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>8ig8</dc:creator>
<dc:identifier>https://www.tallahassee.com/story/news/2020/12/07/agents-raid-home-fired-florida-data-scientist-who-built-covid-19-dashboard-rebekah-jones/6482817002/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Uber sells self-driving unit in deal that will push Aurora’s valuation to $10B</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/07/uber-sells-self-driving-unit-uber-atg-in-deal-that-will-push-auroras-valuation-to-10b/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/07/uber-sells-self-driving-unit-uber-atg-in-deal-that-will-push-auroras-valuation-to-10b/</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;featured__span-first-words&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/aurora-6292&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Aurora Innovation,&lt;/a&gt; the&lt;/span&gt; autonomous vehicle startup backed by Sequoia Capital and Amazon, has reached an agreement with Uber to buy the ride-hailing firm’s self-driving unit in a complex deal that will value the combined company at $10 billion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aurora is not paying cash for &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/uber&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;uber&quot;&gt;Uber&lt;/a&gt; ATG, a company that was &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2019/04/18/uber-atg-1-billion-toyota-denso-vision-fund-spin-out/&quot;&gt;valued at $7.25 billion&lt;/a&gt; following a $1 billion investment last year from Toyota, DENSO and SoftBank’s Vision Fund. Instead, Uber is handing over its equity in ATG and investing $400 million into Aurora, which will give it a 26% stake in the combined company, according to a filing with the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission. (As a refresher, Uber held an 86.2% stake (on a fully diluted basis) in Uber ATG, according to filings with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1543151/000119312519188316/d767435d8k.htm&quot;&gt;SEC&lt;/a&gt;. Uber ATG’s investors held a combined stake of 13.8% in the company.) Shareholders in Uber ATG will now become minority shareholders of Aurora. Notably, once the deal closes, Uber together with existing ATG investors and the ATG employees who continue their employment with Aurora are expected to collectively hold about 40% interest in Aurora on a fully diluted basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uber CEO Dara Khosrowshahi will take a board seat in the newly expanded Aurora.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aurora, which was founded in 2017, is focused on building the full self-driving stack, the underlying technology that will allow vehicles to navigate highways and city streets without a human driver behind the wheel. Aurora has attracted attention and investment from high-profile venture firms, management firms and corporations such as Greylock Partners, Sequoia Capital,  Amazon and T. Rowe Price, in part because of its founders Sterling Anderson, Drew Bagnell and Chris Urmson, all of whom are veterans of the autonomous vehicle industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Urmson led the former Google self-driving project before it spun out to become the Alphabet business Waymo. Anderson is best known for leading the development and launch of the Tesla Model X and the automaker’s Autopilot program. Bagnell, an associate professor at Carnegie Mellon, helped launch Uber’s efforts in autonomy, ultimately heading the autonomy and perception team at the Advanced Technologies Center in Pittsburgh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aurora plans to bring autonomous trucks to market first. However, Urmson has maintained that the company is still pursuing other applications of its self-driving stack such as robotaxis. The deal with Uber ATG provides Aurora with talent and operational facilities. But it delivers on two other important areas: relationships with Uber ATG investors, specifically Toyota, as well as a partnership with Uber that will give it access to its vast ride-hailing platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The way we want to build this company has been with this mindset of let’s build it to scale — let’s create an environment where people can do their best work,” Urmson said in an interview Monday. “And then let’s go look for great teams and bring them in. It’s one way to get a combination of talent and technology, and in this case, also relationships.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The announcement, which confirms &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/13/uber-in-talks-to-sell-atg-self-driving-unit-to-aurora/&quot;&gt;TechCrunch’s reporting in November&lt;/a&gt;, marks the beginning of what promises to be a huge undertaking to merge Uber ATG, a 1,200-person business unit with operations in Pittsburgh, San Francisco and Toronto with its smaller competitor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not clear if all Uber ATG employees will be folded into Aurora, which has 600-person workforce and operations in San Francisco Bay Area, Pittsburgh, Texas and Bozeman, Montana. At least one executive — Uber ATG CEO Eric Meyhofer — will not be joining the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Urmson emphasized that work to integrate the companies and their technology will begin without haste.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“One of the most fun things we’ll be doing over the next 60 days is bringing the two teams together,” Urmson said. “And then kind of dispassionately looking at what is the technology that accelerates our first product to market and then amplifying that — whether it’s from the existing Aurora team or to the new Aurora team — and pushing that forward, whether it’s ideas or code or bits of hardware together to accelerate our time to market.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company plans to assess the workforce and technology as quickly as possible, Urmson said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Uber’s AV history&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Uber, the deal marks one of the last expensive pursuits that it had yet to either spin or sell off as the company narrowed in on its core businesses of ride-hailing and delivery. In the past year, Uber has dumped shared micromobility unit Jump, sold a stake in its growing but still unprofitable logistics arm, Uber Freight and acquired Postmates. Uber is also reportedly in talks to sell off its autonomous air taxi business Uber Elevate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uber ATG was one of those businesses that promised financial benefits in the long term, but delivered lots of pain, controversy and upfront costs since almost the moment it was created.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In early 2015, Uber kicked off its pursuit of autonomous vehicles when it announced a strategic partnership with Carnegie Mellon University’s National Robotics Center. The agreement to work on developing driverless car technology resulted in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/is-uber-a-friend-or-foe-of-carnegie-mellon-in-robotics-1433084582&quot;&gt;Uber poaching dozens of NREC researchers&lt;/a&gt; and scientists. A year later, Uber acquired a self-driving truck startup called Otto, a startup founded by one of Google’s star engineers, Anthony Levandowski, along with three other Google veterans: Lior Ron, Claire Delaunay and Don Burnette.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two months after the acquisition, Google made two arbitration demands against Levandowski and Ron. Uber wasn’t a party to either arbitration. While the arbitrations played out, Waymo separately filed a lawsuit against Uber in February 2017 for trade secret theft and patent infringement. Waymo alleged in the suit, which went to trial but ended in a settlement in 2018, that Levandowski stole trade secrets, which were then used by Uber.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the trial over, Uber pressed on, but almost immediately was involved in another deadlier controversy when one of its autonomous test vehicles — which had a human safety driver behind the wheel — struck and killed a pedestrian in March 2018. The entire industry took pause and Uber halted all testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uber spun out Uber ATG in spring 2019 after closing $1 billion in funding from Toyota, auto parts maker Denso and SoftBank’s Vision Fund. Even with the spin off, Uber still faced a costly enterprise. Uber reported in November that ATG and “other technologies” (which includes Uber Elevate) had a net loss of $303 million in the nine months that ended September 30, 2020. In its S-1 document, Uber said it incurred $457 million of research and development expenses for its ATG and “other Technology Programs” initiatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What Aurora values&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the trail of problems that have plagued Uber ATG, Urmson insists that the company has the talent and some interesting technology that makes it a worthy asset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Some of the work they’ve been doing in designing their next-generation hardware for the vehicles is exciting and interesting,” he said. “On the software side, they have really cool stuff in prediction, and how they’ve combined prediction and the perception system together.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Others close to the deal said Uber ATG has valuable and talented mid-level and low-level engineers, making the acquisition particularly appealing to Aurora.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not Aurora’s first acquisition, although it is certainly its largest and most complex. In 2019, &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/23/fresh-off-a-530m-round-aurora-acquires-lidar-startup-blackmore/&quot;&gt;Aurora acquired Blackmore&lt;/a&gt;, a Bozeman, Montana-based lidar company, and simulation startup 7D Labs. Aurora has touted its  “no jerks” policy and its company culture, which is now about to absorb hundreds of new people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Post-merger integrations can take months, even years, which can in turn slow down technological or operational progress. Urmson thinks differently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If anything, this accelerates our objectives,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 21:08:08 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>seaucre</dc:creator>
<og:title>Uber sells self-driving unit Uber ATG in deal that will push Aurora’s valuation to $10B – TechCrunch</og:title>
<og:description>Aurora Innovation, the autonomous vehicle startup backed by Sequoia Capital and Amazon, has reached an agreement with Uber to buy the ride-hailing firm’s self-driving unit in a complex deal that will value the combined company at $10 billion. Aurora is not paying cash for Uber ATG, a company …</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/aurora-self-driving.jpg?w=711</og:image>
<og:url>https://social.techcrunch.com/2020/12/07/uber-sells-self-driving-unit-uber-atg-in-deal-that-will-push-auroras-valuation-to-10b/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/07/uber-sells-self-driving-unit-uber-atg-in-deal-that-will-push-auroras-valuation-to-10b/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>SpaceX gets $886M from FCC to subsidize Starlink in 35 states</title>
<link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2020/12/spacex-gets-886-million-from-fcc-to-subsidize-starlink-in-35-states/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2020/12/spacex-gets-886-million-from-fcc-to-subsidize-starlink-in-35-states/</guid>
<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/starlink-forest-1-800x600.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;A SpaceX Starlink satellite dish placed on the ground in a forest clearing.&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/starlink-forest-1.jpeg&quot; class=&quot;enlarge-link&quot; data-height=&quot;750&quot; data-width=&quot;1000&quot;&gt;Enlarge&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;sep&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; Starlink satellite dish and equipment in the Idaho panhandle's Coeur d'Alene National Forest.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;aside id=&quot;social-left&quot; class=&quot;social-left&quot; aria-label=&quot;Read the comments or share this article&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;comment-count-before&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;82 posters participating, including story author&quot; class=&quot;comment-count icon-comment-bubble-down&quot; href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2020/12/spacex-gets-886-million-from-fcc-to-subsidize-starlink-in-35-states/?comments=1&quot;&gt;reader comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;a title=&quot;82 posters participating, including story author&quot; class=&quot;comment-count icon-comment-bubble-down&quot; href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2020/12/spacex-gets-886-million-from-fcc-to-subsidize-starlink-in-35-states/?comments=1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;comment-count-number&quot;&gt;107&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;with 82 posters participating, including story author&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;share-links&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Share this story&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;SpaceX has been awarded $885.51 million by the Federal Communications Commission to provide Starlink broadband to 642,925 rural homes and businesses in 35 states. The satellite provider was one of the biggest winners in the FCC's Rural Digital Opportunity Fund (RDOF) auction, the results of which were &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fcc.gov/document/fcc-auction-bring-broadband-over-10-million-rural-americans&quot;&gt;released today&lt;/a&gt;. Funding is distributed over 10 years, so SpaceX's haul will amount to a little over $88.5 million per year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Charter Communications, the second-largest US cable company after Comcast, did even better. Charter is set to receive $1.22 billion over 10 years to bring service to 1.06 million homes and businesses in 24 states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FCC funding can be used in different ways depending on the type of broadband service. Cable companies like Charter and other wireline providers generally use the money to expand their networks into new areas that don't already have broadband. But with Starlink, SpaceX could theoretically provide service to all of rural America once it has launched enough satellites, even without FCC funding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One possibility is that SpaceX could use the FCC money to &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2019/12/no-fiber-zone-fcc-funds-25mbps-data-capped-satellite-in-rural-areas/&quot;&gt;lower prices&lt;/a&gt; in the 642,925 funded locations, but the FCC announcement didn't say whether that's what SpaceX will do. We asked SpaceX and the FCC for more details and will update this article if we get any answers. Starlink is in &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2020/10/spacex-starlink-public-beta-begins-its-99-a-month-plus-500-up-front/&quot;&gt;beta and costs&lt;/a&gt; $99 per month, plus a one-time fee of $499 for the user terminal, mounting tripod, and router.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.fcc.gov/public/attachments/DA-20-1422A2.pdf&quot;&gt;35 states&lt;/a&gt; where SpaceX won FCC funding are Alabama, Arkansas, California, Colorado, Connecticut, Florida, Georgia, Hawaii, Idaho, Illinois, Kentucky, Louisiana, Maine, Maryland, Massachusetts, Michigan, Minnesota, Mississippi, Montana, Nevada, New Hampshire, New Jersey, New Mexico, New York, North Carolina, Oregon, Pennsylvania, South Carolina, Tennessee, Utah, Vermont, Virginia, Washington, West Virginia, and Wyoming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Charter is getting funding in Alabama, California, Florida, Georgia, Illinois, Indiana, Kentucky, Louisiana, Massachusetts, Michigan, Missouri, New Hampshire, New Mexico, North Carolina, Ohio, Oregon, Pennsylvania, South Carolina, Tennessee, Texas, Vermont, Virginia, Washington, and Wisconsin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;180 ISPs get funding in 49 states&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the FCC announced $9.2 billion ($920 million per year) in funding for 180 bidders in 49 states and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands. Windstream, Frontier, and CenturyLink were also among the winners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Combined, the 180 providers will &quot;deploy high-speed broadband to over 5.2 million unserved homes and businesses. Moreover, 99.7 percent of these locations will be receiving broadband with speeds of at least 100/20Mbps, with an overwhelming majority (over 85 percent) getting gigabit-speed broadband,&quot; the FCC said. In addition to wireline and satellite, the winning ISPs included fixed-wireless providers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;ad_wrapper&quot; aria-label=&quot;In Content advertisement&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ad_notice&quot;&gt;Advertisement&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;The FCC had set aside $16 billion for this first phase of the RDOF but said it ended up covering nearly 99 percent of eligible locations with just $9.2 billion. Since the RDOF has $20.4 billion overall, there will be $11.2 billion available in the next phase of the RDOF.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The auction used a multi-round, descending clock auction format in which bidders indicated in each round whether they would commit to provide service to an area at a given performance tier and latency at the current round’s support amount,&quot; the FCC said. &quot;The auction was technologically neutral and open to new providers, and bidding procedures prioritized bids for higher speeds and lower latency.&quot; The FCC &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2020/06/fcc-has-serious-doubts-that-spacex-can-deliver-latencies-under-100ms/&quot;&gt;initially disputed&lt;/a&gt; SpaceX's contention that its low Earth orbit (LEO) satellites can provide latency under 100ms but eventually &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2020/10/spacex-gets-fcc-approval-to-bid-in-16-billion-rural-broadband-auction/&quot;&gt;relented&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No other LEO satellite providers are getting the FCC funding. Hughes, a traditional satellite provider, got $1.27 million over 10 years to serve 3,678 locations in Rhode Island but did not get funding in any other states. Hughes relies on geostationary satellites that don't match Starlink on speed or latency, though Hughes is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hughes.com/resources/press-releases/hughes-join-uk-government-and-bharti-enterprises-new-oneweb-consortium&quot;&gt;investing&lt;/a&gt; in LEO satellite operator OneWeb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;More big winners&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.fcc.gov/public/attachments/DOC-368588A1.pdf&quot;&gt;Other winners&lt;/a&gt; include &lt;a href=&quot;https://ltdbroadband.com/&quot;&gt;LTD Broadband&lt;/a&gt;, which was awarded $1.32 billion to serve 528,088 locations in 15 states; the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.conexon.us/news-events/rural-electric-consortium-becomes-the-first-electric-consortium-to-qualify/&quot;&gt;Rural Electric Cooperative Consortium&lt;/a&gt; with $1.1 billion for 618,476 locations in 22 states; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.windstream.com/about/windstream-information/coverage-map&quot;&gt;Windstream&lt;/a&gt; with $522.89 million for 192,567 locations in 18 states; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lightreading.com/mobile/5g/amgs-nextlink-the-fccs-poster-child-for-crossing-the-digital-divide/d/d-id/752857&quot;&gt;AMG Technology Investment Group&lt;/a&gt; with $429.23 million for 206,136 locations in 12 states; &lt;a href=&quot;https://frontier.com/local&quot;&gt;Frontier&lt;/a&gt; with $370.9 million for 127,188 locations in eight states; &lt;a href=&quot;https://resoundnetworks.com/&quot;&gt;Resound Networks&lt;/a&gt; with $310.68 million for 219,239 locations in seven states; Connect Everyone LLC (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lightreading.com/opticalip/here-are-all-winners-of-fccs-%2492b-rdof-auction/d/d-id/765937&quot;&gt;aka Starry&lt;/a&gt;) with $268.85 million for 108,506 locations in nine states; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.centurylink.com/local.html&quot;&gt;CenturyLink&lt;/a&gt; with $262.37 million for 77,257 locations in 20 states; &lt;a href=&quot;https://geolinks.com/&quot;&gt;GeoLinks&lt;/a&gt; with $234.89 million for 128,297 locations in three states; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://ethericnetworks.com/&quot;&gt;Etheric Networks&lt;/a&gt; with $248.63 million for 64,463 locations in one state (California).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like other universal service programs, the RDOF and Connect America Fund (its predecessor program) are paid for by Americans through fees imposed on phone bills. The first phase of the RDOF targets census blocks where there are no ISPs offering service with at least 25Mbps download and 3Mbps upload speeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That measure leaves out a lot of unserved homes because FCC data &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2020/02/fcc-data-fails-to-count-21-million-people-without-broadband-study-finds/&quot;&gt;counts an entire census block as served&lt;/a&gt; even if only one home in the block can get service. The FCC has &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/08/the-fccs-horrible-broadband-mapping-system-is-finally-getting-an-upgrade/&quot;&gt;ordered ISPs&lt;/a&gt; to provide more precise data using geospatial maps and is on track to conduct the next RDOF auction after the data is collected. The $11.2 billion for Phase 2 would target partially served areas and unserved areas that didn't get funding in the first round.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The FCC has a separate &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fcc.gov/alaska-plan&quot;&gt;$1.5 billion program for Alaska&lt;/a&gt;, which is not among the 49 states that will receive RDOF funding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disclosure: The Advance/Newhouse Partnership, which owns 13 percent of Charter, is part of Advance Publications. Advance Publications owns Condé Nast, which owns Ars Technica.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 19:45:28 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>samizdis</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2020/12/spacex-gets-886-million-from-fcc-to-subsidize-starlink-in-35-states/</og:url>
<og:title>SpaceX gets $886 million from FCC to subsidize Starlink in 35 states</og:title>
<og:image>https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/starlink-forest-1-760x380.jpeg</og:image>
<og:description>Charter also wins big; FCC fund will bring service to 5.2M homes and businesses.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2020/12/spacex-gets-886-million-from-fcc-to-subsidize-starlink-in-35-states/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>14 nations commit to protect oceans</title>
<link>https://www.nationalgeographic.co.uk/environment-and-conservation/2020/12/in-rare-show-of-solidarity-14-key-nations-commit-to-protect</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nationalgeographic.co.uk/environment-and-conservation/2020/12/in-rare-show-of-solidarity-14-key-nations-commit-to-protect</guid>
<description>&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New science supports the plan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The effort was backed up by a team of 253 scientists that conducted new ocean research and published 16 authoritative papers on topics ranging from an assessment of stemming the flow of plastic waste to combating climate change. At least nine of them are being published in &lt;em&gt;Nature&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The scientific process was very rigorous,” says &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dal.ca/faculty/science/biology/faculty-staff/our-faculty/boris-worm/boris-worm.html&quot;&gt;Boris Worm&lt;/a&gt;, a marine scientist at Dalhousie University in Nova Scotia who served as a science advisor to the Canada delegation. “When you get together with people with diverging interests and you look at the available data together, there is less to haggle about. The data is the data. You can act together.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The members of the High Level Panel also were willing to turn conventional thinking on its ear. Instead of considering the ocean as merely a victim of climate change—which it undoubtedly is, as it’s both warming and acidifying—the leaders say the seas should be harnessed to become part of the global solution. The key to that is to take an all-in approach—sustainably manage 100 percent of the ocean, not just the protected areas. Properly managed, the panel says, the ocean economy, including fishing, can expand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, actions such as restoration of mangroves, kelp beds, and seagrasses that absorb carbon could help offset global emissions by as much as a fifth, and help hold global warming to 2.7 degrees Fahrenheit (1.5 degree Celsius), the leaders say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We have acted as if we had to choose between protecting the ocean or using it,” says &lt;a href=&quot;http://gordon.science.oregonstate.edu/lubchenco/&quot;&gt;Jane Lubchenco&lt;/a&gt;, who headed the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration in the Obama Administration and co-chaired the High Level Panel’s experts committee. “That’s a false choice. We are discovering smarter ways to use the ocean without using it up. The secret lies in protecting the health of ocean ecosystems…”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-020-03303-3&quot;&gt;says&lt;/a&gt; the solutions offered by the panel could generate 40 times more renewable energy, through development of offshore wind energy production and wave and tidal power, and lift millions of people out of poverty. The panel’s economists forecast that every $1 (75p) invested in a sustainable ocean would return $5 (£3.75) in economic, social, and environmental benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The solutions involve a range of 74 actions, some already in progress. New technology, for example, enables Ghana to track foreign fishing vessels lurking off its coast and crack down on illegal fishing. While the panel’s call for investment in sewage and waste management infrastructure to curb the flow of plastic waste into the seas is prohibitively expensive and unlikely to happen on a large scale in the coming decades, many developing nations have banned various single-use plastic products and others are deploying catchment systems on major rivers in Thailand, Vietnam, and Indonesia to capture plastic waste before it is disgorged into the seas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ambitious goals are hard to achieve&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the approach sounds to some like just another blue ribbon exercise in futility, the leaders say the time for small steps has passed. The ocean, which covers 70 percent of the globe and produces more than half the oxygen on Earth, has reached such a dire point of decline that more drastic action is needed. The world’s decades-long inability to rebuild dwindling fish stocks to feed a growing world population offers a timeline that strikingly illustrates the point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fishing reached peak catch in the mid-1990s, marking the beginning of a long decline. Canadian Premier &lt;a href=&quot;https://pm.gc.ca/en/prime-minister-justin-trudeau&quot;&gt;Justin Trudeau&lt;/a&gt; was wrapping up his undergraduate days at McGill University in Montreal. Now, more than half his life later, 82 percent of the world’s fish stocks are considered overfished and new research shows that just 27 percent of Canada’s are considered healthy. (Last year, Canada strengthened its fisheries law, making the rebuilding of fish stocks mandatory.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UN’s Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change warned in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ipcc.ch/2019/09/25/srocc-press-release/&quot;&gt;special 2019 report&lt;/a&gt; on fragile ocean health that without action, fish could decrease by 25 percent by 2100. Only Norway and the United States have managed to rebuild fish stocks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“No way is applying more effort to fishing going to get us more fish,” says &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nationalgeographic.org/media/enric-sala-pristine-seas-oceans/#:~:text=Enric%20Sala%20is%20committed%20to,video%20to%20show%20the%20world.&quot;&gt;Enric Sala&lt;/a&gt;, marine scientist and National Geographic Explorer-in-Residence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Likewise, setting aside small slivers of ocean for protection—just seven percent of the seas are designated marine protected areas—will not restore ocean health. Even 30 percent is not considered enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The goal is not to just protect a small fraction of the ocean and trash the rest, so to speak, but to be ambitious in saying 100 percent of our ocean needs to be managed so it’s not deteriorating any further,” Worm says. “And, a lot needs to be rebuilt and recovered and restored. That’s the real question here.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 18:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>hassanahmad</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.nationalgeographic.co.uk/environment-and-conservation/2020/12/in-rare-show-of-solidarity-14-key-nations-commit-to-protect</og:url>
<og:title>In rare show of solidarity, 14 key nations commit to protect oceans</og:title>
<og:image>https://static.nationalgeographic.co.uk/files/styles/image_3200/public/003_mm7895_091219_06443-300-dpi.jpg?w=1600&amp;h=1063</og:image>
<og:description>The world’s most far-reaching pact to protect and sustain ocean health offers hope that our seas’ dire problems might be solved.</og:description>
<dc:language>en-gb</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nationalgeographic.co.uk/environment-and-conservation/2020/12/in-rare-show-of-solidarity-14-key-nations-commit-to-protect</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Gitter now speaks Matrix</title>
<link>https://matrix.org/blog/2020/12/07/gitter-now-speaks-matrix</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://matrix.org/blog/2020/12/07/gitter-now-speaks-matrix</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Hi all,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s been just over 2 months since we revealed that &lt;a href=&quot;https://matrix.org/blog/2020/09/30/welcoming-gitter-to-matrix&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Gitter was going to join Matrix&lt;/a&gt; - and we are incredibly proud to announce that Gitter has officially turned on true native Matrix connectivity: &lt;strong&gt;all public Gitter rooms are now available natively via Matrix, and all Gitter users now natively exist on Matrix.&lt;/strong&gt; So, if you wanted to join the official Scala language support room at &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitter.im/scala/scala&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;https://gitter.im/scala/scala&lt;/a&gt; from Matrix, just head over to &lt;a href=&quot;https://matrix.to/#/#scala_scala:gitter.im&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;#scala_scala:gitter.im&lt;/a&gt; and *boom*, you’re in!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means Gitter is now running a Matrix homeserver at gitter.im which exposes all the active public rooms - so if you go to the the room directory in Element (for instance) and select gitter.im as a homeserver, you can jump straight in:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://matrix.org/blog/img/2020-12-07-gitter-roomdir.png&quot; alt=&quot;Gitter room directory&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you’re in, you can chat back and forth transparently between users on the Gitter side and the Matrix side, and you no longer have the ugly “Matrixbot” user faking the messages back and forth - these are ‘real’ users talking directly to one another, and every public msg in every public room is now automatically exposed into Matrix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://matrix.org/blog/img/2020-12-07-gitter-matrix.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Gitter and Matrix going native!&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, suddenly all the developer communities previously living only in Gitter (&lt;a href=&quot;https://gitter.im/scala&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Scala&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitter.im/nodejs/home&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Node&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitter.im/scala&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Webpack&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitter.im/angular&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Angular&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitter.im/rails&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Rails&lt;/a&gt; and thousands of others) are now available to anyone anywhere on Matrix - alongside communities bridged from Freenode and Slack; the native Matrix communities for Mozilla, KDE, GNOME communities etc. We’re hopeful that glueing everything together via Matrix will usher in a new age of open and defragmented dev collaboration, a bit like we used to have on IRC, back in the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is also great news for mobile Gitter users - as the original mobile Gitter clients have been in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/gitlab-org/gitter/webapp/-/issues/2281&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;holding pattern for over a year&lt;/a&gt;, and native Matrix support for Gitter means they are now officially deprecated in favour of Element (or indeed any other mobile Matrix client).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-features-are-ready&quot;&gt;What features are ready?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, this is the first cut of native Matrix support in Gitter: much of the time since Gitter joined Element has been spent migrating stuff over from Gitlab to Element, and it’s only really been a month of work so far in hooking up Matrix. As a result: all the important features work, but there’s also stuff that’s yet to land:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Features ready today:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Ability to join rooms from Matrix via #org_repo:gitter.im&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bridging Edits, Replies (mapped to Threads on Gitter), Deletes, File transfer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bridging Markdown &amp;amp; Emoji&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;What remains:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Ability to send/receive Direct Messages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to plumb existing Matrix rooms into Gitter natively&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to view past Gitter history from Matrix. This is planned thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/matrix-org/matrix-doc/pull/2716&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;https://github.com/matrix-org/matrix-doc/pull/2716&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Synchronising the full Gitter membership list to Matrix. Currently the membership syncs incrementally as people speak&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turning off the old Gitter bridge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bridging emotes (/me support) (almost landed!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bridging read receipts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Synchronising room avatars&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bridge LaTeX&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stuff we’re not planning to support:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Ability to join arbitrary rooms on Matrix from Gitter. This could consume huge resources on Gitter, and we’re not in a rush to mirror all of Matrix into Gitter. This will get addressed when Gitter merges with Element into a pure Matrix client.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bridging Reactions. Gitter doesn’t have these natively today, and rather than adding them to Gitter, we’d rather work on merging Gitter &amp;amp; Element together.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;For more details, we strongly recommend checking out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/groups/gitterHQ/-/epics/10&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;native Matrix epic on Gitlab&lt;/a&gt; for the unvarnished truth straight from the coal-face!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-do-you-make-an-existing-chat-system-talk-matrix&quot;&gt;How do you make an existing chat system talk Matrix?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of the work which has gone into this - Gitter has been an excellent case study of how you can easily plug an existing large established chat system into Matrix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At high level, the core work needed was as simple as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Add ‘virtual users’, so remote Matrix users can be modelled and represented in Gitter correctly: &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/gitterHQ/webapp/-/merge_requests/2027/diffs&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;https://gitlab.com/gitterHQ/webapp/-/merge_requests/2027/diffs&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;This can be accomplished by simply adding a &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;virtualUser&lt;/code&gt; property to your chat message/post/tweet schema which holds the mxid, displayName, and avatar as an alternative to your &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;author&lt;/code&gt; field. Then display the &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;virtualUser&lt;/code&gt; whenever available over the &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;author&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add an application service to Gitter to bridge traffic in &amp;amp; out of Matrix: &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/gitterHQ/webapp/-/merge_requests/2041/diffs&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;https://gitlab.com/gitterHQ/webapp/-/merge_requests/2041/diffs&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;This &quot;application service&quot; comes pre-packaged for you in many cases, so for example you can simply drop in a library like &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/matrix-org/matrix-appservice-bridge&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;matrix-appservice-bridge&lt;/a&gt; in a Node.js application, and all of the Matrix talking complexity is handled for you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Polish it!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;In practice, Eric (lead Gitter dev) laid out the waypoints of the full journey:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;First big step was to add the concept of virtual users to Gitter. We could also have created a new Gitter user for every new matrix ID that appears, but tagging them as virtual users is a bit cleaner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Figuring out how to balance the Matrix traffic coming into/out of Gitter.
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Spreading the inbound load comes for free via our existing load-balancer setup (ELB) where we already have 8 webapp servers running the various services of gitter.im. We just run the Matrix bridge on those servers alongside each web and api process, and then the load-balancer’s &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;matrix.gitter.im&lt;/code&gt; spreads out to the servers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Events from Matrix then hit the load balancer and reach one of the servers (no duplication when processing events).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If something on Gitter happens, the action occurs on one server and we just propagate it over to Matrix (no duplication or locking needed).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We have realtime websockets and Faye subscriptions already in the app which are backed by Mongoose database hooks whenever something changes. We just tapped into the same thing to be able to bridge across new information to Matrix as we receive it on Gitter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hooking up the official Matrix bridging &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/matrix-org/matrix-appservice-bridge&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;matrix-appservice-bridge&lt;/a&gt; library to use Gitter’s existing MongoDB for storage instead of nedb.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Figuring out how to namespace the mxids of the gitter users:
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;It’s nice to have the mxid as human readable as possible instead of just the numerical userId in your service.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;But if people can change their username in your service, you can’t change your mxid on Matrix. In the future, we’ll have portable accounts in Matrix to support this (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/matrix-org/matrix-doc/pull/2787&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;MSC2787&lt;/a&gt;) but sadly these are still vapourware at this point.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you naively just switch the user’s mxid when they rename their username, then you could end up leaking conversation history between mxids(!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;So we went with &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;@username-userid:gitter.im&lt;/code&gt; for the Matrix ID to make it a bit more human readable but also unique so any renames can happen without affecting anything.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For room aliases, we decided to change our &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;community/room&lt;/code&gt; URI syntax to underscores for the room aliases, &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;#community_room:gitter.im&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Figuring out how to bridge features correctly;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Emoji - mapping between &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;:shortcode:&lt;/code&gt; and unicode emojis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mapping between Gitter threaded conversations &amp;lt;-&amp;gt; Matrix replies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mapping between Matrix mentions and Gitter mentions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keeping users and room data in sync
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;We haven’t gotten there yet, but the data comes through the same Mongoose hook and we can update the bridged data as they change on the Gitter end.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the Matrix side of gitter.im is hosted by &lt;a href=&quot;https://element.io/matrix-services&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Element Matrix Services&lt;/a&gt; and is a plain old Synapse, talking through to Gitter via the Application Service API. An alternative architecture would be to have got Gitter directly federating with Matrix by embedding a “homeserver library” into it (e.g. embedding &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/matrix-org/dendrite&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Dendrite&lt;/a&gt;). However, given Dendrite is still beta and assumes it is storing its data itself (rather than persisting in an existing backend such as Gitter’s mongodb), we went for the simpler option to start with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s been really interesting to see how this has played out week by week in the Gitter updates in This Week in Matrix: you can literally track the progress and see how the integration came to life between &lt;a href=&quot;https://matrix.org/blog/2020/10/09/this-week-in-matrix-2020-10-09#gitter&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Oct 9&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://matrix.org/blog/2020/10/23/this-week-in-matrix-2020-10-23#gitter&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Oct 23&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://matrix.org/blog/2020/11/06/this-week-in-matrix-2020-11-06#gitter&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Nov 6&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://matrix.org/blog/2020/11/27/this-week-in-matrix-2020-11-27#gitter&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Nov 27&lt;/a&gt; and finally &lt;a href=&quot;https://matrix.org/blog/2020/12/04/this-week-in-matrix-2020-12-04#gitter&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Dec 4&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huge thanks go to Eric Eastwood, the lead dev of Gitter and mastermind behind the project - and also to Half-Shot and Christian who’ve been providing all the support and review from the Matrix bridging team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-next&quot;&gt;What’s next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First and foremost we’re going to be working through the “What remains” section of the list above: killing off the old bridge, sorting out plumbed rooms, hooking up DMs, importing old Gitter history into Matrix, etc. This should then give us an exceptionally low impedance link between Gitter &amp;amp; Matrix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, &lt;a href=&quot;https://matrix.org/blog/2020/09/30/welcoming-gitter-to-matrix&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;as per our original announcement&lt;/a&gt;, the plan is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In the medium/long term, it’s simply not going to be efficient for the combined Element/Gitter team to split our efforts maintaining two high-profile Matrix clients. Our plan is instead to merge Gitter’s features into Element (or next generations of Element) itself and then - if and only if Element has achieved parity with Gitter - we expect to upgrade the deployment on gitter.im to a Gitter-customised version of Element. The inevitable side-effect is that we’ll be adding new features to Element rather than Gitter going forwards.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, that means implementing some features in Matrix/Element to match...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Instant live room peeking (less than a second to load the webapp into a live-view of a massive room with 20K users!!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seamless onboarding thanks to using GitLab &amp;amp; GitHub for accounts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Curated hierarchical room directory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magical creation of rooms on demand for every GitLab and GitHub project ever&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GitLab/GitHub activity as a first-class citizen in a room’s side-panel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Excellent search-engine-friendly static content and archives&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;KaTeX support for Maths communities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Threads!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;...and this work is in full swing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only bits which aren’t already progressing yet are tighter GL/GH integration, and better search engine optimised static archives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the plan is to get cracking on the rest of the feature parity, then merge Gitter &amp;amp; Element together - and meanwhile continue getting the rest of the world into Matrix :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We live in exciting times: open standards-based interoperable communication is on the rise again, and we hope Gitter’s new life in Matrix is the beginning of a new age of cross-project developer collaboration, at last escaping the fragmentation we’ve suffered over the last few years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, please do give feedback via &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitter.im/matrix-org/gitter&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Gitter&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://matrix.to/#/#matrix-org_gitter:gitter.im&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Matrix&lt;/a&gt; (or &lt;a href=&quot;https://matrix.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#95f8f4e1e7fcedd5f8f4e1e7fcedbbfae7f2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;mail&lt;/a&gt;!) on the integration and where you’d like to see it go next!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for flying Matrix and Gitter,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-- The Matrix Team&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 17:18:12 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Arathorn</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://matrix.org/blog/2020/12/07/gitter-now-speaks-matrix</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Gitter now speaks Matrix! | Matrix.org</og:title>
<og:image>https://matrix.org/blog/img/2020-09-30-gitter.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://matrix.org/blog/2020/12/07/gitter-now-speaks-matrix/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Tech elites leaving San Francisco threaten Silicon Valley&amp;#039;s supremacy</title>
<link>https://www.businessinsider.com/tech-elites-leaving-san-francisco-threaten-silicon-valley-supremacy-2020-11</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.businessinsider.com/tech-elites-leaving-san-francisco-threaten-silicon-valley-supremacy-2020-11</guid>
<description>&lt;ul class=&quot;summary-list&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Some tech elites are making moves out of San Francisco, as they rethink the area's costs, political climate, safety, and more. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keith Rabois, for example, is heading to Miami, while Ben Ling tells Business Insider he's weighing Austin or Miami. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Silicon Valley, and San Francisco, have long been been the capital of America's tech economy thanks to a variety of important factors. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;But the pandemic, and the rise of remote work via Zoom, has changed things.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More departures could threaten Silicon Valley's tech dominance, but they could also herald in cheaper rents, making the area more attractive to newcomers and residents alike — and maintain the region's longer-term viability as a breeding ground for innovation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/?hprecirc-bullet&quot; data-analytics-module=&quot;summary_bullets&quot;&gt;Visit Business Insider's homepage for more stories&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;San Francisco brought Keith Rabois enormous riches. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His resumé reflects a litany of Silicon Valley's &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/keith-rabois-founders-fund-airbnb-doordash-palantir-unicorn-interview-2020-11&quot; data-analytics-module=&quot;body_link&quot;&gt;success stories&lt;/a&gt;: executive roles with LinkedIn, Square, and Khosla Ventures; investments in YouTube, Airbnb, Palantir, Eventbrite, Lyft, and dozens of others; myriad board seats and IPOs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, the venture capitalist with Founders Fund is done with the Bay Area, citing frustrations with San Francisco's high taxes, high crime rates, and liberal political culture. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rabois is heading to Miami, joining a slow-drip wave of other departures by venture capitalists and startup founders since the start of the pandemic. They include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/ben-ling-describes-how-he-got-hired-by-khosla-for-his-first-vc-job-2020-11&quot;&gt;Ben Ling&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/strong&gt; founder of Bling Capital and a former Khosla Ventures partner, who told Business Insider he's weighing a move to Miami or Austin &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The CEOs of &lt;strong&gt;Splunk, Dropbox,&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Brex&lt;/strong&gt;, who have all recently left the Bay Area, per a report from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theinformation.com/articles/tech-ceos-are-saying-goodbye-to-san-francisco&quot;&gt;The Information.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Joe Lonsdale&lt;/strong&gt;, a VC and Palantir co-founder, who's moving his investment firm to Austin &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;J.D. Ross&lt;/strong&gt;, an Opendoor co-founder and current Atomic general partner, who recently moved to Austin &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The pandemic continues to shift families' priorities, San Franciscans' perceptions of the city, and companies' long-term remote work plans, leading both tech bigwigs and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/one-third-sf-bay-area-tech-workers-remote-pay-cut-2020-5&quot; data-analytics-module=&quot;body_link&quot;&gt;worker bees&lt;/a&gt; to reconsider their San Francisco addresses.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;See more:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/coronavirus-bay-area-tech-workers-relocating-rival-regions-2020-5&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; data-qa=&quot;message_attachment_title_link&quot; data-analytics-module=&quot;body_link&quot;&gt;The remote-work boom born from the COVID-19 lockdown has prompted some tech workers to reconsider living in the Bay Area. The region's rivals see it as a growth opportunity.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While just a small slice of the tech world, these high-profile exits could encourage peers to seriously mull if they need to continue paying sky-high real estate prices and California's taxes, decisions that in aggregate threaten to reshape Silicon Valley's tech dominance. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;lazy-holder&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy-image&quot; src=&quot;data:image/svg+xml,%3Csvg%20xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2000/svg'%20viewBox='0%200%201%201'%3E%3C/svg%3E&quot; data-content-type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot; data-srcs=&quot;{&amp;quot;https://i.insider.com/5dc3457a3afd37549e543f8b&amp;quot;:{&amp;quot;contentType&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;image/jpeg&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;aspectRatioW&amp;quot;:272,&amp;quot;aspectRatioH&amp;quot;:181}}&quot; alt=&quot;Keith Rabois&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.insider.com/5dc3457a3afd37549e543f8b?width=600&amp;amp;format=jpeg&amp;amp;auto=webp&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;image-source-caption&quot;&gt; Keith Rabois has had a string of successful roles and upcoming IPOs &lt;span class=&quot;image-source headline-regular&quot; data-e2e-name=&quot;image-source&quot;&gt;Steve Jennings/Getty Images for TechCrunch&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;There are lots of people that have already moved that haven't been written about that are pretty high profile,&quot; Rabois told Business Insider, declining to name who else left. &quot;Post-COVID, I think the concentration of talent has atrophied, perhaps permanently.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;He said that pre-pandemic, San Francisco's spot at the top of the tech hierarchy outweighed his dislike for the city, but remote work scrambled that hierarchy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other techies are weighing the benefits of living in the Bay Area against drawbacks that include San Francisco's problems with homelessness, theft, and shoebox apartments, and the Bay Area's issues with congestion, taxes, and an ever-worsening fire season. Some VCs have been talking about leaving on a group text, one participant told Business Insider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eight months into the pandemic, the tide of departures is being closely watched, and the habitat choices of tech bigwigs like Rabois and Dropbox CEO Drew Houston are now at the center of a debate about Silicon Valley's future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among residents, city officials, and businesses, the big question is whether the pandemic has permanently made Silicon Valley's mix of startup-friendly features obsolete, or whether the disruptions of the virus have simply provided an opportunity for a certain class of people to make a lifestyle change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Candidly, some of those leaving have already found great wealth here in the Bay Area ecosystem, and so they have the privilege of leaving and declaring some other city 'the next big thing,'&quot; said Ron Conway, the founder of SV Angels who's been called &quot;the godfather of Silicon Valley.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conway helped architect San Francisco's tech-friendly reputation as an investor and through alliances with politicians like the late mayor Ed Lee, who passed one of Conway's pet issues, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://time.com/14335/twitter-tax-break-san-francisco/&quot; data-analytics-module=&quot;body_link&quot;&gt;temporary payroll tax break&lt;/a&gt; that let Twitter and other San Francisco-based companies off the hook for millions of dollars. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not all of Silicon Valley is packing up, of course, and some VCs are &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/loganbartlett/status/1331241810228891653?s=20&quot; data-analytics-module=&quot;body_link&quot;&gt;poking fun&lt;/a&gt; at the departure headlines on Twitter. Some of this year's exits are temporary – Bloomberg Beta's Roy Bahat briefly &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/vc-says-tech-founders-are-helping-dems-in-georgia-2020-11&quot; data-analytics-module=&quot;body_link&quot;&gt;moved his family&lt;/a&gt; to Wisconsin to help Joe Biden win the election – and the permanent exits are a win for some groups. Housing advocates say that after years of worsening tech-catalyzed income inequality, they won't miss the leavers, and lower office and housing rents could attract newcomers and entice residents to stick around.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What makes Silicon Valley so special anyway? &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Silicon Valley has been a fertile breeding ground for launching and growing tech companies in a self-perpetuating ecosystem that's survived cycles. The government kicked off the flywheel with spending on military technology in World War II and the Cold War, as historian Margaret O'Mara traces in her &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07JD1JDF9/ref=dp-kindle-redirect?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;btkr=1&quot; data-analytics-module=&quot;body_link&quot;&gt;2019 book on the history of the region&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;lazy-holder&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy-image&quot; src=&quot;data:image/svg+xml,%3Csvg%20xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2000/svg'%20viewBox='0%200%201%201'%3E%3C/svg%3E&quot; data-content-type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot; data-srcs=&quot;{&amp;quot;https://i.insider.com/597f768285754f162325e2d8&amp;quot;:{&amp;quot;contentType&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;image/jpeg&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;aspectRatioW&amp;quot;:1000,&amp;quot;aspectRatioH&amp;quot;:657}}&quot; alt=&quot;Steve Jobs and Wozniak&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.insider.com/597f768285754f162325e2d8?width=600&amp;amp;format=jpeg&amp;amp;auto=webp&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;image-source-caption&quot;&gt; Steve Jobs, John Sculley and Steve Wozniak in 1984 &lt;span class=&quot;image-source headline-regular&quot; data-e2e-name=&quot;image-source&quot;&gt;AP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buffeted by the constant flow of young talent, academic support, and government funding through Stanford University and the University of California, Berkeley, the Bay Area grew through cycles of space exploration, semiconductors, the Internet, mobile apps, and more. California's lax approach to the non-compete clauses in employment contracts — in sharp contrast to states where job-hopping is hampered by legal constraints — has led to an intellectual cross-pollination, and helped spur the rise of equity-based compensation at the heart of the startup dream, as Villanova University law professor &lt;a href=&quot;https://digitalcommons.law.umaryland.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1198&amp;amp;context=fac_pubs&quot; data-analytics-module=&quot;body_link&quot;&gt;Richard Booth has argued.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Newly-wealthy entrepreneurs who &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/the-most-successful-facebook-alumni-2015-6&quot; data-analytics-module=&quot;body_link&quot;&gt;come out of successful companies&lt;/a&gt;, hungry to start or fund the next big thing, find support from the networks of law firms, banks, marketers, and other groups that sprouted over decades to support growing companies in what O'Mara called an &quot;entrepreneurial Galapagos.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;California, particularly Northern California, consistently &lt;a href=&quot;https://nvca.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/NVCA-2020-Yearbook.pdf&quot; data-analytics-module=&quot;body_link&quot;&gt;tops the fundraising charts&lt;/a&gt;; last year, Pitchbook counted $257.7 billion in venture capital assets under management in California alone, compared with $60.2 billion in the second-biggest state, Massachusetts. The 10 largest funds closed last year were all raised by firms based in California.  Silicon Valley's advantage has only increased as institutional investors diversify out of stocks and bonds, looking to get a slice of the next big thing before it goes public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What's changed in the Bay Area&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O'Mara, the historian, has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-09-10/why-silicon-valley-has-avoided-stagnation?sref=3QUhYeaO&quot; data-analytics-module=&quot;body_link&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; that &quot;no region's glory days last forever.&quot; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bay Area's cost of living, for individuals and businesses, has crept ever higher, often pricing out those without a Big Tech salary and prohibiting startups from being able to pay enough to poach good talent, especially engineers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In its march toward tech dominance, San Francisco lost some of its counter culture and artistic heritage, with WiFi-enabled vans that whisk employees away to campuses where they can eat, do their laundry, exercise, and even get their hair cut without leaving. The monolithic culture, which skews young, white, and male, isn't ideal for some founders' creativity and general diversity of thought. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other cities have tried to woo tech dollars and founders, from Salt Lake City's &quot;Silicon Slopes&quot; to New York's &quot;Silicon Alley.&quot; In New York, coworking companies housed startups that traditionally couldn't afford pricey real estate, and like in the Bay Area, they could benefit from the existing hub of young talent and business services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As competition among VCs has increased, some started looking outside superstar cities like San Francisco, even before the pandemic. Steve Case's Rise of the Rest seed fund invests outside of New York, Silicon Valley, and Boston, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/austin-tech-scene-flourished-austin-ventures-folded-silverton-next-coast-2019-10&quot; data-analytics-module=&quot;body_link&quot;&gt;tech communities in cities like Austin&lt;/a&gt; have flourished, supported by more local investors.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;See more:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/young-vcs-are-gathering-by-the-hundreds-in-a-slack-channel-2020-11&quot; data-analytics-position=&quot;3&quot; data-analytics-module=&quot;body_link&quot;&gt;Young Gen-Z VCs are gathering by the hundreds in a Slack channel that's gone viral this week&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;One easy selling point for the non-New York City and Bay Area locales: taxes. Texas and Florida have no income tax, while California is discussing a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2020/07/30/tax-hike-on-california-millionaires-would-create-54percent-tax-rate.html&quot; data-analytics-module=&quot;body_link&quot;&gt;tax raise&lt;/a&gt; to make up funding for schools and other services hurt by the pandemic. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the pulls away, Conway said he's not counting San Francisco out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The Bay Area's challenges can be frustrating, to be sure, but there's still no place on earth like the Silicon Valley and the San Francisco Bay Area when it comes to talent, access to capital, and the tech ecosystem for startups that have created so many successful companies and founders,&quot; he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;lazy-holder&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy-image&quot; src=&quot;data:image/svg+xml,%3Csvg%20xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2000/svg'%20viewBox='0%200%201%201'%3E%3C/svg%3E&quot; data-content-type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot; data-srcs=&quot;{&amp;quot;https://i.insider.com/55ad732add08959e138b497f&amp;quot;:{&amp;quot;contentType&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;image/jpeg&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;aspectRatioW&amp;quot;:1000,&amp;quot;aspectRatioH&amp;quot;:777}}&quot; alt=&quot;Ed Lee Ron Conway Sean Parker&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.insider.com/55ad732add08959e138b497f?width=600&amp;amp;format=jpeg&amp;amp;auto=webp&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;image-source-caption&quot;&gt; Ed Lee, Ron Conway, and Sean Parker &lt;span class=&quot;image-source headline-regular&quot; data-e2e-name=&quot;image-source&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gettyimages.com/detail/news-photo/ed-lee-ron-conway-and-sean-parker-attend-the-3rd-annual-news-photo/139585631&quot; class=&quot;image-source-link&quot;&gt;Steve Jennings for Tech Fellows/Getty Images&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a Friday &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theinformation.com/articles/the-informations-411-i-left-my-startup-in-san-francisco?utm_campaign=%5Brtsu%5D+Automated+RTS&amp;amp;utm_content=1002704&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_source=cio&amp;amp;utm_term=1000266&quot; data-analytics-module=&quot;body_link&quot;&gt;podcast with The Information&lt;/a&gt;, California state senator Scott Weiner said he didn't buy the seeming tech exodus. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;It's very speculative for people to start asserting that we're going to have broad-based work from home,&quot; he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wealthy San Franciscans' exits could bring &quot;some welcome relief&quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If nothing else, the current departures may be letting some air out of the balloon, which some believe would be a good thing for San Francisco's livability and its longer-term prospects as a viable breeding ground for innovation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the start of the pandemic, city rents have dropped and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/covid-19-moving-companies-profit-tech-workers-leave-silicon-valley-2020-6&quot; data-analytics-module=&quot;body_link&quot;&gt;moving companies' businesses exploded&lt;/a&gt; as some tech companies rolled out remote work structures and others cut staff. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peter Cohen, co-director for the San Francisco housing advocacy group Council of Community Housing Organizations, said some of the exodus could counteract the wealth concentration that's kept lower-income people out of the city and squeezed residents trying to hang onto their homes. &lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&quot;The exodus of a handful of wealthy investors and executives from San Francisco as the bubble now starts to burst is not going to get much worry from affordable housing advocates,&quot; Cohen said. &quot;Moreover, if this is the telltale sign for finally leveling off the growing inequities that have been making our affordable housing and community stabilization work so much harder, it could be some welcome relief.&quot; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;lazy-holder&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy-image&quot; src=&quot;data:image/svg+xml,%3Csvg%20xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2000/svg'%20viewBox='0%200%201%201'%3E%3C/svg%3E&quot; data-content-type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot; data-srcs=&quot;{&amp;quot;https://i.insider.com/5efe1fec4dca68277b7b1014&amp;quot;:{&amp;quot;contentType&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;image/jpeg&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;aspectRatioW&amp;quot;:2000,&amp;quot;aspectRatioH&amp;quot;:1333}}&quot; alt=&quot;twitter HQ san francisco&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.insider.com/5efe1fec4dca68277b7b1014?width=600&amp;amp;format=jpeg&amp;amp;auto=webp&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;image-source-caption&quot;&gt; Twitter headquarters on April 26, 2017 in San Francisco, California. &lt;span class=&quot;image-source headline-regular&quot; data-e2e-name=&quot;image-source&quot;&gt;Justin Sullivan/Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's unclear how the departures of wealthy individuals and businesses will affect San Francisco's bottom line, and neither the mayor's office nor the city's Office of Economic and Workforce Development responded to requests for comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bay Area desertions mirror those happening on the east coast, where financiers have swapped New York City for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/10/22/nyregion/paul-singer-florida.html&quot; data-analytics-module=&quot;body_link&quot;&gt;Florida&lt;/a&gt; and other sunnier locales, seeking more space, better weather, and perhaps most critically, lower taxes. In August, New York's mayor called the wealthy leaving the city &quot;fair weather friends&quot; and said they would be replaced by newcomers. He also proposed a higher tax on wealthy residents.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;San Francisco is more exposed to tech cycles than New York, and this could be just the latest in its long history of booms and busts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Everyone either thinks San Francisco is the center of the universe or it's dead,&quot; venture capitalist Ann Miura-Ko, who's now in Austin, told tech journalist Eric Newcomer in his &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newcomer.co/p/the-center-of-the-universe-or-its&quot; data-analytics-module=&quot;body_link&quot;&gt;Wednesday newsletter.&lt;/a&gt; &quot;It's just super annoying because anyone who has been here for over one cycle knows it always comes back and it always also falls out of favor.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section data-track-content=&quot;&quot; data-post-type=&quot;post&quot; readability=&quot;6.1829652996845&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get in touch!&lt;/strong&gt; Contact Meghan Morris via encrypted messaging app Signal at +1 (646) 768-1627 using a non-work phone, &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:mmorris@businessinsider.com&quot; data-analytics-module=&quot;body_link&quot;&gt;email&lt;/a&gt;, or Twitter DM at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MeghanEMorris&quot; data-analytics-module=&quot;body_link&quot; data-analytics-post-depth=&quot;100&quot; data-uri=&quot;c5fc02d9edc4f13c4dc6de934a24cef0&quot;&gt;@MeghanEMorris&lt;/a&gt;. Contact Berber Jin via Signal at +1 (914) 318-4121 or &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:bjin@businessinsider.com&quot; data-analytics-module=&quot;body_link&quot;&gt;email&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;(PR pitches by email only, please.) You can also &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/how-to-tip-business-insider-securely-guide-signal-securedrop-2017-6&quot; data-analytics-module=&quot;body_link&quot; data-analytics-post-depth=&quot;100&quot; data-uri=&quot;d12fe1ad5ffd98515ff44a5144d50a49&quot;&gt;contact Business Insider securely via SecureDrop&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 16:31:55 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jacksonpollock</dc:creator>
<og:title>Is Silicon Valley finally dead?</og:title>
<og:description>Silicon Valley's mix of startup-friendly features made it the world's tech capital. As tech CEOs and VCs move away, the region faces difficult questions.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.businessinsider.com/tech-elites-leaving-san-francisco-threaten-silicon-valley-supremacy-2020-11</og:url>
<og:image>https://i.insider.com/5fbeccce50e71a00115577f9?width=1200&amp;format=jpeg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.businessinsider.com/tech-elites-leaving-san-francisco-threaten-silicon-valley-supremacy-2020-11</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A Modern JavaScript Tutorial</title>
<link>https://javascript.info/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://javascript.info/</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://javascript.info/&quot;&gt;https://javascript.info/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25333350&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25333350&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 467&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 176&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 15:56:03 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ivanche</dc:creator>
<og:title>The Modern JavaScript Tutorial</og:title>
<og:image>https://javascript.info/img/site_preview_en_1200x630.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://javascript.info/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>With Proton and Steam Play, many Windows games now work on Linux</title>
<link>https://www.protondb.com</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.protondb.com</guid>
<description>&lt;noscript&gt;You need to enable JavaScript to run this app.&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;root&quot; class=&quot;pre-app-start-root&quot;&gt;&lt;style&gt;&lt;![CDATA[body,html{margin:0;height:100%}.pre-app-start{margin:0;height:100%}]]&gt;&lt;/style&gt;&lt;style&gt;&lt;![CDATA[.sk-folding-cube{margin:150px auto;width:40px;height:40px;position:relative;-webkit-transform:rotateZ(45deg);transform:rotateZ(45deg)}.sk-folding-cube .sk-cube{float:left;width:50%;height:50%;position:relative;-webkit-transform:scale(1.1);-ms-transform:scale(1.1);transform:scale(1.1)}.sk-folding-cube .sk-cube:before{content:'';position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;background-color:#f50057;-webkit-animation:sk-foldCubeAngle 2.4s infinite linear both;animation:sk-foldCubeAngle 2.4s infinite linear both;-webkit-transform-origin:100% 100%;-ms-transform-origin:100% 100%;transform-origin:100% 100%}.sk-folding-cube .sk-cube2{-webkit-transform:scale(1.1) rotateZ(90deg);transform:scale(1.1) rotateZ(90deg)}.sk-folding-cube .sk-cube3{-webkit-transform:scale(1.1) rotateZ(180deg);transform:scale(1.1) rotateZ(180deg)}.sk-folding-cube .sk-cube4{-webkit-transform:scale(1.1) rotateZ(270deg);transform:scale(1.1) rotateZ(270deg)}.sk-folding-cube .sk-cube2:before{-webkit-animation-delay:.3s;animation-delay:.3s}.sk-folding-cube .sk-cube3:before{-webkit-animation-delay:.6s;animation-delay:.6s}.sk-folding-cube .sk-cube4:before{-webkit-animation-delay:.9s;animation-delay:.9s}@-webkit-keyframes sk-foldCubeAngle{0%,10%{-webkit-transform:perspective(140px) rotateX(-180deg);transform:perspective(140px) rotateX(-180deg);opacity:0}25%,75%{-webkit-transform:perspective(140px) rotateX(0);transform:perspective(140px) rotateX(0);opacity:1}100%,90%{-webkit-transform:perspective(140px) rotateY(180deg);transform:perspective(140px) rotateY(180deg);opacity:0}}@keyframes sk-foldCubeAngle{0%,10%{-webkit-transform:perspective(140px) rotateX(-180deg);transform:perspective(140px) rotateX(-180deg);opacity:0}25%,75%{-webkit-transform:perspective(140px) rotateX(0);transform:perspective(140px) rotateX(0);opacity:1}100%,90%{-webkit-transform:perspective(140px) rotateY(180deg);transform:perspective(140px) rotateY(180deg);opacity:0}}]]&gt;&lt;/style&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 15:43:35 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>OJFord</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.protondb.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>An Elderly Mathematician Hacked the Lottery for $26M</title>
<link>https://entrepreneurshandbook.co/an-elderly-mathematician-hacked-the-lottery-for-26-million-121c28faa88b</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://entrepreneurshandbook.co/an-elderly-mathematician-hacked-the-lottery-for-26-million-121c28faa88b</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;3b4e&quot; class=&quot;ij ik do il b en ki in io eq kj iq ir is kk iu iv iw kl iy iz ja km jc jd je dg el&quot;&gt;The Lottery has a well-earned mystique. It’s a mountain of cash, shrouded in impossible math, with the subtle promise of bliss and freedom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;0c6a&quot; class=&quot;ij ik do il b en im in io eq ip iq ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz ja jb jc jd je dg el&quot;&gt;In many ways, Jerry was the perfect candidate to spot a hole in the system. Despite his humble life, he had a master's in mathematics and from a young age, could solve problems that adults struggled with. Like other gifted people, answers seemingly leapt out of the fog and into his lap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;24c8&quot; class=&quot;ij ik do il b en im in io eq ip iq ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz ja jb jc jd je dg el&quot;&gt;There was also great irony in his future heist. The Selbees never drank, smoked, did drugs, or gambled. Caffeine was their only vice.&lt;/p&gt;

Author via &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.insider.com/how-jerry-marge-selbee-won-the-lottery-2019-1&quot; class=&quot;cl ii&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;Insider&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;6d29&quot; class=&quot;ij ik do il b en im in io eq ip iq ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz ja jb jc jd je dg el&quot;&gt;Jerry Selbee took an unconventional path after college. He worked in sales, factories, offices, all before growing tired of working for “the man”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;c3e4&quot; class=&quot;ij ik do il b en im in io eq ip iq ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz ja jb jc jd je dg el&quot;&gt;Having six kids and a wife to provide for, they decided to open, of all things, a convenience store in Evart, Michigan.&lt;/p&gt;

Actual grocery store. Author &lt;a href=&quot;https://highline.huffingtonpost.com/articles/en/lotto-winners/media/images/instore.jpg&quot; class=&quot;cl ii&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;pic&lt;/a&gt; highline
&lt;p id=&quot;46a8&quot; class=&quot;ij ik do il b en im in io eq ip iq ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz ja jb jc jd je dg el&quot;&gt;Multi-millions couldn’t have seemed further away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;905d&quot; class=&quot;ij ik do il b en ki in io eq kj iq ir is kk iu iv iw kl iy iz ja km jc jd je dg el&quot;&gt;For years, they sold run-of-mill goods but did better than most stores. Jerry analyzed prices from suppliers. Then, he identified margins and resold supplies to small retailers for a profit. He also had graphs and analytics on the earnings per square foot of his store. Jerry maximized everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;97fe&quot; class=&quot;ij ik do il b en im in io eq ip iq ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz ja jb jc jd je dg el&quot;&gt;They eventually bought and owned one of the only lottery machines in Evart county. People streamed in from miles away to chase the impossible dream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;54e3&quot; class=&quot;ij ik do il b en im in io eq ip iq ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz ja jb jc jd je dg el&quot;&gt;The Selbees never spent a dollar on lottery tickets. Jerry’s bond with numbers and mathematics made it an obvious decision. For fun, he studied the figures on the back of the tickets and marveled at people’s willingness to play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;852f&quot; class=&quot;ij ik do il b en ki in io eq kj iq ir is kk iu iv iw kl iy iz ja km jc jd je dg el&quot;&gt;In 2003, an unusual lottery game, Winfall, was released.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;f36b&quot; class=&quot;kw jn do cf jo kx ky ep jr kz la es ju et lb ev jy ew lc ey kc ez ld fb kg le el&quot;&gt;The premise was simple:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;li id=&quot;0649&quot; class=&quot;ij ik do il b en ki in io eq kj iq ir is kk iu iv iw kl iy iz ja km jc jd je lf lg lh el&quot;&gt;Pick six numbers between 1 and 49&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;a13a&quot; class=&quot;ij ik do il b en li in io eq lj iq ir is lk iu iv iw ll iy iz ja lm jc jd je lf lg lh el&quot;&gt;If you guessed two, three, four, or five numbers, you get a prize in increasing amounts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;9e23&quot; class=&quot;ij ik do il b en li in io eq lj iq ir is lk iu iv iw ll iy iz ja lm jc jd je lf lg lh el&quot;&gt;Guess six, you win the $2 million minimum.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p id=&quot;2fb6&quot; class=&quot;ij ik do il b en im in io eq ip iq ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz ja jb jc jd je dg el&quot;&gt;If nobody won, the lottery purse went up each week. After 6 weeks, or when the jackpot hit the $5M dollar cap, they did a “Roll Down”. A Roll Down occurs when winnings are spread downwards to lower tier winners, at 5, 4, and 3 level matches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;a240&quot; class=&quot;ij ik do il b en im in io eq ip iq ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz ja jb jc jd je dg el&quot;&gt;The State Lottery made a mistake in all this. They listed the odds of winning that was associated with each combination of numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;146e&quot; class=&quot;ij ik do il b en im in io eq ip iq ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz ja jb jc jd je dg el&quot;&gt;The math explanation could fill an article itself. But the short version, Jerry studied those winning odds, and the timing of those Roll Downs. He realized that, statistically, a single one dollar lottery ticket was worth more than one dollar in those final weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;a3b5&quot; class=&quot;ij ik do il b en ki in io eq kj iq ir is kk iu iv iw kl iy iz ja km jc jd je dg el&quot;&gt;He knew he’d need to bet big to create a justifiable margin. In his first attempt, he bought $2,000 in tickets, which was an uncomfortably large sum for a man who never gambled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;360a&quot; class=&quot;ij ik do il b en im in io eq ip iq ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz ja jb jc jd je dg el&quot;&gt;He ended up losing $50. He reckoned this was bad luck and within the margin of error and realized he needed to wager more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;110c&quot; class=&quot;ij ik do il b en im in io eq ip iq ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz ja jb jc jd je dg el&quot;&gt;Three months later, the next rolldown was announced. He buys a full $8,000 in tickets. His winnings total $15,700, leaving him a $7,700 profit. From here, things escalated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;9405&quot; class=&quot;ij ik do il b en im in io eq ip iq ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz ja jb jc jd je dg el&quot;&gt;Each week his bets soared higher and higher. Some weeks, he spent hundreds of thousands of dollars. The game required you buy the tickets in person. So when a rolldown was coming, he and his wife split up into two cars and hit countless convenience stores across the state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;e329&quot; class=&quot;ij ik do il b en im in io eq ip iq ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz ja jb jc jd je dg el&quot;&gt;The government, with its usual iceberg reaction time, didn’t notice anything strange. The Selbees continued this mission for a full decade without the state noticing. Eventually, a group of students at MIT noticed a flaw in the math too, and started buying up tickets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;76c7&quot; class=&quot;ij ik do il b en im in io eq ip iq ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz ja jb jc jd je dg el&quot;&gt;Finally, a news story broke the lid open on the scheme and the local lottery officials shut down the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;dcc5&quot; class=&quot;ij ik do il b en im in io eq ip iq ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz ja jb jc jd je dg el&quot;&gt;But at this point, Jerry had won more than $26 million dollars from the state lottery. After deducting for expenses, they took in more than $8 million in profit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;85cb&quot; class=&quot;ij ik do il b en im in io eq ip iq ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz ja jb jc jd je dg el&quot;&gt;And what makes this story even better? The couple. They were in their 70s at the end of this run and the money hasn’t changed them a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;e21a&quot; class=&quot;ij ik do il b en im in io eq ip iq ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz ja jb jc jd je dg el&quot;&gt;All they’ve done is renovate their house and pay for their 14 grandchildren's college funds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;3134&quot; class=&quot;ij ik do il b en im in io eq ip iq ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz ja jb jc jd je dg el&quot;&gt;No law was ever broken. A clever man, with a mathematical curiosity, spotted a hole and stepped through it.&lt;/p&gt;

Author via CBS
&lt;p id=&quot;1f71&quot; class=&quot;ij ik do il b en im in io eq ip iq ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz ja jb jc jd je dg el&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;lp&quot;&gt;Enjoy this? Subscribe to&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://seanjkernan.substack.com/&quot; class=&quot;cl ii&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;lp&quot;&gt;Relax and Read&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em class=&quot;lp&quot;&gt;for more.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 15:37:17 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pseudolus</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>An Elderly Mathematician Hacked the Lottery for $26 Million</og:title>
<og:description>How Jerry Selbee thrived with a simple algebraic solution.</og:description>
<og:url>https://entrepreneurshandbook.co/an-elderly-mathematician-hacked-the-lottery-for-26-million-121c28faa88b</og:url>
<og:image>https://miro.medium.com/focal/1200/632/37/11/1*NrgfgzvlDuaJqiOUAJJu-Q.jpeg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://entrepreneurshandbook.co/an-elderly-mathematician-hacked-the-lottery-for-26-million-121c28faa88b?gi=e815793e86c2</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Experts are sounding the alarm about the hidden dangers of gas stoves</title>
<link>https://qz.com/1941254/experts-are-sounding-the-alarm-about-the-dangers-of-gas-stoves/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://qz.com/1941254/experts-are-sounding-the-alarm-about-the-dangers-of-gas-stoves/</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;As a physician and epidemiologist with the US Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, T. Stephen Jones spent his career fighting major threats to public health in the US and globally, from smallpox to HIV to viral hepatitis. But it wasn’t until Jones was well into retirement that he learned about a widespread yet widely overlooked health risk in his own home in Florence, Massachusetts, and in most US households: pollution emitted by natural gas appliances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;While many Americans might think illness linked to indoor cooking and heating is a problem &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nationalgeographic.com/photography/proof/2017/07/guatemala-cook-stoves/&quot;&gt;confined to smoke-filled kitchens in the developing world&lt;/a&gt;, the natural gas-burning stoves and furnaces found in millions of US kitchens and basements can produce a range of health-damaging pollutants, including particulate matter (PM), nitrogen dioxide (NO2), carbon monoxide (CO), and formaldehyde. Over the past four decades, researchers have amassed a large body of scientific evidence linking the use of gas appliances, especially for cooking, with a higher risk of a range of respiratory problems and illnesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;Since the publication of two new reports on the subject from the nonprofit research group the &lt;a href=&quot;https://rmi.org/insight/gas-stoves-pollution-health/&quot;&gt;Rocky Mountain Institute&lt;/a&gt; (RMI) and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://coeh.ph.ucla.edu/effects-residential-gas-appliances-indoor-and-outdoor-air-quality-and-public-health-california&quot;&gt;UCLA Fielding School of Public Health&lt;/a&gt;, this past spring, the existence of these gas-fired health hazards has garnered &lt;a href=&quot;https://grist.org/energy/study-gas-powered-appliances-may-be-hazardous-for-your-health/&quot;&gt;increasing&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/energy-and-environment/2020/5/7/21247602/gas-stove-cooking-indoor-air-pollution-health-risks&quot;&gt;media&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/science/archive/2020/10/gas-stoves-are-bad-you-and-environment/616700/&quot;&gt;scrutiny&lt;/a&gt;. But less discussed has been how the Covid-19 pandemic has compounded the risks of this pollution, especially for low-income and vulnerable populations, and how key regulatory agencies have lagged decades behind the science in acting to protect them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;“There’s no question this has been a neglected issue,” said Jones, who has drawn on lessons from his long career in public health epidemiology and disease prevention in sounding the alarm throughout Massachusetts and with former CDC colleagues over the past few years. The first step, he said, is “letting people know what the risks are—particularly when they can be substantial, life-threatening risks that can kill kids.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;One of the clearest signals emerging in the scientific literature is the connection between cooking with gas and childhood asthma—a disease suffered by people of color and lower-income groups at much &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aafa.org/asthma-disparities-burden-on-minorities.aspx&quot;&gt;higher rates&lt;/a&gt; than the rest of the population. A 2013 &lt;a href=&quot;https://academic.oup.com/ije/article/42/6/1724/737113&quot;&gt;meta-analysis&lt;/a&gt; of 41 studies found that children living in homes with gas stoves had a 42% higher risk of experiencing asthma symptoms, and, over their lifetime, a 24% increase in the risk of being diagnosed with asthma. That study confirmed, in turn, what a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.osti.gov/biblio/7159180&quot;&gt;1992 meta-analysis&lt;/a&gt; found: Children exposed to higher levels of indoor NO2 (at an increment “comparable to the increase resulting from exposure to a gas stove”) had an elevated risk of respiratory illness. More recently, a 2018 &lt;a href=&quot;https://espace.library.uq.edu.au/view/UQ:727186&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; from the University of Queensland found that in Australia, where 38% of households rely on gas stoves for cooking, more than 12% of the total burden of childhood asthma was attributable to their use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;Meanwhile, troubling new findings suggest that exposure to NO2—the primary pollutant of concern from gas appliances—could compound the dangers of the novel coronavirus in communities that are already at higher risk of infection and of dying from the disease. A recent peer-reviewed &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cell.com/the-innovation/fulltext/S2666-6758(20)30050-3#%20&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; led by researchers at Emory University examined Covid-19 mortality data in more than 3,000 US counties, and found that long-term exposure to elevated NO2 was correlated with a higher risk of death from Covid-19—and that NO2 appeared to be more dangerous than particulate matter or ozone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;The hazards now have a growing chorus of scientists and public health experts insisting that better and stricter oversight of burning gas indoors—a health threat that has been hiding in plain sight for decades, they say—can no longer be ignored. “It’s fundamental and imperative,” said Jones. “We ought to get up on the rooftops and shout about it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;The cumulative evidence was enough for the venerable New England Journal of Medicine to publish an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nejm.org/doi/pdf/10.1056/NEJMp1913663?articleTools=true&quot;&gt;editorial&lt;/a&gt; in January recommending that “new gas appliances be removed from the market.” It was co-authored by Howard Frumkin, a former director of the CDC’s National Center for Environmental Health, which is responsible for investigating environmental drivers of illness and promulgating guidance about those risk factors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;Despite such calls—and despite &lt;a href=&quot;https://rmi.org/insight/gas-stoves-pollution-health&quot;&gt;compelling evidence&lt;/a&gt; that gas appliances can produce levels of air pollution inside homes that would be illegal outdoors in the US—indoor air quality remains entirely unregulated in the US today, and gas appliances largely maintain their industry-manufactured reputation as “clean.” The Environmental Protection Agency only monitors pollutants in outdoor air. And while building codes typically require natural gas furnaces and water heaters to be vented outside, many states lack requirements that natural gas cooking stoves be vented to the outdoors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;Still, recent signs suggest that some measure of regulatory action reflecting the current understanding of the health risks of gas cooking and heating devices might finally be forthcoming. At the end of September, the California Energy Commission held a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.energy.ca.gov/event/webinar/2020-09/commissioner-workshop-2022-energy-code-pre-rulemaking-advances-scientific&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;day-long workshop&lt;/a&gt; on indoor air quality and cooking to inform its triennial update to its building energy efficiency standards. The California Air Resources Board (CARB), which regulates air pollution in the state, presented evidence that gas stoves harm health, and that a statewide transition to electric appliances would result in substantial health benefits. These obscure energy code deliberations have generated an unprecedented number of &lt;a href=&quot;https://efiling.energy.ca.gov/Lists/DocketLog.aspx?docketnumber=19-BSTD-03&quot;&gt;public comments&lt;/a&gt;—testament, advocates say, to mounting concern about greenhouse gas emissions, and to growing awareness of the health impacts of residential fossil fuel use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;Last month, the 16 members of CARB unanimously adopted a resolution in support of updating building codes to improve ventilation standards and move toward electrification of appliances—making California the first state to issue official guidance addressing the health impacts of gas stoves and other appliances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;This guidance—which cited the evidence linking gas appliances with asthma and exposure to air pollution more generally with elevated Covid-19 risks—boosts the hopes of &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/missionvespa/status/1329566702380609537?s=20&quot;&gt;those advocating for the decarbonization of California’s buildings&lt;/a&gt; that the Energy Commission will require new construction in the state to be all-electric in 2022. If that happens, it would instantly transform the country’s largest market for gas appliances, in a move that could reverberate nationwide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;Until then, advocates for reform suggest they’ll keep pushing—not least because, while this long chain of evidence would be worrying under any circumstance, the Covid-19 pandemic is keeping more people inside cooking at home than ever before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;hr&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;Jones’ advocacy started with a phone call. In 2017, his wife, Adele Franks, also a retired public health physician, received a call from the local chapter of the Sierra Club, asking if she would like to help raise awareness among Massachusetts state public health officials about the health effects of gas appliances. She was too busy, so Jones took on the project instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;He started digging into the peer-reviewed literature. He called experts on air pollution and respiratory health at research universities and reached out to former colleagues at the CDC. While the topic was new to him, analyzing epidemiological studies and assessing their rigor was not. At the CDC, Jones had worked on childhood immunization and child survival programs in Latin America and Africa and spent over a decade as its lead policy expert on HIV and viral hepatitis prevention. (He and Franks are both alumni of the CDC’s Epidemic Intelligence Service, which trains “disease detectives” to investigate and respond to public health emergencies in the US and around the world.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;Jones says he was struck by the discrepancy between the firmness of the evidence and the nearly non-existent response from regulators and public health agencies. Indeed, he found the evidence so persuasive that he traveled around Massachusetts, making presentations to local boards of health in more than 70 different cities and towns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;“One of the things I would always ask them was, ‘Have you heard about this connection between cooking with a gas stove and increased asthma among children living in the household?’” Jones said. The answer he received—from health board members and from former colleagues working in medicine and public health—was almost always “No.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fact that these gas stoves contribute to elevated NO2 is indisputable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;At around this same time, Brady Seals, a researcher at the Rocky Mountain Institute (RMI), a nonprofit clean energy think tank, who co-authored its &lt;a href=&quot;https://rmi.org/insight/gas-stoves-pollution-health&quot;&gt;recent report&lt;/a&gt; summarizing decades’ worth of research on the health effects of gas stoves, was combing through the preceding 20 years’ worth of peer-reviewed studies on the subject. She pored over the EPA’s 2008 and 2016 &lt;a href=&quot;https://cfpub.epa.gov/ncea/isa/recordisplay.cfm?deid=310879&quot;&gt;Integrated Science Assessment&lt;/a&gt;s on nitrogen oxides, the latter of which concluded that short-term NO2 exposure can exacerbate asthma and cause other adverse respiratory effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;“The more I dug in and talked to experts in the field, I kept waiting to find out we were wrong,” Seals said. “It was the opposite. In every case, the evidence seems to be strengthening on NO2 and its impacts on health.” The RMI report (co-sponsored by advocacy groups Mothers Out Front, Physicians for Social Responsibility, and the Sierra Club) drew on that evidence to conclude that combustion products emitted by natural gas stoves can cause chronic respiratory illness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;“And the fact that these gas stoves contribute to elevated NO2 is indisputable,” added Seals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;Indeed, the EPA’s own analysis has found that American homes with gas stoves have much higher concentrations of NO2 than those using electric stoves—levels that would violate legal limits if measured outdoors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;Several of the studies cited in RMI’s report were led by Brett Singer, a staff scientist and leader of the Indoor Environment Group at Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory (LBNL), who has been studying indoor air pollution for two decades. Measurement studies have found higher concentrations of NO2 and other pollutants in homes that rely on gas cooking since at least the 1980s, he said in an email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;“It is still a big problem,” he said. “LBNL has done several moderately-sized measurement studies in California in the past 10 years to show that elevated pollutant concentrations are still associated with gas cooking.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;Given that more than a third of all US households rely primarily on gas for cooking, the extent of the damage to people’s health, the RMI report concluded, could be quite large.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;Seals spent over a decade working on clean cookstove programs in the developing world, where pollution from reliance on burning wood, coal, and dung for cooking kills 3.8 million people each year. But like Steve Jones, she wasn’t aware of these health risks from a fuel long touted by the natural gas industry, and embraced by the American public, as clean. “I was working on nothing but cookstoves for the past 11 years, but I didn’t really know a lot of this,” she said. “It’s humbling, in a way.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;hr&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;The links between gas appliances and asthma—and the fact that environmental regulators and consumer protection agencies have long ignored the risk—have both been on Kevin Hamilton’s radar for a while. Hamilton is a licensed respiratory therapist and leader of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://cencalasthma.org/&quot;&gt;Central California Asthma Collaborative&lt;/a&gt; (CCAC), an organization that provides direct support to residents of California’s San Joaquin Valley who suffer from asthma and advocates for policy on their behalf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;In the San Joaquin Valley, which has long had some of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://undark.org/2018/12/03/air-pollution-california/&quot;&gt;worst outdoor air pollution in the US&lt;/a&gt;, as many as 1 in 4 children &lt;a href=&quot;https://californiahealthline.org/news/dirty-air-and-disasters-sending-kids-to-the-er-for-asthma/&quot;&gt;have asthma&lt;/a&gt;. But from his years of working directly with asthmatics, Hamilton knows firsthand that their indoor air can trigger asthma, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;His organization’s community health workers regularly visit homes to look for potential asthma triggers like mold, dust, and allergens, and help homeowners find ways to reduce their exposure. (Since the Covid-19 pandemic emerged, CCAC staff have been doing “virtual” home assessments using smart phones.) One of the key items on their checklist: the presence of a gas appliance. “We note whether or not they have a gas stove or electric stove, and gas for their heating and cooling,” Hamilton said. “Some homes are pretty old, and still have wall furnaces and floor heaters. We have concerns about all those things.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;Californians’ gas consumption is much higher than the national average. In about two thirds of California’s 14 million homes, gas is the primary cooking fuel, and a similar share relies on gas for heating. (Nationwide, 58% of households &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eia.gov/consumption/residential/data/2015/hc/php/hc6.1.php&quot;&gt;rely&lt;/a&gt; on natural gas as their main space heating fuel and 56% use gas for water heating, according to the Energy Information Administration.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;The vast majority of households that the asthma collaborative serves are low-income. “Our families are all on Medicaid or underinsured,” Hamilton said. Unvented gas-burning space heaters are illegal in California, but he noted that plenty of people still use them because they can’t afford alternatives or live in sub-standard rental housing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;These gas heaters can be even more dangerous than gas cooking appliances, Singer noted, because they are used for much longer periods, and are designed to vent directly into the living space, resulting in “very high pollutant concentrations.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Especially in a home with poor ventilation, these particles can be highly concentrated with long-term health effects on people’s lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;And some people, especially renters, even use their gas ovens as supplemental heating sources in the winter, or as a primary one if their electricity gets shut off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;“These are the most vulnerable folks, and have the least resources to do anything about this,” Hamilton said. “Especially in a home with poor ventilation, these particles can be highly concentrated with long-term health effects on people’s lives.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;Yifang Zhu, a professor of environmental health sciences at UCLA’s Fielding School of Public Health, underscored that point. “Smaller spaces, with more people in them, and poor ventilation, especially in rental apartment units, all mean higher levels of pollutants,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;Zhu led a team of researchers that published &lt;a href=&quot;https://coeh.ph.ucla.edu/effects-residential-gas-appliances-indoor-and-outdoor-air-quality-and-public-health-california&quot;&gt;a report&lt;/a&gt; in April examining the impact of natural gas appliances—including furnaces and water heaters—on health and air quality in California. One of the most striking findings from their modeling: In nearly all small apartments, cooking for just one hour on a gas stove results in NO2 concentrations that would far exceed ambient air quality limits set by the EPA and CARB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;Many of the houses and apartments that the asthma collaborative’s health workers evaluate don’t have functioning range hoods. And survey data cited by Zhu shows that only about a third of Californians who do have exhaust hoods use them regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;“Our work highlights that environmental-justice communities are disproportionately impacted by these issues,” Zhu said, referring to low-income and minority communities who often have higher exposures and greater vulnerability to environmental harms. “We need to understand there’s a cumulative, compounding health impact of those environmental conditions those populations are experiencing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;Zhu’s team also calculated how much &lt;em&gt;outdoor&lt;/em&gt; concentrations of nitrogen oxides and PM2.5—microscopic, airborne particles 2.5 micrometers or less in diameter—would be reduced by eliminating natural gas appliances from California homes. They estimated that the health benefits of going all-electric—in the form of avoided deaths and chronic illness—would amount to $3.5 billion per year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;And that estimate does not include the added benefits of indoor air quality improvements. Gaining access to people’s homes to observe their cooking and heating preferences and patterns, understand the physical layout, and monitor personal exposure is both logistically and ethically challenging, given privacy concerns and funding constraints. As a result, there are comparatively fewer studies that involve direct measurements of indoor air and individuals’ exposure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;Still, Zhu noted that if the impacts of breathing indoor particulate matter, carbon monoxide, and nitrogen oxides from gas combustion were tallied up, the health benefits of avoiding that exposure would almost certainly be far larger. “We know the most serious impacts happen indoors, so we can assume most health benefits will occur from replacing those indoor polluting appliances,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The people most burdened by these impacts are those who struggle the most to pay for cleaner alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;The toll exacted by asthma alone gives a sense of the potential scale. &lt;a href=&quot;https://letsgethealthy.ca.gov/goals/healthy-beginnings/reducing-childhood-asthma/&quot;&gt;Nearly 1.5 million children&lt;/a&gt; in California suffer from asthma. A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.trackingcalifornia.org/cms/file/cost-of-childhood-environmental-health-conditions/cost-report&quot;&gt;2015 report&lt;/a&gt; by the California Environmental Health Tracking Program found that childhood asthma results in more than 72,000 emergency room visits and 1.3 million missed school days per year. It calculated that the costs of childhood asthma—both the direct costs of treatment and hospitalization, as well as indirect costs from keeping sick kids home from school—due to environmental factors alone would be $208 million. The total cost of all asthma in the state, among children and adults, is estimated to be $11 billion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;During the recent wildfires plaguing California, CARB &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/AirResources/status/1296503938091372544&quot;&gt;tweeted&lt;/a&gt; advice to stay indoors and shut windows to avoid breathing wildfire smoke. “Avoid vacuuming, frying foods or using gas-powered appliances,” the agency added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;For the millions of Californians who cook and heat with gas, however, that guidance presents an impossible choice—as does the specter of Covid-19, which has more of us worried about indoor ventilation. Several new studies suggest that people infected with SARS-CoV-2, the virus that causes Covid-19, who have higher exposure to air pollution are more likely to have severe cases of the disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;“The people most burdened by these impacts are those who struggle the most to pay for cleaner alternatives,” says Seals. “We need policymakers to target those folks, and we need better rebates for electric stoves.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;hr&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;For a long time, the blue flame coming out of a gas burner has evoked cleanliness. That was no accident, but the result of a concerted advertising campaign.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;In the late 19th century, the nascent natural gas industry began marketing their product to homeowners as a cleaner, more hygienic alternative to coal and wood. After the famous comedian Bob Hope popularized the catchphrase “now you’re cooking with gas!” on his 1930s-era radio show, the slogan became synonymous with “modern, efficient, clean.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;Compared to the wood and coal it replaced in US households, gas was, and is, undoubtedly far better for air quality and health. That’s still true for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/household-air-pollution-and-health&quot;&gt;the billions&lt;/a&gt; of people in the developing world who rely on solid fuels for cooking and heating, and are exposed to dangerous smoke every day as a result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;But the catchphrase is in need of updating, critics of such marketing argue. Compared to electric-powered appliances, gas burners are unquestionably more polluting. Induction cooktops—which use magnetic fields to heat pots quickly, rather than burning gas or using the resistance heating coils of conventional electric ranges—have been widely used in Europe for many years, and are now becoming more available in the US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;“Induction is both cleaner with fewer pollutant emissions and also the most efficient and least dangerous in terms of burns and fires,” said Brett Singer, “but cooking on induction still can produce pollutants that need to be vented.” Using a ventilation hood is essential with any cooking system, he emphasized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re not accounting for what the pollution from gas stoves is doing to health costs, so we can’t monetize those.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;Electric-powered induction cooktops may save energy and help homeowners breathe easier, but they are more expensive than conventional gas stoves. Right now, the only incentive program in California is a rebate of $100 to $750 from Sacramento’s municipal utility for homeowners who switch to an induction cooktop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;“We’re not accounting for what the pollution from gas stoves is doing to health costs, so we can’t monetize those,” Seals argued. If policymakers took those health costs into account, she added, the dollar value of all those avoided emergency room visits for asthma attacks and lost school and workdays could make wide-scale programs incentivizing adoption of induction cookers look like a bargain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;California is the birthplace of a growing movement by towns and cities to ban natural gas use in new construction. Nearly 40 cities and towns throughout the state have adopted ordinances mandating all-electric appliances in new residential buildings, with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sfgate.com/bayarea/article/San-Francisco-bans-natural-gas-in-new-buildings-15720536.php&quot;&gt;San Francisco&lt;/a&gt; among the most recent to do so. But those ordinances don’t touch the 70 million existing buildings in the US, including California’s 14 million homes—90% of which use natural gas in some form. Retrofitting those homes with electric heat pumps and water heaters and induction cooktops would be an expensive, politically-fraught undertaking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;Organizations such as the Sierra Club and the Natural Resources Defense Council are pushing for state and regional air quality management districts to put in place tighter limits on outdoor emissions from gas appliances. If that happens, it could drive up the costs of those appliances. As homeowners and landlords increasingly switch to electric alternatives for space heating and heating water, keeping the gas line to a building just to supply a stove will become too expensive to justify.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;But without targeted incentives, most homeowners and renters won’t be able to afford new heat pumps and induction cookers, and will be stuck paying for increasingly costly gas hookups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;“People are generally not aware of this issue,” said Hamilton. “Even our asthma patients who we educate about this, they just nod. They’d take a free electric range in a minute. But there’s no incentive to do that. There’s no source of funding—that’s key.” The frustration was evident in his voice when he said, “this is just not a regulated area.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;In Massachusetts, Steve Jones’ efforts helped persuade more than 100 boards of health (representing more than half of the state’s population, and including those from the three biggest cities of Boston, Worcester, and Springfield) to write to Gov. Charlie Baker to express concerns about the health impacts of natural gas consumption and infrastructure, and helped secure the adoption of an unprecedented resolution from the Massachusetts Medical Society, the nation’s oldest, recognizing that gas stoves contribute to childhood asthma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interior air pollution from gas cooking stoves may contribute to higher rates of Covid-19.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;But while these gestures might boost awareness, they haven’t precipitated any changes to the state’s building codes or official state health guidance, nor have they unlocked any resources to help lower-income households make the transition from gas to electric cooking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;Before the pandemic shut everything down, Jones would drive down I-91 to Springfield from his home near Northampton to meet with officials running the city’s Healthy Homes Program, which aims to help reduce environmental triggers of asthma in the home and provides zero-interest loans to upgrade housing for lower-income households.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;The Asthma and Allergy Foundation of America &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aafa.org/asthma-capitals-top-100-cities-ranking/&quot;&gt;ranks Springfield&lt;/a&gt; as the most challenging city in the country to live with asthma. Jones wanted to put them in touch with counterparts in Worcester, who were using Department of Housing and Urban Development funding to rehabilitate rental housing, including installing wiring to enable a switch to electric cooking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;Now those conversations are on hold, but the risks haven’t gone away, said Jones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;“Covid-19 has dramatically demonstrated the health threats of living in small, crowded housing, typically apartments,” he said. “The interior air pollution from gas cooking stoves may contribute to the higher rates of Covid-19 in Chelsea, Lynn, Worcester, and Springfield.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;hr&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;Nearly a quarter-century ago, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thelancet.com/pdfs/journals/lancet/PIIS0140-6736(96)90002-1.pdf&quot;&gt;commentary&lt;/a&gt; appeared in The Lancet, the highly respected British medical journal. “The relation between respiratory health and indoor pollution from [gas] appliances has received considerable attention during the past 25 years; both positive and negative associations have been reported,” the authors noted. “Nevertheless, as the researchers suggest, continued investigation of the role of gas appliances and NO2 in the development and aggravation of respiratory disease is clearly warranted.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;The authors were commenting on a &lt;a href=&quot;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8618483/&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; published in the same issue of The Lancet that tracked 15,000 adults in East Anglia, U.K., and found that women who cooked primarily with gas stoves had a significantly higher risk of asthma-like symptoms and reduced lung functions in tests than those who didn’t. (Intriguingly, they found no significant association among men, perhaps explained by the fact that women spent more time in the kitchen cooking, and in the home generally.) They concluded: “Although the issue of indoor gas appliances, NO2, and respiratory health is not new, this remains an extremely common, possibly increasing, exposure throughout the world. The stakes are high.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;Despite those high stakes, the issue has received scant attention from policymakers and public health authorities up to this day. The natural gas industry points to this fact as an indication that there is nothing for homeowners to worry about, and that its product is safe to burn in the home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;Audrey Casey, a spokesperson for the American Public Gas Association (APGA), a national trade group for municipally-owned gas utilities, flatly denied any link between gas cooking and asthma, despite the emerging consensus from the scientific community. “The risks to respiratory health from NO2 documented in the scientific literature are not associated with gas stoves,” Casey said in an email message. “The association between the presence of a natural gas cooking appliance along with the increases in asthma in children is not supported by data-driven investigations that control for other factors that can contribute to asthma and other respiratory issues.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;She also noted that the Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC), which oversees safety and performance standards for consumer appliances like water heaters, furnaces, and stoves, and the EPA “do not view gas ranges as a significant contributor to adverse air quality or a health hazard in their technical or public information literature, guidance, or requirements.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;While the EPA does not regulate indoor air quality, it does provide extensive information through its Indoor Air Quality program, based on its decades of analysis of the same pollutants found in outdoor air. The EPA includes NO2 on its list of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epa.gov/asthma/asthma-triggers-gain-control#nitro&quot;&gt;asthma triggers&lt;/a&gt;; “unvented combustion appliances, e.g. gas stoves” is first on its list of primary sources of NO2 indoors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;“Existing regulations—including from the CPSC—have found no health or safety risk associated with normal use of gas appliances,” the APGA’s Casey added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;Writ large, the industry’s core response to the scientific indictments laid out in the Rocky Mountain Institute and UCLA reports might be summarized this way: If gas appliances are so dangerous, why aren’t they regulated more tightly?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;But critics of the industry ask precisely the same question: Given the evidence, which has mounted for decades, why hasn’t the CPSC or the CDC taken any action to limit indoor pollution from gas appliances, or issue updated guidance to health professionals and homeowners?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;One possible reason, experts say, is that it’s not clear which US federal agency is responsible for regulating indoor air. The EPA has the authority, under the Clean Air Act, to regulate outdoor air. Should setting standards for the air we breathe indoors be under the purview of a health-focused institution like the CDC? Or should the CPSC take the lead?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;In 1985, the chair of the CPSC wrote to the EPA, requesting help in determining whether gas stoves and appliances produced dangerous levels of nitrogen dioxide, and whether it should set targets for their manufacturers. The EPA directed its Clean Air Scientific Advisory Committee, a panel of independent experts that reviews the latest science and issues recommendations on air quality standards, to address the question, which it did in a 37-page &lt;a href=&quot;https://nepis.epa.gov/Exe/ZyPDF.cgi/P1000J0G.PDF?Dockey=P1000J0G.PDF&quot;&gt;review&lt;/a&gt; on the health effects of exposure to NO2 from gas appliances. The committee characterized the evidence as “equivocal” and stopped short of recommending a standard, but recommended further investigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other than replacement of gas stoves with electric stoves, fewer methods are currently available for indoor NO2 reduction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;Thirty-five years’ worth of subsequent investigation has yielded a large body of research &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK138707/&quot;&gt;confirming&lt;/a&gt; the risks, with little corresponding action from federal regulatory guardians of health and safety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;Change might be on the horizon. In an email message, Patty Davis, the deputy director of communications and press secretary for the CPSC, said that the agency was “aware of recent studies” and “looking at approaches for reviewing this latest research and understanding how this new information could be used to potentially update recommendations for indoor exposure levels and the development of new, or update of existing voluntary standards.” She noted that CPSC has, over the years, conducted emissions testing that led to the development of voluntary standards for nitrogen oxides from gas space heaters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;The CDC did not respond to a request for a telephone interview with a staff scientist, but in an email message, Ginger Chew, a deputy associate director for science within the CDC’s National Center for Environmental Health, said that, while the agency’s current guidance for health professionals on combustion sources and ventilation in the home was “up-to-date,” agency staff were nonetheless “actively reviewing the peer-reviewed literature” on indoor air quality and gas appliances. In the same email message, Chew also noted that one of the CDC’s scientists served on a recent expert working group investigating the effects of indoor environments on childhood asthma. Interestingly, that group’s 2017 &lt;a href=&quot;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28502823/&quot;&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; noted that, while HEPA filter technology has improved in recent years to capture particles in indoor air, only one technology offers similar promise on the cooking front: “Other than replacement of gas stoves with electric stoves,” the report stated, “fewer methods are currently available for indoor NO2 reduction.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;Until there’s more robust action from these agencies, Jones argues at the bare minimum doctors should be asking patients about the presence of gas appliances in their homes. He’s not alone: In &lt;a href=&quot;https://calmatters.org/commentary/my-turn/2020/09/all-electric-building-codes-for-new-homes-would-protect-our-health-and-our-kids-health/&quot;&gt;a commentary&lt;/a&gt; published in September, one pediatrician in the Bay Area compared the risks associated with gas appliances to those posed by leaded gasoline until it was phased out in the 1980s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;“If a child with asthma is seen by a healthcare provider, the provider should ask about what kind of stove they have at home,” Jones said. “There’s absolutely enough evidence for that.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;But most parents are left to fend for themselves. Ellie Goldberg, who like Jones has worked to spread the word in Massachusetts on indoor gas pollution, agreed. As an advocate for children with chronic health conditions in the local school system in Newton, Massachusetts, she says she first became aware of the science connecting gas with asthma in the early 1980s, when she served on an asthma-focused subcommittee of the National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;“I began seeing the literature develop about combustion byproducts indoors from gas appliances,” she said, “and that’s when I saw information on gas as one of the inflammatory triggers for asthma.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;When she moved with her two young daughters, one of whom has asthma, to a home in Newton in 1986—the same year the CPSC asked the EPA for guidance on the subject—she made the switch from gas to electric. “There was no way I was going to move into a house with gas,” she said. “You do everything you can as a parent to lower the risks and exposures.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;Goldberg, of course, was lucky enough to have had options and access to information. Over three decades later, many lower-income Americans, Seals noted, simply don’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;“The idea that our homes are more polluted than outdoors, even in cities,” Seals said, “is just a staggering fact.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;hr&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article was originally published on &lt;a href=&quot;https://undark.org&quot;&gt;Undark&lt;/a&gt;. Read the &lt;a href=&quot;https://undark.org/2020/12/02/hazards-of-gas-appliances-draw-new-scrutiny/&quot;&gt;original article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cyhZ9&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jonathan Mingle is a freelance writer and a 2020 Alicia Patterson Foundation Fellow. He is the author of “Fire and Ice: Soot, Solidarity, and Survival on the Roof of the World,” about the health and climate effects of black carbon pollution, and his work has appeared in The New York Times, The Boston Globe, Slate, Quartz, Atlas Obscura, and the Los Angeles Times, among other publications.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 14:22:14 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mattgreenrocks</dc:creator>
<og:title>Why experts are sounding the alarm about the hidden dangers of gas stoves</og:title>
<og:description>Covid-19 has drawn new attention to indoor air pollution. Science has long considered gas appliances to be key culprits.</og:description>
<og:image>https://cms.qz.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/gas-stove-burner.jpg?quality=75&amp;strip=all&amp;w=1200&amp;h=630&amp;crop=1</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://qz.com/1941254/experts-are-sounding-the-alarm-about-the-dangers-of-gas-stoves/</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://qz.com/1941254/experts-are-sounding-the-alarm-about-the-dangers-of-gas-stoves/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>