<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Hacker Publishes 2TB of Data from Cayman National Bank</title>
<link>https://twitter.com/DDoSecrets/status/1195899716653010945</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://twitter.com/DDoSecrets/status/1195899716653010945</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;To make certain files easier to access, the two Athol servers were combined into a single archive. The raw Athol servers will be released next week, along with the launch of the Hunter Memorial Library which will make over 600,000 of the bank's emails searchable online.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 18:55:30 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>andruby</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mobile.twitter.com/DDoSecrets/status/1195899716653010945</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Office noise bothers some people more than others</title>
<link>https://www.bbc.com/worklife/article/20191115-office-noise-acceptable-levels-personality-type</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bbc.com/worklife/article/20191115-office-noise-acceptable-levels-personality-type</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The second idea – and the one Perham put his money on – is that the way our brains handle the information that’s important for completing certain tasks and the way they deal with background noise is somehow in conflict.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s thought that just like Amazon’s home assistant, Alexa, has to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/tjmccue/2019/04/19/alexa-is-listening-all-the-time-heres-how-to-stop-it&quot;&gt;listen in on people’s homes&lt;/a&gt; 24 hours a day in order to catch commands, our brains can’t ever switch off to what’s going on around us. Even when we’re not consciously paying attention to them, we always have our ears on the order of the sounds in the background – like a ping from mobile phone, then a cough, then a sneeze, then some laughing – just in case they start to appear in an order that means something, such as “hi”, followed by your own name. This means that when we have to focus on other sequences of information, such as a list of numbers, any kind of background noise is particularly distracting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To test if he was right, Perham &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/23412582&quot;&gt;compared how well 36 students did&lt;/a&gt; on a mental arithmetic task which required them to remember a sequence of numbers, while they were exposed to either office noise containing speech, office noise alone or silence. If the similarity between the background noise and our inner voices is important, then you would expect that students would do much worse while listening to office noise containing speech. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We found that both sound conditions produced a significantly poorer performance in mental arithmetic, but there was no real difference between the two levels of performance,” says Perham. This suggests that he was right – it’s not the speech in background noise that affects us, it’s just the fact that there is any noise at all. “The main take-home message really is that most people work best when it’s quiet, despite what they think.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 16:53:40 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>nkc420</dc:creator>
<og:title>Why office noise bothers some people more than others</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.bbc.com/worklife/article/20191115-office-noise-acceptable-levels-personality-type</og:url>
<og:description>No one likes an office whistler or pen clicker – but for some people, these noises aren’t just a nuisance, they’re a full-blown aural assault. Why?</og:description>
<og:image>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/wwfeatures/live/624_351/images/live/p0/7v/2v/p07v2vyy.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bbc.com/worklife/article/20191115-office-noise-acceptable-levels-personality-type</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The cognitive costs of air pollution</title>
<link>https://patrickcollison.com/pollution</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://patrickcollison.com/pollution</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Air pollution is a very big deal. Its adverse effects on numerous health outcomes and general mortality are &lt;a href=&quot;https://ourworldindata.org/air-pollution&quot;&gt;widely documented&lt;/a&gt;. However, our understanding of its &lt;em&gt;cognitive&lt;/em&gt; costs is more recent and those costs are almost certainly still significantly under-emphasized. For example, cognitive effects are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epa.gov/clean-air-act-overview/air-pollution-current-and-future-challenges&quot;&gt;not&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www3.epa.gov/airnow/aqi_brochure_02_14.pdf&quot;&gt;mentioned&lt;/a&gt; in most EPA materials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://data.worldbank.org/indicator/en.atm.pm25.mc.m3?most_recent_value_desc=true&quot;&gt;World Bank data&lt;/a&gt; indicate that 3.7 billion people, about half the world's population, are exposed to more than 50 µg/m³ of PM2.5 on an annual basis, 5x the unit of measure for most of the findings below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Substantial declines in short-term cognitive performance after short-term exposure to moderate (median 27.0 µg/m³) PM2.5 pollution: &quot;The results from the MMSE test showed a statistically robust decline in cognitive function after exposure to both the candle burning and outdoor commuting compared to ambient indoor conditions. The similarity in the results between the two experiments suggests that PM exposure is the cause of the short-term cognitive decline observed in both.&quot; [...] &quot;The mean average [test scores] for pre and post exposure to the candle burning were 48 ± 16 and 40 ± 17, respectively.&quot; – &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-019-44561-0&quot;&gt;Shehab &amp;amp; Pope 2019&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chess players make more mistakes on polluted days: &quot;We find that an increase of 10 µg/m³ raises the probability of making an error by 1.5 percentage points, and increases the magnitude of the errors by 9.4%. The impact of pollution is exacerbated by time pressure. When players approach the time control of games, an increase of 10 µg/m³, corresponding to about one standard deviation, increases the probability of making a meaningful error by 3.2 percentage points, and errors being 17.3% larger.&quot; – &lt;a href=&quot;http://conference.iza.org/conference_files/environ_2019/palacios_j24419.pdf&quot;&gt;Künn et al 2019&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A 3.26x (albeit with very wide CI) increase in Alzheimer's incidence for each 10 µg/m³ increase in long-term PM2.5 exposure? &quot;Short- and long-term PM2.5 exposure was associated with increased risks of stroke (short-term odds ratio 1.01 [per µg/m³ increase in PM2.5 concentrations], 95% CI 1.01-1.02; long-term 1.14, 95% CI 1.08-1.21) and mortality (short-term 1.02, 95% CI 1.01-1.04; long-term 1.15, 95% CI 1.07-1.24) of stroke. Long-term PM2.5 exposure was associated with increased risks of dementia (1.16, 95% CI 1.07-1.26), Alzheimer's disease (3.26, 95% 0.84-12.74), ASD (1.68, 95% CI 1.20-2.34), and Parkinson's disease (1.34, 95% CI 1.04-1.73).&quot; – &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/30577116&quot;&gt;Fu et al 2019&lt;/a&gt;. Similar effects are seen in &lt;a href=&quot;https://pdfs.semanticscholar.org/615f/6b7cf7e9ce6e14b1eb4f2c71fbcc271b8d13.pdf&quot;&gt;Bishop et al 2018&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;We find that a 1 µg/m³ increase in decadal PM2.5 increases the probability of a dementia diagnosis by 1.68 percentage points.&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A study of 20,000 elderly women concluded that &quot;the effect of a 10 µg/m³ increment in long-term [PM2.5 and PM10] exposure is cognitively equivalent to aging by approximately 2 years&quot;. – &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3622279/&quot;&gt;Weuve et al 2013&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;Utilizing variations in transitory and cumulative air pollution exposures for the same individuals over time in China, we provide evidence that polluted air may impede cognitive ability as people become older, especially for less educated men. Cutting annual mean concentration of particulate matter smaller than 10 µm (PM10) in China to the Environmental Protection Agency’s standard (50 µg/m³) would move people from the median to the 63rd percentile (verbal test scores) and the 58th percentile (math test scores), respectively.&quot; – &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pnas.org/content/115/37/9193&quot;&gt;Zhang et al 2018&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stock market returns are lower on polluted days. &quot;This estimate indicates that a one unit increase in PM2.5 decreases the daily percentage returns by 1.7%. Put differently, a one standard deviation increase in PM2.5 decreases the daily percentage returns by 11.9%, a substantial effect on daily NYSE returns.&quot; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nber.org/papers/w22753.pdf&quot;&gt;Hayes et al 2016&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Baseball umpires make worse decisions on polluted days. &quot;Unique characteristics of this setting combined with high-frequency data disentangle effects of multiple pollutants and identify previously under-explored acute effects. We find a 1 ppm increase in 3 hour CO causes an 11.5% increase in the propensity of umpires to make incorrect calls and a 10 µg/m³ increase in 12-hour PM2.5 causes a 2.6% increase.&quot; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.journals.uchicago.edu/doi/abs/10.1086/698728&quot;&gt;Archsmith et al 2018&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Politicians use less complex speech on polluted days. &quot;We apply textual analysis to convert over 100,000 verbal statements made by Canadian MPs from 2006 through 2011 into—among other metrics—speech-specific Flesch-Kincaid grade-level indices. This index measures the complexity of an MP’s speech by the number of years of education needed to accurately understand it. Conditioning on individual fixed effects and other controls, we show that elevated levels of airborne fine particulate matter reduce the complexity of MPs’s peeches. A high-pollution day, defined as daily average PM2.5 concentrations greater than 15 µg/m³, causes a 2.3% reduction in same-day speech quality. To put this into perspective, this is equivalent to the removal of 2.6 months of education.&quot; &lt;a href=&quot;https://muse.jhu.edu/article/721064/pdf&quot;&gt;Heyes et al 2019&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;Exposure to CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; and VOCs at levels found in conventional office buildings was associated with lower cognitive scores than those associated with levels of these compounds found in a Green building.&quot; – &lt;a href=&quot;https://dash.harvard.edu/bitstream/handle/1/27662232/4892924.pdf?sequence=1&quot;&gt;Allen et al 2016&lt;/a&gt;. The effect seems to kick in at around 1,000 ppm of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 16:33:32 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jseliger</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://patrickcollison.com/pollution</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>FedEx responds to The New York Times article from Nov. 17, 2019</title>
<link>https://about.van.fedex.com/newsroom/statement-from-frederick-w-smith-chairman-and-ceo-of-fedex-corporation/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://about.van.fedex.com/newsroom/statement-from-frederick-w-smith-chairman-and-ceo-of-fedex-corporation/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;November 17, 2019&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://about.van.fedex.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/FeClct2_E_Prf_2c_Pos_RGB.png&quot; class=&quot;thickbox&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;206&quot; height=&quot;101&quot; src=&quot;https://about.van.fedex.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/FeClct2_E_Prf_2c_Pos_RGB.png&quot; class=&quot;newsroom-article-image wp-post-image&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Statement from FedEx &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The New York Times article is a deliberate distortion of our company’s actions before and after tax reform. FedEx has paid federal income tax every year, including fiscal year 2018. Following passage of the Tax Cuts and Jobs Act (TCJA), FedEx invested billions in capital items eligible for accelerated depreciation and made large contributions to our employee pension plans. These factors have temporarily lowered our federal income tax, which was the law’s intention to help grow GDP and generate investment in the U.S. The accelerated depreciation deductions are only temporary with higher depreciation and lower taxes early in the life of a new capital asset. This is then offset by lower depreciation and higher taxes later in that asset’s life. These temporary deductions FedEx received for capital investments are minimal compared to the overall impact the company has on the economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FedEx made extensive investments in our team members and our global network to better serve our customers following passage of the TCJA. These investments included a voluntary contribution of $1.5 billion to the FedEx pension plan to ensure it remains a well-funded retirement program, more than $200 million in increased team member compensation – about two-thirds of which went to hourly team members – and more than $3 billion to significantly expand and modernize our Memphis and Indianapolis hubs through 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://about.van.fedex.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/FedEx_Tax_Facts_v8.21.19.pdf&quot;&gt;FedEx takes pride in paying its full share of taxes&lt;/a&gt; and has paid almost $10 billion in total taxes in the U.S. during the last five fiscal years, contributing to tax revenues of the U.S. government. We have supported tax increases in some cases, particularly federal diesel and gasoline taxes, to fund badly-needed infrastructure in the United States. The decrease in U.S. investment over the past year is due to the slowdown in global trade which has a significant impact on the asset-intensive industrial economy, including FedEx.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Statement from Frederick W. Smith, Chairman and CEO of FedEx Corporation &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The New York Times published a distorted and factually incorrect story on the front page of the Sunday, November 17 edition concerning FedEx and our billions of dollars of tax payments and billions of dollars of investments in the U.S. economy.  Pertinent to this outrageous distortion of the truth is the fact that unlike FedEx, the New York Times paid &lt;strong&gt;zero&lt;/strong&gt; federal income tax in 2017 on earnings of $111 million, and only $30 million in 2018 – 18% of their pretax book income.  Also in 2018 the New York Times cut their capital investments nearly in half to $57 million, which equates to a rounding error when compared to the $6 billion of capital that FedEx invested in the U.S. economy during that same year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hereby challenge A.G. Sulzberger, publisher of the New York Times and the business section editor to a public debate in Washington, DC with me and the FedEx corporate vice president of tax.  The focus of the debate should be federal tax policy and the relative societal benefits of business investments and the enormous intended benefits to the United States economy, especially lower and middle class wage earners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I look forward to promptly hearing from Mr. Sulzberger and scheduling this open event to bring further public awareness of the facts related to these important issues.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 15:55:34 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Reedx</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>FedEx responds to The New York Times article from Nov. 17, 2019</og:title>
<og:description>Statement from FedEx  The New York Times article is a deliberate distortion of our company’s actions before and after tax reform. FedEx has paid federal income tax every year, including fiscal year 2018. Following passage of the Tax Cuts and Jobs Act (TCJA), FedEx invested billions in capital items eligible for accelerated depreciation and made …</og:description>
<og:url>https://about.van.fedex.com/newsroom/statement-from-frederick-w-smith-chairman-and-ceo-of-fedex-corporation</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://about.van.fedex.com/newsroom/statement-from-frederick-w-smith-chairman-and-ceo-of-fedex-corporation/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Facebook, Google Fund Nonprofits Shaping Privacy Debate</title>
<link>https://news.bloomberglaw.com/privacy-and-data-security/facebook-google-donate-heavily-to-privacy-advocacy-groups</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.bloomberglaw.com/privacy-and-data-security/facebook-google-donate-heavily-to-privacy-advocacy-groups</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Few companies have more riding on proposed privacy legislation than Alphabet Inc.’s Google and Facebook Inc. To try to steer the bill their way, the giant advertising technology companies spend millions of dollars to lobby each year, a fact confirmed by government filings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not so well-documented is spending to support highly influential think tanks and public interest groups that are helping shape the privacy debate, ostensibly as independent observers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bloomberg Law examined seven prominent nonprofit think tanks that work on privacy issues that received a total of $1.5 million over a 18-month period ending Dec. 31, 2018. The groups included such organizations as the Center for Democracy and Technology, the Future of Privacy Forum and the Brookings Institution. The actual total is undoubtedly much higher—exact totals for contributions were difficult to pin down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tech giants have “funded scores of nonprofits, including consumer and privacy groups, and academics,” said Jeffrey Chester, executive director at the Center for Digital Democracy, a public interest group that does not accept donations from Google or Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further, he says, their influence is strong. The companies have “opposed federal privacy laws and worked to weaken existing safeguards,” Chester said. Accepting donations from these “privacy-killing companies enable them to influence decisions by nonprofits, even subtly,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such organizations—which bristle at the notion that donations may affect their views—often have great sway over legislators, journalists, and the public due largely to their collective expertise on complex issues and inside knowledge of the legislative process. But they also often push positions that favor the goals of Google and Facebook, critics say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook declined to comment for this story. Google declined to discuss their privacy stances and nonprofit contributions. Both companies, however, provided their public third-party political engagement transparency reports.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Legislation Draws Lobbyists&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pressure has been mounting on Congress to rein in companies like Google and Facebook, which report astronomical profits and have enjoyed limited oversight by federal regulators since their creation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google reported $7.1 billion in third-quarter profits while Facebook pulled in $6.1 billion, according to company filings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embedded-image&quot; readability=&quot;7.5&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://db0ip7zd23b50.cloudfront.net/dims4/default/a286faf/2147483647/resize/633x10000%3E/quality/90/?url=http%3A%2F%2Fbloomberg-bna-brightspot.s3.amazonaws.com%2F20%2F85%2F01e84caf4a5d85abc84400da993e%2Ffb-google-campus.png&quot; data-size=&quot;embedded&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;image-info-wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook and Google fund highly influential think tanks and public interest groups that are helping to shape the privacy debate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photographers: Josh Edelson/Getty Images; Michael Short/Getty Images&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;House and Senate lawmakers have privacy legislation high on their list of priorities.The current debate over what should be covered centers around whether Congress should preempt state privacy laws, like the one approved by voters in California, and whether consumers should have a right to sue tech companies for privacy flaws.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google and Facebook want a federal privacy law, as long as it doesn’t disrupt their data collection and advertising empires, critics say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Executives from both companies have testified that they want Congress to preempt states because of a potential surge in local laws—often with more privacy protections than a federal bill will garner. They do support some new consumer rights, like the ability to transfer data between companies, but that could help Facebook and Google get a larger share of user data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, Facebook and Google are seen as unlikely to back laws that strongly restrict the sale of data to third parties or affiliates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The traditional way for companies to get what they want in Washington is pretty straightforward—hire a lobbyist. Indeed, spending in those areas by Google and Facebook has rocketed upward over the past decade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google barely had a Washington, D.C., presence in its early years. Founded in 1998, it spent a little more than $1.5 million on lobbying in 2007, according to the Center for Responsive Politics. By the end of 2018, it spent nearly $22 million, its highest one-year total ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook had an even faster increase, spending about $200,000 in 2009, a total that quickly climbed to a record $12.6 million by the end of 2018.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opinion Makers Targeted&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organizations like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://cdt.org/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Center for Democracy and Technology&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which received at least $960,000 from the two companies in 2018, are often quoted in the media as unbiased third parties and influence how policy is developed in Washington as such, despite receiving the tech company funding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The group supports allowing tech giants to sell user data to third parties with limited restrictions, a position that is in line with technology companies that profit handsomely from such sales, but not so popular with consumers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The nonprofit organization received $430,000 from Google and $330,000 from Facebook in calendar year 2018, internal numbers voluntarily disclosed by the organization shows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The group in fiscal year 2018 also received at least $200,000 from the Chan Zuckerberg Initiative, a nonprofit co-run by Facebook CEO Mark Zuckerberg and his wife, Priscilla Chan. The digital advertising giants’ contributions were nearly one-sixth of its reported revenue for the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google and Facebook’s contributions go into a general operating fund that doesn’t impact what the organization produces on model privacy legislation, Michelle Richardson, director of the advocacy group’s privacy and data project, said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The center has also pushed for some consumer-friendly issues, Richardson said. It supports the creation of a national federal privacy standard with reasonable limits on data collection. It also creates new affirmative privacy rights including data correction, deletion, and portability, issues that tech companies generally support. Neither company opposes those ideas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The group was able to secure a coveted spot testifying before the Senate Judiciary Committee’s tech task force. Lawmakers have hosted Snap Inc., Match Group, and Mozilla Corp. at closed-door meetings aimed at getting staff up to speed on privacy and competition policies that are major regulatory threats facing Facebook and Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embedded-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://db0ip7zd23b50.cloudfront.net/dims4/default/b169429/2147483647/resize/633x10000%3E/quality/90/?url=http%3A%2F%2Fbloomberg-bna-brightspot.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fa4%2F6d%2F1768f62149319122c12111c2009e%2Fpayments-to-nonprofits-and-think-tanks.png&quot; data-size=&quot;embedded&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://fpf.org/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Future of Privacy Forum&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, another nonprofit, is active in the federal privacy debate, hosting events that aim to influence lawmakers to push for a bill that preempts state privacy laws.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The group told Bloomberg Law the two companies are “top corporate donors.” Future of Privacy Forum won’t say how much Facebook and Google have given, but each donated $25,000 to the nonprofit in calendar year 2018, according to spokesman Nat Wood. Both companies sit on the group’s advisory board.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its board of directors also includes Christopher Wolf, the nonprofit’s founder and board chairman. Wolf is of counsel to Hogan Lovells’ privacy and information management practice in Washington, D.C. Google is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hoganlovells.com/en/news/hogan-lovells-helps-to-secure-a-significant-right-to-be-forgotten-ruling-for-google&quot;&gt;client&lt;/a&gt; of the firm. Wolf didn’t respond to requests for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Future of Privacy Forum has pushed for a federal privacy law that would avoid conflicts with international data protection regimes, pre-empt state privacy standards, and create incentives for internal security and privacy accountability measures. These are positions are in line with what Facebook and Google want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“No individual company provides a significant percentage of our support and we also are supported by leading national foundations,” Wood, spokesman for the organization, said.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Foundation Support&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.accessnow.org/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Access Now&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an advocacy group fighting “for human rights in the digital age,” according to its website. The nonprofit aims to influence “decision makers in the halls of parliaments and corporate boardrooms, deliver digital security resources to users at risk, and mobilize global internet users to pressure the powerful.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Access Now received $100,000 from Google and $108,000 from Facebook in calendar year 2018, according to tax documents and figures provided by the nonprofit. The group has pushed for a federal standard that would allow businesses to target consumers with online ads with proper user consent. It has also pushed for increased Federal Trade Commission privacy enforcement powers, including increased fining authority. Their recommendations generally track with industry positions apart from more FTC enforcement powers and fining authority.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Access Now confirmed the donations but didn’t comment further after multiple requests.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/&quot;&gt;Electronic Frontier Foundation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; received $7,500 from Google and $25,000 from Facebook combined in calendar year 2018, Karen Gullo, senior media relations specialist at EFF, said in an email. The fiscal year 2018 totals are a big drop from previous years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The funding drop is due in part to certain programs, like Google’s policy fellows initiative, that EFF no longer relies on, Danny O’Brien, director of strategy for the organization, said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google gave the Electronic Frontier Foundation $75,000 in calendar year 2017, $15,500 in calendar year 2016, and $325,000 in calendar year 2015, according tax forms, annual reports, and interviews with the nonprofit. Facebook gave the advocacy group $25,000 in calendar year 2017, nothing in calendar year 2016, and $5,000 in calendar year 2015, the disclosures show.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Facebook’s and Google’s 2018 contributions accounted for 3 percent of EFF’s corporate donations and .002 percent of its 2018 year-end revenue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The core of the nonprofit’s donations comes “from individuals that are interested in protecting the internet, privacy, and free expression,” O’Brien said. The nonprofit never received enough money from Facebook or Google to affect its privacy messaging and the group has found itself “on the opposing side of these companies,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If Google or Facebook “money went away, we would be fine,” O’Brien said.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D.C. Think Tanks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook and Google are also making contributions to Washington, D.C., think tanks that host a wide array of Beltway power players that have focused their work on privacy and data policy—including the Brookings Institution, The Cato Institute, and the American Enterprise Institute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embedded-image&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://db0ip7zd23b50.cloudfront.net/dims4/default/5f53287/2147483647/resize/633x10000%3E/quality/90/?url=http%3A%2F%2Fbloomberg-bna-brightspot.s3.amazonaws.com%2F28%2Fd7%2F915a6868496ba561a34cef9d0db1%2Fmark-zuckerberg.png&quot; data-size=&quot;embedded&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;image-info-wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook CEO Mark Zuckerberg&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photographer: Chip Somodevilla/Getty Images&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prominent Washington, D.C., think tanks generally take more bipartisan approaches in the federal privacy debate, hosting lawmakers and government officials from both parties at various functions. Bipartisan think tanks are often less forward about their connections to the tech giants, but they benefit from healthy donations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brookings.edu/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brookings Institution&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; has taken between $450,000 to $999,997 from Facebook, Google, and from an early executive of the search engine giant, according to its annual report for fiscal year 2018 ending June 30, 2018. Brookings only discloses broad ranges for donations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook donated between $100,000-$249,999, according to the think tank’s annual report. Google donated between $250,000-$499,999. Former Google CEO Eric Schmidt donated between $100,000-$249,999 in the same time period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brookings doesn’t provide “breakdowns for individual funders beyond what is listed,” said Brennan Hoban, a spokeperson for the think tank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brookings has hosted privacy events featuring an array of privacy advocates, lawmakers, federal enforcers, and international officials. The privacy advocates, however, are sometimes drawn from the groups Google and Facebook are backing. In a July 2018 privacy event, representatives from the Center for Democracy and Technology and the Internet Association, a Facebook and Google trade group, gave their thoughts on whether there should be an online privacy law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The think tank has “strict” policies that limit influence of donors, Hoban said. “Brookings does not accept gifts from donors who seek to undermine the independence of its scholars’ research or otherwise to predetermine or influence recommendations,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Libertarian and conservative learning think-tanks also take money from Facebook and Google. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cato.org/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cato Institute&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; lists both tech giants among nine corporate sponsors. The group, however, doesn’t disclose how much each of its corporate sponsors pays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cato has been active in the privacy debate, weighing in privacy disputes central to Facebook and Google. The group, in an Aug. 2 op-ed, defended Facebook and Google’s advertising practices saying that the companies’ use of targeted advertising is “nothing new.” Cato in the op-ed pushed back on the notion that Facebook and Google see users as products, rather they see tech giants adding value to user data it collects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cato has also hosted conferences featuring Facebook and Google employees. Its 2018 annual surveillance conference invested “representatives from Facebook, Google, and Mozilla, to discuss issues of surveillance and privacy,” according to Cato’s 2018 annual report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cato doesn’t share information on corporate donors, said Corie Whalen, director of media relations at the think tank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aei.org/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;American Enterprise Institute&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a free-market think tank, also has gotten Google money, according to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fastcompany.com/90424503/facebook-google-amazon-are-ramping-up-their-secretive-influence-campaigns-in-dc&quot;&gt;press report&lt;/a&gt;, though the amount is unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AEI has been active in the federal privacy debate. The group’s in-house experts frequently appear before Congress to testify on privacy issues and writes op-eds often defending positions favorable to Facebook and Google. AEI doesn’t want to end advertising business models and has written articles in support of so-called “surveillance capitalism,” or the mass collection of consumer data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AEI didn’t respond to requests for comment.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tougher Stance Taken&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lawmakers and others in the privacy debate that are evaluating different proposals should consider big-tech funding, Emily Peterson-Cassin, project coordinator at nonprofit group Public Citizen, said in an interview. Companies will operate in “non-transparent ways” to get through legislative language they support, she said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Corporations donate to beneficial causes, but it can feel like it is more part of tech company’s advocacy “rather than a truly good-hearted way to come up with the best possible solution through the application of people willing to work for a nonprofit,” Peterson-Cassin said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The landscape of advocacy groups in Washington is complicated, and large technology companies benefit from this confusion,” Daniel Stevens, executive director for the Campaign for Accountability, said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enforcers and lawmakers “often have no idea that tech companies are ultimately behind the positions being put forth by innocuous-sounding advocacy groups.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The group, which warns of the negative impact of “shadowy nonprofit groups” on society, according to its website, declined to disclose its donors.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 15:03:06 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>seapunk</dc:creator>
<og:title>Facebook, Google Fund Nonprofits Shaping Federal Privacy Debate</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Few companies have more riding on proposed privacy legislation than Alphabet Inc.’s Google and Facebook Inc. To try to steer the bill their way, the giant advertising technology companies spend millions of dollars to lobby each year, a fact confirmed by government filings.</og:description>
<og:url>https://news.bloomberglaw.com/privacy-and-data-security/facebook-google-donate-heavily-to-privacy-advocacy-groups</og:url>
<og:image>https://db0ip7zd23b50.cloudfront.net/dims4/default/b6263bb/2147483647/legacy_thumbnail/960x369%3E/quality/90/?url=http%3A%2F%2Fbloomberg-bna-brightspot.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fa1%2F82%2F5e9d43d346b99eae115742752fa2%2Fbli-google-facebook-front-groups-2-958x369.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.bloomberglaw.com/privacy-and-data-security/facebook-google-donate-heavily-to-privacy-advocacy-groups</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Intel&amp;#039;s CIP wants to collect the “categories of websites you visit”</title>
<link>https://www.intel.com/content/www/us/en/support/topics/idsa-cip.html#CollectedData</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.intel.com/content/www/us/en/support/topics/idsa-cip.html#CollectedData</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Intel wants to empower you by providing the best computing experience. This program uses information about your computer's performance to make product improvements that may benefit you in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simply download below and accept consent—we’ll do the rest. Intel uses all reasonable efforts to safeguard your data. This software does not collect your name, email address, phone number, sensitive personal information, or physical location (except for country).
&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://downloadmirror.intel.com/27940/eng/Intel(R)%20Computing%20Improvement%20Program.exe&quot; class=&quot;btn-download&quot;&gt;Download now&lt;/a&gt;
                        &lt;!--&lt;span class=&quot;tab-right&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
                        &lt;a href=''&gt;Learn more about Intel CIP before you download &amp;rsaquo;&lt;/a&gt;--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Check out our FAQ below for more detail on how to participate, what data is collected, privacy &amp;amp; security, and how to leave the program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.intel.com/content/www/us/en/support/topics/idsa-cip.html#Participation&quot;&gt;Participation&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.intel.com/content/www/us/en/support/topics/idsa-cip.html#CollectedData&quot;&gt;Collected Data&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.intel.com/content/www/us/en/support/topics/idsa-cip.html#PrivacySecurity&quot;&gt;Privacy &amp;amp; Security&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.intel.com/content/www/us/en/support/topics/idsa-cip.html#LeavingTheProgram&quot;&gt;Leaving the Program&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Participation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;How do I participate in the Intel® Computing Improvement Program?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

When you download and install the Intel® Computing Improvement Program, click &lt;b&gt;Accept&lt;/b&gt; on the invitation to join.
&lt;/details&gt;&lt;details readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;Why should I participate?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;&lt;p&gt;Intel uses information about your computer's performance to make product improvements that may benefit you in the future. For example, if the data shows that a driver is not performing as expected, Intel uses that information for future driver updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The collected information is used to help Intel:

&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Understand how well our products perform over time

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Determine the usefulness of our products and features

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Detect issues and identify future product improvements&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/details&gt;&lt;details readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;What if I don't choose to participate?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;&lt;p&gt;System performance information is not collected or sent to Intel. As a result, performance information from your computer cannot be used to improve future products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;If I choose not to participate in the program now, can I join the program later?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yes, if the Intel® Driver &amp;amp; Support Assistant software is installed, join the program via the system tray:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Locate the system tray icons and expandable arrow menu in the bottom right of your desktop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Right click on the Intel® Driver &amp;amp; Support Assistant icon and select &quot;Intel® Computing Improvement Program&quot;.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;screen capture of tray icon&quot; src=&quot;https://www.intel.com/content/dam/support/us/en/test/idsa-cip-trayIcon.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consent GUI or download prompt will be opened to join the program.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;screen capture of consent window&quot; src=&quot;https://www.intel.com/content/dam/support/us/en/test/idsa-cip-4.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, join the program via the Control Panel:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Open the Control Panel (Windows Key + “R”, then type “control panel”, and click “OK”)
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.intel.com/content/dam/support/us/en/test/idsa-cip-1.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Click &lt;b&gt;View By&lt;/b&gt; and select &lt;b&gt;Large Icons&lt;/b&gt; or &lt;b&gt;Small Icons&lt;/b&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.intel.com/content/dam/support/us/en/test/idsa-cip-2.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Click the &lt;b&gt;Intel® Computing Improvement Program&lt;/b&gt; label.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.intel.com/content/dam/support/us/en/test/idsa-cip-3.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;If the Windows User Account Control window appears, allow application to make changes.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;In the Intel® Computing Improvement Program window, click &lt;b&gt;Accept&lt;/b&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.intel.com/content/dam/support/us/en/test/idsa-cip-4.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/details&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Collected Data&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;details readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;If I participate in the Intel® Computing Improvement Program, what data is collected and how is it used?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;&lt;p&gt;Intel wants to provide the best computing experiences. To accomplish this, we would like your permission to collect, use, and combine information to understand:

&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The categories of websites you visit, but not the URL itself 
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;How you use your computer
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;System information from your computer
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Other devices in your computing environment&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Usage information contains:

&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Software usage: for example, frequency and duration of application usage such as Intel® Driver &amp;amp; Support Assistant, but not the application content itself such as specific actions or keyboard input. 
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Feature usage: for example, how much RAM you usually use or your laptop’s average battery life. 
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Other devices in your computing environment
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Includes universal plug and play devices and devices that broadcast information to your computer on a local area network: for example, smart TV model and vendor information, and video streaming devices.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The categories of websites you visit, but not the URL itself,
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The information collected includes categorized web browsing history that shows how long and how often you visited specific categories of sites (i.e. social media, personal finance, or news). All site visits are classified into one of 30 categories. We do not collect URLs, web pages titles, or user-specific content without explicit permission from you.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Collected system information contains, but is not limited to:

&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Your device manufacturer
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;CPU model
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Memory and display configuration
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;OS version
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Software versions
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Region and language settings
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Regional location and time zone&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;If I participate in the program, is there any personal information in the data collected?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;&lt;p&gt;The information we collect:

&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Will not include any directly identifying personal information such as name, email address, IP address, or MAC address
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Will not include the URL (web address) for specific sites visited
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Will not be used to identify or contact you&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;If these types of information are requested from you, you will first be prompted for additional consent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The information we collect does include a randomly generated identifier that allows combining information from your system over time to better understand usage trends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Privacy &amp;amp; Security&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;details readability=&quot;7.3955555555556&quot;&gt;&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;How is my data shared?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;&lt;p&gt;The information collected may be shared with Intel partners who are required to keep this information confidential and limit usage in accordance with your consent. For more information see &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.intel.com/privacy&quot;&gt;intel.com/privacy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The information collected may be processed by authorized service providers who are required to keep this information confidential and limit usage in accordance with your consent. For more information see &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.intel.com/privacy&quot;&gt;intel.com/privacy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;&lt;details readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;How does Intel protect my privacy?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;&lt;p&gt;Collected data is associated with a randomly generated unique identifier (GUID) that is stored on your device. The information collected does not include any actual content you create or view, and is not used to identify you without your explicit permission. We also carefully review data elements collected to limit risks to your privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;&lt;details readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;How does Intel keep my data secure?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Intel® Computing Improvement Program utilizes reasonable organizational, technical, and administrative measures to protect the information collected against unauthorized or unlawful access, alteration, disclosure, or destruction. See the Intel’s Privacy Notice for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;How long will data be collected if I participate in the Intel® Computing Improvement Program?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

We continue to periodically monitor your system until you opt out. Periodic monitoring allows Intel to detect when your system or drivers perform poorly.
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details readability=&quot;7.603305785124&quot;&gt;&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;Where and how long is this data kept if I participate in the Intel® Computing Improvement Program?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data collected from your system is temporarily stored locally on your system before being uploaded to a secure cloud environment, which may be physically located in accordance with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.intel.com/privacy&quot;&gt;Intel’s Privacy Notice&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Intel keeps the data for a maximum of seven years. Intel takes reasonable steps to reduce the risk that any data kept for over three years can be traced to a particular computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Leaving the Program&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;If I choose to participate in the program now, can I choose to leave the program later?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

Yes, to stop participation via the Control Panel:

&lt;ol start=&quot;6&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Open the Control Panel (Windows Key + “R”, then type “control panel”, and click “OK”)
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.intel.com/content/dam/support/us/en/test/idsa-cip-1.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Click &lt;b&gt;View By&lt;/b&gt; and select &lt;b&gt;Large Icons&lt;/b&gt; or &lt;b&gt;Small Icons&lt;/b&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.intel.com/content/dam/support/us/en/test/idsa-cip-2.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Click the &lt;b&gt;Intel® Computing Improvement Program&lt;/b&gt; label.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.intel.com/content/dam/support/us/en/test/idsa-cip-3.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;If the Windows User Account Control window appears, allow application to make changes.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;In the Intel® Computing Improvement Program window, click &lt;b&gt;Decline&lt;/b&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.intel.com/content/dam/support/us/en/test/idsa-cip-5.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/details&gt;&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;How do I uninstall the Intel® Computing Improvement Program?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Open the Control Panel (Windows Key + “R”, then type “control panel” and click “OK”)
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.intel.com/content/dam/support/us/en/test/idsa-cip-1.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Open &lt;b&gt;Programs and Features&lt;/b&gt; from the Windows Control Panel by selecting &lt;b&gt;Uninstall a Program&lt;/b&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.intel.com/content/dam/support/us/en/test/idsa-cip-6.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Select &lt;b&gt;Intel® Computing Improvement Program&lt;/b&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.intel.com/content/dam/support/us/en/test/idsa-cip-7.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Click &lt;b&gt;Uninstall&lt;/b&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.intel.com/content/dam/support/us/en/test/idsa-cip-8.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;If prompted to confirm uninstall, click &lt;b&gt;Yes&lt;/b&gt;.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;If prompted to close open applications, select &lt;b&gt;Automatically close applications and attempt to restart them after setup is complete&lt;/b&gt;, and click &lt;b&gt;OK&lt;/b&gt;.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;If prompted again to close applications, click &lt;b&gt;OK&lt;/b&gt;.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Intel® Computing Improvement Program&lt;/b&gt; will now be uninstalled.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.intel.com/content/dam/support/us/en/test/idsa-cip-9.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Uninstall is now complete.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/details&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 12:47:02 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>taspeotis</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://www.intel.com/etc/designs/intel/us/en/images/printlogo.png</og:image>
<og:type>company</og:type>
<og:title>Intel® Computing Improvement Program</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.intel.com/content/www/us/en/support/topics/idsa-cip.html</og:url>
<og:description>Information about the Intel® Computing Improvement Program</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.intel.com/content/www/us/en/support/topics/idsa-cip.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Intel desktop board BIOS update end-of-life</title>
<link>https://www.vogons.org/viewtopic.php?f=46&amp;t=69184</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.vogons.org/viewtopic.php?f=46&amp;t=69184</guid>
<description>Unfortunately I expected this since last year, like the HP thing in 2017. Especially when they said they were revamping their site then, too. &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.vogons.org/images/smilies/confused.png&quot; alt=&quot;:confused:&quot; title=&quot;Confused&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;postlink-local&quot; href=&quot;https://www.vogons.org/viewtopic.php?f=5&amp;amp;t=60219&amp;amp;p=672727#p672727&quot;&gt;viewtopic.php?f=5&amp;amp;t=60219&amp;amp;p=672727#p672727&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;A lot of their older stuff was already gone before that as well. I only noticed when I was looking for additional technical notes to archive for my Intel SAI2 server board... They were pretty much gone from their site, but the archive.org link cyclone3d posted had had them. That was the same day I grabbed a local copy and then eventually mirrored it on my site.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The only other thing I archived (in late 2014) were practically everything for the Intel DG41RQ desktop board: BIOSes from the earliest to the latest, drivers for XP, Vista, and 7, docs (manuals, specs, references), and utilities, which I keep forgetting where I stored them. It's nearly 500MB for that alone; imagine grabbing most of the modern stuff from Intel's site!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Edit:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;kwyjibo wrote:&lt;/cite&gt;I noticed something similar on HP website.&lt;p&gt;A few months ago I could download several recovery images for xpe for a given ThinClient and now only the most recent image is available...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Depressing. Just depressing. &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.vogons.org/images/smilies/depressed.png&quot; alt=&quot;:depressed:&quot; title=&quot;Depressed&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Edit 2:&lt;br /&gt;Just remembered. Despite what I said in that thread I linked last year, most of the files for 2000s and 2010s boards weren't in that download.intel.com FTP archive unless it was products from the '90s and early 2000s (My SAI2 section only had PDF files and one HTML file, but I mirrored the BIOSes, drivers, and utilities they had back then, and imaged the SAI2 CD I had as well), as those were stored on another server. Safe to say those will be pretty much gone at some point.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 10:53:24 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pcdoodle</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-gb</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.vogons.org/viewtopic.php?f=46&amp;t=69184</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Tunnel Boring Machines (2018)</title>
<link>http://www.cat-bus.com/2018/01/far-from-boringmeet-the-most-interesting-tunnel-boring-machines/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.cat-bus.com/2018/01/far-from-boringmeet-the-most-interesting-tunnel-boring-machines/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Right now in Los Angeles, Elon Musk is playing in the dirt with his shiny new toy, a &lt;a onclick=&quot;javascript:pageTracker._trackPageview('/outgoing/www.businessinsider.de/elon-musk-boring-company-tunnel-hawthorne-extension-2017-8');&quot; href=&quot;http://www.businessinsider.de/elon-musk-boring-company-tunnel-hawthorne-extension-2017-8&quot;&gt;second-hand&lt;/a&gt; tunnel-boring machine (“TBM”) named “Godot”. He hopes to revolutionize car travel by building highways underground, in “going 3d”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Musk’s antics have already drawn criticism from transit-planning experts. Jarrett Walker points out that Musk’s &lt;a onclick=&quot;javascript:pageTracker._trackPageview('/outgoing/www.citylab.com/transportation/2017/12/what-elon-musk-doesnt-get-about-urban-transit/548843/?preview=YnTsRH7dNrE5UZ5y1rwhoCh2M-0');&quot; href=&quot;https://www.citylab.com/transportation/2017/12/what-elon-musk-doesnt-get-about-urban-transit/548843/?preview=YnTsRH7dNrE5UZ5y1rwhoCh2M-0&quot;&gt;ideas are inherently anti-urban and anti-transit&lt;/a&gt;. Alon Levy shows that &lt;a onclick=&quot;javascript:pageTracker._trackPageview('/outgoing/pedestrianobservations.com/2017/12/15/elon-musks-ideas-about-transportation-are-boring/');&quot; href=&quot;https://pedestrianobservations.com/2017/12/15/elon-musks-ideas-about-transportation-are-boring/&quot;&gt;the technological claims Musk makes about tunnel technology are bogus&lt;/a&gt;: Musk seems to believe that there are a lot of low-hanging fruits to improve tunneling technology, whereas in reality, the technology is already very advanced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People tend to think it’s the tunnels that are the most expensive part of underground systems like metros, but thanks to the already existing TBM technology, they often represent only a small portion of the overall cost. Sometimes as little as 10%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most expensive parts of subways are the stations. In my view, modern boring technology becomes interesting when we can use it not just for the tunnels in-between the stations, but to build the complete system, including the stations, cheaper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many tunnel building innovations have been developed by various companies to deal with real-world constraints. They give us TBMs like these:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;giant&quot;&gt;The Giant TBM&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Musk says he can build tunnels cheaper if he just makes them smaller. But in reality, it’s not small TBMs that are the future, but big ones. The cost of a TBM doesn’t get much higher as you increase its diameter. Tt is therefore cheaper to build one very large tunnel, rather than two smaller ones. So &lt;a onclick=&quot;javascript:pageTracker._trackPageview('/outgoing/en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bertha_(tunnel_boring_machine)');&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bertha_(tunnel_boring_machine)&quot;&gt;giant&lt;/a&gt;, linear tunnel building factories have been constructed, with some reaching up to &lt;a onclick=&quot;javascript:pageTracker._trackPageview('/outgoing/en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tuen_Mun_-_Chek_Lap_Kok_TBM');&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tuen_Mun_-_Chek_Lap_Kok_TBM&quot;&gt;17.6m in diameter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_496&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;31.766355140187&quot;&gt;&lt;a onclick=&quot;javascript:pageTracker._trackPageview('/downloads/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/barcelona-3-tbm.gif');&quot; href=&quot;http://www.cat-bus.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/barcelona-3-tbm.gif&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[544]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.cat-bus.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/barcelona-3-tbm.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;520&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-496&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;The two phases of tunneling: pushing forward &amp;amp; installing the tunnel lining (check out the full video &lt;a onclick=&quot;javascript:pageTracker._trackPageview('/outgoing/www.youtube.com/watch?v=dJ6BfiPVoGs');&quot; href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dJ6BfiPVoGs&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A large diameter tunnel becomes really interesting for the construction of a metro, if it is large enough to fit not only the tracks, but the station platforms inside it. This saves costs because it’s unnecessary to excavate large caverns, possibly dug from above requiring the purchase of a large amount of land.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A large diameter tunnel was used for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cat-bus.com/2017/10/barcelonas-line-9-inspiring-montreals-pink-line/&quot;&gt;Barcelona’s line 9/10 project&lt;/a&gt;, where the tunnel is so big that two tracks and two platforms can be stacked above each-other, inside a single tunnel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_495&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;a onclick=&quot;javascript:pageTracker._trackPageview('/downloads/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/barcelona-2-line-9-station.jpeg');&quot; href=&quot;http://www.cat-bus.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/barcelona-2-line-9-station.jpeg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[544]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.cat-bus.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/barcelona-2-line-9-station.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;520&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-495&quot; srcset=&quot;http://www.cat-bus.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/barcelona-2-line-9-station.jpeg 1200w, http://www.cat-bus.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/barcelona-2-line-9-station-600x524.jpeg 600w, http://www.cat-bus.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/barcelona-2-line-9-station-768x671.jpeg 768w, http://www.cat-bus.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/barcelona-2-line-9-station-1024x894.jpeg 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;&lt;a onclick=&quot;javascript:pageTracker._trackPageview('/outgoing/www.pemb.cat/ca/projectes-estrategics/construccio_linia_9_de_metro/2/');&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pemb.cat/ca/projectes-estrategics/construccio_linia_9_de_metro/2/&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These arge tunnel can also house other necessary infrastructure: siding tracks to park trains at night, ramps so trains can cross over from one level to the other, evacuation paths, power substations — all items requiring space and cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other projects used very large TBMs to build tunnels hosting six lanes of highways on two levels, plus emergency evacuation and ventilation, all inside a single tube (Madrid, Seattle). There are also &lt;a onclick=&quot;javascript:pageTracker._trackPageview('/outgoing/www.equipmentworld.com/lady-bird-is-the-1300-ton-tunnel-boring-machine-digging-dcs-13-mile-sewer-tunnel-photos-video/');&quot; href=&quot;https://www.equipmentworld.com/lady-bird-is-the-1300-ton-tunnel-boring-machine-digging-dcs-13-mile-sewer-tunnel-photos-video/&quot;&gt;water or sewer tunnels&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_545&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;25.6&quot;&gt;&lt;a onclick=&quot;javascript:pageTracker._trackPageview('/downloads/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/seattle-tunnel.jpg');&quot; href=&quot;http://www.cat-bus.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/seattle-tunnel.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[544]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.cat-bus.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/seattle-tunnel.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;520&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-545&quot; srcset=&quot;http://www.cat-bus.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/seattle-tunnel.jpg 1024w, http://www.cat-bus.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/seattle-tunnel-600x400.jpg 600w, http://www.cat-bus.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/seattle-tunnel-768x512.jpg 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;State Route 99 tunnel (&lt;a onclick=&quot;javascript:pageTracker._trackPageview('/outgoing/www.flickr.com/photos/wsdot/4907983170/in/set-72157624760624786');&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/wsdot/4907983170/in/set-72157624760624786&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One interesting project in Kuala Lumpur, called &lt;a onclick=&quot;javascript:pageTracker._trackPageview('/outgoing/en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SMART_Tunnel');&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SMART_Tunnel&quot;&gt;“SMART Tunnel”&lt;/a&gt;, combines a four lane highway tunnel with a storm drain. During major storms, the road is closed and the whole tunnel is used to carry stormwater.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a onclick=&quot;javascript:pageTracker._trackPageview('/downloads/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/smart-tunnel.png');&quot; href=&quot;http://www.cat-bus.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/smart-tunnel.png&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[544]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.cat-bus.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/smart-tunnel.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-546&quot; srcset=&quot;http://www.cat-bus.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/smart-tunnel.png 1200w, http://www.cat-bus.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/smart-tunnel-600x299.png 600w, http://www.cat-bus.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/smart-tunnel-768x382.png 768w, http://www.cat-bus.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/smart-tunnel-1024x509.png 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other projects combine rail and road in one tunnel. In Wuhan, China, &lt;a onclick=&quot;javascript:pageTracker._trackPageview('/outgoing/zh.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E4%B8%89%E9%98%B3%E8%B7%AF%E9%95%BF%E6%B1%9F%E9%9A%A7%E9%81%93');&quot; href=&quot;https://zh.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E4%B8%89%E9%98%B3%E8%B7%AF%E9%95%BF%E6%B1%9F%E9%9A%A7%E9%81%93&quot;&gt;a twin-tube tunnel under the Yangze River&lt;/a&gt;, currently under construction, combines a &lt;a onclick=&quot;javascript:pageTracker._trackPageview('/outgoing/www.tunneltalk.com/Company-News-03Sept2014-CBE-of-France-secures-Chinese-order.php');&quot; href=&quot;https://www.tunneltalk.com/Company-News-03Sept2014-CBE-of-France-secures-Chinese-order.php&quot;&gt;highway on the upper deck with a metro line on the lower one&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_547&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;26.352941176471&quot;&gt;&lt;a onclick=&quot;javascript:pageTracker._trackPageview('/downloads/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/wuhan-metro-7-tunnel.jpg');&quot; href=&quot;http://www.cat-bus.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/wuhan-metro-7-tunnel.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[544]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.cat-bus.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/wuhan-metro-7-tunnel.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-547&quot; srcset=&quot;http://www.cat-bus.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/wuhan-metro-7-tunnel.jpg 800w, http://www.cat-bus.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/wuhan-metro-7-tunnel-600x338.jpg 600w, http://www.cat-bus.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/wuhan-metro-7-tunnel-768x433.jpg 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Wuhan Metro line 7 tunnel (&lt;a onclick=&quot;javascript:pageTracker._trackPageview('/outgoing/news.cnhubei.com/xw/wuhan/201309/t2713661.shtml');&quot; href=&quot;http://news.cnhubei.com/xw/wuhan/201309/t2713661.shtml&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;vertical&quot;&gt;The Vertical TBM&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s say you’ve built your metro line using a giant TBM, and installed platforms inside the tunnels — you’ll still need to access those stations from the surface. Traditionally, you would dig some access shafts. This may be slow, labor-intensive, and complicated if there’s ground-water. But in the interesting new world of tunnel technology, there’s a TBM for that: the &lt;a onclick=&quot;javascript:pageTracker._trackPageview('/outgoing/www.herrenknecht.com/en/products/core-products/tunnelling/vertical-shaft-sinking-machine-vsm.html');&quot; href=&quot;https://www.herrenknecht.com/en/products/core-products/tunnelling/vertical-shaft-sinking-machine-vsm.html&quot;&gt;“vertical shaft sinking machine”&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_548&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;27.076923076923&quot;&gt;&lt;a onclick=&quot;javascript:pageTracker._trackPageview('/downloads/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/sinking-machine-overview.jpg');&quot; href=&quot;http://www.cat-bus.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/sinking-machine-overview.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[544]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.cat-bus.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/sinking-machine-overview.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-548&quot; srcset=&quot;http://www.cat-bus.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/sinking-machine-overview.jpg 885w, http://www.cat-bus.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/sinking-machine-overview-600x495.jpg 600w, http://www.cat-bus.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/sinking-machine-overview-768x633.jpg 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 885px) 100vw, 885px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Vertical Shaft Sinking Machine (&lt;a onclick=&quot;javascript:pageTracker._trackPageview('/outgoing/www.herrenknecht.com/en/products/core-products/tunnelling/vertical-shaft-sinking-machine-vsm.html');&quot; href=&quot;https://www.herrenknecht.com/en/products/core-products/tunnelling/vertical-shaft-sinking-machine-vsm.html&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a machine that consists of an excavator at the bottom of the tunnel that removes the earth, and machines at the top that build the tunnel lining rings that are being pushed down from above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_549&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;26.181818181818&quot;&gt;&lt;a onclick=&quot;javascript:pageTracker._trackPageview('/downloads/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/sinking-machine.gif');&quot; href=&quot;http://www.cat-bus.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/sinking-machine.gif&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[544]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.cat-bus.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/sinking-machine.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;440&quot; height=&quot;275&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-549&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;digging and adding rings (&lt;a onclick=&quot;javascript:pageTracker._trackPageview('/outgoing/youtu.be/sRNrbQ0cAHg');&quot; href=&quot;https://youtu.be/sRNrbQ0cAHg&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trick here is that rings are installed at the top of the shaft and then the whole shaft is pushed down. It leaves a lot of the complex technology at the surface. It also means you don’t end up with a big machine at the bottom, without an escape: most TBMs can’t go backwards because they’re bigger than the tunnel they’re building, so they need an opening on the other end to escape the underground (or be taken apart at the end).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the bottom, the excavator can work under water, so the shaft can have the same ground-water level as the surrounding environment, until the desired depth is reached and the a concrete seal is poured at the bottom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_550&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;26&quot;&gt;&lt;a onclick=&quot;javascript:pageTracker._trackPageview('/downloads/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/finishing-pouring-bottom.gif');&quot; href=&quot;http://www.cat-bus.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/finishing-pouring-bottom.gif&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[544]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.cat-bus.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/finishing-pouring-bottom.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;440&quot; height=&quot;279&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-550&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;pouring the bottom seal (&lt;a onclick=&quot;javascript:pageTracker._trackPageview('/outgoing/youtu.be/sRNrbQ0cAHg');&quot; href=&quot;https://youtu.be/sRNrbQ0cAHg&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this machine it would be relatively simple to build access shafts for elevators, to access our hypothetical metro line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;diagonal&quot;&gt;The Diagonal TBM&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We could now build our subway line deep underground inside giant tunnels, and vertical shafts down to provide elevator accesses. The thing is, if you want a lot of people to access your station, you need escalators, which move many more people per hour. This means we want tunnels to be neither vertical or horizontal, but built at the 30 degree angle of escalators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1997, Saint-Petersburg opened an extension of its line 5, very deep underground. But one 102m deep station, &lt;a onclick=&quot;javascript:pageTracker._trackPageview('/outgoing/en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Admiralteyskaya_(Saint_Petersburg_Metro)');&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Admiralteyskaya_(Saint_Petersburg_Metro)&quot;&gt;Admiralteyskaya&lt;/a&gt;, wasn’t opened until more than a decade later, because they couldn’t figure out how to build a connection to the surface. For all this time, trains just ran through this ghost station but didn’t stop there, since there was no connection to the surface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem was that there are a lot of museums and heritage buildings nearby and the ground is composed of a soft soil. The usual solution to freeze the ground and treat it like rock was deemed too risky, as the ground expansion from the freezing could damage the buildings (oh also, they ran out of money, and they had trouble finding a plot of land to use for the station).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, they came up with a &lt;a onclick=&quot;javascript:pageTracker._trackPageview('/outgoing/www.tunneltalk.com/TunnelTech-Aug12-Herrenknecht-technology-tackles-St-Petersburg-declining-metro-escalator.php');&quot; href=&quot;https://www.tunneltalk.com/TunnelTech-Aug12-Herrenknecht-technology-tackles-St-Petersburg-declining-metro-escalator.php&quot;&gt;tunnel boring machine that digs at an angle&lt;/a&gt;. The machine takes away soil and immediately replaces it with a tunnel, minimizing movement of the ground. This allows digging without affecting the environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_551&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;25.379310344828&quot;&gt;&lt;a onclick=&quot;javascript:pageTracker._trackPageview('/downloads/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/diagonal-tbm-HK-St-Petersburg-schematic.jpg');&quot; href=&quot;http://www.cat-bus.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/diagonal-tbm-HK-St-Petersburg-schematic.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[544]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.cat-bus.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/diagonal-tbm-HK-St-Petersburg-schematic.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-551&quot; srcset=&quot;http://www.cat-bus.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/diagonal-tbm-HK-St-Petersburg-schematic.jpg 800w, http://www.cat-bus.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/diagonal-tbm-HK-St-Petersburg-schematic-600x380.jpg 600w, http://www.cat-bus.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/diagonal-tbm-HK-St-Petersburg-schematic-768x486.jpg 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Side view of the TBM (&lt;a onclick=&quot;javascript:pageTracker._trackPageview('/outgoing/www.tunneltalk.com/TunnelTech-Aug12-Herrenknecht-technology-tackles-St-Petersburg-declining-metro-escalator.php');&quot; href=&quot;https://www.tunneltalk.com/TunnelTech-Aug12-Herrenknecht-technology-tackles-St-Petersburg-declining-metro-escalator.php&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a way, building tunnels barely more than 100m with a TBM seems crazy. Setting up a tunnel “factory” only makes sense when you have a lot of tunnel to build. To make this economical, the TBM was made as re-usable as possible. Once the TBM reaches the bottom, most of it is disassembled and moved to the next site. The only thing that stays underground is the tunnel shield, the big protective metal sheath at the front of the TBM under which the tunnel lining is assembled – because it’s wider than the tunnel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_552&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;26.514285714286&quot;&gt;&lt;a onclick=&quot;javascript:pageTracker._trackPageview('/downloads/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/diagonal-tbm-HK-St-Petersburg-Logistics.jpg');&quot; href=&quot;http://www.cat-bus.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/diagonal-tbm-HK-St-Petersburg-Logistics.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[544]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.cat-bus.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/diagonal-tbm-HK-St-Petersburg-Logistics.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-552&quot; srcset=&quot;http://www.cat-bus.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/diagonal-tbm-HK-St-Petersburg-Logistics.jpg 740w, http://www.cat-bus.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/diagonal-tbm-HK-St-Petersburg-Logistics-600x400.jpg 600w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 740px) 100vw, 740px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;View down the angled shaft (&lt;a onclick=&quot;javascript:pageTracker._trackPageview('/outgoing/www.tunneltalk.com/TunnelTech-Aug12-Herrenknecht-technology-tackles-St-Petersburg-declining-metro-escalator.php');&quot; href=&quot;https://www.tunneltalk.com/TunnelTech-Aug12-Herrenknecht-technology-tackles-St-Petersburg-declining-metro-escalator.php&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, three angled tunnels were built, at lengths between 105m and 160m allowing three new stations to open. The Admiralteyskaya station opened in 2011, about 14 years after the line itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;rectangular&quot;&gt;The Rectangular TBM&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One issue with traditional TBMs is that they build tunnels with a circular cross section. But the internal cross-section of tunnels usually needs to be rectangular; generally we want a flat bottom, walls going straight up, with some relatively constant ceiling height.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we use a circular TBM to build a tunnel, we have a bunch of wasted space on the sides. This can be especially an issue when space is at a premium, or if we want to build tunnels as close as possible to the surface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is especially true for underpasses, which have to be as close to the surface as possible and which also have a relatively small height (as little as 2.2m) but require a good amount of width (4m and more). Traditionally, these would be constructed using cut-and-cover: the road would be dug up, the tunnel placed in, and the road rebuilt on top. This can be a major disruption to the surface roads above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To deal with all of these issues, some tunnelling technology companies have started to offer a new kind of tunnel boring machine: the rectangular TBM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_553&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;25.142857142857&quot;&gt;&lt;a onclick=&quot;javascript:pageTracker._trackPageview('/downloads/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/rectangular-digger.jpg');&quot; href=&quot;http://www.cat-bus.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/rectangular-digger.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[544]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.cat-bus.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/rectangular-digger.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-553&quot; srcset=&quot;http://www.cat-bus.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/rectangular-digger.jpg 1016w, http://www.cat-bus.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/rectangular-digger-600x347.jpg 600w, http://www.cat-bus.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/rectangular-digger-768x444.jpg 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1016px) 100vw, 1016px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;the rectangular TBM (&lt;a onclick=&quot;javascript:pageTracker._trackPageview('/outgoing/www.youtube.com/watch?v=qBnF2cFizNc');&quot; href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qBnF2cFizNc&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea, &lt;a onclick=&quot;javascript:pageTracker._trackPageview('/outgoing/www.herrenknecht.com/en/innovation/research-development/machines-components/mh-box-machine.html');&quot; href=&quot;https://www.herrenknecht.com/en/innovation/research-development/machines-components/mh-box-machine.html&quot;&gt;proposed by a German company&lt;/a&gt; but already &lt;a onclick=&quot;javascript:pageTracker._trackPageview('/outgoing/tunneltalk.com/Singapore-18May2017-innovative-CREG-box-jacking-rectangular-TBM-powerful-tool-for-urban-underground.php');&quot; href=&quot;https://tunneltalk.com/Singapore-18May2017-innovative-CREG-box-jacking-rectangular-TBM-powerful-tool-for-urban-underground.php&quot;&gt;built and used by a Chinese one&lt;/a&gt;, is to have a small rectangular digger. They can be used to build short, low-depth tunnels, in space-constrained environments, while minimizing surface impacts (which may also reduce costs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_554&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;27.914893617021&quot;&gt;&lt;a onclick=&quot;javascript:pageTracker._trackPageview('/downloads/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/Herrenkencht-Rectangular-TBM-Cropped.jpeg');&quot; href=&quot;http://www.cat-bus.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/Herrenkencht-Rectangular-TBM-Cropped.jpeg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[544]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.cat-bus.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/Herrenkencht-Rectangular-TBM-Cropped.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-554&quot; srcset=&quot;http://www.cat-bus.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/Herrenkencht-Rectangular-TBM-Cropped.jpeg 960w, http://www.cat-bus.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/Herrenkencht-Rectangular-TBM-Cropped-600x300.jpeg 600w, http://www.cat-bus.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/Herrenkencht-Rectangular-TBM-Cropped-768x384.jpeg 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;A rectangular TBM digging an underpass (&lt;a onclick=&quot;javascript:pageTracker._trackPageview('/outgoing/www.herrenknecht.com/en/innovation/research-development/machines-components/mh-box-machine.html');&quot; href=&quot;https://www.herrenknecht.com/en/innovation/research-development/machines-components/mh-box-machine.html&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather than including a facility for assembling the tunnel lining (out of multiple segments) inside the TBM, complete rings are inserted at the insertion shaft, and the whole tunnel is jacked forward one segment at a time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_555&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;a onclick=&quot;javascript:pageTracker._trackPageview('/downloads/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/rectangular-tbm-small.gif');&quot; href=&quot;http://www.cat-bus.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/rectangular-tbm-small.gif&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[544]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.cat-bus.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/rectangular-tbm-small.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-555&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;&lt;a onclick=&quot;javascript:pageTracker._trackPageview('/outgoing/www.youtube.com/watch?v=qBnF2cFizNc');&quot; href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qBnF2cFizNc&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This technology was used to build a metro access at the Havelock Metro Station in Singapore. The company hopes that this technology could be used one day to build whole stations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A station built using this rectangular TBM concept could be very interesting: unlike the ‘giant’ TBMs mentioned before, this technology could allow building stations close to the surface, in much more spatially constrained environments, and allowing a passenger platforms to be side-by-side rather than stacked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When building transportation systems, constraints are usually about physics, geometry and cost, not the technology (see my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cat-bus.com/2017/12/gadgetbahn/&quot;&gt;criticism of the “Gadgetbahn”&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that we have to be careful of primarily technology-based “solutions” to transportation problems. Musk is trying to sell a quick-fix technology that in real life won’t be able to escape geometry and physics. His approach makes little sense, his understanding of cities is poor … but also, his technology is boring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, technology can provide interesting tools to advance projects anchored in the real world, and push geometric, physical, time and cost constraints to its limits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For more reading on tunnel technology, I recommend the website &lt;a onclick=&quot;javascript:pageTracker._trackPageview('/outgoing/tunneltalk.com');&quot; href=&quot;https://tunneltalk.com&quot;&gt;TunnelTalk&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a onclick=&quot;javascript:pageTracker._trackPageview('/outgoing/www.herrenknecht.com/en/products/core-products/tunnelling.html');&quot; href=&quot;https://www.herrenknecht.com/en/products/core-products/tunnelling.html&quot;&gt;Tunneling Products Page of Herrenknecht&lt;/a&gt;, which I’ve both heavily linked in this article.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;postmetadata alt&quot;&gt;&lt;small&gt;Published on Thursday, January 25th, 2018 at 09:52&lt;br /&gt;Filed under &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cat-bus.com/category/technology/&quot; rel=&quot;category tag&quot;&gt;technology&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cat-bus.com/category/tunnels/&quot; rel=&quot;category tag&quot;&gt;tunnels&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cat-bus.com/2018/01/far-from-boringmeet-the-most-interesting-tunnel-boring-machines/feed/&quot;&gt;Comments RSS&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cat-bus.com/2018/01/far-from-boringmeet-the-most-interesting-tunnel-boring-machines/trackback/&quot; rel=&quot;trackback&quot;&gt;trackback&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 03:20:16 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>luu</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.cat-bus.com/2018/01/far-from-boringmeet-the-most-interesting-tunnel-boring-machines/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: A remote browser product, open-sourced</title>
<link>https://github.com/dosycorp/browsergap.ce</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/dosycorp/browsergap.ce</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;Box-body&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content p-5&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simple remote browser isolation application&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Community Edition version of the cloud-based internet isolation solution at &lt;a href=&quot;https://browsergap.xyz&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://browsergap.xyz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What is BrowserGap and Remote Browser isolation?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BrowserGap is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Browser_isolation&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;remote browser isolation&lt;/a&gt; product. RBI means accessing the public internet through a browser that runs in the cloud, rather than through a browser that runs on your device. This helps protect you from attacks on the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This protects you from nearly all web-based hacks, such as viruses, ransomware, browser and device zero day exploits, and also helps protect you from tracking, by changing your device fingerprint and IP address.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In more detail, the browser, normally is an executable application that runs on your device (phone, laptop). In RBI, instead you connect to a thin client web application that provides an interface to a browser that runs remotely. Remotely can mean in a VPS or VPC, in a physical box, or the public cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why is RBI significant?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, if you're interested, read on for more detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It works by providing a thin client over the web that you connect your regular browser to. The thin client provides an interface to a remote browser that you interact with the browser the public internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is significant because the internet is a cesspool of attacks. Malware, ransomware, virii, tracking, exploited PDFs, ways to deliver device zero days over the web, browser zero days. All these things can lead to the security of your device and network being compromised, causing significant inconvenience, distress and loss for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BrowserGap and the RBI methodology acknowledges that not all threats can be detected and neutralized (such as by virus scanners), in order to face that reality, RBI adopts a &quot;isolation&quot; posture towards threats, effectively isolating them in the remote machine and preventing them from reaching your device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With BrowserGap, in order to render the content of a web page, the only thing we send to your device from the remote page is pixels. So no HTML, CSS, JavaScript, etc from your browsing is ever executed on your device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.disa.mil/-/media/Files/DISA/Fact-Sheets/Cloud-Based-Internet-Isolation-CBII-Fact-Sheet20190721.ashx?la=en&amp;amp;hash=5DFC2594478284991F4B005AFA41DE26AC73D84A&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Cloud-based internet isolation&lt;/a&gt; is another name for this security practice and it is an emerging industry. Symantec recently acquired a company in this space, and Menlo Security &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.menlosecurity.com/press-releases-blog/disa-cloud-based-internet-isolation-cbii-awarded-to-the-by-light-professional-it-services-llc-and-menlo-security-team&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;was awarded&lt;/a&gt; an agreement to build a CBII prototype for DISA, after a June 2018 request for RBI solutions that could eventually serve &lt;a href=&quot;https://secureview.cloudbrowser.xyz/uploads/fileajqk.kkpgdih.pdf.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;60% of DoD's&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Browser_isolation&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;~ 3 million users&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Use&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download the repository and self-host on your own machine (at home, or in a VPS, VPC or the public cloud)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;E.g on Debian&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
$ git clone https://github.com/dosycorp/browsergap.ce.git
$ &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;cd&lt;/span&gt; browsergap.ce
$ ./setup_machine.sh
$ npm &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;test&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try for free at &lt;a href=&quot;https://free.cloudbrowser.xyz&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://free.cloudbrowser.xyz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or &lt;a href=&quot;https://hk.cloudbrowser.xyz&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://hk.cloudbrowser.xyz&lt;/a&gt; (if you're in Asia-Pac this is probably faster)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you unwilling to invest more time in your security?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please eamil me at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:cris@dosyago.com&quot;&gt;cris@dosyago.com&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:cris@dosycorp.com&quot;&gt;cris@dosycorp.com&lt;/a&gt; if you want to spend more time on your security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Detailed Instructions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below is from an email I sent to a user to help them set up the first time:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre lang=&quot;txt&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;Okay, I'm not sure about the VirtualBox part, but I'm doing a fresh install from a new droplet now
and I'll list the commands I'm using 1 by 1 in order to help resolve your issue.

(btw to use nodejs v12 I usually use nvm, but I don't bother installing node 12 for root, and I will run some BG processes using sudo, which lets them use the existing node (usually 10) and I have not noticed a problem).

ssh in to droplet, get a root prompt

$ apt update &amp;amp;&amp;amp; apt upgrade

(get a weird error about Debian stretch being expired, okay, moving on)

(later found need to add 

Acquire::Check-Valid-Until &quot;false&quot;;

to /etc/apt/apt.conf, okay)

$ apt install git

$ adduser --disabled-password user

$ update-alternatives --config editor

(selected vim)

$ visudo

(added

user ALL=(ALL) NOPASSWD:ALL

)

logout as root, ssh back in as user

$ sudo apt install curl
$ curl -sL https://deb.nodesource.com/setup_10.x -o nodesource_setup.sh
$ sudo bash ./nodesource_setup.sh
$ sudo apt-get install -y nodejs
$ sudo apt install build-essential

( okay so node 10 is now installed, now I'm going to install nvm
so I can use whatever node version I want )

$ curl -sL https://raw.githubusercontent.com/creationix/nvm/v0.33.11/install.sh -o install_nvm.sh
$ bash ./install_nvm.sh
$ source $HOME/.profile
$ nvm install --lts

(alright now node v12.13.0 is installed)

$ sudo npm i -g serve nodemon pm2
$ sudo apt install psmisc htop nethogs
$ sudo apt install libcgroup1 cgroup-tools

(okay that's a basic setup, now let's clone and install the bg)

$ git clone https://github.com/dosycorp/browsergap.ce.git
$ cd browsergap.ce
$ npm i

(put some coffee on)

$ npm test

(failed &quot;change of cgroup failed&quot;)

$ ./setup_machine.sh
$ npm test

(failed same error)

(I edited the test.sh file to be
#!/bin/bash

username=$(whoami)
nodemon index.js 5002 8002 xxxcookie $username token2

(I have also updated the repo with this change now as well)
)

$ npm test

(works,

opened

http://&amp;lt;ip&amp;gt;:8002/ 

in Chrome browser and I can see the UI and it all works
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That text is also at &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/crislin2046/2fcd103234f93376c44d110d6295f32a&quot;&gt;this gist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 03:09:55 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>slowenough</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars1.githubusercontent.com/u/25386459?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>dosycorp/browsergap.ce</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/dosycorp/browsergap.ce</og:url>
<og:description>Simple Isolated Remote Browsers, Open Source. Contribute to dosycorp/browsergap.ce development by creating an account on GitHub.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/dosycorp/browsergap.ce</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Interpol plans to condemn encryption spread, citing predators</title>
<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-interpol-encryption-exclusive/exclusive-interpol-plans-to-condemn-encryption-spread-citing-predators-sources-say-idUSKBN1XR0S7</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.reuters.com/article/us-interpol-encryption-exclusive/exclusive-interpol-plans-to-condemn-encryption-spread-citing-predators-sources-say-idUSKBN1XR0S7</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;SAN FRANCISCO (Reuters) - The international police organization Interpol plans to condemn the spread of strong encryption in a statement Monday saying it protects child sex predators, three people briefed on the matter told Reuters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;PrimaryAsset_container&quot; readability=&quot;8.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Image_container&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot; readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;LazyImage_container LazyImage_dark&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;amp;d=20191117&amp;amp;t=2&amp;amp;i=1453493617&amp;amp;r=LYNXMPEFAG0UL&amp;amp;w=20&quot; aria-label=&quot;FILE PHOTO: A man passes an Interpol logo during the handing over ceremony of the new premises for Interpol's Global Complex for Innovation, a research and development facility, in Singapore September 30, 2014. REUTERS/Edgar Su/File Photo&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;FILE PHOTO: A man passes an Interpol logo during the handing over ceremony of the new premises for Interpol's Global Complex for Innovation, a research and development facility, in Singapore September 30, 2014. REUTERS/Edgar Su/File Photo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the group’s conference in Lyon, France on Friday, an Interpol official said a version of the resolution introduced by the U.S. Federal Bureau of Investigation would be released without a formal vote by representatives of the roughly 60 countries in attendance, the sources said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Echoing a joint letter last month from the top law enforcement officials in the United States, United Kingdom and Australia, the larger group will cite difficulties in catching child sexual predators as grounds for companies opening up user communications to authorities wielding court warrants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Service providers, application developers and device manufacturers are developing and deploying products and services with encryption which effectively conceals sexual exploitation of children occurring on their platforms,” a draft of the resolution seen by Reuters said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Tech companies should include mechanisms in the design of their encrypted products and services whereby governments, acting with appropriate legal authority, can obtain access to data in a readable and useable format.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interpol did not respond to a request for comment Sunday. The FBI referred questions to Interpol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cooperative law enforcement association is best known for helping countries assist one another in catching suspects outside their jurisdictions. The new statement will not have the force of law, but instead aim at increasing pressure on tech providers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It could provide greater political cover for more countries to pass laws or regulations barring unbreakable encryption or requiring companies to be capable of hacking their own users, both of which are anathema to major U.S.-based global providers including Apple and Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both the United Kingdom and Australia have recently passed laws moving in that direction, though it is unclear how widely they are being wielded. U.S. skirmishes have been fought in sealed court proceedings, without major congressional action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interpol joining the political fray is notable because the group includes Russia and other countries without rules against mass surveillance or spying on political minorities and activists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This proposal will endanger people who rely on strong encryption to keep them safe, including from hackers and repressive regimes,” said a spokesman for Facebook, which was among the tech companies in Lyon for the conference. “It will also weaken the online security of over a billion people.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook, owner of WhatsApp and Instagram, moved to the front of the political fight this year by announcing plans to make its popular Messenger communication service encrypted end-to-end, so that neither Facebook nor law enforcement can view content unless they have access to one of the endpoint devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because Messenger has been one of the most valuable sources of information about child predators, the step provoked the October joint letter from three of the “Five Eyes” intelligence alliance, which also includes Canada and New Zealand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tech activists, pointing to past abuses of “exceptional access” for governments, have been alarmed at the political and legal trend, and that accelerated over the weekend. If an international company provides hacking capability under the legal system in one nation, they say, other countries will demand and get the same access, potentially across borders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The idea that the U.S. is so concerned about having lawful exceptional access to end-to-end encryption that they are willing to spread that to nearly every jurisdiction in the world, including authoritarian states with which we would otherwise not share information, is unthinkable to me,” said Andrew Crocker, an attorney at the nonprofit Electronic Frontier Foundation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“To give that power to Russia, China and other authoritarian states is complete dereliction of duty of the U.S. government to protect us.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Attribution_container&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Attribution_attribution&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Attribution_content&quot;&gt;Reporting by Joseph Menn; editing by Diane Craft&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;StandardArticleBody_trustBadgeContainer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;StandardArticleBody_trustBadgeTitle&quot;&gt;Our Standards:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;trustBadgeUrl&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thomsonreuters.com/en/about-us/trust-principles.html&quot;&gt;The Thomson Reuters Trust Principles.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 02:21:16 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pabs3</dc:creator>
<og:title>Exclusive: Interpol plans to condemn encryption spread, citing predators, sources say</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-interpol-encryption-exclusive-idUSKBN1XR0S7</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>The international police organization Interpol plans to condemn the spread of st...</og:description>
<og:image>https://s3.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;d=20191117&amp;t=2&amp;i=1453493617&amp;w=1200&amp;r=LYNXMPEFAG0UL</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-interpol-encryption-exclusive/exclusive-interpol-plans-to-condemn-encryption-spread-citing-predators-sources-say-idUSKBN1XR0S7</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>