<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Swedish ISP Protests ‘Site Blocking’ by Blocking Rightsholders Website Too</title>
<link>https://torrentfreak.com/swedish-isp-protest-site-blocking-by-blocking-rightsholders-website-and-more-181102/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://torrentfreak.com/swedish-isp-protest-site-blocking-by-blocking-rightsholders-website-and-more-181102/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://torrentfreak.com/images/bahnhof.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;222&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; class=&quot;alignright size-full wp-image-128056&quot;/&gt;As a staunch defender of an open Internet, ISP &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bahnhof.se/&quot;&gt;Bahnhof&lt;/a&gt; has repeatedly spoken out against pirate site blocking efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company has also argued the matter in court recently, after academic publisher Elsevier applied for an order to ban a series of domain names, including Sci-Hub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, Bahnhof announced that it has been ordered to block the sites in question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the worst possible outcome for Bahnhof. TorrentFreak spoke to CEO Jon Karlung who describes it as a “horrifying” decision that “goes against the soul of the Internet.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result, starting today, is that sci-hub.tw, sci-hub.mu, sci-hub.se, libgen.io, and several other domains are being &lt;a href=&quot;http://kampa-for-ett-fritt-internet-utan-upphovsmaffians-blockering.se/&quot;&gt;blocked by the ISP&lt;/a&gt;. But Bahnhof wouldn’t be Bahnhof if it went down without a fight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company has no faith in an expensive appeal, which another ISP lost last year in a similar blocking case. However, it does have another ace up its sleeve. Now that they are blocking anyway, they can easily an extra domain name to make a point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, in addition, Bahnhof has gone ahead and banned its visitors from accessing the official Elsevier.com website as well. Elsevier wanted a site blockade – it now has one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visitors attempting to visit the domains now see a 90s style website explaining what’s going on, complete with an old &lt;a href=&quot;http://this-copyright-syndicate-is-killing-internet-by-blocking-sites.se/SuzanneBeDell-MarciaBalisciano-YoungSukChi-JohnDanaher-HannfriedvonHindenburg-NikunjJinsi-BeverlyMalone-EmilieMarcus-RonMobed-GeraldineRichmond/&quot;&gt;dial-up tone in the background&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Bahnhof opposes censorship in every way, shape and form, but it looks like we won’t be able to dodge Elsevier’s blocking requirement. That’s why we have placed this barrier in front of Elsevier’s website – to make sure that they themselves also get a taste of the blocking they’re currently evoking against others,” it reads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elsevier.com banned&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://torrentfreak.com/images/elseban.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;611&quot; height=&quot;341&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-163648&quot;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The page goes on to explain what Elsevier is, making note of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://torrentfreak.com/sci-hub-tears-down-academias-illegal-copyright-paywalls-150627/&quot;&gt;controversy&lt;/a&gt; surrounding the company’s role in academic publishing. This is one of the reasons why the blocked “pirate” sites have become so popular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bahnhof’s CEO informs TorrentFreak that the company sees no point in appealing the case. The Patent and Market Court, which handles these matters, is made up of people who are biased towards copyright holders, he believes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make another point, the Internet provider also decided to send the court a message. Starting today, users of the court’s network can no longer access Bahnhof’s website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The computer or network you are using belongs to the Patent and Market Court and is therefore blocked from the domain bahnhof.se. You at the Patent and Market Court have recently decided that operators should block certain domains so their customers can no longer visit them,” the message reads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Court banned&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://torrentfreak.com/images/courtban1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;611&quot; height=&quot;275&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-163647&quot;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the ISP is clearly disappointed with the court’s decision, it will not stop its protests. It may not be able to undo the blocking order but the company will continue to make its voice heard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Bahnhof has repeatedly demonstrated how copyright law is being abused and exploited by greedy opportunists, and in the end it is always ordinary people who have to pay,” Bahnhof notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This page you’ve got before you right now is the result, this is what awaits in a future where private interests can regulate community information. Is our legal system really being used in this way?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ISP also hopes that its subscribers will help with its efforts. On the &lt;a href=&quot;http://&quot; http:=&quot;&quot; kampa-for-ett-fritt-internet-utan-upphovsmaffians-blockering.se=&quot;&quot;&gt;blocking page&lt;/a&gt; it provides a form allowing them to send a letter to Justice Minister Morgan Johansson, to share their outrage.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 14:52:07 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kawera</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Swedish ISP Protests 'Site Blocking' by Blocking Rightsholders Website Too - TorrentFreak</og:title>
<og:description>Bahnhof has suffered a major defeat against publisher Elsevier after a court ordered the Swedish ISP to block a series of domain names, including Sci-Hub. The decision goes against everything the company stands for but it can't ignore the blocking order. Instead, the ISP has gone on the offensive by blocking Elsevier's own website and barring the court from visiting Bahnhof.se.</og:description>
<og:url>https://torrentfreak.com/swedish-isp-protest-site-blocking-by-blocking-rightsholders-website-and-more-181102/</og:url>
<og:image>https://torrentfreak.com/images/blocked-1.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://torrentfreak.com/swedish-isp-protest-site-blocking-by-blocking-rightsholders-website-and-more-181102/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Aether – Free, privacy-sensitive public communities</title>
<link>https://getaether.net</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://getaether.net</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;feature-block&quot; readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;👀 Private&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aether is a &lt;strong&gt;peer-to-peer&lt;/strong&gt; app, and it has no servers. A result of this is that source IP of any specific public post cannot &lt;em&gt;(easily)&lt;/em&gt; be determined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most people use pseudonyms, though you can use your real name, or company. Aether is private by default, so that you can choose to be fully private, or fully public yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;feature-block&quot; readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;👻 Ephemeral&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aether keeps a &lt;strong&gt;6 months of content&lt;/strong&gt; by default. It's gone after. If something is worth keeping, someone will save it within six months — but not from beyond that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you screw up, argue for the wrong opinion, and then think otherwise, that's okay. No one is going to come after you — it gives you the freedom to be wrong, and move on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;feature-block&quot; readability=&quot;17&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🔮 Transparent&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actions of moderators are visible to users. &lt;strong&gt;No content can just 'disappear'&lt;/strong&gt;, if something gets deleted, you'll know who did it, why they did it, and if you want, how to get it back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moderation is important for healthy communities, and Aether adds onto it some checks-and-balances. Everyone watches the watchmen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;feature-block&quot; readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📨 Democratic&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Communities can &lt;strong&gt;elect and impeach their own mods by voting&lt;/strong&gt;. If a mod behaves inappropriately, users can disable that mod locally as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doing so reverts all changes by that moderator for the user, and counts for one impeachment vote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 14:10:24 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>HostFat</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://getaether.net/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why I&amp;#039;m Ditching Android</title>
<link>https://kevq.uk/why-im-ditching-android/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://kevq.uk/why-im-ditching-android/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Regular readers of this blog will know that I went through a process of &lt;a href=&quot;https://kevq.uk/category/de-googling&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;de-Googling my life&lt;/a&gt; a while ago. For the most part I think the process was pretty successful, however there were &lt;a href=&quot;https://kevq.uk/de-googling-my-life-06-what-i-cant-replace/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;some things that I couldn’t replace&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward a year, and after a lot of trial and error I’m ready to now take the next step in removing Google from my life – I’m ditching Android.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First I tried to ditch my smartphone completely, but that was a &lt;a href=&quot;https://kevq.uk/ditching-my-smartphone-fail/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;massive fail&lt;/a&gt;. Then I tried replacing Android with Lineage OS on a old phone I had. Whilst that meant I didn’t have any Google Apps on my device, it was still Android underneath. Also many apps kept complaining that I didn’t have Google services on the device. That got very old, very quick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So last night I decided that I’m ditching Android completely and I’ve ordered an Apple iPhone SE. You probably think I’ve jumped out of the frying pan and into the fire, but let me explain the rationale behind the decision…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Google Ad Vortex&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unless you’ve been living under a rock for the last decade, I’m sure you’re probably aware that Google’s business model is based around advertising. That’s how they make their money, and that’s why a lot of their services are free – because you are the product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, Apple’s business model is based around hardware. Yes their hardware is grossly overpriced, but the flagship Android phones are pretty much inline with Apple these days. So it’s a moot point really.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because Google make their money from advertising, it’s in their best interest to get as much information about you as possible. You only need to look at the recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://digitalcontentnext.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/DCN-Google-Data-Collection-Paper.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Digital Content Next&lt;/em&gt; paper&lt;/a&gt;, where they proved Android sends 10x more data about you back to Google than Apple does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a good &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/google/idle-android-phones-send-data-to-google-ten-times-more-often-than-ios-devices-to-apple/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;summary about the paper&lt;/a&gt; on Bleeping Computer if you can’t be bothered reading all 55 pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://kevq.uk/wp/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DCN-google-apple-stats.png&quot; data-rel=&quot;lightbox-image-0&quot; data-rl_title=&quot;&quot; data-rl_caption=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-734&quot; src=&quot;https://kevq.uk/wp/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DCN-google-apple-stats.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;792&quot; height=&quot;472&quot; srcset=&quot;https://kevq.uk/wp/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DCN-google-apple-stats.png 792w, https://kevq.uk/wp/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DCN-google-apple-stats-300x179.png 300w, https://kevq.uk/wp/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DCN-google-apple-stats-768x458.png 768w, https://kevq.uk/wp/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DCN-google-apple-stats-671x400.png 671w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 792px) 100vw, 792px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bloatware&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Android vendors are almost as bad as Windows when it comes to bundling additional applications with their devices. It’s almost a meme at this point. But at least on Windows you can uninstall all the bloatware. Most of the bloatware on Android devices I’ve used over the years cannot be removed as they’re marked as system apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you want to remove Google’s proprietary apps like Google Drive, Google Search, or Google Photos, forget it. They’re all “system apps” that cannot be uninstalled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://kevq.uk/wp/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/android-system-apps.png&quot; data-rel=&quot;lightbox-image-1&quot; data-rl_title=&quot;&quot; data-rl_caption=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-736 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://kevq.uk/wp/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/android-system-apps.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; srcset=&quot;https://kevq.uk/wp/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/android-system-apps.png 900w, https://kevq.uk/wp/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/android-system-apps-300x167.png 300w, https://kevq.uk/wp/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/android-system-apps-768x427.png 768w, https://kevq.uk/wp/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/android-system-apps-720x400.png 720w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 900px) 100vw, 900px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same is also true of iOS to a certain degree. However, on Android it’s much more prevalent. I don’t use HiCare, or Huawei Weather, or Huawei Music – let me bloody remove them!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Notifications&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the last update I received for my Android (around 6 months ago now), the new battery saving measures were implemented. Whilst the battery life on my Huawei is really good, it has done something funky to my notifications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hardly ever get notifications for emails, calendar events, social media etc. I assume this is because the battery saving measures kill the background processes. So the apps can’t carry out background tasks, like checking for new email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve tried to work around this by using the battery optimisation settings in Android, but I just can’t get it to work. On a number of occasions now I’ve missed very important emails, all because my phone decides it doesn’t want to notify me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why the iPhone SE?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I’m gonna flip to Apple, why not get the latest device, right? Well, one of my pet hates about phones these days is the sheer size of them – they’re basically a tablet in your pocket. I want a phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The iPhone SE is actually a phone sized device. It’s cheap, and it’s still supported by Apple. It’s seemed like a no-brainer to give it a try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-742 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://kevq.uk/wp/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/iPhone-SE.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;506&quot; srcset=&quot;https://kevq.uk/wp/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/iPhone-SE.jpg 900w, https://kevq.uk/wp/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/iPhone-SE-300x169.jpg 300w, https://kevq.uk/wp/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/iPhone-SE-768x432.jpg 768w, https://kevq.uk/wp/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/iPhone-SE-711x400.jpg 711w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 900px) 100vw, 900px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I doubt I will have any issues flipping to the iPhone SE, as I already have an iPad. Whilst not the perfect solution, ditching Android in favour of iOS is another step towards getting rid of Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m never going to completely get rid of Google, that’s impossible at this point,  but I think this is the right decision for me. My SE gets delivered this week, so I will post an update after a few months of use to let you guys know how I’m getting on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have you ditched Android? Or have you ditched iOS? Let me know your thoughts below.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 13:54:13 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kevq</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Why I'm Ditching Android - Kev Quirk</og:title>
<og:description>Regular readers of this blog will know that I went through a process of de-Googling my life a while ago. For the most part I think the process was pretty successful, however there were some things that I couldn’t replace. Fast forward a year, and after a lot of trial and error I’m ready to…</og:description>
<og:url>https://kevq.uk/why-im-ditching-android/</og:url>
<og:image>https://kevq.uk/wp/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/ditching-android-feature.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-GB</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://kevq.uk/why-im-ditching-android/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>What Is The Morning Writing Effect?</title>
<link>https://www.gwern.net/Morning-writing</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.gwern.net/Morning-writing</guid>
<description>&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ericsson 1993 notes that many major writers or researchers prioritized writing by making it the first activity of their day, often getting up early in the morning. This is based largely on writers anecdotally reporting they write best first thing early in the morning, apparently even if they are not morning people, although there is some additional survey/software-logging evidence of morning writing being effective. I compile all the anecdotes of writers discussing their writing times I have come across thus far. Do they, and why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interviews with writers often touch on their writing process; the hope of the reader is, deep down, to learn &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; they do the things they do and perhaps the reader can do the same thing. For the most part, the lesson I’ve taken away from such profiles is that every writer is different and there do not seem to be many generalizable practices; for every writer that thrives on writing in longhand with goose quills on parchment, another is unable to think outside a computer text editor, or needs to inhale rotting bananas, or sharpen pencils, or write in a cork-lined room, or insist on a &lt;a href=&quot;https://qualiacomputing.com/2018/06/21/john-von-neumann/&quot; title=&quot;Passing of a Great Mind: John von Neumann, a Brilliant, Jovial Mathematician, was a Prodigious Servant of Science and his Country&quot;&gt;loud phonograph/party&lt;/a&gt; for inspiration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gwern.net/docs/psychology/writing/1993-ericsson.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;q&gt;The Role of Deliberate Practice&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Ericsson 1993 (among &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newappsblog.com/2011/05/new-apps-interview-la-paul.html&quot;&gt;others&lt;/a&gt;), Ericsson draws on some anecdotes and particular long-running &amp;amp; somewhat-standardized &lt;em&gt;Paris Review&lt;/em&gt; interviews of famous writers to make some interesting points about the relative brevity of most writing sessions (perhaps not too surprising as the physical typing/writing is not the bottleneck) but also the &lt;em&gt;timing&lt;/em&gt; of it typically in the morning:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;25.037071362373&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best data on sustained intellectual activity comes from financially independent authors. While completing a novel famous authors tend to write only for 4 hr during the morning, leaving the rest of the day for rest and recuperation ([Cowley, M. (Ed.). (1959). &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Writers-Work-Paris-Review-Interviews/dp/0140045406/?tag=gwernnet-20&quot;&gt;Writers at work&lt;/a&gt;: The &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The%20Paris%20Review%23Interview%20series&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: The Paris Review#Interview series&quot;&gt;Paris review interviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.]; [&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/George%20Plimpton&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: George Plimpton&quot;&gt;Plimpton, G.&lt;/a&gt; (Ed.). (1977). &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Writers-Work-02-Paris-Review/dp/0140045414/?tag=gwernnet-20&quot;&gt;Writers at work&lt;/a&gt;: The Paris review. Interviews, second series&lt;/em&gt;.]). Hence successful authors, who can control their work habits and are motivated to optimize their productivity, limit their most important intellectual activity to a fixed daily amount when working on projects requiring long periods of time to complete…Biographies report that famous scientists such as Charles Darwin, (Erasmus Darwin, 1888), Pavlov (Babkin, 1949), Hans Selye (Selye, 1964), and B.F. Skinner (Skinner, 1983) adhered to a rigid daily schedule where the first major activity of each morning involved writing for a couple of hours. In a large questionnaire study of science and engineering faculty, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gwern.net/docs/psychology/writing/1986-kellogg.pdf&quot; title=&quot;Writing method and productivity of science and engineering faculty&quot;&gt;Kellogg (1986)&lt;/a&gt; found that writing on articles occurred most frequently before lunch and that limiting writing sessions to a duration of 1-2 hr was related to higher reported productivity…In this regard, it is particularly interesting to examine the way in which famous authors allocate their time. These authors often retreat when they are ready to write a book and make writing their sole purpose. Almost without exception, they tend to schedule 3-4 hr of writing every morning and to spend the rest of the day on walking, correspondence, napping, and other less demanding activities (Cowley, 1959; Plimpton, 1977).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Boice &amp;amp; Johnson 1984, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gwern.net/docs/psychology/writing/1984-boice.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;q&gt;Perception and practice of writing for publication by faculty at a doctoral-granting university&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hartley 1980, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gwern.net/docs/psychology/writing/1980-hartley-thepsychologyofwrittencommunication.djvu&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Psychology of Written Communication: Selected Readings&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hartley &amp;amp; Knapper 1984, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gwern.net/docs/psychology/writing/1984-hartley.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;q&gt;Academics and their writing&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lowenthal &amp;amp; Wason 1977, &lt;q&gt;Academics and their writing&lt;/q&gt;. &lt;em&gt;London Times Literary Supplement&lt;/em&gt;, June 24, p. 782.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stein 1974, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gwern.net/docs/psychology/writing/1974-stein-stimulatingcreativity-v1individualprocedures.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stimulating Creativity, Volume 1: Individual Procedures&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. New York: Academic Press.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ghiselin 1952, &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.org/details/creativeprocessa013702mbp&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Creative Process: A Symposium&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vernon et al 1970, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gwern.net/docs/psychology/writing/1970-vernon-creativity.djvu&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Creativity&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was interesting to me because I generally do not write in the morning, so knowing that morning is better would be valuable to me, and because it confused me why it would be true. If you are a morning person, you should write in the morning, and vice-versa if you are an evening person. Why would you write when you are miserable? I was especially not a morning person when I was a teenager, and it certainly showed in my first period class at 8:20AM after waking up at 6AM; certainly I never noticed any hidden gift for writing novels manifesting, even when it was a literature class. (Although I did notice a hidden gift for completely forgetting anything said in the first period.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the post hoc explanations for why morning might be better make no sense. It is true people are less likely to interrupt you early in the morning; but they are less likely to interrupt you at midnight. It is true people can find time for writing by getting up before their job; but they can sacrifice the same amount of sleep to write by staying up later at night. It is true that the morning might not be a circadian nadir; but that’s not helpful to anyone who is an owl, who by definition is sluggish in the morning, and where does all this energy come from for walking or exercising or partying or researching in the evening, when not writing, if the writer is hopelessly fashed after the vicissitudes of the day? (If the secret of morning writing is merely the nigh-tautological &lt;q&gt;if you’re a morning person who writes best in the morning, you should write in the morning, and if you’re an evening person, you should write in the evening&lt;/q&gt;, then it’s surely of no value - is there anyone who doesn’t already know whether they are more of a morning or evening person?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further, morning writing runs counter to the usual stereotype of great writers as rising late and being &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chronotype&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Chronotype&quot;&gt;chronometric&lt;/a&gt; &lt;q&gt;night owls&lt;/q&gt;. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Night%20owl%20%28person%29&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Night owl (person)&quot;&gt;&lt;q&gt;owl&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/a&gt; chronotype is usually linked with creativity &amp;amp; intelligence while morning &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lark%20%28person%29&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Lark (person)&quot;&gt;&lt;q&gt;larks&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/a&gt; are considered less creative (but more industrious &amp;amp; favored in many contexts like schools, to the detriment of owls &amp;amp; teenagers), so one would expect the opposite: writers to report writing mostly in the evening. (And amusingly, the Wikipedia article on &lt;q&gt;owls&lt;/q&gt; includes a list of dozens of writers or other creative types while the &lt;q&gt;lark&lt;/q&gt; article is devoid.) What could be more writerly or bohemian than spending the day researching or enjoying nature or drinking to jazz at the club and then returning to one’s attic in the witching hours to author deathless verse? Nevertheless, great authors routinely rehearse the advantages of living like a farmer and rising with the sun to milk the Muses. (Cal Newport’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://calnewport.com/books/deep-work/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Deep Work&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; book points this way, and there is even a writer self-help fad, &lt;q&gt;The Miracle Morning&lt;/q&gt;, whose central gimmick is getting up early.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Puzzled, I began noticing in author interviews or writings that when writing times were mentioned, it was indeed more, often than not, partially or entirely in the morning (sometimes disgustingly early like pre-dawn), rather than usually in the evening as expected, and it became startling when I ran into an exception like Ian Fleming or Winston Churchill, who wrote at all in the evening, or Brandon Sanderson or Robert Frost, who work entirely into the wee hours. I am, again, not a morning person but I forced myself up early a few days and skipped my usual email &amp;amp; news-reading routine to focus on writing, and darn if it didn’t seem to work and the writing was worth the price in afternoon circadian slumps. Still couldn’t make myself do it regularly, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section id=&quot;causes&quot; class=&quot;level1&quot; readability=&quot;5.8574648864227&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the morning writing effect is real (in the sense that successful writers do disproportionately write in the morning - which is still in doubt given the existing systematic survey evidence is limited to ordinary writers while the elite writers are represented so far purely by haphazardly-selected anecdotes), what is causing it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;35.578758290346&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;23&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One possibility is that there is some sort of ecological fallacy going on: it is possible that, creativity really is higher in owls at night, owls do not improve by writing in the morning, but the best authors are still larks (rather than owls as one would assume from the population-level correlation) and do benefit from writing in the morning (or at least aren’t hurt); and this is because larks have other advantages in becoming the best authors, perhaps related to sheer writing volume &amp;amp; consistent output. No matter how creative it is, an unwritten book is no good. Larks then could write fine at any time and would be overrepresented among the best authors either way, because writing time is confounded with other Conscientiousness-related attributes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking through the anecdotes so far, while it’s true that devotees of &lt;q&gt;The Miracle Morning&lt;/q&gt; and others frequently claim to not be larks and struggle to reap the benefits of morning writing, the &lt;em&gt;elite&lt;/em&gt; writers who happen to write in the morning (currently) do not mention major struggles with getting up early or focusing in the morning, implying that they may well all be larks in the first place!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Simonton’s &lt;q&gt;equal-odds rule&lt;/q&gt; suggests that volume of writing output is much more important than it is usually given credit for being, and that writing or research is too random a process to permit siting down for several years and decide to bang out a beloved masterpiece: one can only try as many things as possible and be surprised when one turns out well, or happens to become a hit.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;A related but somewhat simpler possibility is that people are bad at scheduling and while late-night writing is no different than morning writing and just as effective in theory, people tend to choose to fill up their schedules, and repeatedly accidentally find themselves with too little time to write at night; every hour of evening writing that people do get done is just as effective as morning hours, but there are fewer such hours. Doing it in the morning is then simply a little trick to make sure that other obligations literally cannot come first.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;6.7756833176249&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another possibility is that the day really does use up some sort of &lt;q&gt;willpower&lt;/q&gt; or &lt;q&gt;creativity&lt;/q&gt;: all the little things one does before the writing late in evening fill up one’s mind. There is nothing special about morning hours, they merely happen to be the conscious hours closest in time to sleep pushing the big reset button on the brain. If someone slept during the day &amp;amp; woke up at midnight, that person would then be best off writing at midnight, right after waking up, rather than 8 hours later in the morning, equivalent to their afternoon. (Tononi’s SHY theory of sleep would be a low-level neurobiological explanation along these lines.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;A version of this &lt;q&gt;thing building up/wearing out over the day&lt;/q&gt; is that it is related to ego depletion or &lt;q&gt;decision fatigue&lt;/q&gt; or opportunity cost, where the increasing number of accomplished activities it becomes an excuse to write less - &lt;q&gt;I had a busy day, I can take it easy tonight.&lt;/q&gt; - or one has difficulty truly focusing because there are so many other things which one could do (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sas.upenn.edu/psych/kable_lab/Joes_Homepage/Publications_files/Kurzban,%20Duckworth,%20Kable,%20Myers%20response.pdf&quot; title=&quot;'An opportunity cost model of subjective effort and task performance', Kurzban et al 2013&quot;&gt;Kurzban’s opportunity cost model&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;38.176991150442&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet another version might be that sleep itself is the key: sleep, aside from any resetting, is also responsible for memory formation and appears involved in unconscious processes of creativity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sleep is a long time period in between phases of working, allowing for &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Incubation%20%28psychology%29&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Incubation (psychology)&quot;&gt;the incubation effect&lt;/a&gt; to operate, and the incubation effect may be particularly benefited by sleep. So, one wakes up primed to work on the next piece of writing (that one has likely been mulling a long time), and by instead puttering around making tea or breakfast, one dissipates the potential. In this model, instead of one’s writing potential gradually deteriorating over the course of the day as the mind fills up/willpower is used up, it falls sharply and then hits a baseline and perhaps follows the usual circadian rhythms thereafter with a nadir at siesta time etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or, perhaps there is something special about the liminal half-sleep state, which makes fantasizing or imaging easier. One parallel we might draw is with the ancient connection between fiction writers and alcohol: writers are notorious for drinking, often to excess. Is there something about the depressant or loosening of inhibitions of alcohol which assists writing, which might also be reproduced in the morning? On the other hand, nonfiction writers like journalists or philosophers or scientists tend to be associated with stimulants, particularly &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/nicotine&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: nicotine&quot;&gt;nicotine&lt;/a&gt;, caffeine, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gwern.net/!Wikipeida&quot;&gt;amphetamines&lt;/a&gt; (not to mention &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gwern.net/Modafinil&quot;&gt;modafinil&lt;/a&gt;); while those, particularly amphetamines, are less associated with fiction writers. (This makes me wonder if there is a connection to another anomalous anecdotal phenomenon, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gwern.net/Notes#open-questions&quot;&gt;the so-called alcohol &lt;q&gt;afterglow&lt;/q&gt; effect&lt;/a&gt;, and if my poor &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gwern.net/LSD-microdosing&quot;&gt;LSD microdosing&lt;/a&gt; results reflect my own nonfiction tendencies.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This half-asleep explanation neatly explains why evening doesn’t work. It wouldn’t apply to falling asleep as there is an asymmetry: a half-asleep person in the morning who is writing is getting gradually more alert and spending the rest of the day awake, and can build on whatever mental seeds were planted; while a half-asleep person in the evening would frustrate sleep by trying to write, can’t write for long before falling asleep, and when they do fall asleep, would forget the preceding ~10 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section id=&quot;directions&quot; class=&quot;level1&quot; readability=&quot;1.9644760213144&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few things one could do to generate a little more data on this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol type=&quot;1&quot; readability=&quot;1.9615014436959&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;systematically go through the &lt;em&gt;Paris Review&lt;/em&gt; interviews and the similar &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/featured_lists/1-author-interviews&quot;&gt;GoodReads interviews&lt;/a&gt; to note down all cases where an author is asked about writing time, rather than a few examples; this avoids the risk that morning writing advocates have selectively chosen examples from the interviews. As the writers are not chosen for their writing habits and the interview question are fairly formulaic, presumably the interview series could be considered a quasi-random survey sample of successful authors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;run a population-sample survey (I have done one USA survey myself but more extensive surveys &amp;amp; surveys elsewhere would be useful)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;run surveys in more elite-writer samples&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;run a (non-blinded) self-experiment: create a list of things to systematically work on; flip a coin to decide whether to get up early, record total words-written+time-spent etc. (I can’t decide if I would be biased towards wanting it to work or wanting it to fail: of course I want to be better at writing, but on the other hand - surely there’s some easier way!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section id=&quot;research&quot; class=&quot;level1&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;36.256906077348&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;8.2507774322523&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gwern.net/docs/psychology/writing/1986-kellogg.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;q&gt;Writing method and productivity of science and engineering faculty&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Kellogg 1986: to go into more detail, it reports:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The respondents tended to schedule their work between 8AM and 8PM, with the morning hours being the most common time of day (Table 3). Positive but nonsignificant correlations were obtained for these time intervals. Night owls were rare and not unique in their productivity. In terms of the duration of writing sessions, the data indicate a preference for one to three hours. Working for 1 to 2 hours was significantly correlated with productivity. But as will be explained later in describing the multiple regression analyses, this effect is best attributed to other factors correlated with the frequency of working for 1 to 2 hours. Highly regular work scheduling was not the rule; the most common response was only a 3 on the 7 point scale. &lt;q&gt;Write in spurts&lt;/q&gt; and &lt;q&gt;marathon writing just before a deadline&lt;/q&gt; were comments listed by respondents that match the pattern commonly observed in Boice and Johnson’s (op. cit.) survey. As in Boice and Johnson’s study, regular writing was positively correlated with productivity, but here the relationship was weak and nonsignificant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead/&gt;&lt;tbody readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;odd&quot; readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Midnight-4AM (hour of day)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.76&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.29&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.01&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;even&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;4AM-8AM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.87&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.49&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.04&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;odd&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;8AM-Noon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.61&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.44&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.17&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;even&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Noon-4PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.34&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.33&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.15&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;odd&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;4PM-8PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.60&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.54&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.13&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;even&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;8PM-Midnight&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.80&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.80&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.05&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;odd&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;0-1 hour (Duration)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.50&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.58&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.09&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;even&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;1-2 hours&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.46&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.40&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.22*&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;odd&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;2-3 hours&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.44&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.36&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.07&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;even&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;3-4 hours&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.49&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.63&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-0.04&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;odd&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;More than 4 hours&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2.76&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.73&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-0.12&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;even&quot; readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Every working day (regularity)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.01&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.50&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.11&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;Table 3: Analysis of Work Scheduling (&lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt;=121; The response scale ranged from &lt;q&gt;Never&lt;/q&gt; (1) to &lt;q&gt;Always&lt;/q&gt; (7). * = &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt;&amp;lt;0.05)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Another interesting aspect of Kellogg 1986 is that almost all variables correlate non-statistically-significantly with &lt;q&gt;productivity&lt;/q&gt; (defined in Kellogg as the total number of books/papers/reports/grant-applications/grant-reports written in the previous 3 years), and most are of small magnitude. Measurement error &amp;amp; range restriction come to mind as biasing effects towards zero, but it’s still consistent with my own experience that it is difficult to find anything which strongly correlates with &lt;q&gt;productivity&lt;/q&gt;, much less causes it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;6.0350665054414&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gwern.net/docs/psychology/writing/1989-hartley.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;q&gt;The psychologist as wordsmith: a questionnaire study of the writing strategies of productive British psychologists&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Hartley &amp;amp; Branthwaite 1989 conduct a similar survey as Kellogg but do not give any statistical details that I can find, saying merely&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the present study most of our productive psychologists had no real preference for any time of day at which to work. The morning appeared to be slightly preferred to the afternoon and the afternoon slightly preferred to the evening. Regular working times were correlated with overall productivity, but productive book writers wrote sporadically (in term time). These findings were very similar to those of Kellogg (1986) who showed that the majority of his 121 engineers worked in the morning, and then the afternoon, but that a highly regular work schedule was not the rule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;3.7746096401901&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.rescuetime.com/225-million-hours-productivity/&quot;&gt;&lt;q&gt;Productivity in 2017: What we learned from analyzing 225 million hours of work time&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, RescueTime 2018; analytics over hundreds of thousands of users:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at the time spent in software development tools, our data paints a picture of a workday that doesn’t get going until the late morning and peaks between 2–6pm daily…While writers are more likely to be early birds…Writing apps were used more evenly throughout each day with the most productive writing time happening on Tuesdays at 10AM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Time spent in writing tools (light blue): RescueTime analysis of distributing of writing app use over time of day over the week: note intense band 10-11AM every day&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gwern.net/images/2018-01-04-rescuetime-writingoverweek.png&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;/&gt;&lt;q&gt;Time spent in writing tools (light blue)&lt;/q&gt;: RescueTime analysis of distributing of writing app use over time of day over the week: note intense band 10-11AM every day&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Allowing for the different time buckets, the RescueTime results closely parallel Kellogg 1986’s survey responses. Aside from being an enormous data sample, RescueTime notes an interesting contrast: despite being apparently similar activities (both mostly involve slinging text), the temporal timing of software development &amp;amp; writing are strikingly different. Thinking back, I don’t recall early-morning programming being a trend among programmers (programmers are infamous for preferring to come in late and late-night programming sessions which may wrap around the clock, especially in college - though the original reason, that &lt;q&gt;the computers are less busy at night&lt;/q&gt;, has long since expired). It’s fascinating that the stereotypes about writing vs programming line up so well with the RescueTime data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;62.547392815759&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2018 Google Surveys, general USA population sample, asking self-identified writers/researchers/scientists their chronotype &amp;amp; ideal writing time&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ran this survey in October 2018, using &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Google%20Surveys&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Google Surveys&quot;&gt;Google Surveys&lt;/a&gt;, asking a question akin to Kellogg 1986’s survey, like &lt;q&gt;if you are a professional writer, blogger, researcher, or scientist do you find you write best at: [not a writer]/[Midnight-4AM]/[4-8AM]/etc?&lt;/q&gt; At $0.10 a response, if 5% of the population could be considered some sort of writer (which sounds reasonable to me) and we want another &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt;=121 to equal Kellogg 1986’s sample size, the survey would only cost 0.10⋅20⋅121=$2420.10\cdot 20 \cdot 121 = \$242. A second question could be added to ask if the respondent considers themselves more of a morning or evening person, however, it dectuples the cost; as in my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gwern.net/Catnip-survey&quot;&gt;catnip surveys&lt;/a&gt;, it should be possible to combine the questions into a single question which can hopefully provide a useful datapoint. (GS tries for a representative population sample by techniques like reweighting; I don’t know if they take time-of-day into account and thus lark/owl type, but the surveys typically run over several days so hopefully they wind up being inherently balanced anyway.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If morning is the most common (replicating the Kellogg 1986 &amp;amp; RescueTime results), and if many evening-preferring respondents still answer that mornings work better for writing, that would be pretty good evidence for morning writing being a real phenomenon (although still leaving the causal status ambiguous and not answering the question of whether owls - like me - would benefit from switching to morning writing).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On 27 October 2018, I launched an all-ages all-gender USA population survey on Google Surveys. Because of the need to run as a 1-question survey, I condensed the two questions into one and simplified it considerably into just morning/evening preference and morning/evening self-estimated writing performance, giving 5 possible responses (1+2x2=5). As most respondents will be useless - I guesstimate 5% would consider them professional writers of some sort, so for a few hundred responses, I need 20x as many; I settled on &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt;=5000/$500 for the survey, which should deliver a precise enough result. The question looked as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol type=&quot;1&quot; readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are a writer/researcher/scientist, are you a morning/evening person &amp;amp; when do you write best? [answers displayed either ascending or descending at random]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;I don’t write or blog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Morning person; best writing during morning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Morning person; best writing during evening&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evening person; best writing during morning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evening person; best writing during evening&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The survey finished 29 October 2018 with the following results (percentage is population-weighted out of equivalent &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt;=3,999; &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; is raw counts out of the &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt;=5004 actually collected; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gwern.net/docs/psychology/writing/2018-10-27-googlesurveys-morningwriting.csv&quot;&gt;CSV&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol type=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;70% (3515)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;9.9% (467)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4.0% (196)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4.0% (193)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;12.1% (633)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;The percentage of people willing to claim to be writers was ~6x larger than I expected, which is troubling (do really &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; many people write large amounts?). Otherwise, the responses appear reasonably evenly balanced: 663 morning people vs 826 evening people. The percentage of overall counter-chronotype self-rated writing performance is 26%. On average, 55% of respondents thought evening-writing was best. The key question, of course, is whether morning-writing is more preferred for counter-chronotype writing: there is a slight preference here, but it is the &lt;em&gt;opposite&lt;/em&gt; of predicted, with 29% of morning people believing they write best in evening versus 23% of evening people saying morning is best for them. (The difference is statistically-significant at &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt;=0.008/&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt;~1.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This does not strongly endorse morning-writing, although it is surprising how many people think they write best counter-chronotype. Of course, the fact that fewer people believe they write better in the morning rather than evening doesn’t prove morning-writing isn’t a thing: one possibility is that people simply haven’t given it a fair try, or that it only works for professional writers at a high level, or that it is heterogeneous and there is a small fraction of people for whom morning-writing works really well (and so everyone should give it a try just in case). The overall even split of chronotype does give a baseline expectation for elite writers, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section id=&quot;anecdotes&quot; class=&quot;level1&quot; readability=&quot;0.96280941839404&quot;&gt;
&lt;section id=&quot;table&quot; class=&quot;level2&quot;&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Table&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead/&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;odd&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Kellogg survey&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1986&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Nonfiction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Morning-afternoon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8AM-12PM, 12PM-4PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;even&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;RescueTime users&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2018&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Nonfiction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Morning&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10AM-11AM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;odd&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Gwern Google Surveys&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2018&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fiction+Nonfiction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Evening&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;even&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Kazuo Ishiguro&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2014&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fiction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Morning&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9AM-10:30AM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;odd&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Dan Brown&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2017&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fiction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Morning&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4AM-12PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;even&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Philip Pullman&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2017&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fiction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Morning-afternoon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10AM-1PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;odd&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Ian Fleming&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1964&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fiction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Morning-evening&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10AM-12PM, 6-7PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;even&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Joseph Campbell&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Nonfiction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Morning-evening&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9AM-6PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;odd&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Charles Dickens&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fiction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Morning-afternoon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9AM-2PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;even&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Robert Frost&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fiction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Afternoon-evening&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1PM?-3AM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;odd&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Winston Churchill&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Nonfiction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Morning-evening&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11AM-1PM, 11PM-2AM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;even&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Frank Herbert&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1969&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fiction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Morning-evening&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5AM-7AM, 5PM-1AM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;odd&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Harry Harrison&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1968&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fiction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Afternoon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;12:30PM-5PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;even&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Toni Morrison&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2015&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fiction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Morning&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6AM-10AM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;odd&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Chimamanda N. Adichie&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2013&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fiction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Any&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Any&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;even&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Michael Connelly&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2017&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fiction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Morning&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4AM-7AM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;odd&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Stephenie Meyer&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2016&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fiction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Evening&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8PM-12PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;even&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Stephen King&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2014&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fiction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Morning&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8AM-12PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;odd&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Paulo Coelho&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2014&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fiction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;evening&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;?PM-4AM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;even&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Brandon Sanderson&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2012&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fiction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Evening&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;12PM-4PM, 4PM-3AM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;odd&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Margaret Atwood&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2014&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fiction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Morning-afternoon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;?AM-?PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;even&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Saint-Exupéry&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1947&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fiction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Evening&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11PM-8AM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;odd&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Neil Gaiman&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2004&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fiction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Evening&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;?PM-?AM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;even&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;John Irving&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1986&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fiction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Morning-afternoon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;?AM-?PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;odd&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Donald Hall&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2018&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fiction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Morning-afternoon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5AM-?PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;even&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Hunter Thompson&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Nonfiction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Evening&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;12AM?-6AM?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section id=&quot;examples&quot; class=&quot;level2&quot; readability=&quot;1.9213984943218&quot;&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Examples&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additional anecdotes of writers’ preferred time I’ve collected:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;32.659383801314&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;2.7281553398058&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kazuo%20Ishiguro&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Kazuo Ishiguro&quot;&gt;Kazuo Ishiguro&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/books/2014/dec/06/kazuo-ishiguro-the-remains-of-the-day-guardian-book-club&quot; title=&quot;Kazuo Ishiguro: how I wrote _The Remains of the Day_ in four weeks: The author reveals how the Tom Waits song Ruby's Arms served as inspiration for his Booker prize-winning classic novel&quot;&gt;2014 interview&lt;/a&gt;): morning+evening&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would, for a four-week period, ruthlessly clear my diary and go on what we somewhat mysteriously called a &lt;q&gt;Crash&lt;/q&gt;. During the Crash, I would do nothing but write from 9AM to 10:30PM, Monday through Saturday. I’d get one hour off for lunch and two for dinner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;8.3424101969873&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dan%20Brown&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Dan Brown&quot;&gt;Dan Brown&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/09/30/books/dan-brown-origin.html&quot; title=&quot;The World According to Dan Brown&quot;&gt;profile&lt;/a&gt;): morning (&amp;gt;4AM-noon)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;22&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr. Brown, 53, spent four years writing and researching the book. He is nothing if not disciplined. He rises at 4AM each day and prepares a smoothie comprising &lt;q&gt;blueberries, spinach, banana, coconut water, chia seeds, hemp seeds and … what’s the other kind of seed?&lt;/q&gt; he asked. &lt;q&gt;Flax seeds, and this sort of weird protein powder made out of peas.&lt;/q&gt; He also makes so-called bulletproof coffee, with butter and coconut oil, which he says changes &lt;q&gt;the way your brain processes the caffeine&lt;/q&gt; so as to sharpen your mind. His computer is programmed to freeze for 60 seconds each hour, during which time Mr. Brown performs push-ups, situps and anything else he needs to do. Though he stops writing at noon, it’s hard for him to get the stories out of his head. &lt;q&gt;It’s madness,&lt;/q&gt; he said of his characters. &lt;q&gt;They talk to you all day.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;8.85&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Philip%20Pullman&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Philip Pullman&quot;&gt;Philip Pullman&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/10/12/magazine/philip-pullman-returns-to-his-fantasy-world.html&quot; title=&quot;Philip Pullman Returns to His Fantasy World: After 17 years, the author of the trilogy &amp;quot;His Dark Materials&amp;quot; carries on the story of one of literature's most indelible heroines.&quot;&gt;profile&lt;/a&gt;): late morning-early afternoon (10AM-1PM)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;23&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every day from roughly 10 until 1, Pullman sits at his desk in a monkish study at the top of the house and produces three pages, longhand. He has written three pages a day ever since he started writing. Habit, he is fond of saying, has written far more books than talent. The ritual is sacred. As is the space. &lt;q&gt;Nobody’s photographed this, and nobody will ever photograph this,&lt;/q&gt; he told me, both fierce and faintly amused by the severity of his own rule. &lt;q&gt;I’m superstitious about that, very superstitious about that.&lt;/q&gt;…For a man whose novels are restless, whose characters never stop traveling, Pullman leads a relatively static life. After the morning shift at his desk, he spends his afternoons either tending to the 800-odd trees he and Judith have planted in the fields behind their house or in his carpentry workshop, where he makes things like reading stands and chopsticks. Occasionally, he drives an elderly woman in the village to the library, and he goes to the cinema once a week with his publisher and close friend David Fickling and their wives. &lt;q&gt;I have the company of the people I’m writing about,&lt;/q&gt; Pullman told me. &lt;q&gt;Jude and I are quite happy here with our hermit-like existence.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;26.588375416865&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ian%20Fleming&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Ian Fleming&quot;&gt;Ian Fleming&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/002-Interview-Barry-G-Golson/dp/0399507698?tag=gwernnet-20&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Playboy Interviews II&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, December 1964 interview; pg56-57): morning+evening (10AM-noon, 6-7PM)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;53&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Playboy&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;q&gt;Do you spend most of your time there at the typewriter?&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Ian Fleming&lt;/code&gt;: “By no means. I get up with the birds, which is about half-past 7, because they wake one up, and then I go and bathe in the ocean before breakfast. We don’t have to wear a swimsuit there, because it’s so private; my wife and I bathe and swim a hundred yards or so and come back and have a marvelous proper breakfast with some splendid scrambled eggs made by my housekeeper, who’s particularly good at them, and then I sit out in the garden to get a sunburn until about 10. Only then do I set to work. I sit in my bedroom and type about fifteen hundred words straightaway, without looking back on what I wrote the day before. I have more or less thought out what I’m going to write, and, in any case, even if I make a lot of mistakes, I think, well, hell, when the book’s finished I can change it all. I think the main thing is to write fast and cursively in order to get narrative speed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, about quarter-past 12, I chuck that and go down, with a snorkel and a spear, around the reefs looking for lobsters or whatever there may be, sometimes find them, sometimes don’t, and then I come back, I have a couple of pink gins, and we have a very good lunch, ordinary Jamaican food, and I have a siesta from about half-past 2 until 4. Then I sit again in the garden for about an hour or so, have another swim, and then I spend from 6 to 7 - the dusk comes very suddenly in Jamaica; at 6 o’clock it suddenly gets very dark - doing another five hundred words. I then number the pages, of which by that time there are about seven, put them away 1n a folder, and have a couple of powerful drinks, then dinner, occasionally a game of Scrabble with my wife - at which she thinks she is very much better than I am, but I know I’m the best - and straight off to bed and into a dead sleep.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Playboy&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;q&gt;And you return to England in March with a completed manuscript?&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Ian Fleming&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;q&gt;Except for minor revisions, yes.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;5.2118263473054&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joseph Campbell (&lt;a href=&quot;https://betterhumans.coach.me/joseph-campbells-daily-routine-for-the-most-important-period-of-my-scholarship-and-study-68d1c35dd0d5&quot; title=&quot;Joseph Campbell's daily routine for 'the most important period of my scholarship and study'&quot;&gt;quoted from &lt;em&gt;The Hero’s Journey: Joseph Campbell on His Life and Work&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;): researched/studied in multiple blocks morning-evening&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So during the years of the Depression I had arranged a schedule for myself. When you don’t have a job or anyone to tell you what to do, you’ve got to fix one for yourself. I divided the day into four four-hour periods, of which I would be reading in three of the four-hour periods, and free one of them. By getting up a 8 o’clock in the morning, by 9 I could sit down to read. That meant that I used the first hour to prepare my own breakfast and take care of the house and put things together in whatever shack I happened to be living in at the time. Then three hours of that first four-hour period went to reading. Then came an hour break for lunch and another three-hour unit. And then comes the optional next section. It should normally be three hours of reading and then an hour out for dinner and then three hours free and an hour getting to bed so I’m in bed by 12. On the other hand, if I were invited out for cocktails or something like that, then I would put the work hour in the evening and the play hour in the afternoon. It worked very well. I would get nine hours of sheer reading done in a day. And this went on for five years straight. You get a lot done in that time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;7.0680345572354&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charles%20Dickens&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Charles Dickens&quot;&gt;Charles Dickens&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/books/booksblog/2011/oct/27/best-times-to-write&quot; title=&quot;The best of times to write: Dickens was all done by 2pm, long before Robert Frost got going. Do your words flow better at certain times of day?&quot;&gt;based on &lt;em&gt;Charles Dickens: A Life&lt;/em&gt;, Tomalin 2011, cited by McCrum&lt;/a&gt;): morning-afternoon (9AM-2PM)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then, as you go deeper into Tomalin, you discover that Dickens, in his prime, used to compress his literary energies into five hours, roughly 9am to 2pm, after which he would walk incessantly, and put his mind into neutral. He might return to what he’d written in the morning later in the evening, but those five hours held the key to his output.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;3.3546712802768&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert%20Frost&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Robert Frost&quot;&gt;Robert Frost&lt;/a&gt; (McCrum): afternoon-late evening (?-3AM)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robert Frost, whose remote Vermont cabin I visited recently in company with his biographer Jay Parini, never started work till the afternoon, and often stayed up till two or three in the morning, not rising until midday, or even later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;15.742089552239&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Winston%20Churchill&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Winston Churchill&quot;&gt;Winston Churchill&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.artofmanliness.com/2014/12/15/the-churchill-school-of-adulthood-lesson-2-establish-a-daily-routine/&quot;&gt;as cited to &lt;em&gt;The Last Lion&lt;/em&gt;, Manchester&lt;/a&gt;): morning+late evening (~11AM-1:15PM, 11PM-2AM)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;37.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once all the newspapers have been perused, it’s time to answer the enormous amount of mail Churchill receives each day. A secretary stands by as Churchill dictates (his preferred method of &lt;q&gt;writing&lt;/q&gt;) correspondence to private citizens and government officials. Once the mail is finished, it’s time to dictate memoranda and greet any visitors who have stopped by Chartwell. &lt;q&gt;He will receive anyone except the King in his bedchamber,&lt;/q&gt; and visitors are often tickled by the image which greets them; Vice Admiral Sir Douglas Brownrigg said he presented &lt;q&gt;a most extraordinary spectacle, perched up in a huge bed, with the whole of the counterpane littered with dispatch boxes, red and all colours, and a stenographer sitting at the foot - Mr. Churchill himself with an enormous Corona in his mouth.&lt;/q&gt; Churchill’s next task is to look through galley proofs of the latest book he’s working on, and ask his chief researcher to check and verify certain details. At this point, he often begins to work on his speeches. He paces the room, issuing phrase after phrase at a speed his secretaries have trouble keeping up with. Churchill, one of them recalls, would be &lt;q&gt;dashing around in shorts and undershirt and a bright red cummerbund while I trotted behind him from room to room with a pad and pencil struggling to keep pace with the torrential flow of words.&lt;/q&gt; This flow of masterful oratory increases as the wordsmith warms up and finds his groove; &lt;q&gt;By noon the cadences of his prose have begun to trot; by 1:00PM they are galloping.&lt;/q&gt; Lunch is at 1:15, so Churchill sets aside business and gets dressed to the nines (hence the aforementioned cummerbund)…Churchill believes his afternoon naps help him be much more productive. He has found that he can only produce good writing for a few hours at a stretch, before his brain gets tired and the quality diminishes. So by breaking up his schedule with a nap, he is able to have two creative working periods each day - one in the morning and one late at night - while also having time for socializing and duck feeding…The guests have gone home or retired to their bedrooms to stay over, Churchill begins his second working shift of the day. It’s 11:00 PM, and most of his fellow Englishmen are sleeping, but Churchill is rearing to go. He slips into something more comfortable and asks his aides to join him in the library:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His appearance heralded by the harff, harff of his slippers, he enters the room in his scarlet, green, and gold dressing gown, the cords trailing behind him. Before greeting his researcher and the two secretaries on duty tonight, he must read the manuscript he dictated the previous evening and then revise the latest galleys, which arrived a few hours earlier from London. Since Churchill’s squiggled red changes exceed the copy set - the proofs look as though several spiders stained in crimson ink wandered across the pages - his printers’ bills are shocking. But the expense is offset by his extraordinary fluency. Before the night is out, he will have dictated between four thousand and five thousand words. On weekends he may exceed ten thousand words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Churchill’s night usually ends around 2 am, but when there is extra work to be done, he may not retire until 3 or 4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;7.6047700170358&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Frank%20Herbert&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Frank Herbert&quot;&gt;Frank Herbert&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sinanvural.com/seksek/inien/tvd/tvd2.htm&quot;&gt;3 February 1969 interview with Willis McNelly&lt;/a&gt;): morning+evening (5PM-1AM and 5AM-7AM)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;19&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Willis McNelly&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;q&gt;What is your writing schedule?&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Frank Herbert&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;q&gt;Well, it varies…depends on what I’m doing…writing for the magazine…but as a general rule it goes like this: I’ll get home somewhere around 5 o’clock when Bev is here, when she’s not working as she has been the last couple of weeks. She’ll have dinner ready at that time or very close to that time. I’ll then take an hour’s nap and then work sometimes until 1 o’clock in the morning. Then I hit the sack and get up and sometimes if a story is strong in me I get up in the morning and write…get up at 5 o’clock in the morning or so and write for an hour or two sometimes before going down to San Francisco.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;WM&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;q&gt;Yes.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;FH&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;q&gt;And this is the thing I want to get out of because I can write 8 hours a day in 2 bursts and I don’t see any reason why I shouldn’t be doing what I want…writing what I want to write during those times. I don’t envision supporting myself entirely by science fiction writing in the sense of writing only science fiction, because I have other axes to grind, too.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;3.9138461538462&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Harry%20Harrison%20%28writer%29&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Harry Harrison (writer)&quot;&gt;Harry Harrison&lt;/a&gt; (McNelly interview with Frank Herbert): afternoon (12:30PM-5PM)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Willis McNelly&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;q&gt;It’s interesting…Harry Harrison describes the writing process with him rather well in a tape I made with him a few months ago. He is absolutely uninterruptible from, say, 12:30 in the afternoon ’til 5:00 at night, because the ideas as they form in his mind sort of becomes extensions of his [cough] excuse me, fingers in his typewriter and that they are up here and that …that any interruption, whether it be a telephone ringing or his wife knocking at the door or anything at all is liable to shatter that idea as it transforms itself into paper.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;4.6404494382022&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Toni%20Morrison&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Toni Morrison&quot;&gt;Toni Morrison&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/interviews/show/1029.Toni_Morrison&quot; title=&quot;Interview with Toni Morrison&quot;&gt;Goodreads interview&lt;/a&gt;): early morning (6AM-10AM?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Goodreads&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;q&gt;What’s your average writing day like? When do you write?&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Toni Morrison&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;q&gt;Very early in the morning, before the sun comes up. Because I’m very smart at that time of day. Now, at this time of day [4PM], it’s all drifting away. But tomorrow morning I will be sharp for about 4 hours, say from 6AM to 10AM. If I get up before the sun and greet it, that’s when I start.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;2.2371638141809&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chimamanda%20Ngozi%20Adichie&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Chimamanda Ngozi Adichie&quot;&gt;Chimamanda Ngozi Adichie&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/interviews/show/857.Chimamanda_Ngozi_Adichie&quot; title=&quot;Interview with Chimamanda Ngozi Adichie&quot;&gt;Goodreads interview&lt;/a&gt;): no particular time&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote the book in both Nigeria and the U.S. I don’t have a routine. I like silence and space whenever and wherever I can get it. When the writing is going well, I’m obsessive - I roll out of bed and go to work. I write and rewrite a lot and shut everything out. When it is not going well, I sink into a dark place and read books I love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;6.3783251231527&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Michael Connelly (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/interviews/show/1275.Michael_Connelly&quot;&gt;Goodreads interview&lt;/a&gt;): very early morning when possible (4AM-6AM? pre-dawn)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;18&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Goodreads&lt;/code&gt;: What’s your writing process?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Michael Connelly&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;q&gt;Because of working on a TV show [&lt;em&gt;Bosch&lt;/em&gt;], my writing process is to write whenever I get a chance. Also, my training in journalism has taught me to write - I don’t need to be coddled. I can write in my office, I can write on planes, I can write in cars. I was on a plane last night for five hours, squeezed in so tight, my elbows were pushing into my ribs, but I wrote the whole time and got a lot done. That’s my process: to try to write whenever I can. A perfect day would be to get up before the light gets up in the sky and start writing and get a lot done before the rest of the city wakes up. That’s what I try to do when I’m at home or even when I’m in a hotel on the road. Morning hours are really good for me, dark morning hours. So in that regard I kind of share something with Renée [&lt;em&gt;The Late Show&lt;/em&gt; character] because I like to work till dawn.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;29.151239958086&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stephenie%20Meyer&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Stephenie Meyer&quot;&gt;Stephenie Meyer&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/interviews/show/1189.Stephenie_Meyer&quot; title=&quot;Interview with Stephenie Meyer&quot;&gt;Goodreads interview&lt;/a&gt;): evening (8PM-?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;18&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Goodreads&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;q&gt;Do you have any writing rituals?&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Stephenie Meyer&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;q&gt;None, really, besides time of day. I can never get truly immersed in writing during the daytime. I know it’s a product of being interrupted by work calls and emails, children’s and husband’s questions about where fill-in-the-blank is located, and the dog’s bladder needs. Subconsciously my brain believes that there is no point in trying to focus when my office door is just about to slam open in three…two…one…. So now, even when I’m in a quiet, private environment, I can’t make my brain accept that it is possible to write while the sun is out. When I’m in the middle of a story, I do my self-editing during the day. That part handles interruptions better.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://entertainment.inquirer.net/86937/stephenie-meyer-recaps-twilight-journey&quot; title=&quot;Stephenie Meyer recaps 'Twilight' journey&quot;&gt;2013 interview&lt;/a&gt; clarifies that darkness means late night, not early morning pre-dawn:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That vivid scene took place in the kitchen but these days, she writes in an office room in her house. Like most writers, Stephenie prefers to write in the evening. &lt;q&gt;I write best at night, which is one of the reasons that I’m so slow now,&lt;/q&gt; she said. &lt;q&gt;My kids’ school schedule has forced me to be a morning person, which I am not. I don’t get so much done during the day. There are too many interruptions. It’s better if I can start at 8PM and work through till I pass out.&lt;/q&gt; Laughing, she quipped, &lt;q&gt;Maybe, I should move back into the kitchen.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://stepheniemeyer.com/the-story-of-twilight-getting-published/&quot; title=&quot;The Story Behind _Twilight_&quot;&gt;an autobiographical piece&lt;/a&gt;, Meyers says that the idea for &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Twilight%20%28Meyer%20novel%29&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Twilight (Meyer novel)&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Twilight&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; came in a dream &amp;amp; was initially written in the morning but the bulk was written at night:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;23&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I woke up (on that June 2nd) from a very vivid dream…Though I had a million things to do (i.e. making breakfast for hungry children, dressing and changing the diapers of said children, finding the swimsuits that no one ever puts away in the right place, etc.), I stayed in bed, thinking about the dream. I was so intrigued by the nameless couple’s story that I hated the idea of forgetting it; it was the kind of dream that makes you want to call your friend and bore her with a detailed description. (Also, the vampire was just so darned good-looking, that I didn’t want to lose the mental image.) Unwillingly, I eventually got up and did the immediate necessities, and then put everything that I possibly could on the back burner and sat down at the computer to write-something I hadn’t done in so long that I wondered why I was bothering. But I didn’t want to lose the dream, so I typed out as much as I could remember, calling the characters &lt;q&gt;he&lt;/q&gt; and &lt;q&gt;she.&lt;/q&gt; From that point on, not one day passed that I did not write &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt;. On bad days, I would only type out a page or two; on good days, I would finish a chapter and then some. I mostly wrote at night, after the kids were asleep so that I could concentrate for longer than five minutes without being interrupted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;2.7639593908629&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stephen%20King&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Stephen King&quot;&gt;Stephen King&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/interviews/show/989.Stephen_King&quot;&gt;Goodreads interview&lt;/a&gt;): morning (8AM-noon)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Goodreads&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;q&gt;What’s your average working day like? Do you have any unusual habits/rituals?&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Stephen King&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;q&gt;I start work around 8AM and usually finish around noon. If there’s more to do, I do it in the late afternoon, although that isn’t prime time for me. The only ritual is making tea. I use the loose leaves and drink it by the gallon.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;6.2478097622028&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paulo%20Coelho&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Paulo Coelho&quot;&gt;Paulo Coelho&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/interviews/show/971.Paulo_Coelho&quot;&gt;Goodreads interview&lt;/a&gt;): late evening? (?-4AM)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;18&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Goodreads&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;q&gt;Do you write as soon as you wake up in the morning?&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Paulo Coelho&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;q&gt;First I say that I’m going to write as soon as I wake up. Then I postpone and postpone and start feeling guilty and horrible and feel that I don’t deserve anything. Then I say, OK, today I’m not going to write. Then I write just to not feel guilty, and I’m going to write the first sentence. Then once I’m off the ground, the plane takes off…when I’m writing, I wake up around 12 o’clock because I write until 4 in the morning. Only two weeks. Then of course, I have to make the corrections and do another draft. I have to correct the second draft. So the first draft has, let’s say, one-third more pages than the final draft. So I start cutting.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;11.598971722365&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brandon%20Sanderson&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Brandon Sanderson&quot;&gt;Brandon Sanderson&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;http://faq.brandonsanderson.com/node/351&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt;): afternoon+late evening (noon-5PM, 8PM-3AM)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was in college, I got a job working the graveyard shift at a hotel, which was great for my writing because I was there most weeknights from 11 pm until 7 am, and the only requirements that they put me to were, &lt;q&gt;Just don’t fall asleep. Do whatever you want, just don’t fall asleep. We need you awake in case there’s an emergency or if anyone comes in.&lt;/q&gt; I ended up spending a lot of my time working on novels during those early morning hours, and that’s how I was able to pay for school, attend it full-time, and still have time for writing. I still do most of my writing in the middle of the night…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theoryland.com/intvmain.php?i=740&quot;&gt;2012 chat interview&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sanderson works best at night. &lt;q&gt;I get up about noon,&lt;/q&gt; he says, &lt;q&gt;write until five, and then spend a few hours with the family before starting work again about eight o’clock and then I write until the early morning hours. I often don’t get to bed before three am.&lt;/q&gt; He did try getting up at what most people would consider to be a more normal hour, but after a few weeks his wife capitulated, saying, &lt;q&gt;This routine is making you miserable. Go back to being a night owl!&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;5.3924897119342&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Margaret Atwood (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/interviews/show/990.Margaret_Atwood&quot;&gt;Goodreads interview&lt;/a&gt;): morning-afternoon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Goodreads&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;q&gt;Can you describe a typical day spent writing?&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Margaret Atwood&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;q&gt;There are no typical days spent writing. Let’s pretend there is one. I would get up. We would have breakfast. Then we have the coffee. That is something I really like to have to get myself started. Then I would probably sit down and type something that I had written in manuscript the day before. It’s a kind of overlap method, in which I’m typing out what I did the day before to get myself going for what I’m going to add on to that. I’m revising and then continuing to write in the same day. Then I do the next bit of new writing in the afternoon. I don’t go by how much time I spent at it but how many pages I managed to complete.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Goodreads&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;q&gt;Would you say you have any unusual writing habits?&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Margaret Atwood&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;q&gt;I’m not particularly obsessive about that. But I don’t like other people using my computer. Who does like that?&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;13.483757682177&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saint-Exupéry, in writing &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The%20Little%20Prince%23Tone%20and%20writing%20style&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: The Little Prince#Tone and writing style&quot;&gt;The Little Prince&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; preferred evenings, starting at 11PM, or even later, as described by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.trussel.com/saint-ex/galant.htm&quot;&gt;Lewis Galantière in 1947&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;23&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saint-Exupéry wrote beautifully, but at the price of great effort. He went out rarely, but he had friends in almost every day to lunch and dinner. In the evening, when his friends had gone, he would brew himself a great pot of coffee and sit down to work at his dining table (his desk served merely as a catchall in which his checkbook could never be found). Now and then he would write in an all-night restaurant, where, having eaten a dish of raw chopped beef drowned in olive oil and crusted with pepper, be was likely to scribble from 2 in the morning until dawn. When be had written himself stiff, be would stretch out at home on a sofa under a lamp, take up the mouthpiece of a dictaphone, and record his copy, revising as he went along. Then, towards 7 or 8 o’clock in the morning, he would go to bed. The secretary would come in at 9 and type while be slept. Often, when friends arrived for lunch at 1 o’clock, they would ring and pound for 20 minutes before he woke up and let them in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neil%20Gaiman&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Neil Gaiman&quot;&gt;Neil Gaiman&lt;/a&gt; is described as a night owl (eg collaborators interviewed in &lt;em&gt;Conversations With the Dream King&lt;/em&gt; describe him as phoning them usually late at night or as a &lt;q&gt;vampire&lt;/q&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;6.7678391959799&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John%20Irving&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: John Irving&quot;&gt;John Irving&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theparisreview.org/interviews/2757/john-irving-the-art-of-fiction-no-93-john-irving&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Paris Review&lt;/em&gt; interview&lt;/a&gt;) appears to write mostly in the morning to afternoon:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;19&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A novel is such a long involvement; when I’m beginning a book, I can’t work more than two or three hours a day. I don’t know more than two or three hours a day about a new novel. Then there’s the middle of a book. I can work eight, nine, twelve hours then, seven days a week - if my children let me; they usually don’t. One luxury of making enough money to support myself as a writer is that I can afford to have those eight-, nine-, and twelve-hour days. I resented having to teach and coach, not because I disliked teaching or coaching or wrestling but because I had no time to write. Ask a doctor to be a doctor two hours a day. An eight-hour day at the typewriter is easy; and two hours of reading over material in the evening, too. That’s routine. Then when the time to finish the book comes, it’s back to those two- and three-hour days. Finishing, like beginning, is more careful work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;0.95925925925926&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theparisreview.org/blog/2018/08/08/notes-nearing-ninety-learning-to-write-less/&quot; title=&quot;Notes Nearing Ninety: Learning to Write Less&quot;&gt;Donald Hall&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back then, I wrote all day, getting up at five. By this time, I rise scratchy at six or twitch in bed until seven. I drink coffee before I pick up a pen. I look through the newspaper. I try to write all morning, but exhaustion shuts me down by ten o’clock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;5.9324462640737&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hunter%20Thompson&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Hunter Thompson&quot;&gt;Hunter Thompson&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://mentalfloss.com/article/33487/hunter-s-thompsons-daily-routine&quot;&gt;Carroll’s biography&lt;/a&gt; includes a supposed daily schedule where Thompson starts writing at midnight until 6AM (but the schedule is so clearly exaggerated &amp;amp; humorous in the level of drug use claimed that I don’t know how seriously to take any of it); one of his editors, &lt;a href=&quot;https://lithub.com/so-youve-decide-to-write-what-i-learned-editing-hunter-s-thompson/&quot;&gt;Terry McDonnell&lt;/a&gt; says &lt;q&gt;When he got you on the phone in the middle of the night to listen to someone in his kitchen read to you what he had just written, all you could say was that it sounded good and that he should send it to you&lt;/q&gt;; a collection of letters includes him &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.signature-reads.com/2018/07/hunter-s-thompson-sanity-writers/&quot;&gt;telling a landlady to put down carpets so his typing late at night won’t keep her up&lt;/a&gt;; his &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theparisreview.org/interviews/619/hunter-s-thompson-the-art-of-journalism-no-1-hunter-s-thompson&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Paris Review&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; interviewer describes him as keeping late hours on &lt;q&gt;Owl Farm&lt;/q&gt; and the interview went into the night, where he describes his first writing job as having the advantage of letting him write entirely at night. All together, there’s no doubt Thompson preferred late night, and midnight-6AM specifically does seem plausible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section id=&quot;external-links&quot; class=&quot;level1&quot;&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 09:07:10 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jxub</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.gwern.net/Morning-writing</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Housing can’t both be a good investment and be affordable</title>
<link>http://cityobservatory.org/housing-cant-be-affordable_and_be-a-good-investment/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://cityobservatory.org/housing-cant-be-affordable_and_be-a-good-investment/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A fundamental contradiction lies beneath most of our housing policy debates&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;At City Observatory, we’ve frequently &lt;a href=&quot;http://cityobservatory.org/homeownership-can-exacerbate-inequality/&quot;&gt;made&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://cityobservatory.org/homeownership-a-failed-wealth-creation-strategy/&quot;&gt;the case&lt;/a&gt; that promoting homeownership as an investment strategy is a risky proposition. No financial advisor would recommend going into debt in order to put such a massive part of your savings in any other single financial instrument—and one that, as we learned just a few years ago, carries a great deal of risk.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Even worse, that risk isn’t random: It falls most heavily on low-income, black, and Hispanic buyers, who are given worse mortgage terms, and whose neighborhoods are systematically more likely to see low or even falling home values, with devastating effects on the racial wealth gap.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;But let’s put all that aside for a moment. What if housing&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;were&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;a low-risk, can’t-miss bet for growing your personal wealth? What would that world look like?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Well, in order for your home to offer you a real profit, its price would need to increase faster than the rate of inflation. Let’s pick something decent, but not too crazy—say, annual increases of 2.5 percent, taking inflation into account. So if you bought a home for $200,000 and sold it ten years later, you’d be looking at a healthy profit of just over $56,000.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Sound good? Well, what if I told you that such a city existed? What if I told you it was in a beautiful natural setting, with hills and views of the ocean? And a booming economy? And lots of organic produce?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/otolithe/2241690292/in/photolist-4q6fqC-b6FVfD-eUcDoN-gHEHs-r6YMmE-mQjN7i-abigRk-wS7pFF-btG3uS-skiDQA-ex6mwr-mMULyD-9qb3U3-HbtCbX-ntADcs-967ktA-by84f2-E47bZs-4fbu38-aPq48M-7KiNFB-eNfNcL-4tDJ7J-b7HmjZ-c19dku-b9NGQ4-oiNog-G4oxfZ-ax1vSy-9qySWt-s1KQAh-8D5f6w-bNQKrD-5TTbt5-bLNVaR-bzqxbU-xcxTxV-7U64ZE-qbXBJy-Ecaiho-jAQenG-kppUf-dNoXM5-fkDJe-hUtGLi-4X6kq9-bvtjvR-F98iZ6-diR2Tc-9rRADb&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-2848&quot; src=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/cityobservatory.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/2241690292_bdf4d335b4_b.jpg?resize=640%2C480&quot; alt=&quot;Credit: Olivier ROUX, Flickr&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; srcset=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/cityobservatory.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/2241690292_bdf4d335b4_b.jpg?w=1024 1024w, https://i1.wp.com/cityobservatory.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/2241690292_bdf4d335b4_b.jpg?resize=300%2C225 300w, https://i1.wp.com/cityobservatory.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/2241690292_bdf4d335b4_b.jpg?resize=768%2C576 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Credit: Olivier ROUX, Flickr
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Maybe you’ve guessed by now: The wonderland of ever-increasing housing prices is San Francisco. When researcher&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://cityobservatory.org/the-long-road-to-san-francisco/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Eric Fischer went back to construct a database of rental prices&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;there, he found that rents had been growing by about 2.5 percent, net of inflation, for about 60 years. And&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.economist.com/blogs/graphicdetail/2015/11/daily-chart-0&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;this Zillow data suggests&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;that San Francisco owner-occupied home prices have been growing by just over 2.5 percent since 1980 as well.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Like I said, over ten years, that gives you a profit of just over 25 percent. But compound interest is an amazing thing, and the longer this consistent wealth-building goes on, the more out of hand housing prices get. In 1980, Zillow’s home price index for San Francisco home prices was about $310,000 (in 2015 dollars). By 2015, after 35 years of averaging 2.5 percent growth, home prices were over $750,000.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-2851&quot; src=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/cityobservatory.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/Screen-Shot-2016-07-19-at-9.46.59-PM.png?resize=592%2C480&quot; alt=&quot;Screen Shot 2016-07-19 at 9.46.59 PM&quot; width=&quot;592&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; srcset=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/cityobservatory.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/Screen-Shot-2016-07-19-at-9.46.59-PM.png?w=592 592w, https://i1.wp.com/cityobservatory.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/Screen-Shot-2016-07-19-at-9.46.59-PM.png?resize=300%2C243 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 592px) 100vw, 592px&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Now, if all you cared about were wealth building, this would be fantastic news. The system works! (Although actually even this rosy scenario is missing some wrinkles: San Francisco real estate prices did suffer enormously, if briefly, during the late-2000s crash, and if you bought in the mid-2000s and had to sell in, say, 2010, you would have taken a massive loss.)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;But this sort of wealth building is predicated on a never-ending stream of new people who are willing and able to pay current home owners increasingly absurd amounts of money for their homes. It is, in other words, a massive up-front transfer of wealth from younger people to older people, on the implicit promise that when those young people become old, there will be new young people willing to give them even&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;more&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;money. And of course, as prices rise, the only young people able to buy into this ponzi scheme are quite well-to-do themselves. And because we’re not talking about stocks, but homes, “buying into this ponzi scheme” means “able to live in San Francisco.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In other words, possibly the only thing worse than a world in which homeownership doesn’t work as a wealth-building tool is a world in which it does work as a wealth-building tool.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;This also means that the two stated pillars of American housing policy—homeownership as wealth-building and housing affordability—are fundamentally at odds. Mostly, American housing policy resolves this contradiction by quietly deciding that it really doesn’t care that much about affordability after all. While funds for low-income subsidized housing languish, much larger pots of money are set aside for promoting homeownership through subsidies like the mortgage interest deduction and capital gains exemption, most of which goes to upper-middle- or upper-class households.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;But even markets with large amounts of affordable housing demonstrate the contradiction. Since at least the second half of the 20th century, the vast majority of actually affordable housing has been created via&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://cityobservatory.org/what-filtering-can-and-cant-do/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;“filtering”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;: that is, the falling relative prices of market-rate housing as it ages, or its neighborhood loses social status, often as a result of racial changes. Low-income affordability, where it does exist, is predicated on large portions of the housing market acting as terrible investments.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;And to the extent that low-income people do find a subsidized, price-fixed housing unit to live in, that means that they won’t be building any wealth, even as their richer, market-housing-dwelling neighbors do, increasing wealth inequality.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Even the community land trust, which seems to be a way of squaring the wealth-building/affordability circle, ultimately fails. Community land trusts typically provide subsidized or reduced price ownership opportunities to initial buyers, and assure longer term affordability by limiting the resale price of the home. In other words, CLT-financed homes remain affordable only because they restrict how much wealth building the initial owners are allowed to capture. The result is that CLT-financed homes&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/local/flawed-dc-housing-program-sticks-developer-with-2-unsold-condos-for-3-years/2014/11/01/47fbdaf0-6154-11e4-8b9e-2ccdac31a031_story.html&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;only attract those who couldn’t otherwise purchase a home&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;—which means that the lower-income people in CLTs will be building wealth more slowly than higher-income people in market-rate housing, a fundamentally inequality-increasing situation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We say we want housing to be cheap and we want home ownership to be a great financial investment. Until we realize that these two objectives are mutually exclusive, we’ll continue to be frustrated by failed and oftentimes counterproductive housing policies.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 23:49:02 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>DoreenMichele</dc:creator>
<og:title>City Observatory - Housing can’t both be a good investment and be affordable</og:title>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>http://cityobservatory.org/housing-cant-be-affordable_and_be-a-good-investment/</og:url>
<og:image>http://cityobservatory.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/8885270785_63a210196a_h.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>The City Observatory is a study of modern-day cities and urban development practices.</og:description>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://cityobservatory.org/housing-cant-be-affordable_and_be-a-good-investment/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Thelio – System76</title>
<link>https://system76.com/desktops</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://system76.com/desktops</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Thelio Shells&quot; src=&quot;https://system76.com/assets/assets/thelio/page/pricelist-bg_640.jpg&quot; type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot; data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;summaries&quot; data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot; readability=&quot;13.073529411765&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;theio title&quot; data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;Thelio&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Thelio Motherboard&quot; src=&quot;https://system76.com/assets/assets/thelio/page/thelio-mb-regular_640.jpg&quot; type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot; data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;ul class=&quot;thelio specs&quot; data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;li data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;Ryzen or Core CPUs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;Up to 32GB of Memory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;Radeon or GeForce GPUs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;Up to 24TB of Storage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;Space-Saving Design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;$1,099&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;Pre-Order now!&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;Shipments begin early December&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;major title&quot; data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;Thelio Major&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Thelio Major Motherboard&quot; src=&quot;https://system76.com/assets/assets/thelio/page/thelio-mb-major_640.jpg&quot; type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot; data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;ul class=&quot;major specs&quot; data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;li data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;Threadripper or Core-X CPUs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;Up to 128GB of Memory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;Up to 4 GPUs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;Up to 46TB of Storage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;Maximum Configurability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;$2,299&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;Pre-Order now!&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;Shipments begin early December&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;massive title&quot; data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;Thelio Massive&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Thelio Massive Motherboard&quot; src=&quot;https://system76.com/assets/assets/thelio/page/thelio-mb-massive_640.jpg&quot; type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot; data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;ul class=&quot;massive specs&quot; data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;li data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;Dual XEON CPUs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;Up to 768GB of ECC Memory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;Up to 4 GPUs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;Up to 86TB of Storage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;Epitome of performance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;$2,899&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;Pre-Order now!&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 data-v-c9850d44=&quot;&quot;&gt;Shipments begin late December&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 data-v-646c34ae=&quot;&quot;&gt;Easily Expandable&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot; data-v-646c34ae=&quot;&quot;&gt;Tinker to your heart’s desire. Thelio systems are created for you to customize with ease. Slip in drives, add memory, upgrade graphics cards. Add your own personal touch and make your computer feel like it’s really, truly yours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;button&quot; data-v-646c34ae=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Easily Expandable&quot; src=&quot;https://system76.com/assets/assets/thelio/page/expandable-video_640.jpg&quot; type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot; data-v-646c34ae=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Play Icon&quot; src=&quot;data:image/svg+xml;base64,PHN2ZyBpZD0icGxheS1pY29uIiB2ZXJzaW9uPSIxLjEiIHZpZXdCb3g9IjAgMCAxNTAgMTUwIiB4bWxucz0iaHR0cDovL3d3dy53My5vcmcvMjAwMC9zdmciPgogIDxwYXRoIGlkPSJjaXJjbGUiIGQ9Im03NSAwYy00MS40MDggMC03NSAzMy41OS03NSA3NSAwIDQxLjQxIDMzLjU5IDc1IDc1IDc1IDQxLjQwOCAwIDc1LTMzLjU5IDc1LTc1IDAtNDEuNDEtMzMuNTktNzUtNzUtNzV6bTAgMi4wODc0YzQwLjI4IDAgNzIuOTEgMzIuNjMxIDcyLjkxIDcyLjkxIDAgNDAuMjc5LTMyLjYzMSA3Mi45MS03Mi45MSA3Mi45MS00MC4yOCAwLTcyLjkxLTMyLjYzMS03Mi45MS03Mi45MSAwLTQwLjI3OSAzMi42MzEtNzIuOTEgNzIuOTEtNzIuOTF6IiBzdHlsZT0iZmlsbDojZmZmIi8+CiAgPHBhdGggaWQ9InRyaWFuZ2xlIiBkPSJtNTYuNDY1IDEwNy4wN3YtNjQuMTIzbDU1LjUzIDMyLjA2MXoiIHN0eWxlPSJmaWxsOiNmZmYiLz4KPC9zdmc+Cg==&quot; class=&quot;icon&quot; data-v-646c34ae=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Pop!_OS overview layers&quot; src=&quot;https://system76.com/assets/assets/thelio/page/thumbnail-monitor_640.jpg&quot; type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot; data-v-47f87702=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;div data-v-47f87702=&quot;&quot; readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 data-v-47f87702=&quot;&quot;&gt;Perfect with Pop!_OS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot; data-v-47f87702=&quot;&quot;&gt;Pop!_OS by System76 and Thelio together form the perfect platform to create and discover. Thelio is optimized for maximum performance. Pop!_OS provides tools and development platforms that are always up-to-date and just a single click or command away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot; data-v-47f87702=&quot;&quot;&gt;Write software. Build robots. Train AI models. Dev those ops. Frag your Steam friends on the side! Have fun making a better world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Thelio IO board&quot; src=&quot;https://system76.com/assets/assets/thelio/page/thumbnail-thelio-io_640.jpg&quot; type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot; data-v-47f87702=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;div data-v-47f87702=&quot;&quot; readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 data-v-47f87702=&quot;&quot;&gt;Optimized by Thelio Io&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot; data-v-47f87702=&quot;&quot;&gt;Thelio Io is a System76 designed chassis controller and hard drive backplane that moves proprietary functionality from the mainboard to the open source Thelio Io daughterboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot; data-v-47f87702=&quot;&quot;&gt;Moving chassis and thermal control to Thelio Io enables far more granular performance optimization. Motherboard data, fan speed, and GPU and OS data are used to coordinate optimal airflow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot; data-v-47f87702=&quot;&quot;&gt;Thelio Massive also includes an open source System76 designed SAS backplane for high performance 2.5” PCIe storage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Unleash with tux&quot; src=&quot;https://system76.com/assets/assets/thelio/page/thumbnail-tux_640.jpg&quot; type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot; data-v-47f87702=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;div data-v-47f87702=&quot;&quot; readability=&quot;19.399624765478&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 data-v-47f87702=&quot;&quot;&gt;Open hardware licensed to give you rights&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot; data-v-47f87702=&quot;&quot;&gt;Thelio, Thelio Major, Thelio Massive, and Thelio Io are OSHWA certified open source hardware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot; data-v-47f87702=&quot;&quot;&gt;Licensed under GPL v3 and CC-BY-SA, everyone can learn from what we've created, adapt it, improve it, and make derivative works inspired by the Thelio design. We hope Thelio can be a spark for open source hardware, just as GNU and Linux were the sparks that forever changed the way software was developed and shared nearly three decades ago. Thelio and Thelio Io design files are &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/system76/thelio&quot; data-v-47f87702=&quot;&quot;&gt;hosted on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d1vhcvzji58n1j.cloudfront.net/assets/v3/img/us-flag.bf68c63.svg&quot; class=&quot;flag&quot; data-v-0e1d6ed1=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;h2 data-v-0e1d6ed1=&quot;&quot;&gt;Designed and Manufactured in Colorado&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot; data-v-0e1d6ed1=&quot;&quot;&gt;US-sourced wood and aluminum are formed, finished, etched, and built by artisans in our Denver, Colorado factory. Premium components from around the world are then assembled to your final specifications. And to offset environmental impact, &lt;strong data-v-0e1d6ed1=&quot;&quot;&gt;every Thelio sold plants a tree with the National Forest Foundation&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot; data-v-0e1d6ed1=&quot;&quot;&gt;We back Thelio with a 30-day money back guarantee, lifetime technical support, free two-year hardware warranty, and rapid software updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Colorado Mountains&quot; src=&quot;https://system76.com/assets/assets/thelio/page/colorado-bg_640.jpg&quot; type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot; data-v-0e1d6ed1=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 22:52:41 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>secure</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://system76.com/</og:url>
<og:title>Thelio</og:title>
<og:description>Thelio Desktops boast an arsenal of components for maximum configurability to achieve the epitome of performance. System76 computers are custom-built to run Linux flawlessly.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://system76.com/desktops</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>New antimatter gravity experiments begin at CERN</title>
<link>https://home.cern/about/updates/2018/11/new-antimatter-gravity-experiments-begin-cern</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://home.cern/about/updates/2018/11/new-antimatter-gravity-experiments-begin-cern</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;We learn it at high school: release two objects of different mass in the absence of friction forces and they fall down at the same rate in Earth’s gravity. What we haven’t learned, because it hasn’t been directly measured in experiments, is whether &lt;a href=&quot;https://home.cern/topics/antimatter&quot;&gt;antimatter&lt;/a&gt; falls down at the same rate as ordinary matter or if it might behave differently. Two new experiments at CERN, ALPHA-g and GBAR, have now started their journey towards answering this question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ALPHA-g is very similar to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://home.cern/about/experiments/alpha&quot;&gt;ALPHA experiment&lt;/a&gt;, which makes neutral antihydrogen atoms by taking antiprotons from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://home.cern/about/accelerators/antiproton-decelerator&quot;&gt;Antiproton Decelerator&lt;/a&gt; (AD) and binding them with positrons from a sodium-22 source. ALPHA then confines the resulting neutral antihydrogen atoms in a magnetic trap and shines laser light or microwaves onto them to measure their internal structure. The ALPHA-g experiment has the same type of apparatus for making and trapping antiatoms, except that it is oriented vertically. With this vertical set-up, researchers can precisely measure the vertical positions at which the antihydrogen atoms annihilate with normal matter once they switch off the trap’s magnetic field and the atoms are under the sole influence of gravity. The values of these positions will allow them to measure the effect of gravity on the antiatoms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The GBAR experiment, also located in the AD hall, takes a different tack. It plans to use antiprotons supplied by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://home.cern/about/updates/2016/11/new-ring-slow-down-antimatter&quot;&gt;ELENA deceleration ring&lt;/a&gt; and positrons produced by a small &lt;a href=&quot;https://home.cern/tags/linear-accelerator&quot;&gt;linear accelerator&lt;/a&gt; to make antihydrogen ions, consisting of one antiproton and two positrons. Next, after trapping the antihydrogen ions and chilling them to an ultralow temperature (about 10 microkelvin), it will use laser light to strip them of one positron, turning them into neutral antiatoms. At this point, the neutral antiatoms will be released from the trap and allowed to fall from a height of 20 centimetres, during which the researchers will monitor their behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After months of round-the-clock work by researchers and engineers to put together the experiments, ALPHA-g and GBAR have received the first beams of antiprotons, marking the beginning of both experiments. ALPHA-g began taking beam on 30 October, after receiving the necessary safety approvals. ELENA sent its first beam to GBAR on 20 July, and since then the decelerator and GBAR researchers have been trying to perfect the delivery of the beam. The ALPHA-g and GBAR teams are now racing to commission their experiments before CERN’s accelerators shut down in a few weeks for a two-year period of maintenance work. Jeffrey Hangst, spokesperson of the ALPHA experiments, says: “We are hoping that we’ll get the chance to make the first gravity measurements with antimatter, but it’s a race against time”. Patrice Pérez, spokesperson of GBAR, says: “The GBAR experiment is using an entirely new apparatus and an antiproton beam still in its commissioning phase. We hope to produce antihydrogen this year and are working towards being ready to measure the gravitational effects on antimatter when the antiprotons are back in 2021”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another experiment at the AD hall, AEgIS, which has been in operation for several years, is also working towards measuring the effect of gravity on antihydrogen using yet &lt;a href=&quot;https://home.cern/about/experiments/aegis&quot;&gt;another approach&lt;/a&gt;. Like GBAR, AEgIS is also hoping to produce its first antihydrogen atoms this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discovering any difference between the behaviour of antimatter and matter in connection with gravity could point to a quantum theory of gravity and perhaps cast light on why the universe seems to be made of matter rather than antimatter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/0bgyi4skk9s?rel=0&quot; width=&quot;560&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jeffrey Hangst at the Antiproton Decelerator hall, explaining the ALPHA-g set-up in the run-up to the start of the experiment. (Video: Jacques Fichet/CERN)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 21:19:05 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>lainon</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://home.cern/about/updates/2018/11/new-antimatter-gravity-experiments-begin-cern</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Goldman Sachs Ensnarled in Vast 1MDB Fraud Scandal</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/01/business/goldman-sachs-malaysia-investment-fund.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/01/business/goldman-sachs-malaysia-investment-fund.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;css-18sbwfn StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Goldman Sachs is facing one of the most significant scandals in its history, a multibillion-dollar international fraud that investigators say was masterminded by a flamboyant financier with a taste for Hollywood and carried out with help from the Wall Street firm’s bankers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Federal prosecutors on Thursday unveiled a guilty plea from one former Goldman Sachs banker and announced bribery and money laundering charges against a second banker, as part of an investigation into the alleged embezzlement of billions of dollars from a state-run investment fund in Malaysia. Prosecutors also brought charges against the Malaysian businessman they believe stole some of the money: Jho Low, who spent millions of dollars on gifts to celebrities like the actor Leonardo DiCaprio and the model Miranda Kerr.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The money was used to buy a Picasso painting, diamond necklaces and Birkin bags as well as to pay for the Hollywood blockbuster “The Wolf of Wall Street.” Najib Razak, the Malaysian prime minister who established and oversaw the so-called sovereign wealth fund, lost his re-election bid over the scandal, in which American prosecutors said $731 million of the missing money was deposited into his own bank accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The charges against senior employees of a major American bank, a rare move in the decade since the financial crisis, put enormous pressure on Goldman Sachs and its new chief executive, David M. Solomon. American prosecutors are continuing to investigate other bankers and Goldman itself, according to three people with knowledge of the matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;css-18sbwfn StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The bank has spent years trying to rehabilitate a reputation that was severely damaged by allegations of misconduct and putting profits ahead of clients during the financial crisis. Goldman executives today take pains to emphasize the good that their bank does in societies around the world — efforts that could be eroded by the bank’s role in the sprawling Malaysian scandal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The lengthy court filings by prosecutors in Brooklyn paint an ugly picture for Goldman, which was instrumental in raising money for the fund, 1Malaysia Development Berhad, or 1MDB. According to court documents, the former bankers paid bribes and kickbacks to foreign leaders to secure $6 billion in bond underwriting deals for Goldman that generated $600 million in fees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The authorities said that at least one high-ranking executive in the bank’s Asian operations was aware of the scheme, which dodged Goldman’s systems to detect the payment of bribes. That person, unidentified in the court filings, has not been charged. According to three people familiar with the matter, the executive was Andrea Vella, who was the co-head of Goldman’s Asian investment banking business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Federal prosecutors said Tim Leissner, a former Goldman investment banker who spent years courting Mr. Low, pleaded guilty in August to taking part in the bribery and money laundering scheme. He left the firm in 2016 after the scandal first emerged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The court filings were sealed until Thursday when the two other men, Mr. Low and Roger Ng, Mr. Leissner’s former deputy, were charged. Mr. Ng, who left Goldman in 2014, was arrested in Malaysia; Mr. Low remains at large.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-18sbwfn StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Although the bank knew Mr. Leissner was at the center of the investigation, the breadth of the charges appeared to have caught Goldman off guard. The bank was not expecting a leader of its Asian investment bank to be implicated as well. Goldman on Thursday suspended Mr. Vella, according to a person with direct knowledge but was not authorized to speak publicly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Goldman has repeatedly played down its role in the 1MDB scandal, saying it was unaware of how money from the fund was being used. The company said in a statement that it was cooperating with the investigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Goldman’s chairman, Lloyd Blankfein, sought to frame the matter as the misdeeds of rogue employees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“These are guys who evaded our safeguards, and lie, stuff like that’s going to happen,” Mr. Blankfein said on the sidelines of The New York Times DealBook conference on Thursday. “Somebody’s going to use phones away from us, and personal this and personal that,” he said, referring to personal devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Federal prosecutors have depicted Mr. Low as the mastermind of the scheme to loot the Malaysian sovereign wealth fund. During one exchange with Mr. Leissner, Mr. Low advised of the need to “suck up to” 1MDB officials, including sending “cakes” — that is to say, bribes, according to government filings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Court filings unsealed on Thursday showed that federal prosecutors have built out their case since they first filed charges against Mr. Leissner in June. Back then, the charges did not contain any reference to the co-conspirator identified by people familiar with the matter as Mr. Vella. But the court documents associated with Mr. Leissner’s plea on Aug. 28 do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;According to that filing, the co-conspirator identified separately as Mr. Vella agreed with Mr. Leissner and Mr. Ng, in a 2012 meeting, to keep Goldman’s compliance department in the dark about the scheme to bribe government officials to secure financing for a deal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“This looks pretty terrible and a far cry from post-financial crisis settlements,” said Alex Turnbull, the son of the former Australian prime minister, Malcolm Turnbull, and a former Goldman Sachs employee in Singapore who raised concerns about how Goldman valued the bond deals in 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-18sbwfn StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Vella could not be reached for comment. He has retained a lawyer, according to three people familiar with the case, but those people declined to identify the lawyer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Court papers filed by federal prosecutors describe a long-running scheme begun in 2009 by the Goldman bankers to conceal Mr. Low’s involvement in the fund’s businesses and the money paid out on his advice. Those bribes and kickbacks helped secure business for the bank while a group of people with close ties to the former Malaysian prime minister &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/06/16/world/asia/1mdb-malaysia-najib-razak.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;stole from some of the bond proceeds&lt;/a&gt; to fuel their lavish lifestyles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Prosecutors contend that the bankers had to conceal Mr. Low’s unofficial involvement in the fund because the Goldman’s legal team had concerns about the source of his wealth. Mr. Leissner and other Goldman bankers helped 1MDB raise money through three bond issues while making hundreds of millions of dollars in commissions. During each deal, Mr. Leissner followed Mr. Low’s directions about whom to bribe to win contracts for bond issues that were internally nicknamed “Project Magnolia,” “Project Maximus” and “Project Catalyze.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The money raised was supposed to be spent on projects to help the Malaysian people like those described in the deals’ financing documents. Instead, the court filings describe an elaborate plan to funnel millions of dollars of bond proceeds to so-called shell companies controlled by Mr. Low and others. Some of the money went into bank accounts in Hong Kong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Internal emails, included in the court documents, show that Mr. Leissner and his team referred to one of the bank’s earliest proposed deals with the Malaysians as “Project Tiara.” Among the luxury goods Malaysian authorities eventually seized because they had been purchased with money from 1MDB: 14 diamond-studded tiaras.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Until recently, public attention toward the scandal focused mainly on where that money ended up. Federal prosecutors in Los Angeles &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2016/07/21/world/asia/1mdb-malaysia-us-assets-seized.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;have filed multiple civil suits&lt;/a&gt; to recoup assets bought with some of the money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;According to those lawsuits, Mr. Najib’s wife, Rosmah Mansor, received $30 million worth of jewelry bought with money originating from 1MDB, including a 22-carat pink diamond necklace worth $27.3 million alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-18sbwfn StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Leissner also kept some of the funds for himself, according to the authorities. In pleading guilty, he was ordered to forfeit nearly $44 million that he earned from scheme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Leissner’s lawyer did not return a request for comment. It was not known who was representing Mr. Ng.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;A spokesman for Mr. Low said Mr. Low was innocent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“As noted in the indictment today, Mr. Low held no formal position at 1MDB, nor was he ever employed by Goldman Sachs,” the spokesman, Jim Haggerty, said. He added, “Furthermore, the bond offerings detailed in the indictment were undertaken openly and lawfully between experienced, well-regulated financial institutions and government entities.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The fraud led Malaysian voters to oust Mr. Najib in May; prosecutors there brought corruption charges against him in July. The new prime minister, Mahathir Mohamad, has moved quickly to investigate. The Malaysian government is &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/06/14/business/1mdb-malaysia-goldman-sachs.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;seeking restitution from Goldman Sachs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 19:33:42 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>SREinSF</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/01/business/goldman-sachs-malaysia-investment-fund.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Goldman Sachs Ensnarled in Vast 1MDB Fraud Scandal</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/11/02/us/02goldman/02goldman-facebookJumbo-v3.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>The filing of federal charges could increase pressure on Goldman, the primary bond underwriter for the development fund at the center of the so-called 1MDB scandal.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/01/business/goldman-sachs-malaysia-investment-fund.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A Heretic&amp;#039;s Guide to Deplatforming</title>
<link>https://easydns.com/blog/2018/11/02/a-heretics-guide-to-deplatforming/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://easydns.com/blog/2018/11/02/a-heretics-guide-to-deplatforming/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-16588&quot; src=&quot;https://easydns.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/burned_at_the_stake.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;437&quot; srcset=&quot;https://easydns.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/burned_at_the_stake.jpg 600w, https://easydns.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/burned_at_the_stake-300x219.jpg 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;[&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; Ironically, after ascending rapidly and fostering vigorous commentary over on Hackernews, this article has been &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18365851&quot;&gt;“flagged” there&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update #2:&lt;/strong&gt; A few hours later it was unflagged and is currently on the first page of HN ]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The phenomenon of deplatforming in the internet age, which includes the component of publicly expressed outrage that impels companies to act to remove objectionable content, provides ample fodder for getting all kinds of things wrong against the backdrop of people wanting to put things right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To that end I see three distinct themes around it:&lt;span id=&quot;more-17255&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;We run the risk that the act of deplatforming can become as extreme as the hate speech it seeks to banish.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While it’s within the purview of every private (and by that I mean non-governmental) company to do it, those who do typically undermine their own long term interests. And,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On our present course, we’re headed for a balkanized social media landscape&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;The idea of mobilizing public support, usually just raw emotion, and channeling it toward denying service or infrastructure to something deemed undesirable has taken on an almost macabre element in this day and age. The problem with deplatforming is nobody can give you an objective, rule-of-thumb based guideline that can answer the question&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;“Where does it stop?”&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&quot;https://easydns.com/blog/2018/10/29/axisofeasy-nevermind-television-screen-time-is-rotting-your-kids-brains/&quot;&gt;latest issue of #AxisOfEasy&lt;/a&gt; I mentioned the recent deplatforming of Gab and offhandedly asked readers to reply back to me if they had any thoughts around it. The responses I’ve gotten were all, in depth, long, thoughtful, considered and rational. I’d like to quote one at length:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;26&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“the lines are getting blurrier and blurrier. When we hold someone socially accountable for something they say, or some idea they espouse – and we do so by way of silencing them or terminating services of any kind to them, a few things happen. First, we may be seen as exercising our own right to freely speak (and sure, why not?). Second, we haven’t turned that mind around and instead driving the thing underground (where it can and does continue to fester). Third, we willfully and purposefully exercise an act of control over someone else – an act that in actuality we may or may not have a right to. This third point is the blurriest, and it may simply have no good single answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more frightful thing that seems to be happening is that now we not only hold the individual responsible, but the platform itself responsible. Why? Should the ISP that serves the user’s connection also be responsible for letting that person even access the Internet? Should the email service provider not share in the blame, by allowing that individual the continued ability to communicate with those he or she forms such thoughts and ideas with? If a group rents equipment to loudly broadcast its ideas, or purchases the paper and supplies necessary for its signs, would we or should we hold the suppliers of these things responsible if the group is deemed toxic? How far down the social-justice rabbit-hole can and should we, the society, go? Where will it end?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reality is that an effective deplatforming initiative is built primarily on the momentum of rage and angst and as it gathers momentum, less and less participants have the presence of mind to approach the subject at hand rationally and objectively. It is, as Elias Canetti termed it, a type of hunting pack known as “the baiting crowd”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The baiting crowd forms with reference to a quickly attainable goal. That goal is widely known and clearly marked, and it is also near. This crowd is out for killing and it knows whom it wants to kill. It heads for this goal with unique determination and cannot be cheated of it. The proclaiming of the goal, the spreading about of who it is that is to perish, is enough to make the crowd form. The concentration on killing is of a special kind of unsurpassed intensity. Everyone wants to participate; everyone strikes a blow and, in order to do this, punches as near as he can to the victim. If he cannot hit himself, he wants to see others hit him. Every arm is thrust out as if they all belong to the same creature….&lt;br/&gt;— Elias Canetti, &lt;em&gt;Crowds and Power&lt;/em&gt; “&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s most pernicious about all this is that after it’s over, there are no winners, despite the cheer of those declaring victory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Most successful deplatformings are Pyrrhic victories&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s why: let’s step through the various participants in this and show how they undermined their own long term interests by doing this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, though, a quick word on Gab:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-17256&quot; src=&quot;https://easydns.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Screen-Shot-2018-11-02-at-1.42.15-PM.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;571&quot; srcset=&quot;https://easydns.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Screen-Shot-2018-11-02-at-1.42.15-PM.png 1190w, https://easydns.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Screen-Shot-2018-11-02-at-1.42.15-PM-300x285.png 300w, https://easydns.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Screen-Shot-2018-11-02-at-1.42.15-PM-768x731.png 768w, https://easydns.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Screen-Shot-2018-11-02-at-1.42.15-PM-1024x974.png 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;via &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/caitoz/status/1056783477767471105&quot;&gt;http://twitter.com/caitoz/status/1056783477767471105&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This mirrors my take on it when I created an account and took a look around. Gab illustrates a “catch-22” around setting out to be specifically a “free speech platform”. You initially appeal to the most fringe elements of public discourse. Your first wave of users are going to be people for whom this has been a problem, and if you’re an absolutist and let them on then suddenly that’s your base. And once that’s your base, it’s a hard sell to entice the normies into the ecosystem. It’s entirely understandable then, why Gab acquired a reputation for being an oasis of the alt-right. Adapting the “Pepe the Frog” meme as their logo didn’t help, to many that looks like a dog whistle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It all culminated, in the hours after the tragic shooting in Pittsburgh with their tweet about getting “1 million hits per hour” , possibly the stupidest thing ever tweeted, excepting maybe that time that guy &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dailydot.com/unclick/ariana-grande-joke-twitter-david-leavitt/&quot;&gt;tweeted a few jokes about the Ariana Grande concert bombing mere minutes after it happened&lt;/a&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-17257&quot; src=&quot;https://easydns.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Screen-Shot-2018-11-02-at-1.45.27-PM.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;294&quot; srcset=&quot;https://easydns.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Screen-Shot-2018-11-02-at-1.45.27-PM.png 1276w, https://easydns.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Screen-Shot-2018-11-02-at-1.45.27-PM-300x147.png 300w, https://easydns.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Screen-Shot-2018-11-02-at-1.45.27-PM-768x377.png 768w, https://easydns.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Screen-Shot-2018-11-02-at-1.45.27-PM-1024x502.png 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All that said, their deplatforming is still very much troubling because they claim to have proactively aided the police once they became aware of the perpetrator’s account on their system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is very much in line with how any other social media platform behaves and is normal and responsible. Contrast Gab’s cooperation in the Pittsburgh shooting investigation with Dailystormer who were widely deplatformed for going the extra mile to be indefensibly abominable pricks in the aftermath of Heather Heyer’s murder in Charlottetown. Big difference, but same outcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Here is how the deplatforming participants have undermined their own interests:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Stripe and Paypal:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one rattled me. We use Stripe, it’s our main payment processor and probably the best we’ve ever worked with. But now they’re making fairly loose judgment calls about their clients and letting the actions of a single downstream user, among thousands? (millions?) of a customer decide their fate? It sets a bad precedent. Same goes for Paypal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does this mean that if &lt;strong&gt;Zerohedge&lt;/strong&gt;, or &lt;strong&gt;Black Lives Matter&lt;/strong&gt;, two of our clients from opposite ends of the political spectrum, post something, or even if one of &lt;em&gt;their &lt;/em&gt;users posts something, that is beyond the pale, then we have to worry about having our finances cut off?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know as &lt;a href=&quot;https://easydns.com&quot;&gt;“the DNS guys”&lt;/a&gt; we have a near pathological aversion to single-points-of-failure, but it’s not a stretch to come to the conclusion for any business that it’s not an acceptable risk to have that possibility just looming there and to do nothing about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That means we will now be looking for backup payment processors. That means maybe after 20 years in business, maybe it’s time to just pull it all in-house. Will any other businesses do the same? Anybody doing the same calculus will arrive at the same conclusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stripe and Paypal put the question in their clients head every time they make a judgement call about one. Especially businesses built around downstream users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Godaddy:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is &lt;a href=&quot;https://easydns.com/blog/2014/08/02/is-your-domain-name-safe-from-nefarious-interests/&quot;&gt;known to skimp on due process&lt;/a&gt; before unplugging any domains that garner any kind of quasi-official request , so it’s no surprise that they cut loose Gab’s domain. They’re the 800lb Gorilla in the space and for them, I imagine that it’s all a numbers game. It’s just easier to kick them off than to &lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt; about whether they &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; kick them off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever I come across a fellow Libertarian, anarcho-capitalist or even an Austrian-school economist or &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; kind of contrarian or heterodox voice and I find out they’re using Godaddy, I caution them that they really are playing roulette. All it takes is some coordinated, well aimed outrage and they’ll be gone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And of course, there are groups out there whose entire raison d’être is to do just that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Shopify:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Came under brief criticism for hosting Breitbart material, but they stuck it out, but this time they also deplatformed Gab. Again – anybody using Shopify may want to rethink relying on them solely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Medium:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Medium’s suspensions I find quite troubling, considering that they banned Gab’s official account where they would speak to the criticisms being levelled against themselves, but not rebroadcasting any of the material found on Gab that ostensibly made them problematic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Caitlyn Johnstone was exactly correct when she drew attention specifically to Gab’s statement on the Pittsburgh tragedy and posed the question: &lt;em&gt;what about that statement could possibly justify having their voice cut-off?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I write this, Twitter hasn’t killed the Gab twitter account, yet. But they did seemingly coordinate with Facebook et al in the latest &lt;a href=&quot;https://thefreethoughtproject.com/&quot;&gt;Facebook purge of FreeThoughtProject&lt;/a&gt; (I listened to an &lt;a href=&quot;https://tomwoods.com/ep-1267-the-facebook-purge-continues/&quot;&gt;excellent interview with the co-founders on the Tom Woods podcast&lt;/a&gt; this morning).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes,  all of the above are all within their rights to deplatform Gab. But all of the platforms that do so simply reinforce the notion in everybody’s head: &lt;em&gt;these platforms have power over us&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;they pose existential risk to our businesses or our ability to express ourselves.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What happens next:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For that reason, counter-measures will emerge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The traditional argument &lt;em&gt;“if you’re doing nothing wrong don’t worry”&lt;/em&gt; doesn’t hold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe today, that means “if you are a social justice minded progressive you have nothing to worry about”. But people forget that pendulums swing, history has certain cycles of mean reversion and then overshoot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the years after 9/11 I remember very vividly how the Neo-conservative narrative utterly dominated the mainstream media and the word “liberal” was practically a slur. Those days are certainly gone. Do you think these days won’t be?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happens when everybody on the “safe” side of the narrative today is no longer considered acceptable tomorrow?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally I think it’s more pernicious than a mechanical back-and-forth struggle over control of the narrative. Left-vs-right is a false dichotomy. The real battle, the important one, is between those who would seek to decide what is acceptable for other people to think vs those who would rather think for themselves. It is centralization and consolidation vs decentralization and diversity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next challenger to Twitter will not be another centralized platform like Gab. It will be decentralized – perhaps a federation like &lt;a href=&quot;https://joinmastodon.org/&quot;&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt;, where each node runs its own CoC and community standards – similar to IRC days. Or something blockchain based like &lt;a href=&quot;https://peepeth.com/welcome&quot;&gt;Peepeth&lt;/a&gt;. Over all this recent attention around deplatforming, I’ve suddenly heard the name &lt;a href=&quot;https://mightynetworks.com/&quot;&gt;Mighty Networks&lt;/a&gt; more than once over the past few weeks. Turns out you can create your own network over there, and use your own domain to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tech giants today are by their own actions cultivating the motivation and the will to necessitate the creation of their own challengers and everybody is watching closely what works and what doesn’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next wave of disruption will not look like the last wave, the incumbent giants are not impervious to assault. I always like to remind people that Google, Facebook, Twitter, et al may look unassailable today, but so did Yahoo and Myspace, yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The truly fringe discourse, the stuff nobody normal condones will all go underground, where it will be harder to find and monitor and where it will revel in it’s inscrutability, metastasizing into God-knows-what from whence the occasional shock of really unhinged egregores will surely emerge.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 19:15:22 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>StuntPope</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://easydns.com/blog/2018/11/02/a-heretics-guide-to-deplatforming/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Let&amp;#039;s remove Quaternions from every 3D Engine</title>
<link>http://marctenbosch.com/quaternions/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://marctenbosch.com/quaternions/</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;Content-Type&quot; content=&quot;text/html; charset=UTF-8&quot; /&gt;&lt;title&gt;Let’s remove Quaternions from every 3D Engine (An Interactive Introduction to Rotors from Geometric Algebra)&lt;/title&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot; href=&quot;sh/sh_style.css&quot; /&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body onload=&quot;OnLoad()&quot; id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;554.71037668799&quot;&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;videoplayer&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe id=&quot;videoframe&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/syyK6hTWT7U?enablejsapi=1&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; name=&quot;videoframe&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;subtitle&quot;&gt;(An Interactive Introduction to &lt;strong&gt;Rotors&lt;/strong&gt; from Geometric Algebra)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To represent 3D rotations graphics programmers use &lt;em&gt;Quaternions&lt;/em&gt;. However, &lt;strong&gt;Quaternions are hard to understand because they are taught at face value&lt;/strong&gt;. We sort of just accept their odd multiplication tables and other arcane definitions and use them as black boxes that rotate vectors in the ways we want. Why does $\mathbf{i}^2=\mathbf{j}^2=\mathbf{k}^2=-1$ and $\mathbf{i} \mathbf{j} = \mathbf{k}$? Why do we take a vector and upgrade it to an &quot;imaginary&quot; vector in order to transform it, like $\mathbf{q} (x\mathbf{i} + y\mathbf{j} + z \mathbf{k}) \mathbf{q}^{*}$? Who cares as long as it rotates my vectors the right way, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a way to represents rotations called a &lt;em&gt;Rotor&lt;/em&gt; that subsumes both Complex Numbers (in 2D) and Quaternions (in 3D) and even generalizes to any number of dimensions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can build Rotors &lt;strong&gt;almost entirely from scratch&lt;/strong&gt;, instead of defining quaternions out of nowhere and trying to explain how they work &lt;strong&gt;retroactively&lt;/strong&gt;. This takes more time, but I find it is very much worth it because it makes them much easier to understand!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, 3D Rotors do not require the use of a fourth dimension of space in order to be visualized and understood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would be great if we could start phasing out the use and teaching of Quaternions and replace them with Rotors. The change is simple and &lt;strong&gt;the code remains almost the same&lt;/strong&gt;. Anything you can do with a Quaternion, such as Interpolation and avoiding Gimbal lock, you can do on a Rotor. &lt;strong&gt;But the understanding grows a lot.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol id=&quot;toc&quot;&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;smintro&quot;&gt;(In the following article, every diagram is interactive. The video follows the article, and you can press the &lt;a href=&quot;javascript:PlayVideo(0)&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://marctenbosch.com/quaternions/play.svg&quot; class=&quot;play&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; buttons to play the relevant section of video. Conversely, you can press the &lt;img src=&quot;http://marctenbosch.com/quaternions/gotosection.svg&quot; class=&quot;inlinebutton&quot; /&gt; button to go to the section of the article that corresponds to what the video is playing at this moment. You can maximize your window to have more space for the video, or you can press the &lt;img src=&quot;http://marctenbosch.com/quaternions/fixedsize.svg&quot; class=&quot;inlinebutton&quot; /&gt; button to set it to a fixed size.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Planes of Rotations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Rotations happen in 2D planes &lt;a href=&quot;javascript:PlayVideo(1)&quot; name=&quot;h_1&quot; id=&quot;h_1&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://marctenbosch.com/quaternions/play.svg&quot; class=&quot;play&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 3D, we usually think of rotations as happening around an axis, like a wheel turning around its axle, but instead of thinking about the axle a more correct way is to think about the plane that the wheel lies on, perpendicular to the axle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://marctenbosch.com/quaternions/oldlady.png&quot; alt=&quot;Old Lady shows off rotations&quot; class=&quot;bcenter&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This old lady is spinning wheel in the $\mathbf{xz}$ plane, perpendicular to the $\mathbf{y}$ axis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is because if we split a vector into two pieces, one lying inside the plane ($\mathbf{v}_\parallel$) and one lying outside the plane ($\mathbf{v}_\perp$), the rotation rotates the inside part while keeping the outside part the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rotation in the $yx$ plane [&lt;strong&gt;Drag anywhere to move the camera&lt;/strong&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2D there is only one single plane to rotate in (there is &lt;strong&gt;no outside part&lt;/strong&gt;). Therefore considering rotations to happen around a third axis (perpendicular to the 2D plane) is technically incorrect, since we shouldn’t need to introduce another dimension to perform rotations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you told a 2D &quot;flatlander&quot; (who lives inside a 2D plane and has only ever experienced 2D) about a perpendicular rotation axis they would look at you and ask &quot;which direction does the axis point along? I can't picture it!&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;expandable&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Aside] And in higher dimensions (4D and more) it is impossible to define a single normal vector to a 2D plane (for example in 4D there are two normal directions to a 2D plane, in 5D there are three normals directions, and in $n$D there are $n-2$)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Explicit Sense of Rotation &lt;a href=&quot;javascript:PlayVideo(2)&quot; name=&quot;h_2&quot; id=&quot;h_2&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://marctenbosch.com/quaternions/play.svg&quot; class=&quot;play&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, when thinking about rotation around an axis, the sense of the rotation is undefined, and so needs to be defined by convention (via the so-called &quot;right hand rule&quot;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, if we think about rotations as happening inside planes, the sense is clear: rotation in the $\mathbf{xy}$ plane means a rotation that takes the (unit) vector $\mathbf{x}$ to the (unit) vector $\mathbf{y}$, inside the plane they form together. Rotation in the $\mathbf{yx}$ plane is the opposite rotation: it takes the vector $\mathbf{y}$ to the vector $\mathbf{x}$.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;expandable&quot; readability=&quot;20&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Aside] When I first learned about the three 3D rotation matrices along orthogonal planes, I remember thinking, why the hell does the $\mathbf{R_y}$ matrix have the opposite sign? It's because of the &quot;right hand rule&quot;, where we must define rotation around the $\mathbf{y}$ axis to be from $\mathbf{z}$ to $\mathbf{x}$ instead of $\mathbf{x}$ to $\mathbf{z}$ to maintain a consistent right-handed sense of rotation. That convention becomes unnecessary when we talk directly about the plane itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$R_X(\theta) = \begin{bmatrix}1 &amp;amp; 0 &amp;amp; 0\\0 &amp;amp; cos(\theta) &amp;amp; -sin(\theta)\\0 &amp;amp; sin(\theta) &amp;amp; cos(\theta)\end{bmatrix} \: \: \: R_Y(\theta) = \begin{bmatrix}cos(\theta) &amp;amp; 0 &amp;amp; \bbox[5px,border-bottom:2px solid red]{\ \ }sin(\theta)\\0 &amp;amp; 1 &amp;amp; 0\\ \bbox[5px,border-bottom:2px solid red]{-}sin(\theta) &amp;amp; 0 &amp;amp; cos(\theta)\end{bmatrix} \: \: \: R_Z(\theta) = \begin{bmatrix}cos(\theta) &amp;amp; -sin(\theta) &amp;amp; 0\\sin(\theta) &amp;amp; cos(\theta) &amp;amp; 0\\0 &amp;amp; 0 &amp;amp; 1\end{bmatrix}$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bivectors&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The Outer Product &lt;a href=&quot;javascript:PlayVideo(3)&quot; name=&quot;h_3&quot; id=&quot;h_3&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://marctenbosch.com/quaternions/play.svg&quot; class=&quot;play&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To compute the axis of rotation to rotate one vector $\mathbf{a}$ to another vector $\mathbf{b}$, we take the cross product of the two vectors to get a vector that is perpendicular to both. But why &quot;leave&quot; the plane, since a rotation is fundamentally a 2D thing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead we take what is called the &lt;strong&gt;outer product&lt;/strong&gt; (also called exterior, or wedge product) of the two vectors, building a new element called a bivector (or 2-vector) $\mathbf{B}$ that represents the plane the two vectors form together. If the cross product creates the &lt;strong&gt;normal vector&lt;/strong&gt; to a plane, the outer product creates the &lt;strong&gt;plane itself&lt;/strong&gt;. Taking the normal to the plane is extraneous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bcenter&quot;&gt;$$\mathbf{B} = \mathbf{a} \wedge \mathbf{b}$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$\mathbf{B}$ can be represented as the parallelogram built from the vectors $\mathbf{a}$ and $\mathbf{b}$, in the plane they form together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea of a bivector might seem a bit strange at first, but they are pretty much &lt;strong&gt;as fundamental as vectors&lt;/strong&gt;, as we will see. If a vector is like a line, then a bivector is like a plane... The properties of the outer product are suited to capture the properties of planes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Basis for Bivectors &lt;a href=&quot;javascript:PlayVideo(4)&quot; name=&quot;h_4&quot; id=&quot;h_4&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://marctenbosch.com/quaternions/play.svg&quot; class=&quot;play&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bivectors have components, just like vectors. But they are defined in terms of basis &lt;strong&gt;planes&lt;/strong&gt; instead of basis &lt;strong&gt;lines&lt;/strong&gt; like vectors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The three orthogonal basis planes are $\mathbf{x} \wedge \mathbf{y}$, $\mathbf{x} \wedge \mathbf{z}$, and $\mathbf{y} \wedge \mathbf{z}$, as seen on the diagram to the right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But first let's look at the simpler 2D case...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;2D Bivectors &lt;a href=&quot;javascript:PlayVideo(5)&quot; name=&quot;h_5&quot; id=&quot;h_5&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://marctenbosch.com/quaternions/play.svg&quot; class=&quot;play&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2D there is only one plane, the $\mathbf{xy}$ plane. So a 2D bivector only has one component. For a bivector built from vectors $\mathbf{a}$ and $\mathbf{b}$, this number $B_{xy}$ is equal to the (signed) area of the parallelogram the two vectors form together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bcenter&quot;&gt;$$\mathbf{B}=\mathbf{a} \wedge \mathbf{b} = B_{xy} (\mathbf{x} \wedge \mathbf{y})$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can play with a 2D bivector in the following interactive diagram, by adjusting the (unit) vectors it is made from:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see that by changing the angle between the vectors the area of the parallelogram changes (according to the sine of the angle).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the vectors are the same, or if they are parallel, they don't form a proper plane and the result is zero. This simple property defines what a bivector is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bcenter&quot;&gt;$$\mathbf{a} \wedge \mathbf{a} = 0$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By looking at the sum of two vectors, we can see that this property implies the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bcenter&quot;&gt;$$\begin{eqnarray}(\mathbf{a}+\mathbf{b}) \wedge (\mathbf{a}+\mathbf{b}) &amp;amp;=&amp;amp; 0 \\ \mathbf{a} \wedge \mathbf{a} + \mathbf{b} \wedge \mathbf{a} + \mathbf{a} \wedge \mathbf{b} + \mathbf{b} \wedge \mathbf{b} &amp;amp;=&amp;amp; 0 \\ \mathbf{b} \wedge \mathbf{a} + \mathbf{a} \wedge \mathbf{b} &amp;amp;=&amp;amp; 0 \end{eqnarray} $$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bcenter&quot;&gt;$$\mathbf{a} \wedge \mathbf{b} = -\mathbf{b} \wedge \mathbf{a}$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like the &lt;strong&gt;sense of a rotation&lt;/strong&gt; matters, the order of the arguments to the outer product matters. Swapping the arguments changes the sign of the result (this is called &quot;anti-symmetric&quot;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the diagram, the sign is represented using the color, which changes from blue to green. The sign changes whenever the rotation from $\mathbf{a}$ to $\mathbf{b}$ goes from being clockwise to being anticlockwise (i.e. if it matches the ($\mathbf{x}$ to $\mathbf{y}$) direction or the ($\mathbf{y}$ to $\mathbf{x}$) direction).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see how the properties of the outer product are suited to capture the properties of planes and rotations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;2D Bivectors from non-unit vectors &lt;a href=&quot;javascript:PlayVideo(6)&quot; name=&quot;h_6&quot; id=&quot;h_6&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://marctenbosch.com/quaternions/play.svg&quot; class=&quot;play&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vectors obviously don't have to be unit lengths, and in this diagram the restriction is removed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The signed area of the parallelogram is proportional to the lengths of both vectors: $B_{xy} = sin(\alpha)\|a\|\|b\|$ where $\alpha$ is the angle between $\mathbf{a}$ and $\mathbf{b}$. So for example doubling the length of one vector doubles the area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can get the actual value by plugging in the vectors in component form:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bcenter&quot;&gt;$$\begin{eqnarray}\mathbf{a} \wedge \mathbf{b} &amp;amp;=&amp;amp; (a_x \mathbf{x} + a_y \mathbf{y}) \wedge (b_x \mathbf{x} + b_y \mathbf{y}) \\ &amp;amp;=&amp;amp; a_x b_x (\mathbf{x} \wedge \mathbf{x}) + a_x b_y (\mathbf{x} \wedge \mathbf{y}) + a_y b_x (\mathbf{y} \wedge \mathbf{x}) + a_y b_y (\mathbf{y} \wedge \mathbf{y}) \\ &amp;amp;=&amp;amp; a_x b_y (\mathbf{x} \wedge \mathbf{y}) + a_y b_x (\mathbf{y} \wedge \mathbf{x}) \\ &amp;amp;=&amp;amp; a_x b_y (\mathbf{x} \wedge \mathbf{y}) - a_y b_x (\mathbf{x} \wedge \mathbf{y}) \\ &amp;amp;=&amp;amp; (a_x b_y - a_y b_x) (\mathbf{x} \wedge \mathbf{y}) \end{eqnarray}$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bcenter&quot;&gt;$$B_{xy} = a_x b_y - b_x a_y$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;3D Bivectors &lt;a href=&quot;javascript:PlayVideo(7)&quot; name=&quot;h_7&quot; id=&quot;h_7&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://marctenbosch.com/quaternions/play.svg&quot; class=&quot;play&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just like the coordinates of a vector $\mathbf{v}$ can be thought of as the &lt;strong&gt;projections&lt;/strong&gt; of the vector onto the three orthogonal basis axes ($\mathbf{x},\mathbf{y},\mathbf{z}$), the coordinates of a bivector $\mathbf{B}$ can be thought of as the &lt;strong&gt;projections&lt;/strong&gt; of the small plane onto the three orthogonal basis planes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The projections of the vector are the &lt;strong&gt;lengths&lt;/strong&gt; of that vector along each basis vector, while the projections of the bivector are the &lt;strong&gt;areas&lt;/strong&gt; of the plane on each basis plane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a vector:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bcenter&quot;&gt;$$\mathbf{v} = \bbox[5px,border-bottom:2px solid red]{v_x} \mathbf{x} + \bbox[5px,border-bottom:2px solid green]{v_y} \mathbf{y} + \bbox[5px,border-bottom:2px solid blue]{v_z} \mathbf{z}$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a bivector:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bcenter&quot;&gt;$$\mathbf{B} = \bbox[5px,border-bottom:2px solid coral]{B_{xy}} (\mathbf{x} \wedge \mathbf{y}) + \bbox[5px,border-bottom:2px solid gold]{B_{xz}} (\mathbf{x} \wedge \mathbf{z}) + \bbox[5px,border-bottom:2px solid DarkViolet]{B_{yz}} (\mathbf{y} \wedge \mathbf{z})$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where $B_{xy}, B_{xz}, B_{yz}$ are just numbers like $v_x, v_y, v_z$ (they are underlined to match the diagram colors).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The components of a 3D bivector are just the three 2D projections of the bivector onto the 2D basis planes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the same method as before we find that the actual values of the components look a lot like the XY component from the 2D case, but applied to all three planes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bcenter&quot;&gt;$$B_{xy} = a_x b_y - b_x a_y$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bcenter&quot;&gt;$$B_{xz} = a_x b_z - b_x a_z$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bcenter&quot;&gt;$$B_{yz} = a_y b_z - b_y a_z$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can play with a 3D bivector in the following interactive diagram:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does the exterior product remind you of anything? In 3D, the definition of the outer product is very similar to that of the cross product. In fact, in 3D a vector that comes from a cross product (such as a normal vector) will have three components which are equal to the components of the bivector (the numbers are the same, but the basis is different).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bcenter&quot;&gt;$$\begin{eqnarray}\mathbf{a} \wedge \mathbf{b} &amp;amp;=&amp;amp; &amp;amp; (a_x b_y - b_x a_y)(\mathbf{x} \wedge \mathbf{y}) \\ &amp;amp; &amp;amp; + &amp;amp; (a_x b_z - b_x a_z)(\mathbf{x} \wedge \mathbf{z}) \\ &amp;amp; &amp;amp; + &amp;amp; (a_y b_z - b_y a_z)(\mathbf{y} \wedge \mathbf{z}) \\ \\ \mathbf{a} \times \mathbf{b} &amp;amp;=&amp;amp; &amp;amp; (a_x b_y - b_x a_y) \ \mathbf{z} \\ &amp;amp; &amp;amp; + &amp;amp; (a_x b_z - b_x a_z) \ \mathbf{y} \\ &amp;amp; &amp;amp; + &amp;amp; (a_y b_z - b_y a_z) \ \mathbf{x}\end{eqnarray}$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The bivector definition makes sense geometrically, instead of appearing out of thin air.&lt;/strong&gt; I remember thinking when I was learning the cross product, why the hell does it return a vector that has length equal to the area of the parallelogram formed by the two vectors? That feels so arbitrary. And why would you be allowed to turn the &lt;strong&gt;area&lt;/strong&gt; of the parallelogram into the &lt;strong&gt;length&lt;/strong&gt; of the vector?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Semantics of Vectors and Bivectors &lt;a href=&quot;javascript:PlayVideo(8)&quot; name=&quot;h_8&quot; id=&quot;h_8&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://marctenbosch.com/quaternions/play.svg&quot; class=&quot;play&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 3D, a bivector has three coordinates, one per plane: ($\mathbf{xy}$, $\mathbf{xz}$, and $\mathbf{yz}$). Vectors also have three coordinates, one per axis ($\mathbf{x}$, $\mathbf{y}$ and $\mathbf{z}$). Each plane is perpendicular to one axis. This is a coincidence that only happens in three dimensions &lt;strong&gt;(*)&lt;/strong&gt; and it is why &lt;strong&gt;historically we have been confusing bivectors with vectors&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;expandable&quot; readability=&quot;19&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Aside] &lt;strong&gt;(*)&lt;/strong&gt; In 2D there is only one basis bivector ($\mathbf{xy}$), in 3D there are 3 basis bivectors ($\mathbf{xy},\mathbf{xz},\mathbf{yz}$), in 4D there are 6 basis bivectors ($\mathbf{xy},\mathbf{xz},\mathbf{xw},\mathbf{yz},\mathbf{yw},\mathbf{zw}$), etc...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In programming terms, they both have the same memory layout, but different operations. Using a 3D vector instead of a 3D bivector is like &quot;type-casting&quot; the bivector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's an example: you might have seen how normal vectors transform differently than regular vectors, using the &quot;inverse transpose&quot; of the matrix $(\mathbf{M}^{T})^{-1}$ instead of the matrix itself. That's because they are not really vectors, but actually bivectors, which we have &quot;type-cast&quot; to vectors. In physics, there's a hack called an &quot;axial vector,&quot; which has been introduced to differentiate vectors that come from cross products from regular vectors. Bivector is the actual &quot;type&quot; of the object and it should be thought of and manipulated as such.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;expandable&quot; readability=&quot;31&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;[Aside] Trivectors &lt;a href=&quot;javascript:PlayVideo(9)&quot; name=&quot;h_9&quot; id=&quot;h_9&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://marctenbosch.com/quaternions/play.svg&quot; class=&quot;play&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can keep taking the outer product to build not just oriented 2D areas, but oriented 3D volumes as well. A trivector $T$ can be built by taking the outer product twice:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;$$\mathbf{T} = \mathbf{a} \wedge \mathbf{b} \wedge \mathbf{c}$$&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 3D it stops there. Just like in 2D there is only one plane which fills all of 2D space, in 3D there is only one volume which fills all of 3D space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[But in nD we can keep building more outer products of vectors, until we reach the n-th dimension. For example in 4D, we have four basis tri-vectors ($\mathbf{xyz},\mathbf{xyw},\mathbf{xwz},\mathbf{yzw}$) and one basis 4-vector $\mathbf{xyzw}$]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 3D a trivector has only one basis component ($T_{xyz}$), equal to the volume of the parallelepiped generated by the three vectors. The triple outer product is a better version of the scalar triple product ($(\mathbf{a} \times \mathbf{b}) \cdot \mathbf{c}$) because it only involves one kind of operation, returns the correct type (volume instead of scalar) and works in any number of dimensions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bcenter&quot;&gt;$$\mathbf{T} = T_{xyz} \mathbf{x} \wedge \mathbf{y} \wedge \mathbf{z}$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Geometric Product&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Multiplying Vectors together &lt;a href=&quot;javascript:PlayVideo(10)&quot; name=&quot;h_10&quot; id=&quot;h_10&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://marctenbosch.com/quaternions/play.svg&quot; class=&quot;play&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The geometric product $\mathbf{a b}$ (denoted without a symbol) is another operation one can do on vectors. The geometric product is defined so that vectors have inverses (i.e $\mathbf{a} \mathbf{a}^{-1}= 1$ where 1 is just the number $1$!) and have nice properties like associativity ($\mathbf{a} (\mathbf{b} \mathbf{c}) = (\mathbf{a} \mathbf{b}) \mathbf{c}$). The goal is to be able to multiply vectors together so that —just like for matrices— multiplication corresponds to geometric operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;expandable&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Aside] Having inverses is useful so that whatever object $\mathbf{a} \mathbf{a}^{-1}$ is, it won't have an effect on vectors, i.e. it will just act like multiplying by the number $1$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To define the product, first note that it is possible to split a product (or any function that takes two arguments) into the sum of a part that does not change if we swap the arguments and one that does change, in the following way:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bcenter&quot;&gt;$$\begin{eqnarray}\mathbf{a} \mathbf{b} &amp;amp;=&amp;amp; \frac{1}{2} (\mathbf{a} \mathbf{b} + \mathbf{a} \mathbf{b} + \mathbf{b} \mathbf{a} - \mathbf{b} \mathbf{a}) \\ &amp;amp;=&amp;amp; \frac{1}{2} (\mathbf{a} \mathbf{b} + \mathbf{b} \mathbf{a}) + \frac{1}{2} (\mathbf{a} \mathbf{b} - \mathbf{b} \mathbf{a})\end{eqnarray}$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first term does not depend on the order of the arguments $\mathbf{a}$ and $\mathbf{b}$ anymore (it is called the &quot;symmetric&quot; part), while the second term changes sign when the arguments are swapped (it is called the &quot;antisymmetric&quot; part).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dot product of two vectors (also called inner product) is symmetric and is a measure of distance ($\mathbf{a} \cdot \mathbf{a} = \|\mathbf{a}\|^2 $), so it sounds useful geometrically to set it equal to the symmetric part:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bcenter&quot;&gt;$$\frac{1}{2} (\mathbf{a} \mathbf{b} + \mathbf{b} \mathbf{a}) = \mathbf{a} \cdot \mathbf{b}$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarity, the outer product of two vectors is antisymmetric, so it sounds useful geometrically to set it equal to the antisymmetric part:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bcenter&quot;&gt;$$\frac{1}{2} (\mathbf{a} \mathbf{b} - \mathbf{b} \mathbf{a}) = \mathbf{a} \wedge \mathbf{b}$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, the dot product contains the &lt;strong&gt;cosine&lt;/strong&gt; of the angle between the two vectors ($\mathbf{a} \cdot \mathbf{b} = \|\mathbf{a}\|\|\mathbf{b}\|cos(\alpha)$), while the outer product contains the &lt;strong&gt;sine&lt;/strong&gt; of the angle. Together they fully describe the angle between the vectors, as well the plane they form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;expandable&quot; readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Aside] The completeness of the description is what makes the product invertible, since we can get from one vector to the other using the information contained in their product. If I give you $\mathbf{a}$ and $\mathbf{a} \mathbf{b}$ you can get $\mathbf{b}$. This could not be done with just the cosine, or just the sine/plane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the geometric product is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bcenter&quot;&gt;$$\mathbf{a} \mathbf{b} = \mathbf{a} \cdot \mathbf{b} + \mathbf{a} \wedge \mathbf{b}$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is strange because multiplying two vectors together gives the sum of two different things: a scalar and a bivector. However this is similar to how a complex number is the sum of a scalar and an &quot;imaginary&quot; number, so you might be used to it already. Here the bivector part corresponds to the &quot;imaginary&quot; part of the complex number. &lt;strong&gt;Except it is not &quot;imaginary,&quot; it’s just a bivector, which we have a concrete picture of!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, by multiplying two vectors together we compute useful properties about them (the &quot;length of their projections onto each other&quot; / &quot;cosine of the angle&quot; ($\mathbf{a} \cdot \mathbf{b}$), and the &quot;plane they form together&quot; / &quot;sine of the angle&quot; ($\mathbf{a} \wedge \mathbf{b}$)), which we keep bundled together via the &quot;plus&quot; sign. The geometric product also gives these &quot;property bundles&quot; operations that can be applied to them, and these operations have geometric interpretations (for example: rotating and reflecting vectors), as we shall see now .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;expandable&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Aside] It is possible to express the geometric product in terms of the sine and cosine: $\mathbf{a} \mathbf{b} = \|\mathbf{a}\|\|\mathbf{b}\| ( cos(\alpha) + sin(\alpha) \mathbf{B} )$ where $\mathbf{B}$ is a bivector in the plane of both vectors, made from two unit perpendicular vectors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt; Multiplication Table &lt;a href=&quot;javascript:PlayVideo(11)&quot; name=&quot;h_11&quot; id=&quot;h_11&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://marctenbosch.com/quaternions/play.svg&quot; class=&quot;play&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The multiplication table helps make this product more concrete: let's see what happens if we take products of the basis vectors ($\mathbf{x}$,$\mathbf{y}$,$\mathbf{z}$).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For any basis vector, such as the $\mathbf{x}$ axis, the result is $1$:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bcenter&quot;&gt;$$\mathbf{x} \mathbf{x} = \mathbf{x} \cdot \mathbf{x} + \mathbf{x} \wedge \mathbf{x} = 1$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For any pair of basis vectors, such as the $\mathbf{x}$ and $\mathbf{y}$ axes, the result is just the bivector they form together:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bcenter&quot;&gt;$$\mathbf{x} \mathbf{y} = \mathbf{x} \cdot \mathbf{y} + \mathbf{x} \wedge \mathbf{y} = \mathbf{x} \wedge \mathbf{y}$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(so we can call $\mathbf{x} \wedge \mathbf{y}$ simply $\mathbf{x} \mathbf{y}$ since they are the same thing!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This gives the following table:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;bcenter&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; rowspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$\mathbf{a} \mathbf{b}$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;tcs&quot; colspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;$\mathbf{b}$&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;$\mathbf{x}$&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;$\mathbf{y}$&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;$\mathbf{z}$&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;3&quot; class=&quot;trs&quot;&gt;$\mathbf{a}$&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;$\mathbf{x}$&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$1$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$\mathbf{x} \mathbf{y}$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$\mathbf{x} \mathbf{z}$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;$\mathbf{y}$&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$-\mathbf{x} \mathbf{y}$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$1$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$\mathbf{y} \mathbf{z}$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;$\mathbf{z}$&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$-\mathbf{x} \mathbf{z}$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$-\mathbf{y} \mathbf{z}$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$1$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is basically trivial, unlike the quaternion table for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;expandable&quot; readability=&quot;17&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Aside] For example, multiplying the two vectors $(5,3,0)$ and $(2,0,1)$:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bcenter&quot;&gt;$$\begin{eqnarray}( 5 \mathbf{x} + 3 \mathbf{y} ) ( 2 \mathbf{x} + 1 \mathbf{z} ) &amp;amp;=&amp;amp; 5 \ 2 \ \mathbf{x} \mathbf{x} + 5 \ 1 \ \mathbf{x} \mathbf{z} + 3 \ 2 \ \mathbf{y} \mathbf{x} + 3 \ 1 \ \mathbf{y} \mathbf{z}\\ &amp;amp;=&amp;amp; 10 + 5 \ \mathbf{x} \mathbf{z} - 6 \ \mathbf{x} \mathbf{y} + 3 \ \mathbf{y} \mathbf{z} \end{eqnarray} $$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Reflection Formula (Traditional Version) &lt;a href=&quot;javascript:PlayVideo(12)&quot; name=&quot;h_12&quot; id=&quot;h_12&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://marctenbosch.com/quaternions/play.svg&quot; class=&quot;play&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reflection by a vector [you can move each vector]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we have a unit vector $\mathbf{a}$ and a vector $\mathbf{v}$ we can reflect $\mathbf{v}$ by the plane perpendicular to $\mathbf{a}$.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is done the usual way: we decompose $\mathbf{v}$ into a part perpendicular to the plane $\mathbf{v}_\perp = (\mathbf{v} \cdot \mathbf{a}) \mathbf{a}$, and a part parallel to the plane $\mathbf{v}_\parallel = \mathbf{v} - \mathbf{v}_\perp = \mathbf{v} - (\mathbf{v} \cdot \mathbf{a})\mathbf{a}$.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, to reflect the vector, flip the perpendicular part while keeping the parallel part unchanged:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bcenter&quot;&gt;$$\begin{eqnarray}R_{\mathbf{a}}(\mathbf{v}) &amp;amp;=&amp;amp; \mathbf{v}_\parallel - \mathbf{v}_\perp \\ &amp;amp;=&amp;amp; ( \mathbf{v} - (\mathbf{v} \cdot \mathbf{a})\mathbf{a} ) - ((\mathbf{v} \cdot \mathbf{a}) \mathbf{a}) \\ &amp;amp;=&amp;amp;\mathbf{v} - 2 (\mathbf{v} \cdot \mathbf{a}) \mathbf{a}\end{eqnarray}$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Reflection Formula (Geometric Product Version) &lt;a href=&quot;javascript:PlayVideo(13)&quot; name=&quot;h_13&quot; id=&quot;h_13&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://marctenbosch.com/quaternions/play.svg&quot; class=&quot;play&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point we can replace the dot product $\mathbf{v} \cdot \mathbf{a}$ by its geometric product version $\frac{1}{2} (\mathbf{v} \mathbf{a} + \mathbf{a} \mathbf{v})$ to get the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bcenter&quot;&gt;$$\begin{eqnarray}R_{\mathbf{a}}(\mathbf{v}) &amp;amp;=&amp;amp; \mathbf{v} - 2(\frac{1}{2}( \mathbf{v} \mathbf{a} + \mathbf{a} \mathbf{v})) \mathbf{a} \\ &amp;amp;= &amp;amp; \mathbf{v} - \mathbf{v} \mathbf{a}^2 - \mathbf{a} \mathbf{v} \mathbf{a} \\ &amp;amp;= &amp;amp; - \mathbf{a} \mathbf{v} \mathbf{a}\end{eqnarray}$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;($\mathbf{a}^2 = \mathbf{a} \cdot \mathbf{a} = 1$ since $\mathbf{a}$ is a unit vector)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is saying the exact same thing but in a different notation. Using a simple product notation instead of a formula to encode a fundamental operation such as a reflection is going to prove very useful!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;expandable&quot; readability=&quot;20&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Aside] If you are wondering how taking the geometric product more than once works, just look at the basis vectors. There are only three possible cases:.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bcenter&quot;&gt;$$\begin{eqnarray}\mathbf{x} (\mathbf{x} \mathbf{x}) &amp;amp;=&amp;amp; \mathbf{x} 1 = \mathbf{x} \\ \mathbf{x} (\mathbf{x} \mathbf{y}) &amp;amp;=&amp;amp; \mathbf{x} (\mathbf{x} \cdot \mathbf{y} + \mathbf{x} \wedge \mathbf{y}) = \mathbf{x} (\mathbf{x} \cdot \mathbf{y}) + \mathbf{x} \mathbf{x} \mathbf{y} = \mathbf{x} (\mathbf{x} \cdot \mathbf{y} ) + \mathbf{y} \\ \mathbf{x} (\mathbf{y} \mathbf{z}) &amp;amp;=&amp;amp; \mathbf{x} (\mathbf{y} \cdot \mathbf{z}) + \mathbf{x} \mathbf{y} \mathbf{z}\end{eqnarray}$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results are: vector, vector, vector + trivector. However the last case can only happen if the three vectors are independent, which is never the case for $-\mathbf{ava}$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;expandable&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Aside] For those curious it is possible to look at what happens at each step of $- \mathbf{a} \mathbf{v} \mathbf{a}$ in terms of the geometric product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;biglist&quot; readability=&quot;33.5&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;47&quot;&gt;The first step is:
&lt;p class=&quot;bcenter&quot;&gt;$$\mathbf{v} \mathbf{a} = \mathbf{v} \cdot \mathbf{a} + \mathbf{v} \wedge \mathbf{a}$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If, like before, we split $\mathbf{v}$ into a part perpendicular to the plane ($\mathbf{v}_\perp$) and a part parallel to it ($\mathbf{v}_\parallel$), we get:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bcenter&quot;&gt;$$\begin{eqnarray}(\mathbf{v}_\perp + \mathbf{v}_\parallel) \mathbf{a} &amp;amp;=&amp;amp; (\mathbf{v}_\perp + \mathbf{v}_\parallel) \cdot \mathbf{a} + (\mathbf{v}_\perp + \mathbf{v}_\parallel) \wedge \mathbf{a} \\ &amp;amp;=&amp;amp; \mathbf{v}_\perp \cdot \mathbf{a} + \mathbf{v}_\parallel \cdot \mathbf{a} + \mathbf{v}_\perp \wedge \mathbf{a} + \mathbf{v}_\parallel \wedge \mathbf{a}\end{eqnarray}$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$\mathbf{v}_\parallel \cdot \mathbf{a} = 0$ since these vectors are perpendicular, while $\mathbf{v}_\perp \wedge \mathbf{a} = 0$ since these vectors are parallel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bcenter&quot;&gt;$$\mathbf{v} \mathbf{a} = \mathbf{v}_\perp \cdot \mathbf{a} + \mathbf{v}_\parallel \wedge \mathbf{a}$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first term is just the length of the projection of $\mathbf{v}$ onto $\mathbf{a}$, i.e the first term is just length of $\mathbf{v}_\perp$.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's call $\hat{\mathbf{v}_\parallel}$ the normalized version of $\mathbf{v}_\parallel$, such that $\mathbf{v}_\parallel = \hat{\mathbf{v}_\parallel}\|\mathbf{v}_\parallel\|$. Then the second term is just a bivector $\mathbf{B} = \hat{\mathbf{v}_\parallel} \wedge \mathbf{a}$ multiplied by the length of $\mathbf{v}_\parallel$.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This bivector $\mathbf{B}$ is made out of two perpendicular unit vectors, so it is a very pure representation of the plane of vectors $\mathbf{a}$ and $\mathbf{v}$. It doesn't contain information about their relative angle or their lengths, just the orientation of the plane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So both terms are just the decomposition of $\mathbf{v}$ into two orthogonal projections ($\mathbf{v}_\parallel$ and $\mathbf{v}_\perp$), as well as the plane they form ($\mathbf{B}$):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bcenter&quot;&gt;$$\| \mathbf{v}_\perp \| + \| \mathbf{v}_\parallel \| \mathbf{B}$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before moving on to the next step, we can replace the outer product by the geometric product because $\mathbf{a}$ and $\mathbf{v}_\parallel$ are perpendicular and so their outer and geometric product are equivalent (since the dot product part of their geometric product is zero).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bcenter&quot;&gt;$$\mathbf{v}_\perp \cdot \mathbf{a} + \mathbf{v}_\parallel \wedge \mathbf{a} = \mathbf{v}_\perp \cdot \mathbf{a} + \mathbf{v}_\parallel \mathbf{a}$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;The second step is:
&lt;p class=&quot;bcenter&quot;&gt;$$\mathbf{a} \mathbf{v} \mathbf{a} = \mathbf{a} (\mathbf{v}_\perp \cdot \mathbf{a}) + \mathbf{a} \mathbf{v}_\parallel \mathbf{a}$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first term is just the component of $\mathbf{v}$ along $\mathbf{a}$, i.e. the component of $\mathbf{v}$ perpendicular to the plane. Or in other words the first term is just $\mathbf{v}_\perp$.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bcenter&quot;&gt;$$\mathbf{a} \mathbf{v} \mathbf{a} = \mathbf{v}_\perp + \mathbf{a} \mathbf{v}_\parallel \mathbf{a}$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since (again) $\mathbf{a}$ and $\mathbf{v}_\parallel$ are perpendicular their geometric product is just their outer product, so we can swap them and negate the sign.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bcenter&quot;&gt;$$\begin{eqnarray}\mathbf{a} \mathbf{v} \mathbf{a} &amp;amp;=&amp;amp; \mathbf{v}_\perp - \mathbf{v}_\parallel \mathbf{a} \mathbf{a} \\ &amp;amp;=&amp;amp; \mathbf{v}_\perp - \mathbf{v}_\parallel\end{eqnarray}$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;Finally the last step flips the sign:
&lt;p class=&quot;bcenter&quot;&gt;$$-\mathbf{a} \mathbf{v} \mathbf{a} = -\mathbf{v}_\perp + \mathbf{v}_\parallel$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we see that the component of $\mathbf{v}$ perpendicular to the plane is flipped, while the parallel part stays the same!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;expandable&quot; readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Aside] The length of $\mathbf{a}$ is not very important so the following ignores it, but if $\mathbf{a}$ is not a unit vector, we must divide by its length and the formula becomes $- \mathbf{a} \mathbf{v} \mathbf{a}^{-1}$, which looks more like the &quot;Sandwich Product&quot; you might be used to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Two Reflections is a Rotation: 2D case &lt;a href=&quot;javascript:PlayVideo(14)&quot; name=&quot;h_14&quot; id=&quot;h_14&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://marctenbosch.com/quaternions/play.svg&quot; class=&quot;play&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turns out that if we apply two successive reflections to $\mathbf{v}$ (using vector $\mathbf{a}$ followed by vector $\mathbf{b}$) we get &lt;strong&gt;a rotation by twice the angle between the vectors $\mathbf{a}$ and $\mathbf{b}$.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can apply each successive Reflection Step in the diagram below :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also change the vectors $\mathbf{a}$, $\mathbf{b}$, and $\mathbf{v}$, but the initial configuration of vectors in the diagram (click the &quot;Reset Vector Positions&quot; button) should make it especially clear why the rotation ends up being &lt;strong&gt;twice&lt;/strong&gt; the angle. Another configuration that is not bad is to set $\mathbf{a}$ and $\mathbf{b}$ to the $\mathbf{x}$ and $\mathbf{y}$ axes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Two Reflections is a Rotation: 3D case &lt;a href=&quot;javascript:PlayVideo(15)&quot; name=&quot;h_15&quot; id=&quot;h_15&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://marctenbosch.com/quaternions/play.svg&quot; class=&quot;play&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the 3D case the vector $\mathbf{v}$ can be split into two different parts, one lying inside the plane defined by $\mathbf{a}$ and $\mathbf{b}$, and one lying outside (perpendicular to) the plane. As seen in the following diagram, when the vector gets reflected by each plane its outside part stays the same. So for the inside part, we are back to the 2D case, and it just gets rotated by twice the angle!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Rotors &lt;a href=&quot;javascript:PlayVideo(16)&quot; name=&quot;h_16&quot; id=&quot;h_16&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://marctenbosch.com/quaternions/play.svg&quot; class=&quot;play&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of the Geometric Product, the two reflections simply correspond to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bcenter&quot;&gt;$$R_{\mathbf{b}}(R_{\mathbf{a}}(\mathbf{v})) = - \mathbf{b} (-\mathbf{a} \mathbf{v} \mathbf{a}) \mathbf{b} = \mathbf{b} \mathbf{a} \: \mathbf{v} \: \mathbf{a} \mathbf{b}$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We call $\mathbf{a} \mathbf{b} = \mathbf{a} \cdot \mathbf{b} + \mathbf{a} \wedge \mathbf{b}$ a Rotor because by multiplying by $\mathbf{a} \mathbf{b}$ on both sides of a vector we perform a rotation ($\mathbf{b} \mathbf{a}$ the same as $\mathbf{a} \mathbf{b}$ except the bivector part is flipped).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Applying a Rotor $\mathbf{a} \mathbf{b}$ to both sides of a vector rotates this vector in the plane of vectors $\mathbf{a}$ and $\mathbf{b}$ by twice the angle between $\mathbf{a}$ and $\mathbf{b}$.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;strong&gt;✨⭐💖 &lt;span class=&quot;blink&quot;&gt;That's all there is to it!&lt;/span&gt; 💖⭐✨�&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;3D Rotors vs Quaternions &lt;a href=&quot;javascript:PlayVideo(17)&quot; name=&quot;h_17&quot; id=&quot;h_17&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://marctenbosch.com/quaternions/play.svg&quot; class=&quot;play&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can notice that 3D Rotors look a lot like Quaternions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bcenter&quot;&gt;$$a + B_{xy} \ \mathbf{x} \wedge \mathbf{y} + B_{xz} \ \mathbf{x} \wedge \mathbf{z} + B_{yz} \ \mathbf{y} \wedge \mathbf{z}$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bcenter&quot;&gt;$$a + b \ \mathbf{i} + c \ \mathbf{j} + d \ \mathbf{k}$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://marctenbosch.com/quaternions/planets.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Earth-Centric planetary motion&quot; class=&quot;inmargin&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, as we have seen, 3D Rotors are a 3D concept that does not require the use of &quot;4D double rotations&quot; or &quot;stereographic projection&quot; to visualize. Trying to visualize quaternions as operating in 4D just to explain 3D rotations is a bit like trying to understand planetary motion from an earth-centric perspective i.e. overly complex because you are looking at it from the wrong viewpoint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we have seen, representing rotations as operating inside planes instead of around vectors helps a lot. For example the basis bivectors square to $-1$, just like the basis quaternions ($\mathbf{i}^2=\mathbf{j}^2=\mathbf{k}^2 = -1$) :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bcenter&quot;&gt;$$(\mathbf{x} \mathbf{y})^2 = (\mathbf{x} \mathbf{y}) (\mathbf{x} \mathbf{y}) = - (\mathbf{y} \mathbf{x}) (\mathbf{x} \mathbf{y}) = -\mathbf{y} (\mathbf{x} \mathbf{x}) \mathbf{y} = - \mathbf{y} \mathbf{y} = -1$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Multiplying two bivectors together gives a third bivector, but this is basically trivial, and we don't have to remember how $\mathbf{i} \mathbf{j} = \mathbf{k}$:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bcenter&quot;&gt;$$(\mathbf{x} \mathbf{y}) (\mathbf{y} \mathbf{z}) = \mathbf{x} (\mathbf{y} \mathbf{y}) \mathbf{z} = \mathbf{x} \mathbf{z}$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Note that we have used $\mathbf{x} \wedge \mathbf{y} = \mathbf{x} \mathbf{y}$)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These properties are a consequence of the geometric product instead of appearing out of thin air!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;noTOC&quot;&gt;Further Reading&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;-0.48543046357616&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Linear and Geometric Algebra by Macdonald&lt;/em&gt; [&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1453854932/ref=as_li_qf_sp_asin_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=miegakure-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=1453854932&quot;&gt;Amazon Link&lt;/a&gt;] 
&lt;p&gt;Great because it is very clear and simple since it is meant to replace an undergraduate Linear Algebra Textbook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;2.9436860068259&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Geometric Algebra For Computer Science by Dorst et al.&lt;/em&gt; [&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0123749425/ref=as_li_tf_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0123749425&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=martenbos-20&quot;&gt;Amazon Link&lt;/a&gt;] 
&lt;p&gt;Great because programming something often makes you understand it better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: in the book the authors give the impression that Geometric Algebra is slower than Quaternions (etc...). It actually should be almost the same exact code (i.e. don't write Geometric Algebra code by making a generic struct that can contain all possible types of k-vectors, just write one struct per k-vector type, as needed. This means writing one Bivector struct, and one Rotor struct which is a Scalar + Bivector to replace Quaternions).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;noTOC&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Made by &lt;a href=&quot;http://marctenbosch.com/&quot;&gt;Marc ten Bosch&lt;/a&gt;. If you enjoyed this video/article combo thing, you might consider &lt;a href=&quot;https://paypal.me/marctenbosch&quot;&gt;donating&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 18:28:02 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Glench</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://marctenbosch.com/quaternions/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>