<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Ex-Google recruiter: I was fired because I resisted “illegal” diversity efforts</title>
<link>https://www.arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2018/03/ex-google-recruiter-i-was-fired-because-i-resisted-illegal-diversity-efforts</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2018/03/ex-google-recruiter-i-was-fired-because-i-resisted-illegal-diversity-efforts</guid>
<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/GettyImages-100999891-800x511.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/GettyImages-100999891.jpg&quot; class=&quot;enlarge-link&quot; data-height=&quot;2592&quot; data-width=&quot;4056&quot;&gt;Enlarge&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;sep&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; Employees work at the Youtube headquarters in San Bruno, California, on May, 26, 2010.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;aside id=&quot;social-left&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;104 posters participating&quot; class=&quot;comment-count icon-comment-bubble-down&quot; href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2018/03/ex-google-recruiter-i-was-fired-because-i-resisted-illegal-diversity-efforts/?comments=1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;comment-count-before&quot;&gt;reader comments&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;comment-count-number&quot;&gt;222&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;share-links&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Share this story&lt;/span&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;aside class=&quot;pullbox sidebar story-sidebar right&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;
A former YouTube employee has sued Google—the video site’s parent company—alleging that he was wrongfully terminated from his position after he complained against hiring practices that he claimed were discriminatory against white and Asian men.
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/4391847-18-CIV-00442.html&quot;&gt;lawsuit&lt;/a&gt;, which was filed in late January in San Mateo Superior Court but wasn’t reported in the media until Thursday, comes at a time when many Silicon Valley &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2014/01/major-investors-push-apple-execs-to-be-more-diverse-its-all-white-men/&quot;&gt;companies&lt;/a&gt; (including Google) are becoming increasingly &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2017/10/black-members-of-congress-push-for-more-diversity-in-silicon-valley-hires/&quot;&gt;cognizant&lt;/a&gt; of a largely male, white, and Asian workforce. Some companies have &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2016/12/slacks-top-engineer-suggests-that-google-do-blind-assessments-for-hiring/&quot;&gt;publicly&lt;/a&gt; said that they are trying to rectify this situation by working harder to find candidates who can do the job and who are also traditionally underrepresented minorities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The civil complaint explains that Arne Wilberg, who is described as a 40-year-old white man by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/youtube-hiring-for-some-positions-excluded-white-and-asian-males-lawsuit-says-1519948013&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, worked as a recruiter for YouTube for seven years. In his job, Wilberg was tasked with helping to select engineering and tech talent for YouTube and Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;pullbox sidebar story-sidebar right&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;
According to the lawsuit, Wilberg received high marks for his performance as a recruiter until he began pushing back against Google’s efforts to hire a more diverse workforce in 2017. His manager, Allison Alogna, informed Wilberg and his colleagues that they were to “only accept” a certain rank of engineers (“Level 3”) if they were diverse.
&lt;p&gt;As the lawsuit &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/4391847-18-CIV-00442.html#document/p4/a407608&quot;&gt;continues&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In April of 2017, Google’s Technology Stafﬁng Management team was instructed by Alogna to immediately cancel all Level 3 (0-5 years experience) software engineering interviews with every single applicant who was not either female, Black, or Hispanic and to purge entirely any applications by non-diverse employees from the hiring pipeline. Plaintiff refused to comply with this request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;pullbox sidebar story-sidebar right&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;
Wilberg argues that these practices are “illegal and discriminatory,” and, as he continued to resist these practices, he increasingly chafed against his managers and colleagues. Eventually, Wilberg was fired in November 2017.
&lt;p&gt;His lawyer, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dfederlaw.com/&quot;&gt;Daniel Feder&lt;/a&gt;, did not immediately respond to Ars’ request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a statement, Google said that it would “vigorously defend this lawsuit,” adding that it has a “clear policy to hire candidates based on their merit, not their identity. At the same time, we unapologetically try to find a diverse pool of qualified candidates for open roles, as this helps us hire the best people, improve our culture, and build better products.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google did not respond to Ars’ further questions as to how many similar lawsuits involving alleged wrongful termination and discrimination the company has received.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 12:43:54 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kbwt</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2018/03/ex-google-recruiter-i-was-fired-because-i-resisted-illegal-diversity-efforts/</og:url>
<og:title>Ex-Google recruiter: I was fired because I resisted “illegal” diversity efforts</og:title>
<og:image>https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/GettyImages-100999891-760x380.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Google vows to defend lawsuit, says it hires “candidates based on their merit.”</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2018/03/ex-google-recruiter-i-was-fired-because-i-resisted-illegal-diversity-efforts/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Uber and Lyft drivers&amp;#039; median hourly wage is just $3.37, report finds</title>
<link>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2018/mar/01/uber-lyft-driver-wages-median-report</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2018/mar/01/uber-lyft-driver-wages-median-report</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Uber and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/lyft&quot; data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Lyft&lt;/a&gt; drivers in the US make a median profit of $3.37 per hour before taxes, according to a new report that suggests a majority of ride-share workers make below minimum wage and that many actually lose money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researchers did an analysis of vehicle cost data and a survey of more than 1,100 drivers for the ride-hailing companies for the &lt;a draggable=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;http://ceepr.mit.edu/files/papers/2018-005-Brief.pdf&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; published by the Massachusetts Institute of Technology’s Center for Energy and Environmental Policy Research. The report – which factored in insurance, maintenance, repairs, fuel and other costs – found that 30% of drivers are losing money on the job and that 74% earn less than the minimum wage in their states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The findings have raised fresh &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2017/jun/17/uber-drivers-homeless-assault-travis-kalanick&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;concerns about labor standards&lt;/a&gt; in the booming sharing economy as companies such as Uber and Lyft continue to face scrutiny over their treatment of drivers, who are classified as independent contractors and have &lt;a draggable=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2017/apr/05/uber-drivers-union-seattle-legal-battle&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;few rights or protections&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This business model is not currently sustainable,” said Stephen Zoepf, executive director of the Center for Automotive Research at Stanford University and co-author of the paper. “The companies are losing money. The businesses are being subsidized by [venture capital] money … And the drivers are essentially subsidizing it by working for very low wages.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;element element-rich-link element--thumbnail element-rich-link--not-upgraded&quot; data-component=&quot;rich-link&quot; data-link-name=&quot;rich-link-1 | 1&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Drivers earn a median of 59 cents per mile while incurring a median cost of 30 cents per mile, the report said, adding that for nearly a third of drivers, the costs are ultimately higher than the revenue. The paper reported the average driver profit to be $661 per month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While most drivers employ vehicles for personal use and ride-hailing services, the bulk of the miles they drive are for work, which can lead to significant short-term and long-term costs, the paper said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given inevitable costs of maintenance, repair and depreciation, “effectively what you’re doing as a driver is borrowing against the value of your car,” Zoepf said, adding: “It’s quite possible that drivers don’t realize quite how much they are spending.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.stanford.edu/~diamondr/UberPayGap.pdf&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;studies&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://therideshareguy.com/2018-uber-and-lyft-driver-survey-results-the-rideshare-guy/&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;surveys&lt;/a&gt; have found higher hourly earnings for Uber drivers, in part because there are numerous ways to report income and to calculate costs and time and miles spent on the job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harry Campbell, founder of the Rideshare Guy, a website that has conducted surveys of drivers, said the finding of a $3.37 median hourly profit seemed a bit low, but noted that new drivers were often surprised by the wages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The most common feedback we hear from drivers is they end up earning a lot less than they expected,” said Campbell, who partnered with Zoepf on the surveys used in the paper. “There is a lot of turnover in the industry, and that’s the number one reason I hear from drivers why they are quitting – they are not making enough.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Campbell pointed out that Uber itself had struggled to properly consider vehicle costs. Last year, the company &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/uber-confirms-it-is-shutting-down-u-s-car-leasing-business-1506531990&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;shut down its US auto-leasing business&lt;/a&gt; after discovering it was losing 18 times more money per vehicle than it had previously understood. Some drivers claimed that the leasing program &lt;a draggable=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2017/jun/17/uber-drivers-homeless-assault-travis-kalanick&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;trapped them in debt&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/uber&quot; data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Uber&lt;/a&gt; spokesperson broadly criticized the research in a statement: “While the paper is certainly attention grabbing, its methodology and findings are deeply flawed. We’ve reached out to the paper’s authors to share our concerns and suggest ways we might work together to refine their approach.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lyft did not respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 02:47:41 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pmoriarty</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://www.theguardian.com/technology/2018/mar/01/uber-lyft-driver-wages-median-report</og:url>
<og:description>Majority of drivers make less than minimum wage and many end up losing money, according to study published by MIT</og:description>
<og:image>https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/68b8a109221bd5ea184b6167a8e2428eac136faf/0_195_2469_1482/master/2469.jpg?w=1200&amp;h=630&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;fit=crop&amp;crop=faces%2Centropy&amp;bm=normal&amp;ba=bottom%2Cleft&amp;blend64=aHR0cHM6Ly91cGxvYWRzLmd1aW0uY28udWsvMjAxOC8wMS8zMS9mYWNlYm9va19kZWZhdWx0LnBuZw&amp;s=ce0b69ee97fa5062e1ba9e7b9a982d35</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Uber and Lyft drivers' median hourly wage is just $3.37, report finds</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2018/mar/01/uber-lyft-driver-wages-median-report</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Amazon&amp;#039;s policies promote counterfeiting</title>
<link>https://www.elevationlab.com/blogs/news/amazon-is-complicit-with-counterfeit-sellers</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.elevationlab.com/blogs/news/amazon-is-complicit-with-counterfeit-sellers</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;When someone goes to the lengths of making counterfeits of your products, it's at least a sign you're doing something right. And it deserves a minute of flattery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But when Chinese counterfeiters tool up and make copies of your product, send that inventory to Amazon, then overtake the real product's buy box by auto-lowering the price - it's a real problem. Customers are &lt;em&gt;unknowingly&lt;/em&gt; buying crap versions of the product, while both Amazon and the scammers are profiting, and the reputation you've built goes down the toilet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you've paid Amazon a boat load of money to advertise the product you've designed, built, invested in, and shipped - it's further insult to injury. And when new counterfeit sellers keep popping up every week so you have to play whack-a-mole with Amazon, who take days to remove the sellers, it's the beginning of the end for your small business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is exactly what has happened to us.&lt;/strong&gt; Our popular product &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00P31BMHG&quot; title=&quot;The Anchor&quot;&gt;The Anchor&lt;/a&gt;, the first under desk headphone mount, with 1500+ reviews, has been getting flooded with counterfeits. The current counterfeit seller, suiningdonghanjiaju Co Ltd (yeah they sound legit), has been on there for the past 5 days and taken all the sales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0131/4552/files/Screen_Shot_2018-03-01_at_1.59.04_PM_1024x1024.png?v=1519941658&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They literally reverse engineered it, made steel compression molds, made the logo wrong, used fake 3M adhesive that's very thin and was diecut smaller than the top (measure once, cut twice), they use a lower durometer silicone so it flexes more, its has huge mold parting lines, and the packaging is literally photocopied then reprinted (you can tell by the lack of image contrast). And they had to apply a big sticker to cover our SKU with theirs. But to the untrained eye, it would pass. Can't wait for the negative reviews to come...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can't blame the Chinese counterfeiters for doing it. They are getting paid, they remain anonymous, they know they will face no legal recourse, and the worst that could happen to them is to have their listing removed and counterfeit inventory returned (not destroyed). &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Amazon's policies promote this.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There is something extremely simple Amazon could do about it.&lt;/strong&gt; If you have a registered brand in the Brand Registry and don't sell the product wholesale - there could be one box to check for that. And anyone else would have to get approval or high vetting to sell the product, especially if they are sending large quantities to FBA. I imagine there are some algorithmic solutions that could catch most of it too. And it wouldn't hurt to increase the size of the Brand Registry team so they can do their work faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why Amazon doesn't do this is mind-blowing and makes them complicit in the rampant counterfeiting on their platform. We are definitely not the first seller for this to happen to. And it lowers Amazon customers trust in the platform when they unknowingly receive knockoffs. And the real sellers also have to police this themselves, Amazon isn't active in going after them - and Amazon can hide behind the fact that independent sellers are doing the counterfeiting (though most people, like my Mom, wouldn't read the fineprint of who it's technically &quot;sold by&quot; - they are just buying from Amazon when they buy something on Amazon). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon could also set the bar a little higher for Chinese sellers trying to sell existing products. Because 9/10 times I'd bet they are ripping off an established brand - the margin math wouldn't work and I've never heard of any brand selling to a Chinese seller to then sell on Amazon USA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the record, I love Amazon as a customer, I buy way too much stuff with Prime, I'm a long shareholder, and think they are on track to become the biggest company in the world (unless they get broken up for anti-trust reasons). But if you buy anything on Amazon, take a minute to look at the seller. &lt;strong&gt;Better yet, buy products direct so you can be assured you are not getting a fake. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And Jeff Bezos, if you're reading this, come on - this is day 2 activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-Casey Hopkins&lt;br/&gt;Founder, Elevation Lab&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 01:11:09 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>hop</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.elevationlab.com/blogs/news/amazon-is-complicit-with-counterfeit-sellers</og:url>
<og:title>Amazon is complicit with counterfeiting</og:title>
<og:description>When someone goes to the lengths of making counterfeits of your products, it's at least a sign you're doing something right. And it deserves a minute of flatter</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0131/4552/articles/IMG_0911_2_small.JPG?v=1519942663</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.elevationlab.com/blogs/news/amazon-is-complicit-with-counterfeit-sellers</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Firefox Configuration Guide for Privacy Freaks and Performance Buffs</title>
<link>http://12bytes.org/tech/firefox/firefoxgecko-configuration-guide-for-privacy-and-performance-buffs</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://12bytes.org/tech/firefox/firefoxgecko-configuration-guide-for-privacy-and-performance-buffs</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;See the revision history at the end of this document for a list of changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of us are aware of the immense threats to our privacy and security posed by a plethora of technology corporations, governments and malicious hackers, some of which often go to great lengths to monitor our communications and web browsing habits. Governments and their “intelligence” apparatuses not only spy on each other, but on the citizenry as well and they leverage the services of many mega-corporations to do so, including &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2013/jun/06/us-tech-giants-nsa-data&quot;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://venturebeat.com/2014/05/15/how-the-nsa-fbi-made-facebook-the-perfect-mass-surveillance-tool/&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2013/jun/06/nsa-phone-records-verizon-court-order&quot;&gt;Verizon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.deepdotweb.com/2014/09/13/comcast-declares-war-tor/&quot;&gt;Comcast&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whatreallyhappened.com/WRHARTICLES/spyring2.html&quot;&gt;Amdocs&lt;/a&gt; and countless others, many of which most of us have probably never heard of. While this data may be used for relatively benign purposes, such as displaying ads on web pages, all too often the intentions are far more sinister and invasive. Much of what &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/edward-snowden&quot;&gt;Edward Snowden&lt;/a&gt; has brought to the table is not new at all, but it seems the information has been presented in a way that has captured the attention of much of the public, prompting those who value their privacy to seek ways to mitigate the threats. The goal of this guide is to help the reader to thwart some of the efforts to track and profile us as we surf our way around the World Wide Web. Notice i intentionally use the word “some” for several reasons; 1) because there are too many variables and vectors for attack and 2) because i am in no way an expert on computer security or privacy. If you want to go further than this guide will carry you, check the resources section which includes this fine article, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iotdarwinaward.com/post/improve-your-privacy-in-age-of-mass-surveillance/&quot;&gt;Improve Your Privacy in the Age of Mass Surveillance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a personal experience that may interest you…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I once sold a PC to a guy and we got to talking about the government. He said he had worked for the government either directly or as a contractor. I don’t recall which. He said he had a security clearance and i believe it was a crypto clearance. Our time together was limited, but he touched upon some very interesting topics that i wanted to know more about and so i suggested we continue our conversation through encrypted email. He looked at me and said, “encryption is useless”. Obviously encryption is not entirely useless, but i think what he meant is that, if it is certain government agencies that are targeting you, then indeed it is useless. The point is that one should never make the mistake of assuming that their privacy is guaranteed, no matter what precautions have been taken.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many of us, our web browser is the primary interface we use to explore the digital world and it is therefore necessary for any privacy conscious individual to consider what information our web browsers are sending and receiving and how that information can be used to track our on-line activities and profile us. Only then can we take action to circumvent some of these threats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contrary to the statements made in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/about/manifesto/&quot;&gt;The Mozilla Manifesto&lt;/a&gt;, it is my opinion that, while its flagship product, the Firefox web browser, may be more privacy-centric than the other mainstream web browsers, securing the privacy of its audience is but an afterthought for the non-profit, &lt;a title=&quot;2013 Mozilla Foundation Public Disclosure&quot; href=&quot;https://static.mozilla.com/moco/en-US/pdf/2013_Mozilla_Foundation_Fed_990_Public_Disclosure.pdf&quot;&gt;multi-million dollar Mozilla Foundation&lt;/a&gt;. This is readily apparent when one considers the array of ethically challenged multinationals which Mozilla has chosen to hop in bed with, including Google, Yahoo, Microsoft, Telefónica, LG Electronics, Sony, Verizon, Cisco and others. Even the now defunct Firefox Pocket service was tied to a 3rd party company and it seems more unnecessary and unwanted “features” are being added with each iteration of the browser. And then there’s the ‘Looking Glass’ fiasco which you can read about in a post titled &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://12bytes.org/11087/the-next-bright-idea-from-mozilla&quot;&gt;Looking Glass: The next ‘bright idea’ from Mozilla&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.globalresearch.ca/google-nsa-nexus-new-chromium-browser-installs-eavesdropping-tool-on-your-pc/5457864&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt; is no better and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.techdirt.com/articles/20140725/11013528006/french-company-that-sells-exploits-to-nsa-sat-internet-explorer-vulnerability-three-years.shtml&quot;&gt;Internet Explorer&lt;/a&gt; isn’t worth the effort required to express an opinion as far as i’m concerned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That being said, i think Firefox is still a viable product in many ways and it is still one of the most hackable mainstream web browsers out there. Because it is open source and open to customization, i believe the Gecko family of browsers are good candidates for those who wish to reduce their exposure to privacy and security threats. The folks behind the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.torproject.org/&quot;&gt;Tor Project&lt;/a&gt; seem to think so as well since Firefox is included in their &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.torproject.org/projects/torbrowser.html.en&quot;&gt;Tor Browser Bundle&lt;/a&gt;, though i suspect possibly &lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/&quot;&gt;not for much longer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This guide covers primarily the configuration of Firefox and the add-ons we will be deploying and ends there. For additional privacy you may wish to consider using a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Virtual_private_network&quot;&gt;VPN&lt;/a&gt;. Personally i use and recommend &lt;a href=&quot;https://airvpn.org/?referred_by=223784&quot;&gt;AirVPN&lt;/a&gt; due to their privacy policy, ethics, price and good service, as well as the fact that they run a lot of servers all around the globe and do not restrict any protocol, including BitTorrent traffic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;a-special-note-about-cryptocurrency-miners&quot;&gt;A special note about cryptocurrency miners&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People are now &lt;a href=&quot;https://jonathanmh.com/testing-coin-hive-crowd-source-monero-mining/&quot;&gt;creating scripts to mine cryptocurrencies&lt;/a&gt; which run in your web browser and use your CPU power to mine virtual currencies for them while you visit websites which employ these scripts. I first learned about this when &lt;a href=&quot;https://torrentfreak.com/the-pirate-bay-website-runs-a-cryptocurrency-miner-170916/&quot;&gt;The Pirate Bay used such a script&lt;/a&gt; in certain sections of its website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a very interesting development and it will be equally interesting to see how wide-spread this becomes. Just days after TPB was found running its Monero mining script, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://profiles.wordpress.org/denniske1001#content-plugins&quot;&gt;cryptocurrency mining plug-in for WordPress&lt;/a&gt; was published on wordpress.org.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first i saw these mining scripts as pure malware and, in fact, i would say it was indeed highly unethical when The Pirate Bay introduced it secretively and forced it upon its visitors who had JavaScript enabled without making it opt-in. Soon after, ad-blockers, including uBlock Origin, as well as anti-virus software vendors, started &lt;a href=&quot;https://torrentfreak.com/cryptocurrency-miner-targeted-by-anti-virus-and-adblock-tools-170926/&quot;&gt;targeting these mining scripts&lt;/a&gt;. After giving it some thought however, this seems like it might be an excellent way for independent journalists and others to generate some “cash” to support their work without having to annoy visitors with obtrusive ads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the “&lt;em&gt;uBlock Origin configuration&lt;/em&gt;” section below, you will find that i have included a filter list to block these cryptocurrency scripts from running, at least for now. Hopefully this will change in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;audience&quot;&gt;Audience&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This guide is intended for those who are somewhat technically inclined, or are at least willing to learn, and who wish to reduce the threats to their privacy while enhancing browser security and performance. We will attempt to accomplish these goals while maintaining a reasonably carefree web browsing experience which means there will be some trade-offs between security and privacy for ease of use, but you can always adjust to suit your particular needs. This guide is not intended as a complete solution for those whose well-being depends on anonymity (whistle-blowers, investigative journalists, etc.), though it may be a worthy supplement to more specific information. This guide is, a), a work in progress and b), not authoritative since i do not claim to be an authority on Firefox, internet security or digital privacy. There are simply too many technologies, options and attack vectors for me to comprehend in something as incredibly complex as the modern web browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though this guide is centered around Firefox, it should also be useful for users of other Gecko-based programs, including the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.seamonkey-project.org/&quot;&gt;SeaMonkey&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.debian.org/Iceweasel&quot;&gt;Iceweasel&lt;/a&gt; browsers, as well as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/thunderbird/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Thunderbird&lt;/a&gt; email client and perhaps any others who value their privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mozilla Firefox browser is based on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Mozilla/Gecko&quot;&gt;Gecko layout engine&lt;/a&gt; and, as with any mainstream browser, it is a very complex beast consisting of millions of lines of code and hundreds of configuration options, many of which are interlinked, obscure, or even hidden. Change a few settings without knowing what you’re doing and things can go south pretty quick. Poorly coded add-ons can compound the problem, especially when they conflict with one another. Here we will attempt to accomplish our goals in an efficient manner with a minimal dependency upon 3rd party browser add-ons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/extensions/privacy-security/&quot;&gt;huge selection of Firefox add-ons&lt;/a&gt; for tweaking privacy and security, some of the most popular of which are Adblock Plus and it’s many derivatives, NoScript, Flashblock, Ghostery, Web of Trust, BetterPrivacy, Lightbeam, Disconnect, Self-Destructing Cookies, Cookies Manager+, Request Policy, Policeman, Bluhell Firewall, RefControl, Smart Referer, HTTPS Everywhere and many, many others. With some possible exceptions, we won’t be using any of these, yet will retain much of the most important functionality offered by most of them with just a few add-ons, along with a plethora of changes to our Firefox configuration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A bit of a trade-off should be expected as we tighten up on security and privacy insomuch as some websites will cease to function properly until the settings for the affected sites are adjusted. Anyone who has used a content filter such as NoScript will understand that certain resources must be allowed for many websites to function in a way that is acceptable to us. As with NoScript however, the process of allowing these resources with the add-ons suggested herein, usually requires little more than a mouse click or two and a page refresh. Furthermore, once we have visited all of our favorite websites and made the necessary adjustments, our workload will be greatly reduced. Nevertheless, you should be prepared to put a little more effort into your web browsing experience in general and expect the occasional hard-case which will require more fiddling than usual to get a particular site to function properly. The pay-off however is a much cleaner, faster, garbage-free web that is less able to track and profile us as well as a hardened Firefox that is more resistant to &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.sophos.com/en-us/2014/03/26/how-malware-works-anatomy-of-a-drive-by-download-web-attack-infographic/&quot;&gt;attack&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;terminology&quot;&gt;Terminology&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/&quot;&gt;AMO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: The Mozilla add-ons website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Device_fingerprint&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Browser fingerprinting&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: A method whereby a web server attempts to uniquely identify your configuration (browser, operating system, etc.) using various methods, including information contained in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_HTTP_header_fields&quot;&gt;HTTP headers&lt;/a&gt;, information collected with &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/JavaScript&quot;&gt;JavaScript&lt;/a&gt;, querying cached data, enumerating installed plug-ins, visited websites, installed languages and more. For more information, see &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2010/01/primer-information-theory-and-privacy&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Primer on Information Theory and Privacy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_storage&quot;&gt;Browser storage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (web storage: cache, cookies, etc.): The modern web browser is a far more sophisticated tool than most people probably realize. In addition to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTP_cookie&quot;&gt;HTTP cookies&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_cache&quot;&gt;web caching&lt;/a&gt;, any modern web browser also allows a web server to store data using &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_storage&quot;&gt;local and session storage&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Indexed_Database_API&quot;&gt;indexedDB storage&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTP_cookie#window.name&quot;&gt;window.name storage&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTP_ETag&quot;&gt;Etag cache storage&lt;/a&gt; and whatever other methods i may not be aware of. If you are concerned about preserving your inherent right to privacy, you have far more to worry about than so-called “cookies” which were once just simple text files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pre-installed_software&quot;&gt;Crapware&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: For the purpose of this document, crapware is considered to be code that is included in a browser or browser extension which is not relevant to the functionality users expect. For me, the term crapware encompasses adware, tracking mechanisms and malicious code. Crapware is often added to browser extensions (add-ons) by a marketing company or solo developer for the purpose of monetizing the extension. Crapware can present a significant threat to user privacy and browser security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Content_delivery_network&quot;&gt;CDN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: A Content Delivery Network is a service that often hosts reusable content, such as graphics and scripts, which website authors can leverage to make pages load faster. CDNs can also present a threat to our privacy by tracking our web activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cascading_Style_Sheets&quot;&gt;CSS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Cascading Style Sheets are used to format and beautify website content. CSS itself presents little or no risk to privacy or security so far as i am aware since it is used primarily to apply visual styling to HTML elements, however it can be used for nefarious purposes when combined with a scripting language such as JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain_name&quot;&gt;Domain&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Subdomain&quot;&gt;Sub-domain&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hostname&quot;&gt;Hostname&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Top-level_domain&quot;&gt;TLD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: For the purposes of this document a domain name and a hostname are interchangeable, both being human-friendly names for a website, such as &lt;code&gt;example.com&lt;/code&gt;. A 1st party domain is the website you are currently viewing, (&lt;code&gt;12bytes.org&lt;/code&gt; at the moment) while a 3rd party domain could be a web server which supplies content to the 1st party domain. For example, the web page &lt;code&gt;http://example.com/video&lt;/code&gt; may include a video that is provided by &lt;code&gt;youtube.com&lt;/code&gt;, making &lt;code&gt;youtube.com&lt;/code&gt; a 3rd party domain. A sub-domain is a separate part of the root domain. For example, &lt;code&gt;sub.example.com&lt;/code&gt; is a sub-domain of &lt;code&gt;example.com&lt;/code&gt;. A TLD is a Top Level Domain. For example the &lt;code&gt;com&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;example.com&lt;/code&gt; is the Top Level Domain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hypertext_Transfer_Protocol&quot;&gt;HTTP&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTPS&quot;&gt;HTTPS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Hypertext Transfer Protocol and Hypertext Transfer Protocol Secure are protocols used for sending and receiving data across the Internet. For HTTP, an unsecured, unencrypted connection to the server is established which is vulnerable to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Man-in-the-middle_attack&quot;&gt;man-in-the-middle attacks&lt;/a&gt;, while a secure, encrypted connection is established with HTTPS. One reason you should be concerned with unencrypted connections is the fact that it is possible for anyone between your computer and the site you are visiting, including your ISP (Internet Service Provider), to eavesdrop on your traffic and discover exactly what websites you are visiting and what you may be doing there. While browser extensions like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/https-everywhere%20&quot;&gt;HTTPS Everywhere&lt;/a&gt; will attempt to encrypt your connection whenever possible, some web servers simply do not offer HTTPS. For this reason i will again point out the advantage of &lt;a href=&quot;https://airvpn.org/?referred_by=223784&quot;&gt;using a VPN&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/IndexedDB_API&quot;&gt;IndexDB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (aka “local storage”, “web storage”): The IndexDB API (application programming interface) is somewhat similar to what we once knew as “cookies” before IndexDB was developed. It is a method which websites can leverage to permanently store a very large amounts of data locally, meaning on your computer. The path where this data is stored for Firefox is: &lt;code&gt;/[your Firefox profile folder]/storage/default/&lt;/code&gt;. IndexDB data for a particular domain can only be accessed by that domain. If you choose to delete IndexDB data, be aware that some Firefox add-ons use IndexDB to store their settings, including uBlock Origin and uMatrix. The IndexDB objects for extensions is prefixed with &lt;code&gt;moz-extension&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/JavaScript&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JavaScript&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (JS): A powerful programming language that is used to run code within the browser. Although JavaScript is used by many websites for legitimate reasons, it can and often is used maliciously to perform a wide variety of attacks against the browser and your privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/User_interface&quot;&gt;UI/GUI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: A User Interface, also known as a Graphic User Interface, is the graphical portion of a program usually containing various controls, such as buttons, check-boxes and other widgets which allow you to interact with the underlying code. UIs are often referred to as “windows”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_server&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Web server&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: For the purpose of this document, a web server is a computer that is connected to the internet which hosts (serves) one or more websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ghacks.net/2017/03/09/firefox-legacy-add-on-or-webextension-how-to-find-out/&quot;&gt;WebExtension/Legacy extensions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: from version 57 onwards, Firefox will no longer support so-called “legacy” extensions and instead will move to WebExtensions exclusively which is the same format used by the Google Chrome web browser. The unfortunate result is that many existing extensions in the AMO repository will simply stop working unless their developers port their code to the new format. The problem with porting the code is that the WebExtension API (Application Programmer Interface) does not offer the same level of functionality and therefore many extensions simply cannot be ported. Further compounding the problem for developers is that Mozilla has changed the Firefox extension API several times in as many years, thus forcing developers to rewrite their code multiple times. Note that the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.waterfoxproject.org/&quot;&gt;Waterfox&lt;/a&gt; developer has stated that he will support both WebExtensions and legacy extensions, so you may want to consider using it if you depend on legacy extensions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;prerequisites&quot;&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;getting-firefox&quot;&gt;Getting Firefox&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several flavors of Firefox other than the &lt;a title=&quot;Download Firefox&quot; href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/all/&quot;&gt;mainstream release&lt;/a&gt;, including the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/organizations/&quot;&gt;Firefox ESR&lt;/a&gt; (Extended Support Release) version which is usually an older version that may not contain the latest features, but may be more stable. If you’re running Linux, you may already have Iceweasel installed, which is nearly identical to Mozilla Firefox. Another option is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/developer/&quot;&gt;Firefox Developer Edition&lt;/a&gt; which, though i have not tested it with the configuration outlined in this guide, should work fine. Another option is &lt;a href=&quot;https://8pecxstudios.com/&quot;&gt;Cyberfox&lt;/a&gt; from 8pecxstudios, though, again, i have not tested it with the configuration outlined in this guide. Cyberfox may be more privacy-centric than other versions in that several phone-home features have apparently been gutted, including telemetry, health reporting and possibly the Google “Safe Browsing” feature. One caveat with Cyberfox is that, like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.palemoon.org/&quot;&gt;Pale Moon&lt;/a&gt;, it uses a different format for some of the profile files which requires using a tool to convert your current Firefox profile should you want to import your data. Lastly i would mention &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.waterfoxproject.org/&quot;&gt;Waterfox&lt;/a&gt; as it seems to be an excellent, speedy, privacy-centric alternative to the official Mozilla build which will apparently continue to support legacy extensions. I personally use and have tested Waterfox with this guide. As for the many other custom builds of Firefox, a lot of them are not worthwhile and can/will cause problems due to bugs, add-on incompatibilities, etc.. The last time i tried Pale Moon i ran into some problems as well, though that was long ago and so the issues i had may have been resolved so feel free to try it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;firefox-post-install-cleanup&quot;&gt;Firefox post install cleanup&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some browsers that are based on Firefox may have some extensions, plug-ins and/or search engines preinstalled. Take care to check for this and uninstall or disable any extras that you don’t want. The search engine configuration files are located in the &lt;code&gt;\Mozilla Firefox\browser\searchplugins&lt;/code&gt; folder up to version 57. From version 58 onwards, apparently this folder will disappear. I highly suggest reading my guides, &lt;a href=&quot;http://12bytes.org/tech/firefox/firefox-search-engine-cautions-and-recommendations&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Opting out of the Firefox / Google / Yahoo partnership&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://12bytes.org/tech/firefox/firefox-search-engine-cautions-and-recommendations&quot;&gt;Firefox Search Engine Cautions and Recommendations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; for more detailed information about how Mozilla monetizes Firefox with the included search engines and what you can do to opt out of this affiliate scheme if you so choose. The latter guide also includes information and removal instructions regarding what Mozilla calls “&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/21431&quot;&gt;system extensions&lt;/a&gt;” which are essentially hidden from the user, some of which are used for quite nefarious purposes in my opinion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have already run Firefox you may notice that it has installed the OpenH264 Video Codec plug-in by Cisco Systems without asking you. Currently this plug-in seems to be used only for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WebRTC&quot;&gt;WebRTC&lt;/a&gt; feature. If you do not use these features and do not want the browser to load this plug-in, you can delete the &lt;code&gt;\gmp-gmpopenh264&lt;/code&gt; folder in your profile directory along with the all of its contents. To prevent re-installation, make sure the configuration preferences &lt;code&gt;media.gmp-gmpopenh264.enabled&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;media.gmp-gmpopenh264.autoupdate&lt;/code&gt; are both set to &lt;code&gt;false&lt;/code&gt; before the browser is restarted (they already are in the &lt;code&gt;user.js&lt;/code&gt; file linked to below).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;browser-object-caching&quot;&gt;Browser object caching&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Browser caching is a disk intensive activity where resources such as images are stored locally in order to reduce page loading times upon subsequent visits to the page. If you intend to store cache data, i would suggest storing it in system RAM rather than on your hard drive or SSD if you have enough memory available. Even 50 or 100 megabytes of space can help reduce disk workload for websites which you visit often. The settings in the Pants/ghacks &lt;code&gt;user.js&lt;/code&gt; file linked to below will accomplish this, so if you do not want to store web cache in RAM, you will need to change these settings accordingly. Note that Firefox requires cache size values to be in kilobytes where 1024 KB = 1 MB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;the-userjs-file&quot;&gt;The user.js file&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The primary &lt;code&gt;user.js&lt;/code&gt; file we will be using is a result of allot of effort by the ‘ghacks’ guys whose work became rather popular when it was published under the title, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ghacks.net/2015/08/18/a-comprehensive-list-of-firefox-privacy-and-security-settings/&quot;&gt;A comprehensive list of Firefox privacy and security settings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; by Martin Brinkmann at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ghacks.net/&quot;&gt;ghacks.net&lt;/a&gt;. This work is also now published on GitHub which is where we will be getting it from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ghacksuserjs/ghacks-user.js&quot;&gt;ghacksuserjs/ghacks-user.js&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;user.js&lt;/code&gt; file that we want is hosted on GitHub. To download the file, click on the “release” link. Make sure to download the version which corresponds to the major version of Firefox you are running, so if your Firefox version is 51.0.1 for example, 51 being the major version, then download version v51 of the &lt;code&gt;user.js&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether you want to use &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/atomGit/Firefox-user.js&quot;&gt;my user.js file&lt;/a&gt; in addition to the ghacks one is entirely optional. Note that my &lt;code&gt;user.js&lt;/code&gt; was created as a supplement to the ghacks &lt;code&gt;user.js&lt;/code&gt; above and not a replacement. Some of my preferences are original and some are copies of those in the ghacks version where i changed their values to suit my own needs. In the latter case i tend to be slightly more relaxed with my privacy and security settings in return for a less problematic web surfing experience. It also contains preferences to enable smooth, dynamic scrolling when using a mouse wheel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ghacks crew and i both follow a similar versioning scheme except i add a revision number after the major version number, so where their version might be v51, mine would be v51r1 if it is the first revision, v51r2 for the second revision and so on. If you supplement the ghacks &lt;code&gt;user.js&lt;/code&gt; with my own, you will want the latest revision that corresponds to the major version of Firefox that you’re running. How to combine the two files is explained at the top of my &lt;code&gt;user.js&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;the-necessary-and-not-so-necessary-add-ons&quot;&gt;The necessary (and not so necessary) add-ons&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This guide depends heavily upon the following add-ons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gorhill/uBlock/releases&quot;&gt;Block Origin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: uBlock Origin, by the same developer of uMatrix, is a powerful content filter which works similarly to uMatrix but is tailored to blocking ads. These two excellent extensions compliment each other nicely when they are configured properly. uBlock can use the same filter lists as Adblock Plus for blocking ads, as well as many more which it cannot. There are currently two versions available; the original by Raymond Hill which has been renamed to uBlock Origin, and a fork by Chris Aljoudi which you do not want to use. uBlock Origin is an active project that offers features not found in Chris’ build, which appears to be dead anyway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gorhill/uMatrix&quot;&gt;uMatrix&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: You can think of uMatrix as a browser firewall which can block requests to 1st and 3rd party resources such as JavaScript, images, CSS, plug-ins, frames and more. uMatrix works with Firefox, Chrome and Opera and is &lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/umatrix/&quot;&gt;available on AMO&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following add-ons are optional, but recommended:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/cookie-autodelete/&quot;&gt;Cookie AutoDelete&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (WebExtension): automatically removes cookies, but see the description for Cookies Exterminator below. Note that only one extension should be used to control cookies/storage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/cookies-exterminator/&quot;&gt;Cookies Exterminator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (Legacy): automatically removes cookies, localStorage and IndexedDB objects as soon as they become unused, thus helping to prevent tracking through these objects. Note that as of Dec., 2017, there are no WebExtension add-ons capable of removing LocalStorage items due to limitations in the Firefox WebExtension API. Note that only one extension should be used to control cookies/storage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/decentraleyes/&quot;&gt;Decentraleyes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (WebExtension): this add-on helps protect privacy and speeds-up page rendering by loading several common JavaScript libraries locally rather than fetching them from a CDN. If you use this add-on, you will need to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Synzvato/decentraleyes/wiki/Frequently-Asked-Questions&quot;&gt;whitelist several domains&lt;/a&gt; in uMatrix. When adding the list of domains, be sure that no block rules exist for the same domains.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/header-editor/&quot;&gt;Header Editor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (WebExtension): allows to modify HTTP request and response headers. You can use this to prevent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ghacks.net/2017/12/09/a-solution-to-etag-tracking-in-firefox/&quot;&gt;ETag tracking&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/https-everywhere/&quot;&gt;HTTPS Everywhere&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (WebExtension): forces websites to serve content securely (HTTPS).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/load-from-cache/?src=ss&quot;&gt;Load from Cache&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (Legacy): similar in principle to, but not the same as Decentraleyes, Load from Cache forces the browser to reuse cached data instead of downloading it again. The two work well together.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/neat-url/&quot;&gt;Neat URL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (WebExtension): helps to protect your privacy by striping tracking/garbage parameters from URLs, such as those used by Google Analytics (&lt;code&gt;utm_source&lt;/code&gt;, etc.).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/skip-redirect/&quot;&gt;Skip Redirect&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (WebExtension): skips link redirections such as used by Google and many other companies, thus helping to prevent tracking. For example, Skip Redirect will convert this ugly mess:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;code&gt;https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/new/&amp;amp;sa=U&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwj5z9u1kYLYAhXp1IMKHUvdDb4QFggUMAA&amp;amp;usg=AOvVaw3p80z20jidbJ4GWjzLC0Hq&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br/&gt;to this:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;code&gt;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/new/&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/webapi-manager/&quot;&gt;WebAPI Manager&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (WebExtension): limits how a website can interact with the Firefox web browser, thus increasing your level of privacy and security. Note that this add-on will require some reading to use properly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following add-ons are completely optional:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/noscript/&quot;&gt;NoScript Security Suite&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: since uMatrix will be used to block scripts, this functionality is not required from NoScript, though it may add a bit more protection in terms of cross-site request forgeries, click hijacking and possibly other areas. If you use NoScript i would recommend disabling global script blocking and use uMatrix to handle scripts, though you could do it the other way around if you wanted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;For more possibilities regarding add-ons, see my article &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://12bytes.org/tech/firefox/firefox-extensions-my-picks&quot;&gt;Firefox Extensions: My Picks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. as well as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ghacksuserjs/ghacks-user.js/wiki#small_orange_diamond-scripts&quot;&gt;Scripts&lt;/a&gt; section of the ghacksuserjs wiki.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re running Windows (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Zu0l-Ac7fTU&quot;&gt;shame on you&lt;/a&gt;) and want to unpack an add-on to have a look at the code, you can use &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.7-zip.org/&quot;&gt;7-Zip&lt;/a&gt;. I believe the built-in Windows archive utility can unpack &lt;code&gt;.xpi&lt;/code&gt; files also, though you may have to add the &lt;code&gt;.zip&lt;/code&gt; extension.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;automatic-add-on-updates&quot;&gt;Automatic add-on updates&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding automatic add-on updates, they are disabled in the &lt;code&gt;user.js&lt;/code&gt; file that is linked to below and i would highly suggest keeping them disabled. Automatic checking for updates may be enabled in the ghacks &lt;code&gt;user.js&lt;/code&gt; by the time you read this and that’s fine, however the problem with automatic add-on updates is that developers may, at any time and without warning, partner with or sell their work to a 3rd party which often results in added code to monetize the add-on at the cost of your privacy. Examples of some very popular Firefox add-ons which contain such crapware are &lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/abduction/privacy/&quot;&gt;Abduction&lt;/a&gt;, a screen capture utility, &lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/quick-locale-switcher/privacy/&quot;&gt;Quick Locale Switcher&lt;/a&gt;, a language switcher, &lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/fasterfox-9148/privacy/&quot;&gt;FasterFox Lite&lt;/a&gt;, a largely useless utility which claims to speed-up Firefox but doesn’t, &lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/blocksite/privacy/&quot;&gt;BlockSite&lt;/a&gt;, a content blocker, Google’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/&quot;&gt;Search By Image&lt;/a&gt;, a reverse image search utility, and many others. Not all of these extensions contained crapware when they were first developed which is why i strongly suggest keeping automatic add-on updates disabled and reading the change logs and privacy policies carefully each time an add-on update is available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For peace of mind, you can also search your &lt;code&gt;prefs.js&lt;/code&gt; file for all instances of “http” and check what the URLs are used for. If you want to disable the functionality you can simply add the preference to your &lt;code&gt;user.js&lt;/code&gt; file and replace the URL with &lt;code&gt;&quot;&quot;&lt;/code&gt;, or &lt;code&gt;localhost&lt;/code&gt;, or you could point the URL to &lt;code&gt;localhost&lt;/code&gt; in your &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.rackspace.com/how-to/modify-your-hosts-file/&quot;&gt;HOSTS file&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;backup-your-current-profile&quot;&gt;Backup your current profile&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Before you make any changes, be sure to back-up your current Firefox profile&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;http://kb.mozillazine.org/Profile_folder_-_Firefox&quot;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt; to locate it if you don’t already know). The easiest way to do this is to simply to select your profile folder inside the &lt;code&gt;/Firefox&lt;/code&gt; folder, press &lt;code&gt;Ctrl+C&lt;/code&gt; to copy it, then &lt;code&gt;Ctrl+V&lt;/code&gt; to paste it in the same place with a different name. I might suggest keeping the original name and just appending &lt;code&gt;.bak&lt;/code&gt; to the copy. Next, delete your current &lt;code&gt;user.js&lt;/code&gt; file if you have one in your profile folder, but keep the one in your backup profile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;editing-the-userjs-file&quot;&gt;Editing the user.js file&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you do not have a comprehensive understanding of the the &lt;code&gt;user.js&lt;/code&gt; file that is used by Firefox, i highly suggest r&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ghacksuserjs/ghacks-user.js/wiki/1.1-Overview&quot;&gt;eading this wiki article&lt;/a&gt; at GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will be changing many Firefox preferences and storing them in a custom &lt;a href=&quot;http://kb.mozillazine.org/User.js_file&quot;&gt;user.js file&lt;/a&gt;. You should always use this file to add, remove or change settings that you want to keep across sessions instead of editing the &lt;code&gt;prefs.js&lt;/code&gt; file or using &lt;code&gt;about:config&lt;/code&gt;. If you’re running Windows i would suggest using a quality text/code editor that has syntax highlighting such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://notepad-plus-plus.org/&quot;&gt;Notepad++&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pspad.com/en/&quot;&gt;PSPad&lt;/a&gt; (the latter being a little simpler to use) for editing code. Linux users will likely already have something suitable installed, like &lt;a href=&quot;https://kate-editor.org/&quot;&gt;Kate&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Build your new &lt;code&gt;user.js&lt;/code&gt; file by starting with the ghacks file and then, if you want to use my settings also, simply append the code from my &lt;code&gt;user.js&lt;/code&gt; to theirs. If you already have a &lt;code&gt;user.js&lt;/code&gt; file you will want to be sure to address any preferences which may be duplicated in your new &lt;code&gt;user.js&lt;/code&gt; file in order to avoid unexpected results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;!!! IMPORTANT !!!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please read through this section in its entirety before making any changes in order to gain an understanding of exactly what we will be doing and how to revert those changes should it be necessary.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Because my &lt;code&gt;user.js&lt;/code&gt; file is updated frequently and i wish to avoid the hassle of editing these settings for public consumption each time i update it, the settings it contains are a direct copy of my personal settings. You should therefore read all of the comments in it and review each of the settings carefully as it is very likely that you will want to change some of them&lt;/strong&gt;. See below for my advice on how to edit the existing settings, as well as adding your own.&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;code&gt;user.js&lt;/code&gt; file(s) you downloaded, you will notice the presence of a bogus preferences, &lt;code&gt;_user.js.parrot&lt;/code&gt;, that the ghacks boys and i insert at the beginning of each section of our preferences. &lt;strong&gt;Firefox reads the &lt;code&gt;user.js&lt;/code&gt; file from the top down and, if it encounters a syntax error, it will ignore everything following that error which could present a serious risk to those concerned with privacy and security&lt;/strong&gt;. Not good! To make it easy to discover whether Firefox loaded all of the preferences successfully, these bogus preferences, which Firefox essentially ignores, are used for troubleshooting (this will be explained later).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you want to make changes to your new &lt;code&gt;user.js&lt;/code&gt; file, such as incorporating settings from your old one, or change anything else in it, i highly recommend appending all of your changes to the end of the file in your own custom section instead of editing the settings throughout the file&lt;/strong&gt;. You will find an example section has already been created at the end of my &lt;code&gt;user.js&lt;/code&gt; file for you to place your personal preferences. There is a very good reason why i suggest placing your preferences at the end of the file. Again, these &lt;code&gt;user.js&lt;/code&gt; files are updated frequently and therefore it will be vastly easier to simply delete the contents of the old file, with the exception of your personal settings which you appended to the end of it, and copy and paste the contents of the new files above your personal preferences. This avoids the headache of having to sift through the entire file trying to remember and reset everything you changed prior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making changes to your &lt;code&gt;user.js&lt;/code&gt; file is easy to do. For example, the value for the preference  &lt;code&gt;browser.tabs.warnOnClose&lt;/code&gt; might be ‘&lt;code&gt;false&lt;/code&gt;‘ and you might want to change it to ‘&lt;code&gt;true&lt;/code&gt;‘ to have Firefox warn you when you try to close it with multiple tabs still open. The best way to accomplish this is to copy that line of code, &lt;code&gt;user_pref(&quot;browser.tabs.warnOnClose&quot;, felse);&lt;/code&gt;, and paste it at the end of the file in your own personal preferences section where you would then change ‘&lt;code&gt;false&lt;/code&gt;‘ to ‘&lt;code&gt;true&lt;/code&gt;‘. Having duplicate preferences with different values is not a problem since Firefox will use the value of the last one it reads, thus why you need to place your personal settings at the end of the file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At this point it is important to read all of the comments and review each of the settings in your new &lt;code&gt;user.js&lt;/code&gt; file to be sure each preference is configured the way you want, preferably before you start Firefox&lt;/strong&gt;. As stated above, any preferences you want to change should be copied to your personal preferences section at the end of the file where you will then make the change to the preference value. Note that if you comment out or delete a setting after having run Firefox, that setting will remain active because it will have been copied to the &lt;code&gt;prefs.js&lt;/code&gt; file, so if you want to comment out or remove something from your new &lt;code&gt;user.js&lt;/code&gt; file, you should do so before starting Firefox. If you delete or comment out a setting after you have run Firefox, simply enter &lt;code&gt;about:config&lt;/code&gt; in the Firefox address bar, find the preference, right click it and click “Reset”. The preference and/or value will then be deleted. This only need be done if you remove or comment out a preference and is not necessary when simply changing their values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you are finished editing your new &lt;code&gt;user.js&lt;/code&gt; file, simply drop it in your profile folder alongside &lt;code&gt;prefs.js&lt;/code&gt; and start Firefox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;verifying-the-integrity-of-your-userjs-file&quot;&gt;Verifying the integrity of your user.js file&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This integrity check should be performed every time you edit or update your &lt;code&gt;user.js&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you run Firefox for the first time after making any changes to your &lt;code&gt;user.js&lt;/code&gt; file, the first thing you should do is check the value of the troubleshooting preference by entering &lt;code&gt;about:config&lt;/code&gt; in the address bar and searching for the &lt;code&gt;_user.js.parrot&lt;/code&gt; preference (it will likely be the very first preference listed). If you are using only the ghacks file and have not added anything more to it, then the value should be “&lt;code&gt;SUCCESS: No no he's not dead, he's, he's restin'!&lt;/code&gt;“. If you have appended my &lt;code&gt;user.js&lt;/code&gt; to the ghacks file and have not added anything more, then the value should be “&lt;code&gt;12bytes.org settings loaded&lt;/code&gt;” If you have added anything to the file in your personal preferences section at the bottom, and regardless of which &lt;code&gt;user.js&lt;/code&gt; you are using, the value should be whatever you set it to, such as “&lt;code&gt;user settings loaded&lt;/code&gt;“. An example troubleshooting preference and further instructions are contained in my &lt;code&gt;user.js&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the value for the troubleshooting preference is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; what you expect, then you can use it to quickly determine in which section the syntax error lies. It will not tell you on which line the problem exists, but at least you will know in which section to begin looking. Some common mistakes (at least that i have made) are forgetting to end a line with a semi-colon, forgetting a bracket, a quote character or comma, a typo in &lt;code&gt;user_pref&lt;/code&gt;, forgetting to put string values in quotes, or mistakenly putting quotes around integer or boolean values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;updating-the-userjs-file&quot;&gt;Updating the user.js file&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to keep up with the latest and greatest version of the &lt;code&gt;user.js&lt;/code&gt; files that are published, you might want to subscribe to the following news feeds:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Before updating your &lt;code&gt;user.js&lt;/code&gt;, be sure the ones you download correspond to the version of Firefox you are using as described earlier&lt;/strong&gt;. If you followed my advice and located your personal preferences at the end of the file in your own personal preferences section, then your job should be very easy. All you need to do is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;backup your current profile (might want to dump your old backup if you were happy with the way Firefox was working)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;open your current &lt;code&gt;user.js&lt;/code&gt; and delete everything above your personal preferences section if you created one&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;copy everything from the new file(s) and paste it above your personal preferences section, being sure to paste the ghacks code first and then mine under theirs but above yours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;check the change logs for the new &lt;code&gt;user.js&lt;/code&gt; files so you can determine whether you need to change anything in your personal preferences section&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;start Firefox and check the value for the troubleshooting preference as described in the ‘&lt;em&gt;Verifying the integrity of user.js&lt;/em&gt;‘ section above&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;removing-system-add-ons&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;removing-the-8216follow-on-search8217-system-add-on&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Removing system add-ons&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mozilla forcefully and without consent installs and then essentially hides from the user several so-called “system add-ons”, some of which are used to push browser updates and others which are used specifically to gain an insight as to how you use the default search engine plugins that are packaged with the browser. I would highly suggest disabling or deleting those which you decide present a risk to your privacy. You can learn how to deal with these system add-ons by refering to the &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://12bytes.org/tech/firefox/firefox-search-engine-cautions-and-recommendations#removing-the-8216follow-on-search8217-system-add-on&quot;&gt;Removing the ‘Follow On Search’ system add-on&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; section of the article &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://12bytes.org/tech/firefox/firefox-search-engine-cautions-and-recommendations&quot;&gt;Firefox Search Engine Cautions and Recommendations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;sanitizing-the-default-search-engine-plugins&quot;&gt;Sanitizing the default search engine plugins&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every time you preform a search using one of the search engines Mozilla has partnered with, apparently regardless of whether you search using the search bar or the search engine web page directly, Firefox is collecting data about your habits. To circumvent this risk to your privacy, please read the article &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://12bytes.org/tech/firefox/firefox-search-engine-cautions-and-recommendations&quot;&gt;Firefox Search Engine Cautions and Recommendations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;add-on-configuration&quot;&gt;Add-on configuration&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Between the features offered by Firefox, uMatrix and uBlock Origin, we have some overlapping functionality and it is therefore necessary to configure our settings with this in mind. Let’s start with uMatrix since this is probably the most important add-on of them all…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;umatrix&quot;&gt;uMatrix&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will be using uMatrix as a browser firewall to block entire domains and specific resources (cookies, CSS, images, plug-in enumeration, JavaScript, XHR, frames and ‘other’ requests) from both 1st and 3rd party domains, while uBlock Origin will handle the advertising, annoyance and malware site blocking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;umatrix-configuration&quot;&gt;uMatrix configuration&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the upper-left corner of the uMatrix main interface there is a blue or black block and it is imperative that you understand how it is used.&lt;/strong&gt; Clicking this block sets the &lt;span&gt;scope&lt;/span&gt; of the filter rules. When the block is set to an asterisk with a black background, any filter rules you set will be applied in the &lt;span&gt;global scope&lt;/span&gt;. In other words, any filter rules you set will be applied to &lt;span&gt;all websites&lt;/span&gt; and not just the one you happen to be visiting. If you select any other scope, then you are working in a &lt;span&gt;local scope&lt;/span&gt; and any filter rules you set will be applied only for that scope. For example, if we visit addons.mozilla.org, we will have a choice to apply filtering at the global scope level, or for the subdomain addons.mozilla.org only, or the root domain of mozilla.org which includes all subdomains (addons.mozilla.org, etc.). Just to be perfectly clear, if you set the scope to the root domain — mozilla.org in our example — then any rules you set will be applied to the root domain &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; all subdomains. In many cases websites still prefix their root domain with “www.” and this is actually a subdomain of the root domain. How you set the scope of uMatrix in such instances depends entirely upon what filtering you want to apply where. For instance you may visit some website, let’s say subdomain.example.com, and you want to allow JS for the subdomain but not the root domain (example.com). In this case you would set the scope to subdomain.example.com. On the other hand, maybe you want to allow JS for the entire domain in which case you would set the scope to the root domain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/umatrix-setting-scope.png&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-10177 size-medium-large&quot; src=&quot;http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/umatrix-setting-scope-600x274.png&quot; alt=&quot;uMatrix - Setting the filter scope&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;274&quot; srcset=&quot;http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/umatrix-setting-scope-600x274.png 600w, http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/umatrix-setting-scope-300x137.png 300w, http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/umatrix-setting-scope-768x351.png 768w, http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/umatrix-setting-scope-284x130.png 284w, http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/umatrix-setting-scope.png 779w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;Setting the filter scope
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IMPORTANT: Always keep in mind the scope you are working within before applying any filter rules.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By default uMatrix allows very little, so even images and CSS will not be loaded for any website. As a matter of convenience you may want to allow both images and CSS in the global scope so we don’t have to create filter rules for nearly every single site we visit. Other than the scope block, most of the rest of the blocks are divided into an upper and lower half. Clicking the upper half will allow the resource for a domain by changing its color to green, while clicking the lower half will disallow the resource, changing its color to red.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To allow CSS and images for all websites by default, set the scope to the global scope and click the top half of the “css” and “image” filter blocks in the “all” row:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/umatrix-global-rules.png&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-medium-large wp-image-10174&quot; src=&quot;http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/umatrix-global-rules-600x252.png&quot; alt=&quot;uMatrix Global Scope Rules&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;252&quot; srcset=&quot;http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/umatrix-global-rules-600x252.png 600w, http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/umatrix-global-rules-300x126.png 300w, http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/umatrix-global-rules-768x322.png 768w, http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/umatrix-global-rules-284x119.png 284w, http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/umatrix-global-rules.png 779w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;Setting filter rules in the global scope
&lt;p&gt;Once you are finished, don’t forget to click the padlock icon to save the changes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/umatrix-save-changes.png&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-medium-large wp-image-10176&quot; src=&quot;http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/umatrix-save-changes-600x252.png&quot; alt=&quot;uMatrix - Saving changes&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;252&quot; srcset=&quot;http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/umatrix-save-changes-600x252.png 600w, http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/umatrix-save-changes-300x126.png 300w, http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/umatrix-save-changes-768x322.png 768w, http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/umatrix-save-changes-284x119.png 284w, http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/umatrix-save-changes.png 779w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;Saving temporary changes to the filter rules
&lt;p&gt;The last filter i would suggest creating in the uMatrix main interface will block &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/IndexedDB_API&quot;&gt;IndexDB&lt;/a&gt; storage globally. This is an ongoing battle at the time of this writing (end of Sep., beginning of Oct., 2017) because of the transition to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ghacks.net/2016/11/24/firefox-will-only-support-web-extensions-by-the-end-of-2017/&quot;&gt;WebExtension&lt;/a&gt; API, Firefox v55 stupidity (and possibly v56), large changes in the upcoming Firefox v57, the transition to WebExtensions, etc.. In short, there are multiple issues at this time and there doesn’t seem to be any good alternative to automate the removal of IndexDB storage per domain after its tab is closed and so you may want to use uMatrix to block IndexDB storage globally. This is easy enough to accomplish by setting the “other” filter in the “all” column to red while in the global scope. The problem here is that, if you visit a website that uses local storage, like youtube.com, you may not see any populated blocks under the “other” column in uMatrix for youtube.com, leaving you to assume that there is nothing to block when, in fact, there is. Keep this in mind when you visit a website that doesn’t work properly and try toggling the “other” filter in the “1st-party” row for that domain and see if that solves the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can verify (and i suggest you do) that IndexDB storage is being blocked by watching the contents of the &lt;code&gt;/storage/default&lt;/code&gt; folder in your Firefox profile folder before and after you visit YouTube (make sure to delete any YouTube storage items in &lt;code&gt;/default&lt;/code&gt; prior).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, open the uMatrix Dashboard by clicking the black title bar at the top of the main interface and we’ll configure some more settings:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/umatrix-open-dashboard.png&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-medium-large wp-image-10175&quot; src=&quot;http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/umatrix-open-dashboard-600x253.png&quot; alt=&quot;uMatrix Dashboard&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;253&quot; srcset=&quot;http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/umatrix-open-dashboard-600x253.png 600w, http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/umatrix-open-dashboard-300x126.png 300w, http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/umatrix-open-dashboard-768x323.png 768w, http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/umatrix-open-dashboard-284x120.png 284w, http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/umatrix-open-dashboard.png 779w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;Opening the uMatrix Dashboard
&lt;p&gt;Following are my recommendations for the more important settings for each tab:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dashboard &amp;gt; Settings &amp;gt; Privacy:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[x] Delete blocked cookies&lt;br/&gt;[x] Delete non-blocked session cookies 15 minutes after the last time they have been used&lt;br/&gt;[x] Delete local storage content set by blocked hostnames&lt;br/&gt;[x] Clear browser cache every 90 minutes (adjust as necessary)&lt;br/&gt;[x] Spoof HTTP referrer string of third-party requests&lt;br/&gt;[x] Strict HTTPS: forbid mixed content (you may have to disable this if you have trouble with encrypted (HTTPS) sites&lt;br/&gt;[x] Block all hyperlink auditing attempts&lt;br/&gt;[  ] Spoof User-Agent string by randomly picking a new one below every minutes (not recommended – see section 4700 of the ghacks &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ghacksuserjs/ghacks-user.js/blob/31e7c72f642425668d8153e12f29332a6b2eb5a2/user.js&quot;&gt;custom user.js file&lt;/a&gt; to understand why)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dashboard &amp;gt; Settings &amp;gt; My rules:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The default rules will suffice unless you are using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/decentraleyes/&quot;&gt;Decentraleyes&lt;/a&gt; add-on in which case you need to add &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Synzvato/decentraleyes/wiki/Frequently-Asked-Questions#why-doesnt-it-deliver-resources-from-cdns-i-block-using-a-different-add-on&quot;&gt;the filter rules supplied here&lt;/a&gt; under where is says “&lt;em&gt;If you’re using uMatrix,&lt;/em&gt; […]”. Decentraleyes will not work properly otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dashboard &amp;gt; Settings &amp;gt; Hosts files:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No filter sets are enabled here since all 3rd party filters are handled by uBlock Origin which has many more options in this regard. If you choose not to use uBlock however, then you should probably enable some or all of these.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the configuration of our global scope settings for uMatrix complete, you will find that many websites will no longer function or display properly and therefore you will need to configure the local scope settings for these sites. While this may be a nuisance, the up-side is that you will be far better protected against browser tracking, fingerprinting, malware and other attacks and once you have set the rules for your favorite sites, you usually won’t have to fool with them again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;umatrix-usage&quot;&gt;uMatrix usage&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make sure to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gorhill/uMatrix/wiki&quot;&gt;read the manual&lt;/a&gt; to learn how to properly use uMatrix!&lt;/strong&gt; And once again, &lt;span&gt;always make sure you are aware of what scope you are working in before applying filter rules&lt;/span&gt;. Remember: if you have the global scope selected (the upper-left box is an asterisk as shown earlier), then any rules you create will affect &lt;span&gt;all&lt;/span&gt; websites, whereas if the scope is set to the current domain or subdomain, then the rules will affect either the entire domain or just a subdomain of the root domain, depending on what scope you have selected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any changes you make to the filter rules using the main interface are temporary. To make your changes permanent you must click the lock icon. If you make multiple changes to multiple domains and you click the lock icon, only the changes for the current scope (the domain being visited) will be saved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Typically when i visit a website that isn’t displaying or working correctly, i open the uMatrix main interface and see what resources the website is using. In the example below, stats.searx.oe5tpo.com is using JS. It is up to me if and at what scope i want to allow JS to run. If i never, or rarely visit this site, and i trust it, then i might temporarily enable JS for the subdomain stats.searx.oe5tpo.com only and refresh the page without ever saving my changes. On the other hand, if this is a site i visit often, i may want to allow JS for the root domain as well, in which case i would enable JS for the root domain by clicking where my mouse cursor appears in the image below, after which i would save my changes by clicking the lock icon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/umatrix-usage-scope.png&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-medium-large wp-image-10178&quot; src=&quot;http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/umatrix-usage-scope-600x250.png&quot; alt=&quot;uMatrix - Filter Scopes&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;250&quot; srcset=&quot;http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/umatrix-usage-scope-600x250.png 600w, http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/umatrix-usage-scope-300x125.png 300w, http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/umatrix-usage-scope-768x320.png 768w, http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/umatrix-usage-scope-284x118.png 284w, http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/umatrix-usage-scope.png 778w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;Setting filters for different scopes
&lt;p&gt;Another little trick to using uMatrix is to choose how much information is displayed in the main interface. By default, only root domains are displayed (12bytes.org, 1dmp.io and postimage.org in this instance). If you want to display the subdomains as well so you can make even more granular rules, then find that little drop-down arrow in the “all” cell and click it…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/umatrix-show-domains.png&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-medium-large wp-image-10179&quot; src=&quot;http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/umatrix-show-domains-600x252.png&quot; alt=&quot;uMatrix - Show root domains only&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;252&quot; srcset=&quot;http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/umatrix-show-domains-600x252.png 600w, http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/umatrix-show-domains-300x126.png 300w, http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/umatrix-show-domains-768x323.png 768w, http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/umatrix-show-domains-284x119.png 284w, http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/umatrix-show-domains.png 778w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;Showing only the root domains
&lt;p&gt;…and now both the root and subdomains will be displayed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/umatrix-show-subdomains.png&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-medium-large wp-image-10180&quot; src=&quot;http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/umatrix-show-subdomains-600x277.png&quot; alt=&quot;uMatrix - Show Subdomains&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;277&quot; srcset=&quot;http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/umatrix-show-subdomains-600x277.png 600w, http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/umatrix-show-subdomains-300x138.png 300w, http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/umatrix-show-subdomains-768x354.png 768w, http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/umatrix-show-subdomains-284x131.png 284w, http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/umatrix-show-subdomains.png 779w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;Show the root and subdomains
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;ublock-origin&quot;&gt;uBlock Origin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;uBlock Origin is a powerful content filter which can be used to prevent the loading of resources, or hide page elements when load blocking is not possible. While uBlock Origin can block in-line, 1st party and 3rd party JavaScript, ads, images, frames, remote fonts and more, we will be using it primarily for ad blocking, tracking and malware blocking. uBlock can use all of the same filter lists as Adblock Plus/Edge plus many others. It also features a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/uBlockAdmin/uBlock/wiki/Element-picker&quot;&gt;wizard for easy element hiding&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/uBlockAdmin/uBlock/wiki/The-network-request-logger&quot;&gt;network request logger&lt;/a&gt; which is invaluable for troubleshooting when a website does not display and/or function properly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because uBlock filters unwanted content (ads), websites will generally load much faster while still retaining all the functionality we require once the rules are configured properly for each site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;ublock-origin-configuration&quot;&gt;uBlock Origin configuration&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the uBlock icon is on your tool-bar, click it to reveal the main interface, then click the settings icon to reveal the Dashboard:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-10199 size-full&quot; src=&quot;http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/ublock-main-interface.png&quot; alt=&quot;uBlock Origin - Main Interface&quot; width=&quot;204&quot; height=&quot;566&quot; srcset=&quot;http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/ublock-main-interface.png 204w, http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/ublock-main-interface-54x150.png 54w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 204px) 100vw, 204px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
uBlock Origin – Main interface
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-10200&quot; src=&quot;http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/ublock-settings.png&quot; alt=&quot;uBlock Origin - Settings&quot; width=&quot;208&quot; height=&quot;525&quot; srcset=&quot;http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/ublock-settings.png 208w, http://12bytes.org/wp-content/uploads/ublock-settings-59x150.png 59w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 208px) 100vw, 208px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
uBlock Origin – Settings
&lt;p&gt;Following are my recommendations for the more important settings for each tab:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dashboard &amp;gt; Settings &amp;gt; Privacy:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All options in this section are enabled&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dashboard &amp;gt; Settings &amp;gt; Default behaivor:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[x] Block remote fonts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All other options on the Settings tab are optional&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dashboard &amp;gt; 3rd-party filters:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[x] Auto-update filter lists&lt;br/&gt;[x] My filters​​​​​&lt;br/&gt;[x] uBlock filters​&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dashboard &amp;gt; 3rd-party filters &amp;gt; Ads:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[x] EasyList&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dashboard &amp;gt; 3rd-party filters &amp;gt; Privacy:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All options in this section are enabled&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dashboard &amp;gt; 3rd-party filters &amp;gt; Malware domains:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[x] Malvertising filter list by Disconnect​​​​​​​&lt;br/&gt;[x] Malware Domain List​​​​​​​&lt;br/&gt;[x] Malware domains​​​&lt;br/&gt;[x] Malware filter list by Disconnect​​​​​&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dashboard &amp;gt; 3rd-party filters &amp;gt; Social:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[x] Fanboy’s Anti-Thirdparty Social&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dashboard &amp;gt; 3rd-party filters &amp;gt; Multipurpose:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[x] Dan Pollock’s hosts file​​​​​&lt;br/&gt;[x] hpHosts’ Ad and tracking servers​​​&lt;br/&gt;[x] MVPS HOSTS​​​&lt;br/&gt;[x] Peter Lowe’s Ad and tracking server list​&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dashboard &amp;gt; 3rd-party filters &amp;gt; Custom:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here you can add custom filter lists to uBlock. At this time i have only one filter and it is used to block cryptocurrency miner scripts running on websites you visit. You can find the source for this filter list on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/hoshsadiq/adblock-nocoin-list&quot;&gt;hoshsadiq / adblock-nocoin-list&lt;/a&gt; repository on GitHub. Simply copy and paste the following code in the Custom box and click the “Apply Changes” button:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/hoshsadiq/adblock-nocoin-list/master/nocoin.txt&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that we are not enabling the “I am an advanced user” option since all dynamic filtering will be handled by uMatrix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the “My filters” tab, i have added a few filters which override any exception filters that may be used in the 3rd party filter lists because i want to be sure they are always blocked. This is by no means an extensive list:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;EnlighterJSRAW&quot; data-enlighter-language=&quot;null&quot;&gt;
! override exceptions in existing filter sets - see: https://github.com/chrisaljoudi/uBlock/wiki/Privacy-stuff
||google-analytics.com^$important
||platform.twitter.com/widgets.js$third-party
||gravatar.com^$third-party
||doubleclick.net^$important
||adserver.yahoo.com^$important
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The “My rules” tab is empty since we are using uMatrix to create our filter rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All other settings for the remaining tabs can remain at their defaults.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;ublock-origin-usage&quot;&gt;uBlock Origin usage&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are not using the advanced dynamic blocking features of uBlock Origin since this functionality is being handled by uMatrix. As such, there is basically nothing to configure or adjust after the initial setup, other than possibly disabling uBlock Origin for those websites where you do not want it to run and allowing remote fonts for sites where you want remote fonts to be displayed. Disabling uBlock for a given domain is done by simply clicking the big blue power button on the main interface. Allowing remote fonts for a domain is done by clicking the “A” icon in the lower right of the main interface. Both of these settings will be saved and remembered across browser sessions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please refer to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gorhill/uBlock/wiki&quot;&gt;uBlock Origin wiki&lt;/a&gt; to better learn how to use its many features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;clean-links-configuration&quot;&gt;Clean Links configuration&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can enable all of the options, though some will be ignored when running when the Event Delegation Mode is enabled. While i prefer to have Clean Links rewrite and highlight links in real time, the developer has stated that the code for accomplishing this is old and unmaintained, therefore i personally use the Event Delegation Mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;securing-dns-traffic&quot;&gt;Securing DNS traffic&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Domain Name System (DNS) is an infrastructure which uses DNS resolvers to convert human-friendly domain names (12bytes.org) to IP addresses (143.95.38.204) which are used by the computers that route internet traffic. The problem with DNS is that this traffic is not encrypted or secured and is therefore open to various attacks. To help secure your DNS traffic, please read my guide, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://12bytes.org/tech/encrypting-dns-traffic&quot;&gt;Encrypting DNS Traffic (and why you want to)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. Another option, and perhaps an even better one, is to use a Virtual Private Network provider (VPN) which provides a DNS service, such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://airvpn.org/?referred_by=223784&quot;&gt;AirVPN&lt;/a&gt; which i use myself. In this case, assuming everything is configured correctly, all of your internet traffic is encrypted and your real IP address is not revealed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;testing-your-configuration&quot;&gt;Testing your configuration&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To test your configuration, see the &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ghacksuserjs/ghacks-user.js/wiki&quot;&gt;Appendix C: Test Sites&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; section of the ‘ghacksuserjs’ wiki.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;troubleshooting&quot;&gt;Troubleshooting&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General&lt;/strong&gt;: Both uMatrix and uBlock Origin have the ability to log network requests, similar to how a firewall log might work. This can be a great help when troubleshooting website display or functionality issues. On the uMatrix main interface you will notice a tiny ‘window’ icon that can be clicked to reveal the network request log. See the &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gorhill/uMatrix/wiki/Logger&quot;&gt;Logger&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; documentation to learn how to use this feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Website does not display correctly,&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;uMatrix&lt;/strong&gt;: Check that content is allowed for the domain, as well as other domains which supply content to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Problems making a purchase,&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Firefox&lt;/strong&gt;: make sure to allow 1st party cookies. &lt;strong&gt;uMatrix&lt;/strong&gt;: Check that the necessary functionality is temporarily allowed for the 1st party domain (typically JavaScript, cookies, XHR), as well as any other content that may be needed which is supplied by 3rd party domains. If you are forwarded to a payment gateway such as PayPal during the transaction, make sure that the necessary functionality is allowed for the payment gateway domain as well as any 3rd party resources it may require.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;further-reading-on-12bytesorg&quot;&gt;Further reading on 12bytes.org&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;references-and-resources&quot;&gt;References and resources&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;revision-history&quot;&gt;Revision history&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;collapseomatic&quot; id=&quot;id3228&quot; tabindex=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Click to expand...&quot;&gt;Click to expand...&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;target-id3228&quot; class=&quot;collapseomatic_content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11-APR-2015&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;first publishing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;14-APR-2015&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;removed all Shim Storage add-on information since this functionality is duplicated in HTTP UserAgent cleaner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;almost all of the documentation for HTTP UserAgent cleaner was heavily revised.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;various other edits and corrections.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;15-APR-2015&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;updated user.js file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;several other small updates and a few corrections&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;16-APR-2015&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;updated user.js file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;switched uBlock versions since a new fork was created&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;updated uBlock images and documentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added a “Current notices” section&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;misc. other corrections/updates/edits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;17-APR-2015&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;updated and added more information for uBlock&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;updated one HTTP UserAgent cleaner screen-shot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;misc. other corrections/updates/edits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;18-APR-2015&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;updated HTTP UserAgent cleaner information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;for HTTP UserAgent cleaner settings, the suggested settings were split into &lt;em&gt;Suggested global setting for casual browsing&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Suggested global setting for best protection&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;22-APR-2015&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;updated information for HTTP UserAgent cleaner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;updated user.js file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;minor updates to uBlock information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;misc. other minor changes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;23-APR-2015&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;updated some HTTP UserAgent cleaner information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;deleted information for 2 bugs regarding the X-Forward-For setting for HTTP UserAgent cleaner since they were not bugs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;misc. other minor changes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;25-APR-2015&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;updated information for HTTP UserAgent cleaner, including adding descriptions for the newly added features, Canvas and Fonts on the HTTP tab&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;updated the user.js file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;updated some definitions of terms used in this document&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added some more resources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;26-APR-2015&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;updated the information for the Fonts filter on the HTTP tab of HTTP UserAgent cleaner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;2-MAY-2015&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;updated HTTP UserAgent cleaner information to match changes in version 0.7.4.11a&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;3-MAY-2015&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;added Pure URL as a suggested add-on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;updated contents of the user.js file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added and edited some information for HTTP UserAgent cleaner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added more resources in the References section&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;5-MAY-2015&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;updated list of recommended filters for uBlock&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;updated user.js file contents&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;13-MAY-2015&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;updated user.js file contents&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;updated a few settings recommendations for HTTP UserAgent cleaner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;14-MAY-2015&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;minor updates to user.js file contents&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;17-MAY-2015&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;added information for securing DNS traffic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;misc. minor updates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;5-JUN-2015&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;switched to Raymond Hill’s version of uBlock&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;updated uBlock filter information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added Fetch information for new version of HTTP UserAgent cleaner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;updated user.js file contents&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;misc. minor updates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;25-JUN-2015&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;updated uBlock settings to match the current development version (0.9.9.2)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;misc. minor updates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;8-JUL-2015&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;removed HTTP UserAgent cleaner since it is no longer being developed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;removed Self Destructing Cookies add-on since its functionality can be handled by uMatrix&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added uMatrix&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;9-JUL-2015&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;added more info for uMatrix and IP Config test results&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;updated user.js file contents&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;various other edits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;13-JUL-2015&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Minor edits for uMatrix usage text&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;20-AUG-2015&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;updated user.js file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;removed pcxFirefox as a suggested 3rd party build since i had display corruption issues with it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;5-FEB-2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;updated user.js file contents&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;12-FEB-2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;updated user.js file contents&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;29-APR-2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;updated guide information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;updated user.js file and added a revision history to the file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;1-MAY-2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;updated user.js file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;12-MAY-2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;updated user.js file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;minor grammar/spelling corrections&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;3-JUN-2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;corrected an error with pref ‘layout.css.devPixelsPerPx’ where the value was an integer instead of a string – this caused all prefs following it to be ignored&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;17-JUN-2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;set ‘browser.fixup.hide_user_pass’ back to its default value&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added ‘network.http.redirection-limit’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;23-JUN-2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;added some basic information for configuring the Clean Links add-on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;1-JUL-2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;corrected ‘plugin.scan.*’ values to be strings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added bogus preferences in the user.js file at the end of each section for troubleshooting potential loading problems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;3-JUL-2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;changed the name of the troubleshooting/bogus preference to &lt;code&gt;12bytes.org-user-js-settings&lt;/code&gt; and added values to indicate the point at which the file stopped loading – a huge thanks to commenter ‘Pants’ for suggesting the troubleshooting preference and also for suggesting a far better way of implementing it than what i had done (by the way, ‘Pants’ is the author of the &lt;code&gt;user.js&lt;/code&gt; config file used in the ghacks article, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ghacks.net/2015/08/18/a-comprehensive-list-of-firefox-privacy-and-security-settings/&quot;&gt;A comprehensive list of Firefox privacy and security settings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; by Martin Brinkmann, so i’m very glad to have his input here)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;16-SEP-2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;removed duplicate preferences in use.js file (see change-log in the file for details)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;28-SEP-2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;removed Extension Defender from the list of recommended add-ons since it’s home page is gone and the code hasn’t been updated in two years&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;updated user.js file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;18-FEB-2017&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;switched to using &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ghacksuserjs/ghacks-user.js&quot;&gt;Pants’ config&lt;/a&gt; v0.11 and mostly just appending my settings to the end of his – because this is a major update, no history of changes to individual preferences will be published&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;19-FEB-2017&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;published my user.js on GitHub which was forked from Pants’ code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;removed my user.js code from this page and linked to it on the GitHub page instead&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;changed my versioning scheme to match Pants’ where the user.js version coincides with the version of Firefox it was developed for, so v51r1 would equate to version 51.x of Firefox and the r1 signifies the revision, in this case the first revision&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;updated user.js to include v51 of Pants’ config – no preference changes so far as i know, just added/removed/changed comments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;updated text in user.js section to account for the new changes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;changes to comments and troubleshooting preference names and values, other minor changes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;20-FEB-2017&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;updated user.js to version 51r2 – see &lt;del&gt;the GitHub page&lt;/del&gt; for the change-log&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;updated info here regarding the user custom preferences section of user.js&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;12-MAR-2017&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;deleted the GitHub repository which i forked from Pants’ ghacks repository and created &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/atomGit/Firefox-user.js&quot;&gt;a new repository&lt;/a&gt; which does not include his code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;some changes to user.js&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;some major editing of this document mostly in regard to the creation and changes of the GitHub repositories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;17-SEP-2017&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;rewrote and updated much of the content pertaining to umatrix&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added section “Removing system add-ons”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added section “Sanitizing the default search engine plugins”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;11-DEC-2017&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;added some add-ons to the recommended section&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;misc. minor edits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;22-SEP-2017&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;i didn’t keep track of all the changes and many were made – you’ll have to re-read the guide :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;27-SEP-2017&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;added section “A special note about cryptocurrency miners”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;30-SEP-2017&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;added more info about IndexDB storage in the “Terminology” and “uMatrix configuration” sections.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;11-DEC-2017&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;added to the list of recommended add-ons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;updated some content to reflect the current state of Firefox and WebExtensions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;misc. minor edits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;19-DEC-2017&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;added a link to my post about the Firefox add-on, &lt;a href=&quot;http://12bytes.org/11087/the-next-bright-idea-from-mozilla&quot;&gt;Looking Glass&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;misc. minor edits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;2-MAR-2018&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;minor edits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;juiz_sps_links counters_both juiz_sps_displayed_bottom&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;screen-reader-text juiz_sps_maybe_hidden_text&quot;&gt;Share the post &quot;Firefox Configuration Guide for Privacy Freaks and Performance Buffs&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 00:14:30 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>bigbugbag</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://12bytes.org/tech/firefox/firefoxgecko-configuration-guide-for-privacy-and-performance-buffs</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>YouTube Hiring for Some Positions Excluded White and Asian Males, Lawsuit Says</title>
<link>https://www.wsj.com/articles/youtube-hiring-for-some-positions-excluded-white-and-asian-males-lawsuit-says-1519948013</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.wsj.com/articles/youtube-hiring-for-some-positions-excluded-white-and-asian-males-lawsuit-says-1519948013</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;clearfix byline-wrap&quot;&gt;


    
    &lt;div class=&quot;byline&quot;&gt;
    
    
        &lt;span&gt;By&lt;/span&gt;
    
              &lt;div class=&quot;author mobile-scrim hasMenu&quot; data-scrim=&quot;{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;author&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;header&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Kirsten Grind&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;subhead&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;The Wall Street Journal&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;list&amp;quot;:[{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;bio&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.wsj.com/news/author/8065&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Biography&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;twitter&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;http://twitter.com/kirstengrind&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;@kirstengrind&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;email&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;mailto:kirsten.grind@wsj.com&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;kirsten.grind@wsj.com&amp;quot;}]}&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemprop=&quot;author&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Person&quot;&gt;
                  &lt;span class=&quot;name&quot; itemprop=&quot;name&quot;&gt;Kirsten Grind&lt;/span&gt; and 
                  &lt;/div&gt;

              &lt;div class=&quot;author mobile-scrim hasMenu&quot; data-scrim=&quot;{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;author&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;header&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Douglas MacMillan&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;subhead&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;The Wall Street Journal&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;list&amp;quot;:[{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;bio&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.wsj.com/news/author/7902&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Biography&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;email&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;mailto:douglas.macmillan@wsj.com&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;douglas.macmillan@wsj.com&amp;quot;}]}&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemprop=&quot;author&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Person&quot;&gt;
                  &lt;span class=&quot;name&quot; itemprop=&quot;name&quot;&gt;Douglas MacMillan&lt;/span&gt;
                  &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;time class=&quot;timestamp&quot;&gt;
      Updated March 1, 2018 8:03 p.m. ET
    &lt;/time&gt;

        
  &lt;/div&gt;

  



       &lt;p&gt;YouTube last year stopped hiring white and Asian males for technical positions because they didn’t help the world’s largest video site achieve its goals for improving diversity, according to a civil lawsuit filed by a former employee.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The lawsuit, filed by Arne Wilberg, a white male who worked at Google for nine years, including four years as a recruiter at YouTube, alleges the division of 






            &lt;a href=&quot;http://quotes.wsj.com/GOOGL&quot;&gt;Alphabet&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;company-name-type&quot;&gt; Inc.’s&lt;/span&gt;

      &lt;a href=&quot;http://quotes.wsj.com/GOOGL?mod=chiclets&quot; class=&quot;media-object-chiclet down &quot; data-channel=&quot;/quotes/zigman/59539269/composite&quot; data-symbol=&quot;GOOGL&quot; data-changepercent=&quot;-1.35&quot;&gt;
        GOOGL &lt;span&gt;-1.35%&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;

       Google set quotas for hiring minorities. Last spring, YouTube recruiters were allegedly instructed to cancel interviews with applicants who weren’t female, black or Hispanic, and to “purge entirely” the applications of people who didn’t fit those categories, the lawsuit claims.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;div class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt;




       &lt;p&gt;A Google spokeswoman said the company will vigorously defend itself in the lawsuit. “We have a clear policy to hire candidates based on their merit, not their identity,” she said in a statement. “At the same time, we unapologetically try to find a diverse pool of qualified candidates for open roles, as this helps us hire the best people, improve our culture, and build better products.”&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;People familiar with YouTube’s and Google’s hiring practices in interviews corroborated some of the lawsuit’s allegations, including the hiring freeze of white and Asian technical employees, and YouTube’s use of quotas.&lt;/p&gt; 






                                          &lt;p class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1519941036798-aiPstyle-1-2&quot;&gt;2%&lt;/p&gt;                  &lt;/div&gt;                                    &lt;p class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1519941036798-aiPstyle-1-3&quot;&gt;4%&lt;/p&gt;                  </description>
<pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 23:57:56 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>fmihaila</dc:creator>
<og:title>YouTube Hiring for Some Positions Excluded White and Asian Men, Lawsuit Says</og:title>
<og:description>YouTube last year stopped hiring white and Asian males for technical positions because they didn’t help the company achieve its goals for improving diversity, according to a civil complaint filed by a former employee.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.wsj.com/articles/youtube-hiring-for-some-positions-excluded-white-and-asian-males-lawsuit-says-1519948013</og:url>
<og:image>https://si.wsj.net/public/resources/images/BN-XS113_3ozmB_TOP_20180301184241.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.wsj.com/articles/youtube-hiring-for-some-positions-excluded-white-and-asian-males-lawsuit-says-1519948013</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>NASA finds a large amount of water in an exoplanet&amp;#039;s atmosphere</title>
<link>https://www.nasa.gov/feature/goddard/2018/nasa-finds-a-large-amount-of-water-in-an-exoplanets-atmosphere</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nasa.gov/feature/goddard/2018/nasa-finds-a-large-amount-of-water-in-an-exoplanets-atmosphere</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nasa.gov/feature/goddard/2018/nasa-finds-a-large-amount-of-water-in-an-exoplanets-atmosphere&quot;&gt;https://www.nasa.gov/feature/goddard/2018/nasa-finds-a-large-amount-of-water-in-an-exoplanets-atmosphere&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16496880&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16496880&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Points: 300&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 123&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 22:12:03 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dnetesn</dc:creator>
<og:description>Scientists used NASA's Hubble and Spitzer space telescopes to find the &quot;fingerprints&quot; of water in the atmosphere of a hot, bloated, Saturn-mass exoplanet some 700 light-years away.</og:description>
<og:title>NASA Finds a Large Amount of Water in an Exoplanet's Atmosphere</og:title>
<og:image>http://www.nasa.gov/sites/default/files/thumbnails/image/hubbleimage1stscihp1809af6400x4800.png</og:image>
<og:url>http://www.nasa.gov/feature/goddard/2018/nasa-finds-a-large-amount-of-water-in-an-exoplanets-atmosphere</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nasa.gov/feature/goddard/2018/nasa-finds-a-large-amount-of-water-in-an-exoplanets-atmosphere/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>What Happens to Us Does Not Happen to Most of You</title>
<link>https://www.sigarch.org/what-happens-to-us-does-not-happen-to-most-of-you/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.sigarch.org/what-happens-to-us-does-not-happen-to-most-of-you/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;This blog post is a personal account of sexism, harassment, and racism that I and some anonymous members of the computer architecture community have experienced. We are sharing these experiences in part because of encouragement by male colleagues who found them shocking. We are all still here because the rewards and great colleagues out weigh the bad experiences. However, we want to raise community awareness and instigate change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Men do not experience our community the same way women do. The power dynamics of academia give individuals a lot of power, e.g., hallway conversations and recommendation letters greatly influence career-defining decisions. These dynamics demand the highest ethical practices and vigorous attention to limit the influence of factors that have nothing to do with research quality and impact. We want every individual to take more responsibility for our culture and meritocracy, fostering research excellence by making our community a more welcoming place for women, underrepresented minorities, and everyone else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Me&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was an Assistant Professor, pregnant, and 8 months from going up for tenure, a powerful Full Professor congratulated me on my pregnancy and asked me: “Are you going to quit your job?” At one of my first PC meetings, a Full Professor in Architecture saw me for the first time, and said: “Are you the token woman? Are you qualified?” At conferences, men asked to enter my hotel room. A man I thought was a trusted colleague thought my first conference was the right place to make an agressive pass. Almost every year, a man mistakes me for the administrative assistant. In 2011, a manager at Microsoft told me I was only hired because I was a woman. At a recent industry event I was sitting next to a black colleague and a senior researcher, who upon hearing of this colleague’s career move said “You must have had a lot of offers because you are black.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though some may view me as “research privileged,” I am unfortunately still regularly subject to blatant and subtle forms of sexism. Because of these and some other bad experiences, when I serve in leadership positions, I use them to limit the effects of bias and improve our community. For instance, I helped spread double blind reviewing. I run and speak at workshops designed to help young researchers succeed and feel welcome.  I am the visible face of this blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anonymous Colleague A&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sexism and harassment I’ve experienced in my career has ranged from off-hand comments to creepy suggestions to inappropriate physical behaviour, all from well-respected computer architects. A Full Professor approached me at ISCA when I was a graduate student to ask me where all the pretty girls were. Just after I started my faculty position, a Full Professor asked me (during a post-conference beers, a.k.a. networking) if I had an open marriage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During an internship in graduate school, I faced persistent sexism that probably did the most to undermine my confidence and feeling of belonging. I was constantly referred to as “that girl” by other researchers on the team. Members of my team conveyed to me that there was no point in hiring women because they were just going to be married. This incident occurred in the 2000s, not the 1950s. They expressed dismay when I showed up for my internship recently engaged. My “mentor” told me he had never worked with a woman before and wasn’t sure how to talk to me. I suggested he try talking to me like a person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, around the time I received tenure, I came close to being assaulted at a PC meeting. After the PC meeting dinner, a PC member who was an Assistant Professor followed me back to my hotel room. I thought he was just going back to his room. It didn’t occur to me that he was following me. Without invitation, he tried to kiss me and when I pushed him away he forced his way into my hotel room. After recovering from my initial shock, I regrouped and pushed him out of my hotel room. Nothing “happened” so to speak but the incident left me feeling demeaned and sickened. As a result, the group of people I’m willing to socialize with at conference has shrunk. In “after-hours” situations, I stick with close friends and people who I can very clearly trust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anonymous Colleague B&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When asked for a paragraph, my first reaction was that I didn’t have the sort of big bombshell stories being looked for. But it’s important to portray the drip-drip-drip of smaller stories as well, so here goes. The off-color jokes during a conference coffee break… Getting introduced as the token female… Noting how if two women are talking to each other at a conference, it becomes highly unlikely any guys will walk up and join us. If three women are talking, forget about it. Having my PhD graduation timing be delayed “because you’re not even married yet.“&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That moment of realization when writing an NSF proposal and seeing other salaries, of just how inadequately low my original faculty salary offer had been. Lots of variations on “Come on, you should smile more…” Who else remembers the oddity of that one ASPLOS conference where the banquet entertainment was a pompom squad? And so on. I am still here, and I’m not going anywhere. I wish for this blog we could round up the stories of the women who were in our field briefly and then found other parts of CS more welcoming to their talents—would that be more convincing to you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anonymous Colleague C&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I experienced the unfortunately usual inappropriate comments described by others, my most negative experience built over time, with a set of increasingly disturbing interactions that made me fear where they could end up if given the chance. On the first day of my first ISCA, as I socialized with a group of graduate students, one kept creeping closer to me. As I stepped backwards to compensate, and the rest of the group similarly scooted to hold a circle, the entire group rotated upon an axis between us. This was so obvious that faculty in a nearby group noticed and identified the cause. On the last day of the conference, he complimented me on a buttoned-up shirt with embellishments down the button line. He touched the embroidery between my breasts. I froze in shocked silence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From that moment on, I avoided this student – a student from one of the most productive graduate schools. As a result, I also did not get to know any of the other students from this graduate school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most disturbing interaction occurred the year I went on the job market. He, a new professor, literally cornered me at the end of an open area outside of the conference room. At over a foot taller than I, he used his body to block any normal path around him. He asked whether I was applying to his university and, if not, why. I have no memory of what I told him. I said whatever I could to end the conversation and hoped he would move aside so I could leave. I cannot describe the fear that went through my mind, robbing me of the ability, then and afterwards, to focus on the professional reasons I was at the conference. All I could think of was that if he was willing to use his body size to force me into a professional conversation with professional colleagues nearby, what he would do if I was ever alone in his presence?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What frustrates me the most is that he had sexist jokes in his job talk. He could not make it more clear to those who would hire him how he viewed females. However, the faculty at that university decided that his professional accomplishments were more important than the impact he would have on females at his university and the community as a whole. Some universities make this trade-off in hiring prominent architects who are known to prey on young females. It sends a message to women in the field that their safety and their ability to focus on professional interactions, is a very low priority to others in the field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anonymous Colleague D&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the path to a tenured Full Professor position, I held several research and visiting positions at different universities. My starting salary was called into question by the upper administration until my supervisor pointed out that the same salary had already been awarded to a male candidate. At a different university, I was denied a raise and told by the department chair that he hoped “my husband was receiving a good raise this year”. As PI on a major project, I attended a project review visibly pregnant. A representative of the government funding agency asked me if I had told the organization my intention to have a child before signing up to be PI. Later in the pregnancy, I was confined to bedrest. A manager became angry that I was not able to attend a PI meeting, and criticized me among people who worked for me for “choosing to have a baby”. A manager was concerned about the challenges I faced in balancing work and family, and decided to “protect me” by interfering in my research projects and treating me differently from others regarding a consulting opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I have become more senior, my peers and upper administration have treated me very well, but I still encounter occasional issues with undergraduates and subordinates who are surprised and disbelieving that I am qualified for my position. I have received condescending emails and had people go around me and report trivial issues to supervisors in an attempt to circumvent my authority. I have always eventually prevailed in these negative situations, and remind myself of all the positive experiences and numerous opportunities I have had in my career. My message to younger women is: yes, you will encounter sexist situations, and when you do, seek allies and dig in for the long haul. When you are in the right, you will always succeed. The benefits of this career are worth these occasional challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Take action&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Never underestimate the benefits on these issues that come from the words and actions of allies. If something does not feel right to you, say something. Be the person who says “We don’t do that here.” &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pewsocialtrends.org/2018/01/09/women-and-men-in-stem-often-at-odds-over-workplace-equity/&quot;&gt;Increasing the diversity of your work place tends to decrease bias and harassment.&lt;/a&gt;  Below are more concrete actions you can take to make our community more inclusive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hire and support women and URM&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Encourage qualified undergraduate women and URM to go to graduate school.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hire them for Research Experiences for Undergraduates (REUs) in your lab so they develop better credentials.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hire women and URM graduate students. Treat them the same as your male graduate students.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write letters of recommendation for women that are similar to those for men. Emphasize their technical skills at the same rate – intelligence, creativity, problem selection, etc., versus social skills.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improve our community culture&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Foster a supportive, not competitive, atmosphere with your research group, emphasizing that the entire group benefits when team members are supported.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set expectations on lab behavior in writing. For instance, we work as a team. We ask each other questions when we are stuck. We give constructive feedback on ideas and documents. Everyone is treated with respect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be ready to say something!  Often, we are in shock when someone say something inappropriate, sexist, or racist. Say right away “I don’t believe that.” “That is not as funny as you think it is.” If you miss your opportunity, do it later.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refrain from commenting on people’s appearance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t say “because you are an X, you must Y.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not hire people who make sexist and racist remarks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At conferences, talk to women and URM researchers. Ask them about their research. Include them in group dinner plans.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Increase awareness and inclusiveness&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Egregious harassment, racism, and sexism happens in our community, and is especially harmful to young researchers. Unfortunately, women have left our field as a consequence. For the authors of this article, each negative story is overshadowed by dozens of positive experiences, where someone went out of their way to offer support, provide opportunities, and encourage us. You can change our community by being that voice of encouragement, that ally, that champion that keeps someone in the field. Be that change agent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kathryn S McKinley&lt;/strong&gt; is a Senior Researcher at Google. She is currently SIGPLAN Secretary. She is a member of SIGMICRO, SIGARCH, IEEE TCCA, IEEE TCuARCH, and SIGPLAN. She serves on the board of CRA and CRA-W. She is an ACM and IEEE Fellow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;robots-nocontent sd-block sd-social sd-social-icon-text sd-sharing&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Share this:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 21:24:09 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>RMarcus</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>What Happens to Us Does Not Happen to Most of You</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.sigarch.org/what-happens-to-us-does-not-happen-to-most-of-you/</og:url>
<og:description>This blog post is a personal account of sexism, harassment, and racism that I and some anonymous members of the computer architecture community have experienced. We are sharing these experiences in…</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.sigarch.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/AdobeStock_43355243.jpeg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.sigarch.org/what-happens-to-us-does-not-happen-to-most-of-you/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Queryparser, an Open Source Tool for Parsing and Analyzing SQL</title>
<link>https://eng.uber.com/queryparser/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://eng.uber.com/queryparser/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In early 2015, Uber Engineering migrated its business entities from integer identifiers to UUID identifiers as part of an initiative towards using multiple active data centers. To achieve this, our Data Warehouse team was tasked with identifying every foreign-key relationship between every table in the data warehouse to backfill all the ID columns with corresponding UUIDs.¹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Given the decentralized ownership of our tables, this was not a simple endeavor. The most promising solution was to crowdsource the information by scraping all the SQL queries submitted to the warehouse and observing which columns were joined together. To serve this need, we built and open sourced&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/uber/queryparser&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Queryparser&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, our tool for parsing and analyzing SQL queries.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In this article, we discuss our implementation of Queryparser, the variety of applications it unlocked, and some problems and limitations encountered along the way.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span&gt;Implementation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Internally, Queryparser is deployed in a streaming architecture, as shown in Figure 1, below:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_2258&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;34&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image9.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-2258&quot; src=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image9.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;240&quot; srcset=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image9.png 1686w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image9-300x120.png 300w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image9-768x307.png 768w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image9-1024x410.png 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Figure 1: Uber’s data warehouse streaming architecture feeds all queries through Queryparser. Boxes denote services and pipes denote data-streams. The catalog info service is responsible for tracking the schemas of the tables in the data warehouse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Queryparser consumes the real-time stream of queries submitted to the data warehouse, analyzes every single one, and emits the analysis results to a separate stream. Individual queries are processed in three steps, explained below and illustrated in Figure 2.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Phase 1: Parse&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;. Transforms the query from a raw string of characters into an abstract syntax tree (AST) representation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Phase 2: Resolve&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;. Scans the raw AST and applies scoping rules. Transforms plain column names by adding the table name, and transforms plain table names by adding the schema name. Requires as input the full list of columns in every table and the full list of tables in every schema, otherwise known as “catalog information.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Phase 3: Analyze&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;. Scans the resolved AST, looking for columns which are compared for equality.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_2259&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;36&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image1-3.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-2259&quot; src=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image1-3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; srcset=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image1-3.png 1764w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image1-3-300x175.png 300w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image1-3-768x448.png 768w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image1-3-1024x597.png 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Figure 2: Queryparser takes three passes to fully process a query: parse, resolve, and analyze.The top flow illustrates this sequence conceptually as a transformation of data types. The bottom flow illustrates the sequence concretely on a real query.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The implementation and architecture successfully identified foreign-key relationships—a great result, given that the prototype only had partial coverage of the SQL grammar, the catalog information was entirely hard-coded, and our understanding of what counted as a foreign-key relationship was continually evolving.²&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Haskell choice&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;One of the first things you may have noticed in the open source&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/uber/queryparser&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Queryparser&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;repository is that it is written in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.haskell.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Haskell&lt;/a&gt;. Queryparser was originally conceived by an Uber engineer who was a Haskell enthusiast, and it quickly gained traction with several other engineers. In fact, many of us learned Haskell specifically to develop in it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Haskell turned out to be a good choice for prototyping Queryparser for a variety of reasons. To start, Haskell has very mature&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://hackage.haskell.org/package/parsec&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;library support&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;for language parsers. Its expressive type system was also extremely useful for the frequent and extensive refactors of our internal model of a SQL query. Additionally, we leaned heavily on the compiler to guide us through those big, scary refactors. If we attempted the same using a dynamically-typed language, we would have lost weeks chasing runtime bugs that Haskell’s compiler can quickly flag for us.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The main drawback of writing Queryparser in Haskell was that not enough developers knew it. To introduce more of our engineers to Haskell, we started a weekly reading group, which met over lunch to discuss Haskell books and documentation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Note that for interoperability with the rest of Uber’s non-Haskell infrastructure, Queryparser was (and is) deployed behind a Python proxy server. See the &lt;em&gt;Deploying Queryparser&lt;/em&gt; section of this article for more details.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span&gt;Diversity of solutions&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;After the initial success of Queryparser, we considered other ways in which the tool could improve our data warehouse operations. In addition to implementing join detection, we decided to implement several more analysis functions:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Table access&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;: which tables were accessed in the query&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Column access&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;: which columns were accessed in each clause of the query&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Table lineage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;: which tables were modified by the query, and what were the inputs that determined their final state&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Together, the new analyses gave a nuanced understanding of the access patterns in our data warehouse, permitting advances in the following areas: table administration, targeted communication, understanding data flow, incident response, and defensive operations, outlined below:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;span&gt;Table administration&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;As far as table administration was concerned, the benefits were threefold. First, table access statistics let us free up storage and compute resources by finding tables that were infrequently accessed and then removing them.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Second, column access statistics let us improve database performance by optimizing table layouts on disk, particularly with&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://my.vertica.com/docs/9.0.x/HTML/index.htm#Authoring/AdministratorsGuide/Projections/WorkingWithProjections.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Vertica projections&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. The trick was to set the top GROUP BY columns as the shard keys and the top ORDER BY columns as the order keys.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Finally, column join statistics let us improve data usability and reduce database load by identifying clusters of tables that were frequently joined together and replacing them with a single&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kimballgroup.com/1997/08/a-dimensional-modeling-manifesto/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;dimensionally modeled&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;table.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;span&gt;Targeted communication&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Table access statistics let us send targeted communications to data consumers. Instead of blasting the entire Data Engineering mailing-list with updates about table schemas or data quality issues, we could notify only the data consumers who had recently accessed the table.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;span&gt;Understanding data flow&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Table lineage data unlocked a special use case: if a sequence of queries were analyzed together, then the table lineage data could be aggregated to produce a graph of dataflow across the sequence.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;For example, consider the hypothetical SQL in Figure 3, below, which produces a new version of modeled table A from dependent tables B and C:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;100&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Query&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;drop A_new if exists&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;create A_new as select … from B&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;insert into A_new select … from C&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;drop A_old if exists&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;rename A to A_old&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;rename A_new to A&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Figure 3: Sequence of SQL queries for computing modeled table A from dependent tables B and C.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In Figure 4, below, we describe the table lineage that Queryparser would produce for each query in the sequence. Additionally, we depict and explain the cumulative observed dataflow for each query in the sequence. At the end, the cumulative data flow (correctly!) records that table A has dependencies on tables B and C:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody readability=&quot;19&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Query&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Table lineage of query&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cumulative observed dataflow&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interpretation of cumulative dataflow&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;drop A_new if exists&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;A_new has no dependencies&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image4-3.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-2272&quot; src=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image4-3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;100&quot; srcset=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image4-3.png 300w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image4-3-150x150.png 150w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image4-3-32x32.png 32w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image4-3-50x50.png 50w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image4-3-64x64.png 64w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image4-3-96x96.png 96w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image4-3-128x128.png 128w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 100px) 100vw, 100px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;A_new has no dependencies&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;create A_new as select … from B&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;The data in A_new was determined exclusively by the data in B&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image7-1.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-2274&quot; src=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image7-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;120&quot; srcset=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image7-1.png 752w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image7-1-300x120.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The data in A_new was determined exclusively by the data in B&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;insert into A_new select … from C&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;The data in A_new was determined by the previous data in A_new and the data in C&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image8.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-2275&quot; src=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image8.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;195&quot; srcset=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image8.png 752w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image8-300x195.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;The data in A_new was determined by the data in B&lt;/span&gt; &lt;strong&gt;and the data in C&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;drop A_old if exists&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;A_old has no dependencies&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image5-1.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-2276&quot; src=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image5-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;269&quot; srcset=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image5-1.png 752w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image5-1-300x269.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;The data in A_new was determined by the data in B and the data in C&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A_old has no dependencies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;rename A to A_old&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;The data in A_old was determined by the previous data in A&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;A has no dependencies, anymore&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image6.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-2277&quot; src=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image6.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;345&quot; srcset=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image6.png 752w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image6-261x300.png 261w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;The data in A_new was determined by the data in B and the data in C&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The data in A_old was determined by the previous data in A&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A has no dependencies, anymore&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;rename A_new to A&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;The data in A was determined by the previous data in A_new&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;A_new has no dependencies, anymore&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image2-3.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-2278&quot; src=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image2-3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;329&quot; srcset=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image2-3.png 752w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image2-3-274x300.png 274w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The data in A was determined by the data in B and the data in C&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The data in A_old was determined by the previous data in A&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;A_new has no dependencies, anymore&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Figure 4: SQL from Figure 3, with table lineage for each query in the sequence, and cumulative table lineage for the entire sequence.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We modified our&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extract,_transform,_load&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;ETL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;-framework to record the sequence of SQL queries in every ETL and submit them to Queryparser, at which point Queryparser was programmatically generating graphs of data-flow for all the modeled tables in our warehouse. See Figure 5, below, for an example:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_2265&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;43&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image3-3.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-2265&quot; src=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image3-3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; srcset=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image3-3.png 975w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image3-3-150x150.png 150w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image3-3-300x300.png 300w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image3-3-768x768.png 768w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image3-3-32x32.png 32w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image3-3-50x50.png 50w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image3-3-64x64.png 64w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image3-3-96x96.png 96w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image3-3-128x128.png 128w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 400px) 100vw, 400px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Figure 5: A sample data flow graph representing four raw tables (A, B, C, D) and three modeled tables (E, F, G) portrays how queries are processed by Queryparser. In practice, the raw tables typically come from upstream operational systems such as Kafka topics, Schemaless datastores, and service-oriented architecture (SOA) database tables. The modeled tables are exposed in the data warehouse (Hive) and in downstream data marts (Vertica).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;span&gt;Incident response&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Table lineage data has been useful in responding to data quality incidents, decreasing the mitigation time by offering tactical visibility into incident impact. For example, given the table dependencies in Figure 5, if there was an issue in raw table A, we would know that the scope of impact included the modeled tables E and G. We would also know that once the issue was resolved, E and G would need to be backfilled. To address this, we could combine the lineage data with table access data to send targeted communications to all users of E and G.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Table lineage data is also useful for identifying the root cause of an incident. For instance,  if there was an issue with modeled table E in Figure 5, it could only be due to the raw tables A or B. If there was an issue with modeled table G, it could be due to raw tables A, B, C, or D.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;span&gt;Defensive operations&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Finally, the ability to analyze queries at runtime unlocked defensive operations tactics that enabled our data warehouse to run more smoothly. With Queryparser, queries can be intercepted en route to the data warehouse and submitted for analysis. If Queryparser detects parse errors or certain query anti-patterns, then the query can be rejected, reducing the overall load on the data warehouse.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span&gt;Problems and limitations&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Fred Brooks famously argued that there is&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/No_Silver_Bullet&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;no silver bullet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;in software engineering. While beneficial for our storage needs, Queryparser was no exception. As the project unfolded, it revealed some interesting essential complexities.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;span&gt;Long tail of language features&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;First, and least surprising: when adding support for a new SQL dialect, there is a long tail of infrequently-used language features to implement, which can require significant changes to Queryparser’s internal representation of a query. This was immediately apparent during the prototype phase, when Queryparser exclusively handled&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://my.vertica.com/docs/9.0.x/HTML/index.htm#Authoring/SQLReferenceManual/SQLReferenceManual.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Vertica&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, and was further confirmed when support for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://cwiki.apache.org/confluence/display/Hive/LanguageManual&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Hive&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://prestodb.io/docs/current/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Presto&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;was added. For example, parsing TIMESERIES and OFFSET in Vertica required adding new clauses to SELECT statements. Additionally, parsing LEFT SEMI JOINs in Hive required a new join type with special scoping rules, and parsing the bonus top-level namespace of “databases” in Presto (where tables belong to schemas belong to databases) required extensive re-working of struct-access parsing.³&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;span&gt;Tracking catalog state&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Second, tracking catalog state was hard. Recall that catalog information is needed for resolving column names and table names. Uber’s data warehouse supports highly concurrent workloads, including concurrent schema changes, typically creating, dropping, and renaming tables, or adding or dropping columns from an existing table. We experimented briefly with using Queryparser to track catalog state; if Queryparser was already analyzing every query, we wondered if we could simply add an analysis that reported the schema changes and produce the new catalog state by applying them to the previous catalog state. Ultimately, that approach was unsuccessful due to the difficulty of ordering the entire stream of queries. Instead, our alternative (and more effective) approach was to treat the catalog state as more-or-less static, tracking the schema membership and column-lists of tables through configuration files.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;span&gt;Sessionizing queries&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Third, sessionizing queries with Queryparser was difficult. In a perfect world, Queryparser would be able to track table lineage across an entire database session, accounting for transactions and rollbacks and various levels of&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Isolation_(database_systems)&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;transaction isolation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. In practice, however, reconstructing database sessions from the query logs was difficult, so we decided not to add table lineage support for those features. Instead, Queryparser relies on Uber’s ETL-framework to sessionize the ETL queries on its behalf.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;span&gt;Leaky abstraction&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Finally, Hive is a leaky abstraction over the underlying filesystem. For instance, INSERTs can be accomplished by several means:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;INSERT INTO foo SELECT … FROM bar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;ALTER TABLE foo ADD PARTITION … LOCATION ‘/hdfs/path/to/partition/in/bar’&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Uber’s ETL framework initially used the first method, but was migrated to use the second method, as it showed dramatic performance improvements. This caused issues with table lineage data, as ‘/hdfs/path/to/partition/in/bar’ was not interpreted by Queryparser as corresponding to table bar. This particular issue was&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;temporarily&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;mitigated with a regular expression to infer the table name from the HDFS path. However, in general, if you choose to bypass the SQL abstractions of Hive in favor of filesystem-layer operations, then you opt out of Queryparser analysis.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span&gt;Deploying Queryparser&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Deploying a Haskell service in Uber’s non-Haskell infrastructure required some minor creativity, but never amounted to a substantial problem.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Installing Haskell itself was straightforward. Uber’s standard infrastructure pattern is to run every service in a Docker container. Container-level dependencies are managed through config files, so adding Haskell support was as simple as adding&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.haskellstack.org/en/stable/README/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Stack&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;to the list of required packages.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Queryparser is internally deployed as a Haskell artifact, running behind a Python service wrapper for interoperability with the rest of Uber’s infrastructure. The Python wrapper acts as a proxy server and simply forwards requests to the Haskell backend server in the same docker container. The Haskell server consists of a main thread that listens for requests on a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unix_domain_socket&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;UNIX-domain socket&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;when a new request arrives, the main thread spawns a worker thread to handle the request.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Python wrapper also handles metric emission on behalf of the Haskell backend. Metric data is passed via a second UNIX-domain socket, with data flowing in the reverse direction: a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/2/library/threading.html#thread-objects&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;daemon-thread&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;in the Python layer listens for metrics from the Haskell layer.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In order to share configuration between the Python and Haskell layers, we implemented a tiny configuration parser in Haskell, which understood Uber’s standard Python convention of layered configuration files.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Finally, to define the service interface, we used&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://thrift.apache.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Thrift&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. This is the standard choice at Uber, and since Thrift has Haskell support, the Haskell server worked out-of-the-box. Writing the Python code to transparently forward requests required diving into the binary protocol and was the most difficult operations step.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span&gt;Summary&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Queryparser unlocked a diversity of solutions and had some interesting limitations. From its humble origins as a migration tool, it became a vehicle for insight into large-scale data access patterns.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;If you are interested in working on similar projects, reach out to&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:za@uber.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;za@uber.com&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;and/or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uber.com/careers/list/29589/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;apply for a role on with us via the Uber Careers page&lt;/a&gt; and tell your Uber recruiter that you’d like to work on the Data Knowledge Platform team.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;End Notes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;¹Spoiler alert: there ended up being dozens of primary keys to migrate. Each primary key could have many foreign keys under different aliases. The worst offender had over 50 different aliases.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;² &lt;span&gt;Foreign-key relationships ranged from the obvious like “SELECT * FROM foo JOIN bar ON foo.a = bar.b” to the less obvious like “SELECT * FROM foo WHERE foo.a IN (SELECT b from bar)” to the debatable like “SELECT a FROM foo UNION SELECT b FROM bar”. We erred on the side of being liberal about what we counted as a relationship, since output would be manually inspected anyway.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;³ Given the SQL “w.x.y.z”, which identifier is the column name? Depending on the catalog state and what is in scope, it could be “w” with “x.y.z” referring to nested struct fields, or it could be “z” with “w.x.y” referring to “database.schema.table”, or anything in between.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;sexy-author-bio&quot; class=&quot;matt-halverson&quot; readability=&quot;10.503225806452&quot;&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;sab-social-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;sab-Github&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/mhalverson&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;&lt;img id=&quot;sig-Github&quot; alt=&quot;Matt Halverson on Github&quot; src=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/plugins/sexy-author-bio/public/assets/images/flat-circle/sabgithub.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;sab-Linkedin&quot; href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/matt-halverson-6249854b/&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;&lt;img id=&quot;sig-Linkedin&quot; alt=&quot;Matt Halverson on Linkedin&quot; src=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/plugins/sexy-author-bio/public/assets/images/flat-circle/sablinkedin.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;sab-gravatar&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/author/matt-halverson/&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Matt Halverson&quot; src=&quot;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/2d6c5a73cd8cff8f3bdef961f9bd28fb?s=100&amp;amp;d=blank&amp;amp;r=g&quot; srcset=&quot;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/2d6c5a73cd8cff8f3bdef961f9bd28fb?s=200&amp;amp;d=blank&amp;amp;r=g 2x&quot; class=&quot;avatar avatar-100 photo&quot; height=&quot;100&quot; width=&quot;100&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matt Halverson is a senior software engineer at Uber. When he’s not reading the changelogs for SQL grammars, he enjoys singing with The Choral Project in San Jose. He is eternally grateful to David Thomas for introducing him to Haskell by way of Queryparser. 10 out of 10, would Haskell again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;post-meta&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Categories: &lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/category/uberdata/&quot; rel=&quot;category tag&quot;&gt;Uber Data&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;muted&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tags: &lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/tag/architecture/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Architecture&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/tag/data-analysis/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Data Analysis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/tag/data-architecture/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Data Architecture&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/tag/data-infrastructure/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Data Infrastructure&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/tag/data-ingestion/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Data Ingestion&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/tag/data-knowledge-platform/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Data Knowledge Platform&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/tag/data-warehouse/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Data Warehouse&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/tag/engineering/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Engineering&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/tag/etl/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;ETL&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/tag/haskell/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Haskell&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/tag/hive/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;HIVE&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/tag/matt-halverson/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Matt Halverson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/tag/open-source/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Open Source&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/tag/parsing/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Parsing&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/tag/presto/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Presto&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/tag/python/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/tag/queryparser/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Queryparser&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/tag/sql/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;SQL&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/tag/thirft/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Thirft&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/tag/transaction-isolation/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Transaction Isolation&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/tag/uber-engineering/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Uber Engineering&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/tag/uber-open-source/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Uber Open Source&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/tag/uuid/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;UUID&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/tag/vertica/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Vertica&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 20:45:31 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>manigandham</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Queryparser, an Open Source Tool for Parsing and Analyzing SQL</og:title>
<og:description>Written in Haskell, Queryparser is Uber Engineering's open source tool for parsing and analyzing SQL queries that makes it easy to identify foreign-key relationships in large data warehouses.</og:description>
<og:url>https://eng.uber.com/queryparser/</og:url>
<og:image>http://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Queryparser-Facebook.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://eng.uber.com/queryparser/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>An intro to Pen Plotters</title>
<link>http://www.tobiastoft.com/posts/an-intro-to-pen-plotters</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.tobiastoft.com/posts/an-intro-to-pen-plotters</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-layout sqs-grid-12 columns-12&quot; data-layout-label=&quot;Post Body&quot; data-type=&quot;item&quot; data-updated-on=&quot;1404441442067&quot; id=&quot;item-53b6103fe4b0db979121e6bb&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row sqs-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col sqs-col-12 span-12&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html&quot; data-block-type=&quot;2&quot; id=&quot;block-108d7c43af0071a50350&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been fascinated with pen plotters for a long time now and I've owned several of them – but for some reason never posted any of my explorations or findings online. Until now, at least.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might wonder what's so special about pen plotters? Well, let me tell you. Pen plotters are friendly robots from a not so distant past. They're the missing link between pencils and laser printers. They're lovely pieces of high precision technology that nobody cares about anymore. They're computer controlled machines that use regular pens to draw on regular paper with incredible speed and precision. They would draw blueprints for tweedy engineers and turtlenecked architects back in the 70's and 80's, they would draw colorful charts on transparencies for slick investment bankers to present on overhead projectors, and they probably also drew the schematics for the laser- and inkjet printers that replaced them a decade later. They were expensive, beautifully engineered, high quality machines. Which means that there are still plenty of them around, fully working and very cheap. You can, for instance, pick up an &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.ebay.com/sch/i.html?_trksid=p2050601.m570.l1313.TR11.TRC1.A0.H0.Xhp+7475a&amp;amp;_nkw=hp+7475a&amp;amp;_sacat=0&amp;amp;_from=R40&quot;&gt;HP 7475A on eBay&lt;/a&gt; for roughly $50, it's a great starter machine and I can't recommend it enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They're purely made for drawing though, so you can't print a book with them (unless you want a certain style to it), and they would suck at printing holiday photos or boarding passes. But they excel at crisp line drawings with a wonderful analog feel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block image-block sqs-block-image&quot; data-block-type=&quot;5&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1406417143945_122927&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-outer-wrapper layout-caption-below design-layout-inline&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;intrinsic&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-wrapper has-aspect-ratio&quot; data-description=&quot;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;A closeup of the 7475A's line quality when using a slightly worn felt tip pen on rough paper. No pixels, lots of personality.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/51907831e4b0454b98add7d2/t/53d451b6e4b021e113e52292/1406423509399/&quot; alt=&quot; A closeup of the 7475A's line quality when using a slightly worn felt tip pen on rough paper. No pixels, lots of personality. &quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;thumb-image&quot; alt=&quot; A closeup of the 7475A's line quality when using a slightly worn felt tip pen on rough paper. No pixels, lots of personality. &quot; data-src=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/51907831e4b0454b98add7d2/t/53d451b6e4b021e113e52292/1406423509399/&quot; data-image=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/51907831e4b0454b98add7d2/t/53d451b6e4b021e113e52292/1406423509399/&quot; data-image-dimensions=&quot;2500x1667&quot; data-image-focal-point=&quot;0.5,0.5&quot; data-load=&quot;false&quot; data-image-id=&quot;53d451b6e4b021e113e52292&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A closeup of the 7475A's line quality when using a slightly worn felt tip pen on rough paper. No pixels, lots of personality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html&quot; data-block-type=&quot;2&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1406417143945_123164&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Talking to them&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is one minor problem though, and that is that you can't just hook them up to your laptop and start plotting things from Illustrator: They speak a language that most operating systems have forgotten. Luckily it's a pretty simple language, so with minimal coding skills you can start plotting like it's 1984.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's what you'll (probably) need to get started:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;A pen plotter with &lt;strong&gt;a serial interface&lt;/strong&gt; (watch out for HPIB-only plotters!) – personally I like the HP 7475A and 7550A a lot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pens that fits your plotter. You can find &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.artstuff.net/Koh-I-Noor-Rapidoplot-Archival-DPP-Disposable-Plotter-Pens.html&quot;&gt;pens for old HP's&lt;/a&gt; in lots of places, including eBay.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some paper, whatever size your plotter takes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A USB to Serial adapter (or an Arduino if you're into that)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A DB-9 to DB-25 null-modem, you can find one on &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://amzn.com/B00066HL50&quot;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You might also need a &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://amzn.com/B00004Z5GZ&quot;&gt;DB-25 female gender changer&lt;/a&gt;, depending on your plotter and null modem – I did for my HP 7550A.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A terminal emulator like &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://freeware.the-meiers.org/&quot;&gt;Coolterm&lt;/a&gt; for OSX or &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/download.html&quot;&gt;PuTTY&lt;/a&gt; for Windows.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optional: &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://processing.org/download/&quot;&gt;Processing.org&lt;/a&gt; if you want to start automating things.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most plotters run their serial connection at &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/8-N-1&quot;&gt;9600/8-N-1&lt;/a&gt; as default unless somebody changed the settings. Depending on your plotter you might have some dip switches on the back near the port or a setting in the menu on the front panel. Consult your manual on how to set up the connection – most manuals can be found by Googling the plotter's make and model. It might take a little trial and error to get it working, but it shouldn't be too hard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's jump straight to the fun part: Drawing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, load some paper in the plotter and put a pen in the carousel or pen holder at slot number 1. Open your terminal emulator of choice and connect to the plotter. You probably won't see any response from the machine. Test if it works by typing (or copy-pasting) the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
IN;
SP1;
PA2000,2000;
CI500;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will tell the plotter to first initialize (IN), select pen 1 (SP1), go to absolute position (PA) at (2000, 2000) and then draw a circle (CI) with a radius of 500 plotter units. Did it do that? If not, check your connection – again, the manual is invaluable in these situations. Got it working? Awesome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you've never played with plotters before, then this was probably also your first introduction to the language that most plotters speak: &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HPGL&quot;&gt;HPGL&lt;/a&gt; (Hewlett Packard Graphics Language). Even if you don't have an HP plotter, it probably still speaks HPGL or HPGL/2. There are lots of &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://paulbourke.net/dataformats/hpgl/&quot;&gt;great&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.hpmuseum.net/document.php?catfile=213&quot;&gt;resources&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://cstep.luberth.com/hpgl.htm&quot;&gt;online&lt;/a&gt; about HPGL, so I'll only introduce a few basic commands here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Moving the pen around&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm sure you've already figured out how to select a pen with SP, but just in case: &lt;strong&gt;SP1;&lt;/strong&gt; selects pen 1, &lt;strong&gt;SP2;&lt;/strong&gt; selects pen 2, &lt;strong&gt;SP3;&lt;/strong&gt; selects pen 3, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moving the pen is almost as simple. The two most important commands are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
PU;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
PD;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PU;&lt;/strong&gt; means &quot;Pen Up&quot; and &lt;strong&gt;PD;&lt;/strong&gt; means... yep, &quot;Pen Down&quot;. Now, if you add an XY coordinate after those two commands, the plotter will move to that position after either setting the pen down or lifting it up from the paper. By the way, don't forget that semicolon at the end:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
PU500,500;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will lift the pen, and move to (500,500).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
PD500,1000;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will then set the pen down and move to (500,1000). In other words, it'll draw a line from (500,500) to (500,1000). Try it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You'll notice that if you end your sequence with PD, the plotter won't lift the pen from the paper and the ink will start to bleed through. It's therefore a good idea to issue PU; after drawing a shape to avoid that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's how to draw a box with these very basic commands:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
PU1000,1000;
PD1000,2000;
PD2000,2000;
PD2000,1000;
PD1000,1000;
PU;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you read those lines carefully you'll see that we told the plotter to go to (1000,1000), put the pen down and go to (1000,2000), while keeping the pen down, move to (2000,2000), then (2000,1000) and finally back to (1000,1000) and lift the pen. While it's easy to appreciate the simplicity of that, it might not be the most efficient way to draw a box. More on that later, because I know that you want to put a circle inside that box first. Ok, let's do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
PU1500,1500;
CI500;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nice, right? First we moved to the center of the box, which is (1500,1500) and then we drew a circle with a radius of 500. You probably noticed that the circle command is a little more advanced than PU and PD, in that it automatically handled lifting the pen up and down. As I alluded to earlier, there are other commands like that for drawing primitive shapes, e.g. ER for Edge Rectangles (which are rectangles without a fill):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
PU2000,2000;
ER1000,1600;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you want a rectangle with a fill, use RR:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
PU3000,3600;
RR1000,1000;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now your piece of paper should look roughly like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block image-block sqs-block-image&quot; data-block-type=&quot;5&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1404440609795_19207&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-outer-wrapper layout-caption-below design-layout-inline&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;intrinsic&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-wrapper lightbox has-aspect-ratio&quot; data-description=&quot;&quot; data-lightbox-theme=&quot;dark&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/51907831e4b0454b98add7d2/t/53d4612fe4b09cb24882b621/1406427448063/First+plot.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;First plot.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;thumb-image&quot; alt=&quot;First plot.jpg&quot; data-src=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/51907831e4b0454b98add7d2/t/53d4612fe4b09cb24882b621/1406427448063/First+plot.jpg&quot; data-image=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/51907831e4b0454b98add7d2/t/53d4612fe4b09cb24882b621/1406427448063/First+plot.jpg&quot; data-image-dimensions=&quot;2500x1934&quot; data-image-focal-point=&quot;0.5,0.5&quot; data-load=&quot;false&quot; data-image-id=&quot;53d4612fe4b09cb24882b621&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html&quot; data-block-type=&quot;2&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1404440609795_19446&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not a bad start. Hopefully you found this as fun to play around with as I did when I first started playing with plotters. It does get pretty tedious to manually control it via the terminal though, so next step would naturally be to start automating the drawing part a bit. Luckily there are awesome generative art tools out there, like &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.openframeworks.cc/&quot;&gt;OpenFrameworks&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.processing.org&quot;&gt;Processing.org&lt;/a&gt;. Personally I like using Processing, because it's a neat self contained package and because of it's twin: Processing.js. Processing.js means I can play around with a sketch on my iPad using &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://procoding.audiocommander.de/&quot;&gt;Procoding&lt;/a&gt; while on the train, and when I'm ready to draw it I can dump the exact same code into the &quot;real&quot; Processing IDE on my laptop with access to the serial port, OpenCV, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Connecting to Processing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I'm assuming you know the basics of Processing.org (or a similar environment) if you're reading this. If not, now would be a good time to pick it up. It has never been easier to &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://processing.org/tutorials/gettingstarted/&quot;&gt;get started&lt;/a&gt; – there's a huge community and tons of tutorials to support you.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Essentially the workflow is the same as before: You &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.processing.org/reference/libraries/serial/Serial.html&quot;&gt;set up a simple serial connection&lt;/a&gt; and hand over the drawing part to Processing (or whatever your tool of choice is). One important thing to be aware of is that these plotters have tiny little buffers, so you can't feed them all the HPGL commands at once. There are two ways of going about that: One is to drip feed them with data, which is slow, but also by far the easiest to implement, the other way is to implement a simple form of flow control by asking the plotter if there's enough buffer space available before sending it another chunk of data. I'll cover how to do that later in another article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drip feeding is great for just playing around, especially in the beginning since it's easy to implement. Just add a delay between issuing your drawing commands, so the plotter has time to catch up. Depending on what you draw you might have to experiment a little. If you overflow the buffer your plotter will start behaving weird and it'll probably try to indicate that an error happened. 9 out of 10 times I've had problems, it's been due to the buffer overflowing. A good delay value to start with would be something like 250 - 500 ms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/tobiastoft/SymbolicDisarray&quot;&gt;uploaded&lt;/a&gt; a Processing sketch as an example of something that works with the drip feeding method. It's a recreation of Georg Nees's &quot;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://translab.burundi.sk/code/vzx/#25&quot;&gt;Cubic Disarray&lt;/a&gt;&quot; from the late 60's, and it looks like this if you plot it on an HP 7550A on a sheet of 11x17&quot; paper:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block image-block sqs-block-image&quot; data-block-type=&quot;5&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1404440609795_22607&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-outer-wrapper layout-caption-below design-layout-inline&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;intrinsic&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-wrapper lightbox has-aspect-ratio&quot; data-description=&quot;&quot; data-lightbox-theme=&quot;dark&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/51907831e4b0454b98add7d2/t/53b61126e4b01e06b37b0c9d/1404440913928/Cubic+disarray&quot; alt=&quot;Cubic disarray&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;thumb-image&quot; alt=&quot;Cubic disarray&quot; data-src=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/51907831e4b0454b98add7d2/t/53b61126e4b01e06b37b0c9d/1404440913928/Cubic+disarray&quot; data-image=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/51907831e4b0454b98add7d2/t/53b61126e4b01e06b37b0c9d/1404440913928/Cubic+disarray&quot; data-image-dimensions=&quot;2500x3796&quot; data-image-focal-point=&quot;0.5,0.5&quot; data-load=&quot;false&quot; data-image-id=&quot;53b61126e4b01e06b37b0c9d&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html&quot; data-block-type=&quot;2&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1404440609795_25324&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find it here: &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/tobiastoft/SymbolicDisarray&quot;&gt;https://github.com/tobiastoft/SymbolicDisarray&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried to make the code as easy as possible to modify from a visual point of view, one of the things I did was implement a very simple &quot;symbol&quot; feature, where you can define something else than a square to copy and rotate as the plotter progresses down the page. I've included a few examples in the code. The different symbols are found in the &quot;Symbol&quot; class which starts around line 105 (I'll clean up that file soon, I promise).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also included a quick example of how to use the HPGL &quot;label&quot; (LB) command to add text to a drawing. You'll find the example around line 49 in SymbolicDisarray.pde. Labels are fun to play around with and it's fascinating to watch the plotter write each letter – plus the built-in font isn't too bad either. Here's what the Lightning Bolt pattern looks like, notice the label at the bottom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block image-block sqs-block-image&quot; data-block-type=&quot;5&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1404440609795_26333&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-outer-wrapper layout-caption-below design-layout-inline&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;intrinsic&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-wrapper lightbox has-aspect-ratio&quot; data-description=&quot;&quot; data-lightbox-theme=&quot;dark&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/51907831e4b0454b98add7d2/t/53b61200e4b0aeb10ab92ab1/1404441100257/LightningBoltzzZzzzZzZzz.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;LightningBoltzzZzzzZzZzz.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;thumb-image&quot; alt=&quot;LightningBoltzzZzzzZzZzz.jpg&quot; data-src=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/51907831e4b0454b98add7d2/t/53b61200e4b0aeb10ab92ab1/1404441100257/LightningBoltzzZzzzZzZzz.jpg&quot; data-image=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/51907831e4b0454b98add7d2/t/53b61200e4b0aeb10ab92ab1/1404441100257/LightningBoltzzZzzzZzZzz.jpg&quot; data-image-dimensions=&quot;2500x3796&quot; data-image-focal-point=&quot;0.5,0.5&quot; data-load=&quot;false&quot; data-image-id=&quot;53b61200e4b0aeb10ab92ab1&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html&quot; data-block-type=&quot;2&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1404440609795_26548&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're still with me this far, then first of all: Thanks! I'm not sure I would have been able to concentrate that long myself. Second, if you're still interested in plotting then please go nuts with the example code – fork it like there's no tomorrow and don't forget to share what you make!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 19:22:11 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Tomte</dc:creator>
<og:title>An intro to Pen Plotters</og:title>
<og:url>http://www.tobiastoft.com/posts/an-intro-to-pen-plotters</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>I've been fascinated with pen plotters for a long time now and I've owned several of them – but for some reason never posted any of my explorations or findings online. Until now, at least. You might wonder what's so special about pen plotters? Well, let me tell you. Pen plotters are friendly robots</og:description>
<og:image>http://static1.squarespace.com/static/51907831e4b0454b98add7d2/t/53d45ef4e4b0e08793bc2b58/1406426885773/HP+7475A.jpg?format=1000w</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.tobiastoft.com/posts/an-intro-to-pen-plotters</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Canada to Scrap IBM Payroll Plan Gone Awry Costing $1B</title>
<link>http://www.itprotoday.com/hybrid-cloud/canada-scrap-ibm-payroll-plan-gone-awry-costing-c1-billion</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.itprotoday.com/hybrid-cloud/canada-scrap-ibm-payroll-plan-gone-awry-costing-c1-billion</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;(Bloomberg) --Canada plans to scrap a major IBM federal payroll plan that created chaos for thousands of government workers and will have cost the government almost C$1 billion ($780 million) by the time it’s over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Phoenix project was originally chosen by Prime Minister Justin Trudeau’s Conservative predecessors 10 years ago to centralize the government payroll.  International Business Machines Corp. won the contract to install and help run the system, which uses Oracle Corp. software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It went live in 2016, just months after Trudeau won office. From the beginning, it didn’t work like it was supposed to. Some people were paid too much, others not at all. Those issues snowballed with the deluge of requests to fix incorrect paychecks. The fear of not getting paid still hangs over the country’s more than 260,000 federal public servants. Some put off major financial decisions. Others declined promotions or retirement, fearing any change in their pay could cause more trouble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two years later, some employees are still having problems. The latest data showed a backlog of 384,000 cases linked to the program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IBM said it’s “fulfilling its obligations on the Phoenix contract, and the software is functioning as intended.” The company “continues to work in partnership with the government’s efforts to resolve the project’s issues, and remains committed to the project’s overall success,” it said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An Oracle representative declined to comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Debi Daviau, president of one of the main unions representing government workers, said the blame falls mostly on the senior government officials who ran the project and opened it even though there were glaring warning signs it wasn’t ready. But she also questions why IBM went ahead when it was clear there would be problems, and why the company benefits from a project that never worked as promised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“They should have known better,” Daviau said in an interview. When the company’s warnings that more testing was needed went unheeded, IBM didn’t put its foot down and hold up the project until it was ready, she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“IBM got into a contract with the government that was very beneficial to IBM, which meant that the contract -- despite non-delivery -- could continue to be extended and IBM could continue to come back to the pot for money,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Treasury Board President Scott Brison has said IBM has a responsibility to help the government fix the program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“IBM, as a sophisticated global company, needs to recognize that we as the government of Canada are not just an important client for IBM but there is reputational risk for IBM in not helping us fix this,” Brison said last June during an appearance at the Senate’s finance committee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fiasco illustrates how difficult it is to bring governments into the 21st century when it comes to technology, and the risks and limitations faced by companies like IBM, who get a large amount of their business from governments. IBM, based in Armonk, New York, doesn’t disclose how much of its revenue comes from government contracts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not the first time IBM has been embroiled in a payroll system disaster. The Australian state of Queensland scrapped a similar project after an initial contract went off the rails and ended up costing the government around A$1 billion ($772 million) to fix. A public inquiry mostly blamed government officials, but determined IBM shouldn’t have been chosen for the job. IBM disputed some of the inquiry’s findings in 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Canadian Finance Minister Bill Morneau said Wednesday that the previous government made mistakes in dismissing staff needed to implement Phoenix but that, “it’s not about seeking blame, it’s about trying to get it right.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Canada announced Tuesday it would start moving away from Phoenix and set aside money to find a new solution. The government will spend C$431 million to keep the program running in the near term, on top of C$460 million already spent to put Phoenix in place and fix the problems it generated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project was meant to save costs by firing 1,200 employees handling payroll at various departments around the country and replacing them with about 500 people in a centralized location using Phoenix to handle most of the government’s payroll needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An inquiry from Canada’s auditor general, a position similar to the U.S. Government Accountability Office, found many of the new employees were poorly trained and overworked. The software platform itself, a heavily modified version of Oracle’s PeopleSoft program, had yet to be encoded with many of the payroll complexities faced by a massive and diverse public service, such as unique shift rules for Coast Guard officers or prison guards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phoenix is a classic example of a government wanting to save money on an expensive new technology project by cutting the number of employees working on it, only to discover later that those people were essential to seeing it through, said Nigel Wallis, a vice president with research firm IDC Canada. Other companies considered the project and decided against bidding because it looked too complex, but IBM went ahead, Wallis said. “The promise of short term savings are often illusory,” Wallis said “That’s a real issue not just for government but also for a lot of large scale technology transformations. You need to approach them with a level of seriousness that I don’t think necessarily was done in this instance.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most major technology change-over projects -- for the private and public sectors -- either fail or face significant challenges, according to researcher Standish Group, which tracks thousands of projects every year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Wednesday, a New Democratic Party representative stood up in Parliament to ask Trudeau what he was doing for one of her constituents who was out C$40,000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We didn’t create this mess,” the prime minister said. “But we are going to fix it.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 17:57:12 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>RmDen</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Canada to Scrap IBM Payroll Plan Gone Awry Costing C$1 Billion</og:title>
<og:url>http://www.itprotoday.com/hybrid-cloud/canada-scrap-ibm-payroll-plan-gone-awry-costing-c1-billion</og:url>
<og:description>The Phoenix project was originally chosen by Prime Minister Justin Trudeau’s Conservative predecessors 10 years ago to centralize the government payroll. International Business Machines Corp. won the contract to install and help run the system, which uses Oracle Corp. software.</og:description>
<og:image>http://www.itprotoday.com/sites/itprotoday.com/files/sever-3100049_1920.jpg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.itprotoday.com/hybrid-cloud/canada-scrap-ibm-payroll-plan-gone-awry-costing-c1-billion</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>