<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Apple and Google partner on Covid-19 contact tracing technology</title>
<link>https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2020/04/apple-and-google-partner-on-covid-19-contact-tracing-technology/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2020/04/apple-and-google-partner-on-covid-19-contact-tracing-technology/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Across the world, governments and health authorities are working together to find solutions to the COVID-19 pandemic, to protect people and get society back up and running. Software developers are contributing by crafting technical tools to help combat the virus and save lives. In this spirit of collaboration, Google and Apple are announcing a joint effort to enable the use of Bluetooth technology to help governments and health agencies reduce the spread of the virus, with user privacy and security central to the design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since COVID-19 can be transmitted through close proximity to affected individuals, public health officials have identified contact tracing as a valuable tool to help contain its spread. A number of leading public health authorities, universities, and NGOs around the world have been doing important work to develop opt-in contact tracing technology. To further this cause, Apple and Google will be launching a comprehensive solution that includes application programming interfaces (APIs) and operating system-level technology to assist in enabling contact tracing. Given the urgent need, the plan is to implement this solution in two steps while maintaining strong protections around user privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, in May, both companies will release APIs that enable interoperability between Android and iOS devices using apps from public health authorities. These official apps will be available for users to download via their respective app stores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, in the coming months, Apple and Google will work to enable a broader Bluetooth-based contact tracing platform by building this functionality into the underlying platforms. This is a more robust solution than an API and would allow more individuals to participate, if they choose to opt in, as well as enable interaction with a broader ecosystem of apps and government health authorities. Privacy, transparency, and consent are of utmost importance in this effort, and we look forward to building this functionality in consultation with interested stakeholders. We will openly publish information about our work for others to analyze.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of us at Apple and Google believe there has never been a more important moment to work together to solve one of the world’s most pressing problems. Through close cooperation and collaboration with developers, governments and public health providers, we hope to harness the power of technology to help countries around the world slow the spread of COVID-19 and accelerate the return of everyday life.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 17:05:01 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ikarandeep</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Apple and Google partner on COVID-19 contact tracing technology</og:title>
<og:description>Apple and Google announce a joint effort to help governments and health agencies reduce the spread of the virus, with user privacy central to the design.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2020/04/apple-and-google-partner-on-covid-19-contact-tracing-technology/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/values/corporate/standard/Apple_google-partner-on-covid-19-contact-tracing-technology_04102020_LP_hero.jpg.og.jpg?202004101823</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2020/04/apple-and-google-partner-on-covid-19-contact-tracing-technology/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Senate Stock Watcher</title>
<link>https://senatestockwatcher.com</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://senatestockwatcher.com</guid>
<description>It has become obvious that the STOCK ACT has been violated more than enough times that the penality for doing so is marginal compared to the gains that a senatorial member can earn from insider knowledge of market behavior for upcoming news.&lt;p&gt;Since there is no major reprecussion for insider knowledge trading for a senator or member of congress to act on the best behalf of their wallet. Their actions speak louder than their words.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Members of the Senate must report perodic reports of their portfolio transactions. We compile them for easy reading - make your own deductions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 16:20:02 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ericmay</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://senatestockwatcher.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A man owns the most advanced private air force after buying 46 F/A-18s</title>
<link>https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone/32869/this-man-owns-the-worlds-most-advanced-private-air-force-after-buying-46-f-a-18-hornets</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone/32869/this-man-owns-the-worlds-most-advanced-private-air-force-after-buying-46-f-a-18-hornets</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;article-head&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.thedrive.com/images/warzone-logo_high-contrast_dark-bg.png&quot; class=&quot;channel-logo&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;dek&quot;&gt;We talked to the owner of Air USA about probably the most incredible private aircraft purchase of all time and the future of his adversary business.&lt;/h2&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;news-body&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;hero-image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;image-fade-in&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://the-drive-3.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Fapi.thedrive.com%2Fwp-content%2Fuploads%2F2020%2F04%2FDONKIRLIN.jpg%3Fquality%3D85?w=1440&amp;amp;auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;ixlib=js-1.4.1&amp;amp;s=ddcd58b04f8e0c11c209edac7940aa65&quot; srcset=&quot;https://the-drive-3.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Fapi.thedrive.com%2Fwp-content%2Fuploads%2F2020%2F04%2FDONKIRLIN.jpg%3Fquality%3D85?w=1440&amp;amp;auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;ixlib=js-1.4.1&amp;amp;s=ddcd58b04f8e0c11c209edac7940aa65 1x,https://the-drive-3.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Fapi.thedrive.com%2Fwp-content%2Fuploads%2F2020%2F04%2FDONKIRLIN.jpg%3Fquality%3D85?w=1920&amp;amp;auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;ixlib=js-1.4.1&amp;amp;s=e472c31c6dfb1efbe7202deec15d3b75 1.5x&quot; onload=&quot;this.style.opacity=1&quot;/&gt;© Commonwealth of Australia, Department of Defence&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;has-ad-column&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;articleFragment paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the last 30 years, Don Kirlin has been flying for the airlines, working on real estate deals, setting up the world's biggest skydiving meets, and building a private air force the likes of which even he has a hard time believing is possible. Just last month, &lt;em&gt;The War Zone&lt;/em&gt; was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone/32464/australia-to-sell-retired-f-a-18-hornet-fighters-to-private-aggressor-firm-air-usa&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;among the first to report&lt;/a&gt; that his company would be purchasing multiple squadrons worth of surplus Royal Australian Air Force (RAAF) F/A-18 Hornets to be used in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone/21363/usaf-reveals-timelines-and-basing-plans-for-its-huge-adversary-support-contract&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;contractor adversary air support&lt;/a&gt; role here in the United States. In that role, they would primarily fly against U.S. military fighter pilots, replicating aerial threats from potential enemy nations. So basically, they are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone/25075/how-f-5s-beat-out-f-16s-for-the-navys-latest-commercial-aggressor-contract&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;bad guys for hire&lt;/a&gt;, but strictly for training and development work. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, not only do we have all the details on that purchase, which is even more impressive than it initially seemed, but we talked at length with the entrepreneur owner of &lt;a href=&quot;https://air-usa.com/&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Air USA&lt;/a&gt;, located in Quincy, Illinois, about his company's past and what is turning into a remarkable, if not downright historic, future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;articleFragment paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don Kirlin imported his first foreign military jet, and L-39 Albatross, in 1994, at a time when doing so was an extremely complex and convoluted affair full of pitfalls and unknowns. Since then, he has repeated the process dozens of times over and was the first owner of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone/29292/you-can-buy-paul-allens-mig-29-fulcrum-jet-fighter&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;private MiG-29 Fulcrum&lt;/a&gt; in the United States, among a long list of other exotic flying firsts. He now holds eight licenses with the Bureau of Alcohol Tobacco and Firearms (ATF), allowing him to own military machine guns and cannons, as well as thousands of rounds of ammunition to fire through them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img itemprop=&quot;associatedMedia&quot; class=&quot;figure-image&quot; src=&quot;https://the-drive.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Fs3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2Fthe-drive-cms-content-staging%2Fmessage-editor%252F1586471739121-124124144.jpeg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;ixlib=js-1.4.1&amp;amp;s=eaa3f68361fc0bef4e14209b5fe8a86e&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don Kirlin with members of his Air USA team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;articleFragment paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was also one of the early pioneers of the then-fledgling, if not wholly experimental, adversary air support market. In the early 2000s, he joined forces with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone/32932/private-aggressors-help-the-navy-test-air-defense-systems-on-its-newest-supercarrier&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Airborne Tactical Advantage Company&lt;/a&gt; (ATAC), which was blazing a trail with their contracts with the Navy to supply fast jet targets and electronic warfare pod toting adversaries that mimic everything from enemy cruise missiles to fighters for Navy and Marine fighter aircraft and Navy surface combatants to train against. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During those early years, Air USA worked as a subcontractor for ATAC, flying the vast majority of the contracted subsonic adversary support flight hours. So, Kirlin and his company's experience in what is now an exploding adversary support marketplace dates back to its very genesis. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img itemprop=&quot;associatedMedia&quot; class=&quot;figure-image&quot; src=&quot;https://the-drive-2.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Fs3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2Fthe-drive-cms-content-staging%2Fmessage-editor%252F1586471632120-141441dad.jpeg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;ixlib=js-1.4.1&amp;amp;s=92db1b106d3cdb6606adc9adedcf8d62&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to the Hornet purchase, Kirlin's most outlandish import was not just one, but four MiG-29 Fulcrums. He was the first private owner of one of these jets in the United States. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;articleFragment paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to today and Kirlin now owns an impressive fleet of ex-military aircraft that perform a wide number of roles for the Defense Department, from training &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone/13562/we-chew-the-fat-about-bacn-with-program-boss-and-airman-who-used-it-in-combat&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Joint Terminal Attack Controllers&lt;/a&gt; (JTACs), the modern designation for Forward Air Controllers on the ground, to saturating the sensor systems of America's most advanced tactical fighters with aggressor adversaries in the air. With the individual contracts that will underpin the Air Force's &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone/30557/air-force-hires-seven-companies-in-long-awaited-mega-adversary-air-support-contract&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;gargantuan adversary air support tender&lt;/a&gt; about to doled out, Air USA's operation has to grow in capacity and complexity in order to even attempt to meet demand. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter the most spectacular private aircraft purchase of all time—Air USA's acquisition of &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; of the Royal Australian Air Force's remaining F/A-18A/B Hornets. Canada &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone/25050/canadian-auditors-slam-surplus-aussie-hornet-buy-describe-fighter-force-in-collapse&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;had bought 25 prior&lt;/a&gt; to this deal going through. The jets Air USA is slated to receive, 46 in total, of which 36 are flying today, will be replaced by the F-35A Joint Strike Fighter within the RAAF's ranks and thus will be totally retired from service by the end of 2021. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img itemprop=&quot;associatedMedia&quot; class=&quot;figure-image&quot; src=&quot;https://the-drive-3.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Fs3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2Fthe-drive-cms-content-staging%2Fmessage-editor%252F1586462371684-234234c.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;ixlib=js-1.4.1&amp;amp;s=573fdeaa3b36f4ada89b1d40ed82156f&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;© Commonwealth of Australia, Department of Defence&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aussie F/A-18A/B Hornets and their replacements, F-35As. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;articleFragment paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the terms of the deal have not been disclosed, the purchase does include all of the RAAF's F/A-18 spare parts inventory and test equipment, valued at over a billion dollars alone, according to Kirlin. Those parts will be incredibly valuable as Air USA is planning on putting every single airframe it receives back into service—not just the 36 aircraft that are flyable today, but the other 10 that are not, as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those jets just need inspections and are not parted out or grounded for any other reasons. This will allow Air USA to operate at least three fully outfitted squadrons of the 4th generation fighters at all times, which Kirlin hopes will be forward deployed to key bases around the United States where they will primarily help give fleet pilots, testers, and tactics developers, a run for their money in the air-to-air combat arena. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img itemprop=&quot;associatedMedia&quot; class=&quot;figure-image&quot; src=&quot;https://the-drive-3.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Fs3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2Fthe-drive-cms-content-staging%2Fmessage-editor%252F1586468423423-d2424.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;ixlib=js-1.4.1&amp;amp;s=eef06a74d42e691b783c5eafd4081913&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;© Commonwealth of Australia, Department of Defence&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;articleFragment paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are not Hornets in some dated configuration, either. The RAAF spent a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of money keeping its legacy Hornet fleet relevant until replacements arrived. One of the most important capabilities the jets come with is the bolt-on Elta EL-L/8222 (license-built in the U.S. under the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.harris.com/solution/advanced-capability-pod-acap&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;L3Harris Advanced Capability Pod&lt;/a&gt; name) electronic warfare pod. These Israeli-designed pods are pretty much the world standard in modular self-protection jamming systems and are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.harris.com/press-releases/2013/08/exelis-to-supply-advanced-jamming-pods-for-us-air-force-and-us-navy-tactical&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;used on the Pentagon's own&lt;/a&gt; aggressor fleet, as well as by various nations around the globe on frontline aircraft. You can learn just how powerful this system is, being able to turn even highly antiquated aircraft into formidable and deadly aerial threats, especially when paired with unique tactics, in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone/26880/enough-with-the-indian-mig-21-bison-versus-pakistani-f-16-viper-bullshit&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;this past piece of ours.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div itemprop=&quot;associatedMedia&quot; class=&quot;video-youtube&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe class=&quot;video-youtube__video&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/IflKPVVBG1M?rel=0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;has-ad-column&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;articleFragment paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of Air USA's secondhand Hornets feature the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone/19508/the-best-of-the-usmcs-aging-f-a-18-hornets-to-receive-aesa-radar-upgrade&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;AN/APG-73 radar&lt;/a&gt;—the same one that is found on the F/A-18C/D and early F/A-18E/F Super Hornets—that differs from the less capable AN/APG-65 radar the A/B Hornet was originally equipped with. The AN/APG-73 remains a very capable radar set and is largely superior to anything else on the adversary market at this time. Kirlin also informs us that the radar and electronic warfare pod are integrated in such a way that the aircraft can simultaneously jam and engage (jam and shoot) enemy targets, which he doesn't believe exists anywhere else on the adversary market and is a critical capability when it comes to mimicking more advanced foreign fighter threats. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img itemprop=&quot;associatedMedia&quot; class=&quot;figure-image&quot; src=&quot;https://the-drive-3.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Fs3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2Fthe-drive-cms-content-staging%2Fmessage-editor%252F1586450525586-apg73.jpeg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;ixlib=js-1.4.1&amp;amp;s=79d20754917d3069bebd49744311ac70&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AN/APG-73 Radar in the nose of an F/A-18 Hornet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;articleFragment paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The jets also come with their Northrop Grumman &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.airforce-technology.com/news/northrop-grumman-litening-pods-upgrades/&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;AN/AAQ-28 LITENING&lt;/a&gt; advanced targeting pods, which are hugely capable in the air-to-ground targeting and non-traditional reconnaissance realm, as well as for positively identifying aircraft visually at long ranges. You can read all about this function and its value in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone/21081/the-usaf-has-quietly-added-large-multi-function-cockpit-displays-to-its-f-15c-fleet&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;this past piece of ours&lt;/a&gt;. In addition, the Hornets come with 68 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone/18358/new-digital-eyepiece-will-allow-u-s-fighter-pilots-to-own-the-night-like-never-before&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Joint Helmet Mounted Cueing Systems&lt;/a&gt; (JHMCS), which offers helmet-mounted display capability that drastically increases a pilot's situational awareness and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone/8754/f-22-now-has-aim-9x-but-still-no-helmet-mounted-display-to-use-with-it&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;high-off-boresight targeting&lt;/a&gt; for close-range air-to-air missiles. This will make it easier for these aggressor jets to simulate foreign capabilities of a similar nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img itemprop=&quot;associatedMedia&quot; class=&quot;figure-image&quot; src=&quot;https://the-drive-3.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Fs3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2Fthe-drive-cms-content-staging%2Fmessage-editor%252F1586470163411-20190927raaf0000000_001.t5d93edc6.m1200.xcp-_uaiv.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;ixlib=js-1.4.1&amp;amp;s=de4270d240844d377a6835e7bc760815&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;© Commonwealth of Australia, Department of Defence&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A RAAF Hornet pilot wearing their JHMCS helmet-mounted display. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;articleFragment paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, Kirlin informs us that that the Aussie Hornets are being imported in exactly the same configuration as they are flying operationally today the RAAF. Nothing is being removed, even the jet's Link 16 data-link system and its internal M61 20mm Vulcan cannon are staying put.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the condition of the surplus Hornet fleet, Kirlin says they are in incredible shape and show little signs of corrosion—likely a result of their often hot and dry operating environment down under as opposed to the salty conditions aboard aircraft carriers that U.S. Navy Hornets have had to endure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img itemprop=&quot;associatedMedia&quot; class=&quot;figure-image&quot; src=&quot;https://the-drive.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Fs3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2Fthe-drive-cms-content-staging%2Fmessage-editor%252F1586450571048-wvjmuk-evfmu8cxribcp_ipmkejw89fatdpzksa9scy.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;ixlib=js-1.4.1&amp;amp;s=c13b8b4787d79d860413f38b0fe8fa3a&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;© Commonwealth of Australia, Department of Defence&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An Aussie F/A-18 Hornet in its latest advanced configuration, carrying the AN/AAQ-28 LITENING advanced targeting pod and Elta EL-L/8222 electronic warfare pod, as well as JDAMs and an AMRAAM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;articleFragment paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10 of the fighters have had their &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone/19040/navy-to-slash-legacy-f-a-18-hornet-fleet-to-prop-up-beleaguered-usmc-squadrons&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;center barrel sections replaced&lt;/a&gt;—a critical structural upgrade that is necessary once Hornets hit a certain level of fatigue—but the rest of the fleet shouldn't need them. Kirlin says that since the aircraft have never trapped (landed) aboard or launched off a carrier, which causes extreme stress on the airframes, they should be able to operate continuously through 2035 and possibly even beyond. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img itemprop=&quot;associatedMedia&quot; class=&quot;figure-image&quot; src=&quot;https://the-drive-3.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Fs3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2Fthe-drive-cms-content-staging%2Fmessage-editor%252F1586462318563-225235c.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;ixlib=js-1.4.1&amp;amp;s=cc78dd059425673d767b445143198432&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;© Commonwealth of Australia, Department of Defence&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;articleFragment paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first aircraft will be heading in Air USA's direction soon. For transport, the jets have their outer wings and horizontal stabilizers removed, but that's all the dismantling needed. They will be shipped via ocean freighter and it will only take about 60 days from arrival to get them in the air. The rest of the 36 flyable airframes will be flown in batches across the Pacific with the help of a tanker and will be ready for operations shortly after they arrive in the United States. The last 10 that are grounded due to lack of inspections will come over last.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for what the jets will look like once they lose their RAAF roundels and become Air USA jets, Air USA's owner wasn't entirely sure, but he does like the paint on one of his MiG-29s, which could be replicated on at least some of the Hornets. He also mentioned that a jet-black Hornet would be fun to have, just for the heck of it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img itemprop=&quot;associatedMedia&quot; class=&quot;figure-image&quot; src=&quot;https://the-drive-2.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Fs3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2Fthe-drive-cms-content-staging%2Fmessage-editor%252F1586449862714-mig29finalpaint001.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;ixlib=js-1.4.1&amp;amp;s=054953737f0fef4755396e7d42a2c41f&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the company's two MiG-29UBs in a blue, gray, and teal camouflage pattern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;articleFragment paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kirlin says that he looked at all the aircraft his competitors have bought, especially the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone/29527/the-first-flight-of-a-mirage-f-1-belonging-to-a-private-aggressor-company-has-occurred&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Mirage F-1s from Spain&lt;/a&gt; and France and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone/16966/draken-picks-up-a-dozen-south-african-cheetahs-to-emulate-4th-generation-adversaries&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Atlas Cheetahs from South Africa&lt;/a&gt; that his competitors ATAC and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone/25927/check-out-cockpit-in-draken-internationals-private-mirage-f-1m-aggressor-jet&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Draken USA have snapped up&lt;/a&gt;, and passed on them. He actually showed me the approved ATF forms for importing these jets dated years ago as proof of his claim. Three primary reasons were behind his decisions. The first was concern that they simply weren't the right plane for the job—he wanted something more advanced. Second, that working with certain foreign original equipment manufacturers (OEMs) would be a major hassle. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, he is a firm believer in buying flyers, not aircraft that have been mothballed for years, if at all possible. With this in mind, the Hornets offered Kirlin a ready to go advanced 'air force in a box' that wouldn't be a huge hassle to regenerate once they reached the United States. They would also have great support from a domestic OEM—Boeing—and support and maintenance could be outsourced to firms that are already doing so for some Marine and Navy Hornet operations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img itemprop=&quot;associatedMedia&quot; class=&quot;figure-image&quot; src=&quot;https://the-drive-2.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Fs3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2Fthe-drive-cms-content-staging%2Fmessage-editor%252F1586452730520-asdadscca1.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;ixlib=js-1.4.1&amp;amp;s=d6bb3b1571ae287d5106a355e4fa7eba&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kirlin after checking out South Africa's Atlus Cheetahs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;articleFragment paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The balance between cost and capabilities is a huge factor in the adversary air support marketplace. Does having the most advanced private tactical aircraft on hand for hire mean they will be too costly for the Pentagon's tastes? This has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone/25075/how-f-5s-beat-out-f-16s-for-the-navys-latest-commercial-aggressor-contract&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;turned out to be the case&lt;/a&gt; in at least one limited contract that the Navy recently awarded, but Kirlin doesn't think so overall. He says his team did a deep market evaluation and cost analysis on what 'legacy' Hornets cost to operate, including using the Navy's own historic numbers provided by the General Accounting Office, as well as looking at what the competition has to offer, and the results were very positive. But for Air USA, the strategy isn't really about simply having the best and most capable jet on the ramp, it is all about offering the customer a big menu of choices and allowing them to tailor their aircraft selection based on their needs, not on what is being offered alone. This is where Air USA's growing diverse fleet of aircraft comes in to play. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now, the company's budding air force includes 10 Hawks, four L-39ZAs, and two L-39s. The Hawk jet trainers, which originally came from South Korean stocks, are deceptively capable aircraft. Like all of the Hawk family, they are quick and nimble, as well as reliable and efficient, but they now also pack one hell of a sensor and electronic warfare capability. The jets have been upgraded with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iai.co.il/p/elm-2052&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Elta's ELM-2052&lt;/a&gt; active electronically scanned array &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone/26651/northrop-grumman-is-vying-to-give-b-52-bomber-a-game-changing-new-radar&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;(AESA) radar&lt;/a&gt;. In fact, they are the only private adversary aircraft equipped with an AESA radar set at this time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img itemprop=&quot;associatedMedia&quot; class=&quot;figure-image&quot; src=&quot;https://the-drive-3.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Fs3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2Fthe-drive-cms-content-staging%2Fmessage-editor%252F1586454900697-aesahawk.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;ixlib=js-1.4.1&amp;amp;s=a3f96dc3c9283958914383ad158f5bd7&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;articleFragment paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ELM-2052 is a modular design of Israeli origin that can fit within the tight confines of smaller tactical fighter aircraft radomes, but it is known to be remarkably effective and gives fleet pilots something unique to train against in the adversary air-to-air environment. The jets are also wired to handle the EL-L/8222 electronic warfare pods, like their soon to be Hornet stablemates. Combined with their small size, they are a remarkably formidable and highly dissimilar adversary aircraft. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img itemprop=&quot;associatedMedia&quot; class=&quot;figure-image&quot; src=&quot;https://the-drive.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Fs3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2Fthe-drive-cms-content-staging%2Fmessage-editor%252F1586454942538-img_3351.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;ixlib=js-1.4.1&amp;amp;s=a88060c4172d793251e0f51b892f0e41&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ELM-2052 AESA radar and EL-L/8222 electronic warfare equipped Hawk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;articleFragment paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The L-39ZA, which is a combat-capable derivative of the L-39 Albatross trainer, and the L-39s themselves, have lower performance than the Hawk, but they are very efficient and still can lug different types of countermeasure pods, cannons, and other stores. Air USA has even equipped some of them with advanced electro-optical and infrared sensor turrets. Air USA had Dornier Alpha Jets that fell into a category somewhere between the Hawks and the L-39s, but those aircraft were sold to the Nigerian Air Force, which was in urgent need of the type. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img itemprop=&quot;associatedMedia&quot; class=&quot;figure-image&quot; src=&quot;https://the-drive-2.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Fs3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2Fthe-drive-cms-content-staging%2Fmessage-editor%252F1586457965562-23423424.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;ixlib=js-1.4.1&amp;amp;s=ffc435b9ceb91ba953904a335b3c426e&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img itemprop=&quot;associatedMedia&quot; class=&quot;figure-image&quot; src=&quot;https://the-drive-3.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Fs3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2Fthe-drive-cms-content-staging%2Fmessage-editor%252F1586457567832-p5210002.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;ixlib=js-1.4.1&amp;amp;s=96e81f5811c4c39eefdaf30a047cc536&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Air USA L59 equipped with a towed target on the ramp in Okinawa. The target unspools behind the aircraft on 22,000 feet of cable. It is used for live fire training and testing, in this case of the Navy's major surface combatants' 5-inch deck guns and 20mm Phalanx CIWS. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;articleFragment paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the Aussie Hornet purchase, Air USA also acquired five hand-picked PC-9 turboprop trainers from the RAAF. These aircraft will primarily be used to fulfill the growing demand for cost-effective Joint Terminal Attack Controller training. You can read all about this mission and the contracts being tendered to supply it in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone/32842/the-bronco-is-back-a-fleet-of-ov-10s-will-help-train-air-force-forward-air-controllers&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;this recent piece of ours&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img itemprop=&quot;associatedMedia&quot; class=&quot;figure-image&quot; src=&quot;https://the-drive.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Fs3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2Fthe-drive-cms-content-staging%2Fmessage-editor%252F1586466429629-2342324.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;ixlib=js-1.4.1&amp;amp;s=d7a86abf85ddb6d3a662e4dff01f6946&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;© Commonwealth of Australia, Department of Defence&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RAAF Pilatus PC-9s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;articleFragment paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, JTACs need to get time &quot;on the mic&quot; with real aircraft overhead, in both day and nighttime conditions, to get accustomed to organizing the three-dimensional airspace overhead in relation to the battlespace on the ground, and effectively, safely, and efficiently call in airstrikes on enemy targets. This is an incredibly complex and high-stakes job, but using high-performance fighters in the Pentagon's inventory that cost at least $20,000 an hour to train with is horribly cost-ineffective. As such, being able to provide far less expensive assets via the contractor marketplace for some of this training has become a major priority. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img itemprop=&quot;associatedMedia&quot; class=&quot;figure-image&quot; src=&quot;https://the-drive-3.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Fs3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2Fthe-drive-cms-content-staging%2Fmessage-editor%252F1586458170268-dscn2300.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;ixlib=js-1.4.1&amp;amp;s=b6d6f7965aae739a09cb1446e4fa8e7f&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of Air USA's L-39ZAs equipped with an advanced EO/IR turret for Joint Terminal Attack Controller training. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;articleFragment paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not only where the PC-9s come in, but also the fleet of 17 highly modified Cessna T337 Turbo Skymasters that Air USA just acquired from Airscan Inc. These aircraft were totally reworked for overhead surveillance and counter-insurgency missions in places like Iraq and Afghanistan. They come equipped with the hugely capable &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone/19921/these-secretive-us-specops-spy-planes-are-getting-new-sensors-and-anti-gps-jamming-gear&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;MX-15 infrared/electro-optical sensor&lt;/a&gt; turret and an operator's station in the back. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div itemprop=&quot;associatedMedia&quot; class=&quot;video-youtube&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe class=&quot;video-youtube__video&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/XE4y3PArOmw?rel=0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div itemprop=&quot;associatedMedia&quot; class=&quot;video-youtube&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe class=&quot;video-youtube__video&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/43OFG3mJJ1A?rel=0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;has-ad-column&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;articleFragment paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Cessnas, which have a pair of reciprocating turbocharged IO-360 engines found on normal light planes, are extremely efficient compared to their turbine-powered competitors and feature video downlink, encrypted communications, and night vision goggle compatible cockpits, among other modifications. They are also certified under the FAA's Standard category, not the Experimental category, even with all their modifications, which has a multitude of benefits. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img itemprop=&quot;associatedMedia&quot; class=&quot;figure-image&quot; src=&quot;https://the-drive-3.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Fs3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2Fthe-drive-cms-content-staging%2Fmessage-editor%252F1586466850451-1280px-cessna_337g.jpeg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;ixlib=js-1.4.1&amp;amp;s=e81736d0fee48f43f5151ac63fe3e2ec&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;DTOM/Wikicommons&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Airscan Inc. T337 Turbo Skymaster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;articleFragment paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Air USA's idea here is to provide the lowest possible cost for JTAC training while still having an aircraft that has all the bells and whistles needed to accomplish the mission. Don Kirlin says that from his firm's perspective, for a lot of JTAC training, the customer just wants the most &quot;time on the mic&quot; for their JTACs as possible. Delivering a very low-cost option, one with extremely high endurance, to accomplish just that is the impetus behind acquiring the highly unique fleet of suped-up and battle-proven Turbo Skymasters. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kirlin also states that the company has acquired 10 F-5E Tiger IIs that will slot in between the Hawk and the Hornet in the aggressor role. These jets will be totally refurbished and will get a comprehensive upgrade very similar, if not nearly identical, to the one Tactical Air, another adversary air support purveyor, has developed for its large fleet of F-5s. You can read all about Tactical Air and its highly customized F-5ATs in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone/32615/private-aggressor-f-5-fighter-force-is-flying-with-helmet-mounted-displays&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;this recent piece of ours.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img itemprop=&quot;associatedMedia&quot; class=&quot;figure-image&quot; src=&quot;https://the-drive-2.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Fs3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2Fthe-drive-cms-content-staging%2Fmessage-editor%252F1586467311403-iwojima.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;ixlib=js-1.4.1&amp;amp;s=8319c885bae03bed0f9f4d2e50f66226&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;Don Kirlin and some of his Air USA team on a repositioning flight in the Western Pacific. &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;articleFragment paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kirlin hopes to fit their F-5s with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone/28085/f-15c-eagles-new-infrared-search-and-track-pod-spotted-at-huge-exercise-in-alaska&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Infrared Search and Track Systems (IRSTs)&lt;/a&gt;, which will be a huge force multiplier for other aggressors flying alongside them and a real threat to stealthy &quot;blue air&quot; jets, like the F-35, F-22, and B-2. Leveraging a similar open architecture avionics upgrade that Tactical Air pioneered with its F-5ATs will allow far easier integration of an IRST on the F-5 than on other aircraft in the Air USA fleet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company also owns a quartet of MiG-29 Fulcrums that Kirlin imported. These jets are basically in factory new condition. They each have roughly just 100 hours on them now, which is basically nothing. The two single-seat models are more parts donors than flying aircraft, with the pair of two-seat MiG-29UBs being airworthy. Although some may wonder why these jets are not used for adversary support roles, they simply are not in demand for a number of reasons. They are not specifically equipped for the mission, do not have a radar, and are not the most efficient flying machines available for the task by a long shot. They have done some missile work with Raytheon air-to-air missile system development in the past, and could be pushed into service if a customer really wanted them, but when you have fully upgraded Hornets in your fleet, who needs a dated MiG-29? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div itemprop=&quot;associatedMedia&quot; class=&quot;video-youtube&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe class=&quot;video-youtube__video&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_C4XiuJFtCQ?rel=0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;has-ad-column&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;articleFragment paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With such a varied inventory of aircraft, Air USA's unique business aimed at the ballooning contractor tactical air services market can be summed up by the following: give the customer a huge range of options to tailor to their budget and training requirements. In other words, this is not a one size fits all air force for hire. Quite the opposite. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, for basic air-to-air missions, like radar intercept training, maybe a PC-9 or L-39 is fine. For other more dynamic fighter training, maybe a Hawk or F-5 will do. For the most advanced air-to-air training, the Hornet will be available. The customer only has to pay for what they really need. The same can be said for JTAC training. For basic training scenarios, a T337H gives a tremendous amount of capability for the dollar and for &quot;dry CAS&quot; where weapons are not employed, but for more advanced scenarios where weapons are released, PC-9s, or even L-39s or Hawks, would be the aircraft for the job. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img itemprop=&quot;associatedMedia&quot; class=&quot;figure-image&quot; src=&quot;https://the-drive-3.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Fs3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2Fthe-drive-cms-content-staging%2Fmessage-editor%252F1586467264019-hawkwith30mm.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;ixlib=js-1.4.1&amp;amp;s=72b4e5a649c298032bb8324ae728df32&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Air USA's Hawks came with 30mm ADEN cannon pods, which are fully functional and are used in close air support exercises. Kirlin told us he has 42,000 training rounds 74,000 high-explosive rounds for the cannons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;articleFragment paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, it's all about choice. This business mantra is something Don Kirlin learned by putting on the world's largest skydiving festival, the World Freefall Convention. When I say large, I mean &lt;em&gt;large&lt;/em&gt;. Kirlin tells us that during a past iteration of the event, 5,400 skydivers made&lt;em&gt; 70,000 jumps&lt;/em&gt; in just &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; days&lt;/em&gt;. Many of those skydivers were sick of the same old jump ships, they wanted a variety of exotic platforms to choose from to enhance their experience. Over 17 years of putting on the event, Kirlin ended up bringing in everything from World War II bombers to a high-flying 727 to help quelch attendees' demands. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div itemprop=&quot;associatedMedia&quot; class=&quot;video-youtube&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe class=&quot;video-youtube__video&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/OieVUhq40q8?rel=0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div itemprop=&quot;associatedMedia&quot; class=&quot;video-youtube&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe class=&quot;video-youtube__video&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/xMZfli4Wasc?rel=0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;has-ad-column&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;articleFragment paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By offering so many creative possibilities, he found that the customer really appreciates options and wants to be able to pay for exactly what they need or desire, nothing more and nothing less. This emphasis on customer choice is now being ported over to the adversary air support market via his eclectic fleet of tactical aircraft for hire. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With choice and platform diversity also comes some really exciting opportunities to layer-in different capabilities on a single adversary mission, which can provide more challenging scenarios for trainees. For instance, pairing the Hawk with the Hornet, the Hawk can share its AESA radar targeting information with the Hornet and vice-versa. Throw in an F-5 with an IRST and even the stealthiest opponents will be prone to detection from Air USA's aggressor formation. Layering in other aircraft, like L-39s acting as cruise missiles and more, will help really rachet up the complexity that 'blue air' forces will have to confront, and all of these capabilities can come from one business relationship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img itemprop=&quot;associatedMedia&quot; class=&quot;figure-image&quot; src=&quot;https://the-drive.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Fs3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2Fthe-drive-cms-content-staging%2Fmessage-editor%252F1586461870866-5885.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;ixlib=js-1.4.1&amp;amp;s=072207fce6e3927a6b29217359657954&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An impressive lineup of electronic warfare toting Air USA Albatrosses. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;articleFragment paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With frontline fighter aircraft becoming increasingly capable, especially in terms of the sensors they carry, being able to challenge them has become far more difficult and often requires a mix of high-performance opposing fighters, as well as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone/16682/watch-this-a-4-run-for-its-life-from-a-menacing-f-22-raptor-at-low-level&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;saturating them with other&lt;/a&gt;, less complex aerial targets. Having a turn-key air force for hire with a huge range of capabilities and performance levels available, makes this easier to accomplish in an efficient and integrated manner and without the Air Force, Navy, or Marines having to task their own overtaxed fleets with the mission. Also, contracting out these services already is more cost-effective than having the military perform them, but with tailorable forces like Kirlin's, the cost should only go down, not up. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don Kirlin is truly living what would have been a far-fetched dream not too long ago. He is a man with his own fourth-generation fighter-equipped air force, one larger and more capable than what many entire nations possess. With the introduction of the F/A-18 Hornet into the adversary air support marketplace, especially the number Air USA is bringing to the fight, it could very well be a game-changer, but it also presents risks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking on a supercarrier's worth of modern strike fighters is a hugely expensive proposition. It is also one that is not without its own physical and liability risks. There will be a lot of pressure on Air USA to not only pay its bills, which will be monumentally huge, but also to operate these extremely high-performance jets in a safe and reliable manner. From what I can tell Don Kirlin seems raring to take these challenges head-on and to get himself strapped into the Hornet's ejection seat and taking one up for a spin—he is type rated and flies every plane he owns. The Hornet will be no different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Call it a perk of the job for the man who now owns the world's most advanced private air force. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img itemprop=&quot;associatedMedia&quot; class=&quot;figure-image&quot; src=&quot;https://the-drive.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Fs3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2Fthe-drive-cms-content-staging%2Fmessage-editor%252F1586470801984-20130306raaf8185068_06051.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;ixlib=js-1.4.1&amp;amp;s=9a76bac5cef21fbbbf5c48ab504c08d5&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;© Commonwealth of Australia, Department of Defence&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;articleFragment paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Contact the author: Tyler@thedrive.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;articleFragment&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;newsletter-signup the-warzone-wire&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;blurb&quot;&gt;Don't forget to sign up&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;email-blurb&quot;&gt;Your Email Address&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;related-content related-content--rich&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;title-message&quot;&gt;MORE TO READ&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;related-article&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Air Force Hires Seven Companies In Long-Awaited Mega Adversary Air Support Contract&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dek&quot;&gt;Years in the making, the deal is a long-awaited moment for the contractor aggressor services industry and it will be a game-changer.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;related-article&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Australia To Sell Retired F/A-18 Hornet Fighters To Private Aggressor Firm Air USA&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dek&quot;&gt;The adversary support contractor could get up to 46 of the surplus fighters, giving them one of the most capable private air forces in the world.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;related-article&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Private Aggressor F-5 Fighter Force Is Flying With Helmet Mounted Displays&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dek&quot;&gt;Tactical Air has created what are among, if not the most advanced F-5 Tiger IIs on the planet to slug it out with US Navy and USMC fleet pilots. &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;related-article&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;The Bronco Is Back! A Fleet Of OV-10s Will Help Train Air Force Forward Air Controllers&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dek&quot;&gt;The deal will give the Vietnam War-era aircraft, which haven't seen widespread U.S. military use in any capacity in decades, a new lease on life.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;related-article&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Watch This Crazy Video Of An A-4 Running For Its Life At Low-Level From A Menacing F-22&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dek&quot;&gt;It's like a frantic life-or-death scene out of the documentary Planet Earth.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 15:33:15 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>antman</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>This Man Owns The World's Most Advanced Private Air Force After Buying 46 F/A-18 Hornets</og:title>
<og:description>We talked to the owner of Air USA about probably the most incredible private aircraft purchase of all time and the future of his adversary business.</og:description>
<og:image>https://api.thedrive.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/DONKIRLIN.jpg?quality=85</og:image>
<og:url>https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone/32869/this-man-owns-the-worlds-most-advanced-private-air-force-after-buying-46-f-a-18-hornets</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone/32869/this-man-owns-the-worlds-most-advanced-private-air-force-after-buying-46-f-a-18-hornets</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Systems that defy detailed understanding</title>
<link>https://blog.nelhage.com/post/systems-that-defy-understanding/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.nelhage.com/post/systems-that-defy-understanding/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Last week, I &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.nelhage.com/post/computers-can-be-understood/&quot;&gt;wrote about&lt;/a&gt; the mindset that computer systems can be understood, and behaviors can be explained, if we’re willing to dig deep enough into the stack of abstractions our software is built atop. Some of the ensuing discussion on Twitter and elsewhere lead me to write this followup, in which I want to run through a few classes of systems where I’ve found pursuing in-detail understanding of the system wasn’t the right answer. In these systems, detailed understanding of behaviors was either impossible, impracticable, or just a waste of time compared to other strategies for dealing with the system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;complex-distributed-systems&quot;&gt;Complex distributed systems  &lt;a class=&quot;anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.nelhage.com/post/systems-that-defy-understanding/#complex-distributed-systems&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;small linkify icon&quot;&gt;🔗︎&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The defining characteristic of distributed systems is failure. Once your system is spread across multiple nodes, we face the possibility of one node failing but not another, or the network itself dropping, reordering, and delaying messages between nodes. The vast majority of complexity in distributed systems arises from this simple possibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of this possibility, it is a fundamental requirement of high-reliability distributed systems that they be &lt;em&gt;robust&lt;/em&gt; to failure of individual components. Such systems tend to run multiple copies of a service, and be able to retry requests, or to handle failure and proceed using some fallback strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you’re working on and building out a distributed system, you will inevitably encounter situations where some underlying component fails (say, an individual database node crashes), and in which the system as a whole does not gracefully recover (say, the client hangs instead of timing out and retrying a healthy node). When this happens, you have, broadly, two choices for how to remediate the issue: you can try to understand and fix the underlying failure (why did the node crash?), or you can try to fix the failure in the fault-tolerance layer (why didn’t the client time out?)&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot; id=&quot;fnref:priority&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.nelhage.com/post/systems-that-defy-understanding/#fn:priority&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I faced this sort of dilemma many times during my years on infrastructure teams at Stripe. In these cases, my systems debugging experience and my desire to understand systems tempted me towards wanting to understand what looked like the “root” case of the incident: why did the database crash? Could we track down the bug and report it upstream or fix it? Whether it was a bug in the database software itself, a kernel bug, or even a failure in the underlying cloud hardware, I was &lt;em&gt;sure&lt;/em&gt; I could track it down. I ended up spending a lot of times digging through unfamiliar C++ code, scouring logs, and tracking down kernel bugs to understand various failures. While I did end up identifying a fair number of bugs (here are &lt;a href=&quot;https://nelhagedebugsshit.tumblr.com/post/140317144518/when-observing-your-database-stalls-it&quot;&gt;two&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://nelhagedebugsshit.tumblr.com/post/82612335570/slow-mongo-foreground-index-builds&quot;&gt;examples&lt;/a&gt;), it was always a slow and inconsistent process, and many others were eventually written off as unsolved mysteries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tracing behavior in detail in these systems is so hard for at least two reasons. The first is the sheer complexity and amount of code involved. Modern cloud deployments involve numerous different interacting components, most of which you didn’t write. A “relatively simple” system might touch Docker, Kubernetes, Kafka, Redis, and a hosted AWS service or three; the number and lines of code of dependencies easily drastically outpaces the dependencies of even a very sophisticated single-node program. All of these systems and lines of code add complexity that might potentially need to be understood to track down behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second reason, compounding the first, is the massively concurrent and asynchronous nature of distributed systems. You potentially have thousands of processes or more exchanging messages with a server, and an attempt to reconstruct a precise failure timeline might depend on the precise ordering or relative ordering of any or all of their requests, as well as any other asynchronous events running on the server. This is one of those cases where the “mostly-deterministic” nature of computers that I cited last time breaks down; concurrent execution leads to (effectively) random message ordering, massively exploding the space of possible traces you may have to consider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-works-instead&quot;&gt;What works instead  &lt;a class=&quot;anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.nelhage.com/post/systems-that-defy-understanding/#what-works-instead&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;small linkify icon&quot;&gt;🔗︎&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I came to see the “understand everything!” approach as largely misguided here, I started to conclude that it was usually a better use of my time to focus effort the systems-level failure, instead of the individual component failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Given&lt;/em&gt; that the individual node failed, how could the system as a whole react more robustly? Did we need to add or adjust timeouts or retries? Add health-checking or circuit-breaking or backpressure or fallbacks? Remove that dependency entirely somehow?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such solutions may add complexity and new failure modes of their own. However, if you aspire to high reliability you need some such solutions regardless, because you aspire to be more reliable than any individual server or process, anyways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you do succeed in designing the system as a whole for resilience, then individual failures become much less important, and the details matter less — you can survive a broad class of individual failures, and diagnose them later, or even not at all. If a process keeps failing in the same way you can choose to investigate and debug (with the confidence that the damage is at least being mitigated while you do). And for one-off failures, your reaction can potentially just become “Well, that was weird. Guess I’ll replace the node and investigate if it ever happens again.” It’s a tremendously freeing feeling to get there!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;big-balls-of-mud&quot;&gt;Big balls of mud  &lt;a class=&quot;anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.nelhage.com/post/systems-that-defy-understanding/#big-balls-of-mud&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;small linkify icon&quot;&gt;🔗︎&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will Larson &lt;a href=&quot;https://lethain.com/reasoning-about-big-balls-of-mud/&quot;&gt;writes about big balls of mud&lt;/a&gt;, and observes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big balls of mud appear to have properties, but they don’t. All mutation occurs through an immutable log, you say. Oh, but there are a few caveats. A couple of performance wins. Two adjacent products made a minor exception to hit launch timelines. … No properties remain, and abstract models of system behavior skew from actual behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My experience here agrees with Will’s : When a system gets big enough fast enough, with a large enough team and under lots of competing product pressures, it risks losing nearly all internal logic and guarantees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last time I wrote&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Computer systems tend to be, well, systematic, and have some core algebra or logic that is comprehensible, which is smaller than a complete list of possible behaviors, and which generates or at least organizes all of those behaviors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Big balls of mud” like those Will describes don’t work this way. Insofar as any features work (and usually these systems &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; mostly work; among other reasons, by hypothesis they’ve survived to become popular), they work almost “by chance,” often due to specific pairwise interactions between distant parts of the codebase, and not because of any comprehensible layering or core invariants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-works-instead-1&quot;&gt;What works instead  &lt;a class=&quot;anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.nelhage.com/post/systems-that-defy-understanding/#what-works-instead-1&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;small linkify icon&quot;&gt;🔗︎&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In such systems, we must resort to empirical methods. Instead of reasoning about the system and reading the source to answer questions, we find ways to ask questions about the running system. We can perform such queries by looking at existing logs and metrics, or by adding new instrumentation. Given, for instance, a &lt;code&gt;# this can never happen&lt;/code&gt; comment, we might add a new log line or event emission at that point, deploy the system, and observe empirically if it happens and when, instead of trying to reason our way through the system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to improve productivity on such systems, we invest in sophisticated &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.honeycomb.io/learning-about-observability/intro-to-observability/&quot;&gt;observability&lt;/a&gt; tools, aiming to increase the number of questions we can ask without deploying custom code. We report high-granularity events on each request, and build systems like continuous runtime code coverage, so that we can observe many patterns of behavior in production just by writing the right query, instead of requiring &lt;em&gt;ad hoc&lt;/em&gt; instrumentation and deploys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s important to note that such systems can still be modeled, to a degree — typically they do have design properties which still &lt;em&gt;mostly&lt;/em&gt; hold — but you must remain constantly aware of the distinction between the map and the territory. Mental models can be used to gain intuition and to form hypotheses, but these hypotheses absolutely must be empirically verified before they can be relied upon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;client-side-javascript&quot;&gt;Client-side Javascript  &lt;a class=&quot;anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.nelhage.com/post/systems-that-defy-understanding/#client-side-javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;small linkify icon&quot;&gt;🔗︎&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This example is the area I have the least personal experience with, but I’ve dabbled in it and worked adjacent to some very sophisticated teams who worked in this space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you run an even-moderately-sophisticated web application and install client-side error reporting for Javascript errors, it’s a well-known phenomenon that you will receive a deluge of weird and incomprehensible errors from your application, many of which appear to you to be utterly nonsensical or impossible. Sentry for instance, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.sentry.io/2017/03/27/tips-for-reducing-javascript-error-noise/&quot;&gt;has this blog post&lt;/a&gt; documenting techniques for trying to filter out the worst of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These errors come, in large part, from users running odd niche or out-of-date browsers with broken Javascript or DOM implementations, users with buggy browser extensions injecting themselves into your scope, adblockers blocking one of your &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;script&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tags, broken browser caches or middleboxes, and other weirder and more exotic failure modes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These failures are, individually, mostly comprehensible! You can figure out which browser the report comes from, triage which extensions might be implicated, understand the interactions and identify the failure and a specific workaround. Much of the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, doing that work is, in most cases, just a colossal waste of effort; you’ll often see any individual error once or twice, and by the time you track it down and understand it, you’ll see three new ones from users in different weird predicaments. The ecosystem is just too heterogenous and fast-changing for deep understanding of individual issues to be worth it as a primary strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-works-instead-2&quot;&gt;What works instead  &lt;a class=&quot;anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.nelhage.com/post/systems-that-defy-understanding/#what-works-instead-2&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;small linkify icon&quot;&gt;🔗︎&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Past some point, I think you have to treat this largely as a statistical problem. Attempt to group errors together, and only investigate patterns that appear above some rate, or are trending in notable ways. Collect statistics on your users’ environments, and add sufficiently-common browsers or extensions to your pre-release testing processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For persistent issues that you can’t reproduce, you can resort to empirical methods; push code that queries facts about the environment and reports statistics back, or just guess at possible fixes, push them, and watch your statistics to see if they put a dent in the error rates. Push out deploys gradually and watch error rates in the wild instead of relying solely on your in-house testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These kinds of techniques are also used by browser teams themselves. Browsers, too, run in such heterogenous environments and at such scale that it’s just not feasible for their developers to understand all of the complexity of every environment they run in; they, too, must resort to experimentation, statistical summaries, and other empirical methods to understand the deployed behavior of their software. To this end, modern browser teams all have sophisticated tools for &lt;a href=&quot;https://chromium.googlesource.com/chromium/src/+/master/docs/configuration.md#features&quot;&gt;controlling experiments remotely&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chromium.org/developers/design-documents/rappor&quot;&gt;collecting privacy-preserving metrics&lt;/a&gt; from users, and numerous other tools for empirical discovery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This attitude was concisely expressed on Twitter by Adrienne Porter Felt, a long-time developer and manager on the Chrome team:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Software seems like something we should be able to reason about, yet the reality is that it's often too complex. Since we don't know how it works, we measure it and experiment on it as if we are trying to discover properties of the natural world&lt;/p&gt;
— Adrienne Porter Felt (@&lt;strong&gt;apf&lt;/strong&gt;) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/__apf__/status/1089877319123005440?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;January 28, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;deep-learning&quot;&gt;Deep Learning  &lt;a class=&quot;anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.nelhage.com/post/systems-that-defy-understanding/#deep-learning&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;small linkify icon&quot;&gt;🔗︎&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, during a three-month sabbatical, I spent some time playing with deep learning toolkits and algorithms. I was particularly interested in reinforcement learning, so after reading a bunch of papers and blog posts, I wrote a toy implementation of an actor-critic system to play pong on an emulated Atari, a pretty &lt;a href=&quot;https://deepmind.com/research/publications/playing-atari-deep-reinforcement-learning&quot;&gt;well-known task for deep reinforcement learning&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My system would make progress and I could watch its progress improving slowly … for a little while, and then it would diverge, with all of my parameters going to infinity and everything blowing up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent literal months (on and off) trying to debug that ~200-line program. My experience with systems engineering lead me to go deeper into trying to understand its behavior, adding more and more metrics and summaries to my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tensorflow.org/tensorboard&quot;&gt;tensorboard&lt;/a&gt; setup, trying to comb over parameters and gradients and potentials step by step, hoping that maybe I could find the first moment where things started going wrong, and thereby somehow deduce where my problem was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually — somehow — I found the bug, mostly by accident: I had an &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nelhage/tf-experiments/commit/73be3cb581ac2e363be14995e8637b916bae7bb9#diff-966771c07ddf7937a3c6927b86e0f62e&quot;&gt;off-by-one error&lt;/a&gt; when feeding frames into the training step. Because deep neural networks are so damn good at learning, they were still able to extract signal from the misaligned frames and start learning; but eventually the bad data won out and the system went off the rails. Fixing that data error resolved the problem and the network continued learning much longer and more effectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This experience taught me some really important lessons about deep learning. While working with deep learning “looks” like other programming in a lot of ways — certainly you’re writing and running programs — it’s also deeply different in a lot of important and practical ways. For one, &lt;em&gt;actually no one really understands&lt;/em&gt; why these deep learning systems work. There are certainly many people with much better understanding and intuition than I have, but ultimately trying to understand these systems’ behavior too closely, especially as a novice to the field, is deeply the wrong way to approach it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-works-instead-3&quot;&gt;What works instead  &lt;a class=&quot;anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.nelhage.com/post/systems-that-defy-understanding/#what-works-instead-3&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;small linkify icon&quot;&gt;🔗︎&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The kind of approach I settled on instead — which some friends who work professionally in deep learning echoed — is a far more incrementalist, empirical approach. Start with the simplest possible version of a system, demonstrate that it works as a baseline, and iterate in small steps from there. Make small changes, verify that it still works, and repeats. If it ever stops working, you know it was the most-recent change, and you can try to figure out what went wrong. If you’re reimplementing a paper or published algorithm, try to find their code and first make sure you are matching their behavior as precisely as possible, and only then try to modify from there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and also double- and triple-check your data and your data infrastructure! This part of a system is “just plain-old code,” and your usual engineering strategies work, so double down on it. Write lots of assertions and checks that you’re feeding the right data in to your model and sanity-check it. Once you hit the neural networks errors become incredibly hard to trace, so try to enforce as much rigor as you can before then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking over these systems, I see some common themes. A lot of these systems are distributed, involving many different machines and interacting pieces of software. They may also be heterogenous, involving different implementations of a protocol or different versions of software running side-by-side. Relatedly, many of these systems have many participants and high rates of change, which means knowledge of the system has a shorter half-life of validity; in such systems, high-level architectural knowledge may remain valid, but the details are less worth learning since they’re subject to frequent change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the solutions, a big theme — also cited by several of the people I link to — is moving to empiricism and experiment, instead of abstract reasoning. I think this need additionally explains some of the recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.honeycomb.io/learning-about-observability/intro-to-observability/&quot;&gt;observability&lt;/a&gt; movement; as we rely more and more on empirical observation of our systems, we need better and better tools for actually making and analyzing observations and characterizing the empirical behaviors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reflecting on both this post and the previous one, I want to call out pretty explicitly that I think there’s a lot of value in holding both mindsets as tools available for you, depending on the problems and needs of the situation. It’s both the case that computers are (mostly) comprehensible and can be understood in depth, and also the case that many computer systems are too complex or fast-moving for in-depth understanding, and are best managed by experiment and finding ways to ask the system itself questions about its actual behavior. These techniques can and should also be combined: Theoretical understanding of a system can inform which experiments and observations to perform, and observation refine and feed into mental models. Learning to master and deploy each mindset individually is an important step on the journey of a senior engineer; learning how to effectively switch between them and merge them when faced with a problem is a further step, and one I’m still getting better at.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 14:52:57 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>a7b3fa</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.nelhage.com/post/systems-that-defy-understanding/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Firefox 75.0</title>
<link>https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/75.0/releasenotes/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/75.0/releasenotes/</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/75.0/releasenotes/&quot;&gt;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/75.0/releasenotes/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=22831506&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=22831506&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 354&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 319&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 10:01:33 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>abhiminator</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/75.0/releasenotes/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.mozilla.org/media/protocol/img/logos/firefox/browser/og.4ad05d4125a5.png</og:image>
<og:title>Firefox  75.0, See All New Features, Updates and Fixes</og:title>
<og:description></og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/75.0/releasenotes/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>E Ink smart screen puts a newspaper on your wall</title>
<link>https://onezero.medium.com/the-morning-paper-revisited-35b407822494</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://onezero.medium.com/the-morning-paper-revisited-35b407822494</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;ax ea eb em ed en ef eo eh ep ej eq bc&quot;&gt;Sometimes no user interface is the best user interface&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;er&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;n es et eu ev&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;o n&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ew ex ey&quot;&gt;

&lt;img alt=&quot;Max Braun&quot; class=&quot;r fg ey ex&quot; src=&quot;https://miro.medium.com/fit/c/96/96/1*Pn3d0o9_VO4jj0LjYDVyYg.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;48&quot; height=&quot;48&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

Paper on Thanksgiving Day, 2019. Content: © 2019 The New York Times Company
&lt;p id=&quot;7a67&quot; class=&quot;ic id dh ay ie b eb if ed ig ih ii ij ik il im in io cz&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;r ip iy is ew iz&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;T&quot; class=&quot;ja jb jc jd je jf s t u hn ai&quot; src=&quot;https://miro.medium.com/max/158/1*x3MLNrKVby4_GZ1VCCYktA.png&quot; width=&quot;79&quot; height=&quot;79&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;r ip iq ir is it iu iv iw ix ew hl&quot;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;here’s something special about the layout of a print-edition newspaper. A news website has infinite vertical scrolling space, but a printed front page is fixed to the same size every day. This constraint creates a very particular aesthetic and — if done well — a sense of typographic balance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;78e6&quot; class=&quot;ic id dh ay ie b eb if ed ig ih ii ij ik il im in cz&quot;&gt;I wanted to preserve this analog feeling and infuse it with the possibilities of &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@maxbraun/smarter-mirrors-and-how-theyre-made-327997b9eff7&quot; class=&quot;fp gn jg jh ji jj&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;smart home technology&lt;/a&gt;. That’s why I made Paper, a radically simple prototype that does exactly one thing: show today’s front page on a large e-paper display.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;e580&quot; class=&quot;ic id dh ay ie b eb if ed ig ih ii ij ik il im in cz&quot;&gt;Sometimes no user interface is the best user interface. This project, even more so than &lt;a href=&quot;https://accent.ink/&quot; class=&quot;fp gn jg jh ji jj&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;Accent&lt;/a&gt; previously, was created in the tradition of &lt;a href=&quot;https://calmtech.com/&quot; class=&quot;fp gn jg jh ji jj&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;calm technology&lt;/a&gt;. Paper easily blends into the background, because its screen doesn’t emit any light and the content changes quietly when no one is looking. The display is wall-mounted at eye height, and the nightly front-page update happens automatically, so the only user interaction is simply standing there and looking at it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;4b72&quot; class=&quot;ic id dh ay ie b eb if ed ig ih ii ij ik il im in cz&quot;&gt;I’ve been using different versions of this prototype for about two and a half years now, and I usually read it while getting ready in the morning. It definitely and literally passes the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dealbook.nytimes.com/2014/08/17/in-silicon-valley-mergers-must-meet-the-toothbrush-test/&quot; class=&quot;fp gn jg jh ji jj&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;toothbrush test&lt;/a&gt; for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;jk&quot; readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;8feb&quot; class=&quot;jl jm jn ay di b jo jp jq jr js jt in&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;di b ju jv bc&quot;&gt;Sometimes no user interface is the best user interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;ada5&quot; class=&quot;ic id dh ay ie b eb jw ed jx ih jy ij jz il ka in cz&quot;&gt;This project is not affiliated with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/&quot; class=&quot;fp gn jg jh ji jj&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;kb&quot;&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. While the concept isn’t tied to any particular publication, I picked the &lt;em class=&quot;kb&quot;&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt; because it has an iconic print front page with an attractive &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2003/10/21/business/the-media-business-a-face-lift-for-the-times-typographically-that-is.html&quot; class=&quot;fp gn jg jh ji jj&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;headline typeface&lt;/a&gt; and is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/section/todayspaper&quot; class=&quot;fp gn jg jh ji jj&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;published&lt;/a&gt; in machine-readable high quality.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 09:22:07 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>hiharryhere</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>This Super-Clean Smart Screen Puts a Newspaper on Your Wall</og:title>
<og:description>Sometimes no user interface is the best user interface</og:description>
<og:url>https://onezero.medium.com/the-morning-paper-revisited-35b407822494</og:url>
<og:image>https://miro.medium.com/focal/1200/632/50/34/0*JYoKeC540vHfobsk</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://onezero.medium.com/the-morning-paper-revisited-35b407822494</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Convert Markdown to a Mind Map</title>
<link>https://markmap.js.org/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://markmap.js.org/</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://markmap.js.org/&quot;&gt;https://markmap.js.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=22831015&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=22831015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 435&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 69&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 08:10:40 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>gera2ld</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://markmap.js.org/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Jitsi Meet Electron 2.0</title>
<link>https://github.com/jitsi/jitsi-meet-electron/releases</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/jitsi/jitsi-meet-electron/releases</guid>
<description>&lt;h3&gt;Changes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Updated dependencies, fixing security problems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated jitsi-meet-electron utils, bringing in new features such as system audio sharing (if the Jitsi Meet deployment has support for it).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;This update comes with some caveats: the Windows and macOS releases are unsigned, so auto-update won't work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Windows&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Windows users will need to download the app again. A warning will show up mentioning the app is unsigned. This is expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;macOS&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;macOS users will need to download the app again beccause it's now unsigned. On macOS catalina a warning will be displayed. The app won't open unless &quot;open&quot; is pressed. This dialog is only shown once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/317464/78881965-cab7ad80-7a57-11ea-8d68-e6b614573c25.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/317464/78881965-cab7ad80-7a57-11ea-8d68-e6b614573c25.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screen Shot 2020-04-08 at 08 47 45&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;GNU/Linux&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a known issue which prevents the app from starting on some Linux distributions: &lt;a class=&quot;issue-link js-issue-link&quot; data-error-text=&quot;Failed to load title&quot; data-id=&quot;595933758&quot; data-permission-text=&quot;Title is private&quot; data-url=&quot;https://github.com/jitsi/jitsi-meet-electron/issues/231&quot; data-hovercard-type=&quot;issue&quot; data-hovercard-url=&quot;/jitsi/jitsi-meet-electron/issues/231/hovercard&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/jitsi/jitsi-meet-electron/issues/231&quot;&gt;#231&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The workaround for now is to run the following command: &lt;code&gt;sudo sysctl kernel.unprivileged_userns_clone=1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, launch the app like so &lt;code&gt;./jitsi-meet-x86_64.AppImage --no-sandbox&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 07:37:27 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>DerWOK</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars0.githubusercontent.com/u/3671647?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>jitsi/jitsi-meet-electron</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/jitsi/jitsi-meet-electron</og:url>
<og:description>Jitsi Meet desktop application powered by :electron: - jitsi/jitsi-meet-electron</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/jitsi/jitsi-meet-electron/releases</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Make Linux Fast Again (2019)</title>
<link>https://make-linux-fast-again.com/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://make-linux-fast-again.com/</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://make-linux-fast-again.com/&quot;&gt;https://make-linux-fast-again.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=22830330&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=22830330&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 328&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 286&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 05:45:28 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>laurentdc</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://make-linux-fast-again.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A (possible) solution to Covid-19</title>
<link>https://www.tillett.info/2020/04/05/a-solution-to-covid-19/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.tillett.info/2020/04/05/a-solution-to-covid-19/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tillett.info/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/streeton_cremone.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-1380&quot; src=&quot;https://www.tillett.info/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/streeton_cremone.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.tillett.info/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/streeton_cremone.jpg 1200w, https://www.tillett.info/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/streeton_cremone-300x94.jpg 300w, https://www.tillett.info/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/streeton_cremone-768x240.jpg 768w, https://www.tillett.info/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/streeton_cremone-1024x320.jpg 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;Notice.&lt;/span&gt; Since this seems to be such a common question I think I should describe my background. I have a PhD in molecular microbiology and I used to be a tenured academic (professor). I now work in the biotech sector. I have published a number of peer reviewed papers in virology. If you really want to know more about me then visit my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tillett.info/about/&quot;&gt;About Me&lt;/a&gt; page. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like nearly everyone on the planet I am worried about COVID-19. SARS-CoV-2 (the virus that causes COVID-19) appears to be &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thelancet.com/journals/laninf/article/PIIS1473-3099(20)30235-8/fulltext&quot;&gt;killing between 1% to 3.5% of the people we know it infects (i.e the case fatality rate)&lt;/a&gt; and has a R0 (i.e. how many new people each person infected goes onto infect) of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Severe_acute_respiratory_syndrome_coronavirus_2&quot;&gt;between 2.5 to 3.9&lt;/a&gt;. Left to run wild, the virus will likely kill tens of millions of people worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The governments of the world have implemented strict population isolation protocols to try and limit the spread of the virus, but the economic cost of this is extremely high. A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2020/04/01/white-house-advisor-fauci-says-coronavirus-vaccine-trial-is-on-target-and-will-be-ultimate-game-changer.html&quot;&gt;vaccine for COVID-19 is 12 to 18 months away&lt;/a&gt; (at best).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are stuck in a diabolic situation where the only way to prevent the economy sliding into a slump deeper than the Great Depression is to consign many tens of millions of people to an early grave. Is there a way out?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;SARS-Cov-2 Viral Diversity&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SARS-CoV-2 like all viruses mutates (changes) overtime. Many of these genetic changes are small (single nucleotides) that are not important to the replications or transmission of the virus from person to person, but they can be used to identify the origin of the virus. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.icelandreview.com/sci-tech/icelands-coronavirus-testing-global-pandemic-response/&quot;&gt;DeCODE genetics for example has been testing Icelanders for COVID-19 and genome sequencing the SARS-CoV-2 strains isolated&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;They have found two very important pieces of information:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;More than 50% of the people infected with SARS-CoV-2 are asymptomatic or have only a mild case (i.e. they have no serious illness).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They can identify the geographical origin of the strains by the genetic differences (mutations) between the different strains.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.medrxiv.org/content/10.1101/2020.03.10.20033944v2&quot;&gt;researchers in China have identified a mutant strain of SARS-CoV-2 which appears to be less pathogenic&lt;/a&gt; than most strains infecting people. The strain (ZJ01) had single nucleotide mutations in a key functional gene that made it less able to spread through the body. A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.biorxiv.org/content/10.1101/2020.03.11.987222v1.full.pdf&quot;&gt;recent pre-print paper from Singapore has described a mutant strain of SARS-CoV-2 with a 382 nucleotide deletion&lt;/a&gt; that was found in a cluster of patients in one of their hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This data suggests a simple and testable hypothesis – &lt;em&gt;there are natural strains of SARS-CoV-2 in the world that have mutated to be non-pathogenic (asymptomatic or mild), but are still infective and will provide immunity to the more pathogenic (deadly) strains.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we can find one of these non-pathogenic viral strains out in the wild we could give it to everyone in the world and solve our diabolic problem. This non-pathogenic strain would act much like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polio_vaccine#Attenuated_2&quot;&gt;live attenuated (oral) polio vaccine&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;How do we find the attenuated SARS-CoV-2 strains?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This hypothesis is worthless if we have no way of finding any of these non-pathogenic SARS-CoV-2 viral strains. Luckily there is a quick and cheap way to find these strains if they exist – test &lt;span&gt;asymptomatic &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;people for COVID-19 and then&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Whole_genome_sequencing&quot;&gt;genome sequence&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;the SARS-CoV-2 strain that has infected them with the aim of identifying a virus with mutation(s) in an essential viral gene(s). This is what the Chinese researchers did to find their less pathogenic strain and how the Singaporean researchers found their deletion mutant strain.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;This approach is cheap (a couple of hundreds of dollars a virus strain) and quick (a week or less). With little cost we could sequence a few thousand viral strains, or even tens of thousands of strains, from positive test sample from asymptomatic and/or mild case until we find a virus strain with the right mutations to make it harmless and which could work like a vaccine. We would know that this strain can still reproduce in people and lead to immunity, but not make people seriously ill. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What viral mutations are we looking for in a good non-pathogenic viral strain?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would ideally be looking for a virus strain with a large(ish) deletion in an essential viral gene just like the strain found in Singapore (unfortunately this strain is too dangerous to use as it put people into hospital). This sort of deletion mutation is easy to spot in the SARS-CoV-2 genome data, and because the genetic information has been removed, it makes the virus unlikely to be able to mutate back into a dangerous strain. Ideally, the strain identified will have infected a large number of other people in the local area so we can know it is safe from the epidemiological data. This will be important for getting regulatory approval.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Has this ever been done before?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yes.&lt;/strong&gt; The polio, measles, rubella, mumps, and chickenpox vaccines are all live attenuated viruses. Even something as dangerous as smallpox was controlled in the 18th century using a variation of this idea called &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Variolation&quot;&gt;Variolation&lt;/a&gt;. The idea was the doctor would deliberately infect you with a less harmful strain of smallpox (often at a low dose) to make you immune to the more deadly strains of smallpox. Of course, they didn’t know how this approach worked in the 18th century, but it was still very effective and millions of people were saved from dying from smallpox by it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people have been calling &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.overcomingbias.com/2020/03/variolation-may-cut-covid19-deaths-3-30x.html&quot;&gt;using a low dose of the virus Variolation&lt;/a&gt;, this is not what we think Variolation was, but this is a complex topic. While such a low-dose approach of the dangerous strain might make the COVID-19 less dangerous to the person being deliberately infected, it doesn’t make the virus any less dangerous for those around you that you might infect later. Such an approach could also not be used on the vulnerable, leaving them exposed to the illness. There is no reason in principle that the low dose idea couldn’t be combined with the attenuated strain idea and it might even be a very good idea especially for people who are vulnerable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;What are the risks?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; The major risk is the virus we think is safe is not 100% safe.&lt;/strong&gt; While we can use community spread of the identified strain to estimate how safe it will be (i.e. if it has infected 1000 people and none have got seriously ill then we should have a pretty good idea that it is safe), our knowledge will be incomplete. We can of course spend the next few years testing and trialling, but if we do this by the time any strain is shown to be 99.99% safe (not even the polio vaccine is 100% safe) we will have all got COVID-19 and the world’s economy will be a smoking ruin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a choice of taking some risks now, or face the certainty of a much worse problem later. &lt;strong&gt;Time to accept some risk and do something now.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Q &amp;amp; A&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been getting a few questions on this post so I thought I would address them here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;How do you know there is an attenuated viral strain out there?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.medrxiv.org/content/10.1101/2020.03.10.20033944v2&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Because such strains have already been found&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. I am hypothesising that there is more than one based on the known mutation rate of coronaviruses and the number of cases. &lt;a href=&quot;https://nextstrain.org/ncov/global?l=clock&quot;&gt;Coronaviruses like SARS-COV-2 mutate continuously&lt;/a&gt; (this is why companies like deCODE can tell the geographical origin of different strains) as the molecular machinery for replicating their RNA genome is not very accurate, although it is more accurate than the machinery of other RNA viruses like HIV. When you combine this with the millions of mild cases out in the world, the odds are on our side that there is at least one person infected with a strain that has a mutation that makes the virus less dangerous (attenuated). We just need to go and look for this strain – luckily the tools we need to use (genome sequencing) are now cheap and quick. What would have been impossible 20 years ago can now be done in a week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Aren’t most people who have mild/asymptomatic cases infected with a dangerous strain?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yes.&lt;/strong&gt; Almost all (&amp;gt;99.9%) of people who are infected (and have a mild case) are infected with a dangerous strain of the virus, they just happen to have an immune system that can control the virus well. With COVID-19 a mild case does not mean you are infected with an attenuated strain – for most people with a mild case if they happen to infect a person with preexisting conditions or who is old, that person will be at a high risk of dying. &lt;strong&gt;A mild case does not equal a harmless strain.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My argument is coming from the other direction. &lt;strong&gt;While almost all mild cases of COVID-19 are caused by a dangerous strain of SARS-CoV-2, an attenuated strain of SARS-CoV-2 will only cause mild disease.&lt;/strong&gt; If you want to find an attenuated strain you need to look at mild cases even though &amp;gt;99.9% of the people you check will be infected with a dangerous strain. What we want to find is one of the rare natural viral mutants that is attenuated. Where you will find such a viral mutant is in people with a mild/asymptomatic form of the disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Why only sequence those with mild/asymptomatic cases of COVID-19?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I had to choose one aspect that gets most misunderstood by people who read this idea, it would be the reason for sequencing only mild/asymptomatic cases. This is purely an efficiency issue. In an ideal world we would sequence the strains from all cases, look to see if we can find mutants with deletions, and then see what was the clinical outcome of those infected with that strain. If we find that all cases of a particular mutant strain are mild/asymptomatic, and no cases ended up in hospital, then we would have our candidate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately we live in a constrained world where it is not possible to collect and sequence the virus from all cases of COVID-19, Given this, where should we look first? Since we are looking for a mutant strain that only causes mild/asymptomatic cases, we can exclude patients who have serious symptoms in a first pass. Any strain that causes serious illness won’t be a strain we want to use. Only once we find a good candidate strain that has the right sort of mutation (a deletion), do we then sequence all the cases in the local area, from both the serious and mild, to get the full clinical picture. This approach is just a way to make the search process much more efficient and practicable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Can’t we just wait for a vaccine?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No.&lt;/strong&gt; Apart from the time it will take to develop, trial, and mass produce a vaccine (12-18 months), it is unlikely that any vaccine will be practicable. The reason why is immunity to respiratory viruses (like corona) doesn’t last long – 6 months to 2 years. We would have to keep vaccinating everyone in the world every year (or maybe every 6 months if we are unlucky). This just isn’t going to work in the real world (especially poor countries) and is one of the reasons we don’t have a vaccine for the &lt;span&gt;coronavirus strains that cause the common cold. Unless we can drive the current dangerous SARS-CoV-2 strains to&lt;/span&gt; extinction &lt;span&gt;we are&lt;/span&gt; going &lt;span&gt;to have a problem with this disease&lt;/span&gt; indefinitely&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Won’t the mutations in SARS-CoV-2 make this idea fail?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The coronavirus are &lt;a href=&quot;https://nextstrain.org/narratives/ncov/sit-rep/2020-01-30?n=6&quot;&gt;relatively stable genetically for an RNA virus&lt;/a&gt;. The coronavirus strains that cause the common cold tend to not change much antigenically over time, unlike the Influenza, HIV and Hepatitis C viruses. The way the common cold strains spread is through our immunity to them declining fairly rapidly (in months, not years). The result is the same common cold strain can infect you multiple times in your life as your immunity to it fades, rather than it having to change antigenically so much that our immune systems doesn’t respond to it anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is good news for us as it means we may only need to isolate one mutant strain. Even if in the worse case SARS-CoV-2 does change so much antigenically that our attenuated strain no longer offers protection, we can just repeat the process we used to find the first strain to find the next strain. More fundamentally, this is a problem for all vaccine approaches that we will need to deal with if it happens, but it shouldn’t stop us from acting now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Isn’t social distancing and quarantining solving the problem?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yes and no.&lt;/strong&gt; Yes countries like South Korea and Australia have shown that through mass screening and social distancing you can keep a lid on the disease, but this leaves the population susceptible to a new outbreak. Singapore and Japan have recently seen this in action where they eased restrictions and found the disease came back and they had to reintroduce restrictions. I don’t think many people want to live for years with cycles of restrictions, easings and further outbreaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Wouldn’t the use of such an attenuated strain just be a vaccine?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yes in one way, but it is a little more subtle.&lt;/strong&gt; Assuming we can find an attenuated strain, then how to best use it a separate question. The most important thing to note is that such a virus would not be a vaccine from a regulatory perspective. It is just a natural virus that you can catch in a natural way. Hang out someone infected with the attenuated viral strain and you will catch it without doing anything, go home and those around you will catch it from you and so on. While I wouldn’t suggest this is the best way to get the attenuated virus out into the community (it would be much better to just post a sample of the virus to everyone for example after getting regulatory approval), such spread is outside the regulatory framework for vaccines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Giving it deliberately to lots of people would change the ecosystem for the dangerous strains of the virus. The dangerous strains would find it difficult to spread through the community as many (most) people would have already been infected (and hence immune) with the attenuated strain (i.e. herd immunity). Overtime the dangerous strains would become rarer, and the attenuated strains more common, until eventually the dangerous strains would become extinct and we would just be left with the mild version floating around. While we would not be able to get rid of this mild strain, it would just be another of the hundreds of viruses out there causing common colds. &lt;strong&gt;The idea is at its base is really to replace the dangerous strains with a less dangerous strain that we can live with.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Why can’t we just use the less pathogenic SARS-CoV-2 strain already identified in China?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.medrxiv.org/content/10.1101/2020.03.10.20033944v2&quot;&gt;ZJ01 SARS-CoV-2 strain identified in China&lt;/a&gt; appears to be less pathogenic, the mutations that make it so are single base changes. These can easily mutate back to the more dangerous version of the virus. The viral strain we want to find will have a deletion mutation where a section of the viral genome is removed. Deletion mutations are much more difficult to mutate back to the dangerous type since rather than just a change from one nucleotide to another (e.g. C &amp;gt; T), the deleted region is missing and can’t easily be recreated by mutation. Put simply, deletion mutations are more stable to back reversion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;How should any such attenuated strain be used?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is not a decision for me.&lt;/strong&gt; I think the regulatory authorities like the FDA will approve the use of a natural attenuated strain on the basis of the epidemiological data collected finding the strain. While most regulatory agencies are extremely conservative and slow, they are not idiots and they understand that using an approach with some serious unknowns might be better than the alternative of waiting for the perfect vaccine. COVID-19 is a problem with only hard choices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do think it would be impossible to prevent the use of any such strain even without regulatory approval. Assuming a “safe” strain is found and a test for it developed (this is relatively easy since you are looking for the presence of a deletion), people will start spreading it between themselves at a “grass roots” level. I think this outcome will influence the decision of the regulatory authorities to approve its use – better to have the attenuated virus spread through some controlled and regulated way, rather than illicitly by people doing it on their own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; I have been trying to get this idea in front of someone with the clout to make this happen, but without much luck because the people with the clout (say Bill Gates) don’t read messages from random people like me. For this idea to succeed it needs a two hop process (i.e. someone knows someone, who knows someone, who Bill Gates will take seriously). If you think you might be that first hop person then please get in contact with me at &lt;strong&gt;daniel.tillett@gmail.com&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I should add that it doesn’t have to be only Bill Gates that can push this forward. If you think you know someone who could help then get in contact with me. Unlike Bill I will respond :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;Update 2.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; I have modified this post to better explain those aspects that have confused people (my fault). I hope this idea is now clearer. Keep the comments coming.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 05:43:22 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>danieltillett</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.tillett.info/2020/04/05/a-solution-to-covid-19/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>