<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>New academic journal only publishes &amp;#039;unsurprising&amp;#039; research rejected by others</title>
<link>https://www.cbc.ca/radio/asithappens/as-it-happens-thursday-edition-1.5146761/new-academic-journal-only-publishes-unsurprising-research-rejected-by-others-1.5146765</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.cbc.ca/radio/asithappens/as-it-happens-thursday-edition-1.5146761/new-academic-journal-only-publishes-unsurprising-research-rejected-by-others-1.5146765</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbc.ca/radio/asithappens/as-it-happens-monday-edition-1.5151279/may-27-2019-episode-transcript-1.5153143&quot;&gt;Transcript&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;There's a method to Andrea Menclova's mundane madness.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section id=&quot;inread-wrapper-id-21013752&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Menclova is an associate professor at the University of Canterbury and the editor of a new journal called &lt;em&gt;The Series of Unsurprising Results in Economics&lt;/em&gt; [SURE].&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The mission is simple: only publish research with findings that are boring.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;As It Happens&lt;/em&gt; host Carol Off spoke to Menclova about the journal and why she hopes it will address a bias in academic research publications.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Here is part of their conversation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Andrea, why on Earth would you want to put out a journal full of dull research?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Well, I think science has a problem and it's a problem with publication bias.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We believe that a lot of the other journals are biased in the other direction — towards publishing attractive, catchy, strong, statistically significant results.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We kind of want to fill the void and publish results that are the opposite of that —unsurprising, weaker, statistically insignificant, not conclusive and so on.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;placeholder&quot;&gt;

&lt;span&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;https://i.cbc.ca/1.5049831.1552093234!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_300/scientific-and-scholarly-publication.jpg 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5049831.1552093234!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_460/scientific-and-scholarly-publication.jpg 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5049831.1552093234!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_620/scientific-and-scholarly-publication.jpg 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5049831.1552093234!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/scientific-and-scholarly-publication.jpg 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5049831.1552093234!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_1180/scientific-and-scholarly-publication.jpg 1180w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.cbc.ca/1.5049831.1552093234!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/scientific-and-scholarly-publication.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span&gt;The SURE journal aims to address a bias in academic research publications. (Shutterstock/Lena Lir)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The boring research that you would have in your publication — these are results that didn't prove anything sensational, nothing sexy, nothing unusual. What happens when people do that kind of important research? Why is it so difficult to get that published?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our careers can depend quite crucially on publishing papers and publishing them in good journals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so, oftentimes, after finding a research question, reading up on other people's work, thinking about methods carefully, getting data, cleaning, and so on — months into the project, people finally get results which are outside of their control or should be outside of their control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And whoops! The results are not striking. Oftentimes people just give up at that point and they move on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What also happens often is that people think: &quot;Well, surely there is an attractive result hiding here somewhere. So if I just look long enough I'm going to find it.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very likely, just by sheer coincidence, they do find a statistic that's significant and that's the one that gets published.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so, as a result, what we see in journals is typically — it's the truth, but it's not the full truth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;placeholder&quot;&gt;

&lt;span&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;https://i.cbc.ca/1.5151817.1558988480!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_300/surescreenshot.jpg 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5151817.1558988480!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_460/surescreenshot.jpg 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5151817.1558988480!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_620/surescreenshot.jpg 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5151817.1558988480!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/surescreenshot.jpg 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5151817.1558988480!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_1180/surescreenshot.jpg 1180w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.cbc.ca/1.5151817.1558988480!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/surescreenshot.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span&gt;A screenshot of the SURE journal website, which lists the 'unsuprising' submission requirements. (SURE Journal)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Also, as you mentioned, if getting grants and research money and jobs depends on this [and] if you're only getting published if you have sensational results then the actual science itself starts to get skewed.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Absolutely. So if you then had a policy maker who wanted to implement an intervention and wanted to have evidence-based policy, they might be finding a lot of studies that say the results are really powerful — you know, do this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet for every such published study there might be another study that didn't get published and it just found no results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can you give examples — what would you publish as an unsurprising results in your journal?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good example is the inaugural publication, I think, that we had last week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is from Nick Huntington-Klein and Andrew Gill from California State University Fullerton.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They looked at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ir.canterbury.ac.nz/bitstream/handle/10092/16670/SURE_2019_1-final.pdf?sequence=1&amp;amp;isAllowed=y&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;issue of U.S. college students not finishing their degree&lt;/a&gt;, not graduating within four years, taking longer than that. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's very costly and some recent papers show that the solution to this may be very straightforward and low-cost. You just tell students. You make it explicit to them of what the costs are and how to graduate in four years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nick and Andrew did a similar experiment, they found no effects whatsoever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so they send this to a journal and the response they got was, well, you know, you probably wouldn't expect an effect because this is not fairly novel information to the students. So we are not going to publish this because it's not really surprising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;7.8054711246201&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot; readability=&quot;8.7811550151976&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;This is the very first paper published in the new journal Series of Unsurprising Results in Economics, a journal that only publishes results that have been rejected by other journals specifically because they are not surprising enough. Very good idea! &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/149eb2d7TA&quot;&amp;gt;https://t.co/149eb2d7TA&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span&gt;&amp;amp;mdash;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/nickchk/status/1128363133267894272&quot;&gt;@nickchk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There was a story last year. A very popular food &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbc.ca/radio/thecurrent/the-current-for-september-21-2018-1.4831874/brian-wansink-researcher-behind-100-calorie-snacks-discredited-after-13-papers-retracted-1.4832860&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;researcher at Cornell University had 15 studies retracted&lt;/a&gt; after it was revealed that he had fudged the results to make them more interesting. He had results that if you eat off smaller plates it would make you eat less and things like that. And so it actually influences behaviour at some point, doesn't it? These things get picked up. They get published. We cover them on programs. It all ends up being wrong, doesn't it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it does a lot of harm because evidence shows that even if you retract these results they kind of have already stuck in people's minds and people don't go back and check what has been retracted. So it can do lasting harm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Same thing happens though in journalism. For instance, if there are 1,000 scientists who say there is climate change and there's one scientist who's makes a controversial claim that there isn't climate change then that scientist will actually get exposure. It skews public perception, doesn't it? So I guess we're responsible for the same thing.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, and it's understandable. But you would hope that in science we are slightly removed from that and sheltered from that pressure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by Allie Jaynes and John McGill. Interview produced by Allie Jaynes. Q&amp;amp;A edited for length and clarity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 21:32:59 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>apsec112</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.cbc.ca/radio/asithappens/as-it-happens-thursday-edition-1.5146761/new-academic-journal-only-publishes-unsurprising-research-rejected-by-others-1.5146765</og:url>
<og:title>New academic journal only publishes 'unsurprising' research rejected by others | CBC Radio</og:title>
<og:image>https://i.cbc.ca/1.5147205.1558638646!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/16x9_620/3071985.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>The editor behind a new academic journal that only publishes unsurprising research hopes the journal will help fix a major problem in scientific research — a bias towards surprising, unexpected results.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.cbc.ca/radio/asithappens/as-it-happens-thursday-edition-1.5146761/new-academic-journal-only-publishes-unsurprising-research-rejected-by-others-1.5146765</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Uber and Lyft shutdown in California averted as judge grants emergency stay</title>
<link>https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/20/21377841/uber-lyft-california-judge-block-emergency-stay-employees</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/20/21377841/uber-lyft-california-judge-block-emergency-stay-employees</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;HRURTa&quot;&gt;A California appeals court judge &lt;a href=&quot;https://appellatecases.courtinfo.ca.gov/search/case/dockets.cfm?dist=1&amp;amp;doc_id=2325037&amp;amp;doc_no=A160706&amp;amp;request_token=NiIwLSEmXkw3W1BNSCMtVEtIMFw6UVxfJSJeWzpSUCAgCg%3D%3D&quot;&gt;blocked an order&lt;/a&gt; requiring Uber and Lyft to classify drivers as employees, averting an expected shutdown of the ride-sharing services in California at midnight tonight. The court granted Uber and Lyft a temporary stay while their appeals process play out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;ufuzFe&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/20/21377493/lyft-california-suspend-ride-hailing-service-drivers-ab5&quot;&gt;Lyft had already announced it was planning to temporarily cease operations&lt;/a&gt; in the state earlier today, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/19/21376009/uber-ceo-interivew-california-ab5-drivers-khosrowshahi&quot;&gt;Uber CEO Dara Khosrowshahi had said the same about his company&lt;/a&gt; in an interview yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;58Ng1F&quot;&gt;But the companies won an 11th hour reprieve from the California Court of Appeals hours before the shutdown was expected to go into effect. Uber and Lyft will now have until October to convince the court to throw out the order that it employ its drivers. If they are unsuccessful, the companies will be back where they started, and may again decide to shutdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;c-float-right&quot;&gt;
&lt;aside id=&quot;44V0hm&quot;&gt;&lt;q&gt;Uber and Lyft will now have until October to convince the court to throw out the order&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;pgaHrr&quot;&gt;Uber and Lyft are under enormous pressure to fundamentally alter their business models in California, the state where both companies were founded and raised billions of dollars in venture capital. Uber and Lyft say drivers prefer the flexibility of working as freelancers, while labor unions and elected officials contend this deprives them of traditional benefits like health insurance and workers’ compensation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;9QsHcI&quot;&gt;In January, a new law went into effect called AB5, which makes it more difficult for companies to use independent contractors. The law was mostly targeted at ride-sharing companies like Uber and Lyft, which have built their businesses on the concept of independent contractors using their own vehicles to make trips and shouldering the costs of their work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;UKsbVt&quot;&gt;This won’t be the final word. Uber and Lyft, along with DoorDash, were successful in getting a proposition on the state’s 2020 ballot that, if approved, would allow it to sidestep AB5 and continue classifying its drivers as independent contractors. The measure, Proposition 22, also stipulates that the companies provide more benefits to drivers, such as a minimum wage and access to health insurance. Unions and other pro-AB5 groups argue these benefits fall short of what drivers would be entitled to as employees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;7rFIBE&quot;&gt;In a statement, Uber celebrated the court’s ruling. “We are glad that the Court of Appeals recognized the important questions raised in this case, and that access to these critical services won’t be cut off while we continue to advocate for drivers’ ability to work with the freedom they want,” a spokesperson said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;6rAwaC&quot;&gt;In a statement, Lyft said that the temporary stay was a victory, but the company would still push for the passage of Prop 22. “While we won’t have to suspend operations tonight, we do need to continue fighting for independence plus benefits for drivers,” a Lyft spokesperson said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;7aKX8Q&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update August 20th, 4:23PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Updated to include Lyft’s statement and context about Prop 22.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 19:07:44 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>badwolf</dc:creator>
<og:description>An 11th-hour reprieve for Uber and Lyft.</og:description>
<og:image>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BrZIGOI8O_b5Pqe4baisPFcWYoU=/0x390:4682x2841/fit-in/1200x630/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21788072/1219237832.jpg.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Uber and Lyft shutdown in California averted as judge grants emergency stay</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/20/21377841/uber-lyft-california-judge-block-emergency-stay-employees</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/20/21377841/uber-lyft-california-judge-block-emergency-stay-employees</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Rideshare operations are being suspended in California</title>
<link>https://www.lyft.com/blog/posts/ca-operations-update</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.lyft.com/blog/posts/ca-operations-update</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;StyledText-cx1xxi-0 gVTvCq&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Our previous statement, posted at 9:00AM PT&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;StyledText-cx1xxi-0 kqmrwG&quot;&gt;Rideshare operations are being suspended in California&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;StyledText-cx1xxi-0 gVTvCq&quot;&gt;At 11:59PM PT today our rideshare operations in California will be suspended. This is not something we wanted to do, as we know millions of Californians depend on Lyft for daily, essential trips. We’re personally reaching out to riders and drivers to share more about why this is happening, what you can do about it, and to provide some &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lyft.com/rider/californiaupdate#transportation-options&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;transportation alternatives&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;StyledText-cx1xxi-0 kqmrwG&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why this is happening&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;StyledText-cx1xxi-0 gVTvCq&quot;&gt;For multiple years, we’ve been advocating for a path to offer benefits to drivers who use the Lyft platform — including a minimum earnings guarantee and a healthcare subsidy — while maintaining the flexibility and control that independent contractors enjoy. This is something drivers have told us over and over again that they want. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;StyledText-cx1xxi-0 gVTvCq&quot;&gt;Instead, what Sacramento politicians are pushing is an employment model that 4 out of 5 drivers don’t support. This change would also necessitate an overhaul of the entire business model — it’s not a switch that can be flipped overnight. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;StyledText-cx1xxi-0 gVTvCq&quot;&gt;In this new model that politicians are pushing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;StyledText-cx1xxi-0 gVTvCq&quot; readability=&quot;27.5&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;StyledText-cx1xxi-0 gVTvCq&quot;&gt;Passengers would experience reduced service, especially in suburban and rural areas&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;StyledText-cx1xxi-0 gVTvCq&quot;&gt;80% of drivers would lose work and the rest would have scheduled shifts, and capped hourly earnings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;StyledText-cx1xxi-0 gVTvCq&quot;&gt;Lower-income riders trying to make it to essential jobs and medical appointments would be faced with unaffordable prices (38% of Lyft rides in California begin or end in low-income areas that have few transit options already).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;StyledText-cx1xxi-0 kqmrwG&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What we’re doing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;StyledText-cx1xxi-0 gVTvCq&quot;&gt;We don’t want to suspend operations. We are going to keep up the fight for a benefits model that works for &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; drivers and our riders. We’ve spent hundreds of hours meeting with policymakers and labor leaders to craft an alternative proposal for drivers that includes &lt;strong&gt;a minimum earnings guarantee, mileage reimbursement, a health care subsidy, and occupational accident insurance&lt;/strong&gt;, without the negative consequences.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class=&quot;StyledText-cx1xxi-0 kqmrwG&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What you can do&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;StyledText-cx1xxi-0 gVTvCq&quot;&gt;Your voice can help. A ballot measure this November, &lt;a href=&quot;https://prop22facts.com/lyft/&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Prop 22&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, proposes the necessary changes to give drivers benefits &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; flexibility, while maintaining the rideshare model that helps you get where you need to go. We believe voters should decide. Please sign up to help today. &lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;StyledText-cx1xxi-0 gVTvCq&quot;&gt;Thank you for being a part of the Lyft community. We will keep you updated as this situation develops. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;StyledText-cx1xxi-0 gVTvCq&quot;&gt;You can find further information about the suspension and alternative transportation – From public transportation and airport shuttles, to bikes, scooters and rentals via the Lyft app – &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lyft.com/rider/californiaupdate#get-around&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;













&lt;p class=&quot;StyledText-cx1xxi-0 gVTvCq&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paid for by Lyft, Inc.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;StyledText-cx1xxi-0 gVTvCq&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;This announcement contains forward-looking statements, including statements about Lyft suspending rideshare operations in California, our business model, and the Proposition 22 ballot initiative. Factors that could cause actual results to differ materially from those addressed in the forward-looking statements are detailed in our filings with the Securities and Exchange Commission. We do not undertake an obligation to update our forward-looking statements to reflect future events, except as required by applicable law.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;StyledText-cx1xxi-0 gVTvCq&quot;&gt;Categories&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;NegativeMargin-sc-1ohrrug-0 lnggfp&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ButtonWrapper-sc-11tiw4s-0 eJIgBp&quot;&gt;&lt;a type=&quot;button&quot; href=&quot;https://www.lyft.com/blog/categories/cities&quot; class=&quot;BaseButton-sc-174wt3j-0 primaryTextButton-sc-174wt3j-8 horapK&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;FadeDuringLoading-aqyi1g-1 eCkYes&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;FadeChildren-aqyi1g-0 iDQjNz&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;MultilineTextWrap-sc-11tiw4s-1 kGcXot&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;StyledText-cx1xxi-0 BwsrF&quot;&gt;Cities&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;NegativeMargin-sc-1ohrrug-0 lnggfp&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ButtonWrapper-sc-11tiw4s-0 eJIgBp&quot;&gt;&lt;a type=&quot;button&quot; href=&quot;https://www.lyft.com/blog/categories/news&quot; class=&quot;BaseButton-sc-174wt3j-0 primaryTextButton-sc-174wt3j-8 horapK&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;FadeDuringLoading-aqyi1g-1 eCkYes&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;FadeChildren-aqyi1g-0 iDQjNz&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;MultilineTextWrap-sc-11tiw4s-1 kGcXot&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;StyledText-cx1xxi-0 BwsrF&quot;&gt;News&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 16:24:03 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>el_duderino</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:title>Rideshare operations are being suspended in California</og:title>
<og:description>UPDATE: Rideshare is ON. The California court has granted our request for a further stay, so our rideshare operations can continue uninterrupted, for now. Thanks to the tens of thousands of drivers, riders, and public officials who urged California to keep rideshare available for so many people who depend on it.</og:description>
<og:image>https://images.ctfassets.net/vz6nkkbc6q75/25LgImZYY4qplKhCzSugb6/a98724e9cad2bc3925766163efd9998a/Lyft_CA_Update_Blog_Header_1232x493.png?w=1200&amp;h=630&amp;fm=jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.lyft.com/blog/posts/ca-operations-update</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Suspected Poisoning of Alexey Navalny, Putin’s Most Prominent Adversary</title>
<link>https://www.newyorker.com/news/our-columnists/the-suspected-poisoning-of-alexey-navalny-putins-most-prominent-adversary</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.newyorker.com/news/our-columnists/the-suspected-poisoning-of-alexey-navalny-putins-most-prominent-adversary</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;has-dropcap has-dropcap__lead-standard-heading&quot;&gt;Alexey Navalny, the anti-corruption blogger who for years has been Vladimir Putin’s only formidable opponent—which is to say, his only adversary who has remained in Russia, stayed active, and maintained prominence despite repeated attacks from the authorities—has been hospitalized in an intensive-care unit in the Siberian city of Omsk. He is in a coma. He fell ill aboard a plane, which then made an emergency landing. His assistant and press secretary, Kira Yarmysh, suspects Navalny has been poisoned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Thursday morning, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/tag/alexey-navalny&quot;&gt;Navalny&lt;/a&gt; and Yarmysh boarded a plane from Tomsk to Moscow, about a four-hour flight. Soon after takeoff, Navalny felt unwell and broke out in a sweat, Yarmysh &lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5fp1Xeu3Npk&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5fp1Xeu3Npk&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;told&lt;/a&gt; the Russian radio station Echo of Moscow. He then disappeared into the bathroom. A Russian Twitter user later posted a video showing emergency medical personnel going to Navalny’s aid, as Navalny is heard screaming in the background; it appears that this video was recorded after the plane landed in Omsk, about a third of the way to Moscow from Tomsk. Yarmysh tweeted that all Navalny had consumed that day was tea, and that she suspected that this was how he was poisoned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The history of Russian opposition figures who have been poisoned is so long that it is almost tedious to recite. Pyotr Verzilov, an activist with the protest-art group Pussy Riot and an opposition publisher, spent months recovering from an apparent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/our-columnists/we-now-know-more-about-the-apparent-poisoning-of-the-pussy-riot-member-pyotr-verzilov&quot;&gt;poisoning&lt;/a&gt; that put him in intensive care, in Moscow, in September, 2018. The journalist and historian Vladimir Kara-Murza was poisoned twice, in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/news-desk/putins-russia-dont-walk-dont-eat-and-dont-drink&quot;&gt;2015&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.nybooks.com/daily/2017/02/21/total-catastrophe-of-the-body-kara-murza-poisoning/&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nybooks.com/daily/2017/02/21/total-catastrophe-of-the-body-kara-murza-poisoning/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;2017&lt;/a&gt;, and came close to death both times. The defector spy Sergei Skripal and his daughter, Yulia, were &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/our-columnists/under-russian-terror-all-exiles-are-fearful-and-all-deaths-are-suspicious&quot;&gt;poisoned&lt;/a&gt; with the chemical-warfare agent Novichok in England, in 2018. The defector Alexander Litvinenko was poisoned with polonium, in 2006. The investigative journalist Yuri Shchekochikhin died in agony in a Moscow hospital, in 2003; his colleague Anna Politkovskaya survived a similar poisoning, in 2004, only to be shot to death, in 2006. This is far from a complete list. The habit of poisoning the opposition predates Vladimir Putin—I could list some poisonings from the nineteen-nineties—and even the collapse of the Soviet Union: the Bulgarian writer Georgi Markov, who defected to the U.K., was assassinated by ricin, in London, in 1978. Tea has been used as a vehicle for poison before—in Litvinenko’s case, the polonium was added to a teapot in a restaurant, and in Politkovskaya’s case, the apparent culprit was tea served to her on an airplane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Navalny has been an extraordinarily resilient thorn in Putin’s side. He rose to prominence in the late two-thousands as a blogger who used open-source data to expose corruption in and around the Kremlin. He found government-purchasing contracts that defied credulity and linked opulent real estate to civil servants. Over the last decade, he has built an organization that serves as Russia’s leading alternative-media outlet and its only real political organization. Navalny has mounted several attempts to run for office—the Russian Presidency and the Moscow mayor’s seat—and while rigged election rules have prevented him from succeeding, he has mobilized enough people to make him Putin’s main nemesis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2013, the Kremlin tried to silence Navalny by sending him to prison, but thousands of Muscovites &lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://latitude.blogs.nytimes.com/2013/07/22/that-blunt-russian-force/&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://latitude.blogs.nytimes.com/2013/07/22/that-blunt-russian-force/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;poured&lt;/a&gt; into the streets, themselves risking arrest, and the authorities quickly retracted the sentence. Navalny &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/news-desk/bitter-education-alexey-navalny&quot;&gt;later&lt;/a&gt; spent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/our-columnists/alexey-navalny-and-the-empty-spectacle-of-the-russian-election&quot;&gt;months&lt;/a&gt; under house arrest, then did one stint after another under administrative arrest, which lasted from ten days to a month. The regime, in other words, tried to silence him by a thousand cuts rather than a single blow that might have inspired the kind of protest that scares Putin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why try to assassinate Navalny now? There are two possible explanations. One is that this timing is, in effect, an accident (such explanations should never be discounted, especially in Russia); it is possible that an eager self-appointed Kremlin avenger struck without being given explicit authority. The other plausible explanation is that the Kremlin, which invariably sees its former colonies as mirrors, is terrified by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/our-columnists/after-a-rigged-election-belarus-crushes-protests-amid-an-information-blackout&quot;&gt;the protests in Belarus&lt;/a&gt;. Hundreds of thousands of people there risking their lives to get rid of Alexander Lukashenka, who has been in power for twenty-six years, to Putin’s twenty. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/our-columnists/we-were-locked-up-in-one-country-and-released-into-another-horror-and-hope-as-protests-in-belarus-continue&quot;&gt;Belarusians have shown&lt;/a&gt; that, even in a country where electoral institutions, the media, and civil society are almost entirely dominated by an autocrat, people can still claim the power to say that they’ve had enough. An autocracy has no way to protect itself from that kind of mass protest—except, perhaps, by killing the presumptive leader of the uprising to come.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 15:19:49 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jseliger</dc:creator>
<og:description>Navalny, the creator of Russia’s leading alternative-media outlet and its only real political organization, is now in a coma in the Siberian city of Omsk.</og:description>
<og:image>https://media.newyorker.com/photos/5f3e7cc827748a6a38867ea2/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/Gessen-Navalny.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>The Suspected Poisoning of Alexey Navalny, Putin’s Most Prominent Adversary</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.newyorker.com/news/our-columnists/the-suspected-poisoning-of-alexey-navalny-putins-most-prominent-adversary</og:url>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.newyorker.com/news/our-columnists/the-suspected-poisoning-of-alexey-navalny-putins-most-prominent-adversary</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Kush civilization flourished in Sudan nearly 5K years ago</title>
<link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/travel/sudan-land-kush-meroe-ancient-civilization-overlooked-180975498/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.smithsonianmag.com/travel/sudan-land-kush-meroe-ancient-civilization-overlooked-180975498/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;If you drive north from Khartoum along a narrow desert road toward the ancient city of Meroe, a breathtaking view emerges from beyond the mirage: dozens of steep pyramids piercing the horizon. No matter how many times you may visit, there is an awed sense of discovery. In Meroe itself, once the capital of the Kingdom of Kush, the road divides the city. To the east is the royal cemetery, packed with close to 50 sandstone and red brick pyramids of varying heights; many have broken tops, the legacy of 19th-century European looters. To the west is the royal city, which includes the ruins of a palace, a temple and a royal bath. Each structure has distinctive architecture that draws on local, Egyptian and Greco-Roman decorative tastes—evidence of Meroe’s global connections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Off the highway, men wearing Sudanese jalabiyas and turbans ride camels across the desert sands. Although the area is largely free of the trappings of modern tourism, a few local merchants on straw mats in the sand sell small clay replicas of the pyramids. As you approach the royal cemetery on foot, climbing large, rippled dunes, Meroe’s pyramids, lined neatly in rows, rise as high as 100 feet toward the sky. “It’s like opening a fairytale book,” a friend once said to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot; lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Temple of Soleb&quot; src=&quot;https://thumbs-prod.si-cdn.com/crhVdwbRsRLHpSBQWS0ioMPD_ao=/fit-in/1072x0/https://public-media.si-cdn.com/filer/73/48/7348ecb2-2a2f-4d0c-ba3a-d00cfb31516c/sep2020_b11_sudanpyramids.jpg&quot;/&gt; The 14th-century B.C. Temple of Soleb was built by Egyptian pharaoh Amenhotep III during a period when Egypt’s reign encompassed ancient Nubia. A strong resemblance to Luxor Temple has led some scholars to suggest that both complexes were built by the same architect. &lt;span class=&quot;credits&quot;&gt;(Matt Stirn)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;img class=&quot; lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Map of Sudan&quot; src=&quot;https://thumbs-prod.si-cdn.com/r2JCb7-1X0LqZa0SWCff56mlnv4=/fit-in/1072x0/https://public-media.si-cdn.com/filer/0d/cf/0dcfd3bb-d077-4790-805b-174f125444fa/map_of_sudan.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;I first learned of Sudan’s extraordinary pyramids as a boy, in the British historian Basil Davidson’s 1984 documentary series &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0953817/&quot;&gt;“Africa.”&lt;/a&gt; As a Sudanese-American who was born and raised in the United States and the Middle East, I studied the history of ancient Egypt and Mesopotamia, the Levant, Persia, Greece and Rome—but never that of ancient Nubia, the region surrounding the Nile River between Aswan in southern Egypt and Khartoum in central Sudan. Seeing the documentary pushed me to read as many books as I could about my homeland’s history, and during annual vacations with my family I spent much of my time at Khartoum’s museums, viewing ancient artifacts and temples rescued from the waters of Lake Nasser when Egypt’s Aswan High Dam was built during the 1960s and ’70s. Later, I worked as a journalist in Khartoum, Sudan’s capital, for close to eight years, reporting for the &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt; and other news outlets about Sudan’s fragile politics and wars. But every once in a while I got to write about Sudan’s rich and relatively little known ancient history. It took me more than 25 years to see the pyramids in person, but when I finally visited Meroe, I was overwhelmed by a feeling of fulfilled longing for this place, which had given me a sense of dignity and a connection to global history. Like a long lost relative, I wrapped my arms around a pyramid in a hug.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The land south of Egypt, beyond the first cataract of the Nile, was known to the ancient world by many names: Ta-Seti, or Land of the Bow, so named because the inhabitants were expert archers; Ta-Nehesi, or Land of Copper; Ethiopia, or Land of Burnt Faces, from the Greek; Nubia, possibly derived from an ancient Egyptian word for gold, which was plentiful; and Kush, the kingdom that dominated the region between roughly 2500 B.C. and A.D. 300. In some religious traditions, Kush was linked to the biblical Cush, son of Ham and grandson of Noah, whose descendants inhabited northeast Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot; lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Inside a pyramid tomb at Meroe&quot; src=&quot;https://thumbs-prod.si-cdn.com/AimfXvRlgtcRNIBy1u-fFW4_v60=/fit-in/1072x0/https://public-media.si-cdn.com/filer/ea/b7/eab7ffc4-f12c-44a2-94a3-d777806430a3/sep2020_b10_sudanpyramids.jpg&quot;/&gt; Inside a pyramid tomb at Meroe that some archaeologists believe belonged to Kushite King Tanyidamani. The tomb, adorned with Egyptian-style relief carvings, dates to the second century B.C. &lt;span class=&quot;credits&quot;&gt;(Matt Stirn)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;img class=&quot; lazy&quot; alt=&quot;The largest pyramid at El-Kurru&quot; src=&quot;https://thumbs-prod.si-cdn.com/15jtUXjEzPVPBgKw9jQ_JyykExA=/fit-in/1072x0/https://public-media.si-cdn.com/filer/18/9a/189a418a-3b0a-4616-965a-d441f47ac984/sep2020_b13_sudanpyramids.jpg&quot;/&gt; The largest pyramid at El-Kurru, built around 325 B.C, once stood 115 feet tall. Only its base remains today after it was disassembled during the medieval era to build a nearby fortification wall. &lt;span class=&quot;credits&quot;&gt;(Matt Stirn)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For years, European and American historians and archaeologists viewed ancient Kush through the lens of their own prejudices and that of the times. In the early 20th century, the Harvard Egyptologist George Reisner, on viewing the ruins of the Nubian settlement of Kerma, declared the site an Egyptian outpost. “The native negroid race had never developed either its trade or any industry worthy of mention, and owed their cultural position to the Egyptian immigrants and to the imported Egyptian civilization,” he wrote in an October 1918 bulletin for Boston’s Museum of Fine Arts. It wasn’t until mid-century that sustained excavation and archaeology revealed the truth: Kerma, which dated to as early as 3000 B.C., was the first capital of a powerful indigenous kingdom that expanded to encompass the land between the first cataract of the Nile in the north and the fourth cataract in the south. The kingdom rivaled and at times overtook Egypt. This first Kushite kingdom traded in ivory, gold, bronze, ebony and slaves with neighboring states such as Egypt and ancient Punt, along the Red Sea to the east, and it became famous for its blue glazed pottery and finely polished, tulip-shaped red-brown ceramics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among those who first challenged the received wisdom from Reisner was the Swiss archaeologist Charles Bonnet. It took 20 years for Egyptologists to accept his argument. “Western archaeologists, including Reisner, were trying to find Egypt in Sudan, not Sudan in Sudan,” Bonnet told me. Now 87, Bonnet has returned to Kerma to conduct field research every year since 1970, and has made several significant discoveries that have helped rewrite the region’s ancient history. He identified and excavated a fortified Kushite metropolis nearby, known as Dukki Gel, which dates to the second millennium B.C.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot; lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Inside the tomb of King Tantamani&quot; src=&quot;https://thumbs-prod.si-cdn.com/tGz9WerU0otDnwtgNwJbmPRkSLk=/fit-in/1072x0/https://public-media.si-cdn.com/filer/33/bf/33bfbd74-cc8e-4bb9-9c52-92490d63fa0a/sep2020_b14_sudanpyramids.jpg&quot;/&gt; Inside the tomb of King Tantamani, circa 650 B.C, in El-Kurru, the site of royal burials during Egypt’s 25th Dynasty, when Kush conquered Egypt and initiated the reign of the “Black Pharaohs.”  &lt;span class=&quot;credits&quot;&gt;(Matt Stirn)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;img class=&quot; lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Egyptian-style relief carvings, dates to the second century B.C.&quot; src=&quot;https://thumbs-prod.si-cdn.com/dWXmGmaGpMw59DHMb-EYxmXJF6s=/fit-in/1072x0/https://public-media.si-cdn.com/filer/30/c7/30c7ce55-19a0-404b-8373-0c5072fe8cb8/sep2020_b03_sudanpyramids.jpg&quot;/&gt; Inside a pyramid tomb at Meroe that some archaeologists believe belonged to Kushite King Tanyidamani. The tomb, adorned with Egyptian-style relief carvings, dates to the second century B.C. &lt;span class=&quot;credits&quot;&gt;(Matt Stirn)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around 1500 B.C., Egypt’s pharaohs marched south along the Nile and, after conquering Kerma, established forts and temples, bringing Egyptian culture and religion into Nubia. Near the fourth cataract, the Egyptians built a holy temple at Jebel Barkal, a small flat-topped mountain uniquely situated where the Nile turns southward before turning northward again, forming the letter “S.” It was this place, where the sun is born from the “west” bank—typically associated with sunset and death—that ancient Egyptians believed was the source of Creation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Egyptian rule prevailed in Kush until the 11th century B.C. As Egypt retreated, its empire weakening, a new dynasty of Kushite kings rose in the city of Napata, about 120 miles southeast of Kerma, and asserted itself as the rightful inheritor and protector of ancient Egyptian religion. Piye, Napata’s third king, known more commonly in Sudan as Piankhi, marched north with an army that included horsemen and skilled archers and naval forces that sailed north on the Nile. Defeating a coalition of Egyptian princes, Piye established Egypt’s 25th Dynasty, whose kings are commonly known as the Black Pharaohs. Piye recorded his victory in a 159-line inscription in Middle Egyptian hieroglyphics on a stele of dark gray granite preserved today in the Egyptian Museum in Cairo. He then returned to Napata to rule his newly expanded kingdom, where he revived the Egyptian tradition, which had been dormant for centuries, of entombing kings in pyramids, at a site called El-Kurru.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot; lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Tent camps in the Bayuda Desert&quot; src=&quot;https://thumbs-prod.si-cdn.com/bQnGf4RCgP9P8yalj1B85uVhuzc=/fit-in/1072x0/https://public-media.si-cdn.com/filer/8d/9e/8d9ec1a7-1616-4f84-9358-2b57e69f45e8/sep2020_b08_sudanpyramids.jpg&quot;/&gt; In addition to traditional hotels, tourism companies offer immersive experiences in the Bayuda Desert, allowing travelers to sleep in tent camps like this one, seen at sunrise.  &lt;span class=&quot;credits&quot;&gt;(Matt Stirn)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;img class=&quot; lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Fallen statue of a Kushite king&quot; src=&quot;https://thumbs-prod.si-cdn.com/hfiJdN6jScnJ1pHXst37Xbv3hPE=/fit-in/1072x0/https://public-media.si-cdn.com/filer/90/cf/90cf1eb5-2e60-43eb-9f10-b64e6ef8b07c/sep2020_b07_sudanpyramids.jpg&quot;/&gt; A statue of a Kushite king near Tombos, not far from Kerma, which served as an Egyptian colonial settlement before Kush re-established control over Nubia. The statue retains mystical significance for nearby villagers, who visit for blessings to help with fertility and childbirth. &lt;span class=&quot;credits&quot;&gt;(Matt Stirn)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;img class=&quot; lazy&quot; alt=&quot;local boy &quot; src=&quot;https://thumbs-prod.si-cdn.com/lN4c4gHgbgZ-w-w1Yr7qVDtzmNY=/fit-in/1072x0/https://public-media.si-cdn.com/filer/84/9b/849b24c5-8042-46fc-970e-055c05529385/sep2020_b01_sudanpyramids.jpg&quot;/&gt; Near El-Kurru, a local boy waits for hibiscus tea to serve customers at a roadside teahouse along the remote desert highway connecting Khartoum to Cairo. &lt;span class=&quot;credits&quot;&gt;(Matt Stirn)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of Piye’s sons, Taharqa, known in Sudan as Tirhaka, was mentioned in the Hebrew Bible as an ally of Jerusalem’s King Hezekiah. He moved the royal cemetery to Nuri, 14 miles away, and had a pyra-mid built for himself that is the largest of those erected to honor the Kushite kings. Archaeologists still debate why he moved the royal cemetery. Geoff Emberling, an archaeologist at the University of Michigan who has excavated at El-Kurru and Jebel Barkal, told me that one explanation focusing on Kushite ritual is that Taharqa situated his tomb so that “the sun rose over the pyramid at the moment when the Nile flooding is supposed to have arrived.” But there are other explanations. “There might have been a political split,” he said. “Both explanations might be true.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Black Pharaohs’ rule of Egypt lasted for nearly a century, but Taharqa lost control of Egypt to invading Assyrians. Beginning in the sixth century B.C., when Napata was repeatedly threatened by attack from Egyptians, Persians and Romans, the kings of Kush gradually moved their capital south to Meroe. The city, at the junction of several important trade routes in a region rich in iron and other precious metals, became a bridge between Africa and the Mediterranean, and it grew prosperous. “They took on influences from outside—Egyptian influences, Greco-Roman influences, but also influences from Africa. And they formed their very own ideas, their own architecture and arts,” says Arnulf Schlüter, of the State Museum of Egyptian Art in Munich.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot; lazy&quot; alt=&quot;The Nubian Rest House&quot; src=&quot;https://thumbs-prod.si-cdn.com/fggVmNpJ1m0yDrEjs2bNC0OBtsc=/fit-in/1072x0/https://public-media.si-cdn.com/filer/67/ea/67eacf65-5fdb-40e0-9954-4d604e2899c2/sep2020_b12_sudanpyramids.jpg&quot;/&gt; The Nubian Rest House, near Jebel Barkal. For years, Kushite sites throughout Sudan remained little visited, but the overthrow of authoritarian President Omar al-Bashir energized a nascent tourism industry. &lt;span class=&quot;credits&quot;&gt;(Matt Stirn)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;img class=&quot; lazy&quot; alt=&quot;A nomadic family&quot; src=&quot;https://thumbs-prod.si-cdn.com/zTGZY0qMblUx97lZeX8zL9UsFVo=/fit-in/1072x0/https://public-media.si-cdn.com/filer/54/a9/54a9b883-3c5e-44ef-94b4-c7242e2e8d7c/sep2020_b04_sudanpyramids.jpg&quot;/&gt; A nomadic family prepares to set off into the Bayuda Desert, in the eastern Sahara. In Kushite times, a caravan route through this desert connected Napata in the north to Meroe in the south.  &lt;span class=&quot;credits&quot;&gt;(Matt Stirn)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pyramids in Meroe, which was named a Unesco World Heritage site in 2011, are undoubtedly the most striking feature here. While they are not as old or as large as the pyramids in Egypt, they are unique in that they are steeper, and they were not all dedicated to royals; nobles (at least those who could afford it) came to be buried in pyramids as well. Many Sudanese today are quick to point out that the number of standing ancient pyramids in the country—more than 200—exceeds the number of those in Egypt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Across from the pyramids is the royal city, with surrounding grounds that are still covered in slag, evidence of the city’s large iron-smelting industry and a source of its economic power. Queens called by the title &lt;em&gt;Kandake&lt;/em&gt;, known in Latin as “Candace,” played a vital role in Meroitic political life. The most famous of them was Amanirenas, a warrior-queen who ruled Kush from roughly 40 B.C. to 10 B.C. Described by the Greek geographer Strabo, who mistook her title for her name, as “a masculine sort of woman, and blind in one eye,” she led an army to fight off the Romans to the north and returned with a bronze statue head of Emperor Augustus, which she then buried in Meroe beneath the steps to a temple dedicated to victory. In the town of Naga, where Schlüter does much of his work, another &lt;em&gt;kandake&lt;/em&gt;, Amanitore, who ruled from about 1 B.C. to A.D. 25, is portrayed beside her co-regent, King Natakamani, on the entrance-gate wall of a temple dedicated to the indigenous lion god Apedemak; they are depicted slaying their enemies—Amanitore with a long sword, Natakamani with a battle-ax—while lions rest symbolically at their feet. Many scholars believe that Amanitore’s successor, Amantitere, is the Kushite queen referred to as “Candace, queen of the Ethiopians” in the New Testament, whose treasurer converted to Christianity and traveled to Jerusalem to worship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot; lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Sufi graves of Kerma&quot; src=&quot;https://thumbs-prod.si-cdn.com/u9PdG8q3KER9YxR7jaH_M2PDfXI=/fit-in/1072x0/https://public-media.si-cdn.com/filer/15/12/15121084-6f01-4df2-8634-e58ff57c027f/sep2020_b05_sudanpyramids.jpg&quot;/&gt; Sufi graves from the 17th century near the medieval city of Old Dongola. The style of the burials, adorned with white pebbles and marked by black stones, can be traced to the pre-Islamic city of Kerma, from the third millennium B.C., indicating the continuity of Nubian ritual traditions. &lt;span class=&quot;credits&quot;&gt;(Matt Stirn)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;img class=&quot; lazy&quot; alt=&quot;A fort built by Ottoman forces near the Nile River&quot; src=&quot;https://thumbs-prod.si-cdn.com/vx6z1YcYgYm4cK6kOiG8DrXBIj8=/fit-in/1072x0/https://public-media.si-cdn.com/filer/72/ae/72ae8b2e-3157-467d-a7ba-e4f460c7a318/sep2020_b09_sudanpyramids.jpg&quot;/&gt; A fort built by Ottoman forces near the Nile River’s third cataract, not far from Tombos and Kerma. Ottoman Egypt conquered much of modern Sudan in 1820, which it ruled until 1885. &lt;span class=&quot;credits&quot;&gt;(Matt Stirn)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At another site not far away, Musawwarat es-Sufra, archaeologists still wonder about the purpose that a large central sandstone complex, known as the Great Enclosure, might have served. It dates to the third century B.C., and includes columns, gardens, ramps and courtyards. Some scholars have theorized that it was a temple, others a palace or a university, or even a camp to train elephants for use in battle, because of the elephant statues and engravings found throughout the complex. There is nothing in the Nile Valley to compare it to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the fourth century A.D., the power of Kush began to wane. Historians give different explanations for this, including climate change-driven drought and famine and the rise of a rival civilization in the east, Aksum, in modern-day Ethiopia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For years, Kush’s history and contributions to world civilization were largely ignored. Early European archaeologists were unable to see it as more than a reflection of Egypt. Political instability, neglect and underdevelopment in Sudan prevented adequate research into the country’s ancient history. Yet the legacy of Kush is important because of its distinctive cultural achievements and civilization: it had its own language and script; an economy based on trade and skilled work; a well-known expertise in archery; an agricultural model that allowed for raising cattle; and a distinctive cuisine featuring foods that reflected the local environment, such as milk, millet and dates. It was a society organized differently from its neighbors in Egypt, the Levant and Mesopotamia, with unique city planning and powerful female royals. “At its height, the Kingdom of Kush was a dominant regional power,” says Zeinab Badawi, a distinguished British-Sudanese journalist whose documentary series “The History of Africa” aired on the BBC earlier this year. Kush’s surviving archaeological remains “reveal a fascinating and uncelebrated ancient people the world has forgotten.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot; lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Tent camp at sunrise&quot; src=&quot;https://thumbs-prod.si-cdn.com/rNIgFlODpKwf-5-okujeAPdYykA=/fit-in/1072x0/https://public-media.si-cdn.com/filer/7d/6e/7d6e6927-1732-4f22-95f1-3635500dd5de/sep2020_b06_sudanpyramids.jpg&quot;/&gt; In addition to traditional hotels, tourism companies offer immersive experiences in the Bayuda Desert, allowing travelers to sleep in tent camps like this one, seen at sunrise. &lt;span class=&quot;credits&quot;&gt;(Matt Stirn)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Egypt has long been explained in light of its connections to the Near East and the Mediterranean, Kush makes clear the role that black Africans played in an interconnected ancient world. Kush was “at the root of black African civilizations, and for a long time scholars and the general public berated its achievements,” Geoff Emberling told me. Edmund Barry Gaither, an American educator and director of Boston’s Museum of the National Center of Afro-American Artists, says that “Nubia gave black people their own place at the table, even if it did not banish racist detractors.” The French archaeologist Claude Rilly put it to me this way: “Just as Europeans look at ancient Greece symbolically as their father or mother, Africans can look at Kush as their great ancestor.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, many do. In Sudan, where 30 years of authoritarian rule ended in 2019 after months of popular protests, a new generation is looking to their history to find national pride. Among the most popular chants by protesters were those invoking Kushite rulers of millennia past: “My grandfather is Tirhaka! My grandmother is a Kandake!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intisar Soghayroun, an archaeologist and a member of Sudan’s transitional government, says that rediscovering the country’s ancient roots helped fuel the calls for change. “The people were frustrated with the present, so they started looking into their past,” she told me. “That was the moment of revolution.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 14:53:42 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pseudolus</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://thumbs-prod.si-cdn.com/Ff9Izzf2fa46zVy8qgH8ivEFEtc=/fit-in/1600x0/https://public-media.si-cdn.com/filer/1b/20/1b205e98-4c95-4d82-a053-5bc6e8d34c65/sudan_opener_socialmedia.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Why Sudan's Remarkable Ancient Civilization Has Been Overlooked by History</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/travel/sudan-land-kush-meroe-ancient-civilization-overlooked-180975498/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>The African nation's pyramids and other archaeological sites are only now emerging from the shadow of its more storied neighbor to the north</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/travel/sudan-land-kush-meroe-ancient-civilization-overlooked-180975498/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Moving from YouTube to PeerTube</title>
<link>https://battlepenguin.com/tech/moving-from-youtube-to-peertube/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://battlepenguin.com/tech/moving-from-youtube-to-peertube/</guid>
<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://battlepenguin.com/images/tech/peertube/500px-Sepia.svg.png&quot; alt=&quot;Sepia, Peertube's mascot&quot;/&gt; Sepia, Peertube's mascot
&lt;p&gt;Back when I first started posting videos, I used Vimeo. Even though YouTube was the dominant video site, I wanted to support the underdog. I even bought a Vimeo Pro account. At the time, Vimeo had higher quality video than YouTube, but nowhere near the level of discoverability. Eventually I started posting on YouTube; both new content and some reposts of my older videos. It’s 2020 and YouTube, as well as the rest of big tech, is continuing to &lt;a href=&quot;https://battlepenguin.com/politics/twitter-is-trying-to-erase-the-past/&quot;&gt;remove content&lt;/a&gt; they don’t agree with from their platforms. None of &lt;a href=&quot;https://battlepenguin.com/videos/&quot;&gt;my videos&lt;/a&gt; have ever gotten a large number of views, and none are monetized, so I might as well copy them to a PeerTube instance I control. If you do run a YouTube channel with any type of significant viewership, I highly recommend backing up your videos, in the event you may need to self-host your content in the future.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’m not rehosting everything I’ve posted on Vimeo or YouTube. I’m starting with all the videos that are featured on &lt;a href=&quot;https://battlepenguin.com/tech/a-history-of-personal-and-professional-websites/&quot;&gt;my website&lt;/a&gt;, so I can replace the embedded clips, and point them to my self-hosted PeerTube instance on &lt;a href=&quot;https://battlepenguin.video&quot;&gt;battlepenguin.video&lt;/a&gt;. I’m keeping links to other video platforms in the video descriptions and in my own blog posts. I’m not changing any of the descriptions for existing videos, but newer uploads to YouTube will have a link to my PeerTube mirror.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://battlepenguin.com/images/tech/peertube/ip-addr-screen.png&quot; alt=&quot;Warning on a PeerTube video embed about IP sharing&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://battlepenguin.com/tech/video/upgrading-the-ssd-on-an-msi-gs60-laptop/&quot;&gt;Warning on a PeerTube video embed about IP sharing&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An embedded PeerTube video comes with a warning, because when you watch one of these videos using the web player, you may also be serving that video to other audience members watching it at the same time. PeerTube does this using technologies such as WebTorrent and WebRTC. In theory, this can help PeerTube scale without expensive centralized servers. As a video becomes more popular, other viewers use their web browsers and Internet connections to help distribute the content they’re consuming. This is one of the trade-offs between privacy and decentralization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PeerTube can also communicate to other servers via ActivityPub, allowing people to subscribe to a video channel from other PeerTube instances, or other servers running Mastodon, Pleroma or other ActivityPub compatible software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;subtitles&quot;&gt;Subtitles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YouTube has a feature where you can upload a text document of a video transcription and YouTube will attempt to automatically time-code that text as subtitles. It’s important to write out transcripts whenever you can, to make content accessible for those with hearing disabilities. PeerTube supports subtitles in both the VTT and SRT. YouTube allows creators to download subtitles in several formats, or the &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtube-dl.org/&quot;&gt;youtube-dl&lt;/a&gt; application can be used to download subtitles from videos using the option &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;--all-subs&lt;/code&gt; as seen below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;sh_sourceCode&quot;&gt;
youtube-dl --all-subs --skip-download 'https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=&amp;lt;video_id&amp;gt;'
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://battlepenguin.com/images/tech/peertube/yt-subtitles.png&quot; alt=&quot;Download Subtitles through the YouTube Web Interface&quot;/&gt; Download Subtitles through the YouTube Web Interface
&lt;h3 id=&quot;hosting-with-docker&quot;&gt;Hosting with Docker&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use the official PeerTube container published by chocobozzz. It’s provisioned using my custom Docker tool, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sumdog/bee2&quot;&gt;Bee2&lt;/a&gt;. I adapted it from the project’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Chocobozzz/PeerTube/tree/develop/support/docker/production&quot;&gt;example docker-compose file&lt;/a&gt;. The example doesn’t contain all the configuration options that can be set, but you can find the others in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Chocobozzz/PeerTube/blob/develop/support/docker/production/config/custom-environment-variables.yaml&quot;&gt;custom-environment-variables.yaml&lt;/a&gt; schema file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;sh_sourceCode sh_makefile&quot;&gt;
...
peertube:
  image: chocobozzz/peertube:v2.2.0-buster
  networks:
    - public
    - database
  traefik:
    http:
      hosts:
        - battlepenguin.video
      tls: enabled
      port: 9000
  labels:
    lb.net: public
  env:
    PEERTUBE_REDIS_HOSTNAME: $peertube-redis
    PEERTUBE_DB_USERNAME: peertube
    PEERTUBE_DB_PASSWORD: _postgres^password
    POSTGRES_DB: peertube
    PEERTUBE_DB_HOSTNAME: $postgres
    PEERTUBE_WEBSERVER_HOSTNAME: battlepenguin.video
    PEERTUBE_SMTP_USERNAME: ****
    PEERTUBE_SMTP_PASSWORD: ****
    PEERTUBE_SMTP_HOSTNAME: ****
    PEERTUBE_SMTP_PORT: ****
    PEERTUBE_SMTP_TLS: true
    PEERTUBE_SMTP_FROM: ****
    PEERTUBE_ADMIN_EMAIL: ****
    PEERTUBE_SIGNUP_ENABLED: false
    PEERTUBE_TRANSCODING_ENABLED: true
    PEERTUBE_CONTACT_FORM_ENABLED: true
    PEERTUBE_INSTANCE_NAME: &quot;BattlePenguin Studios&quot;
    PEERTUBE_INSTANCE_DESCRIPTION: &quot;Videos for BattlePenguin.com&quot;
  volumes:
    - peertube_data:/data:rw
    - peertube_config:/config:rw
  db:
    - postgres
peertube-redis:
  networks:
    - database
  image: redis:6.0.5-alpine
  volumes:
    - peertube-redis:/data
...
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;promotion&quot;&gt;Promotion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I’m still uploading videos to YouTube, there is the question of which video do I promote? Do I use a YouTube link, or a PeerTube link? I’ve been doing a mix of the two for recent videos, splitting the difference between various social media platforms. Linking to YouTube helps feed their algorithms and can help generate greater viewership outside of my sphere of influence, but it does direct more traffic towards Google services instead of my own server. I don’t post a lot of videos, my viewership is small and I don’t have any big stakes in the attention economy, so I’ll probably be experimenting with both forms of promotion for the foreseeable future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-big-dogs&quot;&gt;The Big Dogs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some big channels that make a large chunk of of their income from YouTube ads, with other coming from paid promotion, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.patreon.com/bePatron?u=4777528&quot;&gt;fan support&lt;/a&gt; and merchandise. Besides the obvious costs of time investment and hosting, mirroring content outside of YouTube might eat up a non-trivial amount of advertising income. It makes more sense for someone just starting out to host their own content, than a creator who is entrenched in the YouTube world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, self-hosting might also be the only alternative, if Google decides to ban you from their platform. Content creators should have backups, and have plans ready to go, in the event their content is deemed to no longer be acceptable by YouTube. If you don’t have original copies if all your videos, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;youtube-dl&lt;/code&gt; can be used to download entire channels. PeerTube is just one of many open source tools that content creators should look at and evaluate, in order to prepare for a time when your channel, or YouTube as a whole, disappears.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 12:48:39 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>djsumdog</dc:creator>
<og:title>Moving from YouTube to PeerTube</og:title>
<og:url>https://battlepenguin.com/tech/moving-from-youtube-to-peertube</og:url>
<og:image>https://battlepenguin.com/images/tech/peertube/500px-Sepia.svg.png</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://battlepenguin.com/tech/moving-from-youtube-to-peertube/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Startup mistakes: Lessons from failed startups</title>
<link>https://www.failory.com/blog/startup-mistakes</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.failory.com/blog/startup-mistakes</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;blog-rich-text w-richtext&quot; readability=&quot;134.91106662854&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I got invited to do a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.failory.com/interview/dotahaven&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“failed startup” interview&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; at Failory, naturally, I went over their website to check out what they’re all about. As I was between projects and in the process of going over the &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@KyrilKotashev/5-lessons-from-2-failed-startups-fda090d9b278&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lessons of my own ventures&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the opportunity to read about the first-hand experience of other failed founders, my peers, came just at the right time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I did what any other person totally irresponsible with their time would do: I spent the next three to four days reading every single one of the 80+ failed startup interviews and taking notes in a spreadsheet. When I did this I tried to see if some of the mistakes and lessons are mentioned over and over again, and in this article, I’ll present my findings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disclaimer: the interviews are qualitative, even though the founders were asked similar questions, they weren’t asked to fill out a survey, so to gather the “data” I had to interpret their words and put them into boxes. This means mistakes and oversights on my part are likely and you shouldn’t take the data, as presented, too seriously. Nonetheless, I still think the takeaways ought to be useful for anyone embarking on a startup journey.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5966ea9b9217ca534caf13d5/5f3d6e59b68408f0441abb2a_4zNLLzIl6TLtHtu4Nu47Gk-wCh2mvRoX01oo5fBLzvVCuujknN3htsgzmfiI-IeY0TdISqErUYNzMsA4AtvqBXzn7kjPkqFoappd0BaxUqDWTzx3pZWNEylPK3iyMl1Sg2PPY48M.png&quot; alt=&quot;Startup Mistakes&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the interviews, all startups are asked to mention the major reason the project failed. Of course, over the length of the interview, the founders also talk about all other kinds of mistakes they made and problems they ran into which contributed to the failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This allowed me to take all of the mentioned mistakes, put them into their respective box (marketing, team, tech, etc.), and divide them into fatal and non-fatal. This lead to a couple of interesting findings:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol role=&quot;list&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marketing&lt;/strong&gt; mistakes were by far the most common, and they were generally speaking the most deadly with 69% of all mentioned marketing mistakes being fatal. In fact, the fatal marketing mistakes were more numerous than all other fatal mistakes combined (56% vs 44%), as can be seen in the pie chart below. By far the most common reason for shutdown was lack of product-market-fit which constituted more than half of the marketing mistakes, but more on that below.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5966ea9b9217ca534caf13d5/5f3d6e5aa0fe082c0cad1fed_rl5cMUQ0CH18NV2_aTgksG1jF4mtvZTwLSXlRsnxoKVrLRg8ySH4pYRdwtj6gLzqaZ9-Ho_7ve8HXdTZtdu7cj452W4ZVe6GfI9-B6zAPzxvbYr0T6YorYMtATolchfoyetOQjD1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Reasons for Startup Failure&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;2&quot; role=&quot;list&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team&lt;/strong&gt; problems – friction, lack of experience, lack of motivation, etc., were the second most common. They were some of the least-deadly percentage-wise (only 39% of all mentioned team problems being fatal), but because they are abundant they were still the second most common reason for shutdown.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Financial&lt;/strong&gt; problems and mistakes were the third most common. That said, bearing in mind more than 50% of the projects didn’t have any budget to begin with and more than 75% of the projects were self-funded, it’s a surprise that only 16% of the projects point at financial problems as the major reason for failure.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5966ea9b9217ca534caf13d5/5f3d6e5a37f62152539c0660_X0-yxs8pFq61skGbW2j3bclFBk5jSHDYmEO-uMKHOUBBUp5Rr9tXzTJSYclv1mar4w7X6Tb8ieSJ0ttOsfp-C-iWVRT8gikedMH6kwtjJWbCvXCv6f9lWz0Q_rG9nd4NHmaxRWFM.png&quot; alt=&quot;Startup Funding&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;4&quot; role=&quot;list&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tech&lt;/strong&gt; problems were extremely rare, which is surprising considering almost all projects in the data have a technical side to them. The most common remark was that too much time and effort was spent on tech that proved to be useless in the long run. The most common answer to “a thing you would do differently next time” by far was “I’d talk to customers and validate my assumptions before writing a single line of code”. That said, a big % of tech problems were fatal: e.g. relying on a 3rd party API that changes can ruin a business overnight.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Operational&lt;/strong&gt; problems were quite rare and not that deadly, but it’s important to mention that most interviewees ran software projects, so operational problems (e.g. suppliers, distribution) are not as common as in brick-and-mortar and physical product projects by definition.&lt;strong&gt;‍&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Legal&lt;/strong&gt; problems were rarest, mentioned only four times, but two of those four proved to be lethal. For most early-stage startups the legal side is a non-factor. Yet, there are still industries where you can’t afford to ignore it (food, finance, etc.).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Marketing Lessons&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned, marketing problems were both the most abundant and the most deadly. 46 out of 83 startups mentioned a marketing problem as the main reason for the failure of the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Product-market fit:&lt;/strong&gt; 29 out of these 46 were talking about what boils down to lack of product-market fit. 29 out of the 83 projects essentially created something that they later found out no one needed. Unsurprisingly, the most commonly mentioned lesson by far was that you need to validate if the market actually needs what you are offering. Ideally, you need to do it before you invest any considerable amount of effort, time, or capital into the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Competition&lt;/strong&gt; was the second most common marketing problem, but while it was mentioned by 8 startups, it was singled out as the reason for failure only twice (25% fatality rate). 2 out of 83 is quite low, but this doesn’t come as a big surprise. Startup projects are by definition at least partially innovative, and this innovation serves as a form of differentiation. Competition becomes a factor much later in the startup journey, and some form of competition early on is even a good sign: third-party validation that there is demand for something close to what you are offering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Value-added:&lt;/strong&gt; this was a rare mention (two times mentioned, both fatal), but it relates to competition. A common “competitor” of an innovative startup is the current most popular solution to the problem the project is trying to address. This doesn’t even have to be another company – it could be whatever people are currently doing to solve it. If your product/service doesn’t add enough value, people will simply stick to their current solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;User retention:&lt;/strong&gt; again, related to the point above. If your product/service is something cool and shiny, it is likely to attract visitors. But unless it provides real value (solves a problem), you will lose your audience right away – your marketing efforts are simply wasted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Market size:&lt;/strong&gt; even though startup investors very commonly talk about market size, this is because they are chasing Unicorns, not lifestyle businesses. As a founder, however, &lt;strong&gt;a working lifestyle business is not a bad thing to have&lt;/strong&gt;. A small market was mentioned only once as the reason for failure. In reality, even small niche markets are usually enough to sustain at least a single company (thanks to the internet).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lack of focus&lt;/strong&gt; is the last marketing mistake worth mentioning. Often startups have a vision of some grand platform with amazing capabilities and features addressing multiple problems at once. In reality, however, as a startup you simply don’t have the resources to build so much complexity. Even if you do, it’s very likely to turn out most of the features you are envisioning aren’t needed in the first place. A startup is much more likely to succeed if it’s hyper-focused in as many ways as possible. First of all, focused on solving very well a single, well-defined problem for a single, well-defined market. Second, focused in terms of technology (one simple, lean solution) and third - marketing (a single channel that works).&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;newsletter-pop-up&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph-6&quot;&gt;We're publishing articles like this one all weeks. Submit your email if you want to receive them in your inbox + get 80+ deals on tools to help you scale your startup (worth up to $50,000)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;w-embed w-script&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sib-form&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;sib-form-container&quot; class=&quot;sib-form-container&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;error-message&quot; class=&quot;sib-form-message-panel&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sib-form-message-panel__inner-text&quot;&gt;Your subscription could not be saved. Please try again.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;success-message&quot; class=&quot;sib-form-message-panel&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sib-form-message-panel__inner-text&quot;&gt;Your subscription has been successful.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.failory.com/get/genm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;between-ad-div w-inline-block w-clearfix&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5966ea9a9217ca534caf139f/5cfbd0c30e47857f5459cf92_GenM%20Icon.png&quot; width=&quot;40&quot; srcset=&quot;https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5966ea9a9217ca534caf139f/5cfbd0c30e47857f5459cf92_GenM%20Icon-p-500.png 500w, https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5966ea9a9217ca534caf139f/5cfbd0c30e47857f5459cf92_GenM%20Icon.png 512w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;between-ad-image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;between-ad-text&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;between-ad-bold&quot;&gt;Hire digital marketing interns.&lt;/span&gt; 40 hours for $49/month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn More!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;between-ad-ad&quot;&gt;AD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;place-your-ad-interview&quot; readability=&quot;17.767175572519&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;heading-place-your-ad-interview&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reach +20,000 Startup Founders!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph-place-yur-ad-interview&quot;&gt;If you are looking to get your product in front of founders, CEOs, VPs, web and mobile developers, makers, consultants, marketers, bloggers, product managers, and many other thought leaders, then we can help you.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.failory.com/sponsors&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;button-place-your-ad-interview w-button&quot;&gt;👉 Sponsorships&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;lead-magnet&quot; class=&quot;lead-magnet w-condition-invisible&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;w-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;center-column w-col w-col-5&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.failory.com/blog/startup-mistakes&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;image-lead-magnet w-dyn-bind-empty&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;w-col w-col-7&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;lead-magnet-title w-dyn-bind-empty&quot;/&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;w-embed&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;w-clearfix w-form&quot; readability=&quot;8.5&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;newsletter-success-message w-form-done&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you. Check your inbox :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;newsletter-error-message w-form-fail&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oops! Something went wrong while submitting the form. Try again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;blog-rich-text w-richtext&quot; readability=&quot;113.63890441587&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Finance Mistakes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An early-stage startup doesn’t need money, it needs time and effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, this is an exaggeration, but it’s closer to the truth than you’d think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The typical expensive thing in most startups is the dev time. Yet, expensive technology is only important to scale something up and automate it, not to test it. To validate a concept, you can often use no-code (or low code) solutions combined with some manual effort (e.g. a no-code/low-code website and a dude with an excel sheet and an email).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This, of course, is applicable only early on in the life of the startup when you have few clients/users. But going this route will protect you from losing time and money on the wrong thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Funding:&lt;/strong&gt; That’s the main reason that even though 77% of the interviewee projects were bootstrapped and around 50% didn’t have any funding, only 2 out of 83 projects pointed at “lack of sufficient funding” as the reason for the failure of the project. In many cases, the founders understood that if they had a bigger budget, they’d simply lose more money. Funding is only important when the startup starts graduating into a real business and needs to grow, and even then only when it’s going the rapping growth rather than sustainable growth (lifestyle business) route. (The disclaimer here is that you shouldn’t mistake a startup with a new but traditional business, which usually requires initial funding.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monetization:&lt;/strong&gt; the most common financial problem is monetization, and arguably monetization is more of a marketing/business plan issue rather than a financial one. Figuring out how you’re going to make money from the thing you have is a good idea. If no one is willing to pay, you have a problem. That’s one of the reasons why B2B projects are often less risky than B2C projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Profit margins&lt;/strong&gt; were also mentioned as a problem from 5 businesses, 3 of which pointed at it as fatal. This is very dependent on the type of business and the market saturation. E.g. in food startups you are competing with a lot of traditional solutions, where profit margins are razor-thin, which is an unfavorable environment for a non-optimized innovative solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overspending and cashflow&lt;/strong&gt; are the two most important problems you need to keep in mind when it comes to finances for startups, especially once you start making money. Over-hiring too early is generally speaking a big mistake and could easily ruin an otherwise very promising business. Early in the life of the company, it’s important to keep the overheads as low as possible (founder living expenses + servers). You can outsource anything else you need (freelancers, agencies). This gives you the flexibility to cut back on spending almost instantly if you suddenly hit a bump and keep the business alive, giving you more time to iterate and solve the problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Team Mistakes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;w-embed w-script&quot; readability=&quot;5.0192307692308&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; readability=&quot;4.1826923076923&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Above “product-market fit” is “founder-product-market fit.”&lt;/p&gt;
— Naval (@naval) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/naval/status/946276788111470592?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;December 28, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Experience:&lt;/strong&gt; lack of it is one of the most common problems in startups. 20 out of the 83 interviewees mentioned it, 9 pointed at it as the major reason for failure. Usually, lack of experience means a couple of different things, however:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol role=&quot;list&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lack of domain knowledge:&lt;/em&gt; You need to know well the market you’re targeting. If you don’t, it’s your first order of business to talk to potential customers and rapidly learn about it before you build anything. Almost always fatal if you don’t. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lack of marketing knowledge:&lt;/em&gt; How to reach your customers, keep them engaged, grow the business. A very common cause of failure for tech-only founder teams. A good marketer is absolutely vital for a startup and one of the founders needs to take this role early on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lack of technical knowledge: If you have a technical product, it’s a no-brainer that you need a good technical person. If you don’t, you’ll simply fail to build a good product. That said, early in the life of a startup keeping the tech side as lean and agile as possible is vital. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lack of business knowledge: Bad business/startup decisions can easily invalidate all your efforts and ruin the business, but this is easiest to overcome. This problem is solvable by taking on a mentor or at least learning from the mistakes of others from resources like the one you’re reading.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friction:&lt;/strong&gt; the second most common team problem (9 mentions), but fatal only 2 times. That said, even if it’s not fatal, it makes things much more difficult than they have to be. Some people recommend not to start a business with a person before you know them well enough and before you know you share the same vision. Otherwise, you’ll pull the project in different directions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Motivation:&lt;/strong&gt; the quote from Naval Ravikant from above doesn’t simply mean that the founders need to know their market and product well. It also means that they need to be excited about working on the problem, or lack of motivation could mean the slow death of the project (mentioned 6 times, fatal twice).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Availability:&lt;/strong&gt; working on a startup requires a lot of time and effort, and if the founders don’t have it it’s very hard to make progress in good time. The big common mistake here is when the founders have different levels of availability (e.g. one founder works on the startup full-time, the other part-time). This naturally leads to friction and loss of motivation.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;block-ad-div&quot; readability=&quot;13.127725856698&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;black-text&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your one-stop shop for everything dev-related.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;black-text&quot;&gt;Anything you need, our devs can build: complex e-commerce solutions, custom software or SaaS, beautiful WordPress websites… anything. We’ll fix, upgrade &amp;amp; customize your website, so you never have to worry about troubleshooting web stuff ever again.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://nerdpilots.com/?ref=failory&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;ad-block-button-nerdpilots w-button&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let’s get to work!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.failory.com/get/growthmentor&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;between-ad-div w-inline-block w-clearfix&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5966ea9a9217ca534caf139f/5cfbd8cc0e478567d159ea3b_GrowthMentor%20Icon.png&quot; width=&quot;40&quot; srcset=&quot;https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5966ea9a9217ca534caf139f/5cfbd8cc0e478567d159ea3b_GrowthMentor%20Icon-p-500.png 500w, https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5966ea9a9217ca534caf139f/5cfbd8cc0e478567d159ea3b_GrowthMentor%20Icon.png 512w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;between-ad-image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;between-ad-text&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;between-ad-bold&quot;&gt;Grow your business.&lt;/span&gt; Get 1-on-1 calls with +100 mentors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn More!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;between-ad-ad&quot;&gt;AD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;blog-rich-text w-richtext&quot; readability=&quot;160.60833206629&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Tech Mistakes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the most valuable marketing concept for a startup is “validation”, the most valuable technical concept is MVP (minimal viable product). You need to create a product that allows you to find a market with the absolute bare minimum time and effort investment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often the right solution is to take this concept to absolute extremes. If your grand vision is about a platform with 50 features solving 5 problems, the MVP is NOT a platform with 25 features. It’s probably not even a platform, but a static website imitating the 2-3 most important features (with cheats like manual labor) and allowing you to test them and see how customers like them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned in the findings at the top of the article, the most common and fatal tech mistake isn’t even connected to tech: it’s over-investing your time and effort into building something cool before making sure someone needs it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tech people love to build stuff, they don’t love to sell stuff. And initially, you usually need to do 10% building and 90% talking to customers and selling. Later on, it becomes 50% building and 50% selling. But it never, under no circumstances becomes 90% building and 10% selling, because this is when you lose your connection with reality and as a result – you waste your time and efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for real tech mistakes, the most commonly fatal ones are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol role=&quot;list&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;You lack the skill and experience to do the complicated technical thing you are aiming to do. The solution is to bring in someone more experienced, simplifying the thing you’re trying to build.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are tied to a tech solution outside of your control: e.g. you have a business relying on Instagram’s API. If Instagram changes its API, this will lead to the death of your business. This, however, is a risk that is often worth taking, but you should still account for it in your plans.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Operations &amp;amp; Legal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Operational problems were relatively rare (mentioned 9 times in total, only two fatal) and too case-specific to generalize. However, the disclaimer here is that most of the interviewees were running a software business, which means that operational problems are rare by definition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Legal problems were also very rare, but when they appeared they were often deadly. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Operational and legal considerations are very industry and location-specific, so make not to follow general advice before doing some case-specific research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All startups were asked “what would you do differently”, and even though there are a lot of case-specific lessons, one them was repeated over and over: &lt;strong&gt;lean&lt;/strong&gt; startup as a concept was mentioned by 27 of the startups as the most important lesson learned the hard way. This means approximately one-third of all interviewed &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lean: validation –&lt;/strong&gt; talk to customers, test your assumptions, and find a market before you invest a considerable amount of time, effort, and money into an idea. Mentioned directly 20 times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lean: MVP –&lt;/strong&gt; build your prototype (the thing you’d use to test the market) as quickly and cheaply as possible. Iterate often. Mentioned directly 14 times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not a surprise that &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2Yd7DYH&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Lean Startup&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; book is one of the most commonly mentioned resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here are a couple of other lessons that get repeated more than once:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Risk:&lt;/strong&gt; startups are very risky. Investors diversify by investing in multiple startups, but as a founder you don’t have that luxury. This means that you are very, very likely to fail. Make sure you can bear that failure financially, psychologically, etc. E.g. financing a startup idea with a loan is generally speaking a terrible idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Personal wellbeing:&lt;/strong&gt; a business is not a good cause for martyrdom. Being a startup founder by definition means things would be very rough professionally for a long time period. Make sure that outside of the professional realm you are doing OK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team and experience:&lt;/strong&gt; make sure your team ticks the right boxes. If you are a builder, not a marketer, make sure there is a co-founder who will do the marketing tasks well and the other way around. The cliché is that a successful startup team needs a hustler (marketer), a hacker (builder), and a hipster. I don’t know about the hipster, but you will certainly fail without the hustler or hacker, and it’s very hard to be both. A startup team also needs at least some experience running a risky project. If you don’t have any, getting a mentor is a great idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Failure is not the end:&lt;/strong&gt; you’d be surprised how much of the interviewed failed startup founders are currently running another at least somewhat successful venture. Another chunk found a good job because of the skills acquired in the project. With every failed attempt, your competence and chances of success increase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The projects are all failed startups Failory were able to get their hands on, so they are reasonably random. Yet, this doesn’t mean all types of startups have a good representation in the data:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than 75% of the 84 startups are self-funded (or at least don’t mention outside investors). Moreover, over 50% of the interviewed startups invested only the time of the founders in the venture and if possible reinvested revenue (which in a few rare occasions was quite considerable). Only 46% had a budget to work with from the start, ranging from $3-4k to $4.4 million in the highest VC example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, &lt;strong&gt;those conditions are very common for projects in the idea-validation-traction phases&lt;/strong&gt;, which is where most projects die and where the lessons from above are most applicable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s important to mention yet again, that &lt;strong&gt;most interviewees were developing&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;software&lt;/strong&gt; products or services. Physical products are much rarer in the data. This means that the &lt;strong&gt;mistakes and lessons of physical product projects are underrepresented&lt;/strong&gt;. For example, even though supplier problems are very common for physical product projects, they are not common at all in this dataset simply because software projects generally don’t have suppliers. This shouldn’t lead you to believe that supplier problems aren’t important if you’re selling anything physical. Use your common sense and learn from the experience of the projects closest to your own, don’t trust the data and my interpretations blindly!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;--&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading! Hopefully, the failures of the 80+ projects thanks to whom we were able to define these common mistakes were not in vain and would be used to prevent further failures by entrepreneurs like yourself!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have enjoyed this post, make sure to subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest content ;)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;cta-subscribe-blog&quot;&gt;✉️ Subscribe to our newsletter!&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph-subscribe-blog&quot;&gt;Invite us into your inbox and get immense learning and &lt;strong class=&quot;white-text&quot;&gt;80+ deals on tools&lt;/strong&gt; to help you scale your startup (&lt;strong class=&quot;white-text&quot;&gt;worth up to $50,000&lt;/strong&gt;)!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;div-block-sendinblue-form-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;w-embed w-script&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sib-form&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;sib-form-container&quot; class=&quot;sib-form-container&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;error-message&quot; class=&quot;sib-form-message-panel&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sib-form-message-panel__inner-text&quot;&gt;Your subscription could not be saved. Please try again.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;success-message&quot; class=&quot;sib-form-message-panel&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sib-form-message-panel__inner-text&quot;&gt;Your subscription has been successful.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 12:36:38 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mitchbob</dc:creator>
<og:title>Startup Mistakes: First-Hand Lessons from 80+ Failed Startups</og:title>
<og:description>We've analyzed why +80 startups have failed and identified some of their common mistakes. Here're our findings!</og:description>
<og:image>https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5966ea9b9217ca534caf13d5/5f3d7389161c0cdc27f03961_Startup%20Mistakes.png</og:image>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.failory.com/blog/startup-mistakes</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The 212-story skyscraper in Melbourne, Australia</title>
<link>https://twitter.com/liamosaur/status/1296305262144364544</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://twitter.com/liamosaur/status/1296305262144364544</guid>
<description>A year ago, &quot;nathanwright120&quot; made an edit to &lt;a href=&quot;https://mobile.twitter.com/openstreetmap&quot; class=&quot;twitter-atreply dir-ltr&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; data-mentioned-user-id=&quot;17925320&quot; data-screenname=&quot;openstreetmap&quot;&gt;@openstreetmap&lt;/a&gt; , adding a tag that indicates that a building in the suburb of Fawkner in Melbourne, Australia, had 212 floors instead of 2. All his other edits of openstreetmap seem legit, so it appears to have been a typo... (1/2) &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/Mwh1LBu3ap&quot; data-pre-embedded=&quot;true&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; data-entity-id=&quot;1296303989881856000&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; data-url=&quot;https://twitter.com/liamosaur/status/1296305262144364544/photo/1&quot; data-tco-id=&quot;Mwh1LBu3ap&quot; class=&quot;twitter_external_link dir-ltr tco-link has-expanded-path&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot; data-expanded-path=&quot;/liamosaur/status/1296305262144364544/photo/1&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/Mwh1LBu3ap&lt;/a&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 12:27:09 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>noyesno</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mobile.twitter.com/liamosaur/status/1296305262144364544</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Citibank&amp;#039;s $900M Blunder</title>
<link>https://finshots.in/archive/citibank-billion-dollar-blunder/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://finshots.in/archive/citibank-billion-dollar-blunder/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What happens when you accidentally transfer ~$900 million to somebody you didn’t mean to?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-cast&quot;&gt;The Cast&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Revlon is a multinational American Cosmetics company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Citibank is a bank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brigade Capital is a hedge fund.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And a few days back, all three actors were involved in a dramatic sequence of events that can be best described as “comical”. The only problem — it’s not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-story&quot;&gt;The Story&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Revlon was expected to transfer a few million dollars to some of its lenders. Citibank was expected to facilitate this transfer. Unfortunately, somebody in Citibank goofed up. Instead of sending the money from Revlon’s account, Citi transferred $900 million to a group of lenders from its own account. Citibank quickly realised the mistake. They apologised (I think) and asked the lenders to return the money. Some of them agreed. Some of them weren’t all too enthusiastic about parting with their newfound riches. Brigade Capital, one of the biggest beneficiaries flat out refused to even consider Citi’s request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, you’re probably thinking — Finders Keepers. But alas, playground rules don’t apply in the real world. It’s all very very complicated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-principle-of-unjust-enrichment&quot;&gt;The principle of Unjust Enrichment&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In contract law, unjust enrichment happens when there’s an enrichment of one party at the expense of another in circumstances that the law sees as unjust. It can happen for instance when someone pays money to another individual under the mistaken belief he is liable to pay the amount. And in the event, such a transaction does transpire, the law imposes an obligation upon the recipient to pay back the money in full.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The application of this principle is illustrated in a popular case from English Common Law — &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kelly_v_Solari&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kelly v Solari&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The matter was regarding a life insurance policy. Mr. Solari had passed away. His widow claimed £200 from the insurance provider upon his death. The claim was paid in full. But soon enough, the insurers found out that the policy had lapsed before the death of Mr. Solari. They realised they weren’t liable to pay because Mr. Solari had missed a premium installment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the judges agreed. They &lt;a href=&quot;https://swarb.co.uk/kelly-v-solari-cexc-1841/&quot;&gt;noted&lt;/a&gt; —&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Where money is paid to another under the influence of a mistake in circumstances where if the true facts had been known the money would not have been paid, an action lies to recover the money and it is against the conscience of the recipient to retain it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mrs. Solari had to return the money even though she wasn’t in the wrong here. So one could contest that Citibank is entitled to receive its money. However, there is a tiny complication here. Although the bank contests the transaction was a clerical error, Revlon was, in fact, liable to pay the money to Brigade Capital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-logic&quot;&gt;The Logic&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2016, Revlon acquired Elizabeth Arden, an American Cosmetics brand. Brigade Capital financed part of the $1.8 billion loan deal Revlon used to buy the company. As the administrator of the gargantuan arrangement, it was incumbent on Citibank to collect payments from Revlon and transfer it to the lenders, including Brigade Capital. The company was expected to transfer $1.5 million in interest payments to the hedge fund a few days back. Instead, they sent $176.2 mn from their own account — a sum totalling all the accrued interest and the principal in full.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brigade contests that this is simply a prepayment. A loan that was paid before it was due. How can it be a mistake when Citibank transferred the exact amount outstanding under the original credit agreement? What kind of mistake is that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Citibank offers a counter. Their first line of defence is Revlon’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://theprint.in/economy/citigroup-accidentally-wired-900-million-to-revlon-lenders-now-its-fighting-to-get-it-back/482438/&quot;&gt;own statement &lt;/a&gt;—&lt;em&gt; “Revlon did not pay down the loan or any part of the loan”&lt;/em&gt;. That’s what a representative from Revlon had to say when asked about the matter. Besides Revlon did not have this kind of money in their own account. The company is struggling financially. It’s also one of the reasons Brigade does not want to return the money. They don’t think Revlon will be able to honour its obligations. They think Revlon is bound to default soon enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Citibank, this is a potential defence. It said and &lt;a href=&quot;https://edition.cnn.com/2020/08/18/investing/citibank-sues-brigade-capital/index.html&quot;&gt;we quote&lt;/a&gt; — “&lt;em&gt;Virtually no company, let alone a distressed retail and consumer company such as Revlon, would ever make such a substantial prepayment while dealing with the significant financial consequences caused by the ongoing pandemic.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ergo, it must be a mistake. But since Brigade refused to cooperate, Citigroup sued the company in a Federal Court and tried to force its hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The judge saw merit in Citi’s argument. The company was offered temporary relief after the judge granted Citigroup’s request to freeze roughly &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/citi-sues-revlon-lender-brigade-seeks-return-of-mistaken-payment-11597694604&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;$175 million&lt;/a&gt; the bank paid the hedge fund. So, for now, Brigade can’t withdraw, transfer or dispose of the money, until the court can hear both sides and rule on the matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it a mistake?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it not?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is, quite literally, the million-dollar question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do you think?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Share this Finshots on &lt;a href=&quot;https://api.whatsapp.com/send?text=An%20explainer%20on%20Citi's%20$1%20billion%20blunder.%20https://bit.ly/34i6Zx0&quot;&gt;WhatsApp&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=https://bit.ly/34gLKMe&amp;amp;via=finshots&amp;amp;text=An%20explainer%20on%20Citi's%20$1%20billion%20blunder.&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/shareArticle?mini=true&amp;amp;url=https://finshots.in/archive/citibank-billion-dollar-blunder&quot;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 11:17:22 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>superasn</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Citibank's $900 Million Blunder</og:title>
<og:description>An explainer on Citi's $1 billion blunder.</og:description>
<og:url>https://finshots.in/archive/citibank-billion-dollar-blunder/</og:url>
<og:image>https://d3jlwjv6gmyigl.cloudfront.net/images/2020/08/citi2.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://finshots.in/archive/citibank-billion-dollar-blunder/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Gmail and Google Drive Outage</title>
<link>https://www.google.com/appsstatus#hl=en&amp;v=status</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.google.com/appsstatus#hl=en&amp;v=status</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/appsstatus#hl=en&amp;v=status&quot;&gt;https://www.google.com/appsstatus#hl=en&amp;v=status&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24220278&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24220278&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 234&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 81&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 05:46:43 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>severb</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.google.com/appsstatus</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>