<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Two Koreas Agree to End War This Year, Pursue Denuclearization</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-04-27/two-koreas-agree-to-end-war-this-year-pursue-denuclearization</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-04-27/two-koreas-agree-to-end-war-this-year-pursue-denuclearization</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;North Korean leader Kim Jong Un and South Korean President Moon Jae-in agreed Friday to finally end a seven-decade war this year, and pursue the “complete denuclearization” of the Korean Peninsula.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;U.S. President Donald Trump hailed the move, declaring “KOREAN WAR TO END!” on Twitter. He’s agreed to meet with Kim at a time and place yet to be determined.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;thirdparty-embed&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;thirdparty-embed__container&quot; readability=&quot;6.9134078212291&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; align=&quot;center&quot; data-conversation=&quot;none&quot; readability=&quot;7.3743016759777&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;KOREAN WAR TO END! The United States, and all of its GREAT people, should be very proud of what is now taking place in Korea!&lt;/p&gt;
— Donald J. Trump (@realDonaldTrump) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/realDonaldTrump/status/989820401596366849?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;April 27, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kim and Moon embraced after signing the deal during a &lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/politics/articles/2018-04-26/kim-jong-un-set-to-make-history-with-short-walk-into-south-korea&quot; title=&quot;Kim Urges Frequent Talks After Declaring Korean ‘Era of Peace’&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;historic meeting&lt;/a&gt; on their militarized border, the first time a North Korean leader set foot on the southern side. They announced plans to replace the 1953 armistice that ended hostilities with a peace treaty by year’s end.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;lazy-img-327137920&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iIkcM6wCXudk/v0/60x-1.jpg&quot; data-native-src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iIkcM6wCXudk/v0/-1x-1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img__image&quot; data-img-type=&quot;photo&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;news-figure-caption-text caption&quot; readability=&quot;35&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kim Jong Un, left, and Moon Jae-in, hold hands as they cross the Military Demarcation Line in Paju.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Source: Inter-Korean Summit Press Corps/Pool via Bloomberg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their statement on a “common goal of realizing, through complete denuclearization, a nuclear-free Korean Peninsula,” stopped short of the “complete, verifiable and irreversible denuclearnization” long sought by the U.S. and its allies. The statement didn’t elaborate on what the term meant and Kim didn’t personally utter the word during remarks Friday.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/photo-essays/2018-04-27/kim-jong-un-meets-moon-jae-in-in-pictures&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;When Kim Met Moon: In Pictures&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We have agreed to share a firm determination to open a new era in which all Korean people enjoy prosperity and happiness on a peaceful land without war,” Kim told reporters, without taking questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The agreement follows a rapid thaw in tensions on the peninsula after a flurry of North Korean missile tests and a hydrogen bomb detonation last year. The deal was expected to set up meeting soon between Kim and Trump soon, which would be the first summit between a North Korean leader and a sitting American president.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;inline-newsletter&quot; data-state=&quot;ready&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Still, it was Kim’s symbolism-laden encounter with Moon -- the third summit between leaders of the nations since the Korean War and the first since 2007 -- that captivated much of the world Friday. The event marked Kim’s first live, unfiltered appearance on world television: South Koreans gathered around screens to watch Moon lead him past a military honor guard while a band played “Arirang,” an unofficial Korean anthem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moon said their agreement to seek a peace treaty represented a “fundamental change” for the peninsula. The leaders agreed to hold military talks next month and seek a “phased disarmament,” without providing more details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Uneasy Truce&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;South Korea refused to participate in talks to end the Korean War, leaving an uneasy truce between North Korea and China on one side and United Nations forces -- led by the U.S. -- on the other. Although China long ago withdrew its troops, more than 28,000 American personnel remained based in South Korea, which the Kim regime views as an enduring threat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It all sounds good,” William Rhodes, former senior vice chairman of Citigroup Inc., told Bloomberg Television. “The question is how are you going to verify any denuclearization.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investors saw Friday’s deal easing risks. The cost of insuring South Korea’s sovereign bonds against non-payment fell 1.75 basis points to 44.75 basis points as of 6:10 p.m. in Seoul, Barclays Plc prices showed. The credit-default swap contracts, are on track for their lowest close since March 14, according to data provider CMA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question is whether the agreement can last longer than earlier ones by Moon’s predecessors that collapsed amid disputes over inspections, weapons tests and economic aid. North Korea, which committed to not pursuing nuclear weapons in 1992, now has an estimated 60 nuclear bombs and missiles believed capable of reaching any U.S. cities. -- a step Trump has threatened war to stop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Kim Optimistic&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The announcement was followed by a tersely worded commentary from Kim’s Korean Central News Agency decrying sanctions and calling on the U.S. to drop its “anachronistic hostile policy toward” North Korea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any progress on dismantling the Kim’s weapons program would likely be slow and fraught, and involve visits by international inspectors. Prior efforts involving Kim’s late father when he was leader collapsed in acrimony, with North Korea blaming the U.S. for failure to adhere to the agreements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet at least on Friday, optimism prevailed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“There’ll be no victory without pain, no glory without frustration,” Kim said. “One day, we will remember this day with joy for overcoming challenges and hardship.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;— With assistance by Heesu Lee, Sam Kim, and Kyungji Cho&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 09:34:06 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>almost_usual</dc:creator>
<og:description>North Korean leader Kim Jong Un and South Korean President Moon Jae-in agreed Friday to finally end a seven-decade war this year, and pursue the “complete denuclearization” of the Korean Peninsula.</og:description>
<og:image>https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iTu0Qj1Gt1ow/v1/1200x734.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Two Koreas Agree to End War This Year, Pursue Denuclearization</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-04-27/two-koreas-agree-to-end-war-this-year-pursue-denuclearization</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-04-27/two-koreas-agree-to-end-war-this-year-pursue-denuclearization</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>8088 MPH: We Break All Your Emulators (2015)</title>
<link>https://trixter.oldskool.org/2015/04/07/8088-mph-we-break-all-your-emulators/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://trixter.oldskool.org/2015/04/07/8088-mph-we-break-all-your-emulators/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;One of my bucket list items since I read my first party report back in 1991 was to attend a european &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Demoparty&quot;&gt;demoparty&lt;/a&gt; and compete in a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Demoscene_compo&quot;&gt;compo&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slengpung.com/pics/NAID%20%2796/4150.jpg&quot;&gt;I&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pouet.net/prod.php?which=2500&quot;&gt;competed&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pouet.net/party.php?which=159&amp;amp;when=1996&quot;&gt;NAID ’96&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pouet.net/party_results.php?which=159&amp;amp;when=1996&quot;&gt;placed&lt;/a&gt; there, which was awesome, but to compete with the best of the best, and win, has always been a dream of mine.  I’m happy to announce that after six months of hard work with good friends and extremely talented people, we achieved just that.  Our demo, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pouet.net/prod.php?which=65371&quot;&gt;8088 MPH&lt;/a&gt;, won the &lt;a href=&quot;http://2015.revision-party.net/&quot;&gt;Revision 2015&lt;/a&gt; oldskool demo compo.  (A personal victory for me was having it shown last in the compo, which is a sign of respect that the organizers think it’s the best high to end a compo in.) As of April 7th 2015, there are no IBM PC emulators in the world that can run the demo properly; they hang or crash before the demo is finished, and the colors are wrong.  Same goes for anything that isn’t the target hardware (see below).  To see what 8088 MPH looks like, I direct you to the video+audio capture of the demo running on real hardware: &lt;span class=&quot;embed-youtube&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe class=&quot;youtube-player&quot; type=&quot;text/html&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;390&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/yHXx3orN35Y?version=3&amp;amp;rel=1&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;autohide=2&amp;amp;showsearch=0&amp;amp;showinfo=1&amp;amp;iv_load_policy=1&amp;amp;wmode=transparent&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Because there are so many technological world-firsts in the demo, and because we’re bending the hardware in ways that people have never thought to do so, it’s only fair that we try to explain exactly how this was achieved.  One of my roles was “organizer” for the demo, so I’ll break it down scene by scene, covering the basics of each trick.  For parts that I wrote, I go into some detail, but for a deep technical dive into certain areas, I’ll keep this blog entry updated to point to reenigne’s, VileR’s, and Scali’s blog posts about their parts.  It is our hope that these discussions will foster revived “old-school” interest in software development for the platform. After you read this summary post, please visit the following links by us that break down, in-depth, specific sections of the demo:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And for more general info:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before going into each part, let’s define what the target system was for the demo:  A 1981 &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IBM_Personal_Computer&quot;&gt;IBM 5150&lt;/a&gt; (aka the very first “IBM PC”) with 640 KB RAM, a floppy drive, IBM CGA card, and internal speaker.  That setup consists of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;4.77 MHz 8088 CPU.  5 MHz seems like a lot compared to other 8-bit micros, but it takes the CPU 4 cycles to read a single byte.  So, compared to other 8-bit CPUs like the 6502 or 6809, which can read a byte in one clock cycle, the &lt;em&gt;effective&lt;/em&gt; clock speed of the 8088 is more like (4.77 / 4) = 1.19 MHz.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Video adapter that has a 9-pin RGBI interface and an RCA NTSC composite video interface.  Driven by a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Motorola_6845&quot;&gt;Motorola 6845 character generator&lt;/a&gt;.  No facilities for changing text characters; font is fixed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Internal speaker; no sound card like the Sound Blaster, or special sound hardware like the C64 &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MOS_Technology_SID&quot;&gt;SID&lt;/a&gt;.  Speaker can be driven by a timer pin to produce a square wave, or can be bit-banged directly via a port or a one-shot timer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The 640KB RAM requirement seems steep, but not only was it possible to add that to the first IBM PCs, by 1985 it was quite common.  If you still want to cry foul, then please note the only effect that uses just about all of that RAM is the kefrens bars, so that the repeating pattern would take longer to repeat and be more pleasing to the eye.  We could have reduced it, but then you might have noticed the pattern repeating quicker.  With the kefrens bars effect, the demo uses 507 KB RAM; without it, the demo uses 349 KB.  Most effects use much less, and some are tiny, like the plasma which uses only 6KB (which includes the banner graphics) and the picture of the girl which uses 18K (2K more than the size of the raw picture data itself).  We intentionally traded size for speed, which was a deliberate decision to fit as many effects as we could into 8 minutes running time, the compo limit.  If we had a few more minutes running time, we probably could have fit the entire demo into 256 KB or even less, but you would have waited longer between effects. I should also note here that there were &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reenigne.org/blog/comparison-of-cga-card-versions/&quot;&gt;two different versions of IBM CGA&lt;/a&gt; produced, which differ mainly in how composite colors are generated.  We had equal numbers of both “old” and “new” style IBM CGA cards, so we chose to compose graphics for the “old” style.  If you have the “new” style CGA card, the demo will still run, but the colors will be off slightly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Development tools used&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Turbo C&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turbo Pascal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turbo Assembler&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turbo Debugger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visual C++&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OpenWatcom&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NASM (and YASM)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DOSBox&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A few real IBM 5160s (hardware equivalent to the 5150, but easier to find in the real world)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Any data files were directly included in the .exe/.com files themselves.  This kept everything together in the same binary which means the data could benefit from compression (see below). Most development cycles involved designing in &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wetware_%28brain%29&quot;&gt;wetware&lt;/a&gt;, coding on a modern system (or DOSBox running on a modern system), testing/debugging in DOSBox, and then transferring over to real hardware for a final test.  Once an effect grew so sophisticated it couldn’t run in an emulator any more, this cycle slowed down as testing could only be done on real hardware.  Various transfer methods were used to get code to real hardware:  Scali used a serial cable; I used an ethernet card running a packet driver and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.brutman.com/mTCP/&quot;&gt;mTCP&lt;/a&gt;; at the party we used an 8-bit IDE ISA adapter (Silicon Valley ADP-50) connected to a CF-to-IDE adapter to make a CF card the hard drive, then used a USB CF card reader to move stuff back and forth.  The most intriguing method of all was reenigne’s method, who used a custom controller connected to the keyboard port that used the IBM BIOS factory test mode as a poor-man’s serial port.  (I hope Andrew writes up some details on that!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Loader, API, and general structure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all had different preferred development languages and environments, so it was decided early on to create an overseeing “loader” that would execute .EXE and .COM files, and then people could develop effects in whatever environment they wanted to.  This is not a new concept; the famous &lt;a href=&quot;http://fabiensanglard.net/second_reality/second_reality_dis.php&quot;&gt;Second Reality demo did this for exactly the same reasons&lt;/a&gt;, and the same technique was used even earlier than that on numerous demos on other platforms.  (Before you ask: No, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/fabiensanglard/SecondReality&quot;&gt;the Second Reality code&lt;/a&gt; was not copied; in fact, it wasn’t even consulted, as we had to write extremely tight code to minimize memory usage, and also have it work on an 8088 (the Second Reality code uses 80186 opcodes).  The loader API services assemble to about 450 bytes of code. The loader, as designed, would be responsible for:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Playing music in the background&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Masking the load times and precalc times of various effects using “megademo”-style text&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Providing synchronization services (such as providing a vertical-retrace interrupt in software, and a user-definable countdown timer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Running effects with the loader consisted of this workflow:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Print text on the screen and animate it using an interrupt and the 6845 start address register&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Execute the effect&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The effect would decompress, perform precalc, etc. and then signal the loader it is ready to start&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The loader cleans up the moving onscreen text, then signal the effect it can start&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Effect starts, magic occurs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Designing this correctly was extremely important, as any bugs would derail the entire thing.  It was designed fully before even a single line of code was written.  I’ve &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1645juVSRF2M2shcpZ3sOXHiugm0uUP7kOgHHzHzp4AQ/edit?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;shared the design doc online&lt;/a&gt; for the curious.  (I wrote the loader.) The background music playback had to be as simple as possible so as to not interfere with any effects.  A single PC beep, changing (or silencing) once every frame, was the only thing that was practical, so 60Hz beeping is what the background music consists of.  The composition program used for generating the speaker timer values was &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oldskool.org/pc/MONOTONE&quot;&gt;MONOTONE&lt;/a&gt;.  Even though the code for playback is only 18 lines of assembler, it takes up two scanlines onscreen, so you can see how anything even slightly more complicated would have sucked much more CPU out of the system and some of the full-screen 60Hz effects simply would not have been possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Executable compression&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another decision early on was to see if executable compression was feasible, which means the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Does it actually compress things small enough to be worthwhile?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is the decompression quick enough to avoid long pauses in the demo?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does the decompression routine affect the system while it decompresses? (ie. does it disable interrupts or something else equally horrible while it decompresses, which would trash the demo?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;I gathered most classic and modern &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Executable_compression&quot;&gt;executable compressors&lt;/a&gt; and ran tests against old programs that were representative of what we would be producing.  The results were welcome surprises.  The compression ratios were good enough that we could afford to include precalc’d data instead of calculating it on the fly, and the decompression was fast enough that the total end-to-end time loading a program from diskette was actually slightly faster than if it were to load uncompressed.  In the end, pklite emerged as the winner.  I’ve &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1xrZ81AqnRyje98z2QORzeOw28LGh2_wGrF3p6fozicY/edit?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;shared the comparison data online&lt;/a&gt; for comparison.  (If I missed any packers that hold &lt;strong&gt;substantial&lt;/strong&gt; advantages over the ones in the data, please let me know what they are.  There were nearly 100 packers made for DOS, but unless they compress smaller than apack or upx, or decompress faster than pklite or lzexe — &lt;em&gt;all while remaining compatible with 8088&lt;/em&gt; — then I don’t want to hear about them.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Scene-by-scene breakdown&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What follows is a screen-by-screen explanation of each effect.  As previously stated, I’ll only describe scenes in detail if I wrote them; it will be up to the others if they want to write a technical breakdown for their parts.  The explanation for each effect follows after the effect’s screenshot. &lt;a href=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still001.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;1257&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://trixter.oldskool.org/2015/04/07/8088-mph-we-break-all-your-emulators/mph_screenhots-avi-still001/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still001.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1080,720&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;mph_screenhots.avi.Still001&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still001.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440?w=640&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still001.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440?w=1080&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1257 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still001.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440&quot; alt=&quot;mph_screenhots.avi.Still001&quot; width=&quot;660&quot; height=&quot;440&quot; srcset=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still001.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440 660w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still001.png?w=150&amp;amp;h=100 150w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still001.png?w=640&amp;amp;h=427 640w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still001.png?w=768&amp;amp;h=512 768w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still001.png 1080w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 660px) 100vw, 660px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The introduction was meant to serve two purposes:  To educate the audience on the system and explain at just how much of a disadvantage we were trying to make a world-class demo on such hardware, and also simultaneously shatter their expectations :-)  The text mode is obviously simulated; I essentially duplicated the basic BIOS functions for handling text mode but simulated in graphics mode.  The cursor blinking and text blinking are handled identically to how the 6845 does it, adding to the illusion. It is (nearly) impossible to change the display start address of graphics mode such that every single scanline comes from a different place, so the title screen unrolling was done brute force, by copying new scanlines into memory hidden by retrace.  The title screen goes away with a “fade” on the top edge by ANDing a mask on successive lines of the screen data. &lt;a href=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still002.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;1258&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://trixter.oldskool.org/2015/04/07/8088-mph-we-break-all-your-emulators/mph_screenhots-avi-still002/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still002.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1080,720&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;mph_screenhots.avi.Still002&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still002.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440?w=640&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still002.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440?w=1080&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1258 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still002.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440&quot; alt=&quot;mph_screenhots.avi.Still002&quot; width=&quot;660&quot; height=&quot;440&quot; srcset=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still002.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440 660w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still002.png?w=150&amp;amp;h=100 150w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still002.png?w=640&amp;amp;h=427 640w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still002.png?w=768&amp;amp;h=512 768w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still002.png 1080w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 660px) 100vw, 660px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; A lot of people think the title screen is the same picture &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9VPn5gkG_Qo&quot;&gt;demonstrated by VileR a few years ago&lt;/a&gt;.  It’s not!  He recomposed it for 16-color composite specifically for this demo, and changed it subtlety as well. &lt;a href=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still003.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;1259&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://trixter.oldskool.org/2015/04/07/8088-mph-we-break-all-your-emulators/mph_screenhots-avi-still003/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still003.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1080,720&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;mph_screenhots.avi.Still003&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still003.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440?w=640&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still003.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440?w=1080&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1259 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still003.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440&quot; alt=&quot;mph_screenhots.avi.Still003&quot; width=&quot;660&quot; height=&quot;440&quot; srcset=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still003.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440 660w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still003.png?w=150&amp;amp;h=100 150w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still003.png?w=640&amp;amp;h=427 640w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still003.png?w=768&amp;amp;h=512 768w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still003.png 1080w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 660px) 100vw, 660px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The bobbing was achieved by creating a software vertical retrace interrupt that fired at the same place onscreen every time (just after the last displayed line) and then hooking it with a 6845 display start address change routine.  Flags were used to communicate to the interrupt if it was time to erase the letters, which was done by simply using REP STOSW to fill screen memory with black lines.  Because the 6845 displays two onscreen rows per “row”, the text could only move to even lines, which is why the movement isn’t as smooth as it could be.  Well, to be fair, it &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; be made to move to any line we wanted, but doing so would be CPU intensive, and the whole point of the loader is to use as little CPU as possible, so this was the compromise. The simulated vertical retrace interrupt was provided through loader API services for the rest of the effects to use as well.  Effects could disable it, re-initialize it, and hook/unhook their own routines to it. &lt;a href=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still004.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;1260&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://trixter.oldskool.org/2015/04/07/8088-mph-we-break-all-your-emulators/mph_screenhots-avi-still004/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still004.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1080,720&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;mph_screenhots.avi.Still004&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still004.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440?w=640&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still004.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440?w=1080&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1260 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still004.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440&quot; alt=&quot;mph_screenhots.avi.Still004&quot; width=&quot;660&quot; height=&quot;440&quot; srcset=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still004.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440 660w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still004.png?w=150&amp;amp;h=100 150w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still004.png?w=640&amp;amp;h=427 640w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still004.png?w=768&amp;amp;h=512 768w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still004.png 1080w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 660px) 100vw, 660px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The moire (interference pattern) effect was achieved using a base of 40×25 text mode, the half-char block extended ASCII characters, and lots of unrolled code.  The circles were chosen to represent the classic effect, but in reality the effect can combine any two images.  reenigne’s effect. &lt;a href=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still005.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;1261&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://trixter.oldskool.org/2015/04/07/8088-mph-we-break-all-your-emulators/mph_screenhots-avi-still005/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still005.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1080,720&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;mph_screenhots.avi.Still005&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still005.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440?w=640&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still005.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440?w=1080&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1261 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still005.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440&quot; alt=&quot;mph_screenhots.avi.Still005&quot; width=&quot;660&quot; height=&quot;440&quot; srcset=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still005.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440 660w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still005.png?w=150&amp;amp;h=100 150w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still005.png?w=640&amp;amp;h=427 640w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still005.png?w=768&amp;amp;h=512 768w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still005.png 1080w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 660px) 100vw, 660px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The rotozoomer is the same tired old routine I first rolled out in 1996 in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pouet.net/party.php?which=204&amp;amp;when=1996&quot;&gt;8086 compo&lt;/a&gt;, but optimized to the hilt and sped up by only drawing every other line.  A miscommunication between me and VileR resulted in probably not the best texture to demonstrate the effect, but it still runs well enough.  There were plans to include a 60 Hz version of this effect, but we ran out of time. &lt;a href=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still006.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;1262&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://trixter.oldskool.org/2015/04/07/8088-mph-we-break-all-your-emulators/mph_screenhots-avi-still006/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still006.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1080,720&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;mph_screenhots.avi.Still006&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still006.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440?w=640&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still006.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440?w=1080&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1262 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still006.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440&quot; alt=&quot;mph_screenhots.avi.Still006&quot; width=&quot;660&quot; height=&quot;440&quot; srcset=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still006.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440 660w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still006.png?w=150&amp;amp;h=100 150w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still006.png?w=640&amp;amp;h=427 640w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still006.png?w=768&amp;amp;h=512 768w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still006.png 1080w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 660px) 100vw, 660px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The core concept of the 1024-color mode is a serious abuse of 80×25 text mode with the NTSC colorburst turned on.  VileR made the first discovery with 512 colors, and reenigne was able to double this to 1024 with CRTC trickery. Some people thought the entire demo was in this mode.  It was not, because 80-column text mode suffers from the famous &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Color_Graphics_Adapter#Limitations.2C_bugs_and_errata&quot;&gt;CGA “snow” defect&lt;/a&gt; when you write directly to CGA RAM in this mode.  This is unfortunately visible in the plasma effect (see below). BTW, when I saw this picture in 2013, that’s when I knew I had to get all these people together to make a demo.  I mean, geezus, look at it!  My jaw dropped when I saw it.  Had I never seen VileR’s collaboration with reenigne to make the above, 8088 MPH might never have existed. &lt;a href=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still007.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;1263&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://trixter.oldskool.org/2015/04/07/8088-mph-we-break-all-your-emulators/mph_screenhots-avi-still007/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still007.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1080,720&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;mph_screenhots.avi.Still007&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still007.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440?w=640&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still007.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440?w=1080&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1263 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still007.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440&quot; alt=&quot;mph_screenhots.avi.Still007&quot; width=&quot;660&quot; height=&quot;440&quot; srcset=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still007.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440 660w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still007.png?w=150&amp;amp;h=100 150w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still007.png?w=640&amp;amp;h=427 640w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still007.png?w=768&amp;amp;h=512 768w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still007.png 1080w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 660px) 100vw, 660px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; These stars were actually the result of unrolled code and a precalc’d table that, together, take a byte from one location and moves it to another position in video RAM.  While we had other patterns ready, such as a swirling display, we felt the starfield was most appropriate for a typical “oldskool” demo.  reenigne’s effect. &lt;a href=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still008.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;1264&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://trixter.oldskool.org/2015/04/07/8088-mph-we-break-all-your-emulators/mph_screenhots-avi-still008/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still008.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1080,720&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;mph_screenhots.avi.Still008&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still008.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440?w=640&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still008.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440?w=1080&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1264 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still008.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440&quot; alt=&quot;mph_screenhots.avi.Still008&quot; width=&quot;660&quot; height=&quot;440&quot; srcset=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still008.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440 660w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still008.png?w=150&amp;amp;h=100 150w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still008.png?w=640&amp;amp;h=427 640w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still008.png?w=768&amp;amp;h=512 768w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still008.png 1080w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 660px) 100vw, 660px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The sprite part seems like black magic, but is the combination of using a sprite compiler written by Scali, and adjusting the screen vertically using the 6845 start address register.  CGA only has one screen’s worth of video memory, so moving the address down scrolls the screen up, with the data repeating across the boundary.  The data doesn’t repeat evenly across the boundary, however, requiring handling.  The timer was monitored to know when the screen line containing the last pixel of the sprite had been drawn, which prompted redrawing the sprite.  (In other words, re-drawing the sprite was an exercise in &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Racing_the_Beam:_The_Atari_Video_Computer_System&quot;&gt;racing the beam&lt;/a&gt;.)  Timing was very tight to avoid screen/sprite tearing effects. &lt;a href=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still009.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;1265&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://trixter.oldskool.org/2015/04/07/8088-mph-we-break-all-your-emulators/mph_screenhots-avi-still009/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still009.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1080,720&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;mph_screenhots.avi.Still009&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still009.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440?w=640&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still009.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440?w=1080&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1265 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still009.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440&quot; alt=&quot;mph_screenhots.avi.Still009&quot; width=&quot;660&quot; height=&quot;440&quot; srcset=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still009.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440 660w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still009.png?w=150&amp;amp;h=100 150w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still009.png?w=640&amp;amp;h=427 640w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still009.png?w=768&amp;amp;h=512 768w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still009.png 1080w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 660px) 100vw, 660px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Also part of the compiled sprite effect, this displays 30 vectorballs at 30 Hz.  We had an earlier display that used less balls to achieve 60 Hz, but Scali had the idea at the last minute to make them spell out something like “8088”, “IBM”, etc. and coded up the change at the party.  The update is done using double-buffering; the sprites only take up a small rectangular area onscreen, so the screen mode’s CRTC settings were reprogrammed to provide a video mode with a small area in the middle of the physical screen, using only half of available video memory.  This provided a true hidden page to draw/erase vectorballs to, which was then flipped to be visible using the 6845 display start address register. &lt;a href=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still010.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;1266&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://trixter.oldskool.org/2015/04/07/8088-mph-we-break-all-your-emulators/mph_screenhots-avi-still010/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still010.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1080,720&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;mph_screenhots.avi.Still010&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still010.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440?w=640&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still010.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440?w=1080&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1266 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still010.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440&quot; alt=&quot;mph_screenhots.avi.Still010&quot; width=&quot;660&quot; height=&quot;440&quot; srcset=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still010.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440 660w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still010.png?w=150&amp;amp;h=100 150w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still010.png?w=640&amp;amp;h=427 640w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still010.png?w=768&amp;amp;h=512 768w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still010.png 1080w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 660px) 100vw, 660px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Using a 1024-color variant screen mode that could be updated using only the attribute byte (thereby limiting the number of colors to 256), this plasma had to perform writes only when the CRT beam was retracing horizontally or vertically.  Unfortunately, the timing required to get this right stopped working at the party for some reason (probably happened as we were rearranging effect order), and as a result you can see a line of noise along the left side of the screen, and a little bit of noise at the top.  This was my fault, as I wrote the effect using a somewhat lazy polling routine.  It’s a shame CGA snow exists, because without all the retrace handling to avoid it, this effect runs at 60fps.  In the demo with snow avoidance, it runs at only 20fps.  VileR may write more about how this screen mode and color system is constructed, and if so, I’ll update the links at the top of this article to point to the method. If we come out with a final version of the demo, fixing this is at the top of the priority list.  In fact, I’m betting reenigne could change this from a polling effect to a cycle-counting effect, which would not only fix the snow, but speed it up. &lt;a href=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still011.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;1267&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://trixter.oldskool.org/2015/04/07/8088-mph-we-break-all-your-emulators/mph_screenhots-avi-still011/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still011.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1080,720&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;mph_screenhots.avi.Still011&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still011.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440?w=640&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still011.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440?w=1080&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1267 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still011.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440&quot; alt=&quot;mph_screenhots.avi.Still011&quot; width=&quot;660&quot; height=&quot;440&quot; srcset=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still011.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440 660w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still011.png?w=150&amp;amp;h=100 150w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still011.png?w=640&amp;amp;h=427 640w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still011.png?w=768&amp;amp;h=512 768w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still011.png 1080w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 660px) 100vw, 660px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The 1024-color mode reprograms the start address every two lines.  I took advantage of this behavior to create a simple “drip” effect for VileR’s amazing artwork.  Already you can posit that much more complicated effects are possible (thinking of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pouet.net/prod.php?which=2048&quot;&gt;the Copper demo&lt;/a&gt; here) but I ran out of time to make it more awesome. &lt;a href=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still012.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;1268&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://trixter.oldskool.org/2015/04/07/8088-mph-we-break-all-your-emulators/mph_screenhots-avi-still012/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still012.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1080,720&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;mph_screenhots.avi.Still012&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still012.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440?w=640&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still012.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440?w=1080&quot; class=&quot; size-full wp-image-1268 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still012.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440&quot; alt=&quot;mph_screenhots.avi.Still012&quot; width=&quot;660&quot; height=&quot;440&quot; srcset=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still012.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440 660w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still012.png?w=150&amp;amp;h=100 150w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still012.png?w=640&amp;amp;h=427 640w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still012.png?w=768&amp;amp;h=512 768w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still012.png 1080w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 660px) 100vw, 660px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; This classic &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Raster_bar&quot;&gt;Kefrens bars effect&lt;/a&gt; was done by reenigne in 320x200x4 mode.  It’s a cycle-counting effect, as there is simply no time to monitor for horizontal retrace.  To ensure the cycle counting was consistent, several things were done including changing the system default DRAM refresh from it’s default interval of 18 to 19, to get the DRAM refresh periods to line up with CRTC accesses. &lt;a href=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still013.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;1269&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://trixter.oldskool.org/2015/04/07/8088-mph-we-break-all-your-emulators/mph_screenhots-avi-still013/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still013.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1080,720&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;mph_screenhots.avi.Still013&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still013.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440?w=640&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still013.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440?w=1080&quot; class=&quot; size-full wp-image-1269 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still013.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440&quot; alt=&quot;mph_screenhots.avi.Still013&quot; width=&quot;660&quot; height=&quot;440&quot; srcset=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still013.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440 660w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still013.png?w=150&amp;amp;h=100 150w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still013.png?w=640&amp;amp;h=427 640w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still013.png?w=768&amp;amp;h=512 768w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still013.png 1080w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 660px) 100vw, 660px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; This was Scali’s effect and inspired by his &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pouet.net/prod.php?which=62165&quot;&gt;1991 demo&lt;/a&gt; which also featured a large torus.  There are several things going on here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Only changed portions of the screen are calculated and drawn, to minimize the amount of bandwidth needed to update the screen (this is the same “delta drawing” idea used in &lt;a href=&quot;https://x86dc.wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;XDC&lt;/a&gt;).  This was done because CGA video memory has a wait state, so the less you need to write to it, the better.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;320x200x4 mode is used with a background and palette combination that gives this specific composite color palette, which included many shades of blue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To help with the shading, dithering is applied during rasterization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still014.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;1270&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://trixter.oldskool.org/2015/04/07/8088-mph-we-break-all-your-emulators/mph_screenhots-avi-still014/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still014.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1080,720&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;mph_screenhots.avi.Still014&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still014.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440?w=640&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still014.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440?w=1080&quot; class=&quot; size-full wp-image-1270 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still014.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440&quot; alt=&quot;mph_screenhots.avi.Still014&quot; width=&quot;660&quot; height=&quot;440&quot; srcset=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still014.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440 660w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still014.png?w=150&amp;amp;h=100 150w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still014.png?w=640&amp;amp;h=427 640w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still014.png?w=768&amp;amp;h=512 768w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still014.png 1080w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 660px) 100vw, 660px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; At the party, reenigne posited that it should be possible to restart the CRTC start address every single scanline.  This would result in a video mode that was only 100 lines high, and would give a 80×100 resolution 1024-color mode.  The above is the result of that coding, plus &lt;strong&gt;really extensive&lt;/strong&gt; work done on a CGA NTSC composite signal modeling program done by reenigne months earlier to perform the image conversion.  (No, you can’t have it.  And before you ask, the “girl” and “CGA 1k” pictures were not stock conversions, but were hand-pixeled by VileR in Photoshop, and the 4-colors/16-colors/”Until Now” screens in a customized version of Pablodraw he created.) We didn’t have time to put text into this picture, so the people you see above are the same as in credits order:  Trixter, reenigne, Scali, VileR, Phoenix, and virt.  Apologies to coda and puppeh, but as you can see, any more squishing and the faces would have been unrecognizable.  Sorry! &lt;a href=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still015.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;1271&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://trixter.oldskool.org/2015/04/07/8088-mph-we-break-all-your-emulators/mph_screenhots-avi-still015/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still015.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1080,720&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;mph_screenhots.avi.Still015&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still015.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440?w=640&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still015.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440?w=1080&quot; class=&quot; size-full wp-image-1271 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still015.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440&quot; alt=&quot;mph_screenhots.avi.Still015&quot; width=&quot;660&quot; height=&quot;440&quot; srcset=&quot;https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still015.png?w=660&amp;amp;h=440 660w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still015.png?w=150&amp;amp;h=100 150w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still015.png?w=640&amp;amp;h=427 640w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still015.png?w=768&amp;amp;h=512 768w, https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still015.png 1080w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 660px) 100vw, 660px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Finally, the coup de grâce:  A multichannel music engine for the PC speaker.  We didn’t want to just copy a ZX Spectrum engine, nor other engines such as the one used in Music Construction Set, but rather set the bar impossibly high by playing a protracker mod through the speaker.  Other modplayers for the speaker already exist, but they require a 10 MHz 80286, and can barely manage output at a 6KHz sampling rate.  Ours faithfully reproduces all protracker effects, mixing and outputting to the speaker realtime at 16.5 KHz, all on a 4.77 MHz CPU. This was reenigne’s baby, and is a truly stunning technical achievement that required unconventional thinking and considerable 8088 knowledge to pull off.  I’m sure he will write up a more detailed post on how it was done.  Until then, I can mention the following details:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Preconversion of the module was necessary to align data structures and sample data to be favorable to how the 8088 indexes memory.  Sample data is also converted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each sample must take exactly 288 cycles to calculate and output or else the sound goes completely pants.  This was very difficult to achieve.  4.77 MHz / 288 = 16572 Hz sample output.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Audio output was done using traditional &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pulse-width_modulation&quot;&gt;Pulse-Width Modulation&lt;/a&gt; (PWM) techniques, such as the kind made popular by Access’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RealSound&quot;&gt;Realsound&lt;/a&gt;.  PC speaker PWM is performed by tying the PC speaker input pin to the programmable interrupt timer’s (PIT) channel 2, then programming PIT 2 for byte value one-shot mode.  Any value sent to PIT 2 with the system configured like this will set the speaker HIGH and start a count, and when the count expires (ie. the sent value is reached), the speaker goes LOW again.  This results in an audible carrier wave “whine”, which was why the output needed to be fast (16.5 KHz) so that the carrier wave was above the range of human hearing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fun fact:  After preconversion of the song and being turned into a self-playing .exe, the final result is smaller after compression than the size of the original source module.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Party Sprint&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the party, we came with something that was 90% finished.  Prior to arriving at the party, we created what we thought was a decent entry, and created two “failsafe” videos, one that was a capture for the bigscreen and another that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=O4dtJbb6Eow&quot;&gt;showed the demo running on real hardware as verification for the judges&lt;/a&gt;.  We were worried that the hardware we were bringing would get damaged in transit, so this was a precaution so that we could enter &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; if that happened.  Thankfully, reenigne’s and Scali’s IBM 5160s arrived unharmed (which was especially remarkable since reenigne had to bring his from the UK to Germany on a series of trains!).  We also brought two CGA cards, and two capture devices, and three different methods of exchanging new software bits from our laptops to the old hardware.  &lt;strong&gt;You can never be too prepared!&lt;/strong&gt; Most of the coding time at the party was spent adding the kefrens and ending portrait picture, eliminating bugs from each part where possible, adding nice transitions where possible, shaving seconds off of each part to stay within the compo limit, and rearranging parts so that virt’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.backtothefuture.com/&quot;&gt;BTTF&lt;/a&gt;-inspired tune’s intro lined up with the sprite part.  We spent pretty much all our time before the compo coding, eating, or visiting the bathroom, and only had time to socialize after that. While we came mostly prepared for something that was worthy of entering the compo, the time spent at the party was invaluable for turning a rough draft into something that could really compete for first place.  Having all four of us at the same table meant we could collaborate instantly.  So, lesson learned:  There are rarely substitutes for working together in person!  One of the biggest improvements of “party collaborating” was the decision to change the credits from a variable-speed, text-only scrolling to a more evenly-paced, ANSI-style scrolling, which I think was the best implementation change compared to the bits we brought from home. To help save time (and to ensure the video was converted well — sorry, but most people don’t know how to deal with interlaced video properly), I offered to provide Gasman with a 720@60p video.  The NTSC output of CGA is slightly off; instead of 262.5 lines per field, it generates 262.  This means it generates 59.92 fields (29.96 frames) per second instead of the NTSC broadcast standard of 59.94 (29.97 fps).  This throws off most modern capture devices; Scali had access to a high-quality Blackmagic Intensity Shuttle, for example, but it couldn’t lock onto the signal.  I knew from experience that some cheap video capture devices, such as the Terratec Grabby or the Dazzle DVC100, have extra tolerance built into them as they were designed to be used with VCR sources, so I bought a few and sent one to reenigne for testing.  For the capture, we used a DVC100 with some slight proc amp adjustments so that the capture looked as close to the CRT monitor output as possible.  To further ensure better video capturing, we used VirtualDub for the capture software, which has an option to dynamically resample the input audio source to fit the capture framerate you are aiming for in case it’s slightly off, and the software and hardware combination worked very well.  For grabbing the audio, we initially &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fzMZeWFSs1E&quot;&gt;tapped the speaker with alligator clips&lt;/a&gt;, but Scali brought his Sound Blaster which had a real PC speaker tap you could hook up with an internal cable, so we used that for the final capture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After watching the demo and reading the above, you may be wondering if there is actually room for improvement.  Believe it or not, there is:  Alternative methods of sound generation and additional cycle-exact trickery are definitely possible.  We had more effects to put into the demo, but ran out of time:  We ran out of development time, and we also ran out of execution time, as the Revision compo limit was 8 minutes or less. I’ve known everyone who has worked on the demo collectively over 60 years.  It was an honor and a privilege to work with them all to produce this demo.  Will we work together again?  I’d say it’s definitely possible; the day after the compo, we threw around some ideas, such as making a game next instead of a demo.  Me personally, I’m burnt out and will be spending the next few weeks playing some games I’ve always wanted to finish, and working on my health.  I also have some other large projects I want to get kickstarted this summer, such as something the PC software preservation movement desperately needs, and an online sound card museum.  But hey, who knows.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;wpcnt&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wpa wpmrec&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;wpa-about&quot;&gt;Advertisements&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;jp-post-flair&quot; class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-rating-enabled sd-like-enabled sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;robots-nocontent sd-block sd-social sd-social-icon-text sd-sharing&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Share this:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-block sd-like jetpack-likes-widget-wrapper jetpack-likes-widget-unloaded&quot; id=&quot;like-post-wrapper-23286-1246-5ae348e8202cc&quot; data-src=&quot;//widgets.wp.com/likes/index.html?ver=20180319#blog_id=23286&amp;amp;post_id=1246&amp;amp;origin=trixter.wordpress.com&amp;amp;obj_id=23286-1246-5ae348e8202cc&quot; data-name=&quot;like-post-frame-23286-1246-5ae348e8202cc&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Like this:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;button&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Like&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;loading&quot;&gt;Loading...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;jp-relatedposts-headline&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Related&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 02:29:08 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>quietcuriosity</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>8088 MPH: We Break All Your Emulators</og:title>
<og:url>https://trixter.oldskool.org/2015/04/07/8088-mph-we-break-all-your-emulators/</og:url>
<og:description>One of my bucket list items since I read my first party report back in 1991 was to attend a european demoparty and compete in a compo.  I competed at NAID ’96 and placed there, which was awes…</og:description>
<og:image>https://trixter.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/mph_screenhots-avi-still011.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://trixter.oldskool.org/2015/04/07/8088-mph-we-break-all-your-emulators/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Impersonators who are paid to flirt on dating apps</title>
<link>https://qz.com/1247382/online-dating-is-so-awful-that-people-are-paying-virtual-dating-assistants-to-impersonate-them/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://qz.com/1247382/online-dating-is-so-awful-that-people-are-paying-virtual-dating-assistants-to-impersonate-them/</guid>
<description>&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every morning I wake up to the same routine. I log into the Tinder account of a 45-year-old man from Texas—a client. I flirt with every woman in his queue for 10 minutes, sending their photos and locations to a central database of potential “Opportunities.” For every phone number I get, I make $1.75.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m what’s called a “Closer” for the online-dating service ViDA (Virtual Dating Assistants). Men and women (though mostly men) from all over the world pay this company to outsource the labor and tedium of online dating. The matches I speak to on behalf of the Texan man and other clients have no idea they’re chatting with a professional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It shouldn’t come as a surprise that these ghostwriting services exist. Tinder alone &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1607.01952&quot;&gt;produces more than 12 million matches a day&lt;/a&gt;, and if you’re a heterosexual American, you now have a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.technologyreview.com/s/609091/first-evidence-that-online-dating-is-changing-the-nature-of-society/&quot;&gt;one in three chance&lt;/a&gt; of meeting your future husband or wife online. But as e-romance hits an all-time high, our daily dose of rejection, harassment, and heartbreak creeps upward, too. Once you mix in the vague rules of netiquette and a healthy fear of &lt;a href=&quot;https://chicagotonight.wttw.com/2018/02/13/bbb-warns-online-catfishing-scams-rise&quot;&gt;catfishing scams&lt;/a&gt;, it’s easy to see why someone might want to outsource their online-dating profile to a pro, if only to keep themselves sane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But where does the digital social assistant end and the con artist begin?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The online seduction manual&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I tell people that I work as an online-dating assistant, their initial reaction is of morbid curiosity. “How did you even find out about that?” they ask, voices lowering, leaning in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In November 2017, I ran across an ad seeking “people with good Tinder skills” for a job as a “Virtual Dating Assistant.” At first I thought it was a joke, but I completed their online form out of pure fascination. I received a callback three days later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pull-quote&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;quote-line&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Could I work in an “moral gray area?” Would I be comfortable ranking clients’ photographs? Was I dating anyone currently?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;quote-line&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Apparently, professional writers make for good online-dating assistants; knowing how to seduce strangers with the written word is the company’s mandate, after all. But the intake interviewer seemed just as interested in my ethical flexibility as he was in the journalistic details of my résumé. Could I work in an “moral gray area?” Would I be comfortable ranking clients’ photographs? Was I dating anyone currently?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned that there are two main types of writers at the company: “Profile Writers,” who create seductive and click-worthy profiles based on facts our clients have supplied about themselves, and “Closers,” who log in to clients’ dating accounts at least twice a day to respond to messages from matches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite hiring writers to do this work, virtually none of what the company does requires creativity of any kind. Profile Writers follow strict guidelines, often recycling the same half-dozen clichés over and over again. If a client has a dog (jackpot!), all the Profile Writer needs to do is search for the word “dog” in their manual and choose from a list of dog-related one-liners, like this one:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Hey. As an animal lover, I want to find out your opinion… dressing up your dog: yes or no?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process for Closers is a bit more complicated. The initial training period lasts several weeks before we’re given access to clients’ accounts, during which we must read several training manuals and submit draft responses to fake matches. At first, my trainer encouraged me to get creative with my replies, but by the third week, I was still getting back extensive rewrites. My most frequent mistake was asking career-oriented questions, which were deemed too difficult for some women to answer. “She seems more simple,” my trainer would write in response. “Let’s try a different approach.” My meaningful questions would disappear from our shared GoogleDoc, replaced by simpler, condescending small talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Closer manuals were written by the company’s founder, Scott Valdez, a self-taught dating expert with a background in sales. The manuals have titles like &lt;em&gt;Women On Demand&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Automatic Date Transition&lt;/em&gt;, and are loaded with his personal insights into the primal female brain. We are to treat them as dating-assistant gospel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“There’s no question about it,” reads one chapter, “women want to date the alpha male. They are naturally drawn to the ‘leader of the pack.’” Valdez elaborates later in the manual: “The alpha male is the &lt;em&gt;selector&lt;/em&gt;, he &lt;em&gt;chooses…&lt;/em&gt; he is not &lt;em&gt;chosen&lt;/em&gt;.” But how do you present yourself as an Alpha? “Never compliment her without a qualification,” he writes. “Let her know what you want in a woman and make her explain why she fits those criteria.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I’m not a psychologist or self-proclaimed expert in the multiple facets of human psychology,” Valdez told Quartz in a phone call. “I consider myself to be a marketer, a matchmaker, and a dating expert.” He lists the books he’s read that inform his methods: Malcolm Gladwell’s &lt;em&gt;Blink&lt;/em&gt;, Dan Ariely’s &lt;em&gt;Predictably Irrational&lt;/em&gt;, David J. Lieberman’s &lt;em&gt;Get Anyone To Do Anything, (“&lt;/em&gt;which kind of scared my mom”), and the classic &lt;em&gt;Men Are From Mars, Women Are From Venus&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pull-quote&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;quote-line&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;“Online dating takes effort, and effort equals time.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;quote-line&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;“Online dating takes effort, and effort equals time,” he continued. “With [dating apps’] explosion in popularity, it means that you have a huge dating pool at your fingertips, but you’re also in direct competition with everyone else in your area. So if you want to have a chance at meeting your most intriguing matches, you need to have the best possible profile, photos, and messages.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my guise as a middle-aged American male, it’s my job to pursue women on our clients’ behalf. These people are often in their early 20s; young women with less dating savvy are easy targets for the company’s methods. “Rule 1: Don’t make her think too hard,” the manual says. “When writing sales copy…the goal is to reduce her ‘cognitive load’ so she’s more likely to reach the end and still have energy to write out a reply.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does a “low cognitive load” pick-up line look like? My personal favorite:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Dear [MATCH NAME], You seem like someone with a lot of confidence. What’s your secret? A) all in one shampoo and conditioner, B) high fiber diet, C) Photoshop”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These pick-up lines are mostly sent by a third type of employee, “Matchmakers,” who send out opening messages en masse across every dating platform imaginable: Tinder, Bumble, match.com, POF, Luxy, and Seeking Arrangement, to name just a few. As part of the company’s all-inclusive service, Matchmakers will scour these platforms for potential matches and then send copy-and pasted opening messages to those who fulfill their clients’ preferences, such as “must love cats” or “should know how to cook.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But combing through each woman’s profile would require too much time, so Matchmakers are instead taught to generalize a client’s preferences as much as possible and then select an opening line that could work for hundreds of women. For example, does Client X like to travel? That’s easy: Client X’s Matchmaker can search the company manual for the word “travel” and select from a handful of vague travel-related greetings. From there, after the client has approved the message, a one-liner blitz will rain down on dozens of dating sites, targeting hundreds of women with the word “travel” in their profiles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We have a lot of ice-breaker messages that are billed around specific interests, like yoga or skiing or having a very short profile,” Valdez told Quartz. ”If there’s a message that the client doesn’t like, we take it out of rotation.” After the Matchmakers have made contact, the Closers then step in to keep up the flirty banter and, hopefully, get their client a date. Clients are sent weekly emails to alert them of numbers we’ve scored or, for Platinum clients, when and where to go for a date we’ve arranged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This messaging “blast” technique may appear lucrative compared to the average neighborhood yenta, but it has occurred to me that good matchmaking may not be in the company’s financial interest. When a client pairs up, they leave the service. And with ViDA charging each client anywhere from $495 to $1,695 a month for its services, there is a significant financial incentive to keep them coming back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, tell me about yourself&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Originally a sales guy with no time for “real dates,” Valdez grew ViDA’s brand out of his own experiences in the dating world. Before Tinder normalized “DTF” (“Down To Fuck”) as an opening salute, Valdez would send copy-and-pasted pick-up lines to dozens of women a day and track their effectiveness on spreadsheets. “Online dating is a numbers game,” he would write in the ViDA training manual years later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His idea for a digital-dating-assistant service started in 2009, when he was frustrated with the amount of time it took to search for matches online. “I was working 60 to 70 hours a week and simply didn’t have time to keep up with online dating,” he said. “Before my life had gotten so crazy, I’d managed to develop some material that worked really well on the dating sites I was using. But I was at the point where I was only able to return messages sporadically, which obviously didn’t go too well with the matches I was interested in.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pull-quote&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;quote-line&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;“I thought, ‘Why couldn’t I just take what I had developed, and train someone else to sound like me, and outsource my online dating to him?’”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;quote-line&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;“I found myself wishing there were two of me,” he continued. “I thought, ‘Why couldn’t I just take what I had developed, and train someone else to sound like me, and outsource my online dating to him?’” After finding someone on Craigslist who “did a really great job,” Valdez started thinking about how many people were in the same position: time-poor professionals who might benefit from some of the lessons he’d learnt. “If it weren’t for my relentless dedication to cracking the code to meeting and attracting the right person, I probably wouldn’t have met the girl I’m with now.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today the company employs 80 people and boasts 2,500 “satisfied customers.” But the same cannot be said for all of its employees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I asked my coworkers how they handle the moral flexibility that the work demands. One male Closer told me that it felt rewarding to “help men too old to understand the internet,” and that “some people are too busy for all that.” Another writer told me that “finding love is a mysterious process, so we use data.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The service’s data-driven approach to professional flirting became clear to me during my training. “We’ve discovered that a surprisingly large portion of the online dating process can be systematized into what is essentially clerical work,” read one line in my training manual. “Really, when you think about it, you’re writing sales copy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To this end, every message I send is logged into an automated system that analyzes response rates. Closers regularly discuss what works and what doesn’t, swapping tips in extensive email chains. There are required monthly team meetings, in which Closers help workshop opening messages and pitch new ideas. While the list of company-approved opening lines is constantly evolving, the formula is almost always the same: a vague reference to something on the match’s profile, followed by an extremely easy question, like “I see you’re into yoga…. so answer this question once and for all: which is better, hot or not?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paradoxically, ViDA’s manual says that &lt;em&gt;honesty&lt;/em&gt; is key to seduction. One chapter titled &lt;em&gt;Don’t Lie&lt;/em&gt; includes lines like, “There are few things women hate more than insincerity” and “If you’ve told your date you’re a six-foot-tall astronaut when actually you’re 5 ft 9 and sell insurance, she’s going to find out.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s about trust and making sure we represent them in a way that’s comfortable for them and feels authentic, because at the end of the day they’re going to be the one going on the date,” he added over the phone. “It’s important that everything that we do feels right and feels true to who they are.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I’m not an astronaut or an insurance salesman. I’m a woman sitting in my living room in Montréal, running proxies on my smartphone and laptop. I’m logged into my client’s Tinder and match.com accounts, appearing on these platforms (with the help of numerous fake GPS services) to be the man I’m pretending to be. I sit on my couch and wait for messages to arrive in their inbox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Oh, you like Pink Floyd?” I write to one match. “Cool. I saw them in concert in ‘77.” This technically isn’t a fib: My client &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; see Pink Floyd in 1977—though I wasn’t born until 1992.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was three weeks into my contract when I encountered a client whose age was listed as 25. Written beside his photos was a casual disclaimer: “…he’s actually 33 but wants to present like 25 to attract younger ladies.” Shaving two or three years off of a client’s age was common practice, but eight years felt predatory. I sent an email inquiring about the company’s policies, and never heard back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If a client requests it, we may add an inch or two onto the displayed height or shave a year or two off the listed age, but we don’t like to do anything that’s really big,” Valdez explained to Quartz. “The goal is for the client to meet their matches face to face and hopefully spark a long-term relationship. So big lies about important facts undermine that goal. We make sure our clients understand that.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pull-quote&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;quote-line&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;If a woman doesn’t respond to our cheesy pick-up lines or cough up her number by the third message, I’m instructed to move on, as the match is no longer cost-effective.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;quote-line&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Despite my attempts at embracing the “Alpha Male” attitude, the training staff have repeatedly told me that my writing is “too female,” a characteristic that has never been fully explained. To mitigate this “error,” I’ve been told I need to use shorter sentences, ask fewer questions, use fewer smileys, wait longer to reply, and set up dates before even asking if the woman is interested. If a woman doesn’t respond to our cheesy pick-up lines or cough up her number by the third message, I’m instructed to move on, as the match is no longer cost-effective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Closers aren’t paid for the time they spend waiting for new messages, so I reread my clients’ intake questionnaires in order to bill my base salary of $12 an hour. Every client must answer 50 or so questions about themselves when they first sign up and go through a 90-minute interview, supplying Profile Writers and Closers with nuggets of mundane information. Most of it is useless when it comes to fuel for flirtatious banter—like “I took piano lessons until I was 5 years old,” or “I had fun at my sister’s wedding”—but these lifeless anecdotes are all we have to draw from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several times a day, female staffers receive Photo Ranking Requests, in which we rank new clients’ photos in order of attractiveness. This helps Matchmakers select which photos to use when building or updating a client’s dating profile. “We don’t like to declare that this client’s a 9, this client’s a 6, or compare our clients in any way,” Valdez said. “We do, however, rank the attractiveness of a single client’s photos against one another. We just employ a data-driven ranking process for choosing the most attractive pictures…We do this internally to determine a client’s optimal photo lineup.” He mentioned that OkCupid used to run a similar service, and Tinder can also optimize your photographs so that the most popular are shown first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One Profile Writer I spoke with (I’ll call him Doug) was candid about his dilemmas over the company’s practices. After working as a Closer for two years, Doug had asked to switch to Profile Writing. He’d taken to referring to Closer work as “the dark side.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doug told me that a lot of clients never call the women “who have been really engaged emotionally and are responding to our messages.” Once Closers receive their commission for getting a number ($1.75 each), they move on. But if a woman never hears from the client—the man she believes she’s been corresponding with the whole time—she might send more messages through the app, upset that she hasn’t heard from him. But the Closer is no longer allowed to reply, so he ghosts her. There’s no more money to be made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I am creating these bitter women out there,” he said. “I ask myself if I’m part of the problem.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doug learned to unmatch from women once he’d received his commission. It was easier for him that way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fool’s gold&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What kind of person would pay strangers to score them dates online, and then not even bother to call? Clients who can afford to ignore phone numbers because they receive so many a week are internally referred to as “Cash Cows.” They go on several dates a week for months or sometimes years on end, traveling frequently to new areas and an ever-expanding pool of women. These clients tend to be younger men in high-powered finance jobs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Valdez said that the typical client profile tends to be somebody between the ages of about 28 and 52, with most being in their 30s. (He also claims that one third of their clients are female.) From there, it divides into two camps: those who “have more money than time,” and those who are just plain frustrated. “Entrepreneurs, doctors, lawyers,” he lists. “Programmers, too—especially programmers in the Bay Area. We get a lot of them.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pull-quote&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;quote-line&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;“[ViDA allows] them to delegate this particular aspect of their lives to an expert, just as many have financial planners, landscapers, personal trainers, and mechanics on speed dial.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;quote-line&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;These types of professionals are money rich but time poor, he explains. Valdez referenced a recent survey that shows online love seekers are spending &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bustle.com/p/millennials-spend-average-of-10-hours-a-week-on-dating-apps-survey-finds-but-heres-what-experts-actually-recommend-8066805&quot;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bustle.com/p/millennials-spend-average-of-10-hours-a-week-on-dating-apps-survey-finds-but-heres-what-experts-actually-recommend-8066805&quot;&gt;hours a week&lt;/a&gt; on dating sites and apps. “Our clients have successful careers,” he said. “They work, they travel often, and they just don’t have that time. So the need a company like ViDA fills is allowing them to delegate this particular aspect of their lives to an expert, just as many have financial planners, landscapers, personal trainers, and mechanics on speed dial.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, there are plenty of older men seeking age-appropriate, long-term relationships online. These are the types of clients Doug and Valdez always refer to when justifying the service, as our work helps them navigate unfamiliar territory. After all, internet culture does not come naturally to some, and many of our clients are widowed or divorced retirees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I asked one of my trainers if the company takes on any married clients. Men looking to quietly set up extramarital affairs would benefit from the company’s all-hands approach; they wouldn’t even need to install the dating apps or visit the websites we use. Matchmakers will select their best photos, Profile Writers will make them sound appealing, and Closers will do all the flirting for them. Our clients need only check whatever email they’ve provided for date locations and phone numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My trainer was quick to reassure me that they refuse those prospective clients. “Even if the guy’s lying about it, Scott has a whole system for how we deal with that situation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When asked about this policy directly, Valdez pointed out that their website clearly states that they do not take on married clients or those looking to cheat; he also said that the extensive on-boarding process tends to weed out any immoral actors. “I couldn’t sleep well at night knowing we are helping people wreck their families. We’ve never knowingly helped cheaters,” he says. “There are a lot of other ways I’d prefer to make money than helping people mess up their family.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is it even legal?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company’s practices may be unethical—but they’re not illegal. Once the company obtains the client’s permission to impersonate them online, there are no laws against what Closers do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, it’s left to individual platforms to crack down on fake accounts. OKCupid, for instance, makes it clear in their terms of service that third parties are not allowed to open accounts, and it’s not uncommon for clients’ profiles to get flagged and deleted. But from a legal perspective, unless a Closer harasses or threatens a match, exposes a client’s confidential information, or asks for money, everything they do is legal according to US, Canadian, and UK law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But legality aside, these cut-and-paste flirtations perpetuate negative gender stereotypes, and they reinforce an oversimplified (and destructive) view of romantic expectations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pull-quote&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;quote-line&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Men and women on online-dating platforms therefore learn to emulate personalities that yield quantifiable results.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;quote-line&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;As dating platforms become flooded with calculated, flirtatious spam, men and women on these sites learn to emulate personalities that yield quantifiable results. This means playing down unique traits and unorthodox views to the point where a total stranger—like me—could literally do it in their place. By trying to appeal to dozens, if not hundreds, of strangers at the same time, we forfeit our ability to take risks and experiment with social norms; only placing safe bets robs us of new and genuine experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the steepest price of this online anonymity appears to be human decency, which—as I’m often reminded at ViDA—doesn’t lead to dates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, one match told me that she’d just put down her family dog. Still in training, I wasn’t sure what to do. I wrote out an apology for her loss and sent it to my instructor for approval. He crossed out my response and wrote underneath: “Alpha Males don’t apologize.” What we sent back instead was an upbeat story about our client’s two dogs, which was a shamefully inconsiderate reply in my view. I expected to never hear back from her, but three exchanges later, she was sending me her phone number.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was my first commission: $1.75.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Had she blamed my client’s callous response on internet miscommunication? Or was she learning—just as I was—that reaching out for a unique connection online would lead only to awkwardness and rejection? Every time she has an interaction in which her feelings are ignored—whether it’s online or in-person—I worry that she’ll learn not to talk about her emotional needs, or any needs of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the disillusioned masses learn to offer less and expect nothing, companies like these can take advantage of this extraordinarily low barrier to entry. That cringe-worthy shampoo vs. Photoshop line might sound impossibly lame—but it works. (And at least it’s not the bare minimum “DTF?” or an unsolicited dick pic.) As a result, businesses such as these are an economic inevitability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* * *&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was given my first female client after two months with the company. Women seeking out our services require a very different approach. When talking to my new client’s matches, I was told to make her voice sound “feminine (soft, warm, delicious, flowing, focusing on how she feels about things).” I had to “focus less on her career and more on her outside life…write longer sentences, more emoticons, and be more playful.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Doug’s view, it’s our job to act as gatekeepers for these female clients—to make sure no subpar matches make it through. “Women are so put into a box, and they aren’t going to represent what they really want,” he said. According to him, a Closer should ask the tough questions that female clients aren’t comfortable asking themselves: Does the match want children? Are they looking for something serious? Are they dating anyone else right now?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took his advice to heart and played hardball with my female client’s matches. None of the men fit her description of what she wanted, so by the end of the first week, I had not pursued any phone numbers. I was reprimanded for not producing results, and for wasting both the company and the client’s time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Our clients are interested in finding their ideal match, and if the writers aren’t getting them closer to that goal, then we’re not fulfilling our commitment to our customer,” Valdez said. “So we might realize that a writer’s writing style isn’t a fit for a client or the match that client wants to attract, so we simply shift them to a client that he or she is better equipped to help.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another Closer was given my account. Overnight, they scored seven numbers from the matches I’d already vetoed—an additional $12.25 in their pocket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to make my exit soon after.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My initial curiosity about these dating assistants had morphed steadily into deep disgust: with the company, with Valdez and his manual, and—above all—myself. The sight of my first paycheck sent me crawling back to bed in a guilt-ridden panic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I grew suspicious of my own dating accounts—not just of the men I matched with, but of my own ability to present a likable version of myself online. Every new conversation felt like a minefield, filling me with equal parts boredom and dread. To my dismay, I started to want my own virtual dating assistant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This all begs the question: Have you unknowingly flirted with a professional Closer? Me, even?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we grow accustomed to foisting more and more complicated emotional tasks onto digital butlers, we lose our ability to tolerate inelegance or find value in social failure. Moments of awkwardness and heartbreak are an inevitable part of the dating experience, and they are essential in our evolution into mature adults. By outsourcing our courtship to robots (and robot-like humans) we might save ourselves some pain in the short term, but it degrades us, simplifies us, and fails to provide for our ultimate goal of finding someone accepting of our flaws. In this age of automation, romance isn’t just one click away—it’s guaranteed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But if you’re willing to scrape the bottom of the barrel, what isn’t?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Follow Chloe on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/chloerosewrites&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. Learn how to &lt;a href=&quot;http://qz.com/635686/the-complete-guide-to-writing-for-quartz-ideas/&quot;&gt;write for Quartz Ideas&lt;/a&gt;. We welcome your comments at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:ideas@qz.com&quot;&gt;ideas@qz.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article-aside&quot;&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;popular-stories-module&quot;&gt;&lt;article&gt;&lt;h4 class=&quot;module-title&quot;&gt;Most Popular&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://qz.com/1247382/online-dating-is-so-awful-that-people-are-paying-virtual-dating-assistants-to-impersonate-them/&quot; title=&quot;You could be flirting on dating apps with paid impersonators&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://qz.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/iphone.jpg?quality=80&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=240&quot; alt=&quot;iphone in the dark&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://qz.com/1247382/online-dating-is-so-awful-that-people-are-paying-virtual-dating-assistants-to-impersonate-them/&quot; title=&quot;You could be flirting on dating apps with paid impersonators&quot;&gt;You could be flirting on dating apps with paid impersonators&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;button class=&quot;read-full-story-button&quot;&gt;Read full story&lt;/button&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 22:47:56 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>imartin2k</dc:creator>
<og:title>You could be flirting on dating apps with paid impersonators</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://qz.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/iphone.jpg?quality=80&amp;strip=all&amp;w=1600</og:image>
<og:url>https://qz.com/1247382/online-dating-is-so-awful-that-people-are-paying-virtual-dating-assistants-to-impersonate-them/</og:url>
<og:description>Have you unknowingly flirted with a professional dating assistant? Me, even?</og:description>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://qz.com/1247382/online-dating-is-so-awful-that-people-are-paying-virtual-dating-assistants-to-impersonate-them/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Relative&amp;#039;s DNA from genealogy websites cracked East Area Rapist case</title>
<link>http://www.sacbee.com/news/local/crime/article209913514.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.sacbee.com/news/local/crime/article209913514.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Sacramento investigators tracked down East Area Rapist suspect &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sacbee.com/latest-news/article209792989.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Joseph James DeAngelo&lt;/a&gt; using genealogical websites that contained genetic information from a relative, the Sacramento County District Attorney's Office confirmed Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The effort was part of a painstaking process that began by using DNA from one of the crime scenes from years ago and comparing it to genetic profiles available online through various websites that cater to individuals wanting to know more about their family backgrounds by accepting DNA samples, said Chief Deputy District Attorney Steve Grippi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sacbee.com/news/article209779364.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;investigation&lt;/a&gt; was conducted over a long period of time as officials in Sacramento County District Attorney Anne Marie Schubert's office and crime lab explored online family trees that appeared to match DNA samples from the East Area Rapist's crimes, Grippi said. They then followed clues to individuals in the family trees to determine whether they were potential suspects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process finally came to fruition last Thursday, when the investigation focused on the possibility that DeAngelo might be a suspect, a suspicion bolstered by the fact that he had lived in areas where the attacks occurred and was in the right age range, Grippi said.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Schubert said in an interview at her office that the April 19 determination that DeAngelo might be a suspect set the investigation into high gear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sacramento County Sheriff Scott Jones' investigators set up surveillance on DeAngelo in his quiet Citrus Heights neighborhood and obtained his DNA from something he discarded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The crime lab began testing the material and Schubert said she got a call last Friday night from Grippi while she was at a high school fundraiser telling her that the DeAngelo DNA matched that found at decades-old murder scenes in Ventura and Orange counties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I was at a dinner at Cristo Rey High School and Steve Grippi called me,&quot; she said. &quot;And so I probably used a few words I wouldn't put in a newspaper, but basically said, 'You'd better not be lying to me.'&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sample provided &quot;overwhelming evidence that it was him,&quot; Schubert said, but she decided they wanted a second sample, which sheriff's officials recovered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results from testing that second sample came in while Schubert was in her office Monday night, she said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;The second sample was astronomical evidence that it was him,&quot; Schubert said, adding, &quot;There were a whole lot of holy s--- moments.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Authorities began moving quickly to plan the arrest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;111.00986842105&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&quot;We wanted to be able to move quickly because it wasn't like he was in custody somewhere,&quot; she said, adding that she didn't tell all prosecutors with unsolved crimes around the state in an effort to keep the discovery secret.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&quot;Not all the DAs knew at the time that the arrest was made,&quot; she said. &quot;I think it's a fair statement that it was closely held.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&quot;There were concerns about public safety in terms of if he figured out something was going on.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;DeAngelo was arrested outside his home Tuesday afternoon and booked into the county jail on two charges of murder in the February 1978 slayings of Katie and Brian Maggiore in Rancho Cordova.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is expected to face charges in 12 homicide cases in Sacramento, Orange, Santa Barbara and Ventura counties stemming from a rape and slaying spree that authorities say stretched from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sacbee.com/news/local/crime/article209788654.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;1974 through May 1986&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DeAngelo faces arraignment in Sacramento Superior Court on Friday, but authorities still must determine where he ultimately will stand trial and whether he faces death penalty prosecutions. Some of the murders were committed at a time when the death penalty had been ruled unconstitutional, but others are eligible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schubert said she wants to meet with prosecutors from the counties where DeAngelo is suspected of murders and plan a joint prosecution similar to that used in the Luis Bracamontes cop-killing trial that ended with a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sacbee.com/news/local/crime/article209616134.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;death penalty sentence&lt;/a&gt; on Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bracamontes killed deputies in Sacramento and Placer counties in 2014, and was jointly prosecuted in Sacramento by Rod Norgaard from Schubert's office and Dave Tellman from the Placer DA's office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;18&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&quot;It makes sense to do it in one county,&quot; she said, adding that the case could be moved to Southern California because 10 of the 12 murder victims were killed there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&quot;The majority of the murders happened down in Southern California, so I'm comfortable with wherever it's going to be as long as everybody gets to be a participant,&quot; she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;Prosecutors also must grapple with whether to file rape charges against DeAngelo because for many cases the statute of limitations has expired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sacramento prosecutors do not currently plan to file such charges. In Santa Clara County, where the East Area Rapist was linked to two rapes in San Jose in 1978, the district attorney's office said it would not seek to prosecute DeAngelo because the statute of limitations had expired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But other jurisdictions are considering it, including Yolo County, where authorities said Thursday they are &lt;span&gt;investigating three rapes in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;Davis&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;nearly 40 years ago they suspect were committed by DeAngelo.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yolo County District Attorney Jeff Reisig indicated in a written statement he would seek to prosecute DeAngelo in connection with the Davis attacks, the first prosecutor in the state to announce such plans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reisig said his office would work with Schubert, the FBI and Davis police “to solve the Davis rapes, vigorously prosecute the rapist and achieve some sense of justice for the victims, family members and the Davis community.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contra Costa County's district attorney is working with police agencies there to investigate whether DeAngelo committed nine sexual assaults in that county between 1978 and 1979, DA spokesman Scott Alonso said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alonso said the statute of limitations may present a challenge. He said the office is evaluating cases with the county sheriff and police in Concord, Danville and Walnut Creek, where attacks linked to the East Area Rapist occurred.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I think we're very interested in pursuing justice for the victims in these cases and pursue what we can file under the statute of limitations,&quot; Alonso said. &quot;We want to see justice for these terrible crimes.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The East Area Rapist is believed to have killed 12 people, raped at least 51 and burglarized hundreds of homes from 1974 through May 1986 along the length of California.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;News that a suspect had been arrested in the 44-year-old mystery set off a frenzy of calls to the DA's office from news outlets around the world, and left Schubert reaching out to victims and investigators who had spent decades working to solve the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;Schubert, who grew up in Sacramento and was 12 when the attacks began, said her brother recalled their father buying a gun because of the rapes and that her mother slept with a knife under her pillow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;The realization that the case might finally have been solved - and that it involved a man who had lived in Sacramento undetected for decades - comes 18 years after Schubert convinced her bosses in the DA's office to let her begin a cold case investigations unit and two years after she formed a statewide task force to focus efforts on the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&quot;It's just surreal, so many years of people waiting...,&quot; she said. &quot;It’s a big deal. It's a moment in time that I don't think anybody's going to forget...Everybody here understands the significance of this case.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;story-related&quot; class=&quot;story-related element-spacing-large&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Related stories from Sacramento Bee&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 21:33:59 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>HoppedUpMenace</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Relative's DNA from genealogy websites cracked East Area Rapist case, DA's office says</og:title>
<og:url>http://www.sacbee.com/news/local/crime/article209913514.html</og:url>
<og:image>https://cf-images.us-east-1.prod.boltdns.net/v1/static/5502557042001/719b258e-238c-4e5d-9e8b-1a45b6788935/b0ebd744-4e6e-462e-b76b-56eb26a2f5db/1280x720/match/image.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Sacramento investigators tracked down East Area Rapist suspect Joseph James DeAngelo using genealogical websites that contained DNA information from a relative, the District Attorney's Office said Thursday, April 26, 2018.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.sacbee.com/news/local/crime/article209913514.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How Dyson Saw Feynman</title>
<link>http://nautil.us/issue/59/connections/another-side-of-feynman</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://nautil.us/issue/59/connections/another-side-of-feynman</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;A&lt;/span&gt;ll through a long life I had three main concerns, with a clear order of priority. Family came first, friends second, and work third.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So writes the pioneering theoretical physicist Freeman Dyson in the introduction to his newly published collection of letters, &lt;em&gt;Maker of Patterns&lt;/em&gt;. Spanning about four decades, the collection presents a first-person glimpse into a life that witnessed epochal changes both in world history and in physics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, we present short excerpts from nine of Dyson’s letters, with a focus on his relationship with the physicist Richard Feynman. Dyson and Feynman had both professional and personal bonds: Dyson helped interpret and draw attention to Feynman’s work—which went on to earn a Nobel Prize—and the two men traveled together and worked side by side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taken together, these letters present a unique perspective of each man. Feynman’s effervescent energy comes through, as does Dyson’s modesty and deep admiration for his colleague. So too does the excitement each scientist felt for his role in uncovering some of the foundations of modern-day theoretical physics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://static.nautil.us/14595_076d75c0dd9ca27b2f674c8f5433f50b.png&quot; width=&quot;733&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;Freeman Dyson
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;November 19, 1947&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just a brief letter before we go off to Rochester. We have every Wednesday a seminar at which somebody talks about some item of research, and from time to time this is made a joint seminar with Rochester University. I am being taken in Feynman’s car, which will be great fun if we survive. Feynman is a man for whom I am developing a considerable admiration; he is the brightest of the young theoreticians here and is the first example I have met of that rare species, the native American scientist. He has developed a private version of the quantum theory, which is generally agreed to be a good piece of work and may be more helpful than the orthodox version for some problems. He is always sizzling with new ideas, most of which are more spectacular than helpful and hardly any of which get very far before some newer inspiration eclipses them. His most valuable contribution to physics is as a sustainer of morale; when he bursts into the room with his latest brain wave and proceeds to expound it with lavish sound effects and waving about of the arms, life at least is not dull.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The event of the last week has been a visit from Peierls, who has been over here on government business and stayed two nights with the Bethes before flying home. He gave a formal lecture on Monday about his own work, and has been spending the rest of the time in long discussions with Bethe and the rest of us, at which I learnt a great deal. On Monday night the Bethes gave a party in his honour, to which most of the young theoreticians were invited. When we arrived we were introduced to Henry Bethe, who is now five years old, but he was not at all impressed. The only thing he would say was “I want Dick. You told me Dick was coming,” and finally he had to be sent off to bed, since Dick (alias Feynman) did not materialise. About half an hour later, Feynman burst into the room, just had time to say “so sorry I’m late. Had a brilliant idea just as I was coming over,” and then dashed upstairs to console Henry. Conversation then ceased while the company listened to the joyful sounds above, sometimes taking the form of a duet and sometimes of a one-man percussion band. …&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;March 8, 1948&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I went for a long walk in the spring sunshine with Trudy Eyges and Richard Feynman. Feynman is the young American professor, half genius and half buffoon, who keeps all physicists and their children amused with his effervescent vitality. He has, however, as I have recently learned, a great deal more to him than that, and you may be interested in his story. The part of it with which I am concerned began when he arrived at Los Alamos; there he found and fell in love with a brilliant and beautiful girl, who was tubercular and had been exiled to New Mexico in the hope of stopping the disease. When Feynman arrived, things had got so bad that the doctors gave her only a year to live, but he determined to marry her, and marry her he did; and for a year and a half, while working at full pressure on the project, he nursed her and made her days cheerful. She died just before the end of the war.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;reco&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;issue-article&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nautil.us/issue/46/Balance/meet-seven-extraordinary-women-scientists&quot; class=&quot;obnd_lnk&quot; data-trval=&quot;meet-seven-extraordinary-women-scientists&quot; data-trlbl=&quot;foc_rec&quot; data-tract=&quot;internal_art&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://static.nautil.us/11919_b06baa5b82cb371718756e2cc21de109.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sapolsky_TH-F1&quot; width=&quot;314&quot; height=&quot;177&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;article-tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;article-tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;article-tag-focus&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nautil.us/term/f/History&quot;&gt;Also in History&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;article-title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nautil.us/issue/46/Balance/meet-seven-extraordinary-women-scientists&quot; class=&quot;obnd_lnk&quot; data-trval=&quot;meet-seven-extraordinary-women-scientists&quot; data-trlbl=&quot;foc_rec&quot; data-tract=&quot;internal_art&quot;&gt;Meet Seven Extraordinary Women Scientists&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article-author&quot;&gt;By Amanda Phingbodhipakkiya&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amanda Phingbodhipakkiya, a former neuroscientist-turned-designer, wants to galvanize us to safeguard science. Her solution? Put a human face on it. “To encourage the next generation of young minds to take on tomorrow’s challenges and opportunities,” she says, “we should celebrate...&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nautil.us/issue/46/Balance/meet-seven-extraordinary-women-scientists&quot; class=&quot;obnd_lnk&quot; data-trval=&quot;meet-seven-extraordinary-women-scientists&quot; data-trlbl=&quot;foc_rec&quot; data-tract=&quot;internal_art&quot;&gt;READ MORE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was wrong when I wrote that Feynman found his wife Arlene in New Mexico. He married her first in a city hall on Staten Island and then took her with him to New Mexico. The story is movingly told by Feynman in the book &lt;em&gt;What Do You Care What Other People Think?&lt;/em&gt; (1988), the title being a quote from Arlene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Feynman says, anyone who has been happily married once cannot long remain single, and so yesterday we were discussing his new problem, this time again a girl in New Mexico with whom he is desperately in love. This time the problem is not tuberculosis, but the girl is a Catholic. You can imagine all the troubles this raises, and if there is one thing Feynman could not do to save his soul, it is to become a Catholic himself. So we talked and talked and sent the sun down the sky and went on talking in the darkness. At the end of it, Feynman was no nearer to the solution of his problems, but it must have done him good to get them off his chest. I think that he will marry the girl and that it will be a success, but far be it from me to give advice to anybody on such a subject.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;March 15, 1948&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My own work has taken a fresh turn as a result of the visit of Weisskopf last week. He brought with him an account of the new Schwinger quantum theory which Schwinger had not finished when he spoke at New York. This new theory is a magnificent piece of work, so at the moment I am working through it and trying to understand it thoroughly. After this I shall be in a very good position, able to attack various important problems in physics with a correct theory while most other people are still groping. One other very interesting thing has happened recently; our Richard Feynman, who always works on his own and has his own private version of quantum theory, has been attacking the same problem as Schwinger from a different direction and has now come out with a roughly equivalent theory, reaching many of the same ideas independently. Feynman is a man whose ideas are as difficult to make contact with as Bethe’s are easy; for this reason I have so far learnt much more from Bethe, but I think if I stayed here much longer, I should begin to find that it was Feynman with whom I was working more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://static.nautil.us/14596_1a4789e18b41063f512f76ebc5409d42.png&quot; width=&quot;733&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Route 66&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;FPG / Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;June 25, 1948, Santa Fe, New Mexico&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feynman originally planned to take me out west in a leisurely style, stopping and sightseeing en route and not driving too fast. However, I was never particularly hopeful that he would stick to this plan, with his sweetheart waiting for him in Albuquerque. As it turned out, we did the eighteen hundred miles from Cleveland to Albuquerque in three and a half days, and this in spite of some troubles; Feynman drove all the way, and he drives well, never taking risks but still keeping up an average of sixty-five miles per hour outside towns. It was a most enjoyable drive, and one could see most of what was to be seen of the scenery without stopping to explore; the only regret I have is that in this way I saw less of Feynman than I might have done. …&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sailing into Albuquerque at the end of this odyssey, we had the misfortune to be picked up for speeding; Feynman was so excited that he did not notice the speed limit signs. So our first appointment in this romantic city of homecoming was an interview with the justice of the peace; he was a pleasant enough fellow, completely informal, and ended up by fining us ten dollars with $4.50 costs, while chatting amiably about the way the Southwest was developing. After this Feynman went off to meet his lady, and I came up by bus to Santa Fe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;pull-quote&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going into a sort of semistupor as one does after forty-eight hours of bus riding, I began to think very hard about physics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the way Feynman talked a great deal about his sweetheart, his wife Arlene who died at Albuquerque in 1945, and marriage in general. Also about Los Alamos. I came to the conclusion that he is an exceptionally well-balanced person, whose opinions are always his own and not other people’s. He is very good at getting on with people, and as we came West, he altered his voice and expressions unconsciously to fit his surroundings, until he was saying “I don’t know noth’n” like the rest of them.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feynman’s young lady turned him down when he arrived in Albuquerque, having attached herself in his absence to somebody else. He stayed there for only five days to make sure, then left her for good and spent the rest of the summer enjoying himself with horses in New Mexico and Nevada.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;September 14, 1948, 17 Edwards Place, Princeton&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the third day of the journey a remarkable thing happened; going into a sort of semistupor as one does after forty-eight hours of bus riding, I began to think very hard about physics, and particularly about the rival radiation theories of Schwinger and Feynman. Gradually my thoughts grew more coherent, and before I knew where I was, I had solved the problem that had been in the back of my mind all this year, which was to prove the equivalence of the two theories. Moreover, since each of the two theories is superior in certain features, the proof of equivalence furnished a new form of the Schwinger theory which combines the advantages of both. This piece of work is neither difficult nor particularly clever, but it is undeniably important if nobody else has done it in the meantime. I became quite excited over it when I reached Chicago and sent off a letter to Bethe announcing the triumph. I have not had time yet to write it down properly, but I am intending as soon as possible to write a formal paper and get it published. This is a tremendous piece of luck for me, coming at the time it does. I shall now encounter Oppenheimer with something to say which will interest him, and so I shall hope to gain at once some share of his attention. It is strange the way ideas come when they are needed. I remember it was the same with the idea for my Trinity Fellowship thesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My tremendous luck was to be the only person who had spent six months listening to Feynman expounding his new ideas at Cornell and then spent six weeks listening to Schwinger expounding his new ideas in Ann Arbor. They were both explaining the same experiments, which measure radiation interacting with atoms and electrons. But the two ways of explaining the experiments looked totally different, Feynman drawing little pictures and Schwinger writing down complicated equations. The flash of illumination on the Greyhound bus gave me the connection between the two explanations, allowing me to translate one into the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result, I had a simpler description of the explanations, combining the advantages of Schwinger and Feynman. …&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;September 30, 1948&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing which I must always keep in mind to prevent me from getting too conceited is that I was extraordinarily lucky over the piece of work I have just finished. The work consisted of a unification of radiation theory, combining the advantageous features of the two theories put forward by Schwinger and Feynman. It happened that I was the only young person in the world who had worked with the Schwinger theory from the beginning and had also had long personal contact with Feynman at Cornell, so I had a unique opportunity to put the two together. I should have had to be rather stupid not to have put the two together. It is for the sake of opportunities like this that I want to spend five more years poor and free rather than as a well-paid civil servant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;November 1, 1948, Hotel Avery, Boston&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After my last letter to you I decided that I needed a long weekend away from Princeton. I persuaded Cécile Morette to come with me to see Feynman at Ithaca. This was a bold step on my part, but it could not have been more successful, and the weekend was just deliriously happy. Feynman himself came to meet us at the station, after our ten-hour train journey, and was in tremendous form, bubbling over with ideas and stories and entertaining us with performances on Indian drums from New Mexico until one a.m.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;pull-quote&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feynman was obviously anxious to talk and would have gone on quite indefinitely if he had been allowed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cécile Morette was the brightest of the young physicists who arrived at the institute at the same time as I did. She was the only one who quickly grasped the new ideas of Feynman. We immediately became friends. The fact that she happened to be female was irrelevant to our friendship. She was a natural leader, she understood modern mathematics better than I did, and she had a great sense of humor.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day, Saturday, we spent in conclave discussing physics. Feynman gave a masterly account of his theory, which kept Cécile in fits of laughter and made my talk at Princeton a pale shadow by comparison. He said he had given his copy of my paper to a graduate student to read, then asked the student if he himself ought to read it. The student said no, and Feynman accordingly wasted no time on it and continued chasing his own ideas. Feynman and I really understand each other; I know that he is the one person in the world who has nothing to learn from what I have written, and he doesn’t mind telling me so. That afternoon Feynman produced more brilliant ideas per square minute than I have ever seen anywhere before or since. In the evening I mentioned that there were just two problems for which the finiteness of the theory remained to be established; both problems are well-known and feared by physicists, since many long and difficult papers running to fifty pages and more have been written about them, trying unsuccessfully to make the older theories give sensible answers to them. When I mentioned this fact, Feynman said, “We’ll see about this,” and proceeded to sit down and in two hours, before our eyes, obtain finite and sensible answers to both problems. It was the most amazing piece of lightning calculation I have ever witnessed, and the results prove, apart from some unforeseen complication, the consistency of the whole theory. The two problems were the scattering of light by an electric field, and the scattering of light by light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After supper Feynman was working until three a.m. He has had a complete summer of vacation and has returned with unbelievable stores of suppressed energy. On the Sunday Feynman was up at his usual hour (nine a.m.), and we went down to the physics building, where he gave me another two-hour lecture of miscellaneous discoveries of his. One of these was a deduction of Maxwell’s equations of the electromagnetic field from the basic principles of quantum theory, a thing which baffles everybody including Feynman, because it ought not to be possible. Meanwhile Cécile was at mass, being a strict Catholic. At twelve on the Sunday we started our journey home, arriving finally at two a.m. and thoroughly refreshed. Cécile assured me she had enjoyed it as much as I had. I found a surprising intensity of feeling for Ithaca, its breezy open spaces and hills and its informal society. It seemed like a place which I belonged to, full of nostalgic memories. I suppose it really is my spiritual home.  …&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;February 28, 1949, Chicago&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Thursday we had Feynman down to Princeton, and he stayed till I left on Sunday. He gave in three days about eight hours of seminars, besides long private discussions. This was a magnificent effort, and I believe all the people at the institute began to understand what he is doing. I at least learnt a great deal. He was as usual in an enthusiastic mood, waving his arms about a lot and making everybody laugh. Even Oppenheimer began to get the spirit of the thing and said some things less sceptical than is his habit. Feynman was obviously anxious to talk and would have gone on quite indefinitely if he had been allowed; he must have been suffering from the same bottled-up feeling that I had when I was full of ideas last autumn. The trouble with him is that he never will publish what he does; I sometimes feel guilty for having cut in front of him with his own ideas. However, he is now at last writing up two big papers, which will display his genius to the world; and it is possible that I have helped to make him do this by making him conscious of being cut in on, which if it be true is a valuable service on my part. …&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;October 23, 1965&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are all excited because my three friends Tomonaga, Schwinger, and Feynman won the Nobel Prize. You may remember that it was just after their great work in 1947 that I started my career by carrying further what they had begun. I am happy that the prize is given to the three of them equally. To some extent I can take credit for this, since Schwinger originally had all the limelight and Tomonaga and Feynman were struggling in obscurity. It was my big paper “The Radiation Theories of Tomonaga, Schwinger and Feynman” that first did justice to all three of them. I am now writing the historical account of their work which will appear next week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Freeman Dyson is a theoretical physicist and mathematician, a professor emeritus at the Institute for Advanced Study, and the author of &lt;/em&gt;Disturbing the Universe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Adapted from&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Maker-Patterns-Autobiography-Through-Letters/dp/0871403862/ref=mt_hardcover?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;me;=&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Maker of Patterns: An Autobiography Through Letters&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;by Freeman Dyson. Copyright © 2018 by Freeman Dyson. Used with permission of the publisher, Liveright Publishing Corporation, a division of &lt;a href=&quot;http://books.wwnorton.com/books/index.aspx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;W.W. Norton &amp;amp; Company, Inc&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lead Photo Collage Credits: Cern; Pixabay&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;leaderboard-ad-belt&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;leaderboard-ad-belt-inner adarticle&quot;&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;div-gpt-ad-1380044019755-0&quot; class=&quot;leaderboard-ad&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 20:46:35 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dnetesn</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>http://nautil.us/issue/59/connections/another-side-of-feynman</og:url>
<og:title>Another Side of Feynman - Issue 59: Connections - Nautilus</og:title>
<og:description>All through a long life I had three main concerns, with a clear order of priority. Family came first, friends second, and work third.”&amp;#8230;</og:description>
<og:image>http://static.nautil.us/14590_fc56459a18776e2a100854c16a1fd78b.png</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://nautil.us/issue/59/connections/another-side-of-feynman</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Flask 1.0 Released</title>
<link>https://www.palletsprojects.com/blog/flask-1-0-released/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.palletsprojects.com/blog/flask-1-0-released/</guid>
<description>&lt;h2&gt;Flask 1.0 Released&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;written by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/davidism&quot;&gt;David Lord&lt;/a&gt; on 2018-04-26 in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.palletsprojects.com/blog/categories/security/&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/a&gt; , &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.palletsprojects.com/blog/categories/releases/&quot;&gt;Releases&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Pallets team is pleased to release &lt;a href=&quot;https://palletsprojects.com/p/flask/&quot;&gt;Flask&lt;/a&gt; 1.0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Flask framework has been stable for a long time. A little more than 8 years after the first commit, the version number finally reflects that. 1.0 comes with a significant number of changes representing over a year of work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Dropped support for Python 2.6 and 3.3.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The CLI is more flexible. &lt;code&gt;FLASK_APP&lt;/code&gt; can point to an app factory, optionally with arguments. It understands import names in more cases where filenames were previously used. It automatically detects common filenames, app names, and factory names. &lt;code&gt;FLASK_ENV&lt;/code&gt; describes the environment the app is running in, like &lt;code&gt;development&lt;/code&gt;, and replaces &lt;code&gt;FLASK_DEBUG&lt;/code&gt; in most cases. &lt;a href=&quot;http://flask.pocoo.org/docs/1.0/cli/&quot;&gt;See the docs to learn more.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If python-dotenv is installed, the &lt;code&gt;flask&lt;/code&gt; CLI will load environment variables from &lt;code&gt;.flaskenv&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;.env&lt;/code&gt; files rather than having to export them in each new terminal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The development server is multi-threaded by default to handle concurrent requests during development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;flask.ext&lt;/code&gt;, which was previously deprecated, is completely removed. Import extensions by their actual package names.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accessing missing keys from &lt;code&gt;request.form&lt;/code&gt; shows a more helpful error message in debug mode, addressing a very common source of confusion for developers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Error handlers are looked up by code then exception class, on the blueprint then application. This gives more predictable control over handlers, including being able to handle &lt;code&gt;HTTPException&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The behavior of &lt;code&gt;app.logger&lt;/code&gt; has been greatly simplified and should be much easier to customize. The logger is always named &lt;code&gt;flask.app&lt;/code&gt;, it only adds a handler if none are registered, and it never removes existing handlers. &lt;a href=&quot;http://flask.pocoo.org/docs/1.0/logging/&quot;&gt;See the docs to learn more.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;test_client&lt;/code&gt; gained a &lt;code&gt;json&lt;/code&gt; argument for posting JSON data, and the &lt;code&gt;Response&lt;/code&gt; object gained a &lt;code&gt;get_json&lt;/code&gt; method to decode the data as JSON in tests.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A new &lt;code&gt;test_cli_runner&lt;/code&gt; is added for testing an app's CLI commands.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many documentation sections have been rewritten to improve clarity and relevance. This is an ongoing effort.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://flask.pocoo.org/docs/1.0/tutorial/&quot;&gt;tutorial&lt;/a&gt; and corresponding &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pallets/flask/tree/1.0/examples/tutorial&quot;&gt;example&lt;/a&gt; have been rewritten. They use a structured layout and go into more detail about each aspect in order to help new users avoid common issues and become comfortable with Flask.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are many more changes throughout the framework. &lt;a href=&quot;http://flask.pocoo.org/docs/1.0/changelog/&quot;&gt;Read the full changelog&lt;/a&gt; to understand what changes may affect your code when upgrading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;json-security-fix&quot;&gt;JSON Security Fix&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flask previously decoded incoming JSON bytes using the content type of the request. Although JSON should only be encoded as UTF-8, Flask was more lenient. However, Python includes non-text related encodings that could result in unexpected memory use by a request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flask will now detect the encoding of incoming JSON data as one of the supported UTF encodings, and will not allow arbitrary encodings from the request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;install-or-upgrade&quot;&gt;Install or Upgrade&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Install from &lt;a href=&quot;https://pypi.org/project/Flask/&quot;&gt;PyPI&lt;/a&gt; with pip:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;pip install -U Flask
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;get-involved&quot;&gt;Get Involved&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flask and the Pallets team depends on you, the community. Whether you report issues, write documentation, create patches, or answer questions, we appreciate all the help you provide. Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pallets/flask/blob/master/CONTRIBUTING.rst&quot;&gt;contributing guide&lt;/a&gt; to get started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;donate&quot;&gt;Donate&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Pallets organization has joined the Python Software Foundation's Fiscal Sponsorship program. We now accept donations through the PSF in order to support our efforts to maintain the projects and grow the community. &lt;a href=&quot;https://psfmember.org/civicrm/contribute/transact?reset=1&amp;amp;id=20&quot;&gt;Click here to donate.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 20:32:38 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>JonoBB</dc:creator>
<og:title>Flask 1.0 Released</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.palletsprojects.com/blog/flask-1-0-released/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.palletsprojects.com/og_image.png</og:image>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.palletsprojects.com/blog/flask-1-0-released/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Square to buy Weebly for $365M</title>
<link>https://www.cnbc.com/2018/04/26/square-to-buy-weebly-for-365-million.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.cnbc.com/2018/04/26/square-to-buy-weebly-for-365-million.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Square announced an agreement on Thursday to buy website-building company Weebly for $365 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cash-and-stock deal will allow small business customers to use both Weebly and Square to easily build websites and online stores, the companies said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weebly is a website-building service, similar to Squarespace or Wordpress, and was backed by Sequoia, Tencent and Y Combinator, according to Crunchbase. Weebly also competes with Medium, created by former Twitter CEO Evan Williams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;inline_quotes&quot; data-gdsid=&quot;157183&quot; data-inline-quote-symbol=&quot;SQ&quot; href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/quotes/?symbol=SQ&quot;&gt;Square&lt;/a&gt;, run by current Twitter CEO &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/jack-dorsey/&quot;&gt;Jack Dorsey&lt;/a&gt;, is a financial technology company that's best known for its eponymous square white payments devices, typically used at small businesses with iPads to read credit cards. The company, also backed by Sequoia, has had an impressive run on Wall Street this year, with shares rising nearly 35 percent year-to-date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The merger is expected to close in the second quarter of 2018, and Weebly employees will get Square stock that vests over the next four years. Square said the deal will add recurring revenue to Square's business and help its international expansion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Square's rapidly diversified its business recently — last week, it announced the acquisition of Zesty, a corporate catering start-up. Shares of Square rose about half a percent after the Weebly deal was announced in extended trading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;— CNBC's &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/deirdre-bosa/&quot;&gt;Deirdre Bosa&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/stephen-desaulniers/&quot;&gt;Stephen Desaulniers&lt;/a&gt; contributed to this report.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 20:17:12 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rezashirazian</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.cnbc.com/2018/04/26/square-to-buy-weebly-for-365-million.html</og:url>
<og:image>https://fm.cnbc.com/applications/cnbc.com/resources/img/editorial/2016/12/30/104192980-GettyImages-180905749.1910x1000.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Square to buy Weebly for $365 million</og:title>
<og:description>Square is a financial technology company that's best known for its eponymous square white payments devices.</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.cnbc.com/2018/04/26/square-to-buy-weebly-for-365-million.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Go&amp;#039;s New Brand</title>
<link>https://blog.golang.org/go-brand</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.golang.org/go-brand</guid>
<description>&lt;h3 class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.golang.org/go-brand&quot;&gt;Go's New Brand&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;date&quot;&gt;26 April 2018&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;TOC_1.&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am delighted to announce the launch of Go’s new look and logo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go has been on an amazing journey over the last 8+ years. Our project, community and users have evolved through this journey and we wanted the Go brand to reflect where we have been and convey where we are going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go’s new brand is about our identity, our values, and our users. Over the past several months we have worked with a brand agency to develop a brand guide for Go. Our agency, &lt;a href=&quot;http://within.us/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Within&lt;/a&gt;, coordinated with and built upon the great foundation that Renee French established. Rest easy, our beloved Gopher Mascot remains at the center of our brand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;TOC_2.&quot;&gt;New Logo&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our logo follows the brand’s core philosophy of simplicity over complexity. Using a modern, italicized sans-serif typeface combined with three simple motion lines forms a mark that resembles two wheels in rapid motion, communicating speed and efficiency. The circular shape of the letters hints at the eyes of the Go gopher, creating a familiar shape and allowing the mark and the mascot to pair well together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.golang.org/go-brand/logos.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our new logo went through an extensive design process. Here are some of the revisions we went through…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/V4t-ymImW6c?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;TOC_3.&quot;&gt;New Brand Guide&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The brand guide establishes the mission, values and voice for the Go project. In general terms, a brand guide is a reference tool for establishing a consistent brand identity. It is sometimes referred to as a “brand guidelines” or a “brand book”. It is a single document that serves as a guide and reference to designers, writers, and developers to create consistent, on-brand content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.golang.org/go-brand/Go-BB_cover.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.golang.org/go-brand/Go-BB_spread1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.golang.org/go-brand/Go-BB_spread2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;TOC_4.&quot;&gt;New presentation themes&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to our brand guide we have also developed a presentation theme. This presentation theme will enable us to have a consistent representation of Go in person at meetups and conferences as well as online. Go community members are welcome to use this theme for their own presentations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.golang.org/go-brand/go-slides-4up.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The presentations are available as Google Slides presentations. We chose Google slides as it is easy to share and maintain updates. People are welcome to port them to keynote, powerpoint, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like this blog and all our gopher images, the slide themes are Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 licensed. The photos in the slides are all from &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;unsplash&lt;/a&gt; and are released under the unsplash license.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instructions to use slides:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Open the &lt;a href=&quot;https://golang.org/s/presentation-theme&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Go Slide Masters&lt;/a&gt; presentation on Google slides.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;File &amp;gt; “Make a Copy” (you may need to login first)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create new slides using the layouts provided in the layouts menu.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the included example slides to help guide the styling and creation of your presentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h4 id=&quot;TOC_4.1.&quot;&gt;Download&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The brand guide, logo and themes are copyrighted by the Go authors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The brand guide contains the guidelines for acceptable logo use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;TOC_5.&quot;&gt;What’s happening next&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The website will be getting a refresh based on the new design. Since we are making significant changes, we are also taking this opportunity to update our website infrastructure to support internationalization and multilingual to better serve our global community. The migration will happen in stages over the next few months starting with this blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;By Steve Francia&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 19:56:17 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>andybons</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.golang.org/go-brand</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Stack Overflow Isn’t Very Welcoming – It’s Time for That to Change</title>
<link>https://stackoverflow.blog/2018/04/26/stack-overflow-isnt-very-welcoming-its-time-for-that-to-change/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://stackoverflow.blog/2018/04/26/stack-overflow-isnt-very-welcoming-its-time-for-that-to-change/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;m-post-card__excerpt&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;Last week, we rolled out our latest feature designed to help tech industry leaders engage more directly with the developer community. In a partnership with Strangeworks, Stack Exchange launched the...&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;m-post-card__excerpt&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;Each year, we ask the developer community about everything from their favorite technologies to their job preferences. This year marks the eighth year we’ve published our Annual Developer Survey results—with...&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;m-post-card__excerpt&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;Amazon is a technology behemoth, employing half a million people globally and hiring nearly 130,000 people in 2017. Amazon has been headquartered in Seattle since its early days in the...&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 19:40:10 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ingve</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Stack Overflow Isn't Very Welcoming. It's Time for That to Change. - Stack Overflow Blog</og:title>
<og:description>Let’s start with the painful truth:</og:description>
<og:url>https://stackoverflow.blog/2018/04/26/stack-overflow-isnt-very-welcoming-its-time-for-that-to-change/</og:url>
<og:image>https://zgab33vy595fw5zq-zippykid.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/woman-lego-computer.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://stackoverflow.blog/2018/04/26/stack-overflow-isnt-very-welcoming-its-time-for-that-to-change/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>High-Paying Trade Jobs Sit Empty, While High School Grads Line Up for University</title>
<link>https://www.npr.org/sections/ed/2018/04/25/605092520/high-paying-trade-jobs-sit-empty-while-high-school-grads-line-up-for-university</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.npr.org/sections/ed/2018/04/25/605092520/high-paying-trade-jobs-sit-empty-while-high-school-grads-line-up-for-university</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;res605261226&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap image large&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imagewrap&quot; data-crop-type=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/04/24/marcus-washington-vocational-1_slide-238d4249a0de32894b0250a63f73fc9d05041b7a-s1100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/04/24/marcus-washington-vocational-1_slide-238d4249a0de32894b0250a63f73fc9d05041b7a-s1100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-wrap&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image caption&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Garret Morgan (center) is training as an ironworker near Seattle and already has a job that pays him $50,000 a year. &lt;strong class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Sy Bean/The Hechinger Report&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong class=&quot;hide-caption&quot;&gt;hide caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;strong class=&quot;toggle-caption&quot;&gt;toggle caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Sy Bean/The Hechinger Report&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_measure&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img_wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/04/24/marcus-washington-vocational-1_slide-238d4249a0de32894b0250a63f73fc9d05041b7a-s1200.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_html&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image_data&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Garret Morgan (center) is training as an ironworker near Seattle and already has a job that pays him $50,000 a year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Sy Bean/The Hechinger Report&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like most other American high school students, Garret Morgan had it drummed into him constantly: Go to college. Get a bachelor's degree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;All through my life it was, 'if you don't go to college you're going to end up on the streets,' &quot; Morgan said. &quot;Everybody's so gung-ho about going to college.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So he tried it for a while. Then he quit and started training as an ironworker, which is what he is doing on a weekday morning in a nondescript high-ceilinged building with a concrete floor in an industrial park near the Seattle-Tacoma International Airport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morgan and several other men and women are dressed in work boots, hard hats and Carhartt's, clipped to safety harnesses with heavy wrenches hanging from their belts. They're being timed as they wrestle 600-pound I-beams into place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seattle is a forest of construction cranes, and employers are clamoring for skilled ironworkers. Morgan, who is 20, is already working on a job site when he isn't at the Pacific Northwest Ironworkers shop. He gets benefits, including a pension, from employers at the job sites where he is training. And he is earning $28.36 an hour, or more than $50,000 a year, which is almost certain to steadily increase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id=&quot;ad-backstage-wrap&quot; aria-label=&quot;advertisement&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;As for his friends from high school, &quot;they're still in college,&quot; he said with a wry grin. &quot;Someday maybe they'll make as much as me.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res605208450&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap pullquote&quot;&gt;
&lt;aside aria-label=&quot;pullquote&quot; readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;bucket&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some 30 million jobs in the United States that pay an average of $55,000 per year don't require bachelor's degrees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Raising alarms&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While a shortage of workers is pushing wages higher in the skilled trades, the financial return from a bachelor's degree is softening, even as the price — and the average debt into which it plunges students — keeps going up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But high school graduates have been so effectively encouraged to get a bachelor's that high-paid jobs requiring shorter and less expensive training are going unfilled. This affects those students and also poses a real threat to the economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Parents want success for their kids,&quot; said Mike Clifton, who teaches machining at the Lake Washington Institute of Technology, about 20 miles from Seattle. &quot;They get stuck on [four-year bachelor's degrees], and they're not seeing the shortage there is in tradespeople until they hire a plumber and have to write a check.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res605262715&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap image large&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imagewrap&quot; data-crop-type=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/04/24/marcus-washington-vocational-6_custom-76af482c828c036f3e94685635f1e87f3bca0857-s1100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/04/24/marcus-washington-vocational-6_custom-76af482c828c036f3e94685635f1e87f3bca0857-s1100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-wrap&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image caption&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ironworkers practice tying rebar at the Iron Workers Local Union #86 Administrative Offices in Tukwila, Wash. &lt;strong class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Sy Bean/The Hechinger Report&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong class=&quot;hide-caption&quot;&gt;hide caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;strong class=&quot;toggle-caption&quot;&gt;toggle caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Sy Bean/The Hechinger Report&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sao.wa.gov/state/Documents/PA_Career_Tech_Ed_Leading_Practices_ar1020510.pdf&quot;&gt;a new report&lt;/a&gt;, the Washington State Auditor found that good jobs in the skilled trades are going begging because students are being almost universally steered to bachelor's degrees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among other things, the Washington auditor recommended that career guidance — including choices that require less than four years in college — start as early as the seventh grade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;There is an emphasis on the four-year university track&quot; in high schools, said Chris Cortines, who co-authored the report. Yet, nationwide, three out of 10 high school grads who go to four-year public universities haven't earned degrees within six years, &lt;a href=&quot;https://nscresearchcenter.org/wp-content/uploads/SnapshotReport32.pdf&quot;&gt;according to the National Student Clearinghouse&lt;/a&gt;. At four-year private colleges, that number is more than 1 in 5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Being more aware of other types of options may be exactly what they need,&quot; Cortines said. In spite of a perception &quot;that college is the sole path for everybody,&quot; he said, &quot;when you look at the types of wages that apprenticeships and other career areas pay and the fact that you do not pay four years of tuition and you're paid while you learn, these other paths really need some additional consideration.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it's not just in Washington state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res605208452&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap pullquote&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;aside aria-label=&quot;pullquote&quot; readability=&quot;5.5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;bucket&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Parents want success for their kids. They get stuck on [four-year bachelor's degrees], and they're not seeing the shortage there is in tradespeople until they hire a plumber and have to write a check.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;byline&quot;&gt;Mike Clifton, Lake Washington Institute of Technology&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seventy-percent of construction companies nationwide are having trouble finding qualified workers, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.agc.org/news/2017/08/29/seventy-percent-contractors-have-hard-time-finding-qualified-craft-workers-hire-am-0&quot;&gt;according to the Associated General Contractors of America&lt;/a&gt;; in Washington, the proportion is 80 percent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are already more trade jobs like carpentry, electrical, plumbing, sheet-metal work and pipe-fitting than Washingtonians to fill them, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sao.wa.gov/state/Documents/PA_Career_Tech_Ed_Leading_Practices_ar1020510.pdf&quot;&gt;the state auditor reports&lt;/a&gt;. Many pay more than the state's average annual wage of $54,000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Construction, along with health care and personal care, will account for one-third of all new jobs through 2022, according to the Bureau of Labor Statistics. There will also be a need for new plumbers and new electricians. And, as politicians debate a massive overhaul of the nation's roads, bridges and airports, &lt;a href=&quot;http://cte.ed.gov/initiatives/advancing-cte-in-state-and-local-career-pathways-system&quot;&gt;the U.S. Department of Education reports&lt;/a&gt; that there will be 68 percent more job openings in infrastructure-related fields in the next five years than there are people training to fill them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The economy is definitely pushing this issue to the forefront,&quot; said Amy Morrison Goings, president of the Lake Washington Institute of Technology, which educates students in these fields. &quot;There isn't a day that goes by that a business doesn't contact the college and ask the faculty who's ready to go to work.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In all, some 30 million jobs in the United States that pay an average of $55,000 per year don't require bachelor's degrees, &lt;a href=&quot;https://goodjobsdata.org/&quot;&gt;according to the Georgetown Center on Education and the Workforce&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet the march to bachelor's degrees continues. And while people who get them are more likely to be employed and make more money than those who don't, that premium appears to be softening; &lt;a href=&quot;https://nces.ed.gov/programs/coe/pdf/coe_sbc.pdf&quot;&gt;their median earnings were lower in 2015&lt;/a&gt;, when adjusted for inflation, than in 2010.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;There's that perception of the bachelor's degree being the American dream, the best bang for your buck,&quot; said Kate Blosveren Kreamer, deputy executive director of Advance CTE, an association of state officials who work in career and technical education. &quot;The challenge is that in many cases it's become the fallback. People are going to college without a plan, without a career in mind, because the mindset in high school is just, 'Go to college.' &quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res605262117&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap image large&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imagewrap&quot; data-crop-type=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/04/24/marcus-washington-vocational-7_custom-b9be7ed2c4041639230fda13a285cce883e8ac97-s1100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/04/24/marcus-washington-vocational-7_custom-b9be7ed2c4041639230fda13a285cce883e8ac97-s1100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-wrap&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image caption&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matthew Dickinson, 21, asks a classmate for help as they rebuild an automatic transmission in an auto repair technician program classes at the Lake Washington Institute of Technology. &lt;strong class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Sy Bean/The Hechinger Report&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong class=&quot;hide-caption&quot;&gt;hide caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;strong class=&quot;toggle-caption&quot;&gt;toggle caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Sy Bean/The Hechinger Report&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's not that finding a job in the trades, or even manufacturing, means needing no education after high school. Most regulators and employers require certificates, certifications or associate degrees. But those cost less and take less time than earning a bachelor's degree. Tuition and fees for in-state students to attend a community or technical college in Washington State, for example, come to less than half the cost of a four-year public university, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sao.wa.gov/state/Documents/PA_Career_Tech_Ed_Leading_Practices_ar1020510.pdf&quot;&gt;the state auditor points out&lt;/a&gt;, and less than a tenth of the price of attending a private four-year college.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People with career and technical educations are also more likely to be employed than their counterparts with academic credentials, &lt;a href=&quot;https://nces.ed.gov/surveys/ctes/figures/fig_2016107-2.asp&quot;&gt;the U.S. Department of Education reports&lt;/a&gt;, and significantly more likely to be working in their fields of study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Young people don't seem to be getting that message. The proportion of high school students who earned three or more credits in occupational education — typically an indication that they're interested in careers in the skilled trades — has fallen from 1 in 4 in 1990 to 1 in 5 now, &lt;a href=&quot;https://nces.ed.gov/surveys/ctes/table_archive.asp&quot;&gt;according to the U.S. Department of Education&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Washington is not the only state devoting attention to this. California &lt;a href=&quot;http://hechingerreport.org/after-decades-of-pushing-bachelors-degrees-u-s-needs-more-tradespeople/&quot;&gt;is spending $200 million&lt;/a&gt; to improve the delivery of career and technical education. Iowa community colleges and businesses are collaborating to increase the number of &quot;work-related learning opportunities,&quot; including apprenticeships, job shadowing and internships. Tennessee has made its technical colleges free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So severe are looming shortages of workers in the skilled trades in Michigan that Gov. Rick Snyder in February announced &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.michigan.gov/ted/0,5863,7-336-85008%E2%80%94-,00.html&quot;&gt;a $100 million proposal he likens to the Marshall Plan&lt;/a&gt; that rebuilt Europe after World War II.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the federal level, there is bipartisan support for making Pell grants available for short-term job-training courses and not just university tuition. The Trump administration &lt;a href=&quot;https://www2.ed.gov/about/overview/budget/budget19/summary/19summary.pdf&quot;&gt;supports the idea&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For all the promises to improve vocational education, however, a principal federal source of money for it, called Tech-Prep, hasn't been funded since 2011. A quarter of states last year reduced their own funding for postsecondary career and technical education, according to the National Association of State Directors of Career Technical Education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The branding issue&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Money isn't the only issue, advocates for career and technical education say. An even bigger challenge is convincing parents that it leads to good jobs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res605261742&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap image large&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imagewrap&quot; data-crop-type=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/04/24/marcus-washington-vocational-not-used_custom-125e6dee92f11423a2c4596456c23ab551d68347-s1100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/04/24/marcus-washington-vocational-not-used_custom-125e6dee92f11423a2c4596456c23ab551d68347-s1100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-wrap&quot; readability=&quot;8.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image caption&quot; readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Darren Redford, 20, looks to his instructor after completing a connector mockup drill at the Iron Workers Local Union #86 Administrative Offices in Tukwila, Wash. &lt;strong class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Sy Bean/The Hechinger Report&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong class=&quot;hide-caption&quot;&gt;hide caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;strong class=&quot;toggle-caption&quot;&gt;toggle caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Sy Bean/The Hechinger Report&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;They remember 'voc-ed' from what they were in high school, which is not necessarily what they aspire to for their own kids,&quot; Kreamer said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The parents &quot;are definitely harder to convince because there is that stigma of the six-pack-totin' ironworker,&quot; said Greg Christiansen, who runs the ironworkers training program. Added Kairie Pierce, apprenticeship and college director for the Washington State Labor Council of the AFL-CIO: &quot;It sort of has this connotation of being a dirty job. 'It's hard work — I want something better for my son or daughter.' &quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of the $200 million that California is spending on vocational education, $6 million is going into &lt;a href=&quot;http://doingwhatmatters.cccco.edu/Home.aspx&quot;&gt;a campaign&lt;/a&gt; to improve the way people regard it. The Lake Washington Institute of Technology changed its name from Lake Washington Technical College, said Goings, its president, to avoid being stereotyped as a vocational school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These perceptions fuel the worry that, if students are urged as early as the seventh grade to consider the trades, then low-income, first-generation and ethnic and racial minority high school students will be channeled into blue-collar jobs while wealthier and white classmates are pushed by their parents to get bachelor's degrees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;When CTE was vocational education, part of the reason we had a real disinvestment from the system was because we were tracking low-income and minority kids into these pathways,&quot; Kreamer said. &quot;There is this tension between, do you want to focus on the people who would get the most benefit from these programs, and — is that tracking?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res605263174&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap image medium&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imagewrap&quot; data-crop-type=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/04/24/marcus-washington-vocational-8_custom-938985d1dd4646dda6e4958e8fe1bbc0b280ab4b-s800-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/04/24/marcus-washington-vocational-8_custom-938985d1dd4646dda6e4958e8fe1bbc0b280ab4b-s800.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-wrap&quot; readability=&quot;8.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image caption&quot; readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amy Morrison Goings, president of the Lake Washington Institute of Technology, says, &quot;There isn't a day that goes by that a business doesn't contact the college and ask the faculty who's ready to go to work.&quot; &lt;strong class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Sy Bean/The Hechinger Report&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong class=&quot;hide-caption&quot;&gt;hide caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;strong class=&quot;toggle-caption&quot;&gt;toggle caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Sy Bean/The Hechinger Report&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a quest for prestige and rankings, and to bolster real-estate values, high schools also like to emphasize the number of their graduates who go on to four-year colleges and universities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jessica Bruce followed that path, enrolling in college after high school for one main reason: because she was recruited to play fast-pitch softball. &quot;I was still trying to figure out what I wanted to do with my life,&quot; she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She never earned her degree and now, she's an apprentice ironworker, making $32.42 an hour, or more than $60,000 a year, while continuing her training. At 5-foot-2, &quot;I can run with the big boys,&quot; she said, laughing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for whether anyone looks down on her for not having a bachelor's degree, Bruce doesn't particularly care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The misconception,&quot; she said, &quot;is that we don't make as much money.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then she laughed again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res605263725&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap image large&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imagewrap&quot; data-crop-type=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/04/24/marcus-washington-vocational-5_custom-b9c20c88e7b0264833639781f197325618117aff-s1100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/04/24/marcus-washington-vocational-5_custom-b9c20c88e7b0264833639781f197325618117aff-s1100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-wrap&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image caption&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taylor Fawcett, 23, moves a column during a connector mockup drill at the Iron Workers Local Union #86 Administrative Offices in Tukwila, Wash. &lt;strong class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Sy Bean/The Hechinger Report&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong class=&quot;hide-caption&quot;&gt;hide caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;strong class=&quot;toggle-caption&quot;&gt;toggle caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Sy Bean/The Hechinger Report&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 18:34:34 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>duck</dc:creator>
<og:title>High-Paying Trade Jobs Sit Empty, While High School Grads Line Up For University</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.npr.org/sections/ed/2018/04/25/605092520/high-paying-trade-jobs-sit-empty-while-high-school-grads-line-up-for-university</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Huge shortages loom in the skilled trades, which require less — and cheaper — training. Should that make students rethink the four-year degree?</og:description>
<og:image>https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/04/24/marcus-washington-vocational-1_wide-684f9781c62dcaaa7743a9d4126391ab4f4442ff.jpg?s=1400</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.npr.org/sections/ed/2018/04/25/605092520/high-paying-trade-jobs-sit-empty-while-high-school-grads-line-up-for-university</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>