<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Google AMP lowered our page speed, and there&amp;#039;s no choice but to use it</title>
<link>https://unlikekinds.com/article/google-amp-page-speed</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://unlikekinds.com/article/google-amp-page-speed</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;For those that don’t know, a very quick primer. AMP is a set of rules that publishers (typically news and analysis content providers) &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/search/docs/guides/mark-up-content&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;must abide by&lt;/a&gt; in order to appear in the “Top Stories” section of Google’s search results, a lucrative position at the top of the page. It’s also required for your content to appear as a “rich” result, meaning emphasized links with images, which can receive a lot more attention from users. AMP must be implemented by the publisher on their site, and it’s not trivial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google puts the onus on publishers to, effectively, rejig large tracts of their websites layout, content, and functionality, in return for preferential treatment. Google promotes AMP as a way to make websites faster. That’s supposed to be the primary benefit, and the reason Google is pushing AMP so forcefully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;amp-can-make-your-site-slower&quot;&gt;AMP can make your site slower&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We here at unlike kinds decided that we had to implement Google AMP. We have to be in the Top Stories section because otherwise we’re punted down the page and away from potential readers. We didn’t really want to; our site is already fast because we made it fast, largely with a combination of clever caching and minimal code. But hey, maybe AMP would speed things up. Maybe Google’s new future is bright.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It isn’t. According to Google’s own Page Speed Insights audit (which Google recommends to check your performance), the AMP version of articles got a performance score of 80. The non-AMP versions? 86. Mind you, the AMP versions are hobbled - unauthorised javascript interaction is forbidden by Google, so you can’t vote or comment in place - it’ll kick you to the full version of the page. This is the fruit of weeks of labour converting the site: a slower, less interactive, more clunky site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;google-doesnt-need-amp-to-rank-pages-by-speed&quot;&gt;Google doesn’t need AMP to rank pages by speed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But maybe this humble publication is so darn well made, our coders’ abilities so incredible, that when you consider all the slow sites out there, the greater good is served by bringing all sites up to scratch, performance-wise, even if fast sites are forced to slow down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But &lt;a href=&quot;https://webmasters.googleblog.com/2018/01/using-page-speed-in-mobile-search.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Google already ranks websites by speed&lt;/a&gt;. This tells us that every crawled site’s performance is measured in some way that Google finds accurate enough to use for a site’s ranking - you know, the position on Google’s results that can literally mean the difference between a failed business and one that makes millions of dollars, that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/tjmccue/2018/07/30/seo-industry-approaching-80-billion-but-all-you-want-is-more-web-traffic/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;an $80 billion industry&lt;/a&gt; is built upon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So you’d imagine that Google’s existing page speed ranking could easily be used to limit which sites appear in the carousel. Anything with a performance score below an 80 could appear as a performance issue in Google Search Console, and the site demoted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But no, Google insists you build your website with their technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;amp-isnt-about-speed-its-about-control&quot;&gt;AMP isn’t about speed. It’s about control.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AMP is an open source project. That evokes images of open, honest, collaboration amongst equals. But that’s not what’s happening. For a start, anyone contributing to AMP is required to sign a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ampproject/meta/issues/3&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;contributor license agreement&lt;/a&gt; (CLA) for their code to be accepted into the project. The CLA requires that you “grant to Google and to recipients of software distributed by Google a perpetual, worldwide, non-exclusive, no-charge, royalty-free, irrevocable copyright license”. There’s also a clause for much the same regarding any patents. Note, you don’t grant these rights to the AMP Project, you grant them to Google. Google owns the code and patents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The issues on AMP’s GitHub page is littered with revolts. Most notorious was Google’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/02/13/amp-for-email-is-a-terrible-idea/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;attempt&lt;/a&gt; to co-opt email itself. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ampproject/amphtml/issues/13457&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;issue is full&lt;/a&gt; of non-Google developers in open revolt against Google’s power-grab, with users describing it as misguided and user-hostile, complete with frequent use of the thumbs-down emoji. Google’s response? They’ve labeled the issue Priority 2: “Soon” and “INTENT TO IMPLEMENT”, and are powering ahead regardless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ampproject/amphtml/issues/4555&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;users begging Google&lt;/a&gt; to allow them to use more than 50kb of CSS. Yes, most site’s CSS is bloated. But 50kb is an absurdly small, arbitrary limit. Stylesheets these days handle resets for normalising behaviour between browsers, grid systems so you can lay things out without resorting to murder-suicide, and responsive queries so that your site looks great on mobile and desktop (and tablet and landscape and Android and iPhone.) These essential components will take you a decent way to to the 50kb already. If you’re looking to create an advanced layout or something unique and attractive, you’re shit out of luck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google’s own websites and apps are infamously bloated with CSS and JavaScript creating advanced layouts and interactivity, so you can imagine they think interactive or uniquely designed websites are worth the kilobytes. But customizability is for them, not for you. Publishers are limited to a meagre set of bundled components. If you believe in a web that’s beautiful with distinctive websites full of personality, it’s like trying to make an intricate sculpture out out of Legos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an example, you’re limited to using Google’s lightbox implementation. This component won’t let you allow users to close it by tapping on the image itself, instead they have to tap a black area around the image. It goes against the conventions established by other sites on the web, so users will inevitably struggle with it, as it behaves in a way that they won’t expect. And if you want something really nice for users, like scrolling up to dismiss the lightbox? Google says no. No javascript. Only components. Want to add a dark mode button? Google says no.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the core of the problem. If you’re trying to build a brand with something unique or distinctive, Google forbids you. And let’s not forget, it’ll be served from a Google domain, further diminishing your brand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure you can build 2 sites, one AMP, one non-AMP. But it won’t help. Instead you’ll confuse your users (and certainly not entice them) with links like “visit the full version of the site to comment”. Google even &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ampproject.org/docs/fundamentals/converting/discoverable&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;encourages publishers&lt;/a&gt; to make one version of their site. An AMP version. An internet where every publisher is using the same 30 components controlled by one company? No thanks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google’s in an incredible position of power. According to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/google-amp-gets-mixed-reviews-from-publishers-1477648838&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/a&gt;: Publishers who are critical of AMP were reluctant to speak publicly about their frustrations, or to remove their AMP content. One executive said he would not comment on the record for fear that Google might “turn some knob that hurts the company.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure, there’s a technical steering committee. 3/7 of them are Google employees, and the others are platforms: Microsoft, Twitter, Pinterest, and Pantheon (a web host, for some reason) - not the people actually making the content. Not the publishers like the New York Times, just the gatekeepers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-can-google-do-this&quot;&gt;Why can Google do this?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because they own the web. The top positions on Google’s results pages are highly lucrative. If you want to build a business around a website, you need to be up there. If you’re publishing news, you need to be in that Top Stories section. You can’t rely on hits from DuckDuckGo or Bing, you need Google. They own the web as much as they own Android’s Play Store. But at least on mobile you’ve got the option of choosing iPhone. For the web? You don’t. It’s only Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&quot;https://unlikekinds.com/article/how-google-is-getting-between-readers-and-publishers&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;instant answers&lt;/a&gt; where users read content scraped from your site without visiting it, to Google assistant reading your site with barely a nod in your direction, to AMP with plain, samey sites served on different coloured paper, and from a Google domain no less, they want people to visit Google. Not your site. Your site just feeds Google. All these recent initiatives see users consuming your content without even visiting your domain, and in some cases, without seeing your ads or your pleas to subscribe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If Google’s users were all served by scraped content in Instant Answers and Assistant answers, and dull, non-interactive websites served from Google’s domain, publishers become nothing more than a dumb pipe. But unlike ISPs, no one’s paying them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 23:13:57 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>luu</dc:creator>
<og:title>Google AMP lowered our page speed, and there's no choice but to use it</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://i.imgur.com/XFnI26x.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>https://unlikekinds.com/article/google-amp-page-speed</og:url>
<og:description>Google’s AMP project is supposed to speed up your web site. But what do you do when it makes your site slower? Do publishers have a real choice about using it?</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://unlikekinds.com/article/google-amp-page-speed</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Is Anyone Listening to You on Alexa? A Global Team Reviews Audio</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-04-10/is-anyone-listening-to-you-on-alexa-a-global-team-reviews-audio</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-04-10/is-anyone-listening-to-you-on-alexa-a-global-team-reviews-audio</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-04-10/is-anyone-listening-to-you-on-alexa-a-global-team-reviews-audio&quot;&gt;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-04-10/is-anyone-listening-to-you-on-alexa-a-global-team-reviews-audio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19629513&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19629513&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 246&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 138&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 22:53:03 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>minimaxir</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/tosv2.html?vid=&amp;uuid=fe4f9f00-5c2f-11e9-8959-efec44129356&amp;url=L25ld3MvYXJ0aWNsZXMvMjAxOS0wNC0xMC9pcy1hbnlvbmUtbGlzdGVuaW5nLXRvLXlvdS1vbi1hbGV4YS1hLWdsb2JhbC10ZWFtLXJldmlld3MtYXVkaW8=</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>996, GitHub, and China&amp;#039;s digital workers rights awakening</title>
<link>https://chanind.github.io/china/2019/04/10/github-996-china-digital-workers-rights.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://chanind.github.io/china/2019/04/10/github-996-china-digital-workers-rights.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://chanind.github.io/assets/fist.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Tech workers of the world, unite!&quot; width=&quot;150px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In China’s tech sector a peculiar uprising has begun: workers are demanding to be treated fairly. Even more fascinating is that the medium by which this movement is taking shape is via a single &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/996icu/996.ICU&quot;&gt;Github repo&lt;/a&gt;, which at the time of writing has over &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/996icu/996.ICU&quot;&gt;200,000 stars&lt;/a&gt; making it one of Github’s most popular repos of all time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;China’s tech sector is notorious for treating workers like machines, with extremely long working hours being the norm. The phrase &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/996_working_hour_system&quot;&gt;996&lt;/a&gt; refers to 9am - 9pm, 6 days per week, and is an unspoken rule in a lot of Chinese tech companies. The CEO of Youzan, a large Chinese e-commerce company, seemingly didn’t get the memo about keeping 996 as an “unspoken” rule, and surprised his employees at their 2019 yearly company party by telling them Youzan is officially &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zhihu.com/question/309428750&quot;&gt;switching to 996&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ironically, given that China is a communist country, workers’ rights movements and unions are extremely uncommon, so it’s refreshing to see tech workers using their collective power to push back against abusive employers. The 996 Github page maintains a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/996icu/996.ICU/tree/master/blacklist&quot;&gt;blacklist&lt;/a&gt; of tech companies that use 996 working hours, and a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/996icu/996.ICU/tree/master/whitelist&quot;&gt;whitelist&lt;/a&gt; of companies that have reasonable working hours, and encourages tech workers to quit their jobs if their employers insist on the abusive 996 work schedule. The repo also has an &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/996icu/996.ICU/blob/master/LICENSE&quot;&gt;anti-996 software license&lt;/a&gt; which projects can use which bans the software from being used by a 996 company. The license appears to be a modified MIT license with the addition of clauses restricting use by companies violating standard labor laws. The 996 website also points out that the 996 work-week is illegal under Chinese law, despite being so commonplace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time of writing, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://996.icu&quot;&gt;996 website&lt;/a&gt; isn’t blocked in China, but greedy tech companies have decided to block it themselves. Tencent’s Wechat refuses to open the site, as does Alibaba’s UC Browser and Qihoo’s 360 browser. It seems Chinese tech companies don’t want their employees getting the idea that they should be treated fairly. Given the popularity of the 996 repo, though, it seems that the word is getting out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;tech-workers-of-the-world-unite&quot;&gt;Tech workers of the world, unite!&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 22:45:50 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>chanind</dc:creator>
<og:title>996, Github, and China’s Digital Workers Rights Awakening</og:title>
<og:description>Javascript, Python, DevOps, and China</og:description>
<og:url>https://chanind.github.io/china/2019/04/10/github-996-china-digital-workers-rights.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://chanind.github.io/china/2019/04/10/github-996-china-digital-workers-rights.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>EU Agencies Falsely Report More Than 550 Archive.org URLs as Terrorist Content</title>
<link>https://blog.archive.org/2019/04/10/official-eu-agencies-falsely-report-more-than-550-archive-org-urls-as-terrorist-content/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.archive.org/2019/04/10/official-eu-agencies-falsely-report-more-than-550-archive-org-urls-as-terrorist-content/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The European Parliament is set to vote on legislation that would require websites that host user-generated content to take down material reported as terrorist content within one hour. We have some examples of current notices sent to the Internet Archive that we think illustrate very well why this requirement would be harmful to the free sharing of information and freedom of speech that the European Union pledges to safeguard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past week, the Internet Archive has received a series of email notices from Europol’s European Union Internet Referral Unit (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.europol.europa.eu/about-europol/eu-internet-referal-unit-eu-iru&quot;&gt;EU IRU&lt;/a&gt;) falsely identifying hundreds of URLs on archive.org as “terrorist propaganda”. At least one of these mistaken URLs was also identified as terrorist content in a separate take down notice from the French government’s L’Office Central de Lutte contre la Criminalité liée aux Technologies de l’Information et de la Communication (OCLCTIC).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet Archive has a few staff members that process takedown notices from law enforcement who operate in the Pacific time zone. Most of the falsely identified URLs mentioned here (including the report from the French government) were sent to us in the middle of the night – between midnight and 3am Pacific – and all of the reports were sent outside of the business hours of the Internet Archive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one-hour requirement essentially means that we would need to take reported URLs down automatically and do our best to review them after the fact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would be bad enough if the mistaken URLs in these examples were for a set of relatively obscure items on our site, but the EU IRU’s lists include some of the most visited pages on archive.org and materials that obviously have high scholarly and research value. See a summary below with specific examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EU IRU’s mistaken notices&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At least 550 archive.org URLs were falsely identified by the EU IRU in the past week as terrorist propaganda, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;major collection pages&lt;/strong&gt; (displaying millions of items), many pertaining only to material preserved and posted directly by the Internet Archive, others that include user-uploaded content, e.g.:
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;scholarly articles&lt;/strong&gt;, e.g.:
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;US Government-produced broadcasts and reports&lt;/strong&gt;, e.g.:
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;User-posted materials&lt;/strong&gt; that clearly do not fit the EU IRU notices’ description as terrorist propaganda, e.g.:
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Again, these examples are only a few of the some 550 falsely identified URLs. The erroneous reports continue to be sent to us by the EU IRU (the most recent example was sent a day prior to this post).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;French Government’s (OCLCTIC) mistaken notice&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The OCLCTIC emailed us a take down notice a few days ago (April 8&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;) identifying an item making commentary on the Quran as including “provocation of acts of terrorism or apology for such acts”:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.org/details/002Baqarah_201712&quot;&gt;https://archive.org/details/002Baqarah_201712&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The report stated that blocking procedures may be implemented against us if we did not remove the content in 24 hours. This URL was also on one of the lists that the EU IRU reported to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, we are left to ask – how can the proposed legislation realistically be said to honor freedom of speech if these are the types of reports that are currently coming from EU law enforcement and designated governmental reporting entities? It is not possible for us to process these reports using human review within a very limited timeframe like one hour. Are we to simply take what’s reported as “terrorism” at face value and risk the automatic removal of things like THE primary collection page for all books on archive.org?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 19:20:07 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jonah-archive</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.archive.org/2019/04/10/official-eu-agencies-falsely-report-more-than-550-archive-org-urls-as-terrorist-content/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Urgent Quest for Slower, Better News</title>
<link>https://www.newyorker.com/culture/annals-of-inquiry/the-urgent-quest-for-slower-better-news</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.newyorker.com/culture/annals-of-inquiry/the-urgent-quest-for-slower-better-news</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;SectionBreak SectionBreak__sectionBreak___1ppA7&quot; readability=&quot;180.91170925848&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last month, I decided to try an experiment with my media diet. Usually, in the morning, I skim e-mail newsletters in my in-box, scroll through my Twitter feed, and peruse the news apps on my phone; later, in the office, I tap through my notifications and monitor more than a dozen news-related apps, including Facebook and Twitter, while juggling other tasks. I usually feel as though I’m managing to stay abreast of the day’s biggest news stories, but my reading tends to be fragmentary—I’m only skimming a story or absorbing a partial update. Although I’m reading more than ever before, it often feels like I’m understanding less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven’t stopped getting my news in this way, but I’m trying to change my ways to a certain extent. I’ve adopted a new ritual: reading the print edition of the New York &lt;em class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt; over breakfast and on my commute. Since the early two-thousands, when I was a cub reporter at the &lt;em class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt;, I’ve had the newspaper delivered daily to my door, but, as I’ve started getting more and more of my news online, I’ve been neglecting it. Having returned to spending uninterrupted time with the print newspaper each morning, I’m engaging with the news in a more focussed way. Certainly, I’m able to read more broadly. I’ve read articles that weren’t in my social-media feeds, or that I missed while scrolling through my apps: reporting on efforts to make Copenhagen a carbon-neutral city, on talks between the United States and the Taliban, on a new study that found that the size of bullets affects mortality rates in shootings. It seems to me that I’ve become better informed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people have tried such experiments, of course. And much has been made of how being tethered to our phones affects everything from our attention spans to our psychological well-being. In his new book, “&lt;a class=&quot;ArticleBody__link___1FS03&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/0525536515/?tag=thneyo0f-20&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Digital Minimalism: Choosing a Focused Life in a Noisy World&lt;/a&gt;,” Cal Newport, a computer-science professor at Georgetown University, marshals evidence that the addictive properties of our devices are not accidental but, rather, the product of careful thinking by tech companies about the feedback loops that will keep people returning to them. Newport’s main indictment is of social-media platforms, but he also argues that people need to rethink the way they consume news. Exposure to the online torrent of “incomplete, redundant, and often contradictory” information that now invariably follows a major news event is counterproductive and leaves us less informed, he writes. Even when nothing earth-shattering is happening on a given day, he continues, people follow a compulsive pattern of media consumption, triggered by any hint of boredom. “If you’re interested in politics, for example, and lean toward the left side of the political spectrum, this sequence might go from CNN.com, to the New York &lt;em class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt; homepage, to &lt;em class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Politico&lt;/em&gt;, to the &lt;em class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Atlantic&lt;/em&gt;, to your Twitter feed, and finally to your Facebook timeline,” he explains. Techies might add Hacker News and Reddit; sports fans, ESPN. Media companies profit from this “lucrative tic.” “Checking ten different sites ten times a day makes them money, even if it doesn’t leave you more informed than checking one good site once a day,” he concludes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2008, the &lt;em class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Columbia Journalism Review&lt;/em&gt; published an &lt;a class=&quot;ArticleBody__link___1FS03&quot; href=&quot;https://archives.cjr.org/feature/overload_1.php&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; with the headline “Overload!,” which examined news fatigue in “an age of too much information.” When “Overload!” was published, BlackBerrys still dominated the smartphone market, push notifications hadn’t yet to come to the iPhone, retweets weren’t built into Twitter, and BuzzFeed News did not exist. Looking back, the idea of suffering from information overload in 2008 seems almost quaint. Now, more than a decade later, a fresh reckoning seems to be upon us. Last year, Tim Cook, the chief executive officer of Apple, unveiled a new iPhone feature, Screen Time, which allows users to track their phone activity. During an &lt;a class=&quot;ArticleBody__link___1FS03&quot; href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2018/06/26/apple-ceo-tim-cook-monitoring-his-own-iphone-usage-with-screen-time.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;interview&lt;/a&gt; at a &lt;em class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Fortune&lt;/em&gt; conference, Cook said that he was monitoring his own usage and had “slashed” the number of notifications he receives. “I think it has become clear to all of us that some of us are spending too much time on our devices,” Cook said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is worth considering how news organizations have contributed to the problems Newport and Cook describe. Media outlets have been reduced to fighting over a shrinking share of our attention online; as Facebook, Google, and other tech platforms have come to monopolize our digital lives, news organizations have had to assume a subsidiary role, relying on those sites for traffic. That dependence exerts a powerful influence on which stories are pursued, how they’re presented, and the speed and volume at which they’re turned out. In “&lt;a class=&quot;ArticleBody__link___1FS03&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/1101981113/?tag=thneyo0f-20&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;World Without Mind: the Existential Threat of Big Tech&lt;/a&gt;,” published in 2017, Franklin Foer, the former editor-in-chief of &lt;em class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The New Republic&lt;/em&gt;, writes about “a mad, shameless chase to gain clicks through Facebook” and “a relentless effort to game Google’s algorithms.” Newspapers and magazines have long sought to command large readerships, but these efforts used to be primarily the province of circulation departments; newsrooms were insulated from these pressures, with little sense of what readers actually read. Nowadays, at both legacy news organizations and those that were born online, audience metrics are everywhere. At the &lt;em class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt;, everyone in the newsroom has access to an internal, custom-built &lt;a class=&quot;ArticleBody__link___1FS03&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/05/23/technology/personaltech/metrics-media.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;analytics tool&lt;/a&gt; that shows how many people are reading each story, where those people are coming from, what devices they are using, how the stories are being promoted, and so on. Additional, commercially built audience tools, such as Chartbeat and Google Analytics, are also widely available. As the editor of newyorker.com, I keep a browser tab open to Parse.ly, an application that shows me, in real time, various readership numbers for the stories on our Web site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even at news organizations committed to insuring that editorial values—and not commercial interests—determine coverage, it can be difficult for editors to decide how much attention should be paid to these metrics. In “&lt;a class=&quot;ArticleBody__link___1FS03&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/0374279624/?tag=thneyo0f-20&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Breaking News: the Remaking of Journalism and Why It Matters&lt;/a&gt;,” Alan Rusbridger, the former editor-in-chief of the &lt;em class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Guardian&lt;/em&gt;, recounts the gradual introduction of metrics into his newspaper’s decision-making processes. The goal, he writes, is to have “a data-informed newsroom, not a data-led one.” But it’s hard to know when the former crosses over into being the latter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For digital-media organizations sustained by advertising, the temptations are almost irresistible. Each time a reader comes to a news site from a social-media or search platform, the visit, no matter how brief, brings in some amount of revenue. Foer calls this phenomenon “drive-by traffic.” As Facebook and Google have grown, they have pushed down advertising prices, and revenue-per-click from drive-by traffic has shrunk; even so, it continues to provide an incentive for any number of depressing modern media trends, including clickbait headlines, the proliferation of hastily written “hot takes,” and increasingly homogeneous coverage as everyone chases the same trending news stories, so as not to miss out on the traffic they will bring. Any content that is cheap to produce and has the potential to generate clicks on Facebook or Google is now a revenue-generating “audience opportunity.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In theory, a subscription-based model should be a dramatic improvement, substituting for the relentless pursuit of page views the superior goal of producing journalism that can’t be found anywhere else and is worth paying for. Foer asserts that subscription-based reader revenue is the only viable path for a media outlet seeking to maintain its editorial identity. There is a reassuring freedom in his imagined business model: instead of chasing legions of visitors who land on your site from a Google search on some trending topic and never return, a publication might focus on its true fans. “Media need to scale back their ambitions, to return to their niches, to reclaim the loyalty of core audiences,” Foer writes. “To rescue themselves, media will need to charge readers, and readers will need to pay.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the most common approach to subscription growth relies, to a fair extent, on many of the same tactics that ad-driven media businesses employ. Most news organizations pursuing consumer revenue have adopted a metered-paywall strategy, which gives readers access to a certain number of free articles per month before requiring a subscription for access. This allows nonsubscribers to get to know the publication, sampling a piece here and there, perhaps in the course of a few months or longer, before deciding to pay. And yet Facebook and Google remain essential gateways for getting readers into this so-called subscription funnel and pulling them through it. The tyranny of the trending story still holds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The work of transforming casual visitors into regular readers, moreover, creates its own set of incentives. The onslaught of news-related push notifications on our phones is due, in part, to the need to draw readers back, again and again. And enticing readers to subscribe requires the constant creation of new and varied material. It’s not enough for readers to immerse themselves in an article or two per month; they must develop &lt;a class=&quot;ArticleBody__link___1FS03&quot; href=&quot;https://www.americanpressinstitute.org/publications/reports/survey-research/paths-to-subscription/single-page/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;loyalty&lt;/a&gt; to a site, returning repeatedly until they hit the paywall. Quality is paramount—but it must also be produced at scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;SectionBreak SectionBreak__sectionBreak___1ppA7&quot; readability=&quot;126.15827338129&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lately, I have begun to wonder, like Newport, whether the sheer volume of online news actually runs counter to the goal of keeping people informed. Research on this question is surprisingly scant. “My hunch is that readers aren’t less informed than before,” Pablo Boczkowski, a professor of communication studies at Northwestern University, told me. “They’re differently informed.” Among Boczkowski’s areas of research is how young people interact with the news today. Most do not go online seeking the news; instead, they encounter it incidentally, on social media. They might get on their phones or computers to check for updates or messages from their friends, and, along the way, encounter a post from a news site. Few people sit down in the morning to read the print newspaper or make a point of watching the TV news in the evening. Instead, they are constantly “being touched, rubbed by the news,” Bockzkowski said. “It’s part of the environment.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How well can news be absorbed by osmosis? Studies have found that people bounce between tasks on their computers at stunning rates; a paper published last year found a median switch time of eleven seconds. Introduce mobile devices into the mix, and the switching is even faster. It’s no wonder that news is getting chopped up into smaller bits. “If you’re an average site, you have five to seven seconds to tell your story,” Boczkowski told me. It seems reasonable to guess, therefore, that people are now more aware, on a general level, of different topics in the news, but that they also have less depth of understanding in any one area. Even those readers who are inclined to engage deeply and broadly with the news are constrained by social-media filter bubbles, within which agreeable content, posted by people in their networks, is prioritized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A central purpose of journalism is the creation of an informed citizenry. And yet––especially in an environment of free-floating, ambient news––it’s not entirely clear what it means to be informed. In his book “&lt;a class=&quot;ArticleBody__link___1FS03&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/0684827298/?tag=thneyo0f-20&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;The Good Citizen&lt;/a&gt;,” from 1998, Michael Schudson, a sociologist who now teaches at Columbia’s journalism school, argues that the ideal of the “informed citizen”––a person with the time, discipline, and expertise needed to steep him- or herself in politics and become fully engaged in our civic life—has always been an unrealistic one. The Founders, he writes, expected citizens to possess relatively little political knowledge; the ideal of the informed citizen didn’t take hold until more than a century later, when Progressive-era reformers sought to rein in the party machines and empower individual voters to make thoughtful decisions. (It was also during this period that the independent press began to emerge as a commercial phenomenon, and the press corps became increasingly professionalized.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schudson proposes a model for citizenship that he believes to be more true to life: the “monitorial citizen”—a person who is watchful of what’s going on in politics but isn’t always fully engaged. “The monitorial citizen engages in environmental surveillance more than information-gathering,” he writes. “Picture parents watching small children at the community pool. They are not gathering information; they are keeping an eye on the scene. They look inactive, but they are poised for action if action is required.” Schudson contends that monitorial citizens might even be “better informed than citizens of the past in that, somewhere in their heads, they have more bits of information.” When the time is right, they will deploy this information—to vote a corrupt lawmaker out of office, say, or to approve an important ballot measure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In theory, the social-media age could make us better monitorial citizens. But Schudson’s model, which assumes that monitorial citizens will be activated at appropriate moments, didn’t anticipate the ease with which Facebook, Twitter, and other platforms can set off panics at the pool. The danger today—as phenomena such as Brexit and anti-vaccine activism demonstrate—is one of false alarms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2017, the cognitive scientists Steven Sloman and Philip Fernbach published the book “&lt;a class=&quot;ArticleBody__link___1FS03&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/039918435X/?tag=thneyo0f-20&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;The Knowledge Illusion: Why We Never Think Alone&lt;/a&gt;.” Their book, which is about the perils of superficial knowledge, offers as good an explanation as any of how our social-media-based news ecosystem is leading to undesirable outcomes in our democracy. People vastly overestimate what they know, and their unjustifiably strong opinions are reinforced by other people who are similarly ill-informed, creating self-reinforcing communities of misinformation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When group members don’t know much but share a position, members of the group can reinforce one another’s sense of understanding, leading everyone to feel like their position is justified and their mission is clear, even when there is no real expertise to give it solid support. Everyone sees everyone else as justifying their view so that opinion rests on a mirage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That same year, my colleague Elizabeth Kolbert cited Sloman and Fernbach’s work in a piece called “&lt;a class=&quot;ArticleBody__link___1FS03&quot; href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2017/02/27/why-facts-dont-change-our-minds&quot;&gt;Why Facts Don’t Change Our Minds&lt;/a&gt;.” “If your position on, say, the Affordable Care Act is baseless and I rely on it, then my opinion is also baseless,” she explains. “When I talk to Tom and he decides he agrees with me, his opinion is also baseless, but now that the three of us concur we feel that much more smug about our views. If we all now dismiss as unconvincing any information that contradicts our opinion, you get, well, the Trump Administration.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it turns out, there is a way to puncture this illusion of knowledge. It involves forcing people to explain in detail what would happen if their views on a specific public-policy issue were put into practice. It’s when we try to provide a “causal explanation,” Sloman and Ferbach write, that we realize how ignorant we are. That realization, in turn, leads us to become less extreme in our views. This insight has an obvious implication for media: depth matters. Journalism that engages with complexity, examines the implications of proposed policies, and offers the public rigorous analysis can lead to a more informed—and less polarized—citizenry. And yet, if Schudson is right, then only a small portion of readers will have the time, inclination, and disposition to become so ideally informed. Far more people will be monitorial, rather than informed, citizens—and, thanks to social media and high-volume news operations, they will be easily alarmed and distracted. Adding yet more stories to this maelstrom may make a certain economic sense for media organizations, but it won’t necessarily make us any better informed. It might only further fragment our knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;SectionBreak SectionBreak__sectionBreak___1ppA7&quot; readability=&quot;67.827951564077&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps we need to recalibrate our relationship with media—to rethink how we ought to consume information more generally and what it means to be informed. In the recent book “&lt;a class=&quot;ArticleBody__link___1FS03&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/0190641797/?tag=thneyo0f-20&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Slow Media: Why ‘Slow’ is Satisfying, Sustainable, and Smart&lt;/a&gt;,” the journalist and media scholar Jennifer Rauch traces a movement that began to coalesce about a decade ago. In 2010, a document called “&lt;a class=&quot;ArticleBody__link___1FS03&quot; href=&quot;http://en.slow-media.net/manifesto&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Slow Media Manifesto&lt;/a&gt;” was published, online, by Sabria David, Jörg Blumtritt, and Benedikt Köhler—a trio of Germans with backgrounds in media and technology. It urged both journalists and readers to draw inspiration from the Slow Food movement, which emphasizes quality and timelessness. “Slow Media are not about fast consumption but about choosing the ingredients mindfully and preparing them in a concentrated manner,” the authors wrote. “Slow Media cannot be consumed casually, but provoke the full concentration of their users. As with the production of a good meal, which demands the full attention of all senses by the cook and his guests, Slow Media can only be consumed with pleasure in focused alertness.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rauch points to the U.K.-based quarterly &lt;a class=&quot;ArticleBody__link___1FS03&quot; href=&quot;https://www.slow-journalism.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Delayed Gratification&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which was established in 2011, as an example of Slow Media in action. &lt;em class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Delayed Gratification&lt;/em&gt;, which has a Web site but is primarily print-based, describes itself as “the world’s first Slow Journalism magazine.” It promises to revisit “the events of the previous three months to see what happened after the dust settled and the news agenda moved on” and declares itself “proud to be ‘Last to Breaking News.’ ” Meanwhile, earlier this year, James Harding, the former director of news and current affairs at the BBC; Katie Vanneck-Smith, the former president of Dow Jones; and Matthew Barzun, the former U.S. Ambassador to the United Kingdom, launched &lt;a class=&quot;ArticleBody__link___1FS03&quot; href=&quot;https://www.tortoisemedia.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Tortoise Media&lt;/a&gt;, which aims to publish five digital stories a day, along with a quarterly print magazine. Tortoise was formed as a direct response to the overwhelming amount of “daily noise” in the news ecosystem. “The problem isn’t just fake news or junk news,” a statement on the Web site says, “because there’s a lot of good—it’s just that there’s so much of it and so much of it is the same. In a hurry, partial, and confusing. Too many newsrooms chasing the news, but missing the story.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could journalism in general get slower? As I read about the Slow Media movement—which, so far, seems to be a mostly European phenomenon—I inevitably thought about trends in the magazine industry in the United States, where publications are experimenting with paywalls and churning out digital content. The appeal of Slow Media is that it pushes back against the technological pressures that are shaping journalism more broadly. (Newport advocates Slow Media in a section of his book, urging readers to join “the attention resistance.”) It is an attempt to take back control of the way we experience the news. It is also about relinquishing the illusion of knowledge that the passive consumption of news on social media facilitates and bringing our best selves to the act of becoming informed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The challenge for all media organizations, slow or not, is to chart an economically sustainable, responsible course through this landscape of conflicting incentives and ideals. The pressures for speed and volume created by the digital age can’t be ignored—but they can be resisted. Even as publishers try to move more quickly, they can still ask themselves whether granular coverage in a given area is really making readers better informed. They can still consider sitting out certain trending stories, and they can do more, across the board, to engage with complexity. Readers, too, can begin to realize they’re being ill-served by the current media cacophony. Let’s hope that, when they search for alternatives, they will still be able to find journalism capable of rising above the din.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 18:35:19 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>hhs</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://media.newyorker.com/photos/5cad4161ece1841a020ad5ac/16:9/w_1200,h_630,c_limit/luo-slownews.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>The Urgent Quest for Slower, Better News</og:title>
<og:description>The current system for delivering news online is broken. Readers and journalists will need to work together to find a new one.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.newyorker.com/culture/annals-of-inquiry/the-urgent-quest-for-slower-better-news</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.newyorker.com/culture/annals-of-inquiry/the-urgent-quest-for-slower-better-news</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Google launches an end-to-end AI platform</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2019/04/10/google-expands-its-ai-services/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2019/04/10/google-expands-its-ai-services/</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot;&gt;As expected, &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/google&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;google&quot;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt; used the second day of its annual &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/tag/google-cloud-next-2019/&quot;&gt;Cloud Next conference&lt;/a&gt; to shine a spotlight on its AI tools. The company made a dizzying number of announcements today, but at the core of all of these new tools and services is the company’s plan to democratize AI and machine learning with pre-built models and easier to use services, while also giving more advanced developers the tools to build their own custom models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The highlight of today’s announcements is the beta launch of the company’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/ai-platform/&quot;&gt;AI Platform&lt;/a&gt;. The idea here is to offer developers and data scientists an end-to-end service for building, testing and deploying their own models. To do this, the service brings together a variety of existing and new products that allow you to build a full data pipeline to pull in data, label it (with the help of a new built-in labeling service) and then either use existing classification, object recognition or entity extraction models, or use existing tools like AutoML or the Cloud Machine Learning engine to train and deploy custom models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The AI Platform is this place where, if you are taking this terrifying journey from a journeyman idea of how you can use AI in your enterprise, all the way through launch and a safe, reliable deployment, the AI Platform help you move between each of these stages in a safe way so that you can start with exploratory data analysis, start to build models using your data scientists, decide that you want to use this specific model, and then with essentially one click be able to deploy it,” a Google spokesperson said during a press conference ahead of today’s official announcement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-1810433 alignleft&quot; src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/automl.jpg?w=680&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;353&quot; height=&quot;238&quot; srcset=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/automl.jpg 692w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/automl.jpg?resize=150,101 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/automl.jpg?resize=300,202 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/automl.jpg?resize=680,459 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/automl.jpg?resize=50,34 50w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 353px) 100vw, 353px&quot;/&gt;But there is plenty more AI news, too, mostly courtesy of Cloud &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/automl/&quot;&gt;AutoML&lt;/a&gt;, Google’s tool for automating the model training process for developers with limited machine learning expertise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of these new features is &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/blog/products/data-analytics/google-cloud-smart-analytics-accelerates-your-business-transformation&quot;&gt;AutoML Tables&lt;/a&gt;, which takes existing tabular data that may sit in Google’s BigQuery database or in a storage service and automatically creates a model that will predict the value of a given column.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also new is AutoML Video Intelligence (now in beta), which can automatically annotate and tag video, using object recognition to classify video content and make it searchable. For detecting objects in photos, Google also today launched the beta of AutoML Vision and for applications that run at the edge, Google launched the beta AutoML Vision Edge, which includes the ability to then deploy these models to edge devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/IMG_20190410_095309.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;breakout aligncenter size-full wp-image-1810538&quot; src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/IMG_20190410_095309.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;439&quot; srcset=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/IMG_20190410_095309.jpg 3891w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/IMG_20190410_095309.jpg?resize=150,64 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/IMG_20190410_095309.jpg?resize=300,129 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/IMG_20190410_095309.jpg?resize=768,329 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/IMG_20190410_095309.jpg?resize=680,292 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/IMG_20190410_095309.jpg?resize=50,21 50w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of enterprise data comes in the form of straightforward, unstructured text, though. For these use cases, Google today launched the betas of its custom entity extraction service and a custom sentiment analysis service. Both of these tools can be customized to fit the needs of a given organization. It’s one thing to use a generic entity extraction service to understand documents, but for most businesses, the real value here is to be able to pull out information that may be very specific to their needs and processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talking about documents, Google also today announced the beta of its &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/solutions/document-understanding/&quot;&gt;Document Understanding API&lt;/a&gt;. This is a new platform that can automatically analyze scanned or digital documents. The service basically combines the ability to turn a scanned page into machine-readable text and then use Google’s other machine learning services to extract data from it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After introducing it in preview last year, the company also today launched the beta of its Contact Center AI. This service, which was built with partners like Twilio, Vonage, Cisco, Five9, Genesys and Mitel, offers a full contact center AI solution that uses tools like Dialogflow and Google’s text-to-speech capabilities to allow its users to build a virtual agent system (and when things go awry, it can pass the customer to a human agent).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s no secret that many enterprises struggle to combine all of these tools and services into a coherent platform for their own needs. Maybe it’s no surprise then that Google also today launched it first AI solution for a specific vertical: Google Cloud Retail. This service combines the company’s Vision Product Search, Recommendations AI and AutoML Tables into a single solution for tackling retail use cases. Chances are, we will see more of the packages for other verticals in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/tag/google-cloud-next-2019&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/google-cloud-next-2019-banner.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 16:28:52 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kjhughes</dc:creator>
<og:title>Google launches an end-to-end AI platform</og:title>
<og:description>As expected, Google used the second day of its annual Cloud Next conference to shine a spotlight on its AI tools. The company made a dizzying number of announcements today, but at the core of all of these new tools and services is the company’s plan to democratize AI and machine learning with…</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/00000IMG_00000_BURST20190409162701416_COVER.jpg?w=533</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2019/04/10/google-expands-its-ai-services/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2019/04/10/google-expands-its-ai-services/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Problem with ‘5 Whys’ (2016)</title>
<link>https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;boxed-text&quot; id=&quot;boxed-text-1&quot; readability=&quot;60&quot;&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-1&quot;&gt;‘The Problem with…’ series covers controversial topics related to efforts to improve healthcare quality, including widely recommended but deceptively difficult strategies for improvement and pervasive problems that seem to resist solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;sec-1&quot; readability=&quot;33.666884389288&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-2&quot;&gt;The ‘5 whys’ technique is one of the most widely taught approaches to root-cause analysis (RCA) in healthcare. Its use is promoted by the WHO,&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-1-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-1&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt; the English National Health Service,&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-2-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-2&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt; the Institute for Healthcare Improvement,&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-3-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-3&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt; the Joint Commission&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-4-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-4&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt; and many other organisations in the field of healthcare quality and safety. Like most such tools, though, its popularity is not the result of any evidence that it is effective.&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-5-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-5&quot;&gt;5–8&lt;/a&gt; Instead, it probably owes its place in the curriculum and practice of RCA to a combination of pedigree, simplicity and pedagogy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-3&quot;&gt;In terms of pedigree, ‘5 whys’ traces its roots back to the Toyota Production System (TPS).&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-9-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-9&quot;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt; It also plays a key role in Lean&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-10-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-10&quot;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt; (a generic version of TPS) as well as Six Sigma,&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-11-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-11&quot;&gt;11&lt;/a&gt; another popular quality improvement (QI) methodology. Taiichi Ohno describes ‘5 whys’ as central to the TPS methodology:&lt;q id=&quot;disp-quote-1&quot;&gt;The basis of Toyota's scientific approach is to ask why five times whenever we find a problem … By repeating why five times, the nature of the problem as well as its solution becomes clear. The solution, or the how-to, is designated as ‘1H.’ Thus, ‘Five whys equal one how’ (5W=1H). (ref. &lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-9-2&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-9&quot;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;, p. 123)&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;p-5&quot;&gt;This quote also makes the case for the technique's simplicity. Asking ‘why’ five times allows users to arrive at a single root cause that might not have been obvious at the outset. It may also inspire a single solution to address that root cause (though it is not clear that the ‘1H’ side of the equation has been adopted as widely).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;sec-2&quot; readability=&quot;80.652360515021&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;&quot;&gt;‘5 whys’ as a teaching tool&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-6&quot;&gt;The pedagogical argument for ‘5 whys’ is that it creates an ‘aha moment’ by revealing the hidden influence of a distant cause, which illustrates the importance of digging deeper into a causal pathway. This quick and easy learning experience can be a powerful lesson in systems safety and QI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Possibly the most famous ‘5 whys’ case study to be used in this way focuses on efforts to preserve the Washington Monument.&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-12-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-12&quot;&gt;12&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;xref-sep&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-13-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-13&quot;&gt;13&lt;/a&gt; Details vary slightly depending on the source, but it usually looks something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-15&quot;&gt;This is a great teaching example because the ‘root cause’ is so unintuitive. Who would think, before exploring the issue in depth, that lighting choices could endanger a marble monument? But, as is so often the case, reality is messier than this simple illustration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-16&quot;&gt;Joel Gross&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-12-2&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-12&quot;&gt;12&lt;/a&gt; investigated the foundation of this example and discovered that many of the details are incorrect. And, crucially, the broader story it tells is incomplete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-17&quot;&gt;In terms of the story's details, the monument is question was actually the Lincoln Memorial, and it was not being damaged by the use of harsh chemicals. The real culprit was simply water. Pigeons were not an issue at all, and while there were ‘tiny spiders’ (ref. &lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-14-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-14&quot;&gt;14&lt;/a&gt;, p. 8) at the memorial, they were not a major problem. Instead, most of the cleaning was necessary because swarms of midges were dazzled by the lights and flew at high speed into the walls of the memorial, leaving it splattered with bits of the insects and their eggs.&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-12-3&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-12&quot;&gt;12&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;xref-sep&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-14-2&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-14&quot;&gt;14&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-18&quot;&gt;But that only speaks to the details that &lt;em&gt;were&lt;/em&gt; described. The analysis is also incomplete in a number of more important ways. For instance, it only addresses one potential source of deterioration: cleaning water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-19&quot;&gt;The first ‘why’ could just as easily have tackled other causes, such as rain or acid rain (a significant concern at the time), rising damp, erosion from windborne particles or damage from freeze-thaw cycles.&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-15-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-15&quot;&gt;15&lt;/a&gt; Or, if the goal had been to prevent harm to future monuments, the first ‘why’ could have focused on the use of marble as a building material, the choice of building site, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-20&quot;&gt;However, the most important problem with this example is that, while the solution was ‘effective’ in one sense, it still failed:&lt;q id=&quot;disp-quote-2&quot;&gt;Messersmith [the consultant entomologist who worked on this project] thought that because the insects swarmed only at sunset, a one-hour delay in turning on the monument lights would go far in solving the problem. The technique worked, reducing the number of midges in the monuments by about 85 percent.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;q id=&quot;disp-quote-3&quot;&gt;‘But tourists who had driven hundreds of miles to have their photographs taken at the monuments were not happy,’ he said. ‘They complained every day, and the lights went back on.’&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-16-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-16&quot;&gt;16&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-23&quot;&gt;The logic of the solution was sound, as far as it went. But it was predicated on an incomplete understanding of the broader system, its stakeholders and the purpose of the monument itself. If anything, this window on the complexity of real-world problem solving adds to the value of this teaching example. If the first ‘aha moment’ is followed by this second one, trainees will not only learn that distal causes can have unexpected outcomes, but also that systems thinking requires both depth &lt;em&gt;and breadth&lt;/em&gt; of analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;sec-3&quot; readability=&quot;93.633233994451&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The problem with ‘5 whys’ in RCA&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-24&quot;&gt;‘5 whys’ has been the subject of a number of caveats and critiques. For instance, Minoura, one of Ohno's successors at Toyota, highlights the potential for users to rely on off-the-cuff deduction, rather than situated observation when developing answers, as well as difficulty in prioritising causes, if multiple ‘5 whys’ are used.&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-17-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-17&quot;&gt;17&lt;/a&gt; Mark Graban, a thought leader in the Lean community, points out that ‘5 whys’ is just one component of what should be a far more comprehensive problem-solving process.&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-18-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-18&quot;&gt;18&lt;/a&gt; And Serrat clarifies that users should not feel constrained by the arbitrary number in the tool's title: more, or fewer, than five ‘whys’ may be required.&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-19-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-19&quot;&gt;19&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-25&quot;&gt;But the real problem with ‘5 whys’ is not &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; it is used in RCA, but rather that it so grossly oversimplifies the process of problem exploration that it should not be used at all. It forces users down a single analytical pathway for any given problem,&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-13-2&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-13&quot;&gt;13&lt;/a&gt; insists on a single root cause as the target for solutions&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-9-3&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-9&quot;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;xref-sep&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-13-3&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-13&quot;&gt;13&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;xref-sep&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-20-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-20&quot;&gt;20&lt;/a&gt; and assumes that the most distal link on the causal pathway (the fifth ‘why’) is inherently the most effective and efficient place to intervene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;sec-4&quot; class=&quot;subsection&quot; readability=&quot;67.536318834369&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A single causal pathway&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A credible ‘5 whys’ approach to a wrong patient medication error might look like this (adapted from Battles &lt;em&gt;et al&lt;/em&gt;):&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-21-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-21&quot;&gt;21&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-33&quot;&gt;But another team could easily come up with five wholly different and equally valid ‘whys’. And any single string of ‘5 whys’ can provide only a blinkered view of the complex causal pathway that led to the incident. This is illustrated by &lt;a id=&quot;xref-fig-1-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-fig&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#F1&quot;&gt;figure 1&lt;/a&gt;, a causal tree diagram (or, more accurately, a ‘causal and contributing factors tree diagram’) depicting the underlying issues that gave rise to the adverse event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;F1&quot; class=&quot;fig pos-float odd&quot; readability=&quot;4.6666666666667&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highwire-figure&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fig-inline-img-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fig-inline-img&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/qhc/26/8/671/F1.large.jpg?width=800&amp;amp;height=600&amp;amp;carousel=1&quot; title=&quot;A causal event tree (adapted from ref. 21). ID, identification; IT, information technology.&quot; class=&quot;highwire-fragment fragment-images colorbox-load&quot; rel=&quot;gallery-fragment-images-445883191&quot; data-figure-caption=&quot;&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;highwire-markup&amp;quot;&amp;gt;A causal event tree (adapted from ref. 21). ID, identification; IT, information technology.&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&quot; data-icon-position=&quot;&quot; data-hide-link-title=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;hw-responsive-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;highwire-fragment fragment-image lazyload&quot; alt=&quot;Figure 1&quot; src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7&quot; data-src=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/qhc/26/8/671/F1.medium.gif&quot; width=&quot;440&quot; height=&quot;336&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;highwire-fragment fragment-image&quot; alt=&quot;Figure 1&quot; src=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/qhc/26/8/671/F1.medium.gif&quot; width=&quot;440&quot; height=&quot;336&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div xmlns:xhtml=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml&quot; class=&quot;fig-caption&quot; readability=&quot;8.8217821782178&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;fig-label&quot;&gt;Figure 1&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-34&quot; class=&quot;first-child&quot;&gt;A causal event tree (adapted from ref. &lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-21-2&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-21&quot;&gt;21&lt;/a&gt;). ID, identification; IT, information technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-35&quot;&gt;It is clear from the tree diagram that the causal pathway related to the wristband printer is neither the &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; relevant cause of the incident nor indisputably the most important. A serious effort to solve the myriad problems that gave rise to this incident would have to tackle a number of other causal pathways as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-36&quot;&gt;These might include pathways related to a maladaptive workplace culture,&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-22-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-22&quot;&gt;22–25&lt;/a&gt; clinical and information technology (IT) staffing, orientation of agency staff and the absence of a forcing function&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-26-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-26&quot;&gt;26&lt;/a&gt; to ensure that patients are properly identified before medication is administered. It could also include a focus on improved infection control and better preparedness for infectious disease outbreaks. Solutions based on the ‘5 whys’ in the example above would leave all of these issues unaddressed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is also no objective or reliable means of mapping out the causal pathway, which is a critical failing when only one pathway will be examined. Consider the variant below, which follows essentially the same causal reasoning as the first example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-44&quot;&gt;This version skips the step of asking why the wristband was not checked and moves directly to asking why it was not there. It also sticks to the high-level issue of the printer being broken, without delving into the details of the label jam. ‘Skipping’ these questions allows the analysis to go deeper because it leaves more ‘whys’ available. This example also maintains a focus on issues &lt;em&gt;within&lt;/em&gt; the organisation, rather than the design of the printer. This would lead to very different solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-45&quot;&gt;But because this approach skips past the question of why the wristband was not checked, it closes the door to questions about other reasons why it was not checked. In &lt;a id=&quot;xref-fig-1-2&quot; class=&quot;xref-fig&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#F1&quot;&gt;figure 1&lt;/a&gt;, this would include the lack of a forcing function. But in another scenario, it might include a desire to avoid waking the patient;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-27-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-27&quot;&gt;27&lt;/a&gt; an unreadable wristband (eg, smudged, crinkled or occluded);&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-28-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-28&quot;&gt;28&lt;/a&gt; the lack of a label on the medication;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-29-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-29&quot;&gt;29&lt;/a&gt; confusion caused by multiple wristbands;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-30-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-30&quot;&gt;30&lt;/a&gt; lack of trust in the wristband data due to frequent errors&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-31-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-31&quot;&gt;31&lt;/a&gt; or any of a number of other causes.&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-28-2&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-28&quot;&gt;28–31&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users could also go down an entirely different causal pathway. An equally reasonable ‘5 whys’ for this incident could look like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-54&quot;&gt;There are many ‘correct’ ways a team might use ‘5 whys’ to assess even this one incident. And it is unlikely that any two teams would independently arrive at exactly the same results. This subjectivity is critically important because ‘5 whys’ focuses on only one root cause at the end of one causal pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-55&quot;&gt;More sophisticated practice in the use of ‘5 whys’ might produce two causal pathways, focusing on the main service failures uncovered, rather than the event itself (ie, a set of ‘5 whys’ for ‘wristband not checked’ and another for ‘verbal identification failure’). But this is not how use of the tool has generally been taught in the healthcare industry.&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-1-2&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-1&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;xref-sep&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-3-2&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-3&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;xref-sep&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-32-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-32&quot;&gt;32&lt;/a&gt; And even this unusually thorough approach would identify only 2 of the 30 causal pathways shown in the tree diagram.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;sec-5&quot; class=&quot;subsection&quot; readability=&quot;25.920671243326&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A single root cause&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-56&quot;&gt;Forcing users down a single causal pathway should be disqualifying by itself. But ‘5 whys’ narrows the scope for improvement even further by insisting that risk control efforts must focus on a single root cause for each causal pathway. In the first healthcare example above, for instance, the root cause would be ‘poor product design’, and this would serve as the sole target for improvement efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-57&quot;&gt;But accidents are seldom the result of a single root cause.&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-33-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-33&quot;&gt;33&lt;/a&gt; So focusing exclusively on one (or even a few) arbitrarily determined ‘root causes’ is not a reliable method for driving improvement—especially in a system as complex as healthcare. As Wieman and Wieman wrote: “Unfortunately … restricting the number of variables [considered] in a complex system only results in an increased potential for errors of omission” (ref. &lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-34-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-34&quot;&gt;34&lt;/a&gt;, p. 117).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-58&quot;&gt;How much might be omitted when using ‘5 whys’? The tree diagram for our example uncovers more than &lt;em&gt;75 whys&lt;/em&gt; (causes and contributing factors), each of which is a potential target for action to reduce the risk of a recurrence. The ‘5 whys’ approach would identify only one (or possibly two) root cause as target for action. At best, this represents &amp;lt;3% of the opportunities for improvement identified using the tree diagram.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;sec-6&quot; class=&quot;subsection&quot; readability=&quot;51.512880562061&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Targeting only the most distal cause&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-59&quot;&gt;Not only are users of ‘5 whys’ limited to one root cause per causal pathway, but they are also limited to selecting only the most distal cause (conventionally, the fifth ‘why’). There is, however, no logical reason to assume that this is always the most effective or most efficient target for intervention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-60&quot;&gt;Actually, if it were possible to magically place a 100% effective risk control at any one point on the tree diagram, it would be best used on a &lt;em&gt;proximate&lt;/em&gt; cause. For instance, making it impossible to administer medication without checking the wristband would render all the more distal causes moot for the purpose of preventing a recurrence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-61&quot;&gt;And, while 100% effective risk controls are seldom available, an action plan that includes a proven&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-26-2&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-26&quot;&gt;26&lt;/a&gt; (if certainly imperfect)&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-29-2&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-29&quot;&gt;29&lt;/a&gt; intervention like a well-designed bar-code reader with a forcing function for patient identification (ID) is more likely to prevent another serious ‘wrong patient’ medication error than switching to a well-designed printer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-62&quot;&gt;This is not to suggest that more distal causes are not appropriate targets for improvement efforts. In the example presented in &lt;a id=&quot;xref-fig-1-3&quot; class=&quot;xref-fig&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#F1&quot;&gt;figure 1&lt;/a&gt;, for instance, there is clearly a profound need to change the culture from one that is task-oriented and sometimes hostile to one that is outcomes-oriented and psychologically safe. The pervasive impact of such a culture change would be far more important than merely reducing the risk that this particular incident might recur; it would influence almost every quality and safety issue in the organisation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-63&quot;&gt;And, in contrast to that powerful-but-difficult lever for shifting outcomes, sometimes more distal causes represent ‘low-hanging fruit’ that can be addressed while a more proximate solution is in the works. In &lt;a id=&quot;xref-fig-1-4&quot; class=&quot;xref-fig&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#F1&quot;&gt;figure 1&lt;/a&gt;, educating patients about why clinicians will be constantly asking them to identify themselves would be far from foolproof. But it &lt;em&gt;would&lt;/em&gt; be fast, cheap and easy. And it might reduce an important barrier to best practice in verbal identification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-64&quot;&gt;Appropriate targets for intervention may occur anywhere along the causal continuum and on any causal pathway. And efforts to improve safety and quality will often require more than one intervention targeting more than one underlying hazard. It is useful to identify all the key hazards that gave rise to an incident and ensure that each of these is either addressed or intentionally accepted.&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-35-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-35&quot;&gt;35&lt;/a&gt; (See, for instance, the Options Evaluation Matrix.)&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-36-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-36&quot;&gt;36&lt;/a&gt; But the use of ‘5 whys’ makes this impossible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;sec-7&quot; readability=&quot;72.837696335079&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Considering the virtues of ‘5 whys’&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-65&quot;&gt;What, then, of the virtues of ‘5 whys?’ Are the issues above redeemed by the tool's simplicity and pedigree?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;sec-8&quot; class=&quot;subsection&quot; readability=&quot;42.647095959596&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Simplicity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-66&quot;&gt;Simplicity is a complicated virtue when it comes to the frameworks, tools and techniques of QI. For instance, the conceptual simplicity of the Plan-Do-Study-Act (PDSA) framework is one of its main selling points, but it may also lead organisations to underestimate the messy work involved in applying PDSA to real-world problems.&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-37-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-37&quot;&gt;37&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-67&quot;&gt;But, as this paper has shown, the ‘5 whys’ approach has clearly overshot the mark: it is not simple, but &lt;em&gt;simplistic&lt;/em&gt;. It is, as Leveson describes, “… perhaps the most simplistic [accident analysis technique] and … leads to the least amount of learning from events”.&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-13-4&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-13&quot;&gt;13&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-68&quot;&gt;Charles Vincent famously called for RCA to serve as “a window on the system”.&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-38-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-38&quot;&gt;38&lt;/a&gt; If that is the goal, then ‘5 whys’ is doomed to fail. It purposely discards the vast majority of what might be learned about the system being interrogated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-69&quot;&gt;The reality of most healthcare processes and systems is that we face classic design problems: problems that are highly contextualised and often “ill-defined, ill-structured, or ‘wicked’”&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-39-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-39&quot;&gt;39&lt;/a&gt; (ref. &lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-40-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-40&quot;&gt;40&lt;/a&gt;, p. 224). A ‘5 whys’ analysis ignores this. Most of the causal pathways that led to an event are amputated from the start, and consideration of those that remain is limited to a single root cause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-70&quot;&gt;This creates a &lt;em&gt;toy problem&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-fn-3-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-fn&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#fn-3&quot;&gt;i&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; in which it is assumed that simple optimisation of one, or at most a handful of variables will lead to improvement, without any need to consider the rest of the system. This flies in the face of everything we know about solving problems in complex adaptive systems like healthcare.&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-41-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-41&quot;&gt;41&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;sec-9&quot; class=&quot;subsection&quot; readability=&quot;55.115176715177&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Pedigree&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-71&quot;&gt;The positive reputation enjoyed by TPS/Lean provides an aura of credibility for ‘5 whys’. But how applicable is this to the question at hand? The reputation of TPS/Lean was built in a very different context. And the use of ‘5 whys’ as an RCA tool is by no means the same thing as the use of the full TPS/Lean methodology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-72&quot;&gt;Healthcare organisations are not automobile factories. And while there is much to be learned from the automotive industry and other high-reliability organisations (HROs), healthcare delivery will never be truly comparable to automobile manufacturing. Despite efforts in the healthcare industry to adopt the tenets of HROs,&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-42-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-42&quot;&gt;42&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;xref-sep&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-43-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-43&quot;&gt;43&lt;/a&gt; current practice provides recommended care only about 70% of the time.&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-44-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-44&quot;&gt;44&lt;/a&gt; And the percentage of hospital patients who experience an adverse event may be as high as 25–33%.&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-45-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-45&quot;&gt;45–50&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-73&quot;&gt;HROs commonly aim for a reliability rate of ‘six sigma’ (three errors per million opportunities). By these measures, healthcare is struggling to move beyond &lt;em&gt;two sigma&lt;/em&gt; (308 500 errors per million opportunities, or a 30.85% error rate).&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-51-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-51&quot;&gt;51&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-74&quot;&gt;Reliability in the healthcare industry can improve, and indeed it has (cf. ref. 52). But healthcare is far more complex&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-34-2&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-34&quot;&gt;34&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;xref-sep&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-53-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-53&quot;&gt;53&lt;/a&gt; than automobile manufacturing, and takes place amid processes and systems that are woefully underdesigned in comparison to a modern factory. Further, the safety and quality workforce in healthcare is only beginning to move towards professionalisation&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-54-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-54&quot;&gt;54&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;xref-sep&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-55-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-55&quot;&gt;55&lt;/a&gt; and often lacks formal training in engineering, human factors, ergonomics or similar domains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-75&quot;&gt;As a result, approaches developed for solving problems in the automotive manufacturing context may not be as effective in the healthcare arena. And, indeed, the evidence base for the use of Lean/TPS in healthcare is weak&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-56-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-56&quot;&gt;56–58&lt;/a&gt; and increasingly negative.&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-59-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-59&quot;&gt;59&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;xref-sep&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-60-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-60&quot;&gt;60&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-76&quot;&gt;It is also important to differentiate between the use of ‘5 whys’ as a QI &lt;em&gt;method&lt;/em&gt; and the use of Lean/TPS as a QI &lt;em&gt;methodology.&lt;/em&gt; Though the two are sometimes conflated in both the literature&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-59-2&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-59&quot;&gt;59&lt;/a&gt; and practice,&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-61-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-61&quot;&gt;61&lt;/a&gt; they are by no means equivalent. And the use of ‘5 whys’ in healthcare RCA is not typically part of a full-scale Lean management approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-77&quot;&gt;If the use of ‘5 whys’ does not imply the adoption of Lean, and if the evidence to date does not support the effectiveness of Lean in healthcare in any case, there is little reason to be swayed by the pedigree argument.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;sec-10&quot; class=&quot;subsection&quot; readability=&quot;43.021769337656&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Using ‘5 whys’ undermines an already weak RCA process&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-78&quot;&gt;A recent article by Peerally &lt;em&gt;et al&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-33-2&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-33&quot;&gt;33&lt;/a&gt; describes a number of important weaknesses in healthcare RCA practice. Some of these have been explored above (eg, focusing on a single root cause or a small handful of them; and poor quality investigations), but it also raises a number of other issues, such as misuse of the RCA process to pursue (or avoid) other agendas; failure to support feedback loops and double-loop learning; a focus on individual and isolated incidents; a confused approach to blame; the ‘problem of many hands’ (see also ref. &lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-63-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-63&quot;&gt;63&lt;/a&gt;) and the shortfalls of a retrospective approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-79&quot;&gt;The authors also note that RCA often results in poorly designed and/or poorly implemented risk controls.&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-33-3&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-33&quot;&gt;33&lt;/a&gt; While the goal of learning from incidents is to reduce risk and prevent future harm, the actual tools and techniques of current practice focus exclusively on diagnosing problems; they provide no direct support for prescribing and managing &lt;em&gt;treatments&lt;/em&gt; for the organisational pathologies they uncover.&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-64-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-64&quot;&gt;64&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;xref-sep&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-65-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-65&quot;&gt;65&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-80&quot;&gt;Some organisations have adopted the PDSA approach to continuous improvement of their risk control action plans.&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-37-2&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-37&quot;&gt;37&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;xref-sep&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-66-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-66&quot;&gt;66&lt;/a&gt; But this is a high-level framework, akin to the scientific method. And like the scientific method, it must be implemented through an appropriate set of tools and techniques to produce reliable results.&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-37-3&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-37&quot;&gt;37&lt;/a&gt; Although a handful of such tools have been introduced in recent years,&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-35-2&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-35&quot;&gt;35&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;xref-sep&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-36-2&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-36&quot;&gt;36&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;xref-sep&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-67-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-67&quot;&gt;67–72&lt;/a&gt; they have not yet been adopted as the current standard of practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-81&quot;&gt;Perhaps as a result, there is little evidence to suggest that current practice in RCA improves outcomes.&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-65-2&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-65&quot;&gt;65&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-82&quot;&gt;These challenges do not mean that RCA is never worthwhile; it certainly can be a source of important learning&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-73-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-73&quot;&gt;73&lt;/a&gt; and improvement.&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-74-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-74&quot;&gt;74&lt;/a&gt; But it &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; mean that we cannot afford to compound these problems through the use of an RCA tool that is so deeply and fundamentally flawed. Other more systems-focused techniques, such as fishbone&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-75-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-75&quot;&gt;75&lt;/a&gt; or lovebug diagrams,&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-72-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-72&quot;&gt;72&lt;/a&gt; causal tree diagrams,&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-21-3&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-21&quot;&gt;21&lt;/a&gt; Causal Analysis based on Systems Theory (CAST)&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-76-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-76&quot;&gt;76&lt;/a&gt; or even prospective risk assessment approaches,&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-77-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-77&quot;&gt;77–81&lt;/a&gt; should be considered instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section conclusions&quot; id=&quot;sec-11&quot; readability=&quot;20.923774954628&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-83&quot;&gt;When used carefully, ‘5 whys’ may play a powerful role in the classroom. It can illustrate both the need for depth (as a positive example) and the need for breadth (as a negative example) when analysing complex problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-84&quot;&gt;As a tool for conducting RCAs, however, especially in the area of patient safety, the use of ‘5 whys’ should be abandoned. As the (apocryphal) quote goes: “For every complex problem, there is an answer that is clear, simple and wrong”.&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-82-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671#ref-82&quot;&gt;82&lt;/a&gt; When it comes to accident investigation, ‘5 whys’ is that answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 15:39:31 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>zdw</dc:creator>
<og:title>The problem with ‘5 whys’</og:title>
<og:url>https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671</og:url>
<og:image>https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/sites/default/files/highwire/qhc/26/8.cover-source.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>‘The Problem with…’ series covers controversial topics related to efforts to improve healthcare quality, including widely recommended but deceptively difficult strategies for improvement and pervasive problems that seem to resist solution. The ‘5 whys’ technique is one of the most widely taught approaches to root-cause analysis (RCA) in healthcare. Its use is promoted by the WHO,1 the English National Health Service,2 the Institute for Healthcare Improvement,3 the Joint Commission4 and many other organisations in the field of healthcare quality and safety. Like most such tools, though, its popularity is not the result of any evidence that it is effective.5–8 Instead, it probably owes its place in the curriculum and practice of RCA to a combination of pedigree, simplicity and pedagogy. In terms of pedigree, ‘5 whys’ traces its roots back to the Toyota Production System (TPS).9 It also plays a key role in Lean10 (a generic version of TPS) as well as Six Sigma,11 another popular quality improvement (QI) methodology. Taiichi Ohno describes ‘5 whys’ as central to the TPS methodology:The basis of Toyota's scientific approach is to ask why five times whenever we find a problem … By repeating why five times, the nature of the problem as well as its solution becomes clear. The solution, or the how-to, is designated as ‘1H.’ Thus, ‘Five whys equal one how’ (5W=1H). (ref. 9, p. 123) This quote also makes the case for the technique's simplicity. Asking ‘why’ five times allows users to arrive at a single root cause that might not have been obvious at the outset. It may also inspire a single solution to address that root cause (though it is not clear that the ‘1H’ side of the equation has been adopted as widely). The pedagogical argument for …</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://qualitysafety.bmj.com/content/26/8/671</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Unveiling the first-ever image of a black hole [video]</title>
<link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Dr20f19czeE</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Dr20f19czeE</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;eow-description&quot; class=&quot;&quot;&gt;On 10 April 2019 at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Dr20f19czeE#&quot; onclick=&quot;yt.www.watch.player.seekTo(15*60+00);return false;&quot;&gt;15:00&lt;/a&gt; CEST (Brussels time) the European Commission presented a ground-breaking discovery by Event Horizon Telescope - an international scientific collaboration aiming to capture the first image of a black hole by creating a virtual Earth-sized telescope. EU-funded researchers play a key role in the project.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Six press conferences around the world took place simultaneously. In Europe, Commissioner Moedas and lead scientists funded by the European Research Council held a press conference in Brussels to unveil the discovery.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Learn more here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/redirect?event=video_description&amp;amp;v=Dr20f19czeE&amp;amp;redir_token=GKy5ctTaOPiWTn-VhAxpcJNFR8t8MTU1NTA1NjA4N0AxNTU0OTY5Njg3&amp;amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Feuropa.eu%2F%21nr97rr&quot; class=&quot;yt-uix-sessionlink&quot; data-sessionlink=&quot;itct=CDYQ6TgYACITCOrt2r7Jx-ECFYmpxAodKGIKPyj4HUjhm_P69Y_t3g4&quot; data-target-new-window=&quot;True&quot; data-url=&quot;/redirect?event=video_description&amp;amp;v=Dr20f19czeE&amp;amp;redir_token=GKy5ctTaOPiWTn-VhAxpcJNFR8t8MTU1NTA1NjA4N0AxNTU0OTY5Njg3&amp;amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Feuropa.eu%2F%21nr97rr&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://europa.eu/!nr97rr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/results?search_query=%23EHTBlackHole&quot; class=&quot;yt-uix-sessionlink&quot; data-sessionlink=&quot;itct=CDYQ6TgYACITCOrt2r7Jx-ECFYmpxAodKGIKPyj4HQ&quot; data-url=&quot;/results?search_query=%23EHTBlackHole&quot;&gt;#EHTBlackHole&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/results?search_query=%23BlackHoleDay&quot; class=&quot;yt-uix-sessionlink&quot; data-sessionlink=&quot;itct=CDYQ6TgYACITCOrt2r7Jx-ECFYmpxAodKGIKPyj4HQ&quot; data-url=&quot;/results?search_query=%23BlackHoleDay&quot;&gt;#BlackHoleDay&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/results?search_query=%23RealBlackHole&quot; class=&quot;yt-uix-sessionlink&quot; data-sessionlink=&quot;itct=CDYQ6TgYACITCOrt2r7Jx-ECFYmpxAodKGIKPyj4HQ&quot; data-url=&quot;/results?search_query=%23RealBlackHole&quot;&gt;#RealBlackHole&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/results?search_query=%23BlackHoles&quot; class=&quot;yt-uix-sessionlink&quot; data-sessionlink=&quot;itct=CDYQ6TgYACITCOrt2r7Jx-ECFYmpxAodKGIKPyj4HQ&quot; data-url=&quot;/results?search_query=%23BlackHoles&quot;&gt;#BlackHoles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 13:08:34 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>doktorn</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Dr20f19czeE</og:url>
<og:title>Breakthrough discovery in astronomy: first ever image of a black hole</og:title>
<og:image>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/Dr20f19czeE/maxresdefault.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>On 10 April 2019 at 15:00 CEST (Brussels time) the European Commission presented a ground-breaking discovery by Event Horizon Telescope - an international sc...</og:description>
<og:type>video.other</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Dr20f19czeE</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Startup Stock Options – Why a Good Deal Has Gone Bad</title>
<link>https://steveblank.com/2019/04/10/startup-stock-options-why-a-good-deal-has-gone-bad/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://steveblank.com/2019/04/10/startup-stock-options-why-a-good-deal-has-gone-bad/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hbr.org/2019/04/how-to-make-startup-stock-options-a-better-deal-for-employees&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;23506&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://steveblank.com/2017/06/27/why-you-cant-tell-a-company-be-more-like-a-startup/hbr-logo/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2017/06/hbr-logo.jpeg&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;288,168&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;HBR logo&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2017/06/hbr-logo.jpeg?w=288&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2017/06/hbr-logo.jpeg?w=288&quot; class=&quot;alignleft wp-image-23506 size-thumbnail&quot; src=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2017/06/hbr-logo.jpeg?w=150&amp;amp;h=88&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; height=&quot;88&quot; srcset=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2017/06/hbr-logo.jpeg?w=150&amp;amp;h=88 150w, https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2017/06/hbr-logo.jpeg 288w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A version of this article first appeared in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://hbr.org/2019/04/how-to-make-startup-stock-options-a-better-deal-for-employees&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Harvard Business Review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VC’s have just changed the ~50-year old social contract with startup employees. In doing so they may have removed one of the key incentives that made startups different from working in a large company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For most startup employee’s &lt;em&gt;startup stock options are now a bad deal&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Startups Offer Stock Options&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;In tech startups stock options were here almost from the beginning, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.financialpolicy.org/dscprimerstockoption2a.htm&quot;&gt;first offered to the founders in 1957 at Fairchild Semiconductor&lt;/a&gt;, the first chip startup in Silicon Valley. As Venture Capital emerged as an industry in the mid 1970’s, investors in venture-funded startups began to give stock options to &lt;em&gt;all &lt;/em&gt;their employees. On its surface this was a pretty radical idea. The investors were giving away part of their ownership of the company — not just to the founders, but to all employees. Why would they do that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stock options for all employees of startups served several purposes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Because startups didn’t have much cash and couldn’t compete with large companies in salary offers, stock options dangled in front of a potential employee were like offering a lottery ticket in exchange for a lower salary. Startup employees calculated that a) their hard work could change the odds and b) someday the stock options they were vesting might make them into millionaires.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Investors bet that by offering prospective hires a stake in the company’s future growth- &lt;em&gt;with a visible time horizon of a payoff&lt;/em&gt; – employees would act more like owners and work harder– and that would align employee interests with the investor interests. And the bet worked. It drove the relentless “do whatever it takes” culture of 20&lt;sup&gt;th &lt;/sup&gt;century Silicon Valley. We slept under the tables, and pulled all-nighters to get to first customer ship, man the booths at trade shows or ship products to make quarterly revenue – all because it was “our” company.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While founders had more stock than the other employees, they had the same type of stock options as the rest of the employees, and they only made money when everyone else did (though a lot more of it.) Back then, when Angel/Seed investing didn’t exist, to get the company started, founders put a lot more on the line – going without a salary, mortgaging their homes etc. This “we’re all in it together” kept founders and employees aligned on incentives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The mechanics of a stock option was a simple idea – you received an option (an offer) to buy a part of the company via &lt;em&gt;common &lt;/em&gt;stock options (called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.startupcompanylawyer.com/2008/03/05/whats-the-difference-between-an-iso-and-an-nso/&quot;&gt;ISOs or NSOs&lt;/a&gt;) at a low price (the “strike price”.) If the company was successful, you could sell it at a much higher price when the company went public (when its shares were listed on a stock exchange and could be freely traded) or was acquired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You didn’t get to own your stock options all at once. The stock trickled out over four years, as you would “vest” 1/48&lt;sup&gt;th &lt;/sup&gt;of the option each month. And just to make sure you were in the company for at least a year, with most stock option plans, unless you stayed an entire year, you wouldn’t vest any stock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/20th-century-startups.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;25049&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://steveblank.com/2019/04/10/startup-stock-options-why-a-good-deal-has-gone-bad/20th-century-startups/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/20th-century-startups.jpg&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;597,589&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;20th century startups&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/20th-century-startups.jpg?w=203&amp;amp;h=200&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/20th-century-startups.jpg?w=468&quot; class=&quot;alignright wp-image-25049&quot; src=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/20th-century-startups.jpg?w=203&amp;amp;h=200&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;203&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; srcset=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/20th-century-startups.jpg?w=203&amp;amp;h=200 203w, https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/20th-century-startups.jpg?w=406&amp;amp;h=400 406w, https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/20th-century-startups.jpg?w=150&amp;amp;h=148 150w, https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/20th-century-startups.jpg?w=300&amp;amp;h=296 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 203px) 100vw, 203px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Not everyone got the same amount of stock. The founders got most of the &lt;em&gt;common &lt;/em&gt;stock. Early employees got a smaller percentage, and later employees received even a smaller piece – fractions of a percent – versus the double digits the founders owned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the 20&lt;sup&gt;th &lt;/sup&gt;century, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1711.00661.pdf&quot;&gt;the best companies IPO’d in 6-8 years from startup&lt;/a&gt; (and in the Dot-Com bubble of 1996-1999 that could be as short as 2-3 years.) Of the four startups I was in that went public, it took as long as six years and as short as three.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One other thing to note is that all employees – founders, early employees and later ones – all had the same vesting deal – four years – and &lt;em&gt;no one made money on stock options until a “liquidity event&lt;/em&gt;” (a fancy word to mean when the company went public or got sold.) The rationale was that since there was no way for investors to make money until then, neither should anyone else.  Everyone—investors, founders and startup employees—was, so to speak, in the same boat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Startup Compensation Changes with Growth Capital – 12 Years to an IPO&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Much has changed about the economics of startups in the two decades. And &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/marksuster&quot;&gt;Mark Suster&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&quot;https://upfront.com/&quot;&gt;Upfront Capital&lt;/a&gt; has a great &lt;a href=&quot;https://bothsidesofthetable.com/a-deep-dive-into-what-has-really-changed-in-venture-capital-f5d225f7f8&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; that summarizes these changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first big idea is that unlike in the 20&lt;sup&gt;th &lt;/sup&gt;century when there were two phases of funding startups–&lt;em&gt;Seed &lt;/em&gt;capital and &lt;em&gt;Venture &lt;/em&gt;capital–today there is a new, third phase. It’s called &lt;em&gt;Growth &lt;/em&gt;capital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/21st-century-investors.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;25054&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://steveblank.com/2019/04/10/startup-stock-options-why-a-good-deal-has-gone-bad/21st-century-investors/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/21st-century-investors.jpg&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1862,625&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;21st century investors&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/21st-century-investors.jpg?w=300&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/21st-century-investors.jpg?w=468&amp;amp;h=157&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-25054&quot; src=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/21st-century-investors.jpg?w=468&amp;amp;h=157&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;468&quot; height=&quot;157&quot; srcset=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/21st-century-investors.jpg?w=468&amp;amp;h=157 468w, https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/21st-century-investors.jpg?w=936&amp;amp;h=314 936w, https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/21st-century-investors.jpg?w=150&amp;amp;h=50 150w, https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/21st-century-investors.jpg?w=300&amp;amp;h=101 300w, https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/21st-century-investors.jpg?w=768&amp;amp;h=258 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 468px) 100vw, 468px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Instead of a startup going public six to eight years after it was founded to raise capital to grow the company, today companies can do $50M+ funding rounds, deferring the need for an Initial Public Offering to 10 or more years after a company is founded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suster points out that &lt;em&gt;the longer the company stays private, the more valuable it becomes&lt;/em&gt;. And if during this time VC’s can hold onto their pro-rata (fancy word for what percentage of the startup they own), they can make a ton more money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The premise of Growth capital is that if that by staying private longer, all the growth upside that went to the public markets (Wall Street) could instead be made by the private investors (the VC’s and Growth Investors.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The three examples Suster uses – Salesforce, Google and Amazon – show how much more valuable the companies were &lt;em&gt;after &lt;/em&gt;their IPOs. Before these three went public, they weren’t unicorns – that is their market cap was less than a billion dollars. Twelve years later, Salesforce’s market cap was $18 billion, Google’s was $162 billion, and Amazon’s was $17 billion.&lt;a href=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/growth-appreciation.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;25052&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://steveblank.com/2019/04/10/startup-stock-options-why-a-good-deal-has-gone-bad/growth-appreciation/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/growth-appreciation.jpg&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1854,891&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;growth appreciation&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/growth-appreciation.jpg?w=300&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/growth-appreciation.jpg?w=468&amp;amp;h=225&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-25052 size-large&quot; src=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/growth-appreciation.jpg?w=468&amp;amp;h=225&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;468&quot; height=&quot;225&quot; srcset=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/growth-appreciation.jpg?w=468&amp;amp;h=225 468w, https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/growth-appreciation.jpg?w=936&amp;amp;h=450 936w, https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/growth-appreciation.jpg?w=150&amp;amp;h=72 150w, https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/growth-appreciation.jpg?w=300&amp;amp;h=144 300w, https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/growth-appreciation.jpg?w=768&amp;amp;h=369 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 468px) 100vw, 468px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;To Suster’s point, it isn’t that startups today can’t raise money by going public, it’s that their &lt;em&gt;investors can make &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;more money by keeping them private and going public later&lt;/em&gt; – now 10-12 years&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;And currently there is an influx of capital to do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Founders Rule&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;The emergence of Growth capital, and pushing an IPO out a decade or more, has led to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://hbr.org/2017/11/when-founders-go-too-far&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;dramatic shift in the balance of power&lt;/a&gt; between founders and investors. For three decades, from the mid-1970s to the early 2000s, the rules of the game were that a company must become profitable and hire a professional CEO before an IPO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That made sense. Twentieth-century companies, competing in slower-moving markets, could thrive for long periods on a single innovation. If the VCs threw out the founder, the professional CEO who stepped in could grow a company without creating something new. In that environment, replacing a founder was the rational decision. But 21st century companies face compressed technology cycles, which create the need for continuous innovation over a longer period of time. Who leads that process best? Often it is founders, whose creativity, comfort with disorder, and risk-taking are more valuable at a time when companies need to retain a startup culture even as they grow large.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the observation that founders added value during the long runup in the growth stage, VCs began to cede compensation and &lt;a href=&quot;https://hbr.org/2017/11/when-founders-go-too-far&quot;&gt;board control&lt;/a&gt; to founders. (See the HBR story &lt;a href=&quot;https://hbr.org/2017/11/when-founders-go-too-far&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Startup Stock Options – Why A Good Deal Has Gone Bad&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;While founders in the 20&lt;sup&gt;th &lt;/sup&gt;century had more stock than the rest of their employees, they had &lt;em&gt;the same type &lt;/em&gt;of stock options. &lt;em&gt;Today, that’s not true&lt;/em&gt;. Rather, when a startup first forms, the founders grant themselves &lt;em&gt;Restricted Stock Awards&lt;/em&gt; (RSA) instead of common stock options. Essentially the company sells them the stock at zero cost, and they &lt;a href=&quot;https://500.co/founder-equity-101/&quot;&gt;reverse vest.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/untitled.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;25050&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://steveblank.com/2019/04/10/startup-stock-options-why-a-good-deal-has-gone-bad/untitled-5/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/untitled.jpg&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1877,641&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Untitled&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/untitled.jpg?w=300&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/untitled.jpg?w=468&amp;amp;h=160&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-25050 size-large&quot; src=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/untitled.jpg?w=468&amp;amp;h=160&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;468&quot; height=&quot;160&quot; srcset=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/untitled.jpg?w=468&amp;amp;h=160 468w, https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/untitled.jpg?w=936&amp;amp;h=320 936w, https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/untitled.jpg?w=150&amp;amp;h=51 150w, https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/untitled.jpg?w=300&amp;amp;h=102 300w, https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/untitled.jpg?w=768&amp;amp;h=262 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 468px) 100vw, 468px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;In the 20&lt;sup&gt;th &lt;/sup&gt;century founders were taking a real risk on salary, betting their mortgage and future. Today that’s less true. Founders take a lot less risk, raise multimillion-dollar seed rounds and have the ability to cash out way before a liquidity event.&lt;a href=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/founders-vs-employees-stock.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;25056&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://steveblank.com/2019/04/10/startup-stock-options-why-a-good-deal-has-gone-bad/founders-vs-employees-stock/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/founders-vs-employees-stock.jpg&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1295,647&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;founders vs employees stock&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/founders-vs-employees-stock.jpg?w=300&amp;amp;h=150&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/founders-vs-employees-stock.jpg?w=468&quot; class=&quot;alignright size-medium wp-image-25056&quot; src=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/founders-vs-employees-stock.jpg?w=300&amp;amp;h=150&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; srcset=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/founders-vs-employees-stock.jpg?w=300&amp;amp;h=150 300w, https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/founders-vs-employees-stock.jpg?w=600&amp;amp;h=300 600w, https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/founders-vs-employees-stock.jpg?w=150&amp;amp;h=75 150w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Early employees take an equal risk that the company will crater, and they often work equally as hard.  However, today founders own 30-50 times more than a startup’s early employees. (What has happened in founder compensation and board control has mirrored the growth in corporate CEO compensation. In the last 50 years, corporate CEO pay went from 20 times an average employee to over 300 times their compensation.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of the founder/early employee stock disparity, &lt;em&gt;the VC’s have moved the liquidity goal posts but haven’t moved the vesting goal posts &lt;/em&gt;for non-founders. Consider that the &lt;a href=&quot;https://carta.com/blog/employment-tenure-startups/&quot;&gt;median tenure in a startup is 2 years&lt;/a&gt;. By year three, 50% of the employees will be gone. If you’re an early employee, today &lt;em&gt;the company may not go public until eight years after you vest&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why should non-founding employees of startups care? You’ll still own your stock, and you can leave and join another startup. There are four problems:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;First, as the company raises more money, the value of your initial stock option grant gets diluted by the new money in. (VC’s typically have pro-rata rights to keep their percentage of ownership intact, but employees don’t.) So while the VCs gain the upside from keeping a startup private, employees get the downside.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Second, when IPO’s no longer happen within the near time horizon of an employee’s tenure, the original rationale of stock options – offering prospective hires a stake in the company’s future growth with a visible time horizon of a payoff for their hard work – has disappeared. Now there’s &lt;em&gt;little financial reason to stay longer than the initial grant vesting.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Third, as the fair market value of the stock rises (to what the growth investors are paying), the high exercise price isn’t attractive for hiring new employees especially if they are concerned about having to &lt;a href=&quot;https://employeestockoptions.com/exercise-loan/&quot;&gt;leave and pay the high exercise price&lt;/a&gt; in order to keep the shares.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And finally, in many high valued startups where there are hungry investors, the founders get to sell parts of their vested shares at each round of funding. (At times this opportunity is offered to all employees in a “secondary” offering.) A “secondary” usually (though not always) &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@rizstanford/secondary-sales-in-vc-backed-startups-a-quick-primer-for-entrepreneurs-bdc25ea7f39a&quot;&gt;happens when the startup has achieved significant revenue or traction&lt;/a&gt; and is seen as a “leader” in their market space, on the way to an IPO or a major sale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The End of the High-Commitment/High-Performance Work System?&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;In the academic literature, the work environment of a startup is called a &lt;a href=&quot;https://nscpolteksby.ac.id/ebook/files/Ebook/Business%20Administration/ARMSTRONGS%20HANDBOOK%20OF%20HUMAN%20RESOURCE%20MANAGEMENT%20PRACTICE/13%20-%20High-perfomance%20Work%20Systems.pdf&quot;&gt;high-commitment/ high-performance work system&lt;/a&gt;. This is &lt;a href=&quot;https://libjournals.mtsu.edu/index.php/jsbs/article/view/611/658&quot;&gt;a bundle of Human Resources startup practices&lt;/a&gt; that include hiring, self-managing teams, rapid and decentralized decision-making, on-boarding, flexible work assignments, communication, &lt;em&gt;and stock options&lt;/em&gt;. And there is evidence that &lt;a href=&quot;https://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1098&amp;amp;context=workingpapers&quot;&gt;stock options increase the success of startups&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Successful startups need highly committed employees who believe in the goals and values of the company. In exchange for sharing in the potential upside—and being valued as a critical part of the team, they’re willing to rise to the expectation of putting work and the company in front of everything else. But this level of commitment depends on whether &lt;a href=&quot;https://core.ac.uk/download/pdf/140215.pdf&quot;&gt;employees perceive these practices to be fair&lt;/a&gt;, both in terms of the process and the outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VCs have intentionally changed the ~50-year-old social contract with startup employees. At the same time, &lt;em&gt;they may have removed one of the key incentives that made startups different from working in a large company&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While unique technology or market insight is one component of a successful startup everyone agrees that attracting &lt;u&gt;and retaining&lt;/u&gt; A+ talent differentiates the winners from the losers. In trying to keep companies private longer, but not pass any of that new value to the employees, the VC’s may have killed the golden goose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What Should Employees Do?&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;In the past the founders and employees were aligned with the same type of common stock grant, and it was the VCs who got preferential stock treatment. Today, if you’re an employee you’re now are at the bottom of the stock preference pile. The founders have preferential stock treatment and the VC have preferred stock. And you’re working just as hard. Add to that all the other known negatives of a startups– no work-life balance, insane hours, inexperienced management, risk of going out of business, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, joining a startup still has a lot of benefits for employees who are looking to work with high performance teams with little structure. Your impact likely be felt. Constant learning opportunities, responsibility and advancement are there for those who take it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re one of the early senior hires, there’s no downside of asking for the same Restricted Stock Agreements (RSAs) as the founders. And if you’re joining a larger startup, you may want to consider those who are offering restricted stock units (RSUs) rather than common stock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What Should Investors Do?&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;One possibility is to replace early employee (first ~10 employees) stock options with the same Restricted Stock Agreements (RSAs) as the founders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For later employees make sure the company offers “refresh” option grants to longer-tenured employees. Better yet, offer restricted stock units (RSUs). Restricted Stock Units are a company’s promise to give you shares of the company’s stock. Unlike a stock option, which always has a strike (purchase) price higher than $0, an RSU is an option with a $0 purchase price. The lower the strike price, the less you have to pay to own a share of company stock&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; Like stock options, RSU’s vest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But to keep employees engaged, they ought to be allowed buy their vested RSU stock and sell it every time the company raises a new round of funding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lessons Learned&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Venture Capital structures were set up for a world in which successful companies exited in 6-8 years and didn’t raise too much capital&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Venture capital growth funds are now giving startups the cash they would have received at an IPO
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;“Growth Capital” moved the need for an IPO out another five years&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This allows VCs to capture the increase in market cap in the company&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It may have removed the incentive for non-founders to want to work in a startup versus a large company&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As stock options with four-year vesting are no longer a good deal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Investors and Founders have changed the model to their advantage, but no one has changed the model for early employees
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;VCs need to consider a new stock incentive model – RSA’s for the first key hires and then RSU’s – Restricted Stock Units for everyone else&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Large companies now have an opportunity to attract some of the talent that previously went elsewhere&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;jp-post-flair&quot; class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-like-enabled sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;robots-nocontent sd-block sd-social sd-social-official sd-sharing&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Share this:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-block sd-like jetpack-likes-widget-wrapper jetpack-likes-widget-unloaded&quot; id=&quot;like-post-wrapper-6599589-25044-5caef441c8b2a&quot; data-src=&quot;//widgets.wp.com/likes/index.html?ver=20190321#blog_id=6599589&amp;amp;post_id=25044&amp;amp;origin=steveblank.wordpress.com&amp;amp;obj_id=6599589-25044-5caef441c8b2a&amp;amp;domain=steveblank.com&quot; data-name=&quot;like-post-frame-6599589-25044-5caef441c8b2a&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Like this:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;button&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Like&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;loading&quot;&gt;Loading...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;postinfo&quot;&gt;Filed under: &lt;a href=&quot;https://steveblank.com/category/venture-capital/&quot; rel=&quot;category tag&quot;&gt;Venture Capital&lt;/a&gt; |&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 13:01:43 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>furkansahin</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Steve Blank Startup Stock Options – Why A Good Deal Has Gone Bad</og:title>
<og:url>https://steveblank.com/2019/04/10/startup-stock-options-why-a-good-deal-has-gone-bad/</og:url>
<og:description>A version of this article first appeared in the Harvard Business Review VC’s have just changed the ~50-year old social contract with startup employees. In doing so they may have removed one o…</og:description>
<og:image>https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/20th-century-startups.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://steveblank.com/2019/04/10/startup-stock-options-why-a-good-deal-has-gone-bad/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Tesla Model 3 becomes best-selling car in Switzerland</title>
<link>https://electrek.co/2019/04/09/tesla-model-3-best-selling-car-period-switzerland/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://electrek.co/2019/04/09/tesla-model-3-best-selling-car-period-switzerland/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Tesla Model 3 became the best-selling car in Switzerland last month – beating not just other electric vehicles, but all passenger vehicles period.&lt;span id=&quot;more-89235&quot;/&gt; &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle author_ad&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-4655152367470280&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;5555766060&quot;/&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the last few months, Model 3 has become the best-selling electric car in virtually all markets it has been introduced in, but it is also starting to become the best-selling car period in some markets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like in Norway, but electric vehicles are always topping the charts in Norway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now Tesla is also dominating the market in Switzerland with the introduction of the Model 3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;notranslate&quot;&gt;Based on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nzz.ch/mobilitaet/auto-mobil/tesla-model-3-bestverkauftes-auto-in-der-schweiz-ld.1473810&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;registration data&lt;/a&gt;, Tesla delivered 1,094 Model 3 vehicles in Switzerland in March – beating the long-standing bestsellers Skoda Octavia (801) and the VW Golf (546).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Model 3 has helped Tesla already push its 2019 delivery numbers past its full-year 2018 delivery results:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;89236&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://electrek.co/2019/04/09/tesla-model-3-best-selling-car-period-switzerland/screen-shot-2019-04-09-at-3-03-37-pm/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://electrek.co/wp-content/uploads/sites/3/2019/04/Screen-Shot-2019-04-09-at-3.03.37-PM.jpg?quality=82&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1100,916&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Tesla Model 3 Switzerland&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://electrek.co/wp-content/uploads/sites/3/2019/04/Screen-Shot-2019-04-09-at-3.03.37-PM.jpg?quality=82&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=300&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://electrek.co/wp-content/uploads/sites/3/2019/04/Screen-Shot-2019-04-09-at-3.03.37-PM.jpg?quality=82&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1000&quot; title=&quot;Tesla Model 3 becomes best-selling car in Switzerland - not just electric&quot; class=&quot; wp-image-89236 aligncenter jetpack-lazy-image&quot; src=&quot;https://electrek.co/wp-content/uploads/sites/3/2019/04/Screen-Shot-2019-04-09-at-3.03.37-PM.jpg?quality=82&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; alt=&quot;Tesla Model 3 Switzerland&quot; width=&quot;867&quot; height=&quot;722&quot; data-lazy-srcset=&quot;https://electrek.co/wp-content/uploads/sites/3/2019/04/Screen-Shot-2019-04-09-at-3.03.37-PM.jpg 1100w, https://electrek.co/wp-content/uploads/sites/3/2019/04/Screen-Shot-2019-04-09-at-3.03.37-PM.jpg?resize=150,125 150w, https://electrek.co/wp-content/uploads/sites/3/2019/04/Screen-Shot-2019-04-09-at-3.03.37-PM.jpg?resize=300,250 300w, https://electrek.co/wp-content/uploads/sites/3/2019/04/Screen-Shot-2019-04-09-at-3.03.37-PM.jpg?resize=768,640 768w, https://electrek.co/wp-content/uploads/sites/3/2019/04/Screen-Shot-2019-04-09-at-3.03.37-PM.jpg?resize=1024,853 1024w, https://electrek.co/wp-content/uploads/sites/3/2019/04/Screen-Shot-2019-04-09-at-3.03.37-PM.jpg?resize=350,291 350w&quot; data-lazy-sizes=&quot;(max-width: 867px) 100vw, 867px&quot; data-lazy-src=&quot;https://electrek.co/wp-content/uploads/sites/3/2019/04/Screen-Shot-2019-04-09-at-3.03.37-PM.jpg?quality=82&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;is-pending-load=1&quot; srcset=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;89236&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://electrek.co/2019/04/09/tesla-model-3-best-selling-car-period-switzerland/screen-shot-2019-04-09-at-3-03-37-pm/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://electrek.co/wp-content/uploads/sites/3/2019/04/Screen-Shot-2019-04-09-at-3.03.37-PM.jpg?quality=82&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1100,916&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Tesla Model 3 Switzerland&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://electrek.co/wp-content/uploads/sites/3/2019/04/Screen-Shot-2019-04-09-at-3.03.37-PM.jpg?quality=82&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=300&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://electrek.co/wp-content/uploads/sites/3/2019/04/Screen-Shot-2019-04-09-at-3.03.37-PM.jpg?quality=82&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1000&quot; title=&quot;Tesla Model 3 becomes best-selling car in Switzerland - not just electric&quot; class=&quot; wp-image-89236 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://electrek.co/wp-content/uploads/sites/3/2019/04/Screen-Shot-2019-04-09-at-3.03.37-PM.jpg?quality=82&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; alt=&quot;Tesla Model 3 Switzerland&quot; width=&quot;867&quot; height=&quot;722&quot; srcset=&quot;https://electrek.co/wp-content/uploads/sites/3/2019/04/Screen-Shot-2019-04-09-at-3.03.37-PM.jpg 1100w, https://electrek.co/wp-content/uploads/sites/3/2019/04/Screen-Shot-2019-04-09-at-3.03.37-PM.jpg?resize=150,125 150w, https://electrek.co/wp-content/uploads/sites/3/2019/04/Screen-Shot-2019-04-09-at-3.03.37-PM.jpg?resize=300,250 300w, https://electrek.co/wp-content/uploads/sites/3/2019/04/Screen-Shot-2019-04-09-at-3.03.37-PM.jpg?resize=768,640 768w, https://electrek.co/wp-content/uploads/sites/3/2019/04/Screen-Shot-2019-04-09-at-3.03.37-PM.jpg?resize=1024,853 1024w, https://electrek.co/wp-content/uploads/sites/3/2019/04/Screen-Shot-2019-04-09-at-3.03.37-PM.jpg?resize=350,291 350w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 867px) 100vw, 867px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Switzerland has long been an important market for Tesla. The automaker has often delivered more vehicles in the small market than in the much bigger neighboring German market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tesla &lt;a class=&quot;gs-title&quot; href=&quot;https://electrek.co/2016/01/14/tesla-model-s-best-selling-switzerland/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; data-cturl=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?q=https://electrek.co/2016/01/14/tesla-model-s-best-selling-switzerland/&amp;amp;sa=U&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwiJ2s2-2sPhAhXp7IMKHQ9BCigQFggIMAE&amp;amp;client=internal-uds-cse&amp;amp;cx=008464549922976904202:3wy4ipwvlno&amp;amp;usg=AOvVaw1RLH3RoAHHsNb6HVpwW4V0&quot; data-ctorig=&quot;https://electrek.co/2016/01/14/tesla-model-s-best-selling-switzerland/&quot;&gt;Model S was often at the top of the best-selling electric cars in Switzerland&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Electrek’s Take&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I like to mention when discussing Tesla’s Model 3 deliveries in Europe, that’s just with the two most expensive versions of the Model 3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those numbers should go way up when Tesla introduces some less expensive versions of the vehicle later this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wouldn’t be surprised if Model 3 is in the top 5 of the bestselling vehicles in the most important auto markets in Europe several months later this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t think it will be consistent due to Tesla’s cyclical production and deliveries in Europe, but the numbers should still be extremely impressive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCcOIZzJgLCyMPILY7-1Vsdg?sub_confirmation=1&quot;&gt;Subscribe to Electrek on YouTube for exclusive videos&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.electrek.co/guide/electrek-podcast&quot;&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;. &lt;span class=&quot;embed-youtube&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe class=&quot;youtube-player&quot; type=&quot;text/html&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;563&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/xVp0Cr2Pg4g?version=3&amp;amp;rel=0&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;autohide=2&amp;amp;showsearch=0&amp;amp;showinfo=1&amp;amp;iv_load_policy=1&amp;amp;wmode=transparent&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 11:58:30 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>reddotX</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Tesla Model 3 becomes best-selling car in Switzerland – not just electric</og:title>
<og:url>https://electrek.co/2019/04/09/tesla-model-3-best-selling-car-period-switzerland/</og:url>
<og:description>Tesla Model 3 became the best-selling car in Switzerland last month – beating not just other electric vehicles, but all passenger vehicles period.</og:description>
<og:image>https://electrek.co/wp-content/uploads/sites/3/2018/06/screen-shot-2018-06-14-at-7-22-24-pm.jpg?quality=82&amp;strip=all&amp;w=1600</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://electrek.co/2019/04/09/tesla-model-3-best-selling-car-period-switzerland/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>