<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Should you learn C to “learn how the computer works”?</title>
<link>https://words.steveklabnik.com/should-you-learn-c-to-learn-how-the-computer-works</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://words.steveklabnik.com/should-you-learn-c-to-learn-how-the-computer-works</guid>
<description>&lt;time datetime=&quot;2018-10-02&quot; class=&quot;article_time&quot;&gt;October 2, 2018&lt;/time&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ve often seen people suggest that you should learn C in order to learn how computers work. Is this a good idea? Is this accurate? I’m going to start with my conclusion right upfront, just to be crystal clear about what I’m saying here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;C is not “how the computer works.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don’t think most people mean this phrase literally, so that is sort of irrelevant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understanding the context means that learning C for this reason may still be a good idea for you, depending on your objectives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;I plan on making two follow-up posts as well, exploring more implications of this idea, but this is already quite a lot. I’ll update this post with links to them when I make them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ve often seen people suggest this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;large&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By learning C, you can learn how computers work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that this idea is not inherently wrong, but does come with some caveats. As long as you keep those caveats in mind, I think this can be a viable strategy for learning new and important things. However, I rarely see people discuss this slogan in detail, so I’m writing this post so that I can provide that context that I believe is sorely needed. If you’re thinking about learning C for this reason, this post is written for you. I hope it’ll assist you as you learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;large&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we truly begin, I’d like to say one more thing: if you want to learn C, then learn C! Learning things is great. Learning C was quite important to my understanding of computing and my career. Learning C and about its place in programming language history will make you a better programmer. You don’t need a justification. Learn stuff for the sake of learning it. This post is intended to be a guide to your quest for understanding, not a suggestion that you should or should not learn C.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, let’s talk about who is generally recommended this idea. If you’re trying to “learn how computers work,” then it stands to reason that you don’t currently understand that. Which programmers don’t understand how computers work? I’ve mostly seen this sentiment come from people who primarily program in dynamically typed, “scripting” languages, like Ruby, Python, or JavaScript. They “don’t know how computers work” because these languages operate inside of a virtual machine, and therefore, the semantics of the virtual machine are what actually matters. After all, the whole idea of a virtual machine is to provide portability. The goal is to only require knowledge of what’s portable, rather than rely on the details of the hardware that the VM is running on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s just one problem with this: C &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; operates inside of a virtual machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-c-abstract-machine_2&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;head_anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://words.steveklabnik.com/should-you-learn-c-to-learn-how-the-computer-works#the-c-abstract-machine_2&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;The C abstract machine&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.open-std.org/jtc1/sc22/WG14/www/docs/n1256.pdf&quot;&gt;C99 spec&lt;/a&gt;, Section 5.1.2.3, “Program Execution”:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;large&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The semantic descriptions in this International Standard describe the behavior of an abstract machine in which issues of optimization are irrelevant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, this is the most important concept to understand when learning C. C does not “describe how the computer works,” it describes how the “C abstract machine” works. Everything else of importance flows from this concept and its implications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;large&quot; readability=&quot;12.539682539683&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A further note: I’ve chosen C99 here, which is not the latest C standard. Why? Well, &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/146381/visual-studio-support-for-new-c-c-standards&quot;&gt;MSVC has an …interesting amount of C support&lt;/a&gt;, and I’m a Windows user these days. Yes, you can run &lt;code class=&quot;prettyprint&quot;&gt;clang&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;prettyprint&quot;&gt;gcc&lt;/code&gt; on Windows. There is not a ton of difference between C89, C99, and C11 with regards to what we’re talking about in these posts. At some point you have to pick. The version I’ve linked here includes some amendments to the initial spec.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may have heard another slogan when talking about C: “C is portable assembler.” If you think about this slogan for a minute, you’ll also find that if it’s true, C cannot be how the computer works: there are many kinds of different computers, with different architectures. If C is like a version of assembly language that works on multiple computers with multiple architectures, then it cannot function exactly how each of those computers work simultaneously. It &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; hide details, or else it wouldn’t be portable!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, I think this fact is sort of irrelevant, because I don’t think people mean the phrase “C is how the computer works” literally. Before we can talk about that, let’s talk about the C abstract machine, and why many people don’t seem to understand this aspect of the C language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;aside-why-do-people-get-this-wrong_2&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;head_anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://words.steveklabnik.com/should-you-learn-c-to-learn-how-the-computer-works#aside-why-do-people-get-this-wrong_2&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;Aside: why do people get this wrong?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can only relate my own experience, though I think it generalizes to many others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned GW-BASIC, then C, then C++, then Java. I had heard about Java before I started writing it in roughly 1999, four years after it was introduced. Java’s marketing at the time was very anti-C++, and it focused on the JVM as a platform, and how the machine model was what differentiated it from C++, and therefore C. Sun Microsystems no longer exists, but a &lt;a href=&quot;https://tech-insider.org/java/research/1996/0123.html&quot;&gt;mirror of the press release&lt;/a&gt; has this to say:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;large&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Java-based applications are platform-independent; only the Java Virtual Machine needs to be ported to each platform. It acts as an interpreter between an end user’s computer and the Java-based application. An application written in the Java environment can run anywhere, ending the need for porting applications to multiple platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Write once, run everywhere” was the big slogan. These two sentences were how I (and many others) came to understand Java, and how it differed from C++. Java has an interpreter, the Java Virtual Machine. C++ does not have a Virtual Machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this huge marketing push, “virtual machine” became synonymous with “large runtime and/or interpreter” in the minds of many. Languages without this feature were too tied to the particular computer, and required porting between platforms, because they are not truly platform independent. Java’s very reason to exist was to change this aspect of writing applications in C++.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;large&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Runtime”, “virtual machine”, and “abstract machine” are different words for the same fundamental thing. But they’ve since gained different connotations, due to non-essential variance in different implementations of these ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I personally believe that this marketing, in 1995, is why programmers still misunderstand C’s nature today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So is this claim false? Why would Sun Microsystems spend millions and millions of dollars promoting a lie? If C is also based on an abstract machine that offers portability between platforms, why did Java need to exist? I think this is key to understanding what people &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; mean when they say “C is how the computer works.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-do-people-actually-mean_2&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;head_anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://words.steveklabnik.com/should-you-learn-c-to-learn-how-the-computer-works#what-do-people-actually-mean_2&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;What do people actually mean?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though C operates in the context of a virtual machine, it still is significantly different than something like Java. Sun was not lying. In order to understand why, you have to understand C’s history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An operating system was written in assembly language for a computer called the “PDP-7” in 1969 at Bell Labs. In 1970, it was christened UNIX. As time went on, Bell Labs bought more and newer computers; including the PDP-11.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it came time to port Unix to the PDP-11, they considered using a higher-level language, which was a pretty radical idea at the time. Imagine that I said to you “I’m going to write an OS in Java” today, you’d probably laugh, even though &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/JavaOS&quot;&gt;it is possible&lt;/a&gt;. The situation (in my understanding, I wasn’t alive then) was pretty analogous. They considered a language called B, but it didn’t support some of the features that the PDP-11 had, and so they created a successor, naming it “C”, since C was the next letter in the alphabet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;large&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was no “A”; B was a successor to BCPL, the “Basic Combined Programming Language.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1972, on a PDP-11, they wrote the first C compiler, and simultaneously re-wrote UNIX in C. Initially, portability wasn’t the actual goal, but C did resonate with a lot of people, and C compilers were ported to other systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1978, the first edition of “The C Programming Language,” a book on C, was published. Affectionately known as “K&amp;amp;R,” after its authors, the book was very much not a specification, but provided enough of a description of the language that others attempted to write C compilers. This would later be called “K&amp;amp;R C.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As UNIX spread, so did C, and both were ported to many computers. In the 70s and 80s, the ports grew and grew. In the same way that C was created because B couldn’t support all of the features of the PDP-11, many compilers had extensions to the language. Since there was only K&amp;amp;R, and not a spec, as long as they were close enough, that was considered acceptable. By 1983, the lack of any sort of standardization was causing issues, and so a group was created at ANSI to produce a spec. C89 was published in 1989, and is sometimes called “ANSI C.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As such, the C specification was attempting to unify these diverse implementations, on diverse hardware. And so the C abstract machine is sort of the minimal possible specification that would allow the same code to run the same on all platforms. Implementations of C were compiled, not interpreted, and so there was no interpreter, so there was no “VM” in that 1995 sense. However, C programs are written against this abstract, non-existent machine, which is then translated into assembly that is specific to the actual computer that the program is running on. You could not rely on some specific details in order to write portable C code. This makes writing portable C very tricky, as you may have made a platform-specific assumption when writing the initial version of your code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is best illustrated with an example. One of the fundamental data types in C is a &lt;code class=&quot;prettyprint&quot;&gt;char&lt;/code&gt;, named after “character.” However, the C abstract machine does not define how many bits a &lt;code class=&quot;prettyprint&quot;&gt;char&lt;/code&gt; is. Well, it defines it, but not with a number; it defines it as &lt;code class=&quot;prettyprint&quot;&gt;CHAR_BIT&lt;/code&gt; big, which is a constant. Section 5.2.4.2.1 of the spec:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;large&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The values given below shall be replaced by constant expressions suitable or use in &lt;code class=&quot;prettyprint&quot;&gt;#if&lt;/code&gt; preprocessing directives. … Their implementation-defined values shall be equal or greater in magnitude (absolute value) to those shown, with the same sign.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;prettyprint&quot;&gt;CHAR_BIT&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;prettyprint&quot;&gt;8&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So in other words, you know that a &lt;code class=&quot;prettyprint&quot;&gt;char&lt;/code&gt; must be at least 8 bits in size, but implementations are allowed to be larger. In order to properly code against the “C abstract machine”, you must use &lt;code class=&quot;prettyprint&quot;&gt;CHAR_BIT&lt;/code&gt; instead of &lt;code class=&quot;prettyprint&quot;&gt;8&lt;/code&gt; as the size when doing &lt;code class=&quot;prettyprint&quot;&gt;char&lt;/code&gt;-by-&lt;code class=&quot;prettyprint&quot;&gt;char&lt;/code&gt; processing. But this isn’t some sort of interpreter feature, in the way that we think of virtual machines; it’s a property of how the compiler turns your source code into machine code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;large&quot; readability=&quot;0.75&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/2098149/what-platforms-have-something-other-than-8-bit-char&quot;&gt;there are systems where &lt;code class=&quot;prettyprint&quot;&gt;CHAR_BIT&lt;/code&gt; isn’t &lt;code class=&quot;prettyprint&quot;&gt;8&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this “abstract machine”, while still technically being the same idea as the Java VM, is more of a compile-time construct to guide compilers in the task of emitting assembly code than some sort of runtime check or property. The equivalent type in Java is &lt;code class=&quot;prettyprint&quot;&gt;byte&lt;/code&gt;, which is always 8 bits, and it’s up to the implementation of the JVM to decide how to make that happen on platforms where a byte is larger. (I am not sure if the JVM runs on any of those platforms, but that’s how it would work.) The C abstract machine was created to be a minimal papering over of various hardware, not to be some sort of platform created from whole cloth that’s written in software that your code targets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So while Sun is technically incorrect, in practice, they mean something different than what they’re literally saying, and what they &lt;em&gt;mean&lt;/em&gt; is accurate. It’s the same with “learn C to learn how computers work.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;learn-c-to-learn-emmoreem-about-how-computers_2&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;head_anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://words.steveklabnik.com/should-you-learn-c-to-learn-how-the-computer-works#learn-c-to-learn-emmoreem-about-how-computers_2&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;Learn C to learn &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; about how computers work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; people actually mean? In the context of “should a Rubyist learn C to learn about how computers work”, this desire to drop “down to the metal,” as it were, is an interest in understanding not only their program, and how it works inside the VM, but to understand how the combo of their program + their VM operates in the context of the machine itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learning C &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; expose you to more of these kinds of details, because the abstract machine maps so much more closely to hardware, as well as abstractions provided by operating systems. C is very different than these sorts of languages, and so learning C can teach you a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it’s also important to remember that C is fundamentally an &lt;em&gt;abstraction&lt;/em&gt; of hardware, and abstractions are leaky. Don’t conflate what C does or how it operates with the machine itself. If you do, you’re bound to run afoul of these differences, which can cause problems. Most learning resources for C, especially today, as hardware becomes more and more homogeneous, will promote the idea that this is how the computer works. So it can be hard, as a learner, to know what’s going on under the hood, and what’s an abstraction provided by C.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We haven’t even touched on other factors in this discussion, like that due to C’s tremendous popularity, hardware has become more homogeneous because it tends towards being similar to the semantics of C’s abstract machine. If your architecture deviates too much from C’s semantics, C programs may run much more slowly than others, and C programs are often how the speed of hardware is tested. This post is long enough…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this reason, I think a more accurate version of this statement would be “By learning C, you can learn &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; about how computers work.” I do think that a rough familiarity with C can be useful to many programmers, and will serve them well even if they don’t write any C themselves. Learning more about C can also give you insight into the history of how our field has developed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are other ways to learn this stuff as well; C is not &lt;em&gt;inherently&lt;/em&gt; the way to learn these topics, but it is a good option. My next two posts will explore some of the implications of this intersection between portability, the C abstract machine, and how people think about C programs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s so many things to learn in computing. I wish you well on your journey.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;611&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kudos&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;611&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kudos&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 15:56:58 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>steveklabnik</dc:creator>
<og:title>Should you learn C to &quot;learn how the computer works&quot;? • Steve Klabnik</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>I’ve often seen people suggest that you should learn C in order to learn how computers work. Is this a good idea? Is this accurate? I’m going to start with my conclusion right upfront, just to be crystal clear about what I’m saying here: C is not... | Steve Klabnik | “The most violent element in society is ignorance.” - Emma Goldman</og:description>
<og:image>[]</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://words.steveklabnik.com/should-you-learn-c-to-learn-how-the-computer-works</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Tesla delivered 83,500 vehicles in the third quarter, more than expected</title>
<link>https://www.cnbc.com/2018/10/02/tesla-third-quarter-auto-production.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.cnbc.com/2018/10/02/tesla-third-quarter-auto-production.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;group&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tesla delivered 83,500 vehicles during the third quarter, beating Wall Street analysts' expectations for deliveries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But investors are still concerned about the company's profitability and were disappointed it didn't release more detailed data on its production costs and sale prices, analysts said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tesla's shares fell 1.3 percent in midmorning trading despite beating Wall Street estimates for 80,500 deliveries during the quarter, according to data compiled by FactSet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The company produced 80,142 total vehicles: 26,903 Model S and X vehicles combined, and 53,239 Model 3 sedans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its overall deliveries, which included 55,840 of its Model 3 sedans, were comparable to 80 percent of all of its deliveries for 2017, the company said Tuesday. Model 3 deliveries were slightly above consensus estimates of 55,600, according to FactSet. Analysts had lowered their prior estimates over the last week or so, making it easier for Tesla to beat Wall Street expectations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;With production stabilized, delivery and outbound vehicle logistics were our main challenges&quot; during the third quarter, the company said in a statement. &quot;We made many improvements to these processes throughout the quarter, and plan to make further improvements in [the fourth quarter] so that we can scale successfully.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;group&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tesla said it was able to &quot;significantly increase&quot; Model S and X deliveries during the quarter, &quot;notwithstanding the headwinds we have been facing from the ongoing trade tensions between the US and China.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The production and delivery numbers were a positive surprise for sure,&quot; said CFRA analyst Garrett Nelson. &quot;They actually delivered into their guidance. So it seems like they have really improved operationally during the quarter, based on these results.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investors are disappointed because Tesla didn't provide details on average sale prices or vehicle costs, he said. Investors have long been concerned about Tesla profit margins, especially the Model 3. Nelson said some of the company's good news came out ahead of the report and was already priced into the stock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mix of vehicles — comprised in large part of more expensive versions of the Model 3 sedans — suggests that Tesla could be turning a profit on all of its cars, Oppenheimer analyst Colin Rusch said in a research note published Tuesday. But investors were hoping to see more detailed data on its manufacturing costs and cash flow, especially since the automaker said it plans to speed up construction of its factory in Shanghai.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company said it is accelerating construction of the Shanghai factory to try to minimize the impact of the tariffs, which have increased the tax rate on Teslas sold in China to 40 percent, compared with 15 percent for all other imported cars, the company said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Taking ocean transport costs and import tariffs into account, Tesla is now operating at a 55% to 60% cost disadvantage compared to the exact same car locally produced in China,&quot; the company said. &quot;This makes for a challenging competitive environment, given that China is by far the largest market for electric vehicles.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tesla said other disadvantages in China include a lack of cash incentives available to local automakers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;inline_quotes&quot; data-gdsid=&quot;74213&quot; data-inline-quote-symbol=&quot;TSLA&quot; href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/quotes/?symbol=TSLA&quot;&gt;Tesla&lt;/a&gt; previously set a goal of producing between 50,000 and 55,000 Model 3 sedans during the quarter. Heading into the report, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2018/09/30/elon-musk-tells-tesla-to-ignore-distractions-hints-at-profitability.html&quot;&gt;expectations were that the company had exceeded that goal&lt;/a&gt;. The Model 3 is Tesla's midsize electric sedan, and the car that is meant to turn Tesla into a mass manufacturer of electric vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CEO &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/elon-musk/&quot;&gt;Elon Musk&lt;/a&gt; has repeatedly said he expects the company to be profitable for the third quarter. Tesla has had only two profitable quarters since it went public in 2010.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Musk recently reached a settlement with the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission over charges of fraud resulting from comments he made about taking Tesla private. Under &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2018/09/29/sec-settles-charges-with-teslas-elon-musk-will-remain-as-ceo.html&quot;&gt;the terms of the settlement&lt;/a&gt;, Musk and Tesla will pay fines of $20 million each, and Musk will step down for at least three years as chairman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PALO ALTO, Calif., Oct. 02, 2018 (GLOBE NEWSWIRE) -- In Q3, we produced 80,142 vehicles, 50% more than our prior all-time high in Q2, including:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;53,239 Model 3 vehicles, which was in line with our guidance and almost double the volume of Q2. During Q3, we transitioned Model 3 production from entirely rear wheel drive at the beginning of the quarter to almost entirely dual motor during the last few weeks of the quarter. This added significant complexity, but we successfully executed this transition and ultimately produced more dual motor than rear wheel drive cars in Q3. In the last week of the quarter, we produced over 5,300 Model 3 vehicles, almost all of which were dual motor, meaning that we achieved a production rate of more than 10,000 drive units per week.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;26,903 Model S and X vehicles, which was slightly higher than Q2 and in line with our full-year guidance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Q3 deliveries totaled 83,500 vehicles: 55,840 Model 3, 14,470 Model S, and 13,190 Model X. To put this in perspective, in just Q3, we delivered more than 80% of the vehicles that we delivered in all of 2017, and we delivered about twice as many Model 3s as we did in all previous quarters combined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Q3 Model 3 deliveries were limited to higher-priced variants, cash/loan transactions, and North American customers only. There remain significant opportunities to grow the addressable market for Model 3 by introducing leasing, standard battery and other lower-priced variants of the car, and by starting international deliveries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Demand for Model S and X remains high. In Q3, we were able to significantly increase Model S and X deliveries notwithstanding the headwinds we have been facing from the ongoing trade tensions between the US and China. Those trade tensions have resulted in an import tariff rate of 40% on Tesla vehicles versus 15% for other imported cars in China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, Tesla continues to lack access to cash incentives available to locally produced electric vehicles in China that are typically around 15% of MSRP or more. Taking ocean transport costs and import tariffs into account, Tesla is now operating at a 55% to 60% cost disadvantage compared to the exact same car locally produced in China. This makes for a challenging competitive environment, given that China is by far the largest market for electric vehicles. To address this issue, we are accelerating construction of our Shanghai factory, which we expect to be a capital efficient and rapid buildout, using many lessons learned from the Model 3 ramp in North America.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With production stabilized, delivery and outbound vehicle logistics were our main challenges during Q3. We made many improvements to these processes throughout the quarter, and plan to make further improvements in Q4 so that we can scale successfully. As part of this effort, we plan to continue to expand direct deliveries to customers at their home or office, a service we launched in Q3 to improve customer convenience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8,048 Model 3 vehicles and 3,776 Model S and X vehicles were in transit to customers at the end of Q3, and will be delivered in early Q4. Our overall target of 100,000 Model S and X deliveries in 2018 remains unchanged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our net income and cash flow results will be announced along with the rest of our financial performance when we announce Q3 earnings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want to thank the entire Tesla team for executing so well during this challenging ramp up in deliveries. We also want to thank all of our customers who volunteered to help us with deliveries, and our new customers who are showing their faith in Tesla by purchasing our products in such large numbers. It was beyond inspiring to see the contributions made by the whole Tesla community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;***************&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our delivery count should be viewed as slightly conservative, as we only count a car as delivered if it is transferred to the customer and all paperwork is correct. Final numbers could vary by up to 0.5%. Tesla vehicle deliveries represent only one measure of the company's financial performance and should not be relied on as an indicator of quarterly financial results, which depend on a variety of factors, including the cost of sales, foreign exchange movements and mix of directly leased vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forward-Looking Statements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Certain statements herein, including statements regarding future production and delivery of Model S and Model X, expanding direct vehicle deliveries, growing the addressable market for Model 3, and accelerating the buildout of the Shanghai factory in a capital efficient and rapid manner, are &quot;forward-looking statements&quot; that are subject to risks and uncertainties. These forward-looking statements are based on management's current expectations. Various important factors could cause actual results to differ materially, including the risks identified in our SEC filings. Tesla disclaims any obligation to update this information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Correction: Tesla's third-quarter deliveries were more than 80 percent of the vehicles it delivered in all of 2017. An earlier version mischaracterized the percentage.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WATCH:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/video/2018/08/30/tesla-elon-musk-take-private-sec-investigation-autos.html&quot;&gt;Tesla and Elon Musk's wild August — in nine minutes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;group&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 12:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jeffpalmer</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.cnbc.com/2018/10/02/tesla-third-quarter-auto-production.html</og:url>
<og:image>https://fm.cnbc.com/applications/cnbc.com/resources/img/editorial/2018/07/02/105306577-1530537945343rts1ub47.1910x1000.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Tesla beats Wall Street estimates for overall vehicle deliveries</og:title>
<og:description>Its overall third-quarter deliveries beat estimates and were more than 80 percent of the vehicles delivered in all of 2017. But investors are still concerned about the company's profitability.</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.cnbc.com/2018/10/02/tesla-third-quarter-auto-production.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Amazon increases minimum wage for all U.S. workers to $15 an hour</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2018/10/02/amazon-minimum-wage/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2018/10/02/amazon-minimum-wage/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/amazon&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;amazon&quot;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; just &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20181002005317/en/&quot;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; that it will be raising its minimum wage for all U.S. workers to $15 an hour, effective November 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The policy will cover employees at Amazon subsidiaries, including Whole Foods, and well as seasonal and temporary employees. Amazon says that in total, this will cover 250,000 employees, plus 100,000 seasonal employees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This comes as Amazon is &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/08/23/what-is-this-weird-twitter-army-of-amazon-drones-cheerfully-defending-warehouse-work/&quot;&gt;facing increasing scrutiny over how its workers are treated and paid&lt;/a&gt;. Senator Bernie Sanders, for example, &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/05/bernie-sanders-intros-stop-bad-employers-by-zeroing-out-subsidies-bezos-bill/&quot;&gt;recently introduced legislation&lt;/a&gt; to end what he calls “corporate welfare” — and it’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/08/28/bernie-sanders-problem-with-amazon/&quot;&gt;pretty clear who he had in mind&lt;/a&gt;, since the bill was titled Stop Bad Employers by Zeroing Out Subsidies (BEZOS).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/06/whole-foods-workers-seek-to-unionize-says-amazon-is-exploiting-our-dedication/&quot;&gt;a group of Whole Foods workers have been pushing to unionize&lt;/a&gt;, with demands that included a $15 minimum wage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We listened to our critics, thought hard about what we wanted to do, and decided we want to lead,” said Amazon CEO &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/person/jeff-bezos&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;person&quot; data-entity=&quot;jeff-bezos&quot;&gt;Jeff Bezos&lt;/a&gt; in the announcement. “We’re excited about this change and encourage our competitors and other large employers to join us.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon says its existing benefits will not change, except that its RSU stock grant program will be phased out for hourly fulfillment and customer service employees and replaced with a direct stock purchase plan, supposedly because those employees “prefer the predictability and immediacy of cash to RSUs.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, the company &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.aboutamazon.com/working-at-amazon/amazon-raises-minimum-wage-to-15-for-all-us-employees&quot;&gt;also pledges&lt;/a&gt; its public policy team will lobby for an increase to the federal minimum wage from $7.25 — it doesn’t identify a specific wage that it’s targeting, but instead says, “We believe $7.25 is too low. We would look to Congress to decide the parameters of a new, higher federal minimum wage.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed breakout&quot; readability=&quot;7.8786885245902&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-width=&quot;550&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot; readability=&quot;9.6295081967213&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;What Mr. Bezos has done today is not only enormously important for Amazon’s hundreds of thousands of employees, it could well be a shot heard around the world. I urge corporate leaders around the country to follow Mr. Bezos' lead. &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/06wIAHunPq&quot;&gt;https://t.co/06wIAHunPq&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Bernie Sanders (@SenSanders) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/SenSanders/status/1047136187964694530?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;October 2, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 11:55:06 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>doppp</dc:creator>
<og:title>Amazon increases minimum wage for all U.S. workers to $15 an hour</og:title>
<og:description>Amazon just announced that it will be raising its minimum wage for all U.S. workers to $15 an hour, effective November 1. The policy will cover employees at Amazon subsidiaries, including Whole Foods, and well as seasonal and temporary employees. Amazon says that in total, this will cover 250,000 e…</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/71595aa0e1e741bda40efd74e29e13c6.jpg?w=617</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2018/10/02/amazon-minimum-wage/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2018/10/02/amazon-minimum-wage/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Hetzner removes traffic limitation for dedicated servers</title>
<link>https://wiki.hetzner.de/index.php?title=Traffic/en&amp;curid=2842&amp;diff=30324&amp;oldid=29871</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://wiki.hetzner.de/index.php?title=Traffic/en&amp;curid=2842&amp;diff=30324&amp;oldid=29871</guid>
<description>&lt;table class=&quot;diff&quot; readability=&quot;16.935214211076&quot;&gt;&lt;col class=&quot;diff-marker&quot; /&gt;&lt;col class=&quot;diff-content&quot; /&gt;&lt;col class=&quot;diff-marker&quot; /&gt;&lt;col class=&quot;diff-content&quot; /&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot; readability=&quot;0.85836909871245&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; class=&quot;diff-otitle&quot;&gt;




&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; class=&quot;diff-ntitle&quot;&gt;




&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; class=&quot;diff-lineno&quot;&gt;Zeile 5:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; class=&quot;diff-lineno&quot;&gt;Zeile 5:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;diff-marker&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-context&quot; readability=&quot;30&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All dedicated servers have a dedicated 1 Gbit uplink.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-marker&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-context&quot; readability=&quot;30&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All dedicated servers have a dedicated 1 Gbit uplink.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;diff-marker&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-context&quot;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-marker&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-context&quot;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;diff-marker&quot;&gt;−&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-deletedline&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;del class=&quot;diffchange diffchange-inline&quot;&gt;The amount of free traffic a server has is dependant on the base monthly price of the server. For Dell DX&lt;/del&gt; servers &lt;del class=&quot;diffchange diffchange-inline&quot;&gt;is traffic&lt;/del&gt; unlimited&lt;del class=&quot;diffchange diffchange-inline&quot;&gt;. The following table shows the different server prices and the respective amounts of free&lt;/del&gt; traffic. For &lt;del class=&quot;diffchange diffchange-inline&quot;&gt;AX&lt;/del&gt; and CX servers there is a different calculation, which can be seen in &lt;del class=&quot;diffchange diffchange-inline&quot;&gt;the second part of&lt;/del&gt; the table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-marker&quot;&gt;+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-addedline&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;ins class=&quot;diffchange diffchange-inline&quot;&gt;All dedicated&lt;/ins&gt; servers &lt;ins class=&quot;diffchange diffchange-inline&quot;&gt;have&lt;/ins&gt; unlimited traffic. For &lt;ins class=&quot;diffchange diffchange-inline&quot;&gt;AX10/AX20/AX30&lt;/ins&gt; and CX servers there is a different calculation, which can be seen in the table &lt;ins class=&quot;diffchange diffchange-inline&quot;&gt;below&lt;/ins&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;diff-marker&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-context&quot;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-marker&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-context&quot;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;diff-marker&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-context&quot; readability=&quot;30&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;{| class=&quot;wikitable&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 10px&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-marker&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-context&quot; readability=&quot;30&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;{| class=&quot;wikitable&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 10px&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;diff-marker&quot;&gt;−&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-deletedline&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;del class=&quot;diffchange&quot;&gt;|-&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;diff-marker&quot;&gt;−&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-deletedline&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;del class=&quot;diffchange&quot;&gt;! Server Price&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;diff-marker&quot;&gt;−&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-deletedline&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;del class=&quot;diffchange&quot;&gt;! Traffic&amp;lt;big&amp;gt;*&amp;lt;/big&amp;gt;&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;diff-marker&quot;&gt;−&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-deletedline&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;del class=&quot;diffchange&quot;&gt;|-&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;diff-marker&quot;&gt;−&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-deletedline&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;del class=&quot;diffchange&quot;&gt;| Up to € 38.99&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;diff-marker&quot;&gt;−&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-deletedline&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;del class=&quot;diffchange&quot;&gt;| 20 TB&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;diff-marker&quot;&gt;−&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-deletedline&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;del class=&quot;diffchange&quot;&gt;|-&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;diff-marker&quot;&gt;−&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-deletedline&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;del class=&quot;diffchange&quot;&gt;| € 39.00 to € 83.18&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;diff-marker&quot;&gt;−&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-deletedline&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;del class=&quot;diffchange&quot;&gt;| 30 TB&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;diff-marker&quot;&gt;−&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-deletedline&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;del class=&quot;diffchange&quot;&gt;|-&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;diff-marker&quot;&gt;−&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-deletedline&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;del class=&quot;diffchange&quot;&gt;| € 83.19 to € 248.99&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;diff-marker&quot;&gt;−&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-deletedline&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;del class=&quot;diffchange&quot;&gt;| 50 TB&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;diff-marker&quot;&gt;−&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-deletedline&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;del class=&quot;diffchange&quot;&gt;|-&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;diff-marker&quot;&gt;−&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-deletedline&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;del class=&quot;diffchange&quot;&gt;| € 249.00 and above&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;diff-marker&quot;&gt;−&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-deletedline&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;del class=&quot;diffchange&quot;&gt;| 100 TB&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;diff-marker&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-context&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;|-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-marker&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-context&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;|-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;diff-marker&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-context&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;! Server Name&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-marker&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-context&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;! Server Name&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; class=&quot;diff-lineno&quot;&gt;Zeile 47:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; class=&quot;diff-lineno&quot;&gt;Zeile 32:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;diff-marker&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-context&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;| CX60&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-marker&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-context&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;| CX60&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;diff-marker&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-context&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;| 30 TB&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-marker&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-context&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;| 30 TB&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;diff-marker&quot;&gt;−&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-deletedline&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;del class=&quot;diffchange&quot;&gt;|-&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;diff-marker&quot;&gt;−&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-deletedline&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;del class=&quot;diffchange&quot;&gt;| Dell DX servers&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;diff-marker&quot;&gt;−&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-deletedline&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;del class=&quot;diffchange&quot;&gt;| unlimited**&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;diff-marker&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-context&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;|-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-marker&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-context&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;|-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;diff-marker&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-context&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;! Cloud&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-marker&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-context&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;! Cloud&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; class=&quot;diff-lineno&quot;&gt;Zeile 58:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; class=&quot;diff-lineno&quot;&gt;Zeile 40:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;diff-marker&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-context&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;|}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-marker&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-context&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;|}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;diff-marker&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-context&quot;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-marker&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-context&quot;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;diff-marker&quot;&gt;−&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-deletedline&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;big&amp;gt;*&amp;lt;/big&amp;gt;The monthly traffic is only calculated with outgoing traffic. Incoming and internal traffic is not calculated.&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-marker&quot;&gt;+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-addedline&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;big&amp;gt;*&amp;lt;/big&amp;gt;The monthly traffic is only calculated with outgoing traffic. Incoming and internal traffic is not calculated.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;big&amp;gt;**&amp;lt;/big&amp;gt;only if using the 1G uplink&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;diff-marker&quot;&gt;−&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-deletedline&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;big&amp;gt;**&amp;lt;/big&amp;gt;only if using the 1G uplink&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-marker&quot;&gt;+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-addedline&quot;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;diff-marker&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-context&quot;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-marker&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-context&quot;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;diff-marker&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-context&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;== Exceeding Traffic ==&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-marker&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;diff-context&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;== Exceeding Traffic ==&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Aktuelle Version vom 1. Oktober 2018, 08:09 Uhr&lt;/h2&gt;


&lt;p&gt;All dedicated servers have a dedicated 1 Gbit uplink.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All dedicated servers have unlimited traffic. For AX10/AX20/AX30 and CX servers there is a different calculation, which can be seen in the table below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;wikitable&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;Server Name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Traffic&lt;big&gt;*&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;AX10, 20 and 30&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10 TB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;CX10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2 TB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;CX20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5 TB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;CX30&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8 TB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;CX40&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10 TB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;CX50&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;20 TB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;CX60&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;30 TB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;Cloud&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Traffic&lt;big&gt;*&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;CX11-CX51&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;20 TB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;big&gt;*&lt;/big&gt;The monthly traffic is only calculated with outgoing traffic. Incoming and internal traffic is not calculated.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;big&gt;**&lt;/big&gt;only if using the 1G uplink&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We use calendar months to calculate traffic usage. The intervals start on the first of the month and end on the last day of month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the traffic limit is exceeded then the bandwidth will be restricted to 10 Mbit/s. You will receive warning messages via email prior to reaching the limit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exception Cloud Server&lt;/strong&gt;: If the traffic limit is exceeded, the bandwidth is not reduced. Additional traffic is automatically charged in 1TB increments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This restriction to 10 Mbit/s is permanent unless one of the following two options is chosen. Please note that Option 2 can only be chosen once. If the traffic limit is exceeded a second time then only Option 1 is available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;editsection&quot;&gt;[&lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.hetzner.de/index.php?title=Traffic/en&amp;amp;action=edit&amp;amp;section=3&quot; title=&quot;Abschnitt bearbeiten: Option 1&quot;&gt;Bearbeiten&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Option_1&quot;&gt;Option 1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you expect to exceed the traffic limit on a regular basis, we can offer a permanent default connection for your server. This means that if your server crosses the traffic limit the connection will not be restricted but you will be charged € 1.00 (&lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.hetzner.de/index.php/Payment_FAQ/en#How_much_VAT_do_I_need_to_pay.3F&quot; title=&quot;Payment FAQ/en&quot;&gt;price plus VAT, if applicable&lt;/a&gt;) per additional TB. To order the permanent connection please log in to your robot account, click on the server in your server overview, click on the &quot;IPs&quot;-tab (already preselected) and then click on the button &quot;Traffic-Flatrate&quot; and follow the instructions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;editsection&quot;&gt;[&lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.hetzner.de/index.php?title=Traffic/en&amp;amp;action=edit&amp;amp;section=4&quot; title=&quot;Abschnitt bearbeiten: Option 2&quot;&gt;Bearbeiten&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Option_2&quot;&gt;Option 2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you exceeded the traffic limit once, and don't plan on exceeding it again, we can remove the restriction, though this is only possible in the following month. To request this, please send a support request to our &quot;Product advice&quot; team via the &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.hetzner.de/index.php/Robot/en&quot; title=&quot;Robot/en&quot;&gt;Robot&lt;/a&gt;, clearly stating the cause of the increased traffic usage and the reason it will not happen again. For example, a single application caused a lot of traffic but has now been removed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;editsection&quot;&gt;[&lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.hetzner.de/index.php?title=Traffic/en&amp;amp;action=edit&amp;amp;section=5&quot; title=&quot;Abschnitt bearbeiten: Traffic Limit Reporting&quot;&gt;Bearbeiten&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Traffic_Limit_Reporting&quot;&gt;Traffic Limit Reporting&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under the &quot;IPs&quot; tab of your server in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.hetzner.de/index.php/Robot/en&quot; title=&quot;Robot/en&quot;&gt;Robot&lt;/a&gt; you can activate traffic warnings. This system will send you emails when pre-determined limits are exceeded, giving you a handy tool that notifies you of any irregular peaks in your traffic. You can set hourly, daily and monthly limits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note that this traffic warning system is in no way related to the amount of actual free traffic you have. If you do not like receiving the warning emails or are receiving too many then you can change the limits or turn the system off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The traffic usage can be viewed online in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.hetzner.de/index.php/Robot/en&quot; title=&quot;Robot/en&quot;&gt;Robot&lt;/a&gt;. Simply click on &quot;Traffic statistics&quot; in the menu on the left and then select the IPs you want to see the traffic usage for. You can get daily, monthly and yearly overviews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The measured values of the traffic usage are determined by the routers only after disconnecting a TCP connection. If a TCP connection exists for several hours, the total volume of this traffic will be displayed as a peak at the time of disconnection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The traffic API is described in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://robot.your-server.de/doc/webservice/en.html#traffic&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Robot webservice&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 11:23:56 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>TimWolla</dc:creator>
<dc:language>de</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://wiki.hetzner.de/index.php?title=Traffic/en&amp;curid=2842&amp;diff=30324&amp;oldid=29871</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Coders Automating Their Own Job</title>
<link>https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2018/10/agents-of-automation/568795/?single_page=true</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2018/10/agents-of-automation/568795/?single_page=true</guid>
<description>&lt;section id=&quot;article-section-1&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;I&lt;span class=&quot;smallcaps&quot;&gt;n 2016, an anonymous&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/cscareerquestions/comments/4km3yc/finally_fired_after_6_years/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'0',r'568795'&quot;&gt;confession&lt;/a&gt; appeared on Reddit: “From around six years ago up until now, I have done nothing at work.” As far as office confessions go, that might seem pretty tepid. But this coder, posting as FiletOFish1066, said he worked for a well-known tech company, and he really meant &lt;em&gt;nothing&lt;/em&gt;. He wrote that within eight months of arriving on the quality assurance job, he had fully automated his entire workload. “I am not joking. For 40 hours each week, I go to work, play League of Legends in my office, browse Reddit, and do whatever I feel like. In the past six years, I have maybe done 50 hours of real work.” When his bosses realized that he’d worked less in half a decade than most Silicon Valley programmers do in a week, they fired him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tale quickly &lt;a href=&quot;https://boingboing.net/2016/06/08/coder-fired-after-6-years-for.html&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'1',r'568795'&quot;&gt;went viral in tech corners of the web&lt;/a&gt;, ultimately prompting its protagonist to delete not just the post, but his entire account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About a year later, someone calling himself or herself Etherable &lt;a href=&quot;https://workplace.stackexchange.com/questions/93696/is-it-unethical-for-me-to-not-tell-my-employer-i-ve-automated-my-job&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'2',r'568795'&quot;&gt;posted a query&lt;/a&gt; to Workplace on Stack Exchange, one of &lt;a href=&quot;http://nymag.com/selectall/2017/03/the-hidden-power-of-stack-overflow.html&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'3',r'568795'&quot;&gt;the web’s most important forums for programmers&lt;/a&gt;: “Is it unethical for me to not tell my employer I’ve automated my job?” The conflicted coder described accepting a programming gig that had turned out to be “glorified data entry”—and, six months ago, writing scripts that put the entire job on autopilot. After that, “what used to take the last guy like a month, now takes maybe 10 minutes.” The job was full-time, with benefits, and allowed Etherable to work from home. The program produced near-perfect results; for all management knew, their employee simply did flawless work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post proved unusually divisive, and comments flooded in. (It’s now been viewed nearly half a million times.) Reactions split between those who felt Etherable was cheating, or at least deceiving, the employer, and those who thought the coder had simply found a clever way to perform the job at hand. Etherable never responded to the ensuing discussion. Perhaps spooked by the attention—&lt;a href=&quot;https://qz.com/1019161/a-programmer-automated-their-data-entry-job-now-the-question-is-whether-to-tell-their-employer/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'4',r'568795'&quot;&gt;media&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://hk.thenewslens.com/article/72638&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'5',r'568795'&quot;&gt;outlets&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ibtimes.co.uk/if-you-automate-your-job-make-it-easier-it-unethical-not-tell-your-employer-1628316&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'6',r'568795'&quot;&gt;around&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.stuff.co.nz/technology/digital-living/99164024/a-programmer-wrote-scripts-to-secretly-automate-his-job&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'7',r'568795'&quot;&gt;the&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.news.com.au/technology/innovation/inventions/is-it-unethical-for-me-not-to-tell-my-employer-ive-automated-my-job/news-story/7a47989a2a55cdbf66202d130afe9687&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'8',r'568795'&quot;&gt;world&lt;/a&gt; picked up the story—the user vanished, leaving that sole contribution to an increasingly crucial conversation about who gets to automate work, and on what terms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id=&quot;article-section-2&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Call it &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/8gx354/how-to-automate-your-job-and-never-work-again&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'9',r'568795'&quot;&gt;self-automation&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://hbr.org/2011/08/why-you-should-automate-parts.html&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'10',r'568795'&quot;&gt;auto-automation&lt;/a&gt;. At a moment when the specter of mass automation haunts workers, rogue programmers demonstrate how the threat can become a godsend when taken into coders’ hands, with or without their employers’ knowledge. Since both FiletOFish1066 and Etherable posted anonymously and promptly disappeared, neither were able to be reached for comment. But their stories show that workplace automation can come in many forms and be led by people other than executives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;c-section-divider&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;T&lt;span class=&quot;smallcaps&quot;&gt;he&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;smallcaps&quot;&gt;promise of automation&lt;/span&gt;, touted by optimistic economists and sanguine futurists, has been that yielding work to machines would eliminate the drudgery of mindless, repetitive labor, freeing humans to fill our days with leisure, creative pursuits, or more dynamic work. In 1930, John Maynard Keynes &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.econ.yale.edu/smith/econ116a/keynes1.pdf&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'11',r'568795'&quot;&gt;famously speculated&lt;/a&gt; that “automatic machinery and the methods of mass production” would help deliver a 15-hour workweek—and even those hours would only be necessary to help men feel they had something to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nearly a century later, despite formidable advances in technology, repetitive tasks persist. Automation continues apace; millions of jobs once carried out by humans are accomplished by software and mechanized factories, while Americans are working harder and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/on-leadership/wp/2014/09/02/the-average-work-week-is-now-47-hours/?noredirect=on&amp;amp;utm_term=.929d519eece1&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'12',r'568795'&quot;&gt;increasingly longer hours&lt;/a&gt;. The gains from automation have generally been enjoyed not by those who operate the machines, &lt;a href=&quot;https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/3dknk5/the-rich-and-their-robots-are-about-to-make-half-the-worlds-jobs-disappear&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'13',r'568795'&quot;&gt;but those who own them&lt;/a&gt;. According to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oecd.org/eco/Decoupling-of-wages-from-productivity-Macro-level-facts.pdf&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'14',r'568795'&quot;&gt;Organisation for Economic Cooperation and Development&lt;/a&gt;, the share of income going to wages in OECD nations has been decreasing since the 1970s, while the share being funneled into capital—into things like cash reserves and machinery—&lt;a href=&quot;https://theconversation.com/the-benefits-of-job-automation-are-not-likely-to-be-shared-equally-90859&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'15',r'568795'&quot;&gt;has been increasing&lt;/a&gt;. It can seem that some of the only workers who have realized any scrap of that rusty old promise of automation are the ones who’ve carved out the code to claim it for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id=&quot;article-section-3&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Programmers, of course, have been writing code that automates their work for decades. Programming generally involves utilizing tools that add automation at different levels, from code formatting to merging to different codebases—most just don’t take it to the extreme of fully or nearly fully automating their job. I chatted, via direct message on Reddit and email, with around a dozen programmers who said they had. These self-automators had tackled inventory management, report writing, graphics rendering, database administration, and data entry of every kind. One automated his wife’s entire workload, too. Most asked to remain anonymous, to protect their jobs and reputations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“When I started, my job literally took me eight hours a day,” an early self-automator, who I’ll call Gary, told me. He worked for a large corporate hotel chain that was beginning to computerize its workflow in the ‘90s. Gary quickly recognized that he was spending a lot of his time repeating the same tasks, so he started learning to code after-hours. “Over the course of about three months, I built a piece of code in Lotus [1-2-3, then a popular PC spreadsheet program] that not only automated individual repetitive tasks, it effectively automated the entire job.” He didn’t tell his bosses exactly what he had done, and the quality of his working life improved considerably.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It felt weird to have free time during the day,” he told me. “I spent that time learning about the other systems in the hotel.” He then made himself useful, helping management with bottlenecks in those systems. Auto-automation had erased menial toil, reduced his stress, and let him pursue his actual interests. “In effect, I made my position into something I love, which is troubleshooting,” he said. Two weeks before he left, he handed his boss a diskette loaded with the program and documentation on how it ran. His boss was upset that he was quitting, Gary says—until he handed over the disk, showed him how the program worked, and told him to call him if there was ever any problem. No call ever came.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id=&quot;article-section-4&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Todd Hilehoffer was compiling reports for a Pennsylvania insurance company in 2000 when he realized his work could be done by a computer program. “I was very green at the time, with only a year of IT experience,” he told me in a direct message, when he started writing code that could replace his job. “It took me about a year to automate it. I always thought my bosses would be impressed and would find more work for me.” They were, but they also didn’t have another job for him. He passed his days playing chess online. “I was really only completely idle for about 6-9 months,” Hilehoffer said, after which he received a promotion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In most fields, workers rarely have any formal input over whether their job is automated, or how and when automation could be implemented. Self-automators offer a glimpse of what it looks like when automation is orchestrated not by top-down corporate fiat, but by the same workers who stand to reap its benefits. Some embrace the extra leisure time, while others use the spare hours to learn new skills and tackle new programmatic challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What I quite like about these stories is that it shows that automation still has the potential to reduce the amount of boring work we have to do,” Jamie Woodcock, a sociologist of work at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oii.ox.ac.uk/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'16',r'568795'&quot;&gt;Oxford Internet Institute&lt;/a&gt;, told me. “Which was the promise of automation, which was that we wouldn’t have to work 60-hour workweeks, and we could do more interesting things like stay home with our kids.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id=&quot;article-section-5&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yet many self-automators are afraid of sharing their code outside the cubicle. Even if a program impeccably performs their job, many feel that automation for one’s own benefit is wrong. That human labor is inherently virtuous—and that employees should always maximize productivity for their employers—is more deeply coded into American work culture than any automation script could be. And most employment contracts stipulate that intellectual property developed on company time belongs to the employer. So, any efficiency hack or automation gain an employee might make is apt to be absorbed by the employer, the benefits re-routed upstream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One coder &lt;a href=&quot;https://workplace.stackexchange.com/questions/79774/i-automated-my-job-and-the-company-doesnt-know-what-do-i-do-now?noredirect=1&amp;amp;lq=1&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'17',r'568795'&quot;&gt;described keeping the fact that he’d fully automated his job&lt;/a&gt; from his company because he feared it would claim the IP as its own and refuse to compensate him. Another, who asked to be identified only as Jordan, told me he once inadvertently automated an entire department into redundancy. He now saves “several weeks” worth of time a year with automation scripts. Jordan says he and his colleagues keep a tight lid on their automation techniques, to maintain control over how they’re used: “We generally keep these tools to ourselves.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another programmer went to great lengths to conceal the contours of his &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/Python/comments/810crm/urgent_i_have_fully_automated_my_50k_py_job_and/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'18',r'568795'&quot;&gt;fully automated $50,000 per year job&lt;/a&gt; from his boss. Management could check in on his computer screen via the network, so he ran a loop of prerecorded video to hide the fact that he wasn’t actually working. In his advice-seeking post, Etherable wrote, “it doesn’t feel like I’m doing the right thing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id=&quot;article-section-6&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I don’t understand why people would think it’s unethical,” Woodcock said. “You use various tools and forms of automation anyway; anyone who works with a computer is automating work.” He says if any of these coders had sat in front of the computer, manually inputting the data day after day, they’d never be reprimanded. But by demonstrating that they’re capable of higher levels of efficiency, some may, perversely, feel like they’re shirking a duty to the companies that employ them. This is perhaps why automating work can feel like cheating, and be treated as such by corporate policy. On Amazon &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mturk.com/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'19',r'568795'&quot;&gt;Mechanical Turk&lt;/a&gt;, the tech company’s marketplace for microwork, automation is explicitly &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mturk.com/acceptable-use-policy&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'20',r'568795'&quot;&gt;against its terms of service&lt;/a&gt;—and the gig workers like those on the platform, who labor for cents per task, could stand to benefit from automation most of all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some coders say that they’ve been fired outright for automating their work. In 2011, a user posting as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/jcdad/my_wife_works_from_home_and_ive_automated_her_job/c2azurt/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'21',r'568795'&quot;&gt;AcceptableLosses&lt;/a&gt; wrote, “They took what I had developed, replaced me with an idiot that they showed how to work it, and promptly fired me for ‘insubordination.’ I had taken a business asset that was making them $30 grand a year profit and turned it into a million dollar a year program for the company, and they fired me for it to save ~30 grand a year on my salary. Job creators my ass.” As such, gainfully employed self-automators’ concerns are less likely rooted in ethical questions, and more in not wanting to be fired or exploited by an employer that, as Woodcock notes, “expects not only all our time, but anything we create.” Wary self-automators, he speculates, “don’t trust our workplaces. The boss is going to say thank you, good work, now do it again.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id=&quot;article-section-7&quot;&gt;&lt;hr class=&quot;c-section-divider&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;F&lt;span class=&quot;smallcaps&quot;&gt;ew workers may&lt;/span&gt; have the desire to fully self-automate, but it appears a growing number are interested in scripting the busy work. The productivity web is littered with blog posts and how-to articles with titles like &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/dailyjs/how-i-automated-my-job-with-node-js-94bf4e423017&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'22',r'568795'&quot;&gt;How I Automated My Job with Node JS&lt;/a&gt;, and there are dozens of podcasts about every conceivable kind of automation: small-business, marketing, smartphone. It’s a burgeoning cottage industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I see it as a grassroots effort by office workers and others who use a computer as part of their job,” Al Sweigart, the author of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Automate-Boring-Stuff-Python-Programming/dp/1593275994&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'23',r'568795'&quot;&gt;Automate the Boring Stuff with Python&lt;/a&gt;, told me in an email. Even those with little or no familiarity with programming are now seeking out his work, driven by the ease of automating modern jobs. “I get emails from readers who tell me that they’ve freed up several hours of their (and their coworkers’) days with a collection of small programs,” Sweigart said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it stands, self-automation can be empowering. But as automation techniques become better understood, they may simply become yet another skill set management can expect employees to possess, or learn—passing the gains to their organization, then making themselves useful in some other way. “Employees will increasingly need to automate their own jobs or get moved out,” &lt;a href=&quot;https://hbr.org/2011/08/why-you-should-automate-parts.html&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'24',r'568795'&quot;&gt;exhorts the &lt;em&gt;Harvard Business Review&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. “Worldwide, we’ll see many more top-down managerial mandates for bottom-up automation initiatives.” And the rich and their employee-built bots will again swallow the gains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id=&quot;article-section-8&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before that happens, anyone who works with code may want to consider the benefits enjoyed by self-automation. They’re a sort of test case for how automation could deliver a higher quality of life to the average worker, albeit an imperfect one. “The problem is for automation to work, it needs to be democratized,” Woodcock told me. “It’s a step forward that it’s not a corporate manager who’s delivering automation. It’s still not a democratic process.” Self-automators are acting alone, deciding when and how to replace their own job with code. Ideally, automation decisions would happen collectively, with colleagues’ and peers’ input, so, the gains could be evenly distributed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;callout&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r' ',d,r'related',#data-omni-index,@data-article-id&quot;&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Related Stories&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/business/archive/2018/08/robot-babysitters/567691/&quot; data-omni-index=&quot;0&quot; data-article-id=&quot;1027831&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;inherit&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;242&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.theatlantic.com/assets/media/img/mt/2018/08/GettyImages_956745740/thumb_wide_medium.jpg?1534535718&quot; alt=&quot;A human fixes a human-looking robot&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 1932, Bertrand Russell wrote that “a great deal of harm is being done in the modern world by the belief in the virtuousness of &lt;em&gt;work,&lt;/em&gt; and that the road to happiness and prosperity lies in an organized diminution of work.” In 2018, that might mean self-automators reclaiming parts of their work day; tomorrow, it could mean working to secure automated gains for the masses. “I worry quite a bit that there really isn’t enough work to go around for everyone to work full-time,” Todd Hilehoffer said. “Why is earning money for stockholders more important than employee quality of life?” Gary, the early-’90s self-automator, asked me. “The system shouldn't be more important than the individuals who helped make that system relevant.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Self-automators show that coders are actually in a unique position to negotiate with employers over which automation-derived gains—like shorter workweeks and greater flexibility to pursue work that interests them—should be kept by workers. There’s little evidence of any interest in doing so, but theoretically, self-automators could organize, and distribute automation techniques among middle- and working-class coders, giving rising to an industry that &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; actually enjoy that 15-hour workweek. It seems a rare opportunity—perhaps, with the advance of AI, one of the last—to try to set the terms for a mode of automation that puts people first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Related Video&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/section&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 10:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>myinnerbanjo</dc:creator>
<og:title>The Coders Programming Themselves Out of a Job</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2018/10/agents-of-automation/568795/</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn.theatlantic.com/assets/media/img/mt/2018/08/RTX38KFM/facebook.jpg?1535500163</og:image>
<og:description>When workers automate their own duties, who should reap the benefits?</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2018/10/agents-of-automation/568795/?single_page=true</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Amazon raises minimum wage to $15 for all US employees</title>
<link>https://www.cnbc.com/2018/10/02/amazon-raises-minimum-wage-to-15-for-all-us-employees.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.cnbc.com/2018/10/02/amazon-raises-minimum-wage-to-15-for-all-us-employees.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;group&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;inline_quotes&quot; data-gdsid=&quot;9399&quot; data-inline-quote-symbol=&quot;AMZN&quot; href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/quotes/?symbol=AMZN&quot;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;inline_asset&quot; href=&quot;https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20181002005317/en/&quot;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; Tuesday it's raising the minimum wage for all U.S. employees to $15, effective next month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new minimum wage will benefit more than 250,000 Amazon employees — including part-time and temporary employees — as well as another 100,000 seasonal employees, the company said. Some employees who already make $15 per hour will also see a pay increase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon said the effect of the higher pay will be reflected in its forward-looking quarterly guidance. Shares of Amazon were trading marginally lower Tuesday morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The company and CEO Jeff Bezos have been facing criticism for its pay disparity. Sen. Bernie Sanders &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2018/09/05/bernie-sanders-introduces-the-bezos-act-slamming-amazon-low-wages.html&quot;&gt;last month&lt;/a&gt; introduced legislation called the Bezos Act to tax corporations for every dollar that their low-wage workers receive in government health-care benefits or food stamps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;group&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Today I want to give credit where credit is due,&quot; Sanders said in response to the announcement. &quot;What Mr. Bezos has done today is not only enormously important for Amazon's hundreds of thousands of employees, it could well be, and I think it will be, a shot heard around the world.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon said it will also start advocating for an increase to the federal minimum wage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon's starting pay varies by location — $10 an hour at a warehouse in Austin, Texas, for example, and $13.50 an hour in Robbinsville, New Jersey. For 2017, the median Amazon employee earned just under $28,500, according to company filings. Bezos earned $1.7 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon is also raising wages for British employees to a minimum of £10.50 ($13.61) for workers in London and £9.50 ($12.31) in the rest of the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;We listened to our critics, thought hard about what we wanted to do, and decided we want to lead,&quot; Bezos said in a statement. &quot;We're excited about this change and encourage our competitors and other large employers to join us.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Retail rival &lt;a class=&quot;inline_quotes&quot; data-gdsid=&quot;34172&quot; data-inline-quote-symbol=&quot;TGT&quot; href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/quotes/?symbol=TGT&quot;&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt; announced in its holiday hiring release it would raise minimum hourly wage to $15 by 2020. &lt;a class=&quot;inline_quotes&quot; data-gdsid=&quot;36809&quot; data-inline-quote-symbol=&quot;WMT&quot; href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/quotes/?symbol=WMT&quot;&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt; announced plans in January to raise its minimum wage to $11.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The announcement comes ahead of Amazon's annual holiday hiring push. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2017/10/12/amazon-is-hiring-120000-people-for-the-holiday-season.html&quot;&gt;Last year&lt;/a&gt; the e-commerce giant said it would hire 120,000 temporary employees for the holiday season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2018/09/07/us-nonfarm-payrolls-aug-2018.html&quot;&gt;In August&lt;/a&gt;, national wage growth posted its biggest increase of the economic recovery, according to the Bureau of Labor Statistics. Payroll gains beat expectations and the unemployment rate held near a generational low of 3.9 percent — &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2018/09/28/retailers-tout-hiring-more-this-holiday-season-but-wont-fill-all.html&quot;&gt;making holiday hiring tougher for many retailers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;—CNBC's Tom Rotunno and Jeff Cox contributed to this report. The Associated Press also contributed.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WATCH:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/video/2018/06/05/how-jeff-bezos-invests-his-billions.html&quot;&gt;Jeff Bezos is so much bigger than Amazon — a look at his extraordinary empire&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;group&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 10:13:54 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>deegles</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.cnbc.com/2018/10/02/amazon-raises-minimum-wage-to-15-for-all-us-employees.html</og:url>
<og:image>https://fm.cnbc.com/applications/cnbc.com/resources/img/editorial/2018/09/20/105462253-1537460170067rts219t3.1910x1000.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Amazon raises minimum wage to $15 for all US employees </og:title>
<og:description>Amazon and CEO Jeff Bezos have been facing criticism for its pay disparity.</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.cnbc.com/2018/10/02/amazon-raises-minimum-wage-to-15-for-all-us-employees.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>‘Goblin’ world found orbiting at the edges of the Solar System</title>
<link>https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-018-06885-1</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-018-06885-1</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;content position-relative cleared clear mq1200-padded&quot; data-component=&quot;article-container&quot; role=&quot;main&quot;&gt;
&lt;header class=&quot;article-item__header clear cleared pull--both&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article__type&quot;&gt;NEWS
&lt;div class=&quot;ml10 article__date&quot;&gt;&lt;time itemprop=&quot;datePublished&quot;&gt;01 October 2018&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;article-item__teaser-text serif&quot;&gt;The object never gets closer to the Sun than 65 times the Earth–Sun distance.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bordered-container clear cleared pull--both&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;author-affiliations&quot; class=&quot;tab-group text14&quot; role=&quot;tablist&quot; data-test=&quot;author-affiliations&quot; data-tab-group=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cleared&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;author-affiliation-news-0&quot; class=&quot;tab-box js-box-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;author-affiliation-news-0-head&quot; data-track=&quot;click&quot; data-track-label=&quot;view author info&quot; class=&quot;sans-serif strong tab tab-skin&quot; role=&quot;tab&quot; aria-controls=&quot;author-affiliation-news-0-content&quot; data-tooltip=&quot;Show author information&quot;&gt;Alexandra Witze&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;author-affiliation-news-0-content&quot; class=&quot;tab-content pin-right grid grid-12 last&quot; role=&quot;tabpanel&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;pa10&quot; aria-labelledby=&quot;author-affiliation-news-0-head&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;clear cleared&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;align-left&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;sans-serif&quot;&gt;Search for this author in:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;align-left&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article__body serif cleared&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed intensity--high&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;figure__image&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-src=&quot;//media.nature.com/w800/magazine-assets/d41586-018-06885-1/d41586-018-06885-1_16164380.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://media.nature.com/w800/magazine-assets/d41586-018-06885-1/d41586-018-06885-1_16164380.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Astronomers have discovered a distant world in the outer Solar System. Named 2015 TG387 and nicknamed The Goblin, it never gets any closer to the Sun than about 65 times the Earth–Sun distance, or roughly twice the current distance between Pluto and the Sun. At its farthest, the object ranges out to 2,300 times the Earth–Sun distance (see 'Far out').&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2015 TG387 is one of only a handful of objects known in these distant realms. Its orbit is consistent with, but does not prove, the existence of a proposed big planet in the distant Solar System that is popularly known as Planet Nine. A team led by Scott Sheppard, at the Carnegie Institution for Science in Washington DC, discovered The Goblin using Japan’s 8.2-metre Subaru telescope on Mauna Kea, Hawaii. The researchers announced the finding on 1 October in a circular from the International Astronomical Union.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;emphasis&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/d41586-018-06885-1&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;c-latest-content mt40 hide-print&quot; data-simple-tab=&quot;&quot; data-tab-group=&quot;&quot; data-component-id=&quot;latest-news&quot; data-track=&quot;in-view&quot; data-track-action=&quot;in-view&quot; data-track-category=&quot;latest content&quot; data-track-label=&quot;visible&quot;&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;latest-content&quot; role=&quot;tablist&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;serif strong&quot;&gt;Latest on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cleared&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;latest-content-0&quot; class=&quot;c-latest-content__container&quot; data-container=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;latest-content-0-head&quot; class=&quot;c-latest-content__category c-latest-content__switch serif&quot; data-switch=&quot;&quot; role=&quot;tab&quot; aria-controls=&quot;latest-content-0-content&quot; data-track=&quot;click&quot; data-track-label=&quot;latest tag (rank:0)&quot;&gt;Planetary science&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;nature-briefing nature-briefing--article cleared hide-print&quot; data-component-id=&quot;nature-briefing-box&quot; data-track=&quot;in-view&quot; data-track-action=&quot;in-view&quot; data-track-category=&quot;nature briefing&quot; data-track-label=&quot;box visible&quot;&gt;
&lt;header class=&quot;nature-briefing__header&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;Nature Briefing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/header&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;pa10 pt20&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;serif nature-briefing__slogan mr30&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sign up for the daily &lt;span class=&quot;emphasis&quot;&gt;Nature Briefing&lt;/span&gt; email newsletter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;sans-serif nature-briefing__standfirst mr30&quot;&gt;Stay up to date with what matters in science and why, handpicked from &lt;span class=&quot;emphasis&quot;&gt;Nature&lt;/span&gt; and other publications worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cleared&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;nature-briefing__link&quot; data-track-category=&quot;nature briefing&quot; data-track=&quot;click&quot; data-track-label=&quot;nature briefing article link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/briefing/signup/&quot;&gt;Sign Up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;article__aside align-right&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;related-content shrink--aside hide-print&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;aside__title sans-serif&quot;&gt;Related Articles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;div-gpt-ad-right-2&quot; class=&quot;div-gpt-ad advert medium-rectangle js-ad text-center hide-print grade-c-hide hide-overflow&quot; data-gpt-unitpath=&quot;/285/nature.com/article&quot; data-gpt-sizes=&quot;300x250&quot; data-gpt-targeting=&quot;pos=right;artid=/articles/d41586-018-06885-1;path=/articles/d41586-018-06885-1&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pubads.g.doubleclick.net/gampad/jump?iu=/285/nature.com/article&amp;amp;sz=300x250&amp;amp;c=1434134923&amp;amp;t=pos%3Dright%26artid%3D/articles/d41586-018-06885-1&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-test=&quot;gpt-advert-fallback-img&quot; src=&quot;https://pubads.g.doubleclick.net/gampad/ad?iu=/285/nature.com/article&amp;amp;sz=300x250&amp;amp;c=1434134923&amp;amp;t=pos%3Dright%26artid%3D/articles/d41586-018-06885-1&quot; alt=&quot;Advertisement&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;250&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 08:41:09 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>okket</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-018-06885-1</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>‘Goblin’ world found orbiting at the edges of the Solar System</og:title>
<og:description>The object never gets closer to the Sun than 65 times the Earth–Sun distance.</og:description>
<og:image>https://media.nature.com/lw1024/magazine-assets/d41586-018-06885-1/d41586-018-06885-1_16164512.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-018-06885-1</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Brendan Eich Writes to the US Senate: We Need a GDPR for the United States</title>
<link>https://brave.com/us-gdpr-senate</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://brave.com/us-gdpr-senate</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;et-boc&quot; class=&quot;et-boc&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_builder_inner_content et_pb_gutters3&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_section et_pb_section_1 et_pb_with_background et_section_regular&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_row et_pb_row_0&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_column et_pb_column_4_4 et_pb_column_0 et_pb_css_mix_blend_mode_passthrough et-last-child&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_module et_pb_text et_pb_text_0 et_pb_bg_layout_light et_pb_text_align_left&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_text_inner&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brendan Eich, the CEO of Brave, has written to the US Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation, to present the case for GDPR-like data protection standards in the United States. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The full text of this letter is copied &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/us-gdpr-senate#letter&quot;&gt;below&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/Letter-to-Senator-Thune-and-Senator-Nelson-Senate-Committee-on-Commerce-Science-and-Transportation.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;download the PDF&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_module et_pb_text et_pb_text_1 et_pb_bg_layout_light et_pb_text_align_left&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_text_inner&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;one_half&quot;&gt;The Honorable John Thune Chairman Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation United States Senate 512 Dirksen Senate Office Building Washington, DC 20510&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;one_half et_column_last&quot;&gt;The Honorable Bill Nelson Ranking Member Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation United States Senate 512 Dirksen Senate Office Building Washington, DC 20510&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;28 September 2018&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Examining Safeguards for Consumer Data Privacy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Chairman Thune and Ranking Member Nelson,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am the CEO of Brave, a rapidly growing Internet browser, based in San Francisco. I am also the inventor of JavaScript, and co-founded Mozilla/Firefox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I write to commend the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation for engaging with this most pressing issue. It is our view as a company born and based in the United States, and as leading technologists, that the new framework for privacy regulation in the European Union represents a model that should be followed here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I view the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) as a great leveller. The GDPR establishes the conditions that can allow young, innovative companies like Brave to flourish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As regulators broaden their enforcement of the new rules in Europe, the GDPR’s principle of “purpose limitation” will begin to prevent dominant platforms from using data that they have collected for one purpose at one end of their business to the benefit of other parts of their business in a way that currently disadvantages new entrants. In general, platform giants will need “opt-in” consent for each purpose for which they want to use consumers’ data. This will create a breathing space for new entrants to emerge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The character of the GDPR is congruent with the United States’ understanding of privacy. Indeed, the primary principles of the GDPR are based on principles that the United States already endorsed in 1980, in the OECD Guidelines on the Protection of Privacy and Transborder Flows of Personal Data. These previously endorsed principles include a GDPR-like definition of “personal data”. It is also worth noting that many features of the GDPR have been sought by the FTC for over a decade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the coming years, common GDPR-like standards for commercial use of consumers’ personal data will apply in the EU, Britain (post EU), Japan, India, Brazil, South Korea, Argentina, and China, for civil and commercial use of personal data. These countries account for 51% of global GDP. A common standard reduces friction and uncertainty, allowing companies from these countries to operate and innovate together with greater efficiency. A United States GDPR-like standard will ensure our position and competitive edge as leaders in  technology and innovation in the global marketplace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The online media and advertising industry&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A GDPR-like standard in the United States will also establish the foundation of trust to enable innovation and growth. This certainly applies in our own online media and advertising industry. Contrary to some of our industry colleagues, I believe that it is not tenable for any platform, publisher, technology vendor, or trade body, to claim that they must track people in order to generate revenue from advertising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The enormous growth of ad-blocking by people across the globe (to 615 million active devices by late 2017) proves the terrible cost of inadequately regulating the tracking-based advertising system. Trust will only return as the GDPR-like laws begin to curtail the online advertising industry’s worst practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The economic benefit of “behavioral tracking” to publishers’ businesses is questionable. The IAB, an ad targeting industry trade body, recently funded a lobbying study on “The economic value of behavioral targeting in digital advertising” that claimed that publishers (in Europe) rely on tracking for their advertising revenue. It is now public knowledge that a startling omission was at the heart of this report. Without any indication that it was doing so, the report combined Google and Facebook’s massive revenue from behavioural ad tech with the far smaller amount that actual publishers receive from it. Inclusion of Google and Facebook revenues enormously and incorrectly inflated the benefit that publishers derive from permitting ad tech companies to surveil and profile their visitors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Political micro-targeting&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The GDPR is also an important regulatory tool to fight political micro-targeting, and the attendant issues of micro-targeting. Currently, a person browsing the Web is tracked across nearly every webpage they visit by “online behavioral advertising” (OBA), which leverages persistent data collection to select the ads that are displayed. There is a massive and systematic data breach at the heart of this system that causes web users’ personal data to be leaked in such a way that can be harvested by unscrupulous data brokers. It is highly likely that this contributes to micro-targeting user data profiles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, so-called “dark ads” on websites, targeted using OBA, may be considerably less traceable than those served on social media, because the websites themselves are not aware of what ads they serve. Unlike Facebook, the OBA industry consists of a vast array of third party networks, operating behind the scenes with opaque processes, with no central authority to hold to account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For these reasons, I urge you to consider the GDPR as a model to pursue. I would be delighted to provide further information, or to meet and brief you, to assist in your deliberations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sincerely,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-12196&quot; src=&quot;https://brave.com/images/brendan-eich-small.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;142&quot; srcset=&quot;images/brendan-eich-small.png 500w, images/brendan-eich-small-300x85.png 300w, images/brendan-eich-small-24x7.png 24w, images/brendan-eich-small-36x10.png 36w, images/brendan-eich-small-48x14.png 48w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brendan Eich&lt;br/&gt;CEO, Brave Software&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_section et_pb_section_2 et_pb_with_background et_section_regular&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_row et_pb_row_1&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_column et_pb_column_4_4 et_pb_column_1 et_pb_css_mix_blend_mode_passthrough et-last-child&quot;&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_module et_pb_blog_0 et_pb_blog_grid_wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_blog_grid clearfix et_pb_bg_layout_light&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_ajax_pagination_container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_salvattore_content&quot; data-columns=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;article id=&quot;post-11439&quot; class=&quot;et_pb_post clearfix post-11439 post type-post status-publish format-standard has-post-thumbnail hentry category-announcements category-brave-insights category-gdpr category-policy category-privacy-category tag-adtech tag-advertising tag-authorized-buyers tag-behavioral tag-behavioural tag-breach tag-consent-framework tag-data-breach tag-gdpr tag-google tag-iab tag-open-rights-group tag-openrtb tag-ravi-naik tag-rtb&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_image_container&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/adtech-data-breach-complaint/&quot; class=&quot;entry-featured-image-url&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://brave.com/images/complaint-400x250.png&quot; alt=&quot;Regulatory complaint concerning massive, web-wide data breach by Google and other “ad tech” companies under Europe’s GDPR&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;250&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;post-meta&quot;&gt;by &lt;span class=&quot;author vcard&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/joryan/&quot; title=&quot;Posts by Johnny Ryan&quot; rel=&quot;author&quot;&gt;Johnny Ryan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; | &lt;span class=&quot;published&quot;&gt;Sep 12, 2018&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  Dublin, Ireland and London, United Kingdom, Wednesday, 12 September 2018 -- Simultaneous complaints have been filed with European data protection authorities against Google and other ad tech firms. The complainants are being made by Dr Johnny Ryan of Brave, the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/adtech-data-breach-complaint/&quot; class=&quot;more-link&quot;&gt;read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;article id=&quot;post-11023&quot; class=&quot;et_pb_post clearfix post-11023 post type-post status-publish format-standard has-post-thumbnail hentry category-announcements category-brave-insights category-community category-features category-gdpr category-policy category-privacy-category category-research&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_image_container&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/ama-with-johnny-ryan/&quot; class=&quot;entry-featured-image-url&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://brave.com/images/johnny.ryan_-1-400x250.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;AMA with Johnny Ryan&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;250&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;post-meta&quot;&gt;by &lt;span class=&quot;author vcard&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/brave/&quot; title=&quot;Posts by Brave&quot; rel=&quot;author&quot;&gt;Brave&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; | &lt;span class=&quot;published&quot;&gt;Sep 6, 2018&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the third post in our series of BAT Community-run AMAs. The ongoing AMA series on Reddit is a six-month long event that features various guests from the Brave and BAT teams. The goal of the series, which will run until January 2019, is twofold: to give fans...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/ama-with-johnny-ryan/&quot; class=&quot;more-link&quot;&gt;read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;article id=&quot;post-10860&quot; class=&quot;et_pb_post clearfix post-10860 post type-post status-publish format-standard has-post-thumbnail hentry category-brave-insights category-gdpr category-policy tag-adcom tag-bid-request tag-data-breach tag-iab tag-iab-techlab tag-openrtb tag-openrtb-3 tag-rtb tag-techlab&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_image_container&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/iab-rtb-problems/&quot; class=&quot;entry-featured-image-url&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://brave.com/images/brave-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Critical data protection problems in the IAB’s new OpenRTB 3.0 Spec&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;250&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;post-meta&quot;&gt;by &lt;span class=&quot;author vcard&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/joryan/&quot; title=&quot;Posts by Johnny Ryan&quot; rel=&quot;author&quot;&gt;Johnny Ryan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; | &lt;span class=&quot;published&quot;&gt;Sep 4, 2018&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A ruling of the European Court of Justice this month in the “Facebook fan page case” exposes marketers to severe legal risk from programmatic advertising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/iab-rtb-problems/&quot; class=&quot;more-link&quot;&gt;read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_section et_pb_section_4 et_pb_with_background et_section_regular&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_row et_pb_row_2&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_column et_pb_column_1_4 et_pb_column_2 et_pb_css_mix_blend_mode_passthrough&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_module et_pb_image et_pb_image_0&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;et_pb_image_wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://brave.com/fonts/brave-logotype-dark.svg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_module et_pb_blurb et_pb_blurb_0 et_pb_bg_layout_light et_pb_text_align_left et_pb_blurb_position_top&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_blurb_content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_blurb_container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_blurb_description&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The new Brave browser blocks the ads and trackers that slow you down, chew up your bandwidth, and invade your privacy. Brave even lets you contribute to your favorite creators automatically.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_column et_pb_column_1_4 et_pb_column_3 et_pb_css_mix_blend_mode_passthrough&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_module et_pb_text et_pb_text_3 et_pb_bg_layout_light et_pb_text_align_left&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_text_inner&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Additional Links&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_column et_pb_column_1_4 et_pb_column_5 et_pb_css_mix_blend_mode_passthrough et-last-child&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_module et_pb_text et_pb_text_7 et_pb_bg_layout_light et_pb_text_align_left&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;et_pb_text_inner&quot;&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Brave San Francisco&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;512 Second Street, Floor 2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;San Francisco, CA 94107&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt; &lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Brave London&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;&lt;span&gt;Mindspace Shoreditch&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;&lt;span&gt;9 Appold St&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;&lt;span&gt;London, EC2A 2AP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 07:02:23 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mochtar</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Brendan Eich writes to the US Senate: we need a GDPR for the United States | Brave Browser</og:title>
<og:description>Brendan Eich, the CEO of Brave, has written to the US Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation, to present the case for GDPR-like data protection standards in the United States.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.brave.com/blog/us-gdpr-senate/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.brave.com/images/senateletter.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://brave.com/us-gdpr-senate</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Vigilante engineer stops Waymo from patenting key lidar technology</title>
<link>https://arstechnica.com/cars/2018/10/lone-engineer-spanks-waymo-in-lidar-patent-battle/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://arstechnica.com/cars/2018/10/lone-engineer-spanks-waymo-in-lidar-patent-battle/</guid>
<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/laser-diode-car-blueprint-800x450.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Article intro image&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;caption-credit&quot;&gt;Google LLC / Aurich&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id=&quot;social-left&quot;&gt;&lt;a aria-describedby=&quot;95 posters participating&quot; class=&quot;comment-count icon-comment-bubble-down&quot; href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/cars/2018/10/lone-engineer-spanks-waymo-in-lidar-patent-battle/?comments=1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;comment-count-before&quot;&gt;reader comments&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;comment-count-number&quot;&gt;127&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;share-links&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Share this story&lt;/span&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;A lone engineer has succeeded in doing what Uber's top lawyers and expert witnesses could not—overturning most of a foundational patent covering arch-rival Waymo's lidar laser ranging devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following a surprise left-field complaint by Eric Swildens, the US Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/4936884-2018-Sep-12-Final-Rejection.html&quot;&gt;rejected all but three&lt;/a&gt; of 56 claims in Waymo's &lt;a href=&quot;https://patents.google.com/patent/US9368936B1/en?oq=9368936&quot;&gt;936 patent&lt;/a&gt;, named for the last three digits of its serial number. The USPTO found that some claims replicated technology described in an earlier patent from lidar vendor Velodyne, while another claim was simply &quot;impossible&quot; and &quot;magic.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Swildens, who receives no money or personal advantage from the decision, told Ars that he was delighted at the news. &quot;The patent shouldn't have been filed in the first place,&quot; he said. &quot;It's a very well written patent. However, my personal belief is that the thing that they say they invented, they didn't invent.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 936 patent played a key role in last year's &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/series/waymo-v-uber/&quot;&gt;epic intellectual property lawsuit with Uber&lt;/a&gt;. In December 2016, a Waymo engineer was inadvertently copied on an email from one of its suppliers to Uber, showing a lidar circuit design that looked almost identical to one shown in the 936 patent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The patent describes how a laser diode can be configured to emit pulses of laser light using a circuit that includes an inductor and a gallium nitride transistor. That chance discovery helped spark a lawsuit in which &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/series/waymo-v-uber/&quot;&gt;Waymo accused Uber&lt;/a&gt; of patent infringement and of using lidar secrets supposedly stolen by engineer Anthony Levandowski.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In August 2017, Uber agreed to redesign its Fuji lidar not to infringe the 936 patent. Then, in February 2018, Waymo settled the remaining trade secret theft allegations in exchange for Uber equity worth around $245 million and a commitment from Uber not to copy its technology. &quot;This includes an agreement to ensure that any Waymo confidential information is not being incorporated in Uber… hardware and software,&quot; said a Waymo spokesperson at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That redesign now seems to have been unnecessary, says Swildens, the engineer who asked the USPTO to take a closer look at 936. &quot;Waymo's claim that Uber infringed the 936 patent was spurious, as all the claims in the patent that existed at the time of the lawsuit have been found to be invalid,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uber told Ars that despite the ruling, it would not be redesigning its lidars yet again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Just an interested bystander&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remarkably, Swildens does not work for Uber or for Velodyne, nor for any other self-driving developer—he works for a small cloud computing startup. Swildens became interested in the patent when it surfaced during the Uber case, and he saw how simple Waymo's lidar circuit seemed to be. &quot;I couldn't imagine the circuit didn't exist prior to this patent,&quot; he told &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/story/eric-swildens-uber-waymo-lawsuit-patent/&quot;&gt;Wired&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Swildens' research uncovered several patents and books that seemed to pre-date the Waymo patent. He then spent $6,000 of his own money to launch a formal challenge to 936. Waymo fought back, making dozens of filings, bringing expert witnesses to bear, and attempting to re-write several of the patent's claims and diagrams to safeguard its survival.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The USPTO was not impressed. In March, an examiner noted that a re-drawn diagram of Waymo's lidar firing circuit showed current passing along a wire between the circuit and the ground in two directions—something generally deemed impossible. &quot;Patent owner's expert testimony is not convincing to show that the path even goes to ground in view of the magic ground wire, which shows current moving in two directions along a single wire,&quot; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/4936885-2018-March-27-Non-Final-Action-90020113-16.html&quot;&gt;noted the examiners&lt;/a&gt; dryly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In September, the axe finally dropped. With a few exceptions, those claims that were not physically impossible were found to have replicated lidar circuits found in pre-existing patents, in particular one called &lt;a href=&quot;https://patents.google.com/patent/US7969558B2/en&quot;&gt;558&lt;/a&gt; issued to Dave Hall, founder of lidar-maker Velodyne. Swildens says that he's unsurprised by the result and considers his money well spent. &quot;As I investigated the 936 patent, it became clear it was invalid due to prior art for multiple reasons,&quot; he says. &quot;I only filed the reexamination because I was absolutely sure the patent was invalid.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Waymo declined to comment on the record, but the company could now find itself in an awkward position. In 2017, Waymo CEO John Krafcik stood up at the Automobili-D conference in Detroit and announced that his company, which had previously bought dozens of lidars from Velodyne, was now designing and building all of its sensors in-house and &quot;from the ground up.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Krafcik went on to deliver &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xRGIlwgc--g&amp;amp;t=13m5s&quot;&gt;some sly digs&lt;/a&gt; at his former supplier. &quot;Designing our own lidar system has not only given us a more reliable product than what we can get off the shelf, but it's enabled us to do it at a fraction of the cost,&quot; he said. &quot;Just a few years ago, a single top of the range [Velodyne] lidar unit would have cost $75,000. Today, we've brought that cost down by more than 90 percent.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The USPTO's findings call that narrative into question, believes Swildens. &quot;The design of the Waymo lidar appears to be based on the design of the Velodyne lidar units they had been using,&quot; he says. &quot;As part of this, Waymo utilized circuitry similar to Velodyne circuitry and then attempted to patent (and did patent) those circuit designs as their own novel inventions.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Pot, meet kettle?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In its original lawsuit against Uber, Waymo wrote: &quot;Waymo developed its patented inventions… at great expense, and through years of painstaking research, experimentation, and trial and error. If defendants are not enjoined from their infringement and misappropriation, they will cause severe and irreparable harm to Waymo.&quot; If Velodyne believes that its 558 patent covers lidars that Waymo is now on the point of commercializing, it could make a similar complaint in court itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the situation is complicated by the fact that Velodyne is currently embroiled in its own patent dispute with a startup called Quanergy that is developing solid-state lidars. Velodyne has accused Quanergy of infringing its intellectual property, while Quanergy in turn claims that Velodyne's original 558 patent is itself invalid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Velodyne is attempting to shore up 558 by rewriting it, but judges in the case noted in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/4936888-IPR2018-00255-DI-Mailed-EXCELLENT.html&quot;&gt;recent filing&lt;/a&gt; that there was &quot;a reasonable likelihood&quot; that at least one of its claims is also unpatentable. Velodyne did not respond to requests for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Self-driving startups should not take this legal confusion as carte blanche to use the lidar technology described in Waymo's and Velodyne's patents, warns Brian Love, co-director of the High Tech Law Institute at the Santa Clara University School of Law. &quot;There's a joke among patent lawyers that a final rejection is anything but final, because owners still have options even after a final rejection,&quot; he tells Ars. &quot;And to get an award in a patent action, you only have to show infringement of one claim in one patent. The fact that there's even one claim left in Waymo's patent means there's one shot for arguing that someone infringes that claim.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Waymo also has &lt;a href=&quot;https://patents.google.com/?assignee=Waymo+Llc&quot;&gt;hundreds of other patents&lt;/a&gt; developed in-house, or bought from rivals. They might not all contain the &quot;magic&quot; claims of 936, but they are probably enough to keep Waymo in the driving seat of autonomous vehicles for some time—especially as Swildens says he's too busy right now to issue any more patent challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 03:36:52 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>sonnyblarney</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://arstechnica.com/cars/2018/10/lone-engineer-spanks-waymo-in-lidar-patent-battle/</og:url>
<og:title>Vigilante engineer stops Waymo from patenting key lidar technology</og:title>
<og:image>https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/laser-diode-car-blueprint-760x380.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Eric Swildens had no dog in the fight other than intellectual curiosity.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://arstechnica.com/cars/2018/10/lone-engineer-spanks-waymo-in-lidar-patent-battle/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Sourcegraph is now open source</title>
<link>https://about.sourcegraph.com/blog/sourcegraph-is-now-open-source</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://about.sourcegraph.com/blog/sourcegraph-is-now-open-source</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Sourcegraph development is now open source at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sourcegraph/sourcegraph&quot;&gt;github.com/sourcegraph/sourcegraph&lt;/a&gt; (Apache License)! You can now contribute to Sourcegraph:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We opened up Sourcegraph to bring code search and intelligence to more developers and developer ecosystems—and to help us realize the &lt;a href=&quot;https://about.sourcegraph.com/plan&quot;&gt;Sourcegraph master plan&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Make basic code intelligence ubiquitous (for every language, and in every editor, code host, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make code review continuous and intelligent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increase the amount and quality of open-source code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;We're also excited about what this means for Sourcegraph as a company. All of our customers, many with hundreds or thousands of developers using Sourcegraph internally every day, started out with a single developer spinning up a Sourcegraph instance and sharing it with their team. Being open-source makes it even easier to start using Sourcegraph in that way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organizations using Sourcegraph can upgrade to &lt;a href=&quot;https://about.sourcegraph.com/pricing&quot;&gt;Sourcegraph Enterprise&lt;/a&gt; (previously called Data Center) to get the features that large organizations need (single sign-on, backups and recovery, cluster deployment, etc.). These additional features in Sourcegraph Enterprise are paid and not open source. The success of Sourcegraph Enterprise makes it possible for Sourcegraph Inc to keep working towards our &lt;a href=&quot;https://about.sourcegraph.com/plan&quot;&gt;master plan&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond open-sourcing Sourcegraph's code and development, we're also opening up other product and company processes. Our &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sourcegraph/about/blob/master/projects/about-repository.md&quot;&gt;product roadmap&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sourcegraph/browser-extensions&quot;&gt;browser extension&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sourcegraph/about&quot;&gt;about.sourcegraph.com website&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sourcegraph/careers&quot;&gt;open job posts&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sourcegraph&quot;&gt;much more&lt;/a&gt; are now public, too. And the &lt;a href=&quot;https://about.sourcegraph.com/plan&quot;&gt;Sourcegraph master plan&lt;/a&gt; has always been public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you over at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sourcegraph/sourcegraph&quot;&gt;Sourcegraph open-source repository&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thanks to Philip Thomas, Jay Taylor, Kevin Wang, and Dan Bentley for feedback on the open-source repository's docs and scripts, and to all of the AUTHORS who have contributed to the project so far.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 23:50:15 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>aranw</dc:creator>
<og:title>Sourcegraph is now open source</og:title>
<og:url>https://about.sourcegraph.com/blog/sourcegraph-is-now-open-source</og:url>
<og:description>Sourcegraph development is now open source at github.com/sourcegraph/sourcegraph (Apache License)! You can now contribute to Sourcegraph…</og:description>
<og:image>https://images.ctfassets.net/le3mxztn6yoo/t4Qpcq5kA0AYM24Ws4mOk/4edf5502a936bbec90c262fa00355aed/sourcegraph-mark.png</og:image>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://about.sourcegraph.com/blog/sourcegraph-is-now-open-source/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>