<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Google Cloud networking issues in us-east1</title>
<link>https://status.cloud.google.com/incident/cloud-networking/19016</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://status.cloud.google.com/incident/cloud-networking/19016</guid>
<description>&lt;tr readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;status&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;date&quot;&gt;Jul 02, 2019&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;time&quot;&gt;16:05&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;description&quot; readability=&quot;17&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The disruptions with Google Cloud Networking and Load Balancing have been root caused to physical damage to multiple concurrent fiber bundles serving network paths in us-east1, and we expect a full resolution within the next 24 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, we are electively rerouting traffic to ensure that customers' services will continue to operate reliably until the affected fiber paths are repaired. Some customers may observe elevated latency during this period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will provide another status update either as the situation warrants or by Wednesday, 2019-07-03 12:00 US/Pacific tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;next-row-desc&quot; readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&quot;3&quot; readability=&quot;17&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The disruptions with Google Cloud Networking and Load Balancing have been root caused to physical damage to multiple concurrent fiber bundles serving network paths in us-east1, and we expect a full resolution within the next 24 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, we are electively rerouting traffic to ensure that customers' services will continue to operate reliably until the affected fiber paths are repaired. Some customers may observe elevated latency during this period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will provide another status update either as the situation warrants or by Wednesday, 2019-07-03 12:00 US/Pacific tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;status&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;date&quot;&gt;Jul 02, 2019&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;time&quot;&gt;14:31&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;description&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The disruptions with Google Cloud Networking and Load Balancing have been root caused to physical damage to multiple concurrent fiber bundles serving network paths in us-east1. We are electively rerouting some traffic to ensure that customers’ services will continue to operate reliably until the affected fiber paths are repaired. Some customers will observe elevated latency during this period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will provide another status update by Tuesday, 2019-07-02 16:30 US/Pacific with current details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;next-row-desc&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&quot;3&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The disruptions with Google Cloud Networking and Load Balancing have been root caused to physical damage to multiple concurrent fiber bundles serving network paths in us-east1. We are electively rerouting some traffic to ensure that customers’ services will continue to operate reliably until the affected fiber paths are repaired. Some customers will observe elevated latency during this period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will provide another status update by Tuesday, 2019-07-02 16:30 US/Pacific with current details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;status&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;date&quot;&gt;Jul 02, 2019&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;time&quot;&gt;12:39&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;description&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mitigation work is currently underway to address the issue with Google Cloud Networking and Load Balancing in us-east1. The rate of errors has decreased, however some users may still notice elevated latency, and our Engineering Team is continuing to work on it. We will provide another status update by Tuesday, 2019-07-02 14:30 US/Pacific with current details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;next-row-desc&quot; readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&quot;3&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mitigation work is currently underway to address the issue with Google Cloud Networking and Load Balancing in us-east1. The rate of errors has decreased, however some users may still notice elevated latency, and our Engineering Team is continuing to work on it. We will provide another status update by Tuesday, 2019-07-02 14:30 US/Pacific with current details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;10.5&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;status&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;date&quot;&gt;Jul 02, 2019&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;time&quot;&gt;11:35&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;description&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mitigation work is currently underway by our Engineering Team to address the issue with Google Cloud Networking and Load Balancing in us-east1. The rate of errors is decreasing, however some users may still notice elevated latency. We will provide another status update by Tuesday, 2019-07-02 12:30 US/Pacific with current details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;next-row-desc&quot; readability=&quot;10.5&quot;&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&quot;3&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mitigation work is currently underway by our Engineering Team to address the issue with Google Cloud Networking and Load Balancing in us-east1. The rate of errors is decreasing, however some users may still notice elevated latency. We will provide another status update by Tuesday, 2019-07-02 12:30 US/Pacific with current details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;status&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;date&quot;&gt;Jul 02, 2019&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;time&quot;&gt;10:56&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;description&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We continue to experience an issue with Cloud Networking and Load balancing within us-east1. Issue is currently mitigated and we are working towards a resolution. Customers may still observe traffic through Global Load balancers being directed away from backends in us-east1 at this time. We will provide an update by Tuesday, 2019-07-02 11:29 US/Pacific with current details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;next-row-desc&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&quot;3&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We continue to experience an issue with Cloud Networking and Load balancing within us-east1. Issue is currently mitigated and we are working towards a resolution. Customers may still observe traffic through Global Load balancers being directed away from backends in us-east1 at this time. We will provide an update by Tuesday, 2019-07-02 11:29 US/Pacific with current details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;status&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;date&quot;&gt;Jul 02, 2019&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;time&quot;&gt;10:25&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;description&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We continue to experience an issue with Cloud Networking within us-east1. Issue is currently mitigated and we are working towards a resolution. Customers may still observe traffic through Global Load-balancers being directed away from back-ends in us-east1 at this time. We will provide an update by Tuesday, 2019-07-02 11:29 US/Pacific with current details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;next-row-desc&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&quot;3&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We continue to experience an issue with Cloud Networking within us-east1. Issue is currently mitigated and we are working towards a resolution. Customers may still observe traffic through Global Load-balancers being directed away from back-ends in us-east1 at this time. We will provide an update by Tuesday, 2019-07-02 11:29 US/Pacific with current details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 18:57:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>decohen</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://status.cloud.google.com/incident/cloud-networking/19016</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Superhuman embeds tracking pixels in user emails</title>
<link>https://mikeindustries.com/blog/archive/2019/06/superhuman-is-spying-on-you</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://mikeindustries.com/blog/archive/2019/06/superhuman-is-spying-on-you</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past 25 years, email has weaved itself into the daily fabric of life. Our inboxes contain everything from very personal letters, to work correspondence, to unsolicited inbound sales pitches. In many ways, they are an extension of our homes: private places where we are free to deal with what life throws at us in whatever way we see fit. Have an inbox zero policy? That’s up to you. Let your inbox build into the thousands and only deal with what you can stay on top of? That’s your business too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is disappointing then that one of the most hyped new email clients, Superhuman, has decided to embed hidden tracking pixels inside of the emails its customers send out. Superhuman calls this feature “Read Receipts” and turns it on by default for its customers, without the consent of its recipients. You’ve heard the term “Read Receipts” before, so you have most likely been conditioned to believe it’s a simple “Read/Unread” status that people can opt out of. &lt;strong&gt;With Superhuman, it is not&lt;/strong&gt;. If I send you an email using Superhuman (no matter what email client &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; use), and you open it &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Hh_vLKlz2Mc&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;9 times&lt;/a&gt;, this is what I see:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mikeindustries.com/blog/images/inline/SuperhumanLog.png&quot; alt=&quot;A log of every time someone has opened your email and what location they opened it from.&quot; width=&quot;995&quot; height=&quot;525&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-29106&quot; srcset=&quot;/blog/images/inline/SuperhumanLog.png 995w, /blog/images/inline/SuperhumanLog-300x158.png 300w, /blog/images/inline/SuperhumanLog-768x405.png 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 995px) 100vw, 995px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s right. A running log of every single time you have opened my email, including your location when you opened it. Before we continue, ask yourself if you &lt;strong&gt;expect&lt;/strong&gt; this information to be collected on you and relayed back to your parent, your child, your spouse, your co-worker, a salesperson, an ex, a random stranger, or a stalker every time you read an email. Although some one-to-many email blasting software has used similar technologies to track open rates, the answer is no; most people don’t expect this. People reasonably expect that when — and especially where — they read their email is their own business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I initially tweeted about this last week, the tweet was faved by a wide variety of people, including current and former employees and CEOs of companies ranging from Facebook, to Apple, to Twitter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mikeindustries/status/1144288602001571840&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mikeindustries.com/blog/images/inline/Mike.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1166&quot; height=&quot;446&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-29131&quot; srcset=&quot;/blog/images/inline/Mike.png 1166w, /blog/images/inline/Mike-300x115.png 300w, /blog/images/inline/Mike-768x294.png 768w, /blog/images/inline/Mike-1024x392.png 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1166px) 100vw, 1166px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was also met critically by several Superhuman users, as well as some Superhuman investors (who never disclosed that they were investors, even in past, private conversations with me). I want to talk about this issue because I think it’s instructive to how we build products and companies with a sense of ethics and responsibility. I think what Superhuman is doing here demonstrates a lack of regard for both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, a few caveats:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;I was invited into the Superhuman service several months ago. I began their onboarding process, was excited to try using it as my primary email client, and bailed out the moment I found out about this spyware functionality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nothing in this post evaluates other things about the Superhuman service. I’m not here to tell you it isn’t fast, isn’t good looking, or doesn’t save you time. I suspect it is all of those things, in fact. So if your response to this post is &lt;em&gt;“BUT I LIKE IT!”&lt;/em&gt;, I believe you that there are things to like about it. That is not the subject of this post.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I know people whom I consider to be ethical people who use workplace software that embeds tracking pixels in emails.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Second, I want to talk about &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; this particular issue is so important. Not why privacy is important; we are all already learning that the hard way. Rather, why making ethical decisions at the earliest stages of your company is important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a company first forms, there are no norms or principles guiding how its people should make decisions. It’s basically just what’s in the founders’ heads. With each decision a company makes, its “decision genome” is established and subsequently hardened. You’ve decided in your first month that you’re only going to hire engineers from Top 10 engineering schools? That’s now part of your genome and will determine the composition of your company. You’ve decided to forgo extra profits by keeping your prices low for consumers? That’s now part of your genome. You’ve decided to employ a single dark pattern to trick users into adding more things to their shopping cart? Part of your genome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason this matters is that what may seem like small decisions early on become the basis for many more decisions down the road. These decisions affect your &lt;strong&gt;ethical trajectory&lt;/strong&gt; as a company. Let’s use the dark pattern example. Maybe the shopping cart thing was pretty minor and you were able to rationalize it internally in a variety of ways, including the fact that the extra item in the user’s cart was inexpensive and provided value (like a product warranty, for instance). Down the road, when employees want to employ more dark patterns, here is how the conversation would go:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Greg: “Hey, we aren’t getting enough people to opt-into our mailing list when they sign up. Can we try maybe unchecking that box by default but using language such that leaving it unchecked opts people in?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Desi: “Wouldn’t we be intentionally deceiving users if we did that?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Greg: “Uhhhh, we already add things to your shopping cart that you don’t even ask for!”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Desi: “True. This seems like less of a big deal than that. I guess I’m OK with it.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’ve never worked at a tech company before, this is how things go. When faced with making a product decision that is even mildly uncomfortable, employees often first look towards expressed company principles like “Always put the customer first”, but the next thing they look for is &lt;em&gt;precedent&lt;/em&gt;. What other decisions have we made that look like this one? Designers do this. Engineers do this. Product managers do this. Executives do this. It’s an easy way to inform your current decision, and it’s also an easy way to &lt;em&gt;cover your ass&lt;/em&gt;. Imagine the above decision was made by a product manager, and later on the company was called out publicly on it. The CEO or Head of Product marches over to the product manager and says “what were you thinking here?!?” The product manager needs only to point to the shopping cart behavior in order to let him or herself off the hook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point here is that companies decide early on what sort of companies they will end up being. The company they may &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; to be is often written in things like “core values” that are displayed in lunch rooms and employee handbooks, but the company they &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; be is a product of the actual decisions they make — especially the tough decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So back to Superhuman. Here we have a company that professes to create a better email experience mainly through better design and engineering. So far so good! Those who know me know that I would be among the first people to sign up for something like this and also among the most vocal to evangelize it. Heck, I love &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/s?k=kohler+flipside&quot;&gt;a certain showerhead&lt;/a&gt; so much that I:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Have bought one for every shower in every place I’ve lived for the past several years.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bought one for every member of my leadership team at Twitter for Christmas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Used to keep a brand new spare one in my trunk to give away to friends every time the subject came up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turned &lt;a href=&quot;https://abs-0.twimg.com/emoji/v2/svg/1f6bf.svg&quot;&gt;the damn showerhead emoji on Twitter into a Flipside&lt;/a&gt;. Actually, my team did this, but as an homage to my love for it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;In other words, when I see great design, I proactively try to spread it as far and wide as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I see in Superhuman though is a company that has mistaken taking advantage of people for good design. They’ve identified a feature that provides value to some of their customers (i.e. seeing if someone has opened your email yet) and they’ve trampled the privacy of every single person they send email to in order to achieve that. Superhuman never asks the person on the other end if they are OK with sending a read receipt (complete with timestamp and geolocation). Superhuman never offers a way to opt out. Just as troublingly, &lt;strong&gt;Superhuman teaches its user to surveil by default&lt;/strong&gt;. I imagine many users sign up for this, see the feature, and say to themselves “Cool! Read receipts! I guess that’s one of the things my $30 a month buys me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When products are introduced into the market with behaviors like this, customers are trained to think they are not just legal but also ethical. They don’t always take the next step and ask themselves “wait, &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; I be doing this?” It’s kind of like if you walked by someone’s window at night and saw them naked. You could do one of two things: a) look away and get out of there, realizing you saw something that person wouldn’t want you to see, or b) keep staring, because if they really didn’t want anyone to see them, they should have closed their blinds. It’s two ways of looking at the world, and Superhuman is not just allowing for option B but &lt;em&gt;actively causing it to happen&lt;/em&gt;. It’s almost as if Superhuman is aiming a motion-sensitive camera outside people’s windows and sending alerts when there is motion. It’s automated and designed to capture info when your family, your friend, your co-worker, or your victim is not aware. You may think “victim” is too harsh of a word to use here, but remember, we aren’t talking about &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt;. We are talking about anyone who might use Superhuman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though most of the feedback I’ve gotten about raising this issue has been supportive, here is a collection of replies I’ve gotten on Twitter, so we can address them all in one place:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol readability=&quot;9.2144187283852&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Email clients have done this for years. Even Apple does this with iMessage.”&lt;/strong&gt; — Multiple People. This argument is naive at best and disingenuous at worst. Superhuman’s competitors are Apple Mail, Gmail, and Outlook. Exactly zero of those companies insert a tracking pixel into their emails. Furthermore, both Outlook and iMessage use Read Receipts that are turned off by default and controlled completely by the receiving user. In other words, when you buy a new iPhone or start using Outlook, no one requesting an Outlook or iMessage read receipt can receive one without your explicit permission. Furthermore, even if you &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; turn those on, it’s a simple one-time receipt… not a log of times and geolocations every time the recipient views the message. Both Microsoft and Apple — as well as other messaging platforms like Twitter, LinkedIn, and Signal — have designed their read receipts in an ethical way. Superhuman has not. Also ask yourself what the backlash would be if a company somehow retrofit these spying capabilities on top of iMessage. What if every single time you viewed someone’s text message, your phone sent a timestamp and location to back to the sender, creating a map of your movements? There’s a reason Apple doesn’t allow this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Other tools like MailChimp, PersistIQ, SendGrid, and MailTrack do this.”&lt;/strong&gt; — Multiple People. Superhuman is an e-mail client, much like Gmail, Outlook, and Apple Mail. It is not mail automation software. Mass mailing companies, for the most part, use that technology to track open rates and also to *stop* sending out emails to people who haven’t opened them in months. There are indeed some sales-enablement companies that use this technology to track individual opens, and I find that just as creepy. The main point here is: just because technology is being used unethically by others does not mean you should use it unethically yourself. Harmful pesticides have also been around for years. That doesn’t mean you should use them yourself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;6.8723404255319&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/sheynk/status/1144347611148771329?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mikeindustries.com/blog/images/inline/Sheynk-e1562044774641.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1155&quot; height=&quot;477&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-29122&quot; srcset=&quot;/blog/images/inline/Sheynk-e1562044774641.png 1155w, /blog/images/inline/Sheynk-e1562044774641-300x124.png 300w, /blog/images/inline/Sheynk-e1562044774641-768x317.png 768w, /blog/images/inline/Sheynk-e1562044774641-1024x423.png 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1155px) 100vw, 1155px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where to start with this one from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/sheynkman/&quot;&gt;Gary Sheynkman&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;You&lt;/em&gt;, the sender, do not get to decide how &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt;, the receiver, respond to you. Not returning your email right away is not passive-aggressive. It’s often just being busy or prioritizing. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/EricaJoy/status/1144599839042183168&quot;&gt;As pointed out by Erica, being “left on read” can send unintended hurtful messages&lt;/a&gt;. Furthermore, in the workplace, this can be used as a tool to monitor or coerce around-the-clock work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;9.9009900990099&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/nickabouzeid/status/1144329661209407489?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mikeindustries.com/blog/images/inline/Nick-e1562044724372.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1156&quot; height=&quot;419&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-29123&quot; srcset=&quot;/blog/images/inline/Nick-e1562044724372.png 1156w, /blog/images/inline/Nick-e1562044724372-300x109.png 300w, /blog/images/inline/Nick-e1562044724372-768x278.png 768w, /blog/images/inline/Nick-e1562044724372-1024x371.png 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1156px) 100vw, 1156px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/nickabouzeid/&quot;&gt;Nick Abouzeid&lt;/a&gt;, a Superhuman investor (who did not disclose that, but I got it by going to his website) from the aptly named “Shrug Capital”. This comment gets to the crux of the ethics question we are talking about here. When you are making software, you can either say “lets exploit everything in the world that can act to our benefit” or you can say “lets build something that’s great for the world”. This person looks at all people who use email as potential people to exploit. How many people use email? 2 billion or so? How many of those have images turned off? Probably a tiny percentage. And how many are expecting that every time they open an email from a friend, their friend gets notified with their geolocation? I would guess almost zero. So what this person is essentially saying is that since most people leave their curtains open at night, it’s ethical for the company he funds to film what goes on inside. Furthermore, &lt;strong&gt;Superhuman doesn’t even let its own customers turn images off. So merely by using Superhuman, you are vulnerable to the exact same spying that Superhuman enables you to do to others&lt;/strong&gt;. He is right about one thing though: &lt;em&gt;because&lt;/em&gt; of spyware-foisting companies like Superhuman, you should unfortunately turn off all image loading in your email client.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you start to think about all of the ways Superhuman can be used to violate privacy, you really wonder why The New York Times spent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/06/27/technology/superhuman-email.html&quot;&gt;1,200 words&lt;/a&gt; on a tongue-bath that doesn’t even talk meaningfully about privacy issues at all. We don’t need journalism to tell us where venture capitalists are putting other people’s money. We need it to examine the ramifications of the technology we are pushing into the world and in what ways it might shift the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Overton_window&quot;&gt;Overton Window&lt;/a&gt; for Ethics in either helpful or hurtful ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some bad people out there, so what are some bad things that people can do with technology like this? Here are just a few:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;An ex-boyfriend is a Superhuman user who pens a desperate email. Subject: &lt;em&gt;“I’ve been thinking about us”&lt;/em&gt;. He sends it to his former partner. She reads it when she gets to work in Downtown Los Angeles at 9am. She reads it again before dinner with friends in Pasadena at 7pm. She reads it again at home in Santa Monica at 1am. Over the weekend, she takes a trip to New York and reads it again. Twice. She decides not to answer the email, because her ex has stalked her in the past and she doesn’t want to communicate any further. But because of the tracking pixel, her email is &lt;em&gt;always communicating&lt;/em&gt;, and it’s sharing info she does not want to send and doesn’t even know she is sending. She didn’t reply, but her ex still knows she read his email five times, including most likely in her bed. And he knows she took a trip to New York.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A pedophile uses Superhuman to send your child an email. Subject: &lt;em&gt;“Ten Tips to Get Great at Minecraft”&lt;/em&gt;. Your child keeps the email in their inbox and refers back to it often over the course of a year. Sometimes when they are at home in Vermont. Sometimes when they are at school in New Hampshire. Sometimes when they are with their grandparents in Massachusetts. Every time your child opens the email, that person knows generally where they are (or specifically, if they have other info to triangulate against).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Superhuman decides they can make more money by supplementing their subscription fees with data licensing agreements. Maybe they decide to leave out data from paying Superhuman customers but they include location history from every single person you’ve ever emailed, because they have no contract with those people. Location maps with timestamps, other insights about things like working hours and locations, device types, and whatever else they collect. That data is then used to target those people in a variety of ways. If Superhuman is truly willing to commit to &lt;em&gt;never license any data to anyone for any reason&lt;/em&gt;, they should be able to clearly say so right now. But they probably won’t, because they want to keep their options open.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;I understand wanting to cover a new product, but an outfit as respected as the Times needs to go deeper on this stuff. Heck, I’m already at 4000 words — on a single subject — and I just wrote this on a whim over the weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though I wish companies didn’t make the sorts of product decisions Superhuman has made, I’m glad they are at least showing their cards early (and appear to stand by them) so I can avoid their service. Not just on principle but because I have no reason to trust them with any of my data. Remember that they require &lt;em&gt;full access&lt;/em&gt; to your Gmail in order to do their thing. Fast forward a year or two and I can see them licensing location data either from their own customers or their non-customers to a third-party for any number of distasteful purposes. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/vsodera/status/1145027988053823488&quot;&gt;They say&lt;/a&gt; they have a privacy policy that forbids this, but I don’t read &lt;a href=&quot;https://superhuman.com/privacy&quot;&gt;their policy&lt;/a&gt; that way at &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt;. It allows and even specifies all sorts of things they can do. Here’s an excerpt (emphasis mine):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HOW WE USE TRACKING TECHNOLOGY TO COLLECT INFORMATION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We automatically collect usage information when you visit our Website or use the Service through the use of tracking technologies, including tracking pixels and similar technology&lt;/strong&gt; (collectively, “Tracking Technologies”). We may use the data collected through Tracking Technologies to: (a) remember information so that you will not have to re-enter it the next time you visit the Website or use the Service; (b) &lt;strong&gt;provide and monitor the effectiveness of our Service&lt;/strong&gt;; (c) &lt;strong&gt;provide functionality of the Service including read receipts&lt;/strong&gt;; (d) &lt;strong&gt;monitor and collect analytics data using third-party tools&lt;/strong&gt; like Google Analytics in order to help measure traffic and usage trends for the Service; (e) diagnose or fix technology problems; and (f) &lt;strong&gt;otherwise to plan for and enhance our Service.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The form of this paragraph is very familiar to lawyers. Specify some stuff that sounds mundane and then leave yourself all sorts of escape routes. Item F is essentially a universal license to do whatever they want (i.e. “We’ve ‘enhanced’ our service by using your location data in a new way!”). Now, I’m not saying this privacy policy is out of the ordinary at all. I’m just saying there is nothing about Superhuman’s Terms of Service that prevent them from making further decisions that violate your privacy in the future. Not to mention, companies can change their policy at any time. When you use a product, you need to trust the &lt;em&gt;people&lt;/em&gt; who are building it — not the documents their attorneys create. And finally, once again, because of this spyware pixel, most of the people they are collecting information on aren’t even Superhuman customers and never even signed up for this policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what would I do if I were Rahul Vohra, Superhuman’s CEO?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing I’d do is apologize and remove this functionality for everyone. You don’t need to take out a front page ad in the Times. Just own the mistake and disable the feature unless and until you can design it in an ethical way. Don’t keep it up for a year while you work on it. Take it down. This would show responsibility and regard for doing the right thing. A sign of an honorable company is when it is willing to learn, take responsibility, and improve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next I would recalibrate how important it is to even offer Read Receipts. Superhuman seems to be doing just fine in terms of customer satisfaction. I know some people like this functionality but does the success of Superhuman’s business depend on it? I would guess not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Third, if Superhuman really cared about protecting the privacy of its users, they would actually provide the exact opposite of this feature. &lt;em&gt;Protect&lt;/em&gt; all Superhuman users from emails loaded with surveillance pixels, do it by default, and never embed them in their own outbound emails. There are a few &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/pixelblock/jmpmfcjnflbcoidlgapblgpgbilinlem&quot;&gt;browser extensions&lt;/a&gt; that do this decently while keeping most benign images turned on, but this would be a great feature to have baked into an email client. Use this moment as a turning point to honor all of the other work going on at the company and turn this negative into a positive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, if I still didn’t agree that tracking the geolocations and reading behavior of unwitting people was deceptive, I’d wear it on my sleeve:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; readability=&quot;13.450151057402&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;A good ethics test for investors, employees &amp;amp; users of Superhuman. If you use SH’s default spyware behavior, you should be willing to change your signature to this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;– Sent via Superhuman. Every time you open this email, the time and your location are sent to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who’s first?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Mike Davidson (@mikeindustries) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mikeindustries/status/1144360664275673088?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 27, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of Superhuman’s customers — and I assume most of its employees and execs — use the “&lt;em&gt;Sent with Superhuman&lt;/em&gt;” signature already. If you are so sure that automatically receiving a recipient’s geolocation every time they read one of your emails is OK, you should be OK with telling them that when you send them an email. In fact, since it’s a feature you are proud of, you should be &lt;em&gt;more than happy to market it so clearly&lt;/em&gt;, right? (In case you’re wondering, exactly zero people stepped up to do this. Not Rahul Vohra, no employees, no investors, and no customers.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I close, I want to talk about blame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t automatically blame Superhuman designers for this, because I don’t know if they fought for it or against it. Likewise, I don’t blame Superhuman engineers, product managers, or anyone else, for the same reason. For all I know, this was something the team pushed back strenuously on and lost. If so, thanks for fighting the good fight, and you should have your equity grant doubled for trying to do the right thing. If not, this whole article also applies to you. The only person I know for sure shares some or all of the responsibility for this is Superhuman’s CEO, Rahul Vohra. He is the only employee I’ve seen actively defend it (although perhaps others have), and it’s safe to say he was intimately involved in its development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is also important: I do not know Rahul&lt;/strong&gt;. I don’t know if he’s nice, mean, a good person, a bad person, likes his steak medium rare or well-done with ketchup, or anything else about him. I make no value judgements about him as a human, and as with most other humans, I try to assume the best about him. &lt;em&gt;This article is about a very specific decision of his that I find to be dangerous and wrong&lt;/em&gt;. Whenever I see something like this, I always give the benefit of the doubt and assume the person simply doesn’t realize the downside consequences of their decision. I brought this up several months ago and the company did nothing to address it. I brought it up again last week and still nothing. In light of that, and in light of some of the responses from investors defending Superhuman’s surveillance behavior, I felt justified writing a proper piece about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, if you are a user wanting to protect yourself against automatically having your email behavior and geolocation sent to people who use Superhuman and other surveillance tools, you need to do both of these things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Don’t use Superhuman yourself. As mentioned earlier, Superhuman leaves you unprotected from spying because they don’t allow you to block these spyware pixels. It also turns you into an unwitting information collection machine, aggregating info on every single person you send email to. Possibly including your parents, children, partners, and friends.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turn off remote image loading in whatever email client you use. Almost every client these days allows you to do this, with the strange exception of Gmail for iOS. If you are a Gmail user, I recommend switching to something like Outlook on your iPhone. It’s free and allows you to use your existing Gmail account. No migration necessary. Apple Mail is fine too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;So to sum up — whether you are an email provider or an email user — don’t surveil, and don’t allow yourself to be surveilled. I hope Superhuman does the right thing and decides to help &lt;em&gt;stop&lt;/em&gt; this problem instead of trying to normalize it.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 16:35:18 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>minimaxir</dc:creator>
<og:description>Over the past 25 years, email has weaved itself into the daily fabric of life. Our inboxes contain everything from very personal letters, to work correspondence, to unsolicited inbound sales pitches. In many ways, they are an extension of our …</og:description>
<og:image>https://mikeindustries.com/blog/images/inline/IMG_3263.jpeg</og:image>
<og:title>Superhuman is Spying on You » Mike Industries</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mikeindustries.com/blog/archive/2019/06/superhuman-is-spying-on-you</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Cloudflare outage caused by bad software deploy</title>
<link>https://blog.cloudflare.com/cloudflare-outage/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.cloudflare.com/cloudflare-outage/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;This is a short placeholder blog and will be replaced with a full post-mortem and disclosure of what happened today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For about 30 minutes today, visitors to Cloudflare sites received 502 errors caused by a massive spike in CPU utilization on our network. This CPU spike was caused by a bad software deploy that was rolled back. Once rolled back the service returned to normal operation and all domains using Cloudflare returned to normal traffic levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was not an attack (as some have speculated) and we are incredibly sorry that this incident occurred. Internal teams are meeting as I write performing a full post-mortem to understand how this occurred and how we prevent this from ever occurring again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;update-at-2009-utc-&quot;&gt;Update at 2009 UTC:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting at 1342 UTC today we experienced a global outage across our network that resulted in visitors to Cloudflare-proxied domains being shown 502 errors (“Bad Gateway”). The cause of this outage was deployment of a single misconfigured rule within the Cloudflare Web Application Firewall (WAF) during a routine deployment of new Cloudflare WAF Managed rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The intent of these new rules was to improve the blocking of inline JavaScript that is used in attacks. These rules were being deployed in a simulated mode where issues are identified and logged by the new rule but no customer traffic is actually blocked so that we can measure false positive rates and ensure that the new rules do not cause problems when they are deployed into full production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, one of these rules contained a regular expression that caused CPU to spike to 100% on our machines worldwide. This 100% CPU spike caused the 502 errors that our customers saw. At its worst traffic dropped by 82%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This chart shows CPU spiking in one of our PoPs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.cloudflare.com/content/images/2019/07/cpuspike-1.png&quot; class=&quot;kg-image&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;We were seeing an unprecedented CPU exhaustion event, which was novel for us as we had not experienced global CPU exhaustion before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We make software deployments constantly across the network and have automated systems to run test suites and a procedure for deploying progressively to prevent incidents. Unfortunately, these WAF rules were deployed globally in one go and caused today’s outage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At 1402 UTC we understood what was happening and decided to issue a ‘global kill’ on the WAF Managed Rulesets, which instantly dropped CPU back to normal and restored traffic. That occurred at 1409 UTC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then went on to review the offending pull request, roll back the specific rules, test the change to ensure that we were 100% certain that we had the correct fix, and re-enabled the WAF Managed Rulesets at 1452 UTC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We recognize that an incident like this is very painful for our customers. Our testing processes were insufficient in this case and we are reviewing and making changes to our testing and deployment process to avoid incidents like this in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 15:55:57 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>TomAnthony</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Cloudflare outage caused by bad software deploy (updated)</og:title>
<og:description>Starting at 1342 UTC today we experienced a global outage across our network that resulted in visitors to Cloudflare-proxied domains being shown 502 errors (“Bad Gateway”). The cause of this outage was deployment of a single misconfigured rule within the Cloudflare Web Application Firewall (WAF)</og:description>
<og:url>https://blog.cloudflare.com/cloudflare-outage/</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.cloudflare.com/cloudflare-outage/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Chinese authorities install app on phones of people entering Xinjiang</title>
<link>https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/7xgame/at-chinese-border-tourists-forced-to-install-a-text-stealing-piece-of-malware</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/7xgame/at-chinese-border-tourists-forced-to-install-a-text-stealing-piece-of-malware</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Foreigners crossing certain Chinese borders into the Xinjiang region, where authorities are conducting a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/ne94dg/jingwang-app-no-encryption-china-force-install-urumqi-xinjiang&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;massive campaign of surveillance&lt;/a&gt; and oppression against the local Muslim population, are being forced to install a piece of malware on their phones that gives all of their text messages as well as other pieces of data to the authorities, a collaboration by Motherboard, Süddeutsche Zeitung, the &lt;em&gt;Guardian&lt;/em&gt;, the &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt;, and the German public broadcaster NDR has found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Android malware, which is installed by a border guard when they physically seize the phone, also scans the tourist or traveller's device for a specific set of files, according to multiple expert analyses of the software. The files authorities are looking for include Islamic extremist content, but also innocuous Islamic material, academic books on Islam by leading researchers, and even music from a Japanese metal band.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In no way is the downloading of tourists’ text messages and other mobile phone data comparable to the treatment of the Uighur population in Xinjiang, who live under the constant gaze of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/04/14/technology/china-surveillance-artificial-intelligence-racial-profiling.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;facial recognition systems&lt;/a&gt;, CCTV, and physical searches. Last week, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=v7AYyUqrMuQ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;VICE News published an undercover documentary&lt;/a&gt; detailing some of the human rights abuses and surveillance against the Uighur population. But the malware news shows that the Chinese government’s aggressive style of policing and surveillance in the Xinjiang region has extended to foreigners, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;[This app] provides yet another source of evidence showing how pervasive mass surveillance is being carried out in Xinjiang. We already know that Xinjiang residents—particularly Turkic Muslims—are subjected to round-the-clock and multidimensional surveillance in the region,&quot; Maya Wang, China senior researcher at Human Rights Watch, said. &quot;What you’ve found goes beyond that: it suggests that even foreigners are subjected to such mass, and unlawful surveillance.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One tourist who crossed the border and had the malware installed on their device provided a copy to Süddeutsche Zeitung and Motherboard. A member of the reporting team from Süddeutsche Zeitung then also crossed the border and had the same malware installed on their own phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Motherboard has uploaded a copy of the Android app to our GitHub account. You can download &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/motherboardgithub/bxaq&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the Android file here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the border crossing from Kyrgyzstan into China, surrounded by desolate, mountainous peaks, border authorities take travelers' phones to be searched and install the malware, called BXAQ or Fengcai. Those crossing the border entered a clean, sterile environment to be searched, and in all, the process of getting through several stages of scrutiny and security takes around half a day, one of the travelers said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together with the &lt;em&gt;Guardian&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt;, the reporting team commissioned several technical analyses of the app. Penetration testing firm Cure53 on behalf of the Open Technology Fund, researchers at Citizen Lab from the University of Toronto, and researchers from the Ruhr University Bochum as well as the &lt;em&gt;Guardian&lt;/em&gt; itself all provided insights about BXAQ. The app's code also includes names such as &quot;CellHunter&quot; and &quot;MobileHunter.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once installed on an Android phone, by &quot;side-loading&quot; its installation and requesting certain permissions rather than downloading it from the Google Play Store, BXAQ collects all of the phone's calendar entries, phone contacts, call logs, and text messages and uploads them to a server, according to expert analysis. The malware also scans the phone to see which apps are installed, and extracts the subject’s usernames for some installed apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;article__blockquote&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do you know any other cases of government malware? We'd love to hear from you. Using a non-work phone or computer, you can contact Joseph Cox securely on Signal on +44 20 8133 5190, Wickr on josephcox, OTR chat on jfcox@jabber.ccc.de, or email joseph.cox@vice.com.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The app does not try to hide itself. Instead, it displays an icon on the device's app select screen, suggesting that it is designed to be removed from the phone after use by the authorities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;This is yet another example of why the surveillance regime in Xinjiang is one of the most unlawful, pervasive, and draconian in the world,&quot; Edin Omanovic, state surveillance programme lead at Privacy International said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Modern extraction systems take advantage of this to build a detailed but flawed picture into people’s lives. Modern apps, platforms, and devices generate huge amounts of data which people likely aren’t even aware of or believe they’ve deleted, but which can still be found on the device. This is highly alarming in a country where downloading the wrong app or news article could land you in a detention camp,&quot; he added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article__media&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://video-images.vice.com/_uncategorized/1562065619503-Screenshot_2019-06-26-12-18-14-314_commiuihome.png?resize=320:*&quot; alt=&quot;bxaq_app_menu&quot; class=&quot;col-12-xs&quot; data-src=&quot;https://video-images.vice.com/_uncategorized/1562065619503-Screenshot_2019-06-26-12-18-14-314_commiuihome.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;A screenshot of the app on the Android home screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Süddeutsche Zeitung reporter said they saw machines that appeared to be for searching iPhones at the border.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patrick Poon, China researcher at Amnesty International, said &quot;it's pretty alarming to see how even foreigners and tourists would be subject to this kind of surveillance.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Included in the app's code are hashes for over 73,000 different files the malware scans for. Ordinarily, it is difficult to determine what specific files these hashes relate to, but the reporting team and researchers managed to uncover the inputs of around 1,300 of them. This was done by searching for connected files on the file search engine Virus Total. Citizen Lab identified the hashes in the VirusTotal database, and researchers from the Bochum team later downloaded some of the files from VirusTotal. The reporting team also found other copies online, and verified what sort of material the app was scanning for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of the files that are scanned for contain clearly extremist content, such as the so-called Islamic State's publication Rumiyah. But the app also scans for parts of the Quran, PDFs related to the Dalai Lama, and a music file from Japanese metal band Unholy Grave (the band has a song called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QtSPmzIFIDQ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&quot;Taiwan: Another China.&quot;&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article__media&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://video-images.vice.com/_uncategorized/1562065528226-Screenshot_20190212-124352.jpeg?resize=320:*&quot; alt=&quot;bxaq_scan&quot; class=&quot;col-12-xs&quot; data-src=&quot;https://video-images.vice.com/_uncategorized/1562065528226-Screenshot_20190212-124352.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;A screenshot of the app scanning for files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The Chinese government, both in law and practice, often conflates peaceful religious activities with terrorism. Chinese law defines terrorism and extremism in a very broad and vague manner. For example, terrorism charges can stem from mere possession of 'items that advocate terrorism,' even though there is no clear definition of what these materials may be,&quot; Wang from Human Rights Watch said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the scanned files is &lt;em&gt;The Syrian Jihad&lt;/em&gt;, a book written by Charles Lister, a leading terrorism scholar and senior fellow and director of the Countering Terrorism and Extremism program at the Middle East Institute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;This is news to me!&quot; Lister wrote in an email. &quot;I’ve never had any criticism for the book—in fact, in all honesty, the opposite.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Instead, I suspect China’s authorities would find anything with the word 'jihad' in the title to be potentially suspicious,&quot; he added. &quot;The book covers, albeit minimally, the role of the Turkistan Islamic Party in Syria, which may also be a point of sensitivity for Beijing. I’ve met with and engaged with Chinese officials to brief them on these issues, so I’m not aware of any problem Beijing would have with me.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;article__pull-quote&quot;&gt;&quot;This is yet another example of why the surveillance regime in Xinjiang is one of the most unlawful, pervasive, and draconian in the world.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/ne94dg/jingwang-app-no-encryption-china-force-install-urumqi-xinjiang&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Motherboard previously covered&lt;/a&gt; JingWang, a piece of malware installed on devices in the Xinjiang region of China. Authorities typically installed JingWang on phones belonging to the Muslim Uighur population, and the app also scanned a phone for a similar particular set of files. According to expert analysis, the list of hunted files in BXAQ overlaps somewhat, but not entirely, with those that JingWang searches for, but BXAQ goes further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chinese authorities did not respond to a request for comment. Neither did Ninjing FiberHome StarrySky Communication Development Company Ltd, the partly state-owned company that developed the app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;There is an increasing trend around the world to treat borders as law-free zones where authorities have the right to carry out whatever outrageous form of surveillance they want,&quot; Omanovic said. &quot;But they’re not: the whole point of basic rights is that you’re entitled to them wherever you are. Western liberal democracies intent on implementing increasingly similar surveillance regimes at the border should look to what China is doing here and consider if this is really the model of security they want to be pursuing.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Subscribe to our new cybersecurity podc&lt;strong&gt;ast,&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/gb/podcast/cyber/id1441708044?mt=2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CYBER&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 15:05:26 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>el_duderino</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>China Is Forcing Tourists to Install Text-Stealing Malware at its Border</og:title>
<og:image>https://video-images.vice.com/articles/5d1b1953a25a2d0008e3f771/lede/1562057136894-AT_CHINESE_BORDERS_TOURISTS_FORCED_TO_INSTALL_A_TEXT_STEALING_PIECE_OF_MALWARE_NT.png?crop=1xw:1xh;center,center&amp;resize=1200:*</og:image>
<og:url>https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/7xgame/at-chinese-border-tourists-forced-to-install-a-text-stealing-piece-of-malware</og:url>
<og:description>The malware downloads a tourist’s text messages, calendar entries, and phone logs, as well as scans the device for over 70,000 different files.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/7xgame/at-chinese-border-tourists-forced-to-install-a-text-stealing-piece-of-malware</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Minnesota Will Pay Residents to Grow Bee-Friendly Lawns</title>
<link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/minnesota-will-pay-residents-grow-bee-friendly-lawns-180972430/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/minnesota-will-pay-residents-grow-bee-friendly-lawns-180972430/</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;100.89270998415&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plump rusty patched bumblebee, &lt;em&gt;Bombus affinis&lt;/em&gt;, once buzzed all across the eastern United States, the upper Midwest and parts of Canada. But today, the chunky critter is &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.nationalgeographic.com/2017/03/bumblebees-endangered-extinction-united-states/&quot;&gt;endangered&lt;/a&gt;, its population reduced by nearly 90 percent. In Minnesota, where the rusty patched bumblebee can still be found, officials have hatched a plan to help bolster the species’ population. As Jessica Leigh Hester reports for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.atlasobscura.com/articles/minnesota-bees&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Atlas Obscura&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; the state wants to pay residents to turn their lawns into bumblebee havens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In late May, Minnesota Governor Tim Walz &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/GovTimWalz/status/1134485260606070785&quot;&gt;signed a series of budget bills&lt;/a&gt; that included the provision of $900,000 for helping homeowners populate their pristine lawns with bee-friendly plants, like native grasses, creeping thyme and dutch white clover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“When people look at these flowers, they see a nuisance, they see a weed,” James Wolfin, a graduate student who works at the University of Minnesota’s Bee Lab, tells Esme Murphy of the local &lt;a href=&quot;https://minnesota.cbslocal.com/2019/05/30/program-to-help-minnesota-homeowners-make-their-lawns-bee-friendly-habitats/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;WCCO&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. “I see a forage for pollinators.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A major threat to the survival of the rusty patched bumblebee—and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.greenpeace.org/usa/sustainable-agriculture/save-the-bees/&quot;&gt;other bee species&lt;/a&gt;—is habitat loss. According to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fws.gov/midwest/endangered/insects/rpbb/factsheetrpbb.html&quot;&gt;U.S. Fish &amp;amp; Wildlife Service&lt;/a&gt;, most of the prairies and grasslands where the bees once roamed have been converted to “monoculture farms or developed areas.” Widespread pesticide use is another problem.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the USFWS explains:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Bumble bees can absorb toxins directly through their exoskeleton and through contaminated nectar and pollen. Rusty patched bumble bees nest in the ground and may be susceptible to pesticides that persist in agricultural soils, lawns and turf.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To that effect, experts have for some years been encouraging homeowners to &lt;a href=&quot;https://phys.org/news/2016-10-bees-herbicides-pesticides-lawns-naturally.html&quot;&gt;leave their grasses untreated&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.beelab.umn.edu/sites/beelab.umn.edu/files/floweringlawninfoenrtflogo.pdf&quot;&gt;enrich lawns with flowering plants&lt;/a&gt;, thereby creating a safe and diverse habitat for bees. Greg Stanley of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.startribune.com/program-pays-minnesota-homeowners-to-let-their-lawn-go-to-the-bees/510593382/?refresh=true&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Star Tribune&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; reports that Minnesota officials are still working out the kinks of their conservation plan, like how grants will be issued, but the state is expected to cover up 75 percent of the cost of converting participants’ lawns to flowering habitats. The program may be ready to launch by next spring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I have gotten a ton of e-mails and so much feedback from people who are interested in this,” State Representative Kelly Morrison, who introduced the bill, tells Stanley. “People are really thinking about how they can help.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minnesota has taken other measures to raise awareness about the plight of the rusty patched bumblebee, including &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mprnews.org/story/2019/05/31/bombus-affinis-meet-the-rusty-patched-bumblebee-new-state-bee-minnesota&quot;&gt;making it the state’s official bee&lt;/a&gt;. But the lawn conversion plan is also expected to help other species, which in turn may help humans. Bumblebees are vital to the ecosystem, pollinating not only wildflowers, but crops like blueberries, cranberries, apples and tomatoes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“One third of every bite you eat is due to a pollinator pollinating that plant,” Wolfin tells Murphy. He adds that even small steps, like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.popularmechanics.com/science/animals/a19550487/dont-mow-your-lawn-and-help-save-the-bees/&quot;&gt;letting lawns grow a little longer&lt;/a&gt;, can make a difference for the bees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We want you to still be able to have that family picnic, we want you to be able to have a catch on the lawn,” Wolfin says, “and we want you to put a little bit of food there to support the pollinators.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like this article?&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;SIGN UP&lt;/span&gt; for our newsletter&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 14:07:38 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pseudolus</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://thumbs-prod.si-cdn.com/v3Xx9fimAsxnz5eXa_EhvjRB-UU=/fit-in/1600x0/https://public-media.si-cdn.com/filer/12/c4/12c4e429-324f-4614-833d-43ae5d8e7db8/rusty_patched_bumble_bee_on_wild_bergamot_28626833097.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Minnesota Will Pay Residents to Grow Bee-Friendly Lawns</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/minnesota-will-pay-residents-grow-bee-friendly-lawns-180972430/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Leaving lawns untreated and allowing flowering plants to grow can help support the endangered rusty patched bumblebee</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/minnesota-will-pay-residents-grow-bee-friendly-lawns-180972430/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Backbone of VHF Amateur Radio May Be Under Threat</title>
<link>https://hackaday.com/2019/07/01/the-backbone-of-vhf-amateur-radio-may-be-under-threat/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://hackaday.com/2019/07/01/the-backbone-of-vhf-amateur-radio-may-be-under-threat/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;A story that has been on the burner for a few weeks concerns &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.arrl.org/news/proposed-wrc-23-agenda-items-causing-concern&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a proposal that will be advanced to the ITU World Radiocommunication Conference 2023&lt;/a&gt;. It originates with French spectrum regulators and is reported to be &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.southgatearc.org/news/2019/june/wia-news-discussion-point.htm#.XRnLcSbTU5k&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;at the behest of the Paris-based multinational defence contractor Thales&lt;/a&gt;. The sting in its tail is the proposed relegation of amateur radio to secondary status of the widely used two-meter band (144 MHz) to permit its usage by aircraft. The machinations of global spectrum regulation politics do not often provide stories for Hackaday readers, but this one should be of concern beyond the narrow bounds of amateur radio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most parts of the radio spectrum are shared between more than one user, and there is usually a primary occupant and a secondary one whose usage is dependent upon not interfering with other users. If you’ve used 435 MHz radio modems you will have encountered this, that’s a band shared with both radio amateurs and others including government users. While some countries have wider band limits, the two-meter band between 144 MHz and 146 MHz is allocated with primary status to radio amateurs worldwide, and it is this status that is placed under threat. The latest ARRL news is that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.arrl.org/news/no-strong-opposition-to-144-146-mhz-reallocation-proposal-at-cept-meeting&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;there has been little opposition at the pan-European regulator CEPT level&lt;/a&gt;, which &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kb6nu.com/will-we-lose-the-2m-band/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;appears to be causing concern&lt;/a&gt; among the amateur radio community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why should this bother you? If you are a radio amateur it should be a grave concern that a band which has provided the “glue” for so many vital services over many decades might come under threat, and if you are not a radio amateur it should concern you that a commercial defence contractor in one country can so easily set in motion the degradation of a globally open resource governed by international treaties penned in your grandparents’ time. Amateur radio is a different regulatory being from the licence-free spectrum that we now depend upon for so many things, but the principle of it being a free resource to all its users remains the same. If you have an interest in retaining the spectrum you use wherever on the dial it may lie, we suggest you support your national amateur radio organisation in opposing this measure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 14:01:55 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Errorcod3</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>The Backbone Of VHF Amateur Radio May Be Under Threat</og:title>
<og:url>https://hackaday.com/2019/07/01/the-backbone-of-vhf-amateur-radio-may-be-under-threat/</og:url>
<og:description>A story that has been on the burner for a few weeks concerns a proposal that will be advanced to the ITU World Radiocommunication Conference 2023. It originates with French spectrum regulators and …</og:description>
<og:image>https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/2metre-secondary-featured.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://hackaday.com/2019/07/01/the-backbone-of-vhf-amateur-radio-may-be-under-threat/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Svelte is the most beautiful web framework I&amp;#039;ve seen</title>
<link>https://www.thefutureoftheweb.com/blog/svelte-is-the-most-beautiful-framework-ive-ever-seen</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.thefutureoftheweb.com/blog/svelte-is-the-most-beautiful-framework-ive-ever-seen</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I first heard about Svelte a year ago, when Rich Harris &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qqt6YxAZoOc&quot;&gt;presented it at JSConf EU 2018&lt;/a&gt;. The demo gods were a bit harsh on him, but it didn't matter to me, because I was so impressed by his philosophy and ideas that I was already sold. I knew he'd work out the kinks, go through a few major versions, and Svelte would be mature enough in no time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I kind of forgot about Svelte after that, that was until last week when I read Rich Harris' blog post &lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.to/richharris/why-i-don-t-use-web-components-2cia&quot;&gt;Why I don't use web components&lt;/a&gt;. It reminded how simple and beautiful Svelte's syntax is, and I decided it was time to give it some serious consideration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, I played a little bit with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://svelte.dev/repl/&quot;&gt;Svelte REPL&lt;/a&gt;, and got a sense for how it works. Then I decided to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=S_6ApOagzzM&quot;&gt;try building a Tic Tac Toe game live on Twitch and YouTube&lt;/a&gt;. Even though I'm a total noob when it comes to Svelte, and I'd barely read the docs, it only took me about half an hour to get a Tic Tac Toe game working. After that, I explored some different Svelte features, trying to move the game state into a non-Svelte module, and discovered a few anti-patterns in the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;594&quot; height=&quot;334&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/S_6ApOagzzM&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end, I was completely blown away when I discovered that the production build had only 2,418 bytes of JavaScript..! That's 2.4kb including the Svelte runtime!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does Svelte do it? Because Svelte is a compiler. It only includes the bare minimum of JavaScript necessary to get the job done. It turns the HTML templates you write into extremely simple DOM scripting. It transpiles the JavaScript you write so that your simple variable assignments trigger a re-render. It generates JavaScript classes to represent your &lt;code&gt;.svelte&lt;/code&gt; files and wires everything up for you, so the only boilerplate you really need is a &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;script&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tag and a &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;style&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're interested in seeing the Tic Tac Toe game I built, you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jesseskinner/svelte-tic-tac-toe&quot;&gt;clone it on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;, and spin it up with &lt;code&gt;npm install&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;npm start&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, I highly recommend you check out the official &lt;a href=&quot;https://svelte.dev/tutorial/basics&quot;&gt;Svelte Tutorial&lt;/a&gt; and try it out for yourself!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 13:58:20 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>bhalp1</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.thefutureoftheweb.com/blog/svelte-is-the-most-beautiful-framework-ive-ever-seen</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Cloudflare Network Performance Issues</title>
<link>https://www.cloudflarestatus.com/incidents/tx4pgxs6zxdr</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.cloudflarestatus.com/incidents/tx4pgxs6zxdr</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;row update-row&quot; readability=&quot;7.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resolved&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;update-container span9&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cloudflare has resolved the issue and services have resumed normal operation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Posted &lt;span class=&quot;ago&quot;&gt;about &lt;var data-var=&quot;num&quot;&gt;10&lt;/var&gt; hours ago.&lt;/span&gt; Jul &lt;var data-var=&quot;date&quot;&gt;02&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&quot;year&quot;&gt;2019&lt;/var&gt; - &lt;var data-var=&quot;time&quot;&gt;14:57&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row update-row&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;update-container span9&quot; readability=&quot;11.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;update-body font-regular&quot; readability=&quot;37&quot;&gt;Cloudflare has implemented a fix for this issue and is currently monitoring the results.&lt;p&gt;Description:&lt;br/&gt;Major outage impacted all Cloudflare services globally. We saw a massive spike in CPU that caused primary and secondary systems to fall over. We shut down the process that was causing the CPU spike. Service restored to normal within ~30 minutes. We’re now investigating the root cause of what happened.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Posted &lt;span class=&quot;ago&quot;&gt;about &lt;var data-var=&quot;num&quot;&gt;10&lt;/var&gt; hours ago.&lt;/span&gt; Jul &lt;var data-var=&quot;date&quot;&gt;02&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&quot;year&quot;&gt;2019&lt;/var&gt; - &lt;var data-var=&quot;time&quot;&gt;14:50&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row update-row&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monitoring&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;update-container span9&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;update-body font-regular&quot; readability=&quot;34&quot;&gt;Cloudflare has implemented a fix for this issue and is currently monitoring the results.&lt;p&gt;We will update the status once the issue is resolved.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Posted &lt;span class=&quot;ago&quot;&gt;about &lt;var data-var=&quot;num&quot;&gt;11&lt;/var&gt; hours ago.&lt;/span&gt; Jul &lt;var data-var=&quot;date&quot;&gt;02&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&quot;year&quot;&gt;2019&lt;/var&gt; - &lt;var data-var=&quot;time&quot;&gt;14:15&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row update-row&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investigating&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;update-container span9&quot; readability=&quot;10.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;update-body font-regular&quot; readability=&quot;35&quot;&gt;Cloudflare is observing network performance issues. Customers may be experiencing 502 errors while accessing sites on Cloudflare.&lt;p&gt;We are working to mitigate impact to Internet users in this region.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Posted &lt;span class=&quot;ago&quot;&gt;about &lt;var data-var=&quot;num&quot;&gt;11&lt;/var&gt; hours ago.&lt;/span&gt; Jul &lt;var data-var=&quot;date&quot;&gt;02&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&quot;year&quot;&gt;2019&lt;/var&gt; - &lt;var data-var=&quot;time&quot;&gt;13:52&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This incident affected: North America (Ashburn, VA, United States - (IAD), Atlanta, GA, United States - (ATL), Boston, MA, United States - (BOS), Buffalo, NY, United States - (BUF), Calgary, AB, Canada - (YYC), Charlotte, NC, United States - (CLT), Chicago, IL, United States - (ORD), Columbus, OH, United States - (CMH), Dallas, TX, United States - (DFW), Denver, CO, United States - (DEN), Detroit, MI, United States - (DTW), Houston, TX, United States - (IAH), Indianapolis, IN, United States - (IND), Jacksonville, FL, United States - (JAX), Kansas City, MO, United States - (MCI), Las Vegas, NV, United States - (LAS), Los Angeles, CA, United States - (LAX), McAllen, TX, United States - (MFE), Memphis, TN, United States - (MEM), Miami, FL, United States - (MIA), Minneapolis, MN, United States - (MSP), Montgomery, AL, United States - (MGM), Montréal, QC, Canada - (YUL), Nashville, TN, United States - (BNA), Newark, NJ, United States - (EWR), Norfolk, VA, United States - (ORF), Omaha, NE, United States - (OMA), Phoenix, AZ, United States - (PHX), Pittsburgh, PA, United States - (PIT), Portland, OR, United States - (PDX), Queretaro, MX, Mexico - (QRO), Richmond, Virginia - (RIC), Sacramento, CA, United States - (SMF), Salt Lake City, UT, United States - (SLC), San Diego, CA, United States - (SAN), San Jose, CA, United States - (SJC), Saskatoon, SK, Canada - (YXE), Seattle, WA, United States - (SEA), St. Louis, MO, United States - (STL), Tampa, FL, United States - (TPA), Toronto, ON, Canada - (YYZ), Vancouver, BC, Canada - (YVR), Tallahassee, FL, United States - (TLH), Winnipeg, MB, Canada - (YWG)), Asia (Bangkok, Thailand - (BKK), Cebu, Philippines - (CEB), Chengdu, China - (CTU), Chennai, India - (MAA), Colombo, Sri Lanka - (CMB), Dongguan, China - (SZX), Foshan, China - (FUO), Fuzhou, China - (FOC), Guangzhou, China - (CAN), Hangzhou, China - (HGH), Hanoi, Vietnam - (HAN), Hengyang, China - (HNY), Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam - (SGN), Hong Kong - (HKG), Hyderabad, India - (HYD), Islamabad, Pakistan - (ISB), Jinan, China - (TNA), Karachi, Pakistan - (KHI), Kathmandu, Nepal - (KTM), Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia - (KUL), Lahore, Pakistan - (LHE), Langfang, China - (NAY), Luoyang, China - (LYA), Macau - (MFM), Manila, Philippines - (MNL), Mumbai, India - (BOM), Nanning, China - (NNG), New Delhi, India - (DEL), Osaka, Japan - (KIX), Phnom Penh, Cambodia - (PNH), Qingdao, China - (TAO), Seoul, South Korea - (ICN), Shanghai, China - (SHA), Shenyang, China - (SHE), Shijiazhuang, China - (SJW), Singapore, Singapore - (SIN), Suzhou, China - (SZV), Taipei - (TPE), Tianjin, China - (TSN), Tokyo, Japan - (NRT), Ulaanbaatar, Mongolia - (ULN), Wuhan, China - (WUH), Wuxi, China - (WUX), Xi'an, China - (XIY), Yerevan, Armenia - (EVN), Zhengzhou, China - (CGO), Zuzhou, China - (CSX)), Africa (Cairo, Egypt - (CAI), Casablanca, Morocco - (CMN), Cape Town, South Africa - (CPT), Dar Es Salaam, Tanzania - (DAR), Djibouti City, Djibouti - (JIB), Durban, South Africa - (DUR), Johannesburg, South Africa - (JNB), Lagos, Nigeria - (LOS), Luanda, Angola - (LAD), Maputo, MZ - (MPM), Mombasa, Kenya - (MBA), Port Louis, Mauritius - (MRU), Réunion, France - (RUN), Kigali, Rwanda - (KGL)), Oceania (Auckland, New Zealand - (AKL), Brisbane, QLD, Australia - (BNE), Melbourne, VIC, Australia - (MEL), Perth, WA, Australia - (PER), Sydney, NSW, Australia - (SYD)), Latin America &amp;amp; the Caribbean (Asunción, Paraguay - (ASU), Bogotá, Colombia - (BOG), Buenos Aires, Argentina - (EZE), Curitiba, Brazil - (CWB), Fortaleza, Brazil - (FOR), Lima, Peru - (LIM), Medellín, Colombia - (MDE), Mexico City, Mexico - (MEX), Panama City, Panama - (PTY), Porto Alegre, Brazil - (POA), Quito, Ecuador - (UIO), Rio de Janeiro, Brazil - (GIG), São Paulo, Brazil - (GRU), Santiago, Chile - (SCL), Willemstad, Curaçao - (CUR)), Middle East (Amman, Jordan - (AMM), Baghdad, Iraq - (BGW), Baku, Azerbaijan - (GYD), Beirut, Lebanon - (BEY), Doha, Qatar - (DOH), Dubai, United Arab Emirates - (DXB), Kuwait City, Kuwait - (KWI), Manama, Bahrain - (BAH), Muscat, Oman - (MCT), Ramallah - (ZDM), Riyadh, Saudi Arabia - (RUH), Tel Aviv, Israel - (TLV)), and Europe (Amsterdam, Netherlands - (AMS), Athens, Greece - (ATH), Barcelona, Spain - (BCN), Belgrade, Serbia - (BEG), Berlin, Germany - (TXL), Brussels, Belgium - (BRU), Bucharest, Romania - (OTP), Budapest, Hungary - (BUD), Chișinău, Moldova - (KIV), Copenhagen, Denmark - (CPH), Dublin, Ireland - (DUB), Düsseldorf, Germany - (DUS), Edinburgh, United Kingdom - (EDI), Frankfurt, Germany - (FRA), Geneva, Switzerland - (GVA), Gothenburg, Sweden - (GOT), Hamburg, Germany - (HAM), Helsinki, Finland - (HEL), Istanbul, Turkey - (IST), Kyiv, Ukraine - (KBP), Lisbon, Portugal - (LIS), London, United Kingdom - (LHR), Luxembourg City, Luxembourg - (LUX), Madrid, Spain - (MAD), Manchester, United Kingdom - (MAN), Marseille, France - (MRS), Milan, Italy - (MXP), Moscow, Russia - (DME), Munich, Germany - (MUC), Nicosia, Cyprus - (LCA), Oslo, Norway - (OSL), Paris, France - (CDG), Prague, Czech Republic - (PRG), Reykjavík, Iceland - (KEF), Riga, Latvia - (RIX), Rome, Italy - (FCO), Saint Petersburg, Russia - (LED), Sofia, Bulgaria - (SOF), Stockholm, Sweden - (ARN), Tallinn, Estonia - (TLL), Thessaloniki, Greece - (SKG), Vienna, Austria - (VIE), Vilnius, Lithuania - (VNO), Warsaw, Poland - (WAW), Zagreb, Croatia - (ZAG), Zürich, Switzerland - (ZRH)).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 13:49:51 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>drcongo</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.cloudflarestatus.com/incidents/tx4pgxs6zxdr</og:url>
<og:image>https://dka575ofm4ao0.cloudfront.net/assets/logos/favicon-2b86ed00cfa6258307d4a3d0c482fd733c7973f82de213143b24fc062c540367.png</og:image>
<og:title>HTTP 502 errors</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.cloudflarestatus.com/incidents/tx4pgxs6zxdr</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: Vector – A High-Performance Log and Metric Router Written in Rust</title>
<link>https://github.com/timberio/vector</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/timberio/vector</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;Box-body&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content p-5&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chat.vector.dev&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Slack Chat&lt;/a&gt;  •   &lt;a href=&quot;https://forum.vector.dev&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Forums&lt;/a&gt;  •   &lt;a href=&quot;https://vector.dev/mailing_list&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Mailing List&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/timberio/vector/blob/master/docs/assets/readme_diagram.svg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/timberio/vector/raw/master/docs/assets/readme_diagram.svg?sanitize=true&quot; alt=&quot;Vector&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vector is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.vector.dev/performance&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;high-performance&lt;/a&gt; observability data router. It makes &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.vector.dev/usage/configuration/sources&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;collecting&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.vector.dev/usage/configuration/transforms&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;transforming&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.vector.dev/usage/configuration/sinks&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;sending&lt;/a&gt; logs, metrics, and events easy. It decouples data collection &amp;amp; routing from your services, giving you control and data ownership, among &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.vector.dev/use-cases&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;many other benefits&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Built in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rust-lang.org/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Rust&lt;/a&gt;, Vector places high-value on &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.vector.dev/performance&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;performance&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.vector.dev/correctness&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;correctness&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.vector.dev/usage/administration&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;operator friendliness&lt;/a&gt;. It compiles to a single static binary and is designed to be &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.vector.dev/setup/deployment&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;deployed&lt;/a&gt; across your entire infrastructure, serving both as a light-weight &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.vector.dev/setup/deployment/roles/agent&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;agent&lt;/a&gt; and a highly efficient &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.vector.dev/setup/deployment/roles/service&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;service&lt;/a&gt;, making the process of getting data from A to B simple and unified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;About&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Setup&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Usage&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Resources&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fast&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; - Built in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rust-lang.org/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Rust&lt;/a&gt;, Vector is &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.vector.dev/performance&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;fast and memory efficient&lt;/a&gt;. No runtime. No garbage collector.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Correct&lt;/strong&gt; - Obsessed with &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.vector.dev/correctness&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;getting the details right&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vendor Neutral&lt;/strong&gt; - Does not favor a specific storage. Fair, open, with the user's best interest in mind.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agent Or Service&lt;/strong&gt; - One simple tool to get data from A to B. Deploys as an &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.vector.dev/setup/deployment/roles/agent&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;agent&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.vector.dev/setup/deployment/roles/service&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;service&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Logs, Metrics, or Events&lt;/strong&gt; - Logs, metrics, and events. Collect, unify, and ship all observability data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clear Guarantees&lt;/strong&gt; - A &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.vector.dev/about/guarantees&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;guarantee support matrix&lt;/a&gt; helps you understand your tradeoffs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easy To Deploy&lt;/strong&gt; - Cross-compiles to a single static binary with no runtime.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hot Reload&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.vector.dev/usage/administration/reloading&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Reload configuration on the fly&lt;/a&gt;, without skipping a beat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Performance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;Test&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;Vector&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;Filebeat&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;FluentBit&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;FluentD&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;Logstash&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;SplunkUF&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;SplunkHF&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/timberio/vector-test-harness/tree/master/cases/tcp_to_blackhole_performance&quot;&gt;TCP to Blackhole&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;86mib/s&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;n/a&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;64.4mib/s&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;27.7mib/s&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;40.6mib/s&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;n/a&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;n/a&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/timberio/vector-test-harness/tree/master/cases/file_to_tcp_performance&quot;&gt;File to TCP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;76.7mib/s&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;7.8mib/s&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;35mib/s&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;26.1mib/s&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;3.1mib/s&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;40.1mib/s&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;39mib/s&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/timberio/vector-test-harness/tree/master/cases/regex_parsing_performance&quot;&gt;Regex Parsing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;13.2mib/s&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;n/a&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20.5mib/s&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;2.6mib/s&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;4.6mib/s&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;n/a&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;7.8mib/s&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/timberio/vector-test-harness/tree/master/cases/tcp_to_http_performance&quot;&gt;TCP to HTTP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;26.7mib/s&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;n/a&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;19.6mib/s&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;1mib/s&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;2.7mib/s&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;n/a&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;n/a&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/timberio/vector-test-harness/tree/master/cases/tcp_to_tcp_performance&quot;&gt;TCP to TCP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;69.9mib/s&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;5mib/s&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;67.1mib/s&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;3.9mib/s&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;10mib/s&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;70.4mib/s&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;7.6mib/s&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;To learn more about our performance tests, please see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/timberio/vector-test-harness/&quot;&gt;Vector test harness&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Correctness&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn more about our performance tests, please see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/timberio/vector-test-harness/&quot;&gt;Vector test harness&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run the following in your terminal, then follow the on-screen instructions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
curl https://sh.vector.dev -sSf &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; sh
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or view &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.vector.dev/setup/installation&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;platform specific installation instructions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.vector.dev/usage/configuration/sources/file&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;file&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Ingests data through one or more local files and outputs log events.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.vector.dev/usage/configuration/sources/statsd&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;statsd&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Ingests data through the StatsD UDP protocol and outputs log events.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.vector.dev/usage/configuration/sources/stdin&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;stdin&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Ingests data through standard input (STDIN) and outputs log events.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.vector.dev/usage/configuration/sources/syslog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;syslog&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Ingests data through the Syslog 5424 protocol and outputs log events.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.vector.dev/usage/configuration/sources/tcp&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;tcp&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Ingests data through the TCP protocol and outputs log events.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.vector.dev/usage/configuration/sources/vector&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;vector&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Ingests data through another upstream Vector instance and outputs log events.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/timberio/vector/issues/new?labels=Type%3A+New+Feature%2C%7B%3Atitle%3D%3E%22New+%60%3Cname%3E%60+source%22%7D&amp;amp;title=New+%60%3Cname%3E%60+source&quot;&gt;+ request a new source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Transforms&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.vector.dev/usage/configuration/transforms/add_fields&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;add_fields&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Accepts log events and allows you to add one or more fields.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.vector.dev/usage/configuration/transforms/field_filter&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;field_filter&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Accepts log and metric events and allows you to filter events by a field's value.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.vector.dev/usage/configuration/transforms/grok_parser&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;grok_parser&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Accepts log events and allows you to parse a field value with Grok.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.vector.dev/usage/configuration/transforms/json_parser&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;json_parser&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Accepts log events and allows you to parse a field value as JSON.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.vector.dev/usage/configuration/transforms/lua&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;lua&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Accepts log events and allows you to transform events with a full embedded Lua engine.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.vector.dev/usage/configuration/transforms/regex_parser&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;regex_parser&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Accepts log events and allows you to parse a field's value with a Regular Expression.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.vector.dev/usage/configuration/transforms/remove_fields&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;remove_fields&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Accepts log and metric events and allows you to remove one or more event fields.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.vector.dev/usage/configuration/transforms/sampler&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;sampler&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Accepts log events and allows you to sample events with a configurable rate.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.vector.dev/usage/configuration/transforms/tokenizer&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;tokenizer&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Accepts log events and allows you to tokenize a field's value by splitting on white space, ignoring special wrapping characters, and zipping the tokens into ordered field names.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/timberio/vector/issues/new?labels=Type%3A+New+Feature%2C%7B%3Atitle%3D%3E%22New+%60%3Cname%3E%60+transform%22%7D&amp;amp;title=New+%60%3Cname%3E%60+transform&quot;&gt;+ request a new transform&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sinks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.vector.dev/usage/configuration/sinks/aws_cloudwatch_logs&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;aws_cloudwatch_logs&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Batches log events to AWS CloudWatch Logs via the &lt;code&gt;PutLogEvents&lt;/code&gt; API endpoint.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.vector.dev/usage/configuration/sinks/aws_kinesis_streams&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;aws_kinesis_streams&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Batches log events to AWS Kinesis Data Stream via the &lt;code&gt;PutRecords&lt;/code&gt; API endpoint.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.vector.dev/usage/configuration/sinks/aws_s3&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;aws_s3&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Batches log events to AWS S3 via the &lt;code&gt;PutObject&lt;/code&gt; API endpoint.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.vector.dev/usage/configuration/sinks/blackhole&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;blackhole&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Streams log and metric events to a blackhole that simply discards data, designed for testing and benchmarking purposes.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.vector.dev/usage/configuration/sinks/console&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;console&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Streams log and metric events to the console, &lt;code&gt;STDOUT&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;STDERR&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.vector.dev/usage/configuration/sinks/elasticsearch&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;elasticsearch&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Batches log events to Elasticsearch via the &lt;code&gt;_bulk&lt;/code&gt; API endpoint.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.vector.dev/usage/configuration/sinks/http&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;http&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Batches log events to a generic HTTP endpoint.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.vector.dev/usage/configuration/sinks/kafka&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;kafka&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Streams log events to Apache Kafka.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.vector.dev/usage/configuration/sinks/splunk_hec&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;splunk_hec&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Batches log events to a Splunk HTTP Event Collector.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.vector.dev/usage/configuration/sinks/tcp&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;tcp&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Streams log events to a TCP connection.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.vector.dev/usage/configuration/sinks/vector&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;vector&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Streams log events to another downstream Vector instance.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/timberio/vector/issues/new?labels=Type%3A+New+Feature%2C%7B%3Atitle%3D%3E%22New+%60%3Cname%3E%60+sink%22%7D&amp;amp;title=New+%60%3Cname%3E%60+sink&quot;&gt;+ request a new sink&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copyright 2019, Vector Authors. All rights reserved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the &quot;License&quot;); you may not use these files except in compliance with the License. You may obtain a copy of the License at&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software distributed under the License is distributed on an &quot;AS IS&quot; BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied. See the License for the specific language governing permissions and limitations under the License.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;Developed with ❤️ by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://timber.io&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Timber.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 13:33:48 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>zhs</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars1.githubusercontent.com/u/16866914?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>timberio/vector</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/timberio/vector</og:url>
<og:description>A High-Performance, Logs, Metrics, &amp; Events Router - timberio/vector</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/timberio/vector</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Decoded: GNU coreutils (2018)</title>
<link>https://www.maizure.org/projects/decoded-gnu-coreutils/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.maizure.org/projects/decoded-gnu-coreutils/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;October 2018&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.maizure.org/projects/decoded-gnu-coreutils/GNU.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;320&quot; alt=&quot;coreutils brought to you by the GNU project&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a long-term project to decode all of the GNU coreutils in version 8.3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This resource is for novice programmers exploring the design of command-line utilities. It is best used as an accompaniment providing useful background while reading the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/MaiZure/coreutils-8.3/tree/master/src&quot;&gt;source code&lt;/a&gt; of the utility you may be interested in. This is &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; a user guide -- Please see applicable &lt;a href=&quot;http://man7.org/linux/man-pages/dir_by_project.html#coreutils&quot;&gt;man pages&lt;/a&gt; for instructions on using these utilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Status&lt;/strong&gt;: Paused -- &lt;strong&gt;52%&lt;/strong&gt; complete  (3 complete, 95 partial)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Phase 1 [&lt;strong&gt;complete&lt;/strong&gt;] - Each utility has a dedicated page discussing the namespace and execution overview.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phase 2 - Line by line code walkthrough for each utility. Links from execution steps to v8.3 source. Expanded discussion about important ideas. Porting diagrams to something more collaborative. Resuming 2H 2019.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr class=&quot;section-divider&quot;/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;The GNU Core Utilities&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll link the utility pages here at the top. Click the command name for the detailed page decoding that utility. The discussion, source code, and walkthroughs are available on each page. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Helpful background for code reading&lt;/h2&gt;
The GNU coreutils has its foibles. Many of these utilities are approaching 30 years old and include revisions by many people over the years. Here are some things to keep in mind when reading the code:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tiny programs&lt;/strong&gt; - These utilities are small, (mostly) single-source file programs designed to do one thing and do it well. They are not designed for long life or to scale beyond their role. Consequently, we see designs often considered 'bad practice' such as:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Many globals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Liberal use of macros&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;goto&lt;/code&gt; statements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Long functions with nested switchs/loops&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Know POSIX&lt;/strong&gt; - Start with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://pubs.opengroup.org/onlinepubs/9699919799/basedefs/V1_chap12.html#tag_12_02&quot;&gt;Utility Syntax Guidelines&lt;/a&gt;. In general, POSIX supports interoperability by defining appropriate inputs and outputs, but leaves the 'work' to the implementation. While the GNU coreutils &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/coreutils/manual/html_node/Standards-conformance.html&quot;&gt;may not strictly conform&lt;/a&gt; to POSIX, many ideas are entrenched: permission bits, uids/gids, environment variables, exit status, and about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.open-std.org/jtc1/sc22/open/n4217.pdf&quot;&gt;3718 pages&lt;/a&gt; of more trivia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Outside help&lt;/strong&gt; - Portability is a complex problem and coreutils relies on extra help from a related project: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/s/gnulib/&quot;&gt;gnulib&lt;/a&gt;. Almost every utility includes functions from gnulib which are specially designed for common problems used in many places across various systems - No need to reinvent the wheel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Launched from a shell&lt;/strong&gt; - The Core utilities expect support from a shell such as bash, zsh, ksh, and others. The shell forks/clones in to the utility, passes the arguments, sets up the environment, redirects I/O via pipes, and retains exit values.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Three families&lt;/strong&gt; - GNU coreutils were originally three distinct packages for shell, text, and file utilities. Utilities within the same type share many of the same design patterns.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Basic design&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under the hood, most CLI utilities break down to this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.maizure.org/projects/decoded-gnu-coreutils/general_cli_utility.png&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;240&quot; alt=&quot;General CLI procedure&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key ideas:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;A setup phase for flags, options, localization, etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An argument parsing phase thats reads input to set execution parameters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A processing/execution phase that prepares input for one or more syscalls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many opportunities to check constraints and fail out of execution
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Distinct EXIT status hint about problem location&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EXIT_FAILURE is general and commonly used&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Providing feedback after failed execution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the framework I'll use to organize the decoding of each utility. We'll see that each has a unique variant of this idea which range from a few lines to thousands of lines. I'd categorize the variants in three groups: trivial, wrappers, and full utilities&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trivial utilities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Trivial utilities have a unique set up phase which defines a macro in a couple lines. Then it 'includes' the source of another utility in which the macro forces a specific flow control. Examples include: &lt;em&gt;arch&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;dir&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;vdir&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wrapper utilities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Wrappers perform setup and parse command line options which are passed directly as arguments to a syscall. The result of the syscall is the result of the utility. These utilities do little processing on their own. Examples include: &lt;em&gt;link&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;whoami&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;hostid&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;logname&lt;/em&gt;, and more&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full utilities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The diagram above shows a design for full utilities. A setup phase, an option/argument parsing phase, and execution. Execution means processing input data and may invoke many syscalls along the way to handle more data until complete. Most utilities fall in to this category.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;section-divider&quot;/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Digging deeper&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's go through the most common ideas shared across many of the utilities. Knowing these concepts beforehand should speed up code reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;i18n&quot;&gt;Utility Initialization&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All utilities have a short initialization procedure near the beginning of &lt;code&gt;main()&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
  initialize_main (&amp;amp;argc, &amp;amp;argv);
  set_program_name (argv[0]);
  setlocale (LC_ALL, &quot;&quot;);
  bindtextdomain (PACKAGE, LOCALEDIR);
  textdomain (PACKAGE);

  atexit (close_stdout);
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This preamble solves a few administrative issues; the most important of which are &lt;a href=&quot;http://pubs.opengroup.org/onlinepubs/9699919799/basedefs/locale.h.html&quot;&gt;internationalization&lt;/a&gt; and assigning the exit action. I'll go through each of these lines &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.maizure.org/projects/decoded-gnu-coreutils/index.html#commonlines&quot;&gt;below&lt;/a&gt;. This lines don't impact the specific action of a utility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;getopt&quot;&gt;Parsing with Getopt&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever wonder why command line utilities have had the same look and feel for the past 40 years? You can thank the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/libc/manual/html_node/Parsing-Program-Arguments.html&quot;&gt;Getopt&lt;/a&gt; toolset. The bare minimum you need to know to follow the coreutils is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Command line options can be 'short' and 'long', prefixed with (-) and (--) respectively. Short options are defined as a string while long options use a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/libc/manual/html_node/Getopt-Long-Options.html#Getopt-Long-Options&quot;&gt;struct&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Short options use 1) only a letter if the option has no argument, 2) A single colon (:) for mandatory arguments, and (::) for optional arguments. For example, the short option string for &lt;em&gt;kill&lt;/em&gt; is: &lt;code&gt;Lln:s:t&lt;/code&gt;. Which says that &lt;code&gt;L&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;l&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;t&lt;/code&gt; take no arguments but &lt;code&gt;n&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;s&lt;/code&gt; need an argument.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Long options often have a short analogue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;getopt_long()&lt;/code&gt; function returns the next option and is used in all utilities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;optind&lt;/code&gt; index is a position within the &lt;code&gt;argv[]&lt;/code&gt; array for the next argument.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;optarg&lt;/code&gt; char pointer points to the value of the option's argument.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;fts&quot;&gt;Traversing the file system with fts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unix-like systems often support the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.freebsd.org/cgi/man.cgi?query=fts&amp;amp;apropos=0&amp;amp;sektion=3&amp;amp;manpath=FreeBSD+11.2-RELEASE+and+Ports&amp;amp;arch=default&amp;amp;format=html&quot;&gt;fts&lt;/a&gt; library to easily manage walking through the file system. The basic hand-waved details are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The tree is represented by an &lt;code&gt;FTS&lt;/code&gt; structure built by calling &lt;code&gt;fts_open()&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;xfts_open()&lt;/code&gt; on a path.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A node (file/directory) from the tree is a &lt;code&gt;FTSENT&lt;/code&gt; structure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Calling &lt;code&gt;fts_read()&lt;/code&gt; on the FTS generates &lt;code&gt;FTSENT&lt;/code&gt;s. This is walking the tree.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;FTSENT-&amp;gt;fts_info&lt;/code&gt; field describes the entries. It is used often to decide how to handle the entry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Syscall wrappers, and helpers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;coreutils often invokes syscalls through wrappers and helpers beyond those provided by libc. Many are linked through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/gnulib/&quot;&gt;Gnulib project&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;write&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;libc provides many text writing functions, such as &lt;code&gt;fwrite()&lt;/code&gt; for buffered stream access, and the &lt;code&gt;write()&lt;/code&gt; syscall wrapper. Coreutils brings in non-standard functions such as &lt;code&gt;full_write()&lt;/code&gt;. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/coreutils/gnulib/blob/master/lib/full-write.c&quot;&gt;full_write()&lt;/a&gt; function continuously retries writes unless there is a hard failure. It relies on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/coreutils/gnulib/blob/master/lib/safe-read.c&quot;&gt;safe_write()&lt;/a&gt; to retry the &lt;code&gt;write()&lt;/code&gt; syscall across interrupts. Other write-related helpers are used only in a single utility. Such as &lt;code&gt;iwrite()&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;em&gt;dd&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;code&gt;cwrite()&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;em&gt;split&lt;/em&gt;. I'll discuss those within the utilities themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Common functions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All utilities use at least three functions: &lt;code&gt;main()&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;usage()&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;_()&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;usage()&lt;/code&gt; function displays help for the utility that includes a list of input parameters, their meaning, and appropriate syntax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;_()&lt;/code&gt; function is really a macro defined in &lt;code&gt;system.h&lt;/code&gt; that binds simple strings to the Native Language Support capability in GNU &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/coreutils/gnulib/blob/master/lib/gettext.h&quot;&gt;gettext.h&lt;/a&gt;. If it's a string meant to be shown to the user, it's probably wrapped with this function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;commonlines&quot;&gt;Common code lines&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following code lines occur in most non-trivial utilities:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;#include &quot;system.h&quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This header defines system-dependent marcos, variables, and functions. It provides 'translations' necessary to allow coreutils to build on as many architectures as possible. The file really is a patchwork of corner cases with little organization. I won't be taking this apart unless there is overwhelming number of requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;#define PROGRAM_NAME &quot;cat&quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Defines the official name for the utility. Used in the 'version' check.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;#define AUTHORS proper_name (&quot;Richard M. Stallman&quot;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Defines the authors for the utility. Used in the 'version' check.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;emit_try_help ()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Prints help suggestion after failed output. Includes a link to the online documents. This will appear at the beginning of &lt;code&gt;usage()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;emit_ancillary_info (PROGRAM_NAME)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Prints common extra help info after the command-specific output. Includes a link to the online documents. This appears close to the end of &lt;code&gt;usage()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;exit (status)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Syscall to end execution with the given status. This appears at the end of &lt;code&gt;usage()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;initialize_main(&amp;amp;argc, &amp;amp;argv)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Special handler for OS/2 forcing built-in wildcard expansion. This is defined away for most other operating systems&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;set_program_name(argv[0]);&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Saves the basic program name using the first input argument. Discards the path component of argv[0].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;setlocale(LC_ALL, &quot;&quot;);&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Sets up internationalization options during execution. Provided by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/libc/manual/html_node/Setting-the-Locale.html&quot;&gt;libc&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;locale.h&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;bindtextdomain (PACKAGE, LOCALEDIR);&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Sets the directory of intenationalization features using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/gettext/&quot;&gt;free software&lt;/a&gt; gettext.h&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;textdomain (PACKAGE);&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Sets the text domain to enable i18n.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;atexit(close_stdout);&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Registers the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gagern/gnulib/blob/master/lib/closeout.c&quot;&gt;close_stdout&lt;/a&gt; function for call when the program ends. This flushes the buffer steam in addition to closing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;IF_LINT(something);&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Suppresses GCC warnings if using a linter by including the code within the parens. Usually this is NOP&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;C idioms&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few idioms buried in the coreutils source that may be unfamiliar to beginners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;!!&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The double exclaimation point is exactly what you see, a double unary NOT operation. The purpose is to coerce a value in to a boolean. It's often used to make a flag from a function return value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;do { ... } while (0)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The non-loop often encloses a multi-statement macro to ensure proper tokenization after preprocessor substitution. The core use-case is as a consequent:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
if (condition)
  MACRO;
else 
  something else
&lt;/pre&gt;
Note that lack of semi-colon after the while -- this is included wherever the macro appears in the C code.
&lt;hr class=&quot;section-divider&quot;/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Fun facts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shortest utility: &lt;strong&gt;false&lt;/strong&gt; (2 lines - tied with arch, dir, and vdir)&lt;br/&gt;Shortest standalone utility: &lt;strong&gt;true&lt;/strong&gt; (80 lines)&lt;br/&gt;Longest utility: &lt;strong&gt;ls&lt;/strong&gt; (5308 lines)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Many utilities trace their origins to pre-System V UNIX (some as far back as &lt;a href=&quot;https://multicians.org/multics-commands.html&quot;&gt;Multics&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The oldest spiritual ancestor is the CTSS &lt;em&gt;LISTF&lt;/em&gt; command (~1963). Thankfully shorted to &lt;em&gt;ls&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The distinct syntax of the &lt;em&gt;dd&lt;/em&gt; utility is reminiscent of the OS/360 &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Job_Control_Language#Concatenating_input_files&quot;&gt;job control language&lt;/a&gt; (early 1960s).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;em&gt;sort&lt;/em&gt; program is the only utility that takes advantage of multi-threading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;em&gt;fmt&lt;/em&gt; utility demonstrates optimization of lines and paragraphs using feature costs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The deceptively simple &lt;em&gt;yes&lt;/em&gt; utility has high-performance output using page-aligned memory buffers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;em&gt;df&lt;/em&gt; utility is faster than &lt;em&gt;du&lt;/em&gt;. The former uses device metadata while the latter checks all files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;cksum&lt;/em&gt; includes two entry points, one for normal operation and one to generate the CRC-32 table&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is no failure condition for the &lt;em&gt;echo&lt;/em&gt; utility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The design of the &lt;em&gt;test&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;expr&lt;/em&gt; utilities departs significantly from the typical utility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;expr&lt;/em&gt; is a standalone example of left-associative expression evaluation that doesn't rely on automated tools&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My personal least used utilities are &lt;em&gt;tsort&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;ptx&lt;/em&gt; - haven't touched either since the 1990s&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr class=&quot;section-divider&quot;/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;FAQ&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No questions yet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 12:15:14 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mariuz</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.maizure.org/projects/decoded-gnu-coreutils/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>