<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Does Facebook pay Apple 30% of revenue derived from ads made within its iOS app?</title>
<link>https://twitter.com/SpencerDailey/status/1299063704483438593</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://twitter.com/SpencerDailey/status/1299063704483438593</guid>
<description>Maybe it's common knowledge that FB pays Apple 30% of its mobile-derived ad revenue, and I just look dumb. But if it's not the case, then it has to be exhibit A in rule enforcement double standards. Like, &lt;a href=&quot;https://mobile.twitter.com/marcoarment&quot; class=&quot;twitter-atreply dir-ltr&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; data-mentioned-user-id=&quot;14231571&quot; data-screenname=&quot;marcoarment&quot;&gt;@marcoarment&lt;/a&gt;'s ads for Overcast are sold out-of-app, lowering conversion %</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 19:49:54 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>spenvo</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mobile.twitter.com/SpencerDailey/status/1299063704483438593</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>ReMarkable 2.0 – A digital notebook that feels like paper</title>
<link>https://remarkable.com/#What_Is_New</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://remarkable.com/#What_Is_New</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://remarkable.com/#What_Is_New&quot;&gt;https://remarkable.com/#What_Is_New&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24295443&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24295443&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 817&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 500&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 16:38:03 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>punnerud</dc:creator>
<og:title>Home | reMarkable</og:title>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://remarkable.com/</og:url>
<og:description>Replace your notebooks and printed documents with the only tablet that feels like paper.</og:description>
<og:image>https://remarkable.comhttps://cdn.sanity.io/images/0e4kwcjv/production/fa8cf2f316203111c843c229347f6bee7528f94e-1200x630.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://remarkable.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Wind and solar are cheaper than thought, admits UK government</title>
<link>https://www.carbonbrief.org/wind-and-solar-are-30-50-cheaper-than-thought-admits-uk-government</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.carbonbrief.org/wind-and-solar-are-30-50-cheaper-than-thought-admits-uk-government</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Electricity generated from wind and solar is 30-50% cheaper than previously thought, according to newly published UK government figures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/beis-electricity-generation-costs-2020&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;new estimates&lt;/a&gt; of the “levelised cost” of electricity, published this week by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/organisations/department-for-business-energy-and-industrial-strategy&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy&lt;/a&gt; (BEIS), show that renewables are much cheaper than expected in the previous iteration of the report, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/beis-electricity-generation-costs-november-2016&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;published in 2016&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The previously published version had, in turn, already &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.carbonbrief.org/analysis-dramatic-shift-uk-government-outlook-gas-clean-energy&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;trimmed the cost&lt;/a&gt; of wind and solar by up to 30%. As a result, electricity from onshore wind or solar could be supplied in 2025 at half the cost of gas-fired power, the new estimates suggest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new report is the government’s first public admission of the dramatic reductions in renewable costs in recent years. It had previously carried out internal updates to its cost estimates, in both 2018 and 2019, but these were never published despite &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theyworkforyou.com/search/?q=levelised&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;repeated questions in parliament&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The BEIS report also presents new estimates of the “enhanced levelised cost” of different technologies, which reflects any wider system benefits and their “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.carbonbrief.org/in-depth-whole-system-costs-renewables&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;system integration costs&lt;/a&gt;”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These alternative figures, which have been under development for several years, put gas with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.carbonbrief.org/around-the-world-in-22-carbon-capture-projects&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;carbon capture and storage&lt;/a&gt; (CCS) in a particularly favourable light, with costs comparable to wind or solar. CCS is expected to feature in the upcoming energy white paper, due this autumn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Levelised cost&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new BEIS report on electricity generation costs is the first to be published in nearly four years. It sets out estimates of the “levelised cost of electricity” (LCOE) for various technologies, ranging from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theccc.org.uk/2012/05/24/unabated-gas-fired-generation-24-may-2012/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;unabated&lt;/a&gt; gas-fired power stations through to wind, solar and gas CCS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LCOE estimates are presented as the average cost of electricity, per megawatt hour (MWh) generated, across the lifetime of a new power plant. The new report gives these figures in £(2018). (Where comparisons are made, Carbon Brief has adjusted earlier estimates &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/statistics/gdp-deflators-at-market-prices-and-money-gdp-june-2020-quarterly-national-accounts&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;in line with inflation&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The LCOE is designed to offer uniform cost comparisons between technologies, based on a consistent framework and a series of assumptions. These include how much power plants cost to build and their average electricity output each year, as well as project lifetimes and financing costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The LCOE does not include wider costs and benefits at a system level. This could include reductions in wholesale prices due to abundant zero-carbon generation, or higher grid costs due to the variable output from wind and solar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The latest BEIS report gives LCOE estimates for projects that start operating in 2025, 2030, 2035 or 2040. Changes over time result from “technological learning”, as well as future prices for fossil fuels and CO2 emissions. For the first time, the report also presents “enhanced levelised cost” estimates. These attempt to capture wider costs and benefits, and are discussed below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The BEIS estimates are updated at regular intervals, with previous iterations having been published in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/beis-electricity-generation-costs-november-2016&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;2016&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/decc-electricity-generation-costs-2013&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;2013&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/electricity-generation-cost-model-update-of-non-renewable-technologies-2012&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;2012&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/electricity-generation-cost-model-update-by-parsons-brinckerhoff-2011&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;2011&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/uk-electricity-generation-costs-mott-macdonald-update-2010&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;2010&lt;/a&gt;. The department made internal updates in 2018 and 2019, with these revisions the subject of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/peer-review-of-2018-electricity-generation-cost-updates&quot;&gt;peer&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/peer-review-of-2019-electricity-generation-cost-updates&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;review&lt;/a&gt; papers also published this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the 2018 and 2019 updates remain unpublished, despite numerous questions in parliament in which MPs asked repeatedly after the latest BEIS cost estimates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Renewable costs slashed again&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most striking result of the new 2020 report is that BEIS has once again slashed its estimates for the levelised cost of wind and solar power. This is illustrated in the chart, below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2013, the UK government estimated that an offshore windfarm opening in 2025 would generate electricity for £140/MWh. By 2016, this was revised down by 24%, to £107/MWh. The latest estimate puts the cost at just £57/MWh, another 47% reduction (leftmost red column, below).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new estimates include similarly dramatic reductions for onshore wind and solar, with levelised costs in 2025 now thought to be some 50% lower than expected by the 2013 government report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In contrast, the new report does not revise earlier estimates for the cost of nuclear power. Instead, BEIS notes the government’s “ambition” that nuclear should deliver a 30% cost reduction by 2030.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.carbonbrief.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Levelised-cost-estimates-for-electricity-generation-in-2025.png&quot; id=&quot;mob&quot; alt=&quot;Levelised cost estimates for electricity generation in 2025, in £(2018) per megawatt hour, for a range of different technologies. For each technology, estimates were published in 2013 (dark grey), 2016 (light grey) and 2020 (red). Source: Carbon Brief analysis of BEIS estimates adjusted for inflation using Treasury deflators. Chart by Carbon Brief using Highcharts.&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-33774&quot;/&gt; Levelised cost estimates for electricity generation in 2025, in £(2018) per megawatt hour, for a range of different technologies. For each technology, estimates were published in 2013 (dark grey), 2016 (light grey) and 2020 (red). Source: Carbon Brief analysis of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/collections/energy-generation-cost-projections&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;BEIS estimates&lt;/a&gt; adjusted for inflation using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/statistics/gdp-deflators-at-market-prices-and-money-gdp-june-2020-quarterly-national-accounts&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;Treasury deflators&lt;/a&gt;. Chart by Carbon Brief using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.highcharts.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;Highcharts&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;The reasons for the renewable cost reductions are well documented. They include technological learning in the industry – with larger, more efficient manufacturing plants for solar and larger turbines for wind – but also operational experience, longer project lifetimes and cheaper finance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reductions have already been reflected in auctions for UK government contracts. Most recently, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.carbonbrief.org/analysis-record-low-uk-offshore-wind-cheaper-than-existing-gas-plants-by-2023&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;contracts were awarded&lt;/a&gt; for offshore windfarms due to start operating in the mid-2020s, at prices below the costs of existing gas-fired power stations – making them effectively “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.carbonbrief.org/guest-post-the-era-of-negative-subsidy-offshore-wind-power-has-almost-arrived&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;subsidy free&lt;/a&gt;”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The levelised costs published by BEIS are a slightly different measure to the “strike prices” awarded under these government “contracts for difference”. The central estimate of £57/MWh LCOE for offshore wind in 2025 is higher than strike prices of £44/MWh awarded at auction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to BEIS, the difference is partly explained by winning project bids having particularly favourable site conditions, as well larger sizes that bring economies of scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wind and solar cheapest&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new BEIS estimates make another small reduction in the levelised cost of electricity from gas, attributable to the department assuming turbines are now slightly more efficient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite this small reduction, the much larger cuts for renewables mean onshore wind and solar are now expected to be half as costly as gas in 2025, as shown in the chart below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notably, the BEIS cost estimates for onshore wind and solar assume no access to government contracts, meaning higher borrowing costs and an increased LCOE. Since these technologies will now once again be &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.carbonbrief.org/daily-brief/uk-government-lifts-block-on-new-onshore-windfarm-subsidies&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;able to bid for contracts&lt;/a&gt;, their costs will be even lower than presented here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carbon Brief estimates using a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nrel.gov/analysis/tech-lcoe.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;basic LCOE calculator&lt;/a&gt; and 2018 BEIS figures for &lt;a href=&quot;https://assets.publishing.service.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/attachment_data/file/910814/Cost_of_Capital_Update_for_Electricity_Generation_Storage_and_Demand_Side_Response_Technologies.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;financing costs&lt;/a&gt;, with or without a government contract, suggest around £2/MWh could be shaved off onshore wind and solar prices, based on a 0.8 percentage point reduction in the cost of capital.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.carbonbrief.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Levelised-cost-estimates-for-electricity-generation-in-2025-for-a-range-of-different-technologies.png&quot; id=&quot;mob&quot; alt=&quot;Levelised cost estimates for electricity generation in 2025, in £(2018) per megawatt hour, for a range of different technologies. For each technology, the bars show the range of uncertainty for construction and borrowing costs, while the whiskers show uncertain fuel prices. Source: Carbon Brief analysis of BEIS estimates adjusted for inflation using Treasury deflators. Chart by Carbon Brief using Highcharts.&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-33774&quot;/&gt; Levelised cost estimates for electricity generation in 2025, in £(2018) per megawatt hour, for a range of different technologies. For each technology, the bars show the range of uncertainty for construction and borrowing costs, while the whiskers show uncertain fuel prices. Source: Carbon Brief analysis of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/collections/energy-generation-cost-projections&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;BEIS estimates&lt;/a&gt; adjusted for inflation using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/statistics/gdp-deflators-at-market-prices-and-money-gdp-june-2020-quarterly-national-accounts&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;Treasury deflators&lt;/a&gt;. Chart by Carbon Brief using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.highcharts.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;Highcharts&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;BEIS has also significantly reduced its levelised cost estimates for gas CCS, meaning the technology is seen as competitive with unabated gas in 2025 and cheaper thereafter, as the price of emitting CO2 rises (see chart below).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The department explains this reduction by pointing to assumptions of more rapid CCS construction timelines and higher associated gas turbine efficiency, along with lower estimates for the cost of CO2 transport and storage. These changes are based on a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/power-carbon-capture-usage-and-storage-ccus-technologies-technical-and-cost-assumptions&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;2018 report for government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The levelised cost reduction for CCS also relates to an assumption that financing costs will be much lower – by at least 2 percentage points – than thought in the 2016 estimates. Given the technology has yet to be deployed at scale in the UK, this assumption is highly uncertain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Offshore wind to overtake onshore&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The BEIS estimates show that wind and solar will continue to get cheaper over time as larger turbines are deployed and other sources of learning continue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is shown in the chart below, including the notable fact that BEIS now expects offshore wind to become cheaper than onshore by the mid-2030s. This is primarily due to much larger turbine sizes, reaching 20 megawatts (MW) by 2040, up from 9MW today.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.carbonbrief.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Levelised-cost-estimates-for-electricity-generation-in-2025-2040.png&quot; id=&quot;mob&quot; alt=&quot;Levelised cost estimates for electricity generation in 2025-2040, in £(2018) per megawatt hour, for a range of different technologies. For each technology, the lines show expected changes in cost over time. Source: Carbon Brief analysis of BEIS estimates adjusted for inflation using Treasury deflators. Chart by Carbon Brief using Highcharts.&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-33774&quot;/&gt; Levelised cost estimates for electricity generation in 2025-2040, in £(2018) per megawatt hour, for a range of different technologies. For each technology, the lines show expected changes in cost over time. Source: Carbon Brief analysis of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/collections/energy-generation-cost-projections&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;BEIS estimates&lt;/a&gt; adjusted for inflation using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/statistics/gdp-deflators-at-market-prices-and-money-gdp-june-2020-quarterly-national-accounts&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;Treasury deflators&lt;/a&gt;. Chart by Carbon Brief using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.highcharts.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;Highcharts&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;Larger turbines placed further out to sea give access to stronger and much more consistent winds, meaning offshore windfarms are expected to have “load factors” reaching as high as 63% in 2040.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Load factors represent the proportion of theoretical maximum electricity output achieved across an entire year, after accounting for variations due to maintenance and weather conditions. For reference, the average load factor for the world’s coal-fired power stations is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.carbonbrief.org/analysis-the-global-coal-fleet-shrank-for-first-time-on-record-in-2020&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;now around 50%&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the chart above, note that the rising cost of gas-fired electricity is due to an assumption that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.carbonbrief.org/qa-will-reformed-eu-emissions-trading-system-raise-carbon-prices&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;CO2 prices&lt;/a&gt; will continue to increase over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Whole system costs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wind and solar are the clear winners of the new BEIS estimates, expected to be able to generate electricity much more cheaply than any other technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the report also publishes estimates of the “enhanced levelised cost” of each source of electricity, which it says “changes our cost perception of different technologies”. The department started work on this area in 2015 and has only now published its findings for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is an attempt to capture the “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.carbonbrief.org/in-depth-whole-system-costs-renewables&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;whole system costs&lt;/a&gt;” of an individual power plant. This could include the costs of enhancing the electricity network to connect a new power station, balancing supply and demand in real time, and providing backup power during periods of low wind or sun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(See Carbon Brief’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.carbonbrief.org/in-depth-whole-system-costs-renewables&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;2017 article&lt;/a&gt; on system costs for more background.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The BEIS estimates of these enhanced levelised costs are shown in the chart below, for each technology in 2025, 2030 and 2035. The grey bars represent the standard LCOE and the blue diamonds show the “enhanced” estimate under six different scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, gas and gas+CCS have “enhanced” costs that are lower than their respective LCOEs, whereas renewables are higher. Overall, the chart shows that enhanced cost estimates are in a similar ballpark across the different technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_34613&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;38.035714285714&quot;&gt;&lt;img aria-describedby=&quot;caption-attachment-34613&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-34613&quot; src=&quot;https://www.carbonbrief.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Enhanced-levelised-cost-estimates-for-electricity-generation-in-2025-2035.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Enhanced levelised cost estimates for electricity generation in 2025-2035, in £(2018) per megawatt hour, for a range of different technologies. For each technology, the grey bars show the levelised cost and the blue diamonds show enhanced levelised costs in six scenarios, which vary as to the characteristics of the overall electricity system. Source: BEIS 2020.&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;596&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.carbonbrief.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Enhanced-levelised-cost-estimates-for-electricity-generation-in-2025-2035.jpg 1024w, https://www.carbonbrief.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Enhanced-levelised-cost-estimates-for-electricity-generation-in-2025-2035-300x175.jpg 300w, https://www.carbonbrief.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Enhanced-levelised-cost-estimates-for-electricity-generation-in-2025-2035-768x447.jpg 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p id=&quot;caption-attachment-34613&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Enhanced levelised cost estimates for electricity generation in 2025-2035, in £(2018) per megawatt hour, for a range of different technologies. For each technology, the grey bars show the levelised cost and the blue diamonds show enhanced levelised costs in six scenarios, which vary as to the characteristics of the overall electricity system. Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://assets.publishing.service.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/attachment_data/file/911817/electricity-generation-cost-report-2020.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;BEIS 2020&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is difficult to go beyond a broad interpretation of these new estimates, however, because they span a very wide range of cost figures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ukerc.ac.uk/about/people/rob-gross/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;Dr Rob Gross&lt;/a&gt;, director of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ukerc.ac.uk/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;UK Energy Research Centre&lt;/a&gt; (UKERC), tells Carbon Brief that system costs are not fixed, as they depend strongly on the characteristics of the system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result, Gross says “it is particularly important for assumptions to be explicit” and that numbers presented without such transparency run the risk of being “misleading”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imperial.ac.uk/people/philip.heptonstall&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;Dr Phil Heptonstall&lt;/a&gt; is research fellow at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imperial.ac.uk/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;Imperial College London&lt;/a&gt; and a co-author, with Gross, of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.carbonbrief.org/in-depth-whole-system-costs-renewables&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;2017 review&lt;/a&gt; of system cost estimates for renewables. He tells Carbon Brief:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;wp-block-quote&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You can come up with quite a high number if you assume that you make no attempt to make the system more flexible. But that’s not a rational or sensible thing to do.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lack of transparency about the assumptions in the BEIS report is “frustrating”, Heptonstall adds, and makes it “difficult to form any conclusions about what it means”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notably, the BEIS report does not set out its assumptions around the makeup of the overall system, within which the “enhanced levelised cost” estimates are being made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All it says is that the six scenarios shown in the chart represent higher or lower electricity demand, combined with three pathways towards net-zero in 2050, using high shares of renewables, high nuclear or a “balanced” mix of the two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, key assumptions around the assumed levels of flexibility of the electricity system are not disclosed by BEIS. Flexibility could include greater levels of interconnection with other countries, higher deployment of battery storage or enhanced use of electric vehicle “smart charging”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theccc.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Net-Zero-Technical-Annex-Integrating-variable-renewables.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; from the Committee on Climate Change (CCC) shows that system costs depend very strongly on flexibility. For offshore wind, for example, integration costs range from less than £10/MWh to £50/MWh, with the high end representing no progress over current levels of flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The BEIS report includes system costs in the range of around £12-30/MWh in 2025 rising to around £20-40/MWh in 2040. Heptonstall tells Carbon Brief:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;wp-block-quote&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If we don’t know what types of flexibility is provided in those scenarios, we can’t tell if those numbers are a fair reflection.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carbon Brief has asked BEIS to explain its assumptions on flexibility. This article will be updated, if a response is received.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;artShareLine&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sharelines from this story&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wind and solar are 30-50% cheaper than thought, admits UK government&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wind and solar are 50% cheaper than gas-fired electricity, says UK government&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 16:28:14 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>open-source-ux</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Wind and solar are 30-50% cheaper than thought, admits UK government</og:title>
<og:description>The most striking result of the new 2020 report is that BEIS has once again slashed its estimates for the levelised cost of wind and solar power. This is illustrated in the chart, below.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.carbonbrief.org/wind-and-solar-are-30-50-cheaper-than-thought-admits-uk-government</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.carbonbrief.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Solar-farm-in-the-UK.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.carbonbrief.org/wind-and-solar-are-30-50-cheaper-than-thought-admits-uk-government</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Rust 1.46</title>
<link>https://blog.rust-lang.org/2020/08/27/Rust-1.46.0.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.rust-lang.org/2020/08/27/Rust-1.46.0.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Aug. 27, 2020 · The Rust Release Team&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;96.515368120086&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Rust team is happy to announce a new version of Rust, 1.46.0. Rust is a programming language that is empowering everyone to build reliable and efficient software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have a previous version of Rust installed via rustup, getting Rust 1.46.0 is as easy as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-console&quot;&gt;rustup update stable
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don't have it already, you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rust-lang.org/tools/install&quot;&gt;get &lt;code&gt;rustup&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; from the appropriate page on our website, and check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/blob/master/RELEASES.md#version-1460-2020-08-27&quot;&gt;detailed release notes for 1.46.0&lt;/a&gt; on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What's in 1.46.0 stable&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This release enables quite a lot of new things to appear in &lt;code&gt;const fn&lt;/code&gt;, two new standard library APIs, and one feature useful for library authors. See the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/blob/master/RELEASES.md#version-1460-2020-08-27&quot;&gt;detailed release notes&lt;/a&gt; to learn about other changes not covered by this post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;code&gt;const fn&lt;/code&gt; improvements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/72437/&quot;&gt;several core language features&lt;/a&gt; you can now use in a &lt;code&gt;const fn&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;if&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;if let&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;match&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;while&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;while let&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;loop&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the &lt;code&gt;&amp;amp;&amp;amp;&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;||&lt;/code&gt; operators&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can also &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/73862/&quot;&gt;cast to a slice&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-rust&quot;&gt;const fn foo() {
  let x = [1, 2, 3, 4, 5];

  // cast the array to a slice
  let y: &amp;amp;[_] = &amp;amp;x;
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While these features may not feel &lt;em&gt;new&lt;/em&gt;, given that you could use them all outside of &lt;code&gt;const fn&lt;/code&gt;, they add a lot of compile-time computation power! As an example, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rylev/const-sha1&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;const-sha1&lt;/code&gt; crate&lt;/a&gt; can let you compute SHA-1 hashes at compile time. This led to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/microsoft/winrt-rs/pull/279#issuecomment-668436700&quot;&gt;40x performance improvement&lt;/a&gt; in Microsoft's WinRT bindings for Rust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;code&gt;#[track_caller]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in March, the release of Rust 1.42 introduced &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.rust-lang.org/2020/03/12/Rust-1.42.html#useful-line-numbers-in-option-and-result-panic-messages&quot;&gt;better error messages when &lt;code&gt;unwrap&lt;/code&gt; and related functions would panic&lt;/a&gt;. At the time, we mentioned that the way this was implemented was not yet stable. Rust 1.46 stabilizes this feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This attribute is called &lt;code&gt;#[track_caller]&lt;/code&gt;, which was originally proposed in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rfcs/pull/2091&quot;&gt;RFC 2091&lt;/a&gt; way back in July of 2017! If you're writing a function like &lt;code&gt;unwrap&lt;/code&gt; that may panic, you can put this annotation on your functions, and the default panic formatter will use its caller as the location in its error message. For example, here is &lt;code&gt;unwrap&lt;/code&gt; previously:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-rust&quot;&gt;pub fn unwrap(self) -&amp;gt; T {
    match self {
        Some(val) =&amp;gt; val,
        None =&amp;gt; panic!(&quot;called `Option::unwrap()` on a `None` value&quot;),
    }
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It now looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-rust&quot;&gt;#[track_caller]
pub fn unwrap(self) -&amp;gt; T {
    match self {
        Some(val) =&amp;gt; val,
        None =&amp;gt; panic!(&quot;called `Option::unwrap()` on a `None` value&quot;),
    }
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are implementing a panic hook yourself, you can use the &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.rust-lang.org/stable/std/panic/struct.Location.html#method.caller&quot;&gt;caller&lt;/a&gt; method on &lt;code&gt;std::panic::Location&lt;/code&gt; to get access to this information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Library changes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keeping with the theme of &lt;code&gt;const fn&lt;/code&gt; improvements, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/73887/&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;std::mem::forget&lt;/code&gt; is now a &lt;code&gt;const fn&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Additionally, two new APIs were stabilized this release:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/blob/master/RELEASES.md#version-1460-2020-08-27&quot;&gt;detailed release notes&lt;/a&gt; for more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Other changes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are other changes in the Rust 1.46.0 release: check out what changed in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/blob/master/RELEASES.md#version-1460-2020-08-27&quot;&gt;Rust&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/cargo/blob/master/CHANGELOG.md#cargo-146-2020-08-27&quot;&gt;Cargo&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust-clippy/blob/master/CHANGELOG.md#rust-146&quot;&gt;Clippy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Contributors to 1.46.0&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people came together to create Rust 1.46.0. We couldn't have done it without all of you. &lt;a href=&quot;https://thanks.rust-lang.org/rust/1.46.0/&quot;&gt;Thanks!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 15:58:54 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pietroalbini</dc:creator>
<og:title>Announcing Rust 1.46.0 | Rust Blog</og:title>
<og:description>Empowering everyone to build reliable and efficient software.</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.rust-lang.org/static/images/rust-social-wide.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.rust-lang.org/2020/08/27/Rust-1.46.0.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: Muse – Tool for Thought on iPad</title>
<link>https://launch-preview.museapp.com/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://launch-preview.museapp.com/</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your thinking shouldn‘t be constrained to linear documents of mostly text. You want to move stuff around, bring in new ideas, cull irrelevant material, get a little messy. &lt;strong&gt;So here’s how Muse is different:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;37&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;You can put &lt;strong&gt;anything&lt;/strong&gt; on a Muse board.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pull in relevant information from the web, email, Twitter, Slack, your files, notes or photos from your phone. Then arrange as you see fit. Muse lets you sift and sort through it all, helping you find new patterns and insights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trying to work within the rigid lists and grids of file browsers, notes apps, or wikis doesn‘t leave room for freeform creativity. Putting everything on a Muse board helps you discover and focus on what matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Muse lets you ink &lt;strong&gt;anywhere&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sketching in Muse isn‘t restricted to a dedicated space. Ink on top of, next to, or between things. Type a sentence, then scribble a note over it. Paste a link, then move it into a sketch you made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Muse treats the Apple Pencil as the magical tool it is—not as one with boundaries and conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;3&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Your content is nested &lt;strong&gt;spatially&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your work on a Muse board is alive. You can zoom into and read a PDF, or interact with text and images. Navigate with one hand and carry cards throughout your 3D knowledge garden with the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The unique zooming interface lets you rely on your brain‘s spatial memory to switch contexts without ever getting lost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 15:06:34 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>adamwiggins</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://5f48159d832ea900074ddc59--muse-website.netlify.app</og:url>
<og:title>Muse — tool for thought</og:title>
<og:description>Spatial canvas for your research, sketches, and bookmarks. Because deep thinking doesn’t happen in front of a computer.</og:description>
<og:image>https://5f48159d832ea900074ddc59--muse-website.netlify.app/assets/muse-unfurl.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://museapp.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A Short Guide to Minimal Web Development (2018)</title>
<link>https://meiert.com/en/blog/minimal-web-development/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://meiert.com/en/blog/minimal-web-development/</guid>
<description>&lt;h2&gt;A Short Guide to Minimal Web Development&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;Post from September 25, 2018 (↻ November 28, 2019), filed under &lt;a href=&quot;https://meiert.com/en/blog/categories/development/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Web Development&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s an art and even a bit of magic around simple frontend code. I love researching such code, and keeping code simple. Well beyond the point of understandable-simple, then, instead not-so-understandable-simple but rather &lt;a href=&quot;https://meiert.com/en/blog/simple-code/&quot;&gt;minimal-simple&lt;/a&gt;. For that reason have I enjoyed writing about &lt;a href=&quot;https://meiert.com/en/blog/best-html-template/&quot;&gt;“best templates”&lt;/a&gt; and suggested &lt;a href=&quot;https://meiert.com/en/blog/optional-html/&quot;&gt;omitting optional tags&lt;/a&gt; and other technically unnecessary things like unneeded attribute quotes. But I have also contemplated writing a short book about the matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That book I started writing last year, but it didn’t assume the structure and size that I imagined for it. Or, I wasn’t quite sure about the material I ended up gathering. Maybe I turned lazy. And therefore (and &lt;a href=&quot;https://meiert.com/de/publications/experiments/20140717/&quot;&gt;not for the first time&lt;/a&gt;), instead of just writing &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oreilly.com/pub/au/6348&quot;&gt;another&lt;/a&gt; “little book” I decided to just publish what I so far collected. All to ponder, how could we learn, or could we teach, web development, quite off the current “&lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/web/progressive-web-apps/&quot;&gt;web app&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/web/tools/&quot;&gt;tool&lt;/a&gt; all the things” path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Contents&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://meiert.com/en/blog/minimal-web-development/#toc-technology&quot;&gt;Master the Core Technologies&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://meiert.com/en/blog/minimal-web-development/#toc-technology-read&quot;&gt;Read the Specs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://meiert.com/en/blog/minimal-web-development/#toc-technology-practice&quot;&gt;Practice&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://meiert.com/en/blog/minimal-web-development/#toc-technology-publish&quot;&gt;Publish&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://meiert.com/en/blog/minimal-web-development/#toc-related&quot;&gt;Familiarize with Related Topics&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://meiert.com/en/blog/minimal-web-development/#toc-related-primary&quot;&gt;Primary Subjects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://meiert.com/en/blog/minimal-web-development/#toc-related-secondary&quot;&gt;Secondary Subjects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://meiert.com/en/blog/minimal-web-development/#toc-diy&quot;&gt;Do It Yourself&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://meiert.com/en/blog/minimal-web-development/#toc-diy-recommended&quot;&gt;Recommended&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://meiert.com/en/blog/minimal-web-development/#toc-diy-recommended-not&quot;&gt;To Be Avoided&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://meiert.com/en/blog/minimal-web-development/#toc-ways&quot;&gt;Find the Shortest Way&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://meiert.com/en/blog/minimal-web-development/#toc-ways-kiss&quot;&gt;Keep It Simple&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://meiert.com/en/blog/minimal-web-development/#toc-ways-tailor&quot;&gt;Tailor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://meiert.com/en/blog/minimal-web-development/#toc-ways-know-simple&quot;&gt;Know Simple and Simple&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://meiert.com/en/blog/minimal-web-development/#toc-automate&quot;&gt;Automate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://meiert.com/en/blog/minimal-web-development/#toc-review&quot;&gt;Review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;toc-technology&quot;&gt;Master the Core Technologies&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beginners achieve simplicity because they don’t know about all the options and possibilities. (One could liken this to an &lt;a href=&quot;https://meiert.com/en/blog/expertise-and-the-inverted-parabola/&quot;&gt;inverted parabola&lt;/a&gt;.) But as professionals and experts, as this article wants it, we cannot approach minimalism from not knowing what’s there, and pat ourselves on the back when we wrote something simple just because we couldn’t produce anything else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;toc-technology-read&quot;&gt;Read the Specs&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step for mastering appears to come through a thorough look at the technical specifications. While the specs aren’t always kind in terms of how easy they are to understand, and while they’re not small in size, they offer the greatest degree of precision and detail. As the goal is mastery, precision and detail are more important than convenience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the specs to work through are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;note&quot;&gt;Personally, I’ve never worked through any ECMAScript spec—and my scripts will show—but I wished to include them here for my own encouragement as well. Then, note that ES and WCAG only carry version numbers because these aren’t, at the moment, “living” standards as are HTML and CSS. Pick the latest relevant versions of these standards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some important topics, like performance or maintainability, aren’t covered by particular standards and specifications, but are only accessible through literature. (A future edit of this article may cover recommendations.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;toc-technology-practice&quot;&gt;Practice&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not necessarily after but while familiarizing with the specs, it will be useful to put the knowledge into practice. That means: developing. Developing as much as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the greatest aspects about web development is probably that the results show immediately—save an .html file, open it in a browser, test any content, structure, styling, scripting changes instantly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This ease of trying things is an advantage. It allows us to be very fast in setting up test cases as well as entire sites and apps, and therefore to build up experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This practice seems important for every web developer. The following habits are of help:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Try newly learned things immediately (for example, through local test files).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set up a personal website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Help friends and family with their websites.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work on websites &lt;em&gt;pro bono&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contribute to open source projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h4 id=&quot;toc-technology-publish&quot;&gt;Publish&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Practice inevitably leads to the here final point of technology mastery: making one’s work public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This exposure has several great side effects. The scrutiny it brings may seem a bit intimidating at first, but a novice need not fear but welcome scrutiny: It means great opportunities to become better, faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The benefit, then, should usually consist of great extra motivation: One wishes to present one’s work well, and hence focuses more on the output’s quality; and this focus comes as an asset for all one’s professional work. One takes the work more seriously and learns the necessary caution. Very often, too, one enjoys one’s work more as well, because publishing means sharing, and shared work can be of use for others, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Publishing, as an important step for exposure, feedback, professionalism, also sets people up to build their portfolio: Every published work can add credibility to one’s professional claims. One can demonstrate far more easily what one can and does do. There’s a tremendous difference in perception of a web developer with a quality website compared to one &lt;a href=&quot;https://meiert.com/en/blog/hire-only-web-designers-with-a-website/&quot;&gt;without one&lt;/a&gt; (or a bad one).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;❧ Reading the specs, practicing, and publishing: When exercised diligently—over the course of 6–12 months—, these make for a great basis, after which it’s time to look at some specifics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;toc-related&quot;&gt;Familiarize with Related Topics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Web development is not a small, isolated topic. For a web developer to become good at their work, and particularly to become excellent, they need to acquire a great grasp of what’s happening around them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To give an impression of what topics and areas should be of interest, but also to convey that not everything is of equal import, one may categorize those other areas as “primary” and “secondary” topics to familiarize with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following topics all serve the &lt;a href=&quot;https://meiert.com/en/blog/big-picture-thinking/&quot;&gt;“Big Picture,”&lt;/a&gt; and still, the two lists aren’t exhaustive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;toc-related-primary&quot;&gt;Primary Subjects&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/standards/webdesign/i18n&quot;&gt;Internationalization (I18N)&lt;/a&gt;, to build international sites and apps;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Localization (L10N), to handle content translations;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Software Development, to identify useful practices from the sister field;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Project Management, to learn to manage work and resources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h4 id=&quot;toc-related-secondary&quot;&gt;Secondary Subjects&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Usability, to relate to the principles of usable interfaces;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Information Design, to assist with the creation of well-designed sites and apps;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy writing and editing, to create, assess, and improve contents;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Typography, to assist designers and content owners publish typographically crafted projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;note&quot;&gt;For few of these topics is there a single main resource; the list may get amended to point to outstanding books on the matters. Some topics, like character sets and encodings to pick just one example, are not part of these lists because luckily, this situation seems so much under control that a web developer may not anymore in their career stumble into difficulties and issues related to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;❧ At this point, what we’ve covered must appear more like &lt;em&gt;maximal&lt;/em&gt; rather than minimal web development. The idea, however, is that we can only tell what’s really needed &lt;em&gt;once we can tell what’s really important&lt;/em&gt;, and why it’s really important. For that it seems beneficial to thoroughly understand our field and its surroundings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;toc-diy&quot;&gt;Do It Yourself&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The call to “Practice” already meant the “Go” to work and—practice, but that practice needs a little more detail. Most of all, practice means to do it yourself—without any direct help, and without any tools that take over our tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s the option to use tools for development, and tools are increasingly important—even critical in complex projects—, but they’re as useful to learn coding as it is to use ready-to-heat-up dough and buns to become a baker. That refers to tools that do things &lt;em&gt;for&lt;/em&gt; us, of course, as editors are still as allowed as are ovens: We just don’t want the editor to auto-correct or auto-strip or auto-compress just yet, much as we wouldn’t want the oven to auto-blend and auto-spread and auto-check to assist the baker apprentice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To practice and code for ourselves, what is allowed, and what isn’t?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;toc-diy-recommended&quot;&gt;Recommended&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;“Passive” editors (editors that don’t change code)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Terminal clients&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Image editing tools&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upload tools&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Web browsers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h4 id=&quot;toc-diy-recommended-not&quot;&gt;To Be Avoided&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Reset style sheets or normalizers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Web frameworks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Script libraries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Polyfills&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shims&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Formatting scripts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compression tools&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Package managers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build tools&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deployment tools&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Templating systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Static site generators&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Content management systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shop systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;note&quot;&gt;These lists are neither ordered nor exhaustive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;❧ The benefits are as manifold, as the approach aims to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;build skills and &lt;em&gt;coding experience&lt;/em&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;build the &lt;em&gt;confidence&lt;/em&gt; that we can do things on our own;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;grasp more clearly and firmly the &lt;em&gt;uses but also the &lt;a href=&quot;https://meiert.com/en/blog/difficult-developer-life/&quot;&gt;side-effects&lt;/a&gt; of tools and automation&lt;/em&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;present a &lt;em&gt;thorough understanding&lt;/em&gt; of web development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The goal here, after all, is to learn the &lt;em&gt;craft&lt;/em&gt; of web development. Over time, and my suggestion is again to work like this for 6–12 months, we can add and play with tools; but as much as tools are important, and again critical in large-scale projects (really not so much in small ones), they’ll leave our story now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;toc-ways&quot;&gt;Find the Shortest Way&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After we’ve learned and practiced and published for a while it’s time to lock in on the primary goal of minimal web development: to find the shortest way, to determine the least amount of code possible to build whatever we set out to build.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn’t simple itself, and, as I’m explaining in &lt;a href=&quot;https://leanpub.com/css-optimization-basics&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;CSS Optimization Basics&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, it’s the &lt;em&gt;mindset&lt;/em&gt; that’s really interesting here. To quote:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea to keep it simple has a lazy touch, and yet it requires high skill. Keeping it simple really means &lt;em&gt;focus&lt;/em&gt;, to know what’s important, and &lt;em&gt;through that&lt;/em&gt; be efficient. Keeping it simple does not mean simply to do less; it means only to do what matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;toc-ways-kiss&quot;&gt;Keep It Simple&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Focus, then, is at the heart of the idea of keeping it simple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet contrary to the idea of simplicity that’s understable, here, in this post, this is all about simplicity that is minimal. Simplicity is not simplicity: When we push hard on the least amount of code possible, the results will certainly be minimal, but they usually suffer on the part of understanding. Hence the differentiation between &lt;a href=&quot;https://meiert.com/en/blog/simple-code/&quot;&gt;minimal-simple and understandable-simple&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Normally we do want to find a balance (and balance is important in many matters web development)—but here the goal is to first go for what’s most minimal, what’s the minimum needed, what can achieve the result and do the job: the shortest way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The task still requires understanding, but &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; one has thoroughly understood and pierced through the topic. To repeat the objective of this writing, emphasis is on learning &lt;em&gt;minimal&lt;/em&gt; web development, and to take it from there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keeping it simple, therefore, is first leaving out what can be left out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;toc-ways-tailor&quot;&gt;Tailor&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keeping it simple then also demands for the notion of tailoring. Tailoring means to develop and cut everything to one’s precise needs. This translates quite well into the real world: an off-the-rack suit may happen to fit us, but it never quality-wise beats the bespoke one; and if we only have the option for something off the shelf, customizing it will also always look nicer on us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal is quality, no: excellence; and that goal is important to keep in mind. If quality and excellence are not the goal, then clearly, a potato bag will make for a garment just as well as will Bootstrap serve the local church site. (Yes.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the goal is quality, however, and excellence, indeed, then tailoring is mandatory, and it brings up one important condition and one important practical point:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The condition is to &lt;em&gt;know our needs&lt;/em&gt;, because otherwise we cannot develop nor even customize anything so to truly suit us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The practical point is to &lt;em&gt;be aware of customization&lt;/em&gt;, because yes, we need it for tailoring, but no, it’s also a burden on our resources, asking for development time. Most people respond by not customizing—a great example are &lt;a href=&quot;https://meiert.com/en/blog/reasons-against-resets/&quot;&gt;the odd&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://perishablepress.com/a-killer-collection-of-global-css-reset-styles/&quot;&gt;reset style sheets&lt;/a&gt; which are in 99.99% of all cases used without modification, precisely because that is work—, but: that comes at the price of (lower) quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;toc-ways-know-simple&quot;&gt;Know Simple and Simple&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The beginning of this post gave it away: minimal-simple was the goal rather than understandable-simple. The idea explained in more detail in a separate article, &lt;a href=&quot;https://meiert.com/en/blog/simple-code/&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Understandable-Simple vs. Minimal-Simple Code&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, we’ll jump to its conclusion:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;!DOCTYPE html&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;title&amp;gt;Foo&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That, for example, is the absolute minimum for an HTML document. That is true minimalism. That is also true minimal-simple: for understandable-simple, it’s not, not for each and every developer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The example shall remind us where we want to take minimalism, but also show a potential pitfall regarding the balance mentioned: It’s greatly instructive and impactful for us to explore the absolute minimum possible—that’s absolutely encouraged here—but there’s another dimension then in that &lt;em&gt;later&lt;/em&gt;, once we managed to push all the way for minimalism, we use the experience we acquired to find those spots that allow, in our teams, the right amount of understanding and, with that, collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minimal, yes, but not at all cost. Simple and simple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;toc-automate&quot;&gt;Automate&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ambition to become a professional, an expert web developer who knows their craft so to find effective but simple solutions comes with another particular balance to strike. That balance is to automate as much as possible without, at least at the current stage of our field, getting too comfortable and neglecting the craft itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may sound more obscure and difficult than it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, the recommendation for the already knowledgeable developer is to &lt;em&gt;automate&lt;/em&gt;: Any task repeated should be checked for automatability through scripts and tools. This sense and skill is useful to be developed and fine-tuned, and it makes for an invaluable asset especially in enterprises involving more than one person (the developer themselves).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, balancing needs to take place where either of the following is true:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Automation &lt;em&gt;costs more&lt;/em&gt; than keeping on doing the task manually (the factor is left to the judgement of the reader);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The task can only be automated at a detriment to overall &lt;em&gt;quality&lt;/em&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The original task is of (even temporary) &lt;em&gt;instructional value&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first reason makes it economically unwise to automate; the second regards quality a greater priority than efficiency; and the third places higher value on the craft and teaching it than on the efficiency achieved through automation. These factors do all want to be considered when it is about automation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;note&quot;&gt;What is there to automate? I came out ahead of myself here when simply saying that “any task” should be automated, and indeed one can generalize the matter and say that everything possible should be automated (unless balancing is important). In the original structure for book and post I had subdivided the matter into development, testing, and monitoring—each with extra considerations and possibly tools. A note for future reference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;toc-review&quot;&gt;Review&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s another—though probably not final—aspect to web development, which consists of reviewing. Reviewing our work—which never precludes understanding and contributing to &lt;em&gt;others’&lt;/em&gt; work—is the counterpart to the more chance-based opportunities for improvement we get through our peers, when they eventually (or not) comment and review and file bug reports against our work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reviewing, or auditing, or criticizing (as in analyzing) one’s work, is important: We want to acquire a habit of healthy self-reflection so to improve our work and its produce.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ways are manifold, for there’s the option to review everything from code snippets to entire repositories; one can establish a practice of sanity checking code by oneself if there are no peers to review it; reviews can then be one-offs or scheduled to be repeated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Automated tests, then, are part of the review process, too, and so are reviews through external experts. The idea is to constantly check and monitor the health and quality of our work—for while in practice, our businesses will depend on it, doing so also makes us experts, also makes us professionals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;❧ This is a sketch. A sketch about minimal web development, yes—what’s most important to it. But also a sketch about how to become a web developer, something that I’ve so far never truly desired to cover—the &lt;a href=&quot;https://meiert.com/en/blog/solid-web-developer/&quot;&gt;only&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://meiert.com/en/blog/teaching-developers/&quot;&gt;attempts&lt;/a&gt;, they have been basal, or very different, like &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/268379549&quot;&gt;my May talk at beyond tellerrand&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a sketch this lacks detail and is incomplete. Perhaps I’ll wish to add to it, perhaps you like to. But in any case it contains some ideas on what to do if one wants to become a web developer and wants to focus not on the bare minimum, but on &lt;em&gt;the minimum that is tailored and of quality&lt;/em&gt;. (This idea of web development I’ve always liked a lot.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what are the keys? In a nutshell: Understand the technologies by reading the standards and specifications, by practicing, and by publishing; familiarize with related topics; do it yourself; look for the shortest way by keeping things simple, by tailoring, and by telling simple and simple apart; automate; and review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That may be one basic and perhaps a little different approach—to minimal web development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;alt&quot;&gt;About Me&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://meiert.com/en/biography/&quot; class=&quot;media alt&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://meiert.b-cdn.net/media/meiert-20200429.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Jens Oliver Meiert, on April 29, 2020.&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m Jens Oliver Meiert, and I’m a &lt;a href=&quot;https://meiert.com/en/blog/categories/development/&quot;&gt;web developer&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/13623828.Jens_Oliver_Meiert&quot;&gt;author&lt;/a&gt;. I love trying things (sometimes involving &lt;a href=&quot;https://meiert.com/en/blog/categories/philosophy/&quot;&gt;philosophy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://meiert.com/en/blog/categories/art/&quot;&gt;art&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://meiert.com/en/blog/categories/adventure/&quot;&gt;adventure&lt;/a&gt;). Here on meiert.com I share some of my views and experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;note&quot;&gt;If you have a question or suggestion about what I write, please leave a comment or a &lt;a href=&quot;https://meiert.com/en/contact/&quot;&gt;message&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 14:45:51 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>uberswe</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://meiert.b-cdn.net/media/logo-social.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://meiert.com/en/blog/minimal-web-development/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Scrollbar Blindness</title>
<link>https://svenkadak.com/blog/scrollbar-blindness</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://svenkadak.com/blog/scrollbar-blindness</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;In 2011, Apple released &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mac_OS_X_Lion&quot;&gt;Mac OS X Lion&lt;/a&gt; which introduced an enhanced scrollbar behavior that made scrollbars hidden by default. The scrollbar appears when the user starts scrolling a document and disappears after the scrolling stops.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It appears, however, that this enhancement did not only change the user interface, but has also shaped how developers (don't) think about that specific UI element when creating cross-platform solutions. I call it &lt;strong&gt;scrollbar blindness&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lately, for some reason, I've started to notice more of it. I have been to numerous websites that have elements with &lt;code&gt;overflow-y&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;overflow-x&lt;/code&gt; set to &lt;code&gt;scroll&lt;/code&gt; while the element is not meant to be scrollable. For no apparent reason, some even set both &lt;code&gt;x&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;y&lt;/code&gt; axes scrollable or create multiple levels of stacked scrollbars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Comparison&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's a side-by-side comparison of the same scrollbar-heavy containers rendered by Firefox on Linux (with scrollbars) and MacOS (without).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;comparison&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;comparisonImage&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://svenkadak.com/media/scrollbar_blindness_linux.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;comparisonImage&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://svenkadak.com/media/scrollbar_blindness_macos.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Examples&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some examples of scrollbar blindness I've stumbled upon:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pricing&quot;&gt;github.com&lt;/a&gt;: Pricing plan and companies containers have &lt;code&gt;overflow-x: scroll&lt;/code&gt;, should be &lt;code&gt;auto&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://story.snapchat.com/s/southpark&quot;&gt;snapchat.com&lt;/a&gt;: Story's up next section is a mess with multiple unnecessary scrollbars.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/pages/advertisement-events-calendar&quot;&gt;techcrunch.com&lt;/a&gt;: Menu has &lt;code&gt;overflow-y: scroll&lt;/code&gt;, should be &lt;code&gt;auto&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.producthunt.com/posts/tesla-cybertruck&quot;&gt;producthunt.com&lt;/a&gt;: Hunter and maker lists have an unnecessary vertical scrollbar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.algolia.com&quot;&gt;algolia.com&lt;/a&gt;: Code editors have &lt;code&gt;overflow-x: scroll&lt;/code&gt;, should be &lt;code&gt;auto&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://render.com&quot;&gt;render.com&lt;/a&gt;: Page has an unnecessary horizontal scrollbar.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(Fixed)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://spectrum.chat/spectrum?tab=posts&quot;&gt;spectrum.chat&lt;/a&gt;: Menu meant for smaller screens sits at the top of the main content column with &lt;code&gt;overflow-x: scroll&lt;/code&gt; which should be &lt;code&gt;auto&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.foxcademy.com&quot;&gt;foxcademy.com&lt;/a&gt;: Menu bar has &lt;code&gt;overflow-x: scroll&lt;/code&gt;, should be &lt;code&gt;auto&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.creatorspot.co&quot;&gt;creatorspot.co&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Media lists have &lt;code&gt;overflow-x: scroll&lt;/code&gt;, should be &lt;code&gt;auto&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Menu dropdowns have &lt;code&gt;overflow-y: scroll&lt;/code&gt;, should be &lt;code&gt;auto&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creator details modal has &lt;code&gt;width: 100vw&lt;/code&gt; which makes its scrollbar stay underneath document's scrollbar. This produces a very confusing user experience as the view is scrollable, but the (document's) scrollbar is not moving. After scrolling to the bottom of the modal, document's scrollbar takes over and scrolls the main view instead.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://conversationswithtyler.com/episodes/mark-zuckerberg-interviews-patrick-collison-and-tyler-cowen&quot;&gt;embed.ly&lt;/a&gt;: Embedded audio player widget has an unnecessary vertical scrollbar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nerdy.dev&quot;&gt;nerdy.dev&lt;/a&gt;: Page container has unnecessary &lt;code&gt;overflow: scroll&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.happyhues.co&quot;&gt;happyhues.co&lt;/a&gt;: Palette sidebar has an unnecessary horizontal scrollbar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://visalist.io/united-states-of-america/visa-requirements/australia&quot;&gt;visalist.io&lt;/a&gt;: Double vertical scrollbars.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://theglobalhack.com/how-it-works&quot;&gt;theglobalhack.com&lt;/a&gt;: Timeline section has &lt;code&gt;overflow-x: scroll&lt;/code&gt;, should be &lt;code&gt;auto&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://getpocket.com/premium&quot;&gt;getpocket.com&lt;/a&gt; Page has an unnecessary horizontal scrollbar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.seb.ee/eng/internship&quot;&gt;seb.ee&lt;/a&gt;: Footer columns have unnecessary vertical scrollbars.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://embarkstudios.teamtailor.com&quot;&gt;teamtailor.com&lt;/a&gt;: Cookie notice has an unnecessary scrollbar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.recursive.design/&quot;&gt;recursive.design&lt;/a&gt;: Page and all text editing sections have unnecessary horizontal scrollbars. In mobile view, some containers are given an extra scrollbar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;As can be seen from the examples, even big organizations like Github and Snapchat that have tens if not a hundred front-end developers and probably have a code review process in place, let the problem slip through. I collected these examples months ago and the scrollbars are still just as I found them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are a front-end developer that uses macOS, I kindly ask you to dedicate a little more attention to how the websites you create behave on platforms other than your own. Alternatively, you can set the scrollbars to be visible at all times by setting &lt;code&gt;System Preferences -&amp;gt; General -&amp;gt; Show scroll bars&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;Always&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 13:24:34 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kadfak</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://svenkadak.com/blog/scrollbar-blindness</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Blanked-out spots on China&amp;#039;s maps helped us uncover Xinjiang&amp;#039;s camps</title>
<link>https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/alison_killing/satellite-images-investigation-xinjiang-detention-camps</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/alison_killing/satellite-images-investigation-xinjiang-detention-camps</guid>
<description>&lt;div data-keywords=&quot;skincare&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-text&quot; readability=&quot;143.26926797807&quot;&gt;
  
  




&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Read Part 1 of this investigation &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/meghara/china-new-internment-camps-xinjiang-uighurs-muslims&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Read Part 2 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/alison_killing/china-ex-prisoners-horrors-xinjiang-camps-uighurs&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;This project was supported by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.opentech.fund/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Open Technology Fund&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://pulitzercenter.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Pulitzer Center&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eyebeam.org/eyebeam-center-for-the-future-of-journalism/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Eyebeam Center for the Future of Journalism&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the summer of 2018, as it became even harder for journalists to work effectively in Xinjiang, a far-western region of China, we started to look at how we could use satellite imagery to investigate the camps where Uighurs and other Muslim minorities were being detained. At the time we began, it was believed that there were around 1,200 camps in existence, while only several dozen had been found. We wanted to try to find the rest.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our breakthrough came when we noticed that there was some sort of issue with satellite imagery tiles loading in the vicinity of one of the known camps while using the Chinese mapping platform Baidu Maps. The satellite imagery was old, but otherwise fine when zoomed out — but at a certain point, plain light gray tiles would appear over the camp location. They disappeared as you zoomed in further, while the satellite imagery was replaced by the standard gray reference tiles, which showed features such as building outlines and roads.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At that time, Baidu only had satellite imagery at medium resolution in most parts of Xinjiang, which would be replaced by their general reference map tiles when you zoomed in closer. That wasn’t what was happening here — these light gray tiles at the camp location were a different color than the reference map tiles and lacked any drawn information, such as roads. We also knew that this wasn’t a failure to load tiles, or information that was missing from the map. Usually when a map platform can’t display a tile, it serves a standard blank tile, which is watermarked. These blank tiles are also a darker color than the tiles we had noticed over the camps.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once we found that we could replicate the blank tile phenomenon reliably, we started to look at other camps whose locations were already known to the public to see if we could observe the same thing happening there. Spoiler: We could. Of the six camps that we used in our feasibility study, five had blank tiles at their location at zoom level 18 in Baidu, appearing only at this zoom level and disappearing as you zoomed in further. One of the six camps didn’t have the blank tiles — a person who had visited the site in 2019 said it had closed, which could well have explained it. However, we later found that the blank tiles weren’t used in city centers, only toward the edge of cities and in more rural areas. (Baidu did not respond to repeated requests for comment.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Having established that we could probably find internment camps in this way, we examined Baidu's satellite tiles for the whole of Xinjiang, including the blank masking tiles, which formed a separate layer on the map. We analyzed the masked locations by comparing them to up-to-date imagery from Google Earth, the European Space Agency’s Sentinel Hub, and Planet Labs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In total there were 5 million masked tiles across Xinjiang. They seemed to cover any area of even the slightest strategic importance — military bases and training grounds, prisons, power plants, but also mines and some commercial and industrial facilities. There were far too many locations for us to sort through, so we narrowed it down by focusing on the areas around cities and towns and major roads.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Prisons and internment camps &lt;a href=&quot;https://content.unops.org/publications/Technical-guidance-Prison-Planning-2016_EN.pdf?mtime=20171215190045&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;need to be near infrastructure&lt;/a&gt; — you need to get large amounts of building materials and heavy machinery there to build them, for starters. Chinese authorities would have also needed good roads and railways to bring newly detained people there by the thousand, as they did in the early months of the mass internment campaign. Analyzing locations near major infrastructure was therefore a good way to focus our initial search. This left us with around 50,000 locations to look at.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We began to sort through the mask tile locations systematically using a custom web tool that we built to support our investigation and help manage the data. We analyzed the whole of Kashgar prefecture, the Uighur heartland, which is in the south of Xinjiang, as well as parts of the neighboring prefecture, Kizilsu, in this way. After looking at 10,000 mask tile locations and identifying a number of facilities bearing the hallmarks of detention centers, prisons, and camps, we had a good idea of the range of designs of these facilities and also the sorts of locations in which they were likely to be found.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We quickly began to notice how large many of these places are — and how heavily securitized they appear to be, compared to the earlier known camps. In site layout, architecture, and security features, they bear greater resemblance to other prisons across China than to the converted schools and hospitals that formed the earlier camps in Xinjiang. The newer compounds are also built to last, in a way that the earlier conversions weren’t. The perimeter walls are made of thick concrete, for example, which takes much longer to build and perhaps later demolish, than the barbed wire fencing that characterizes the early camps.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In almost every county, we found buildings bearing the hallmarks of detention centers, plus new facilities with the characteristics of large, high-security camps and/or prisons. Typically, there would be an older detention center in the middle of the town, while on the outskirts there would be a new camp and prison, often in recently developed industrial areas. Where we hadn’t yet found these facilities in a given county, this pattern pushed us to keep on looking, especially in areas where there was no recent satellite imagery. Where there was no public high-resolution imagery, we used medium-resolution imagery from Planet Labs and Sentinel to locate likely sites. Planet was then kind enough to give us access to high-resolution imagery for these locations and to task a satellite to capture new imagery of some areas that hadn’t been photographed in high resolution since 2006. In one county, this allowed us to see that the detention center that had previously been identified by other researchers had been demolished and to find the new prison just out of town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div data-keywords=&quot;fast fashion&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-text&quot; readability=&quot;130.46004277659&quot;&gt;
  
  




&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Prison requirements — why prisons are built where they are&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There’s good reason why these places are developed &lt;a href=&quot;https://content.unops.org/publications/Technical-guidance-Prison-Planning-2016_EN.pdf?mtime=20171215190045&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;close to towns&lt;/a&gt;. There’s the occasional camp in a more remote location, such as the sprawling internment camp in Dabancheng, but even there it’s next to a major road, with a small town nearby. Having the prison or camp close to an existing town minimizes, in principle, the distance that detainees must be transported (although there are also examples of prisoners and detainees being taken right across Xinjiang, from Kashgar to Korla, as in the drone &lt;a href=&quot;https://observers.france24.com/en/20190925-drone-video-shows-mass-displacement-prisoners-china-xinjiang-uyghur-region&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; that reemerged recently, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Nrg8000/status/1175353408749891584?s=20&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;according to analysts&lt;/a&gt;). It is easier for families to visit loved ones who are in custody. Being near a town means that a prison or camp can be staffed more easily. Guards have families, their children need to go to school, their partners have jobs, they need access to healthcare, etc. Construction workers are needed to build the prison in the first place. It is also useful for amenities. Prisons and camps need electricity, water, telephone lines. It is way cheaper and easier to connect to an existing nearby network than to run new pipes and cables tens of kilometers to a more remote location.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, you need a large plot of land for a prison, preferably with space to expand in the future, and this is what the recently developed industrial estates offer: large, serviced plots, close to existing towns and cities. Building in industrial estates also places the camps close to factories for forced labor. While many camps have factories within their compounds, in several cases that we know of detainees are bused to other factory sites to work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Our list of sites&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In total we identified 428 locations in Xinjiang bearing the hallmarks of prisons and detention centers. Many of these locations contain two to three detention facilities — a camp, pretrial administrative detention center, or prison. We intend to analyze these locations further and make our database more granular over the next few months.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of these locations, we believe 315 are in use as part of the current internment program — 268 new camp or prison complexes, plus 47 pretrial administrative detention centers that have not been expanded over the past four years. We have witness testimony showing that these detention centers have frequently been used to detain people, who are often then moved on to other camps, and so we feel it is important to include them. Excluded from this 315 are 39 camps that we believe are probably closed and 11 that have closed — either they’ve been demolished or we have witness testimony that they are no longer in use. There are a further 14 locations identified by other researchers, but where our team has only been able to check the satellite evidence, which in these cases is weak. These 14 are not included in our list.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We have also located 63 prisons that we believe belong to earlier, pre-2016 programs. These facilities were typically built several years — in some cases, several decades — before the current internment program and have not been significantly extended since 2016. They are also different in style from the detention centers, known in Chinese as “kanshousuo,” and also from the newer camps. These facilities are not part of the 315 we believe to be in use as part of the current internment program and are included separately in our database.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many of the earlier camps, which were converted from other uses, had their courtyard fencing, watchtowers, and other security features removed, often in late 2018 or early 2019. In some cases, the removal of most barricading, plus the fact that there are often cars parked in several places across the compounds, suggests that they’re no longer camps and are classified as probably closed in our database. The removal of the security features, in several cases, coincided with the opening of a larger, higher-security facility being completed nearby, suggesting that detainees may have been moved to the newer location.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Where facilities were purpose-built as camps and have had courtyard fencing removed but otherwise don’t show any change of use (like cars in the compound), we think they’re likely to still be camps — albeit with lower levels of security.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Acknowledgments&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our work has also built on the work of others, Shawn Zhang, Adrian Zenz, Bitter Winter, Gene Bunin, ETNAM, Open Street Map contributors, and the Laogai Handbook — we have sought to verify all of the locations in these databases (and attempted to locate the camps in the case of the Laogai Handbook), added them to our database where relevant, and classified them. The work of the Australian Strategic Policy Institute (ASPI), especially Nathan Ruser and his advice at an early stage of this project, was also invaluable. We would also like to note the contribution of the interpreters who worked with us. For security reasons, we aren’t sharing names or other identifying details, but would like nevertheless to publicly extend our thanks — you know who you are.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Alison Killing conducted this reporting with a grant and further assistance from the&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.opentech.fund/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Open Technology Fund&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 12:28:26 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>danso</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/alison_killing/satellite-images-investigation-xinjiang-detention-camps</og:url>
<og:image>https://img.buzzfeed.com/buzzfeed-static/static/2020-08/27/16/campaign_images/4b74ed238220/blanked-out-spots-on-chinas-maps-helped-us-uncove-2-272-1598544559-0_dblbig.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Blanked-Out Spots On China's Maps Helped Us Uncover Xinjiang's Camps</og:title>
<og:description>China's Baidu blanked out parts of its mapping platform. We used those locations to find a network of buildings bearing the hallmarks of prisons and internment camps in Xinjiang. Here's how we did it.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/alison_killing/satellite-images-investigation-xinjiang-detention-camps</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Hunting the Nearly-Invisible Personal Website</title>
<link>https://cheapskatesguide.org/articles/personal-website-hunting.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://cheapskatesguide.org/articles/personal-website-hunting.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&quot;left&quot; src=&quot;https://cheapskatesguide.org/pics/jungle-300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Jungle&quot;/&gt; The personal website is a somewhat mysterious animal that lives mostly unobserved in the jungle of the Internet. A few inexperienced Internet users who live completely within the golden-walled gardens of Facebook and Google may not even be aware of the species' existence. Other inexperienced users may consider the personal website to be either extinct, like brontosaurus, or a myth, like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.smithsonianmag.com/history/why-bigfoot-and-abominable-snowman-loom-large-human-imagination-180975365/&quot;&gt;Bigfoot or the Abominable Snowman&lt;/a&gt;. The truth is that many specimens exist in the wild, but in order to successfully hunt the personal website, a hunter must know the habits of this species well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please allow me to be your guide on this safari through the murky and predator-filled Internet jungle, and I will lead you to some representative specimens of the personal website species and teach you hunting methods that are likely to lead you to others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As legend has it, during a more peaceful time, soon after the genesis of the Internet jungle and before the mid 1990's, personal websites were the predominant species. But queen Sophia the demiurge, wife of King Berners-Lee, at the pleading of her daughter Pandora, acquiesced to provide a breeding ground for Pandora's pets. Over time, more and more pets were allowed to roam free in the jungle, including not a few predators. Eventually, these pets became the predominant species of the Internet jungle and personal websites became nearly invisible among all the bellowing and commotion raised by Pandora's pets. This near invisibility made personal websites very difficult to hunt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before discussing personal websites in detail, I should first mention two common predators in the Internet jungle. The corporate predator induces the Internet user to willingly approach him by pretending to be a harmless domesticated animal, much like a horse or a cow. Note that not all corporate websites are predators, though a large number of them do have certain similarities to cows, ponderousness often being one. But, many corporate websites are not nearly as domesticated as they appear. Just read the details of their terms-of-service agreements if you doubt this. As with many humans and their cats, the truth is that deciding in any given instance whether a corporate website or its Internet user is the dominant species can be a difficult task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A less well understood animal is the hacker. Hacker is a genus containing a number of species. Some are predatory, and others are harmless or even beneficial to the ecology of the Internet jungle. By far, the most populous species of predatory hacker is the &quot;script kiddie&quot;. Script kiddies tend to be blind, feeling their way around the Internet jungle from IP address to IP address. Their goal seems to be to find those websites that have ingested corporate website code that has made them susceptible to infection. When a script kiddie finds such a website, it frequently injects malware, which it sometimes uses to help it find and attack other websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason for the script kiddie's behavior remains a mystery, since it usually provides little nourishment. Some script kiddie observers speculate that script kiddies engage in the noted behavior simply to impress others of their species. While other animals must impress potential mates in order to improve the genetics of their offspring, most potential mates of script kiddies seem unimpressed by their behavior. A possibility also exists that the script kiddie's behavior serves primarily as a means of determining pecking order, primarily among males of the species. However, one observation that tends to bolster the mating theory is that most script kiddies that have successfully mated no longer engage in their typical behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even many moderately experienced hunters fear the personal website, because they have been led to believe that personal websites frequently carry diseases--viruses in particular, or parasites generally known as &quot;malware&quot;. Though both of these are possible, they are uncommon. The truth is that personal websites practice habits that are generally no less cleanly than other Internet jungle species. However, some of the less wary personal websites do become susceptible to viruses and malware by ingesting code defecated by corporate websites, including code from the unusually flatulent and dyspeptic Microshaft. Nevertheless, hunters' fear of personal websites is largely overblown. &lt;a href=&quot;https://cheapskatesguide.org/articles/no-such-thing-as-secure.html&quot;&gt;Well-equipped&lt;/a&gt; hunters have little to fear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike most other animals that must constantly evade predators to survive, the personal website has few known enemies. The personal website is, however, susceptible to the DMCA parasite, which is capable of suing it to death. Fortunately, this is a rare occurrence, perhaps mainly due to the near invisibility of the personal website. For this reason, and because personal websites are almost always so small that they have very little meat on them (otherwise known as posts or articles), they are rarely in danger from predators. Personal websites also tend to taste bad to the larger corporate predators, as they rarely advertise or produce much of an income. Very rarely, however, a well-fed personal website may grow to a large enough size to successfully compete with corporate websites for the food provided by users. When this occurs, some observers fear this fat personal website may be in danger of being killed (see &lt;a href=&quot;https://johnfowler.co/facebook-blocked-my-website/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://heavy.com/news/2018/10/facebook-purge-list-deleted-accounts/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.convinceandconvert.com/social-media-strategy/3-ways-facebook-is-killing-your-website/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-does-google-steal-content-from-honest-businesses-us-congressman-2271102&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;), but few corporate predators ingest even the fattest personal websites, perhaps because they simply do not know what to do with them. On rare occasions, however, corporate predators will capture both personal and non-revenue-generating corporate websites and allow them to live for a few more years while dying &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcommunity.microsoft.com/t5/healthcare-and-life-sciences/skype-for-business-online-end-of-life-july-31-2021/ba-p/779137&quot;&gt;slow deaths from starvation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike other animals that are seen or heard mainly at mating time, personal websites do not reveal their presence in this manner, because they do not mate. Instead, they reproduce asexually. Some produce offspring by budding, a plantlike characteristic. Many, if not most, also exhibit another plantlike characteristic. They sprinkle their spoors (technically, known as hyperlinks) over the floor of the Internet jungle in the hope of being one day chanced upon by an Internet user and ingested. Though ingestion rarely occurs, when it does, through some process not well understood by present-day science, the Internet user is occasionally induced to create his own personal website. This website is then free to bud under the careful attention and care of the host Internet user, who has now been transformed into an entity sometimes known as a &quot;developer&quot;, though developer is not an especially well-defined designator. At the proper time, the new website naturally begins to produce its own spoors, and its life cycle repeats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, spoors and bits of code are exchanged directly with other personal websites, in a manner analogous to bacterial conjugation, in which genetic material, called plasmids, are exchanged between bacteria. This type of spoor is known as a &quot;backlink&quot;. Sometimes, websites collect backlinks and place them in groups called blogrolls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As alluded to previously, the main reason personal websites are so difficult to find in the Internet jungle is that they are almost completely invisible to the bloodhounds of the Internet, known as &quot;search engines&quot;. Search engines use search algorithms, rather than smell, to find websites. Except on rare occasions, the only search in which a personal website appears on &lt;em&gt;any page&lt;/em&gt; of a search result is a search that includes the personal website's exact domain name (its location in the Internet jungle) or the exact title of one its articles. Therefore, less than a hundred of the most popular personal websites can be found through the overwhelming majority of Internet searches. Though this may be hard to believe, it is true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even the smaller search engines like millionshort.com, swisscows.com, and wiby.me are largely blind to any personal websites other than the top 100. Internet zoologists speculate that smaller search engines are not actually blind to personal websites. They only pretend to be blind by keeping their eyes tightly closed whenever they encounter a personal website, so as to imitate their leader, the Google search engine, which is truly blind to all but the top 100 or so personal websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the lack of attention that personal websites receive, they often congregate together, or at least maintain an association with others of their kind. They do this for survival. You see, personal websites need some amount of attention to survive. If they cannot get attention from Internet users, they try to get it from each other. This is the primary behavior by which an experienced hunter may successfully track them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When by the greatest stroke of luck, a hunter happens to stumble upon a nearly-invisible personal website, he should immediately look for others nearby. Personal websites often have blogrolls or other internal links that lead a persistent hunter to others of their species. Here are some blogrolls of personal websites that I have been lucky enough to track down during my hunts in the well-lighted regions of the Internet jungle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;https://distinctly.pink/blogroll.html&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;https://kevq.uk/blogroll&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;https://jlelse.blog/blogroll&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;https://www.garron.blog/blogroll.html&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;https://jan.boddez.net/links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes website congregation is voluntary, and sometimes it is the result of having been collected or captured by a social media website. Here are a few congregation points that I have found:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The webring, an exceedingly rare, nearly extinct Internet jungle species, can also lead hunters to personal websites, because webrings are more visible to search engines than are personal websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though nearly all social media animals have an extreme distaste for the meat of the personal website, some forum animals like &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://voat.co&quot;&gt;Voat&lt;/a&gt; are more tolerant of it than most. Patient hunters may benefit by searching these websites for the meat of personal websites and following the associated spoors to their dens (also known as home pages or main pages).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some parts of the Internet jungle are more productive hunting grounds for personal websites than others. One especially productive hunting ground is called &lt;a href=&quot;https://cheapskatesguide.org/articles/gopherspace.html&quot;&gt;Gopherspace&lt;/a&gt;. From its name, one may be inclined to wonder if Gopherspace could be a region of the Internet jungle that contains giant gophers or other &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rodents_of_unusual_size&quot;&gt;rodents of unusual size&lt;/a&gt;. Sadly, this is not the case. Gopherspace is predominantly populated by personal websites. It is an area of the Internet that was larger in the 1990's, but has since shrunken to a rather small size. Hunters who manage to find Gopherspace will immediately be amazed by the total absence of all corporate predators. You see, Gopherspace does not contain sufficient quantities of users who believe that corporate websites are as harmless as they pretend to be. Hence, Gopherspace users refuse to feed corporate predators. This is one of a number of reasons that corporate predators would immediately starve to death should they ever risk trying to build their dens in Gopherspace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other excellent hunting grounds for personal websites are the less traveled, and therefore, largely misunderstood regions of the Internet that are said to be cloaked in perpetual darkness. These areas are called the &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Darknet&quot;&gt;darknets&lt;/a&gt;&quot;. Here, personal websites are the predominant species, and corporate predators are rare. Some darknets are the Tor network, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://cheapskatesguide.org/articles/ipfs.html&quot;&gt;IPFS&lt;/a&gt; network, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://cheapskatesguide.org/articles/i2p.html&quot;&gt;I2P&lt;/a&gt; network, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://cheapskatesguide.org/articles/zeronet.html&quot;&gt;ZeroNet&lt;/a&gt;. Despite claims to the contrary by some media beasts who have never actually visited the darknets, the darknets are still very small in comparison to the rest of the Internet jungle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An interesting fact is that, thanks in part to the the near total absence of corporate predators and government species in the darknets, these areas are growing in number and size. More users are coming to the darknets in particular to breath in the wonderful aroma of a beautiful flower called &quot;free speech&quot;. Not many free speech flowers continue to bloom in the well-lighted areas of the Internet jungle. Almost all have now been trampled by corporate and government animals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Internet zoologists are currently studying the fauna of the darknets to better understand their prospects for continued survival. &lt;a href=&quot;https://cheapskatesguide.org/articles/the-next-internet.html&quot;&gt;Some believe&lt;/a&gt; darknets may one day grow to be larger than the rest of the Internet jungle. Others are doubtful. I guess we will just have to wait and see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another interesting fact about &quot;darknets&quot; is that the name is largely a misnomer; darknets are only dark to corporate predators whose eyes can only see with large dollar signs illuminating the landscape. Since darknets contain few or no dollar signs, all but a very few corporate predators stay away. The eyes of the Internet user, however, can see without the light of dollar signs. This makes them well-adapted to explore the darknets. Unfortunately, however, the average Internet user has been led to believe by predatory corporate animals and two-faced government animals that the darknets of the Internet jungle are too predator-filled and dangerous to explore, so few but the most experienced users venture into them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was lucky enough during one hunt to discover the personal website of an experienced and brave darknet hunter. Her personal website has already budded to produce a number of offspring on both light and darknets. She has created the largest blogroll of darknet websites that I have seen so far, and many of the websites in &lt;a href=&quot;https://mayvaneday.art/rollcall.html&quot;&gt;her blogroll&lt;/a&gt; are personal websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To summarize, though some Internet users are unaware of this fact, a large number of personal websites still exist in the Internet jungle. They can be found in the well-lighted regions, but Gopherspace and the darknets are more productive hunting grounds. Since search engines in the well-lighted areas of the Internet jungle are nearly blind to all but the most well-known personal websites, other hunting methods are more productive in those areas. Some of those methods are: looking for webrings, searching for personal website congregation points, and combing the blogrolls of previously-discovered personal websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This concludes our safari through the Internet jungle. Thank you for allowing me to be your guide. If any readers have developed other techniques for hunting personal websites, please share them via the comment form below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have found this article worthwhile, please share it with your favorite social media animals. You will find links at the top of the page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Related Articles:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cheapskatesguide.org/articles/what-i-learned-about-the-internet.html&quot; class=&quot;plain-link&quot;&gt;What I Learned about the Internet by Creating My Own Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cheapskatesguide.org/articles/the-next-internet.html&quot; class=&quot;plain-link&quot;&gt;The Next Internet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cheapskatesguide.org/articles/going-dark.html&quot; class=&quot;plain-link&quot;&gt;Going Dark: Looking for the End of the Internet, Part 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cheapskatesguide.org/articles/gopherspace.html&quot; class=&quot;plain-link&quot;&gt;Gopherspace in the Year 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cheapskatesguide.org/articles/zeronet.html&quot; class=&quot;plain-link&quot;&gt;ZeroNet and the Future of the Internet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cheapskatesguide.org/articles/i2p.html&quot; class=&quot;plain-link&quot;&gt;An Introduction to the I2P Distributed, Peer-to-Peer Network&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cheapskatesguide.org/articles/ipfs.html&quot; class=&quot;plain-link&quot;&gt;How to Access the Interplanetary File System&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cheapskatesguide.org/articles/no-such-thing-as-secure.html&quot; class=&quot;plain-link&quot;&gt;There's no Such Thing as a Secure Computer--How to be Relatively Secure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 11:40:28 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>sT370ma2</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://cheapskatesguide.org/articles/personal-website-hunting.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ask HN: How does onlyfans.com work around the “no porn” Stripe rule?</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24291790</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24291790</guid>
<description>&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.58823529411765&quot;&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=&quot;#FF6600&quot;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;pagespace&quot; title=&quot;Ask HN: How does onlyfans.com work around the &amp;#x201C;no porn&amp;#x201D; Stripe rule?&quot;&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;11.343005181347&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;fatitem&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;7.4165803108808&quot;&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing&quot; id=&quot;24291790&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;title&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24291790&quot; class=&quot;storylink&quot;&gt;Ask HN: How does onlyfans.com work around the “no porn” Stripe rule?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.69230769230769&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;subtext&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;score&quot; id=&quot;score_24291790&quot;&gt;267 points&lt;/span&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/user?id=capableweb&quot; class=&quot;hnuser&quot;&gt;capableweb&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;age&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24291790&quot;&gt;13 hours ago&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span id=&quot;unv_24291790&quot;/&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/hide?id=24291790&amp;amp;goto=item%3Fid%3D24291790&quot;&gt;hide&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://hn.algolia.com/?query=Ask%20HN%3A%20How%20does%20onlyfans.com%20work%20around%20the%20%E2%80%9Cno%20porn%E2%80%9D%20Stripe%20rule%3F&amp;amp;sort=byDate&amp;amp;dateRange=all&amp;amp;type=story&amp;amp;storyText=false&amp;amp;prefix&amp;amp;page=0&quot; class=&quot;hnpast&quot;&gt;past&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/fave?id=24291790&amp;amp;auth=78f545c4fad77d2e1eb56b907e06d9f0a93540ba&quot;&gt;favorite&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24291790&quot;&gt;214 comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;22.5&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;22&quot;&gt;For reasons beyond this ask, I'm needing to use a payment processor that is fine with high-risk transactions (which the porn industry certainly fits in) so started looking around what adult websites are using.
&lt;p&gt;Many are using probiller, vendo and similar, since Stripe and others have rules against porn/adult industry, citing high risk transactions for this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then I came across onlyfans.com, which is using Stripe for its payments, although Stripe has a strict &quot;no porn&quot; rule in their terms of service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does this work? Onlyfans is by now a huge website, with lots of transactions, so it's surely not flying under the radar. It's the only adult website I could find that is using Stripe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it as simple as they have an agreement with Stripe to bypass the rule? Or am I missing something else obvious here?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;yclinks&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsguidelines.html&quot;&gt;Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsfaq.html&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Support&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/HackerNews/API&quot;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/security.html&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/lists&quot;&gt;Lists&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/bookmarklet.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Bookmarklet&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/legal/&quot;&gt;Legal&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Apply to YC&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Contact&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 09:43:57 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>capableweb</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24291790</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>