<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>CGA in 1024 Colors – A New Mode: The Illustrated Guide (2015)</title>
<link>https://int10h.org/blog/2015/04/cga-in-1024-colors-new-mode-illustrated/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://int10h.org/blog/2015/04/cga-in-1024-colors-new-mode-illustrated/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;By now you may have heard of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pouet.net/prod.php?which=65371&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;8088 MPH demo&lt;/a&gt;, the winning entry in &lt;a href=&quot;http://2015.revision-party.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Revision 2015&lt;/a&gt;'s Oldskool Demo compo this month.  It's been my pleasure to combine efforts with the likes of &lt;a href=&quot;http://trixter.oldskool.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Trixter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reenigne.org/blog/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;reenigne&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://scalibq.wordpress.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Scali&lt;/a&gt; to make it happen - not only did I get the opportunity to work alongside a bunch of extremely talented wizards of code, we also achieved what we set out to do: break some world records on the venerable (and yet much-maligned!) IBM PC, the mommy and daddy of the x86 platform as we still know it today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of our &quot;hey, this hardware shouldn't be doing that!&quot;-moments was extending the CGA's color palette by a cool order of magnitude or two.  How'd we pull that off? - reenigne has already posted an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reenigne.org/blog/1k-colours-on-cga-how-its-done/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;excellent technical article&lt;/a&gt; answering that very question.  To complement his writeup, I'll take a bit of a different approach – here's my 'pictorial' take on how we arrived at this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://int10h.org/blog/img/1k01_graffiti1k2.png&quot; alt=&quot;8088 MPH 1K color CGA graffiti&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Old dog, posing with new tricks. (Not pictured: blood, sweat, tears.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea that such multi-color trickery was possible came to me some time ago, as I was looking at reenigne's code for patching up composite CGA emulation in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dosbox.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;DOSBox&lt;/a&gt;; messing with that patch during development gave me a much better picture of composite CGA's inner workings.  When I had ironed out the basic concept for this hack, I divulged it to reenigne for 'peer review' and for testing on real hardware.  Soon enough, we had an improved recipe:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Take two familiar (though officially undocumented) tweaks. Blend to an even mixture producing a new effect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add one crucial new trick – an ingredient of reenigne's devising.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Test and calibrate until blue in the face.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Below is my rundown of how it all fits together.  Fair warning: the 'target audience' for this writeup is people who may not be overly familiar with CGA, and/or come from other demo platforms.  As such, there's a whole bunch of background that's already well-known in CGA-land.  To prevent acute boredom, I decided to stick this TOC here – feel free to skip to the interesting part(s):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;centered&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;Because, much like a broken clock, even Wikipedia gets it right sometimes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
 
&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-id-16-colors-rgbi-a-old-trick-1-16-color-graphics-over-rgbi&quot;&gt; Old Trick #1: 16-color graphics over RGBI&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A short crash course on CGA basics: the first graphics standard available on PCs supports a 16KB memory buffer, and is driven by an MC6845 CRTC (some later cards used alternatives).  Video output options are composite NTSC through a standard RCA jack, and the more widely-used DE9 connector, which outputs an RGBI signal (red, green, blue and intensity).  The latter is what most people think of when they hear &quot;CGA&quot;; this is a &lt;em&gt;digital (TTL)&lt;/em&gt; signal, where each component can be either on or off, hence 16 different colors.  Despite what arcade hardware buffs would like you to think, CGA – in the strict sense – is NOT analog RGB, and never was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Standard (BIOS-supported) graphics modes are high-resolution (640x200) in 2 colors, and medium-resolution (320x200) in 4 colors.  Not a lot of wiggle room here: in hi-res mode, only one of the colors (foreground) is redefinable – the background is always black; in medium-res, it's the background color that's adjustable, while the other 3 are determined by the infamously nasty &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Color_Graphics_Adapter#Standard_graphics_modes&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;fixed palettes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Infuriatingly, in an almost-trollish move, IBM &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.org/stream/bitsavers_ibmpccardsptionsandAdaptersVolume2Apr84_25079400/Technical_Reference_Options_and_Adapters_Volume_2_Apr84#page/n49/mode/2up/search/%22low-resolution+color+graphics+mode%22&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;mentioned&lt;/a&gt; an additional low-resolution 16-color mode - &quot;not supported in ROM&quot; - with zero information on how to actually achieve it.  That nut was cracked pretty early on, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-id-low-resolution-mode-a-low-resolution-mode&quot;&gt; Low-resolution mode&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is no graphics mode at all, but a modified 80-column &lt;a href=&quot;http://webpages.charter.net/danrollins/techhelp/0089.HTM&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;text mode&lt;/a&gt;. Basically, you adjust CRTC registers to get 100 rows of text instead of the usual 25; this gives you a character box of 8x2 pixels, a quarter of the normal 8x8.  Filling the screen with one &quot;magic&quot; ASCII character, 0xDE, effectively splits each character cell into left and right &quot;pixels&quot;, corresponding to the background and foreground colors.  These two colors can be individually set to any of the 16 CGA values, as in any CGA text mode, as long as you remember to turn off blinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://int10h.org/blog/img/1k02_16c_low-resolution_cga_160x100.png&quot; alt=&quot;CGA low resolution mode&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;CGA low resolution mode&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So there you have it; 160x100 @ 16c.  This mode was used in games &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mobygames.com/game/pc-booter/moon-bugs/screenshots&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;as early as 1983&lt;/a&gt;, but never got wildly popular - probably because of the &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Color_Graphics_Adapter#Limitations.2C_bugs_and_errata&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;snow&lt;/a&gt;&quot; that plagues IBM CGA cards in 80-column mode, unless you burn some costly CPU time to avoid it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-id-the-macrocom-method-a-the-macrocom-method&quot;&gt; The Macrocom Method&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may ask: since this is text mode, what's stopping you from using the &lt;em&gt;entire&lt;/em&gt; ASCII character set? Other than a healthy respect for your own sanity, nothing really!  This was first attempted around the mid-'80s by a few brave souls at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mobygames.com/featured_article/feature,10/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Macrocom&lt;/a&gt;, who combined the 100-rows trick with ASCII art, to create what Trixter once succinctly called &quot;ANSI from hell&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://int10h.org/blog/img/1k03_16c_cga_ansi_from_hell.png&quot; alt=&quot;CGA ANSI from Hell&quot;/&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see above, I've experimented with this a little.  With judicious use of the character set, you can &lt;em&gt;almost&lt;/em&gt; fool somebody into thinking that this is a 640x200 mode - although there's some inevitable &quot;attribute clash&quot;, a little like the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.retroyak.com/clash-of-the-bright-dims/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ZX Spectrum&lt;/a&gt;: each 8x2 character cell can contain only two colors, foreground and background. Also, you have to be a bit of a glutton for punishment to actually draw in this mode from scratch... but that's a subject for a future post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This trick isn't directly relevant to our demo: we were targeting composite displays. Even if CGA's composite output didn't have its share of bugs and quirks in 80-column mode – &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reenigne.org/blog/cga-why-the-80-column-text-mode-requires-the-border-color-to-be-set/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;which it does&lt;/a&gt; – there'd be no way to see this level of detail over NTSC.  There's a reason I mention this effect, however; the idea behind it does figure into the story.  But more on that later.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-id-16-colors-composite-a-old-trick-2-16-color-graphics-over-composite&quot;&gt; Old Trick #2: 16-color graphics over composite&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digital RGB monitors were still a luxury item at the time of CGA's introduction, and IBM itself didn't offer one until a couple of years later, coinciding with the release of the PC/XT.  But CGA also provided composite output, giving out (mostly) NTSC-compatible video. At the expense of resolution, there's more fun to be had here with color.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-id-direct-colors-a-direct-colors&quot;&gt; Direct colors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://int10h.org/blog/img/1k04_cga_composite_direct_colors.png#floatleft&quot; alt=&quot;Composite CGA, 16 direct colors&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the composite output, the familiar 16-color CGA palette is represented by a series of color signals, whose hue is determined by their &lt;strong&gt;phase&lt;/strong&gt; relative to a reference signal (the NTSC &lt;em&gt;color burst&lt;/em&gt;).  The &lt;strong&gt;frequency&lt;/strong&gt; of the NTSC color clock (3.579545 MHz) works out to exactly &lt;strong&gt;160&lt;/strong&gt; color cycles per active CGA scanline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are directly generated by CGA hardware as color signals, so we'll conveniently call them &quot;direct colors&quot;.  IBM had &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reenigne.org/blog/comparison-of-cga-card-versions/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;two main revisions&lt;/a&gt; of the CGA, which produce composite video somewhat differently: 'new-style' cards contain additional circuitry, which helps the palette match its RGBI counterpart a little more closely.  For the demo, we standardized on 'old-style' cards, simply because we happened to have done more testing on those (with somwhat better results), so all images in this post will reflect 'old-style' CGA colors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If these 16 &lt;em&gt;direct&lt;/em&gt; colors were all we had, it wouldn't be a whole lot of fun, would it?  They're also shockingly ugly, esepcially on an old-style CGA, which doesn’t help matters either.  Just look at that palette... gross, dude.  Luckily, there's a way to go one better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-id-artifact-colors-a-artifact-colors&quot;&gt; Artifact colors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to bandwidth restrictions, NTSC video doesn't fully separate chrominance (color) from luminance.  Effectively, any high-resolution detail – that is, detail with higher frequency than the NTSC color clock – gets 'smeared' when the signal is decoded. This is responsible for the characteristic color bleed, seen in the form of fetching little fringes at the edges of text characters and other fine detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember how you get 160 color cycles per active CGA scanline? Standard CGA gives us either &lt;strong&gt;320&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;640&lt;/strong&gt; active pixels per scanline, depending on the video mode.  Ergo, we can switch pixels on and off at &lt;strong&gt;2x&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;4x&lt;/strong&gt; the frequency of the color carrier.  Since this high-frequency detail cannot be fully separated from color information, the upshot is this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;centered&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The hue of a pixel, or a fringe (transition between pixels), depends on its position within the color-cycle period.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://int10h.org/blog/img/1k05_ntsc_color_wheel.png#floatleft&quot; alt=&quot;NTSC color wheel&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;This NTSC color cycle is sometimes represented as a wheel: one complete period of this cycle equals a 360° revolution around the color wheel, and we have 160 complete revolutions per scanline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's say we're in hi-res (640x200) mode, where 4 pixels fit into one such color cycle: moving one pixel left or right translates to moving 90° along the wheel, in either direction, and accordingly shifts the hue by 90°.  Likewise, in 320x200 mode, we move in 180° increments of hue-shift.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, manipulating detail at high resolutions is effectively a method of generating color; being an artifact of NTSC's imperfections, this is known as &lt;em&gt;artifact&lt;/em&gt; color.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://int10h.org/blog/img/1k06_cga_composite_fringing_artifacts.png&quot; alt=&quot;CGA composite output: fringing and artifact colors&quot;/&gt;  &lt;br/&gt;Various filters can be (and often are) employed on the receiving end to recover some of the high-frequency detail, reducing color bleed and making edge transitions somewhat sharper.  We're still dealing with technology, not magic, so full separation of detail and color can never quite be achieved, and the trade-off is a whole new set of artifacts (in the form of &quot;echoing&quot; or &quot;ringing&quot;).  This trade-off may or may not be acceptable, depending on what you're doing, but the above image doesn't attempt to reproduce any such filtering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-id-solid-artifact-colors-a-solid-artifact-colors&quot;&gt; Solid artifact colors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All this business of &quot;fringing&quot; and &quot;bleeding&quot; sure sounds like a bummer, and that's exactly what it is: the unwanted side-effect of a less-than-ideal encoding scheme.  But like any good flaw, it can be turned into an advantage by an enterprising soul, and this is where we get to the fun part (your mileage may vary).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you look at the interplay of color vs. detail over NTSC, a very handy fact becomes apparent:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;centered&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Any periodic composite signal, with the same frequency as the color carrier (160 per line), will be decoded as a solid, continuous color.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;Our 16 &lt;em&gt;direct&lt;/em&gt; colors are exactly this type of periodic composite signal.  But hold on – with some simple high-resolution pixel-pushing, we can manually put together our own periodic waveforms!  Any pattern of dots will do, as long as it repeats at the right frequency.  This lets us achieve solid colors that lie &lt;em&gt;outside&lt;/em&gt; the direct color palette.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://int10h.org/blog/img/1k07_cga_composite_solid_colors_1.png#floatleft&quot; alt=&quot;CGA solid artifact colors 1&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &quot;classic&quot; way of doing this on CGA is to set up BIOS mode 6 – 640x200 in 2 colors, white on black – and set the color-burst bit (which is off by default, for a B&amp;amp;W picture).  At this resolution we can squeeze 4 pixels into a color clock period, and at 1 bit per pixel, there are 16 possible patterns – giving us 16 solid artifact colors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is pretty much the same &lt;a href=&quot;http://laboratorium.net/archive/2009/03/08/why_did_the_applie_ii_have_six_colors&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;technique&lt;/a&gt; used by Steve Wozniak to generate color on the Apple ][.  In fact, on an old-style CGA card, these 16 colors are &lt;em&gt;identical&lt;/em&gt; to the 16 low-res Apple colors (although you couldn't get them on a poster, like Apple owners &lt;a href=&quot;http://beagle.applearchives.com/the_posters/poster_1.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;could&lt;/a&gt;).  More to the point: the pixels themselves are white, which carries no color information; it's the detail that does the deed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*But wait, there's more!*  Despite popular wisdom, CGA lets us one-up the Apple, and then some.  OUR underlying pixels don't have to be white: in 640x200 mode, we can play with the palette register and set any of the 16 &lt;em&gt;direct&lt;/em&gt; colors as the foreground (background is always black).  By using the same pixel patterns with a different foreground color, we get 16 &lt;em&gt;entirely new&lt;/em&gt; sets of artifact colors, with 16 colors each.  We can only use one such set at a time, but we get to pick and choose what our 16 colors are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there's 320x200 mode, which supports a palette of 4 direct colors.  Only one of those, color #0 (background), is freely selectable.  For the rest, intensity may be on or off, but we can only use green/red/yellow or cyan/magneta/white; the undocumented cyan/red/white palette involves disabling the color burst, making the composite picture greyscale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since our pixels are twice as fat in this mode, only two of them can squeeze into a color-clock cycle – but at 2 bits per pixel, the total count of artifact colors is still 16.  The possible combinations of palette, plus the user-defined background color, provide us with a whole slew of other 16-color sets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://int10h.org/blog/img/1k08_cga_composite_solid_colors_2.png&quot; alt=&quot;CGA solid artifact colors 2&quot;/&gt;  &lt;br/&gt;This may be a good place to correct a bit of a misconception.  Since we have 160 color cycles per scanline, many people treat CGA's graphics modes over composite as 160x200 &quot;modes&quot;, but that's not quite accurate.  Our &lt;em&gt;effective color resolution&lt;/em&gt; is indeed 160x200, and it's impossible to get finer detail than that using solid artifact colors.  But as we've seen, on NTSC the pixel grid and color grid are NOT one and the same – which makes the question of horizontal resolution a bit fuzzy, depending on how you're sampling and/or filtering the signal.  It even varies with the specific color waveforms you're using.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IBM itself never documented any of these artifact color tricks, other than one oblique reference to &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.org/stream/IbmPcjrTechnicalReference#page/n331/mode/2up/search/%22color+mixing+techniques%22&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;color mixing techniques&lt;/a&gt;&quot; in the PCjr tech ref (if I'm wrong about this, drop me a line and link me!).  The concept is fairly old hat, however – it was used in games very early on; some of the first ones I can think of were Microsoft's &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mobygames.com/game/pc-booter/microsoft-decathlon/screenshots&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Decathlon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mobygames.com/game/pc-booter/microsoft-flight-simulator-v10/screenshots&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Flight Simulator&lt;/a&gt;, both in 1982.  And the limitation has always been the same: the maximum simultaneous color count you can get over composite CGA is 16.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;....Or is it?  On the off chance that you've been following me so far, and you're still reading, you may have an idea of what the next step is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-id-256-colors-a-256-colors&quot;&gt; 256 colors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've already observed that our choice of 16 artifact colors depends on the palette and color register settings.  One fairly obvious strategy seems to suggest itself here – change those registers at particular scanlines on every frame, and get &amp;gt;16 colors on screen that way.  Right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://int10h.org/blog/img/1k09_reenigne_chart1a00.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://int10h.org/blog/img/1k09_reenigne_chart1a00.png&quot; title=&quot;CGA 256 colors chart.com&quot; alt=&quot;CGA 256 colors chart.com&quot; width=&quot;123&quot; height=&quot;92&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has been done before on CGA, and you &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; actually exploit this for 256 colors (as proven by reenigne - see the image to the left), but that's &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; how we did our multi-color hacking in the demo.  We were actually toying with the idea of including a static screen that uses this technique, but I didn't have the time to pursue this; if anyone manages to compose some nice artwork using this method, I'd love to see it – that's gotta be a bit of an artistic challenge.  But no, the way we wrangled more color out of CGA is a whole other shenanigan... which I came across by equal parts chance and morbid curiosity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recall how any color/dot pattern of the right length (four repeating pixels in 640x200, or two in 320x200) produces a solid color on a composite display?  Back when I was testing composite emulation for DOSBox, that fact was fresh in my mind.  At around the same time, I was experimenting with the &quot;ANSI from Hell&quot; graphical hack detailed &lt;a href=&quot;https://int10h.org/blog/2015/04/cga-in-1024-colors-new-mode-illustrated/#the_macrocom_method&quot;&gt;above&lt;/a&gt;; that's purely a text mode / RGBI trick, but it requires a close familiarity with the ROM character set... closer than most sane people would want or need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's take another look at a particular section of the CGA ROM font, in 80-column mode, with the top 2 scanlines highlighted:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://int10h.org/blog/img/1k10_cga_charset_subset.png&quot; alt=&quot;CGA ROM font subset&quot;/&gt;  &lt;br/&gt;At this point, if you're a visually-oriented person, and if you've been following my drift, you're probably catching on.  Don't see it yet? Here's a fatter clue:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://int10h.org/blog/img/1k11_ascii_0x55.png&quot; alt=&quot;ASCII char 0x55&quot;/&gt;  &lt;br/&gt;See those top 25% of the character bitmap?  Two dots of foreground and two dots of background, doubled horizontally across.  We're in hi-res/80-column mode, so there are two color cycles per character... corresponding exactly to those two matching halves.  And those top two scanlines are identical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's just the type of repeating pattern that gets us a solid artifact color over NTSC.  In fact, it's the very same waveform that 320x200 mode lets us play with.  Except that now we have it available in &lt;em&gt;text mode&lt;/em&gt;: you know, where we can freely assign a foreground AND a background to each character, from the 16 direct colors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's 256 possibilities right there... this is the part that made me go &lt;em&gt;&quot;I have a cunning plan&quot;&lt;/em&gt;, in my best imitation of Blackadder's &lt;a href=&quot;https://int10h.org/blog/img/baldrick.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Baldrick&lt;/a&gt; (just not out loud).  Indeed, it's possible to achieve &amp;gt;16 colors on CGA without any flickering, dithering, interlacing or per-scanline effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's what the possible combinations work out to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://int10h.org/blog/img/1k12_cga_artifact_colors_ascii_0x55.png&quot; alt=&quot;CGA artifacts - ASCII char 0x55&quot;/&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-id-512-colors-a-512-colors&quot;&gt; 512 colors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, we're not done yet: once that lightbulb went off over my head, I had another look at the CGA ROM font to see if any other useful bit sequences emerge.  There are a few character bitmaps that give us the exact same waveform as 'U' does – 'H', 'V', 'Y' and '¥' – but only one with a &lt;em&gt;different&lt;/em&gt; suitable bit sequence right where we need it: 0x13, the double exclamation mark ('‼').&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The top two scanlines of 'U' give us a bitmask of 11001100 for foreground/background; '‼' is 01100110 – a single shift to the right, or a 90° shift in phase.  This perfectly complements 'U' in terms of having a well-rounded palette, because we get all the colors that the &quot;...1100...&quot; waveform has to offer: going from 'U' to '‼' shifts the phase by 90° (0110); 180° and 270° are achieved by flipping the foreground and background colors for 'U' and '‼' respectively – the same as going '0011' and '1001'.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://int10h.org/blog/img/1k13_cga_artifact_colors_ascii_0x13.png&quot; alt=&quot;CGA artifacts - ASCII char 0x13&quot;/&gt;  &lt;br/&gt;Okay, we've pushed the envelope even further: 512 simultaneous colors!  Granted, the real number is lower, because a good few are duplicates (and others are very close).  But 512 seems to be the limit for this technique: no other characters in our font fit the bill for solid colors.  The CGA character ROM does have an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.seasip.info/VintagePC/cga.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;alternate 'thin' 8x8 font&lt;/a&gt;; but, besides the fact that you'd have to mod your card if you wanted to use it, the 'thin' font has none of the magic bit patterns in the right places, which makes it useless for our purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My kingdom for redefinable characters... alas, when you're dealing with old PC hardware, IBM's penchant for cost-cutting over innovation can &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; sneak up from behind and ruin your day – even in the most unusual of places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, I was pleased with my little discovery: extending the palette by a factor of &lt;strong&gt;32&lt;/strong&gt; has to count for something, right?  At this point, I shared my ideas with reenigne.  Little did I know that he'll promptly come up with a new devious scheme to double our color count yet again...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-id-1024-colors-a-1024-colors&quot;&gt; 1024 colors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This part is some next-level CRTC black magic which I could never have figured out by myself – I'm just a graphics guy; you might as well ask me to wait for a full moon and chant the MC6845 spec-sheet backwards in hexadecimal.  All credit goes to reenigne for this particular bit of mad science, which, despite its complex execution, stems from a wonderfully simple idea: our fixed character bitmaps don't play nice with what we're trying to do? No problem – we'll &lt;em&gt;make&lt;/em&gt; them play nice, or else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://int10h.org/blog/img/1k14_ascii_0xb0_0xb1.png#floatleft&quot; alt=&quot;ASCII chars 0xb0, 0xb1&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;See, there are two additional characters whose very &lt;em&gt;first&lt;/em&gt; scanline could be used; problem is, the second scanline is different, which would ruin our solid color effect.  These are ASCII codes 0xB0 and 0xB1, the 'shaded block' characters. It would be quite convenient if we could just tell that offending second scanline to buzz off, wouldn't it? As it turns out, we can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lowdown on how this is done is all in reenigne's writeup, which is linked to at the top of this post.  But this is the basic idea: by starting a new CRTC frame &lt;em&gt;every other scanline&lt;/em&gt; and twiddling with the start address, it's possible to lay down our character rows so that the first scanline of each gets duplicated twice!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we can make use of those two extra characters, and doing so gets us two more 256-color sets:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://int10h.org/blog/img/1k15_cga_artifact_colors_ascii_0xb0_0xb1.png&quot; alt=&quot;CGA artifacts - ASCII chars 0xb0, 0xb1&quot;/&gt;  &lt;br/&gt;Naturally, there are downsides: having to mess with the CRTC every couple of scanlines is quite taxing for the poor 4.77MHz 8088, so there's not much you can do with this other than static pictures.  The 512-color variant, using only ASCII 0x55 and 0x13, doesn't suffer from this – it's basically &quot;set and forget&quot;, requiring no more CPU intervention than any 80-column text mode (the familiar overhead of avoiding snow).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, there's that other problem which plagues 80-column CGA on composite displays... the hardware bug that leads to bad hsync timing and missing color burst.  There are ways to compensate for that, but none that reliably works with &lt;em&gt;every&lt;/em&gt; monitor and capture device out there.  This proved to be an enduring headache in calibrating, determining the actual colors, and obtaining a passable video capture of the entire demo... but that's all covered elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At any rate, we now have 1K colors on a 1981 IBM CGA, at an effective resolution of 80x100 'chunky pixels'.  'Chunky' describes the memory layout, but it also applies in the visual sense: we're really plumbing the depths of resolution here.  160x100,  that's as low as you could go? allow me to snicker, IBM - &quot;low-res&quot; just got &lt;em&gt;lower&lt;/em&gt;, baby!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One might object that this isn't a lot of canvas.  Yeah, yeah: 80x100 is a bit on the cramped side, 'artistically' speaking; but the limitation is part of the challenge, as it has always been in demos.  You can keep your fancy 4K monitors - 0.008 megapixels should be enough for anybody.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://int10h.org/blog/img/1k16_flowergirl_cga_1024_colors.png&quot; alt=&quot;CGA flowergirl 1k colors&quot;/&gt;  &lt;br/&gt;When we first showed Trixter the 'proof-of-concept' 1024c drawings, his response was, and I quote: &quot;HOLY F!@#$%G SHIT. WOW. I must know how this works!!&quot;.   Achievement unlocked: getting THAT out of a veteran 8088/CGA hacker and demomaker is, by itself, almost as good as... well, joining the team, 'making a demo about it' and winning the oldskool compo. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's about it for my writeup.  If you made it this far, congratulations!  There's more I could write about the tools and techniques I used to actually compose these graphics... but we'll get to that some other time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 16:30:34 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mariuz</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://int10h.org/blog/2015/04/cga-in-1024-colors-new-mode-illustrated/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>US emissions fell 2.1% in 2019</title>
<link>https://rhg.com/research/preliminary-us-emissions-2019/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://rhg.com/research/preliminary-us-emissions-2019/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;After a sharp uptick in 2018, we estimate that US greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions fell by 2.1% last year based on preliminary energy and economic data. This decline was due almost entirely to a drop in coal consumption. Coal-fired power generation fell by a record 18% year-on-year to its lowest level since 1975. An increase in natural gas generation offset some of the climate gains from this coal decline, but overall power sector emissions still decreased by almost 10%. Unfortunately, far less progress was made in other sectors of the economy. Transportation emissions remained relatively flat. Emissions from buildings, industry and other parts of the economy rose, though less than in 2018. All told, net US GHG emissions ended 2019 slightly higher than at the end of 2016. At roughly 12% below 2005 levels, the US is at risk of missing its Copenhagen Accord target of a 17% reduction by the end of 2020, and is still a long way off from the 26-28% reduction by 2025 pledged under the Paris Agreement.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;A Coal-Driven Decline&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The switch from coal to natural gas and renewables in the electric power sector accounts for the majority of the progress the US has made in reducing emissions over the past decade. This was particularly true last year. Based on a combination of monthly data from the Energy Information Administration and daily data from Genscape, we estimate that coal-fired power generation fell by 18% in 2019 (Figure 1). That’s the largest year-on-year decline in recorded history with coal generation now at its lowest level since 1975. It also marks the end of a decade in which total US coal generation was cut in half.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure waypoint-fade-in&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://rhg.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/US-preliminary-emissions-2019_Figure-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Figure 1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Natural gas generation made up much of the gap last year, as it has consistently in recent years, thanks to extremely cheap gas prices. Average annual prices at Henry Hub were down 20% in 2019, adjusted for inflation, to their lowest level in decades. Renewables played an important role as well thanks in part to continued cost declines in both wind and solar generation. Based on preliminary data from EIA and Genscape, utility-scale renewable generation (including hydro) was up 6% in 2019. That’s higher than the 3% gain in 2018, but lower than the 13% gains posted in 2016 and 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The drop in coal generation reduced emissions by 190 million metric tons in 2019. The growth in gas generation shaved a little more than 40 million metric tons off this number. But electric power sector emissions were still down by nearly 10%—the biggest year-on-year drop in decades, and a significant change from a 1.2% increase in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Little Progress Elsewhere&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, there was little good news outside the power sector, continuing a trend we have observed for the past several years. Based on preliminary data, we estimate that transportation emissions declined slightly—by 0.3% year-on-year (Figure 2). Industrial emissions (both energy and process) rose by 0.6%. Direct emissions from buildings increased by 2.2% and emissions from other sectors (agriculture, waste, land use, oil and gas methane, etc) rose by 4.4%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure waypoint-fade-in&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://rhg.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/US-preliminary-emissions-2019_Figure-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Figure 2&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was an improvement from the relatively sharp increase in building, transportation and industrial emissions recorded last year (Figure 3). As noted in &lt;a href=&quot;https://rhg.com/research/final-us-emissions-estimates-for-2018/&quot;&gt;our analysis last year&lt;/a&gt;, most of the increase in building emissions and some of the increase in industrial emissions in 2018 were weather-related. 2017 had been an atypically warm year and 2018 was colder (and closer to the ten-year average). This boosted year-on-year demand for heating in homes, offices, stores and factories. 2019 had about as many heating degree days (HDDs) as 2018, so there wasn’t the same year-on-year spike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strong economic growth also contributed to the increase in end-use emissions in 2018. GDP expanded by 2.9% that year compared to 2.4% in 2017 and 1.6% in 2016. Growth slowed again in 2019, down to 2.3% during the first three quarters of the year. That also contributed to more modest end-use emissions growth last year. For example, in the transportation sector, domestic air travel grew by 2.3% year-on-year in the first three quarters of 2019, compared to 4.1% during the same period in 2018. As a result, jet fuel demand growth slowed from 2.6% to 1.8% during the first three quarters of 2019. Growth in the amount of freight moved by truck slowed from 7.1% year-on-year during the first three quarters of 2018 to 4.1% during the same period in 2019. That turned a 5.6% increase in year-on-year diesel demand during the first three quarters in 2018 to a 0.8% decline during the same period in 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond the year-to-year fluctuations in weather and economic growth, it’s clear that US decarbonization success is still largely limited to the 27% of net emissions that come from the power sector. Improvements in vehicle, lighting, and appliance efficiency have been successful in slowing the pace of emissions growth in transportation and buildings (and perhaps even halting it in transportation), but it will require much more than efficiency to achieve meaningful absolute declines. Large-scale fuel substitution (to decarbonized electricity and other zero-carbon fuels) will be required. States have some ability to drive this in absence of federal policy action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The industrial, agriculture, and waste sectors remain largely untouched, either by policy or technology innovation. Industry is now a larger source of emissions than coal-fired power generation, and growing. There are low-cost technology solutions to reduce oil and gas methane emissions, but their deployment at scale requires strengthening regulations that the Trump Administration instead has been weakening. Reducing HFC emissions also requires new policy action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure waypoint-fade-in&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://rhg.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/US-preliminary-emissions-2019_Figure-3.png&quot; alt=&quot;Figure 3&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Coming up Short on Climate Targets&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using preliminary data and IPCC accounting protocols, we estimate that net economy-wide GHG emissions fell by 2.1% in the US in 2019 to 5,783 million metric tons. That’s a 12.3% cumulative decline relative to 2005 levels, with one year to go to meet the Copenhagen Accord target of reducing emissions “in the range” of 17% below 2005 levels by 2020, and six years to go to reach the 26-28% reduction by 2025 pledged under the Paris Agreement (Figure 4). The fact that the US has achieved no net reductions over the past three years makes meeting these targets extremely challenging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If our preliminary emissions estimates prove correct, hitting the Copenhagen Accord’s 17% target exactly will require a 5.3% reduction in net GHG emissions this year—a bigger annual drop than the US has experienced during the post-war period, with the exception of 2009 due to the Great Recession. Meeting the Paris Agreement targets requires a 2.8-3.2% average annual reduction in emissions over the next six years. This is significantly faster than the 0.9% average annual reduction achieved since 2005. It’s still possible, but will require a significant change in federal policy—and pretty soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure waypoint-fade-in&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://rhg.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/US-preliminary-emissions-2019_Figure-4.png&quot; alt=&quot;Figure 4&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;related-link&quot; href=&quot;https://rhg.com/research/final-us-emissions-estimates-for-2018/&quot; title=&quot;Related Work: 2018 US Emissions Estimates&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://rhg.com/wp-content/themes/site/static/images/arrow-blue-large.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Related Work: 2018 US Emissions Estimates&quot;/&gt;Related Work: 2018 US Emissions Estimates&lt;/a&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 16:26:26 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>prostoalex</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Preliminary US Emissions Estimates for 2019 | Rhodium Group</og:title>
<og:description>After a sharp uptick in 2018, we estimate that US greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions fell by 2.1% last year based on preliminary energy and economic data. This decline was due almost entirely to a drop in coal consumption. Coal-fired power generation fell by a record 18% year-on-year to its lowest level since 1975. An increase …</og:description>
<og:url>https://rhg.com/research/preliminary-us-emissions-2019/</og:url>
<og:image>https://rhg.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/us-preliminary-emissions-2019.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://rhg.com/research/preliminary-us-emissions-2019/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>I opened a link some random person sent me and I got raided (2015)</title>
<link>https://blog.haschek.at/2015-that-not-so-awesome-time-the-police</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.haschek.at/2015-that-not-so-awesome-time-the-police</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;A few years ago I saw the blooming of new IRC communities. In fact I haven't seen so many people in IRC channels since the end of the last century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; src=&quot;https://www.pictshare.net/300/04d12066b0.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since I'm a security researcher and sysadmin I was interested in this topic so I joined a small community on one of the bigger IRC servers. The atmosphere was nice and not at all hostile. The topics were mostly politics and the lastest news from hacks on the news.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was this one guy I briefly talked to and he said that he was still in school and always trying to find new security tools. The tool he recently found was &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sullo/nikto&quot;&gt;Nikto&lt;/a&gt; a simple webserver scanning tool that automatically tries to find badly configured sites and tested against kown vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was a nice kid but obviously a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Script_kiddie&quot;&gt;script kiddie&lt;/a&gt; so I didn't talk to him very long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&quot;lol, check this out&quot; -scriptkiddie&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few hours later, close to midnight, he sent me a private message via IRC with a link to the official website of a political party with the text &quot;lol, check this out&quot;. The link was like this &lt;code&gt;http://political-party-website/stuff&lt;/code&gt; (only with the real domain of course). It didn't look suspicious at all since it was the real domain and I thought the path &lt;code&gt;/stuff&lt;/code&gt; was some sort of download section or maybe a login form but no..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Inside of /stuff&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;/stuff&lt;/code&gt; folder had directory listing enabled so you could see all files in that folder from your browser. I didn't look too much around, clicked a few things but seemed like just some directory where the admin put files up that were linked somewhere on the page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn't use a VPN or proxy because I only wanted to talk on IRC and usually I don't click on any links but in this case the link seemed official and clean I didn't think about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since it was late I shut down my PC and went to bed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&quot;The website of a political party has been hacked last night&quot; - All news sites&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing I did after waking up was scrolling through the news on my phone. It was all over the news that the exact website I was surfing on yesterday was hacked and usernames, emails and hashed passwords were published on pastebin. The kiddie obviously found some exploit in the &lt;code&gt;/stuff&lt;/code&gt; directory and used it to gain access to the server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was on a site around the time it was hacked and I had no proxy or VPN.. &lt;strong&gt;oh fuck&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Four months later I was picking up my girlfriend from the trainstation and driving back home. I didn't think about the &lt;code&gt;/stuff&lt;/code&gt; folder anymore but when I opened the door we were greeted by the police, counter terrorism agents and a state-prosecutor. In all 7 people who were very polite and explained that they have evidence that I have hacked the website of a political party and that they have a search warrant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.pictshare.net/7359dafc47.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot;/&gt;Raiding police &lt;a href=&quot;https://logr.org/nwmo/wissenswertes/rechtliches/&quot;&gt;src&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They thought that I was the script kiddie and that my VPN failed for a moment and that's why they saw my public IP address.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pictshare.net/0086dd509b.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.pictshare.net/800x400/forcesize/negative/0086dd509b.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot;/&gt;Search warrant&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was also asked for my password and if I had any encrypted data on my PC (which I didn't have at the time).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;After the first shock&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We sat down at the table and I told them what happened and how my IP got in there. I told them about the script kiddie, the link and that I wasn't using a VPN because I did nothing wrong but of course they were sceptical even thought one of the agents said my story sounded plausible to him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was mostly talking to the agent of the federal agency for counter terrorism (in german &quot;Bundesamt für Verfassungsschutz und Terrorismusbekämpfung) and he said we had to go to the next police station where he can enter my statement into the police computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pictshare.net/6910d8af15.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.pictshare.net/800x400/forcesize/6910d8af15.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot;/&gt;What they took&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The police said they had no intention in jailing me since after surveilling my phone calls and my movements for weeks they didn't think I was a &quot;big fish&quot; but rather they might find the real bad people through me. Little did they know that I was just some dude who clicked a link he shoudln't have clicked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn't sleep well the next days and weeks and often had the fear that they will charge me for something I didn't do and I had dreams of innocently going to jail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What did they take? EVERYTHING&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They took all my computers, spare harddrives, USB drives and laptops - all my equipment. They were sighing when they saw how many computers and harddrives I owned since they said they had to look through every one of them, look at all images, skip through all videos and had to document everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They said it would roughly take &lt;strong&gt;a year&lt;/strong&gt; until I get everything back since I have so much data. They were right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About a year later I got everything back &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pictshare.net/e7f7c6cb10.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.pictshare.net/800x500/forcesize/e7f7c6cb10.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot;/&gt;Some of my things&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the lucky coincidence that I just put all my personal and company files to my cloud (at the time: Dropbox) just a few days before the raid, I didn't lose any data. The police also said they fear cloud data the most because they need different and most of the time international search warrants to get data from Google or Dropbox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How did it end?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A year and a half after I clicked the link, the case was dropped because no evidence pointed at me and what I did (clicking a link) was not illegal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything ended well except that I had to buy a new computer because the government kept mine for a year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pictshare.net/3df5939705.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.pictshare.net/800x400/forcesize/3df5939705.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot;/&gt;Dropping the case&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h3&gt;One funny thing though&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After getting my drives back I checked one of my USB drives and it had a .docx file on it that didn't come from me. In this Word file there was a photo of some guy (unpixeled). I have no idea who that is (maybe the script kiddie?) but the federal agency must have put it in there by accident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.pictshare.net/500/f8df258bbb.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot;/&gt;random dude&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 15:58:02 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>geek_at</dc:creator>
<og:title>That (not so) awesome time the police raided my home</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://blog.haschek.at/2015-that-not-so-awesome-time-the-police</og:url>
<og:image>https://blog.haschek.at/data/renderedposts/f7b6d.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>lesson learned: Don't click on links random people send you</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.haschek.at/2015-that-not-so-awesome-time-the-police</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>AirPods revenue does not exceed Spotify, Twitter, Snapchat, and Shopify revenue</title>
<link>https://twitter.com/neilcybart/status/1214867813464236032</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://twitter.com/neilcybart/status/1214867813464236032</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;4 / What is the lesson here?

Misinformation is rampant. Be careful what you link to / retweet on Twitter.

(By the way, the article in question put AirPods revenue at $12 billion in 2019. The actual number will end up being more like half that - closer to $7.5 billion.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 14:19:32 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>coloneltcb</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mobile.twitter.com/neilcybart/status/1214867813464236032</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: Beef, a new performance-oriented programming language</title>
<link>https://github.com/beefytech/Beef</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/beefytech/Beef</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Beef is an open source performance-oriented compiled programming language which has been built hand-in-hand with its IDE environment. The syntax and many semantics are most directly derived from C#, while attempting to retain the C ideals of bare-metal explicitness and lack of runtime surprises, with some &quot;modern&quot; niceties inspired by languages such as Rust, Swift, and Go. See the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.beeflang.org/docs/language-guide/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Language Guide&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beef's primary &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.beeflang.org/docs/foreward/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;design goal&lt;/a&gt; is to provide a fluid and pleasurable development experience for high-performance real-time applications such as video games, with low-level features that make it suitabile for engine development, combined with high-level ergonomics suitable for game code development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beef allows for safely mixing different optimization levels on a per-type or per-method level, allowing for performance-critical code to be executed at maximum speed without affecting debuggability of the rest of the application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Memory management in Beef is manual, and includes first-class support for custom allocators. Care has been taken to reduce the burden of manual memory management with language ergonomics and runtime safeties – Beef can detect memory leaks in real-time, and offers guaranteed protection against use-after-free and double-deletion errors. As with most safety features in Beef, these memory safeties can be turned off in release builds for maximum performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Beef IDE supports productivity features such as autocomplete, fixits, reformatting, refactoring tools, type inspection, runtime code compilation (hot code swapping), and a built-in profiler. The IDE's general-purpose debugger is capable of debugging native applications written in any language, and is intended to be a fully-featured standalone debugger even for pure C/C++ developers who want an alternative to Visual Studio debugging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Binaries and documentation are available on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.beeflang.org&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;beeflang.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/beefytech/Beef/blob/master/IDE/screenshot0.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/beefytech/Beef/raw/master/IDE/screenshot0.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 13:53:43 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>beefdev</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars0.githubusercontent.com/u/54323569?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>beefytech/Beef</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/beefytech/Beef</og:url>
<og:description>Beef Programming Language. Contribute to beefytech/Beef development by creating an account on GitHub.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/beefytech/Beef</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>ALBERT: A Lite BERT for Self-Supervised Learning of Language Representations</title>
<link>https://ai.googleblog.com/2019/12/albert-lite-bert-for-self-supervised.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://ai.googleblog.com/2019/12/albert-lite-bert-for-self-supervised.html</guid>
<description>&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;byline-author&quot;&gt;Posted by Radu Soricut and Zhenzhong Lan, Research Scientists, Google Research&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ever since the advent of &lt;a href=&quot;https://ai.googleblog.com/2018/11/open-sourcing-bert-state-of-art-pre.html&quot;&gt;BERT&lt;/a&gt; a year ago, natural language research has embraced a new paradigm, leveraging large amounts of existing text to pretrain a model’s parameters using self-supervision, with no data annotation required. So, rather than needing to train a machine-learning model for &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing&quot;&gt;natural language processing&lt;/a&gt; (NLP) from scratch, one can start from a model primed with knowledge of a language. But, in order to improve upon this new approach to NLP, one must develop an understanding of what, exactly, is contributing to language-understanding performance — the network’s height (i.e., number of layers), its width (size of the hidden layer representations), the learning criteria for self-supervision, or something else entirely?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In “&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1909.11942&quot;&gt;ALBERT: A Lite BERT for Self-supervised Learning of Language Representations&lt;/a&gt;”, accepted at &lt;a href=&quot;https://iclr.cc/Conferences/2020&quot;&gt;ICLR 2020&lt;/a&gt;, we present an upgrade to BERT that advances the state-of-the-art performance on 12 NLP tasks, including the competitive &lt;a href=&quot;https://rajpurkar.github.io/SQuAD-explorer/&quot;&gt;Stanford Question Answering Dataset&lt;/a&gt; (SQuAD v2.0) and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SAT&quot;&gt;SAT&lt;/a&gt;-style reading comprehension &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.qizhexie.com/data/RACE_leaderboard.html&quot;&gt;RACE&lt;/a&gt; benchmark. ALBERT is being &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/google-research/ALBERT&quot;&gt;released&lt;/a&gt; as an open-source implementation on top of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tensorflow.org/&quot;&gt;TensorFlow&lt;/a&gt;, and includes a number of ready-to-use ALBERT pre-trained language representation models.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What Contributes to NLP Performance?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Identifying the dominant driver of NLP performance is complex — some settings are more important than others, and, as our study reveals, a simple, one-at-a-time exploration of these settings would not yield the correct answers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The key to optimizing performance, captured in the design of ALBERT, is to allocate the model’s capacity more efficiently. Input-level embeddings (words, sub-tokens, etc.) need to learn context-&lt;em&gt;independent&lt;/em&gt; representations, a representation for the word “bank”, for example. In contrast, hidden-layer embeddings need to refine that into context-&lt;em&gt;dependent&lt;/em&gt; representations, e.g., a representation for “bank” in the context of financial transactions, and a different representation for “bank” in the context of river-flow management.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is achieved by factorization of the embedding parametrization — the embedding matrix is split between input-level embeddings with a relatively-low dimension (e.g., 128), while the hidden-layer embeddings use higher dimensionalities (768 as in the BERT case, or more). With this step alone, ALBERT achieves an 80% reduction in the parameters of the projection block, at the expense of only a minor drop in performance — 80.3 &lt;a href=&quot;https://rajpurkar.github.io/SQuAD-explorer/&quot;&gt;SQuAD2.0&lt;/a&gt; score, down from 80.4; or 67.9 on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.qizhexie.com/data/RACE_leaderboard.html&quot;&gt;RACE&lt;/a&gt;, down from 68.2 — with all other conditions the same as for BERT.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another critical design decision for ALBERT stems from a different observation that examines redundancy. &lt;a href=&quot;https://ai.googleblog.com/2017/08/transformer-novel-neural-network.html&quot;&gt;Transformer&lt;/a&gt;-based neural network architectures (such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://ai.googleblog.com/2018/11/open-sourcing-bert-state-of-art-pre.html&quot;&gt;BERT&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.borealisai.com/en/blog/understanding-xlnet/&quot;&gt;XLNet&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://ai.facebook.com/blog/roberta-an-optimized-method-for-pretraining-self-supervised-nlp-systems/&quot;&gt;RoBERTa&lt;/a&gt;) rely on independent layers stacked on top of each other. However, we observed that the network often learned to perform similar operations at various layers, using different parameters of the network. This possible redundancy is eliminated in ALBERT by parameter-sharing across the layers, i.e., the same layer is applied on top of each other. This approach slightly diminishes the accuracy, but the more compact size is well worth the tradeoff. Parameter sharing achieves a 90% parameter reduction for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1706.03762&quot;&gt;attention-feedforward&lt;/a&gt; block (a 70% reduction overall), which, when applied in addition to the factorization of the embedding parameterization, incur a slight performance drop of -0.3 on &lt;a href=&quot;https://rajpurkar.github.io/SQuAD-explorer/&quot;&gt;SQuAD2.0&lt;/a&gt; to 80.0, and a larger drop of -3.9 on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.qizhexie.com/data/RACE_leaderboard.html&quot;&gt;RACE&lt;/a&gt; score to 64.0.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Implementing these two design changes together yields an ALBERT-base model that has only 12M parameters, an 89% parameter reduction compared to the BERT-base model, yet still achieves respectable performance across the benchmarks considered. But this parameter-size reduction provides the opportunity to scale up the model again. Assuming that memory size allows, one can scale up the size of the hidden-layer embeddings by 10-20x. With a hidden-size of 4096, the ALBERT-xxlarge configuration achieves both an overall 30% parameter reduction compared to the BERT-large model, and, more importantly, significant performance gains: +4.2 on &lt;a href=&quot;https://rajpurkar.github.io/SQuAD-explorer/&quot;&gt;SQuAD2.0&lt;/a&gt; (88.1, up from 83.9), and +8.5 on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.qizhexie.com/data/RACE_leaderboard.html&quot;&gt;RACE&lt;/a&gt; (82.3, up from 73.8).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These results indicate that accurate language understanding depends on developing robust, high-capacity contextual representations. The context, modeled in the hidden-layer embeddings, captures the meaning of the words, which in turn drives the overall understanding, as directly measured by model performance on standard benchmarks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Optimized Model Performance with the RACE Dataset&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;To evaluate the language understanding capability of a model, one can administer a reading comprehension test (e.g., similar to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://collegereadiness.collegeboard.org/sat/inside-the-test/reading&quot;&gt;SAT Reading Test&lt;/a&gt;). This can be done with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aclweb.org/anthology/D17-1082/&quot;&gt;RACE dataset&lt;/a&gt; (2017), the largest publicly available resource for this purpose. Computer performance on this reading comprehension challenge mirrors well the language modeling advances of the last few years: a model pre-trained with only context-independent word representations scores poorly on this test (45.9; left-most bar), while BERT, with context-dependent language knowledge, scores relatively well with a 72.0. Refined BERT models, such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.borealisai.com/en/blog/understanding-xlnet/&quot;&gt;XLNet&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://ai.facebook.com/blog/roberta-an-optimized-method-for-pretraining-self-supervised-nlp-systems/&quot;&gt;RoBERTa&lt;/a&gt;, set the bar even higher, in the 82-83 score range. The ALBERT-xxlarge configuration mentioned above yields a RACE score in the same range (82.3), when trained on the base BERT dataset (Wikipedia and Books). However, when trained on the same larger dataset as XLNet and RoBERTa, it significantly outperforms all other approaches to date, and establishes a new state-of-the-art score at 89.4.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;tr-caption-container&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-vleNCv0Au08/Xf1Ajms5u0I/AAAAAAAAFDM/fuaBlAsVDn0VjIuvgTwKTFpgL10FEG3RgCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/image1.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;819&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1600&quot; height=&quot;326&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-vleNCv0Au08/Xf1Ajms5u0I/AAAAAAAAFDM/fuaBlAsVDn0VjIuvgTwKTFpgL10FEG3RgCLcBGAsYHQ/s640/image1.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tr-caption&quot;&gt;Machine performance on the RACE challenge (SAT-like reading comprehension). A random-guess baseline score is 25.0. The maximum possible score is 95.0.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
The success of ALBERT demonstrates the importance of identifying the aspects of a model that give rise to powerful contextual representations. By focusing improvement efforts on these aspects of the model architecture, it is possible to greatly improve both the model efficiency and performance on a wide range of NLP tasks. To facilitate further advances in the field of NLP, we are &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/google-research/ALBERT&quot;&gt;open-sourcing ALBERT&lt;/a&gt; to the research community. &lt;/noscript&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 13:44:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>agluszak</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>ALBERT: A Lite BERT for Self-Supervised Learning of Language Representations</og:title>
<og:image>http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-qRz-hnwUdY4/WulXSQ6Rv4I/AAAAAAAATvQ/shk7KsphA0c3E3nUMsDVASqYaH0PhLPNwCK4BGAYYCw/s1600/GoogleAI_logo_horizontal_color_rgb.png</og:image>
<og:url>http://ai.googleblog.com/2019/12/albert-lite-bert-for-self-supervised.html</og:url>
<og:description>Posted by Radu Soricut and Zhenzhong Lan, Research Scientists, Google Research Ever since the advent of BERT a year ago, natural languag...</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://ai.googleblog.com/2019/12/albert-lite-bert-for-self-supervised.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ask HN: Is there a platform for sharing ideas that people want to “give away”?</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=21991260</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=21991260</guid>
<description>&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.58823529411765&quot;&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=&quot;#FF6600&quot;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;pagespace&quot; title=&quot;Ask HN: Is there a platform for sharing ideas that people want to &amp;#x201C;give away&amp;#x201D;?&quot;&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.4788732394366&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;fatitem&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.4014084507042&quot;&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing&quot; id=&quot;21991260&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;title&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=21991260&quot; class=&quot;storylink&quot;&gt;Ask HN: Is there a platform for sharing ideas that people want to “give away”?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.75&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;subtext&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;score&quot; id=&quot;score_21991260&quot;&gt;239 points&lt;/span&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/user?id=balzss&quot; class=&quot;hnuser&quot;&gt;balzss&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;age&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=21991260&quot;&gt;11 hours ago&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span id=&quot;unv_21991260&quot;/&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/hide?id=21991260&amp;amp;goto=item%3Fid%3D21991260&quot;&gt;hide&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://hn.algolia.com/?query=Ask%20HN%3A%20Is%20there%20a%20platform%20for%20sharing%20ideas%20that%20people%20want%20to%20%E2%80%9Cgive%20away%E2%80%9D%3F&amp;amp;sort=byDate&amp;amp;dateRange=all&amp;amp;type=story&amp;amp;storyText=false&amp;amp;prefix&amp;amp;page=0&quot; class=&quot;hnpast&quot;&gt;past&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=Ask%20HN%3A%20Is%20there%20a%20platform%20for%20sharing%20ideas%20that%20people%20want%20to%20%E2%80%9Cgive%20away%E2%80%9D%3F&quot;&gt;web&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/fave?id=21991260&amp;amp;auth=f5ede58ad3235590a3b7fb68a548a32a7f1a2670&quot;&gt;favorite&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=21991260&quot;&gt;150 comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;I'm in the camp of &quot;Ideas are worthless, execution is everything&quot;. Not in a literal sense, obviously, but I definitely have more ideas than time for executing them. Most of them are fun little thing or tools that would be helpful but not enough to actually do them.
&lt;p&gt;I would like to submit them somewhere and maybe someone likes it and wants to create it. Or maybe I could get input why it's a stupid idea or how to improve them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would be also nice to see others' fun ideas. Maybe find a collaborator to work on them together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you aware of such a platform? If there is none, what do you think about the concept?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;yclinks&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsguidelines.html&quot;&gt;Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsfaq.html&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Support&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/HackerNews/API&quot;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/security.html&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/lists&quot;&gt;Lists&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/bookmarklet.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Bookmarklet&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/legal/&quot;&gt;Legal&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Apply to YC&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Contact&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 13:36:26 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>balzss</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=21991260</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Blackout Bug: Boeing 737 cockpit screens go blank if lands on specific runways</title>
<link>https://www.theregister.co.uk/2020/01/08/boeing_737_ng_cockpit_screen_blank_bug/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theregister.co.uk/2020/01/08/boeing_737_ng_cockpit_screen_blank_bug/</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;29.903930131004&quot;&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Odd thing haunts Next Generation airliner family (not the infamous Max)&lt;/h2&gt;


&lt;img src=&quot;https://regmedia.co.uk/2015/11/16/qantas_boeing_737_838_vh_vzr.jpg?x=442&amp;amp;y=293&amp;amp;crop=1&quot; alt=&quot;Qantas Boeing 737-838, VH-VZR&quot; width=&quot;442&quot; height=&quot;293&quot; class=&quot;article_img&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;A Boeing 737-800 (file photo)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;body&quot; readability=&quot;97.569685218978&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boeing's 737 Next Generation airliners have been struck by a peculiar software flaw that blanks the airliners' cockpit screens if pilots dare attempt a westwards landing at specific airports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amid the various &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theregister.co.uk/2019/06/27/boeing_737_max_control_bug_found/&quot;&gt;well-reported woes&lt;/a&gt; facing America's largest airframe maker, yet another one has emerged &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://rgl.faa.gov/Regulatory_and_Guidance_Library/rgad.nsf/AOCADSearch/3948342A978CC27B862584DD005C1A60?OpenDocument&quot;&gt;from the US Federal Aviation Administration&lt;/a&gt;; a bug that causes all pilots' display screens in the 737-NG airliner family to simply go blank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That bug kicks in when airliner crews try to program the autopilot to follow what the FAA described as &quot;a selected instrument approach to a specific runway&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seven runways, of which five are in the US, and two in South America - in Colombia and Guyana respectively – trigger the bug. Instrument approach procedures guide pilots to safe landings in all weather conditions regardless of visibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;All six display units (DUs) blanked with a selected instrument approach to a runway with a 270-degree true heading, and all six DUs stayed blank until a different runway was selected,&quot; noted the &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.federalregister.gov/documents/2019/12/27/2019-27966/airworthiness-directives-the-boeing-company-airplanes&quot;&gt;FAA's airworthiness directive&lt;/a&gt;, summarising three incidents that occurred on scheduled 737 flights to Barrow, Alaska, in 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;CaptionedImage Center&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://regmedia.co.uk/2020/01/08/shutterstock.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://regmedia.co.uk/2020/01/08/shutterstock.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The controls in the 737 cockpit&quot; title=&quot;The controls in the 737 cockpit&quot; height=&quot;429&quot; width=&quot;648&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text_center&quot;&gt;The DUs are the five main screens in front of the pilots plus the sixth in the lower middle position of the instrument panel. When they go offline, pilots rely on analogue backups&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although full technical details were not given in the airworthiness directive, the FAA said that the seven runways had &quot;latitude and longitude values&quot; that &quot;triggered the blanking behaviour&quot;, suggesting some kind of memory interaction between onboard computers causing the screens to stop displaying any information until a different runway was selected in the flight plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bug affects 737-600, -700, -700C, -800, -900 and -900ER model aircraft, which are running Common Display System Block Point 15 (CDS BP 15) software for their display electronic units (DEUs) together with flight management computer (FMC) software version U12 or later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FMCs hold the flight plan, thus navigating the aeroplane from waypoint to waypoint. DUs are the main screens displaying aircraft information to the pilots and are powered by two DEUs, each of which serves three of the DUs. The system arrangement is described in more detail &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.b737.org.uk/flightinsts.htm&quot;&gt;on this website&lt;/a&gt; under the heading &quot;NG Flight Instruments.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the airworthiness directive the FAA said it had &quot;confirmed that the faulty version of DEU software has already been removed from all airplanes conducting scheduled airline service into the affected airports&quot; in the US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;CaptionedImage Center Border&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://regmedia.co.uk/2020/01/07/boeing_737ng_banned_runways.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Runways which Boeing 737 Next Generation aircraft are not supposed to land at&quot; title=&quot;Runways which Boeing 737 Next Generation aircraft are not supposed to land at&quot; height=&quot;304&quot; width=&quot;593&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;text_center&quot;&gt;Runways where Boeing 737 Next Generation aircraft are not supposed to land. &lt;em&gt;Source: US FAA&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Commercial jet airliners are far from immune to software bugs. Infamously, Boeing's 787 Dreamliner needed power cycling every 248 days to &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theregister.co.uk/2015/05/01/787_software_bug_can_shut_down_planes_generators/&quot;&gt;prevent the aircraft's electronics from powering down in flight&lt;/a&gt;, while Airbus' A350 was struck by a similar bug &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theregister.co.uk/2019/07/25/a350_power_cycle_software_bug_149_hours/&quot;&gt;requiring a power cycle every 149 hours&lt;/a&gt; to prevent avionics systems from partially or even totally failing to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Human error with electronics can also cause problems for commercial aviation: a typo in GPS co-ordinates left an Air Asia Airbus A330's navigational system &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theregister.co.uk/2016/09/07/air_asia_x_navigation_system_typo_melbourne_malaysia/&quot;&gt;thinking it was 11,000km away from its true position&lt;/a&gt;, while the captain of another airline's A330 &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theregister.co.uk/2019/09/13/condor_a330_coffee_radio/&quot;&gt;found out the hard way that hot coffee and electronic hardware really do not mix&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boeing has not responded to &lt;em&gt;The Reg&lt;/em&gt;'s request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;boxout&quot; readability=&quot;16.481294236603&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;176 die in crash of Ukraine Airlines' 737-800&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adding to Boeing's unfortunate media coverage today is the crash of a Ukraine International Airlines 737-800 in Iran early this morning. The airliner had taken off from Imam Khomeini airport near the capital of Tehran before coming down minutes after takeoff, reportedly killing all 176 people aboard. BBC Iran correspondent Ali Hashem &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alihashem_tv/status/1214756252749877250&quot;&gt;obtained footage of a burning object in the sky crashing in a fireball&lt;/a&gt;. Although Iranian authorities were quick to issue a statement blaming the crash on an engine fire, a photo reportedly issued by a state-run Iranian news agency &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-7863359/Ukrainian-passenger-plane-carrying-180-people-crashes-near-Tehran-local-media.html&quot;&gt;shows what appears to be shrapnel damage to pieces of wreckage&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Semi-official news agency Mehr News reported that the head of Iran's civil aviation authority, Ali Abedzadeh, said it was not clear to which country Iran would send the &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/article/us-iran-crash-black-box-idUSKBN1Z71C7&quot;&gt;downed airliner's black boxes for analysis&lt;/a&gt;. International custom is for the manufacturer to analyse these boxes; in this case, US-based Boeing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;®&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 13:14:19 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>DemiGuru</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://regmedia.co.uk/2015/11/16/qantas_boeing_737_838_vh_vzr.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.theregister.co.uk/2020/01/08/boeing_737_ng_cockpit_screen_blank_bug/</og:url>
<og:title>Blackout Bug: Boeing 737 cockpit screens go blank if pilots land on specific runways</og:title>
<og:description>Odd thing haunts Next Generation airliner family (not the infamous Max)</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theregister.co.uk/2020/01/08/boeing_737_ng_cockpit_screen_blank_bug/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Add &amp;#039;127.0.0.1 xn–9q8h&amp;#039; to /etc/hosts gives you &quot;localghost&quot;</title>
<link>https://twitter.com/rfreebern/status/1214560971185778693</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://twitter.com/rfreebern/status/1214560971185778693</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/rfreebern/status/1214560971185778693&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/rfreebern/status/1214560971185778693&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=21991044&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=21991044&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 217&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 89&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 13:08:01 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>DyslexicAtheist</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mobile.twitter.com/rfreebern/status/1214560971185778693</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How scientists across three continents produced an Ebola vaccine</title>
<link>https://www.statnews.com/2020/01/07/inside-story-scientists-produced-world-first-ebola-vaccine/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.statnews.com/2020/01/07/inside-story-scientists-produced-world-first-ebola-vaccine/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;big-cap-wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;big-cap&quot;&gt;I&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;n the spring of 2014, as Ebola exploded across West Africa, a scientist named Gary Kobinger was following the news intently from Canada.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kobinger was the head of the special pathogens unit at the National Microbiology Laboratory in Winnipeg. He and the team he led had a well-deserved reputation for their work on Ebola and other viral hemorrhagic fevers; Kobinger himself had led development of a promising Ebola therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Winnipeg lab also had been working for years on an Ebola vaccine, one that looked tremendously effective in animal models. The lab had even produced human-grade vaccine in the hopes of testing it in people. But as of April 2014, that still hadn’t happened. The vaccine had never been deployed in an outbreak. No major pharmaceutical company had expressed interest in developing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Ebola appearing to spread rapidly in a country that had no experience trying to control it — Guinea — Kobinger contacted the World Health Organization to offer the vaccine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The WHO declined the offer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“They thought it was premature to advance it,” recalled Kobinger, who said he was told that Guinea lacked the infrastructure to approve use of an experimental vaccine. “That was true,” he added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reality was that, for years, scientists who studied Ebola, which belongs to a family of viruses called filoviruses, had poured their hearts into work to develop vaccines and drugs to combat these deadly scourges. And for years, they had seen promising work smash up against unscalable walls. There was no potential for drug makers to recoup development costs; and, with outbreaks only sporadic, there was little opportunity to subject experimental vaccines to rigorous tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But faced with the prospect of Ebola victims lying abandoned in the streets of African cities — and the world’s self-interested realization that the virus rampaging through West Africa wasn’t likely to stay there — the balance would eventually tip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“That big outbreak was a game-changer and reminded people that this exotic virus could become a real threat to public health regionally as well as in a global perspective,” said Dr. Heinz Feldmann, Kobinger’s predecessor, who led the work to develop the vaccine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;read-more standard&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;By 2014 Feldmann had long since given up hope that the vaccine — known in the myriad studies he and others published on it as rVSV-ZEBOV — would ever get made. But through an unlikely series of twists and turns, some fortuitous and not-so-fortuitous, the vaccine has finally been developed by Merck, approved by regulatory agencies in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statnews.com/2019/12/19/fda-approves-an-ebola-vaccine-long-in-development-for-the-first-time/&quot;&gt;United States&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statnews.com/2019/11/11/ebola-vaccine-approved-in-europe-in-landmark-moment-in-fight-against-a-deadly-disease/&quot;&gt;Europe&lt;/a&gt; late last year, and used in the field to save lives in Africa. It is known as Ervebo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a feat that built on the work of scientists in multiple countries on three continents who toiled in obscurity for years. And it ensured that when future outbreaks strike, health workers have a crucial new tool at their disposal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This vaccine … from the beginning to the end — it should have never happened. On so many levels … against all odds, it made it,” said Kobinger, now director of the Infectious Disease Research Center at Laval University in Quebec.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is how it happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;media-content wp-image-479263 size-medium_large&quot; src=&quot;https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Ebola-In-line-02-01-768x91.png&quot; alt=&quot;Ebola Inline&quot; width=&quot;768&quot; height=&quot;91&quot; data-id=&quot;479263&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Ebola-In-line-02-01-768x91.png 768w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Ebola-In-line-02-01-328x39.png 328w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Ebola-In-line-02-01-1024x122.png 1024w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Ebola-In-line-02-01-500x59.png 500w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Ebola-In-line-02-01-1600x190.png 1600w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Ebola-In-line-02-01-640x76.png 640w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Ebola-In-line-02-01.png 1920w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 1024px) 676px, (min-width: 768px) 66vw, calc(100vw - 40px)&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;big-cap-wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;big-cap&quot;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;he story of the Ebola vaccine began, as scientific advances often do, with a good idea and a lucky break.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the early 1990s, a Yale University scientist named John “Jack” Rose was trying to figure out a way to use a livestock virus called vesicular stomatitis virus, or VSV, as a vaccine delivery system. While it can infect people, VSV doesn’t sicken them. The immune system response to the virus is rapid and the levels of antibodies induced are surprisingly high.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rose thought the virus could be an effective backbone for a vaccine — if it could be engineered to include genes of viral pathogens like influenza or HIV. The idea was that the harmless virus would teach the immune system to recognize harmful potential invaders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But he and students in his lab had been trying for about six years to successfully manipulate VSV to add in the genes of other viruses. One very good student left his lab, he recalled, because she concluded the work was never going to pan out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, in 1994, Rose heard that researchers in Germany had succeeded where he had struggled — with a rabies virus. Using their approach, he was able to recover modified VSV viruses in a few months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“That opened up a whole new area of research on VSV for us and others,” Rose recalled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;To see if the system worked, his group added a protein from an influenza virus to VSV and injected it into mice. “The neutralizing antibody responses were fast and off the charts,” he said. “And of course the mice were completely protected after a single dose.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rose’s lab and others later used VSV as a backbone for experimental vaccines for bird flu, measles, SARS, Zika, and other pathogens. It always worked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without the high-security laboratories needed to handle the world’s most dangerous viruses, the researchers couldn’t work on Ebola. Rose, nonetheless, thought a VSV Ebola vaccine, in theory, would work as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yale patented Rose’s VSV construct, and licensed it to Wyeth Pharmaceuticals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;big-cap-wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;big-cap&quot;&gt;B&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;y his own estimate, Rose shared his VSV vector with at least 100 labs worldwide. One of them was located in a city in Germany with a rather auspicious name: Marburg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was there, in 1967, that laboratory workers and people related to them became sick with what was later named the Marburg virus. The source: primates imported for research purposes. (Nine years later, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statnews.com/2016/07/14/history-ebola-peter-piot/&quot;&gt;scientists would discover&lt;/a&gt; a related virus, Ebola.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a scientist named Hans-Dieter Klenk moved to the city in the 1980s to lead the Institute of Virology at the Philipps-University Marburg, there was no research being conducted there on Marburg or Ebola. Klenk decided that ought to change. He asked one of his students, Heinz Feldmann, if he wanted to continue to work on influenza, or move over to filoviruses like Marburg. “He did not think long,” Klenk said. “This is how it started.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;media-content wp-image-479258 size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/JohnRose-328x419.png&quot; alt=&quot;Dr. John Rose&quot; width=&quot;328&quot; height=&quot;419&quot; data-id=&quot;479258&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/JohnRose-328x419.png 328w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/JohnRose-1024x1309.png 1024w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/JohnRose-768x982.png 768w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/JohnRose-500x639.png 500w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/JohnRose-640x818.png 640w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/JohnRose-450x576.png 450w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/JohnRose.png 1084w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 1024px) 328px, (min-width: 768px) 32vw, calc(100vw - 40px)&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;John “Jack” Rose in his lab at Yale.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;cite class=&quot;media-credit&quot;&gt;Courtesy&lt;/cite&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Rose’s virus, Klenk’s team could study individual Ebola genes by putting them onto the VSV backbone. The beauty of the approach was that they could do the work at lower biocontainment levels than Ebola research is normally conducted, which made it safer, faster, and cheaper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, the protein on the surface of the VSV virus — known as the glycoprotein or G protein — was swapped out and replaced with the Ebola glycoprotein. Later the group made a VSV virus with the G protein of the Marburg virus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Klenk said that, even then, there was some discussion about whether the hybrid VSV virus could be made into Ebola or Marburg vaccines. But the group didn’t have high-containment labs in which to do animal studies, so it couldn’t test the theory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back across the Atlantic, though, Canada was building a new national microbiology laboratory — one that included biosafety level 4 facilities, the type needed to study Ebola. Feldmann was recruited to lead the special pathogens team there. And when he left Germany in 1999, he asked Klenk if he could take the VSV construct with him, so he could continue his work. Klenk agreed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This became ‘the Canadian vaccine’ — how it was known for many years. But certainly it has also roots in Marburg,” Klenk said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;big-cap-wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;big-cap&quot;&gt;A&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;s Feldmann recalls it, he wasn’t even thinking about using Rose’s VSV construct as a vaccine when he was in Marburg. “We had no vaccine program. We had no interest in vaccines,” he said. “We used it basically as a model system to study the glycoprotein.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After he’d moved to the Canadian lab, though, Feldmann and Tom Geisbert, a friend and frequent collaborator, heard Dr. Gary Nabel, then head of the National Institutes of Health’s Vaccine Research Center, deliver a lecture on Ebola. He argued the glycoprotein was the cause of the profound damage Ebola does when it infects animals and people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feldmann and Geisbert, an Ebola expert who was then at the U.S. Army Medical Research Institute of Infectious Diseases, thought Nabel was wrong and that they could use the VSV construct to prove it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Winnipeg, Feldmann’s team infected mice with the VSV virus containing the Ebola glycoprotein. If Nabel’s theory was correct, exposure to the protein should have been toxic to the mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rodents were unharmed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an afterthought, the group decided to expose the mice to Ebola to see what would happen. All the mice that had been infected with the VSV virus carrying the glycoprotein were &lt;a href=&quot;https://jvi.asm.org/content/78/10/5458.long&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;fully protected from illness&lt;/a&gt;; the mice that had not been exposed to the VSV virus all died.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I guess that was basically the start of the vaccine project, even though I don’t think we really jumped on it with a lot of priority right away,” said Feldmann.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;read-more standard&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;In hindsight, that delayed response might seem striking. But at the time the Winnipeg group faced more urgent matters. In 2003, an alarming new disease — which came to be called severe acute respiratory syndrome, or SARS — burst out of China and spread to Hong Kong, Vietnam, Singapore, and Toronto. The special pathogens team at the Canadian lab joined the search to try to determine what was causing the new illness and how to contain it. Other work was put on hold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the Winnipeg team tied up, Geisbert agreed to replicate the mouse study in nonhuman primates, considered the best animal model for what happens when humans are infected with Ebola.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like the mice before them, monkeys that had first been exposed to rVSV-ZEBOV survived what should have been a lethal Ebola challenge. A paper on the study was published in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/nm1258&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Nature Medicine&lt;/a&gt; in 2005 — and it “blew the doors off,” recalled Geisbert, who is now with the University of Texas Medical Branch in Galveston.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was suddenly clear that the modified VSV vector, loaded with the Ebola glycoprotein, was not only safe, but that it could be used as the foundation of an effective vaccine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientifically speaking, it was thrilling. But realistically, it was a nonstarter. Vaccines are estimated to cost in the neighborhood of $1 billion to develop. The pharmaceutical industry was not interested in making a product to protect against a disease that emerged only now and again in impoverished countries. At the time, Ebola had killed about 1,300 people over the nearly 30 years since it had been discovered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Yes, it was exciting, but where would you go with that excitement?” Feldmann said when asked about the results. “You went to the bar next door and had a beer and continued working.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“No one was interested in Ebola.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2008, Feldmann left Winnipeg to become the head of the virology program at the NIH’s Rocky Mountain Laboratories in Hamilton, Mont.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;media-content wp-image-479275 size-medium_large&quot; src=&quot;https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/mobile-biocontainment-unit-Hamburg1-768x576.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mobile biocontainment unit Hamburg&quot; width=&quot;768&quot; height=&quot;576&quot; data-id=&quot;479275&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/mobile-biocontainment-unit-Hamburg1-768x576.jpg 768w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/mobile-biocontainment-unit-Hamburg1-328x246.jpg 328w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/mobile-biocontainment-unit-Hamburg1-500x375.jpg 500w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/mobile-biocontainment-unit-Hamburg1-640x480.jpg 640w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/mobile-biocontainment-unit-Hamburg1.jpg 800w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 1024px) 676px, (min-width: 768px) 66vw, calc(100vw - 40px)&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;Mobile biocontainment unit used to monitor a German researcher who had pierced her finger with a syringe containing Ebola virus during an experiment in 2009.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;cite class=&quot;media-credit&quot;&gt;Bernhard-Nocht-Institute for Tropical Medicine&lt;/cite&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;big-cap-wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;big-cap&quot;&gt;I&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;n March 2009, a sudden crisis led to a critical decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A German researcher &lt;a href=&quot;https://academic.oup.com/jid/article/204/suppl_3/S785/2192258&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;pricked her finger with a needle containing Ebola virus&lt;/a&gt; while doing a mouse experiment. The needle penetrated three layers of gloves; though the wound didn’t draw blood, her skin had been punctured.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The University Medical Center Hamburg, where she was taken, reached out to Ebola researchers in the U.S. and Canada to see if there was anything that could be done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The experts on the call — a who’s who of Ebola researchers and field workers at the time — concluded that she should be offered the VSV vaccine. Some &lt;a href=&quot;https://journals.plos.org/plospathogens/article?id=10.1371/journal.ppat.0030002&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;testing in animals&lt;/a&gt; had shown it had increased survival when given after exposure, even as late as 48 hours afterward — though whether that translated into a similar effect in people was unclear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Canadian government agreed to send the vaccine — which was not human-grade product, but material the lab had produced for animal studies. Roughly 48 hours after the accident, the woman, who was not publicly identified, was vaccinated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;read-more popularnow&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following day, she developed a fever. It’s not uncommon for a live virus vaccine, like rVSV-ZEBOV, to trigger a fever; it’s actually a sign that the immune system has activated. But fever could also have been the first symptom of an Ebola infection. With no way to know which scenario they were facing, the doctors monitoring the researcher transferred her into a specially erected bio-containment treatment unit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fever subsided; the woman did not develop overt symptoms of Ebola. It was impossible to know whether the vaccine had shut down a developing infection, or whether she had never been infected in the first place. Feldmann and others believed the latter was more likely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, importantly, there were no negative consequences to using the vaccine, a fact that would later give comfort to people who were struggling with whether to deploy rVSV-ZEBOV in a much larger emergency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;media-content wp-image-479263 size-medium_large&quot; src=&quot;https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Ebola-In-line-02-01-768x91.png&quot; alt=&quot;Ebola Inline&quot; width=&quot;768&quot; height=&quot;91&quot; data-id=&quot;479263&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Ebola-In-line-02-01-768x91.png 768w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Ebola-In-line-02-01-328x39.png 328w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Ebola-In-line-02-01-1024x122.png 1024w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Ebola-In-line-02-01-500x59.png 500w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Ebola-In-line-02-01-1600x190.png 1600w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Ebola-In-line-02-01-640x76.png 640w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Ebola-In-line-02-01.png 1920w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 1024px) 676px, (min-width: 768px) 66vw, calc(100vw - 40px)&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;big-cap-wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;big-cap&quot;&gt;I&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;f two assets hadn’t come researchers’ way, it’s almost a certainty that Ervebo would have never come to fruition. One was money, the other was a rare talent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The monetary asset was a $2 million grant awarded to the Winnipeg lab. The grant, though a drop in the bucket when it comes to scientific research, was hard-won. Feldmann and Steven Jones, who had done a lot of the animal testing in the lab, had repeatedly applied to U.S. government agencies for funding. Their applications were repeatedly rejected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, the whole special pathogens program was always in the crosshairs of government bean counters. Every year during the budget process, Frank Plummer, scientific director of the National Microbiology Laboratory from 2000 to 2014, would get pressed on why Canada needed to work on pathogens like Ebola. “I always had to defend it, and we always were scrambling for money,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The grant was doled out by a Canadian defense program that funded research into tools to combat bioterrorism. It was to be used to produce test lots of human-grade VSV vaccine for Ebola Zaire, the species of the virus that has been the most common cause of Ebola outbreaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea was to hire a German contract manufacturer, IDT Biologika, to produce the vaccine. First, though, the Winnipeg lab had to create the starter material from which it could do so. That work was laborious and tedious, and it fell to the second asset — Judie Alimonti, an unassuming immunologist and lab scientist dedicated to the cause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among other tasks, Alimonti had to develop tests to show that the materials being transferred to IDT did not contain any microorganisms that inadvertently contaminated the product. When IDT had produced vaccine, it shipped back vials to Alimonti who ran the tests to ensure the material was pathogen-free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Judie did that. … She spent two years on this alone, I think,” said Kobinger. “She put all her heart into it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alimonti, who &lt;a href=&quot;https://ottawacitizen.com/news/local-news/obit-judie-alimonti-was-one-of-canadas-unsung-scientific-heroes&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;died of cancer in 2017&lt;/a&gt;, loved the project. Her former colleagues describe her as the unsung hero of the Ebola vaccine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She was “a very meticulous, methodical scientist,” said Plummer, who oversaw the VSV vaccine project after Feldmann and then Jones left the Winnipeg lab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, if IDT didn’t already have in hand the seed material to make more vaccine, the time needed to develop usable material would simply have been too great when a crisis struck. And the Winnipeg lab’s Ebola vaccine would have missed the chance to attract the big-league help needed to get the vaccine tested and eventually licensed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I think probably it would have never happened,” Kobinger said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;big-cap-wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;big-cap&quot;&gt;A&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;fter securing a patent for the vaccine system — and obtaining permission from Wyeth Pharmaceuticals to use its platform to produce Ebola and other viral hemorrhagic fever vaccines — the Winnipeg lab talked to a variety of pharma companies, big and small, looking for a development partner. The only interest came from a tiny firm called BioProtection Systems Corp., a spinoff of NewLink Genetics, a biotech working on cancer vaccines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;media-content wp-image-479572 size-medium_large&quot; src=&quot;https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/who_003061-768x512.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Gary Kobinger&quot; width=&quot;768&quot; height=&quot;512&quot; data-id=&quot;479285&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/who_003061-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/who_003061-328x219.jpg 328w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/who_003061-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/who_003061-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/who_003061-2048x1365.jpg 2048w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/who_003061-1600x1067.jpg 1600w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/who_003061-640x427.jpg 640w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/who_003061-864x576.jpg 864w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 1024px) 676px, (min-width: 768px) 66vw, calc(100vw - 40px)&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;Heinz Feldmann (left) and Gary Kobinger operating an Ebola testing lab provided by the Public Health Agency of Canada during a 2007 outbreak at Luebo, DRC.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;cite class=&quot;media-credit&quot;&gt;Christopher Black/WHO&lt;/cite&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interest had little to do with Ebola, or even infectious disease vaccine platforms, which is what BioProtection Systems would be licensing. The company was looking for assets to add to its portfolio to generate capital investment, Jones recalled. “It was a business decision for them that it would enhance their portfolio and make it easier to get funding to do the other work they were interested in,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The deal turned out to be a steal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NewLink &lt;a href=&quot;http://investors.linkp.com/node/9016/html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;agreed to pay&lt;/a&gt; the Canadian government — which officially held the patent — about $156,000 for each product it developed. (An amendment a couple of years later would increase that amount to roughly $360,000.) The Canadian government would also get royalties from some sales, though in truth those royalties were never expected to deliver much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company, which would later be absorbed into a drug maker called Lumos Pharma, never pushed development of the Ebola vaccine. For all intents and purposes, it would have remained no more than a scientific idea gathering dust on a shelf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then came the West African Ebola crisis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;big-cap-wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;big-cap&quot;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;he outbreak, which probably started in late 2013, smoldered in the way Ebola outbreaks do. At first, the assumption is the people who fall ill have contracted malaria or some other disease. Eventually, health workers become ill. Finally, a diagnosis of Ebola is made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The WHO reported a “rapidly evolving” Ebola outbreak in southeastern Guinea on March 23, 2014. By that point, there were already 49 cases and 29 deaths, making it larger than about half of all previous known Ebola outbreaks. The following day, the tally grew: 86 cases and 59 deaths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before the week was out, cases were reported in Guinea’s capital, the first time Ebola had taken root in an urban setting. By the end of March, one of Guinea’s neighbors, Liberia, was investigating possible cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;read-more standard&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Back in Canada, Kobinger’s offer to the WHO had been rebuffed. He heard that, a few weeks later, GSK, which was developing its own Ebola vaccine, also offered vaccine to the WHO. It, too, was turned down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, Kobinger saw a bright side: “The seed of the [vaccine] being available was planted.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He mentioned the offer to Dr. Armand Sprecher, an Ebola expert with Doctors Without Borders who he knew as a strong supporter of the VSV vaccine. As Ebola spread from Guinea to Liberia and Sierra Leone, the group, known by the acronym of its French name, MSF, had been emphatically warning the WHO and others that conditions on the ground were rapidly deteriorating. Prompted by Sprecher, MSF started pushing for use of the VSV vaccine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Aug. 8, 2014, the WHO declared the outbreak a global health emergency. A couple of days later, the Canadian government announced it would donate its vaccine to the agency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a pivotal moment, but it also created a conundrum. Was the vaccine safe to use? What was an appropriate dose? And how could human trials be conducted in the midst of an epidemic?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;media-content wp-image-479484 size-large-fill&quot; src=&quot;https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Ebola-liberia-GettyImages-453918798-1024x700.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Liberia Battles Spreading Ebola Epidemic&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;700&quot; data-id=&quot;479343&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Ebola-liberia-GettyImages-453918798-1024x700.jpg 1024w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Ebola-liberia-GettyImages-453918798-328x224.jpg 328w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Ebola-liberia-GettyImages-453918798-768x525.jpg 768w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Ebola-liberia-GettyImages-453918798-500x342.jpg 500w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Ebola-liberia-GettyImages-453918798-2048x1401.jpg 2048w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Ebola-liberia-GettyImages-453918798-1600x1095.jpg 1600w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Ebola-liberia-GettyImages-453918798-640x438.jpg 640w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Ebola-liberia-GettyImages-453918798-842x576.jpg 842w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 1024px) 1024px, 100vw&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;People with suspected Ebola virus lie on the ground after arriving by ambulance and just before being admitted to the Doctors Without Borders Ebola treatment center near Monrovia, Liberia, in August 2014.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;cite class=&quot;media-credit&quot;&gt;John Moore/Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;big-cap-wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;big-cap&quot;&gt;I&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;t is widely considered to be unethical to use untested drugs or vaccines in Africa, where clinical safeguards are sometimes lacking and where memories linger of scandals like Pfizer’s use of a meningitis drug that resulted in the death of 11 children in 1996. Yet given the scale of the expanding crisis, experts were now &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nationalgeographic.com/news/2014/8/140811-ebola-ethics-experimental-drugs-vaccines-science-health/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;scouring the medical literature&lt;/a&gt;, looking for any existing medicines that could be repurposed to fight Ebola, or experimental vaccines or drugs, regardless of where they were in the developmental pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The WHO convened a meeting to determine the best path forward. It concluded there was an “&lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.who.int/iris/bitstream/handle/10665/130997/WHO_HIS_KER_GHE_14.1_eng.pdf;jsessionid=152E65CED16365260F36D6571D9DA179?sequence=1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;ethical imperative&lt;/a&gt;” to try experimental vaccines and therapies, given the extraordinary threat Ebola presented. But it was also decided that in order to use the donated Canadian vaccine, clinical trials first had to assess its safety and establish the appropriate dose. It was apparent to everyone that NewLink didn’t have the expertise or bandwidth to take on this work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marie-Paule Kieny, who then headed the division of the WHO tasked with trying to spur development of drugs and vaccines for diseases like Ebola, noted the company had never conducted a clinical trial. “So when we were saying, ‘We should do a clinical trial in Africa,’ they were completely lost,” Kieny recalled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researchers at the NIH and Walter Reed Army Institute of Research (WRAIR) started planning a Phase 1 trial to determine the appropriate dose of the vaccine. Others started working on Phase 1 trials that would be conducted in Switzerland, Germany, Gabon, and Kenya.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The WHO and others — including players in the U.S. government — began casting about to find a more experienced pharmaceutical company to partner with, or to acquire the vaccine from NewLink.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The list of potential white knights wasn’t long. Sanofi Pasteur wasn’t interested. Novartis had sold its vaccines division to GSK earlier that year. GSK was racing to test its own experimental Ebola vaccine. Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson’s vaccines division, Janssen, was also working on an Ebola vaccine, but it wasn’t as far along as the GSK or the NewLink vaccines. But Merck had experience producing vaccines in the types of cells the VSV vaccine was made in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;read-more standard&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;The company started fielding approaches from the WHO, the Biomedical Advanced Research and Development Authority (BARDA), and others asking if Merck would step up. Merck had already been debating what it could do to help with the outbreak, and the vaccine seemed like a good fit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We already understood how to scale production of vectors in that system, and we knew how to manage the whole scaling process. We had an enormous amount of know-how that was kind of complementary to the work that had already been done,” said Dr. Julie Gerberding, Merck’s executive vice president and chief patient officer for strategic communications, global public policy, and population health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gerberding said there was “moral clarity” at Merck that this was something the company should do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the anxious autumn of 2014, when Ebola was ravaging West Africa, it seemed like rumored negotiations between NewLink and Merck were taking forever. But in terms of a pharmaceutical deal, negotiations happened at warp speed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“[From] Merck deciding to get involved from the initial sort of exploratory discussions at the beginning of October to licensing the vaccine in mid-November, that is unprecedented in terms of internal decision-making within the company because people recognized how urgent it was,” said Dr. Mark Feinberg, the company’s chief science officer at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Merck agreed to pay NewLink $50 million for the license. The deal &lt;a href=&quot;http://investors.linkp.com/news-releases/news-release-details/merck-and-newlink-genetics-enter-licensing-and-collaboration&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;was announced&lt;/a&gt; Nov. 24, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;media-content wp-image-479311 size-medium_large&quot; src=&quot;https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/VSV-Ebola_Remich-768x432.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;rVSV ZEBOV Ebola vaccine&quot; width=&quot;768&quot; height=&quot;432&quot; data-id=&quot;479311&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/VSV-Ebola_Remich-768x432.jpg 768w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/VSV-Ebola_Remich-328x185.jpg 328w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/VSV-Ebola_Remich-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/VSV-Ebola_Remich-500x281.jpg 500w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/VSV-Ebola_Remich-2048x1152.jpg 2048w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/VSV-Ebola_Remich-1600x900.jpg 1600w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/VSV-Ebola_Remich-640x360.jpg 640w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 1024px) 676px, (min-width: 768px) 66vw, calc(100vw - 40px)&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;rVSV ZEBOV Ebola vaccine&lt;/span&gt; &lt;cite class=&quot;media-credit&quot;&gt;WRAIR&lt;/cite&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;big-cap-wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;big-cap&quot;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;hat same month, around the time the researchers at NIH and WRAIR arrived at an agreement about the appropriate dose for the vaccine, Kobinger made a heart-stopping discovery. It was about the vaccine being used in the trials, donated by the Canadian government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From its earliest iteration, when Feldmann and his team saw that it saved mice from Ebola, the vaccine had been made with the glycoprotein from the Ebola Zaire strain known as Mayinga. But somewhere along the line, a key feature in the vaccine had been changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The human-grade vaccine made by the German contractor contained the glycoprotein from a different Ebola Zaire strain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No one had told Kobinger the change had been made; he discovered that Alimonti, who had done all the work to prepare the materials for IDT Biologika, had used the different glycoprotein on instructions from one of her supervisors. No one outside the lab realized that the vaccine being tested in people was not identical to the one that had been studied so thoroughly in animals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feldmann believed the switch would have no impact on whether the vaccine was effective. “Quite frankly, from a scientific prospective, it doesn’t matter,” agreed Kobinger. “From a regulatory perspective, it matters a lot.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kobinger quickly fired off an email to the Food and Drug Administration to inform the agency of his discovery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He feared fireworks. That’s not what he got. “We never heard back,” he said, noting the fact that Phase 1 human trials were already underway may have helped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, Kobinger urgently shipped off some doses to Montana so Feldmann could test the vaccine in primates to ensure the change had not affected the vaccine’s efficacy. It had not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;media-content wp-image-479378 size-large-fill&quot; src=&quot;https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Merck-map-Ebola-1024x576.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Merck map Ebola&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;576&quot; data-id=&quot;479378&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Merck-map-Ebola-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Merck-map-Ebola-328x185.jpg 328w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Merck-map-Ebola-768x432.jpg 768w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Merck-map-Ebola-500x281.jpg 500w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Merck-map-Ebola-2048x1152.jpg 2048w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Merck-map-Ebola-1600x900.jpg 1600w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Merck-map-Ebola-640x360.jpg 640w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 1024px) 1024px, 100vw&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;Caption tk&lt;/span&gt; &lt;cite class=&quot;media-credit&quot;&gt;Courtesy MERCK&lt;/cite&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;big-cap-wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;big-cap&quot;&gt;A&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;s researchers who conducted the Phase 1 and Phase 2 trials crunched their data, others were planning pivotal Phase 3s. The earlier trials were to determine if the vaccine was safe to administer; the Phase 3s would tell the world if it actually worked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The NIH had reached an agreement with Liberia to test both the GSK vaccine and the VSV vaccine that Merck had acquired. Scientists from the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention were to test the vaccines in Sierra Leone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The government in Guinea was also keen to host a trial. But the country’s health infrastructure was weaker than those of its neighbors, making it a more challenging place in which to conduct a study. When no other group stepped forward, the WHO announced it would conduct a trial there, with help from MSF.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plan was to use an approach known as ring vaccination. People who had had direct contact with anyone infected with Ebola were to be vaccinated, as were their contacts. The goal would be to both protect people in the virus’s path and to block it from spreading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In place of a placebo control, the rings were randomly assigned to either immediate vaccination, or vaccination after a 21-day delay. If there were more cases among the people in the rings that were vaccinated after the delay, the vaccine was working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The approach was distinct from the one used in classical trials, in which participants are randomly selected to get either an intervention or a placebo, with neither the researchers nor the participants aware of which was administered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To proponents, ring vaccination, a type of adaptive trial design, was the most feasible approach. Not everyone would agree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;media-content wp-image-479356 size-medium_large&quot; src=&quot;https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/GettyImages-454689576-768x512.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;WHO Ebola meeting 2014&quot; width=&quot;768&quot; height=&quot;512&quot; data-id=&quot;479356&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/GettyImages-454689576-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/GettyImages-454689576-328x219.jpg 328w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/GettyImages-454689576-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/GettyImages-454689576-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/GettyImages-454689576-2048x1365.jpg 2048w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/GettyImages-454689576-1600x1067.jpg 1600w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/GettyImages-454689576-640x427.jpg 640w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/GettyImages-454689576-864x576.jpg 864w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 1024px) 676px, (min-width: 768px) 66vw, calc(100vw - 40px)&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;WHO Assistant Director-General Marie-Paule Kieny (left); professor Oyewale Tomori from Redeemer’s University in Nigeria; and Samba Sow, director-general of the Center for Vaccine Development in Mali, discuss the outcome of a WHO-led expert meeting on fast-tracking experimental Ebola vaccines and drugs in September 2014.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;cite class=&quot;media-credit&quot;&gt;FABRICE COFFRINI/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;big-cap-wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;big-cap&quot;&gt;G&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;uinean health professionals made up the bulk of the team that conducted the ring vaccination trial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Abdourahmane Diallo, a public health physician who works for Guinea’s health ministry, was one of those who answered the WHO’s appeal for help. He recalled that his colleagues were excited at the prospect of taking part in the study. “The only thing in our mind was that we wanted to assess if the vaccine worked or not because we wanted to contribute if possible to find a solution,” Diallo told STAT via email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were hints that it was working, he remembered. Others agreed. Neighborhoods where transmission had been intractable stopped producing cases after vaccination occurred. “But that’s not proof, of course,” said Kieny of the WHO. “That’s just a feeling.’’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In June, however, the trial’s data and safety monitoring board concluded there were not likely to be enough additional cases to change the outcome of the study. The vaccine had worked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From 10 days after vaccination — the time needed for the immune system to respond to the vaccine — there were no cases among people who had been vaccinated in the early rings, but there were cases among the delayed vaccination rings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data and safety monitoring board recommended that health workers vaccinate anyone who had come in contact with people infected with Ebola as quickly as they could be found, rather than delaying some vaccinations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On July 31, 2015, less than a year after the Canadian government donated the vaccine, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thelancet.com/journals/lancet/article/PIIS0140-6736(15)61117-5/fulltext&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;the findings&lt;/a&gt; of the trial were published by the journal The Lancet. In less than 12 months, 12 clinical trials running the gamut from a “first in man” dosing study to a Phase 3 efficacy trial had been conducted. “That has never happened,” said Feinberg, who is now CEO of the International AIDS Vaccine Initiative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an editorial, The Lancet called the trial “a remarkable scientific and logistical achievement.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“That such a trial was even possible is a testament not only to the skill of the research teams but also to the commitment of communities to defeating an epidemic that has devastated their nation,” the journal’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thelancet.com/journals/lancet/article/PIIS0140-6736(15)61177-1/fulltext&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;editors wrote&lt;/a&gt;. “Before this work, no clinical trial on this scale had ever been performed in the country.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Guinea vaccine trial — the trial that almost hadn’t happened — was the only one to reach a conclusion. The trials in Sierra Leone and Liberia ended without having enrolled enough patients to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content-column one_half&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;media-content wp-image-479393 size-large&quot; src=&quot;https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/ProvedItWorked-GettyImages-465765562-1-1024x683.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;683&quot; data-id=&quot;479357&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/ProvedItWorked-GettyImages-465765562-1-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/ProvedItWorked-GettyImages-465765562-1-328x219.jpg 328w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/ProvedItWorked-GettyImages-465765562-1-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/ProvedItWorked-GettyImages-465765562-1-500x334.jpg 500w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/ProvedItWorked-GettyImages-465765562-1-2048x1366.jpg 2048w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/ProvedItWorked-GettyImages-465765562-1-1600x1067.jpg 1600w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/ProvedItWorked-GettyImages-465765562-1-640x427.jpg 640w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/ProvedItWorked-GettyImages-465765562-1-864x576.jpg 864w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 768px) 50vw, 100vw&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;A woman gets vaccinated at a health center in Conakry in March 2015 during the Guinea clinical trial of the rVSV-EBOV vaccine.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;cite class=&quot;media-credit&quot;&gt;Cellou Binani/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content-column one_half last_column&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;media-content wp-image-479359 size-large&quot; src=&quot;https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/VSV-in-use-Ebola-vaccine-2019-AP_19198465625938-1024x683.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2019 Ebola vaccine in Beni&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;683&quot; data-id=&quot;479359&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/VSV-in-use-Ebola-vaccine-2019-AP_19198465625938-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/VSV-in-use-Ebola-vaccine-2019-AP_19198465625938-328x219.jpg 328w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/VSV-in-use-Ebola-vaccine-2019-AP_19198465625938-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/VSV-in-use-Ebola-vaccine-2019-AP_19198465625938-500x334.jpg 500w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/VSV-in-use-Ebola-vaccine-2019-AP_19198465625938-2048x1366.jpg 2048w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/VSV-in-use-Ebola-vaccine-2019-AP_19198465625938-1600x1067.jpg 1600w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/VSV-in-use-Ebola-vaccine-2019-AP_19198465625938-640x427.jpg 640w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/VSV-in-use-Ebola-vaccine-2019-AP_19198465625938-863x576.jpg 863w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 768px) 50vw, 100vw&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;A girl receives the Ebola vaccine in Beni, DRC, in July 2019.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;cite class=&quot;media-credit&quot;&gt;Jerome Delay/AP&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;big-cap-wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;big-cap&quot;&gt;D&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;espite the success, the study produced a backlash that was almost instantaneous in some quarters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While everyone wanted an effective Ebola vaccine, there was heated debate over whether adaptive design studies were sufficient to prove that the Merck vaccine met that threshold. The detractors were vocal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It was ugly, frankly. It was ugly,” Kieny said. “I thought everybody would be happy to say: ‘This is great.’ But actually, this is when the bashing started. ‘This is not a study.’ … ‘Only a randomized controlled trial.’ The campaign against these results was flabbergasting.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both the findings and the approach were critiqued — and to this day are challenged by some experts. In the spring of 2017, the National Academy of Sciences &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statnews.com/2017/04/12/epidemics-clinical-trials-ebola/&quot;&gt;issued a report&lt;/a&gt; on conducting research during disease outbreaks that called into question the way the trial was conducted and its findings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We concur that, taken together, the results suggest that the vaccine most likely provides some protection to recipients — possibly ‘substantial protection,’ as stated in the preliminary report,” the authors wrote. “However, we remain uncertain about the magnitude of its efficacy, which could in reality be quite low or even zero, as the confidence limits around the unbiased estimate include zero.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the trial, the vaccine had been found to be 100% effective. But the number of people enrolled was limited, and no vaccine works every single time. Still, the results were strong enough to convince Merck to push forward with the vaccine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It did so with support from BARDA, which began funding rVSV-ZEBOV during the West African outbreak. The agency’s director, Rick Bright, estimated that it has spent about $175 million supporting production of vaccine and validation of Merck’s production facility for the vaccine in Germany.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Ebola broke out in Equateur province in the Democratic Republic of the Congo in the spring of 2018, the country agreed to use the vaccine under a “compassionate use” protocol — similar to the protocol used in a clinical trial when there is no approved therapy. Vaccination began again in the country in the current outbreak, this time eight days after it was declared. Since then more than 260,000 people have been vaccinated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I’m really proud of that,” Rose said of the role played by the vaccine. “We worked night and day … trying to get VSV to work and finally got it to work.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Nov. 11, 2019, Ervebo was approved by the European Commission, the first time it had been licensed by any regulatory agency. On Dec. 21, the FDA approved the vaccine in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beth-Ann Coller, who has been the project lead at Merck — another unsung hero of the vaccine, said Kobinger — choked up a little describing her reaction to the approval of the vaccine. “We are thrilled and we are proud,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kieny waxed a bit philosophical about the unlikely success of rVSV-ZEBOV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You know, when things go really wrong, quite often it’s a succession of little issues in which none by themselves could have derailed the train. And sometimes for something good to happen it’s the same,” she said. “It’s just bringing together a number of discrete actions and discrete facts, which each alone would not have made it. But everything together makes it a success.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 12:36:18 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>bookofjoe</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>The inside story of how scientists produced an Ebola vaccine</og:title>
<og:description>For years, scientists poured their hearts into work to develop vaccines. And, for years, they saw promising work smash up against unscalable walls.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.statnews.com/2020/01/07/inside-story-scientists-produced-world-first-ebola-vaccine/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Ebola-Liberia-GettyImages-462658754-1024x576.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.statnews.com/2020/01/07/inside-story-scientists-produced-world-first-ebola-vaccine/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>