<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Small mail server best current practices</title>
<link>https://bridge.grumpy-troll.org/2020/07/small-mailserver-bcp/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://bridge.grumpy-troll.org/2020/07/small-mailserver-bcp/</guid>
<description>&lt;header&gt;
&lt;time itemprop=&quot;datePublished&quot; datetime=&quot;2020-07-24&quot;&gt;July 24, 2020&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/header&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(This post was originally written as a reply on the mailop mailing-list, but a friend asked me to turn it into a blog post. I've edited it, mostly adding more links to elsewhere, but there are some additions here.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Context: someone with a mail-server hosted in a German facility with a poor reputation for handling abuse reports was asking for help on sending email to their Gmail-using friends; they had SPF and didn't see the point of DKIM; they had TLS setup for their mail-server, using a certificate from CACert.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's a PDF from Google from 2006 which is still worth reading: &lt;a href=&quot;https://research.google.com/pubs/archive/45.pdf&quot;&gt;https://research.google.com/pubs/archive/45.pdf&lt;/a&gt;, entitled “Sender Reputation in a Large Webmail Service” by Bradley Taylor. Anyone running a mail-server today needs to read that document.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don't send much email, then the only IP-based reputation which Google can assess you on is the reputation of your address-block, so being in a “troublesome” hosting provider will score heavily against you. At that point, if not moving away, you need to try to balance out that negative score with enough positives that any of the large providers using reputation scoring will accept the mail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working forward-and-reverse paired DNS is even more important for IPv6 than for IPv4; for better or worse, some of the large providers have decided that exemptions in old standards for old behavior should not apply when folks deploy standards which are far newer. So you absolutely need an &lt;code&gt;MX&lt;/code&gt; record, you must not just rely upon address-records (&lt;code&gt;A&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;AAAA&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a poor IP-based reputation, you need to see if you can score a better domain-based reputation. This is where DKIM comes into play: once you can provably link a message to really be from a given domain, then even if you don't send much mail you can benefit from stuff like “not on day-old-bread domain-lists”. But having DKIM and then a DMARC record does help (and &lt;a href=&quot;/2014/04/dmarc-stance/&quot;&gt;I'm no fan of DMARC&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the mail-server's TLS: for that to count in your favor instead of being a wash, I strongly suspect that it needs to be a certificate which senders can verify. For those people scoring up for “better TLS”, those senders using DANE will be happy with a TLSA record in DNSSEC for your CACert anchor. But the large webmail providers are Resistant to having to deploy DNSSEC verification, so instead have pushed out an alternative called MTA-STS. With MTA-STS, you're tied into “whichever subset of CAs all the large senders you care about will trust”, and then using that CA for the certificates both for the MTA-STS web-server and for your mail-server. Note that you don't need to implement the client logic for MTA-STS (and I think it's antithetical to an open federated platform) but do need to just publish the static information for those senders who do use it. At that point, CACert is not going to cut it. You'd need to try Let's Encrypt instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ongoing natural tendency from larger providers is to favor supporting what the majority of their users want the majority of the time. With so many people using larger providers, they naturally tilt towards stuff which works with the larger senders, and requiring more hoops. Those additional hoops create more work for smaller providers and self-hosters doing thing manually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need better automation tools around all of this. The below will make it clearer why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, here is my current understanding of the best current practices here, in reality not IETF idealism. This includes making mandatory stuff which some folks insist must be optional, because realistically to send to some large providers it's not optional. This list includes features to make you compatible with ongoing trends in the EU (particularly Germany) to strongly disfavor allowing clear-text SMTP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This assumes that you are &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; a large sender who should also be setting up feedback loops, learning how to “warm” IPs, considering BIMI, postmaster tooling domain verification, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;deliverability-fixes&quot;&gt;Deliverability fixes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;reverse DNS with matching forward DNS; the name used should not pattern-match anything generic and ideally would include a DNS label of &lt;code&gt;mail&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;mx&lt;/code&gt; or the like in it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MX record, always.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accurate SPF;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;ideally not too broad; pay attention to SPF's query limits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;avoid &lt;code&gt;-all&lt;/code&gt; at the end because, with the sole exception of “this domain never sends email” records, the larger operators have metrics to show that using &lt;code&gt;-all&lt;/code&gt; &lt;em&gt;tends&lt;/em&gt; to be a sign of over-enthusiasm rather than reality, so it will slightly count against you;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;remember to have an SPF record for your &lt;code&gt;HELO&lt;/code&gt; hostname, because when you send a “bounce” rejection, this is the thing which will be looked up (since there's no domain in &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DKIM set up, with thought towards the selector namespace.
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;RSA2048 key is effectively a hard-requirement
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;DNS TXT records consist of one or more DNS strings, each of which is limited to 255 ASCII characters. For a key of this size, you will end up needing two DNS strings in the zonefile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ed25519 keys are not yet widely supported, but by now are not likely to actively break and make things worse for you, if you dual-sign. This needs to be a different selector.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Note that for various good reasons you should design this to be something you routinely rotate.
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Some folks use yearly, some monthly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I rotate every three months.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DMARC record; see &lt;a href=&quot;https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc7489&quot; title=&quot;Domain-based Message Authentication, Reporting, and Conformance (DMARC)&quot;&gt;RFC 7489&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;But for domains which humans send from &lt;em&gt;don't&lt;/em&gt; use &lt;code&gt;p=quarantine&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;p=reject&lt;/code&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do consider setting up a receiver for reports, just so that you can see how much of a privacy breach DMARC reporting is when you send to mailing-lists which don't re-sign. :-/&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TLS certificate from a CA in the main trust anchor bundles;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Just use Let's Encrypt.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MTA-STS web-server with HTTPS certificate from the same CA, and the relevant MTA-STS txt file in place; add the DNS record when it's up and happy. See &lt;a href=&quot;https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc8461&quot; title=&quot;SMTP MTA Strict Transport Security (MTA-STS)&quot;&gt;RFC 8461&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For the independent mail providers using the stuff broadly supported in open source MTAs, you should look at DNSSEC, because the patterns here are less susceptible to rent-seeking pressures:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;DNSSEC-signed zone for your own domain
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Use whichever signing algorithm CloudFlare are currently using: this should be both current for cryptography and widely enough supported that if it's not supported by someone's resolver, then they have bigger problems than just your domain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DNSSEC validating resolver for you to look up records of others (consider &lt;a href=&quot;https://nlnetlabs.nl/projects/unbound/about/&quot;&gt;Unbound&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.knot-resolver.cz/&quot;&gt;Knot Resolver&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DANE records for your own domain (TLSA records in DNS)
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;See &lt;a href=&quot;https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc7672&quot; title=&quot;SMTP Security via Opportunistic DNS-Based Authentication of Named Entities (DANE) Transport Layer Security (TLS)&quot;&gt;RFC 7672&lt;/a&gt; for the SMTP details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;See &lt;a href=&quot;https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc6698&quot; title=&quot;The DNS-Based Authentication of Named Entities (DANE) Transport Layer Security (TLS) Protocol: TLSA&quot;&gt;RFC 6698&lt;/a&gt; for the base spec with &lt;a href=&quot;https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc7218&quot; title=&quot;Adding Acronyms to Simplify Conversations about DNS-Based Authentication of Named Entities (DANE)&quot;&gt;RFC 7218&lt;/a&gt; for some common acronyms which make talking about it easier.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;See &lt;a href=&quot;https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc7671&quot; title=&quot;The DNS-Based Authentication of Named Entities (DANE) Protocol: Updates and Operational Guidance&quot;&gt;RFC 7671&lt;/a&gt; for the updates and operational guidance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are other RFCs, for SRV records and for OpenPGP, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tell your mail-server to obey DANE stuff, so that if there's a TLSA record in DNSSEC-verified DNS then the mail-server can disable fallback to cleartext for delivery to MX (and ideally also then verify the TLS connection has a cert chain which is anchored in one of the TLSA records)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dnsviz.net&quot;&gt;https://dnsviz.net&lt;/a&gt; is your friend&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;_smtp._tls&lt;/code&gt; record so you can get reports of TLS failures sending to you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seeing if you can get your IP onto one of the open DNS-based allow-lists (also called “whitelists” but some folks are moving away from that term), such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dnswl.org/&quot;&gt;https://www.dnswl.org/&lt;/a&gt; or Spamhaus's SWL.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Periodically check if you appear in any DNS-based deny-lists.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure you're not sending from “ISP residential address-space”; if need be route your mail outbound via a host in better address-space (and update SPF etc to match)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don't do sender call-out verification to SMTP servers which aren't yours.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For your own sanity, do make sure you set up &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fail2ban.org/&quot;&gt;fail2ban&lt;/a&gt;, or something like it, scanning your mail-server logs, because SMTP AUTH online cracking is widespread. If they ever get in, your deliverability will be negatively impacted by their spam campaign through your mail-server.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;convenience-stuff&quot;&gt;Convenience Stuff&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outside of “Phil's BCP” above, additional non-deliverability but convenience options include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;DNS SRV records for submission(s)/imap(s)/pop3(s)/sieve, even if just to say with «&lt;code&gt;0 0 0 .&lt;/code&gt;» that it's not supported.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If your communications base includes people using OpenPGP with email, then set up WKD to publish OpenPGP keys for your domain too.
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;This is just a fixed schema for laying out keys for HTTPS retrieval.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;See the &lt;a href=&quot;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-koch-openpgp-webkey-service/?include_text=1&quot; title=&quot;OpenPGP Web Key Directory&quot;&gt;WKD draft&lt;/a&gt; for details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I wrote &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/PennockTech/openpgpkey-control&quot;&gt;https://github.com/PennockTech/openpgpkey-control&lt;/a&gt; as a management framework for an organization; the &lt;code&gt;other/standalone-update-website&lt;/code&gt; script is designed to be embeddable into an existing site-building workflow without anything else from the repository.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The GnuPG project has tooling available which manages the WKD layout as an email-integrated workflow, for people to update their own keys.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If your communications base includes people using S/MIME then set up SMIMEA records in your DNSSEC-signed DNS.
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;They look a lot like TLSA records; both are trust anchors in DNS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;See &lt;a href=&quot;https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc8162&quot; title=&quot;Using Secure DNS to Associate Certificates with Domain Names for S/MIME&quot;&gt;RFC 8162&lt;/a&gt; for details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The moment you start specifying “must be TLS-secured” it's worth adding &lt;code&gt;CAA&lt;/code&gt; records into DNS, so that Certificate Authorities which are broadly trusted will refuse to issue for your domain unless you list them.
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;See &lt;a href=&quot;https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc8659&quot; title=&quot;DNS Certification Authority Authorization (CAA) Resource Record&quot;&gt;RFC 8659&lt;/a&gt; for details&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The values checked by each Certificate Authority as indicating they have permission are required to be listed in their Certification Practice Statement, as part of the CA/Browser forum's Baseline Requirements. If it's missing, then browsers are not supposed to be trusting that CA.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For domain-validation CAs such as Let's Encrypt, consider adding account information to those records to tie it to your specific account. See &lt;a href=&quot;https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc8657&quot; title=&quot;Certification Authority Authorization (CAA) Record Extensions for Account URI and Automatic Certificate Management Environment (ACME) Method Binding&quot;&gt;RFC 8657&lt;/a&gt; for details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beware that at time of writing, Let's Encrypt only honors the &lt;code&gt;accounturi&lt;/code&gt; restriction in their staging environment, not their production setup; this will likely change.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remember that DNS zonefiles support comments. You'll want them here!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.libravatar.org/api/&quot;&gt;https://wiki.libravatar.org/api/&lt;/a&gt; for Gravatar-style images in some MUAs (with caching for privacy reasons); this is a fixed schema HTTPS layout and a DNS record. I think almost nobody uses this but I don't have usage figures. If you have a Claws user, perhaps?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;A lot of the DNS items above can be found in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/StackExchange/dnscontrol/blob/master/commands/test_data/example.org.zone&quot;&gt;sample DNS zonefile&lt;/a&gt; contributed to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackexchange.github.io/dnscontrol/&quot;&gt;DNSControl&lt;/a&gt; project for their regression test suite, after my production zone broke their converters. DNS hosting platforms which try to over-simplify will make some of the above hard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've written this as a reply so it's the stuff I can remember / spot now, so I might be missing something big or “too obvious to me”. Other tech exists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;footer class=&quot;article-categories&quot;&gt;Categories: &lt;span class=&quot;category-tag&quot;&gt;SMTP&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;category-tag&quot;&gt;email&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;category-tag&quot;&gt;BCP&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;category-tag&quot;&gt;DNS&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;category-tag&quot;&gt;DNSSEC&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;category-tag&quot;&gt;MTA&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;category-tag&quot;&gt;SPF&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;category-tag&quot;&gt;DKIM&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;category-tag&quot;&gt;DMARC&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;category-tag&quot;&gt;TLS&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;category-tag&quot;&gt;DANE&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;category-tag&quot;&gt;OpenPGP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/footer&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 17:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ebcase</dc:creator>
<og:title>Small Mailserver Best Current Practices</og:title>
<og:url>https://bridge.grumpy-troll.org/2020/07/small-mailserver-bcp/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://bridge.grumpy-troll.org/2020/07/small-mailserver-bcp/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Publishing thousands of police discipline records that New York kept secret</title>
<link>https://www.propublica.org/article/nypd-civilian-complaint-review-board-editors-note</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.propublica.org/article/nypd-civilian-complaint-review-board-editors-note</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;top-notes&quot; readability=&quot;5.6178571428571&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;note&quot; id=&quot;newsletter-txt-note&quot; readability=&quot;6.9142857142857&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ProPublica is a nonprofit newsroom that investigates abuses of power. Sign up to receive &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.propublica.org/newsletters/the-big-story?source=www.propublica.org&amp;amp;placement=top-note&amp;amp;region=national&quot;&gt;our biggest stories&lt;/a&gt; as soon as they’re published.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;1.0&quot;&gt;Until last month, New York state prohibited the release of police officers’ disciplinary records. Civilians’ complaints of abuse by officers were a secret. So were investigators’ conclusions. The public couldn’t even know if an officer was punished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;1.1&quot;&gt;The New York City police officer whose use of a prohibited chokehold led to the death of Eric Garner in 2014 had a record of misconduct. Garner’s last words — “I can’t breathe” — became a rallying cry for the Black Lives Matter movement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;1.2&quot;&gt;The city investigator who &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.thinkprogress.org/daniel-pantaleo-records-75833e6168f3/&quot;&gt;revealed&lt;/a&gt; the existence of the officer’s record was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nydailynews.com/new-york/ccrb-worker-forced-quit-info-leak-killed-garner-article-1.3007427&quot;&gt;forced to resign&lt;/a&gt; in 2017; the officer himself wasn’t &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nydailynews.com/new-york/nyc-crime/nym-pantaleo-chokehold-garner-oneill-decision-20190819-andrfsleevgu7jn4nybyzx2eim-story.html&quot;&gt;fired&lt;/a&gt; until 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;1.3&quot;&gt;When the death of George Floyd and footage of his pleas for his life ignited worldwide protests, activists in New York renewed their push to repeal the statute that kept disciplinary records under wraps, known as 50-a. State lawmakers finally acted, voting to repeal the provision, which had been on the books for decades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;1.4&quot;&gt;Soon after, ProPublica asked New York’s Civilian Complaint Review Board, or CCRB, for a list of officers, along with the complaints against them, and what discipline, if any, had been recommended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;1.5&quot;&gt;Today, we are making this information public and, with it, providing an unprecedented picture of civilians’ complaints of abuse by NYPD officers as well as the limits of the current system that is supposed to hold officers accountable. We’ve published a &lt;a href=&quot;https://projects.propublica.org/nypd-ccrb/&quot;&gt;database that lets you search the police complaints&lt;/a&gt; so you can see the information for yourself. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.propublica.org/datastore/dataset/civilian-complaints-against-new-york-city-police-officers&quot;&gt;Data experts can also download the data&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside data-pp-id=&quot;2&quot; data-pp-blocktype=&quot;promo&quot; class=&quot;promo large left&quot;&gt;&lt;h3 class=&quot;aside-head&quot;&gt;Search Thousands of Civilian Complaints Against New York City Police Officers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;story-entry section-externals&quot; readability=&quot;23.28506097561&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;lead-art&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;aspect-3-2&quot; href=&quot;https://projects.propublica.org/nypd-ccrb/&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://assets-c3.propublica.org/images/externals/_threeTwo400w/20200725-ccrb-nypd-look-up-app-3x2-c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;267&quot; srcset=&quot;https://assets-c3.propublica.org/images/externals/_threeTwo400w/20200725-ccrb-nypd-look-up-app-3x2-c.jpg 400w, https://assets-c3.propublica.org/images/externals/_threeTwo800w/20200725-ccrb-nypd-look-up-app-3x2-c.jpg 800w, https://assets-c3.propublica.org/images/externals/_threeTwo1200w/20200725-ccrb-nypd-look-up-app-3x2-c.jpg 1200w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 1720px) 335px, (min-width: 960px) calc(18.38vw + 23px), (min-width: 780px) 18.75vw, (min-width: 600px) 27.5vw, 43.21vw&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;3.0&quot;&gt;The database lists active-duty officers who’ve had at least one allegation against them substantiated by the CCRB: That’s about 4,000 officers out of the NYPD’s 36,000-member force.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;3.1&quot;&gt;Unions for city police officers, firefighters and corrections officers have sued New York City to stop the disclosure of most of these and other disciplinary records. The unions &lt;a href=&quot;https://gothamist.com/news/police-and-fire-unions-sue-block-disciplinary-records-public&quot;&gt;objected&lt;/a&gt; to the release of any cases other than “proven and final disciplinary matters.” That would exclude the vast majority of complaints against officers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;3.2&quot;&gt;“We are defending privacy, integrity and the unsullied reputations of thousands of hard-working public safety employees,” a union spokesman &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pix11.com/news/local-news/cops-fire-correction-unions-sue-de-blasio-administration-over-release-of-disciplinary-records&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; on the filing of the lawsuit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;3.3&quot;&gt;On Wednesday, a federal judge issued a temporary restraining order, blocking the city, including the CCRB, from releasing disciplinary records. Judge Katherine Polk Failla also barred the New York Civil Liberties Union from disclosing data it had obtained. ProPublica has not been a party to the case and is not subject to the order by Failla, who has scheduled a hearing for next month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;newsletter small left&quot; readability=&quot;1.6531791907514&quot;&gt;&lt;h3 class=&quot;newsletter-head&quot;&gt;Get Our Top Investigations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subscribe to the Big Story newsletter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;5.0&quot;&gt;In releasing the information included in our database, ProPublica is not publishing all complaints against officers. As we’ve noted, we’ve limited the data to only those officers who’ve had at least one substantiated allegation. And every complaint in the database was fully investigated by the CCRB, which means, among other steps, a civilian provided a sworn statement to investigators. We’ve also excluded any allegations that investigators concluded were unfounded, meaning investigators determined the incident did not happen as the complainant alleged. There were about 3,200 allegations listed as unfounded in the data we were provided, about 9% of the total.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;5.1&quot;&gt;We chose to include the basic information disclosed by the CCRB about allegations that investigators deemed unsubstantiated. Unsubstantiated means the CCRB — which has limited investigative powers — was not able to confirm that the alleged incident happened and that it violated the NYPD’s rules. Still, these records can help readers examine the records of officers who have been the subject of a pattern of complaints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;5.2&quot;&gt;“We understand the arguments against releasing this data. But we believe the public good it could do outweighs the potential harm,” said Stephen Engelberg, ProPublica’s editor in chief. “The database gives the people of New York City a glimpse at how allegations involving police misconduct have been handled, and allows journalists and ordinary citizens alike to look more deeply at the records of particular officers.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;ad-300&quot;&gt;

&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;7.0&quot;&gt;The CCRB receives thousands of complaints every year, but it is only able to substantiate a tiny fraction of them. In 2018, the agency examined about 3,000 allegations of misuse of force. It substantiated 73.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;7.1&quot;&gt;Investigators are often not able to reach conclusions on cases, in significant part because they must rely on the NYPD to hand over evidence, such as footage from body-worn cameras. Often, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.propublica.org/article/the-nypd-isnt-giving-critical-bodycam-footage-to-officials-investigating-alleged-abuse&quot;&gt;the department doesn’t do so&lt;/a&gt;, despite a legal &lt;a href=&quot;https://www1.nyc.gov/assets/ccrb/downloads/pdf/about_pdf/nyc_ccrb_charter.pdf&quot;&gt;duty to cooperate&lt;/a&gt; with CCRB investigations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;7.2&quot;&gt;In other cases included in our database, investigators concluded that what a civilian alleged &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; happen, but the conduct was allowed by the NYPD’s rules. The Police Department’s guidelines often give officers substantial discretion, particularly around use of force. In the curious jargon of police oversight, those cases are classified as “exonerated.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;7.3&quot;&gt;“I exonerated tons of cases that involved awful conduct that fell within the guidelines,” said former CCRB investigator Dan Bodah, who now researches police oversight at the Vera Institute of Justice. “It’s kind of haunting. The law and policy gives cops a lot of discretion.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;7.4&quot;&gt;Despite all the limitations, some officers still have multiple allegations against them that have been substantiated. According to the records, 303 officers still working at the NYPD have had five or more substantiated allegations against them. The data we have only shows the briefest of descriptions of alleged abuse. Usually just a few words. But they add up: There are nearly 5,000 allegations of “&lt;a href=&quot;https://projects.propublica.org/nypd-ccrb/allegations/force-physical-force&quot;&gt;physical force&lt;/a&gt;,” nearly 2,000 of “&lt;a href=&quot;https://projects.propublica.org/nypd-ccrb/allegations/abuse-of-authority-frisk&quot;&gt;frisk&lt;/a&gt;” and more than 600 of “&lt;a href=&quot;https://projects.propublica.org/nypd-ccrb/allegations/force-gun-pointed&quot;&gt;gun pointed&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;7.5&quot;&gt;Readers can use the information in the database to request details on cases from the CCRB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;7.6&quot;&gt;And, even without those further details — which the CCRB is currently barred from releasing because of the order by Failla — users can look at the records and see potential patterns of abuse. Thirty-four officers have had 40 or more allegations against them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;figure-head&quot;&gt;Help Us Hold the NYPD Accountable&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tell us about your experience with the NYPD. Did you have an interaction with a certain officer that bothered you? Do certain cops have a reputation in your neighborhood? Have you ever filed a complaint? Have you ever been harassed and wanted to file a complaint but didn’t? Are you a police officer who’s tried to call out misconduct? &lt;a href=&quot;https://propublica.forms.fm/help-us-hold-nypd-accountable/forms/8128&quot;&gt;We want to hear from you&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;topics-list&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Filed under:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 15:43:11 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jbegley</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.propublica.org/article/nypd-civilian-complaint-review-board-editors-note</og:url>
<og:title>We’re Publishing Thousands of Police Discipline Records That New York Kept Secret for Decades</og:title>
<og:description>ProPublica obtained these police records from New York City’s Civilian Complaint Review Board. NYPD unions are suing to halt the city from making the data public.</og:description>
<og:image>https://assets-c3.propublica.org/images/articles/_1200x630_crop_center-center_82_none/20200726-ccrb-editors-note-1200x630.jpg?mtime=1595766986</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.propublica.org/article/nypd-civilian-complaint-review-board-editors-note</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>New ‘Meow’ attack has deleted almost 4k unsecured databases</title>
<link>https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/new-meow-attack-has-deleted-almost-4-000-unsecured-databases/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/new-meow-attack-has-deleted-almost-4-000-unsecured-databases/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Wiper&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; src=&quot;https://www.bleepstatic.com/content/hl-images/2019/10/03/Data_Wiper_Shredder_Malware.jpg&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;07/25 Update added below. This post was originally published on July 22nd, 2020.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hundreds of unsecured databases exposed on the public web are the target of an automated 'meow' attack that destroys data without any explanation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The activity started recently by hitting Elasticsearch and MongoDB instances without leaving any explanation, or even a ransom note. Attacks then expanded to other database types and to file systems open on the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A quick search by BleepingComputer on the IoT search engine Shodan initially found dozens of databases that have been affected by this attack. Recently, the number of wiped databases increased to over 1,800.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These attacks have pushed researchers into a race to find the exposed databases and report them responsibly before they become 'meowed.'&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Cat's out of the bag&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the first publicly known examples of a Meow attack is an Elasticsearch database belonging to a VPN provider that claimed not to keep any logs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discovered by researcher &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MayhemDayOne&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Bob Diachenko&lt;/a&gt;, the database was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.comparitech.com/blog/vpn-privacy/ufo-vpn-data-exposure/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;initially secured&lt;/a&gt; in July only to become exposed again five days later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second time, though, the owner no longer received a well-intended notification. Instead, they got ‘meowed,’ with almost all records getting wiped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://www.bleepstatic.com/images/news/u/1100723/2020%20Misc/ufo-vpn-2nd-exposure.jpg&quot; width=&quot;984&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diachenko told BleepingComputer that there are not many details about the attacker or the purpose of their actions. He says that the attack appears to be an automated script that “overwrites or destroys the data completely.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researchers first observed the ‘meow’ database attacks at the beginning of the week. They could be the work of a vigilante trying to give administrators a hard lesson in security by raining destruction on unsecured data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Victor Gevers, the chairman of the non-profit GDI Foundation, saw this type of attack, too. He says that the actor is also attacking exposed MongoDB databases, hitting as much as they can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;336&quot; src=&quot;https://www.bleepstatic.com/images/news/u/1100723/2020%20Misc/MongoDB_Meow-VicGev-ed.png&quot; width=&quot;780&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He also saw the first ‘meow’ attacks a few days ago, with a recent one occurring on July 22, just a couple of hours after a GDI volunteer disclosed it responsibly to the owner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researcher observed on Thursday that whoever is behind the 'meow' attack is apparently targeting any database that is insecure and reachable over the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He saw these data-wiping attacks on systems running Cassandra, CouchDB, Redis, Hadoop, Jenkins, as well as against network-attached storage devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time of writing, BleepingComputer saw that 'meow' attacks impacted mostly Elasticsearch databases (1,395), followed by MongoDB (383), and Redis (54). This amounts to 1,832 but the real figure is higher as search engines start indexing the other database types. We will update the numbers when we get result for other database types.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href=&quot;https://leakix.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;LeakIX&lt;/a&gt;, a project that indexes open services, Apache ZooKeeper has been added on the list of &quot;meow&quot; attacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;07/25 Update:&lt;/em&gt; The Meow attacks continue to escalate with almost 4,000 databases deleted as of Saturday, July 25th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new search on Saturday using Shodan shows that more than 3,800 databases have entry names matching the 'meow' attack. More than 97% of them are Elastic and MongoDB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it is still not known why the threat actors are wiping databases, a security researcher named &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/anthrax0&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Anthr@X&lt;/a&gt; discovered that the attacks are being conducted via ProtonVPN IP addresses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/anthrax0/status/1286550353995956225&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Tweet&quot; height=&quot;550&quot; src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==&quot; width=&quot;526&quot; data-src=&quot;https://www.bleepstatic.com/images/news/security/attacks/m/meow/meow-tweet.jpg&quot; class=&quot;b-lazy&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Obstructing researchers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If behind these incidents are positive intentions, sometimes nothing good comes out of them and valuable data that could be lost in the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data leaks from unsecured MongoDB and Elasticsearch instances reachable over the public internet are on a descending curve, but there is still some “very sensitive” information exposed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Gevers puts it, “some leaks bring bad things to the light, which need to be shared,” and wiping them brings benefits to no one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cat_quote&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It is becoming a race to find these leaks as early as possible. This reduces the amount of time that can be spent on researching and reporting” - Victor Gevers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whoever is behind the 'meow' attacks is likely to keep on targeting unsecured databases, aggressively destroying them. Administrators should make sure that they expose only what needs to be exposed and make sure the assets are properly secured.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update [July 25, 2020]&lt;/strong&gt;: Added image with overall status of 'meow' attacks from LeakIX. Recalculated amount of deleted databases due to Meow attacks.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 14:58:56 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>based2</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/new-meow-attack-has-deleted-almost-4-000-unsecured-databases/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>New ‘Meow’ attack has deleted almost 4,000 unsecured databases</og:title>
<og:description>Dozens of unsecured databases exposed on the public web are the target of an automated 'meow' attack that wipes data without any explanation.</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.bleepstatic.com/content/hl-images/2019/10/03/Data_Wiper_Shredder_Malware.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/new-meow-attack-has-deleted-almost-4-000-unsecured-databases/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Headphones are collecting too much personal data (2019)</title>
<link>https://www.soundguys.com/headphones-are-collecting-too-much-personal-data-21524/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.soundguys.com/headphones-are-collecting-too-much-personal-data-21524/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Trading personal data for useful software features is nothing new, but do we really need them in headphones? One of the biggest ongoing debates in tech right now is regarding privacy. There’s a lot of money in data aggregation, and while companies like Google have done a decent job at showing how all of that data can be put to practical use (i.e the Assistant), others don’t seem to be making as strong a case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What kind of personal data are they collecting?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This became apparent when I was recently reviewing the Soul Run Free Pro fitness earbuds which come with an associated app to help users get the most out of them. Granted, the earbuds in question are marketed to runners and are supposed to provide exceptional biometric data and feedback to help improve everything from your posture to your gait, so I was expecting to have to accept a privacy policy or two. That said, I found myself clicking “Accept” a few &lt;em&gt;too&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;many&lt;/em&gt; times. I eventually decided to actually read what I was agreeing to, which led to this article.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_21593&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/PrivacySoul-1.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img aria-describedby=&quot;caption-attachment-21593&quot; class=&quot;size-large wp-image-21593&quot; src=&quot;https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/PrivacySoul-1-1024x576.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Close-up of an agree button.&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;576&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/PrivacySoul-1-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/PrivacySoul-1-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/PrivacySoul-1-768x432.jpg 768w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/PrivacySoul-1-16x9.jpg 16w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/PrivacySoul-1-32x18.jpg 32w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/PrivacySoul-1-28x16.jpg 28w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/PrivacySoul-1-56x32.jpg 56w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/PrivacySoul-1-64x36.jpg 64w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/PrivacySoul-1-712x400.jpg 712w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/PrivacySoul-1-1000x563.jpg 1000w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/PrivacySoul-1-1200x675.jpg 1200w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/PrivacySoul-1-560x315.jpg 560w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/PrivacySoul-1-365x205.jpg 365w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/PrivacySoul-1-818x460.jpg 818w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/PrivacySoul-1-711x400.jpg 711w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/PrivacySoul-1-418x235.jpg 418w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/PrivacySoul-1.jpg 1920w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;caption-attachment-21593&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Be mindful of what you’re agreeing to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides the usual information like access to height, weight, age, and sex, the app also requested a few, let’s say, rather unique bits of information. Some of the “additional information” the app collects includes things like leg length, the shoes you wear, and whether you were right or left footed. Weird, but not completely unrelated as this is technically a running app after all. Plus, the entire shtick of these headphones is that they’ve partnered with a company called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.beflex.co/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Beflex Inc&lt;/a&gt;. to provide you with next level information about your workouts. However, it gets weirder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_21589&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; readability=&quot;34&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Soul-app-privacy.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img aria-describedby=&quot;caption-attachment-21589&quot; class=&quot;size-large wp-image-21589&quot; src=&quot;https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Soul-app-privacy-1024x576.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Privacy policy of Soul Run Free Pro app. &quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;576&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Soul-app-privacy-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Soul-app-privacy-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Soul-app-privacy-768x432.jpg 768w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Soul-app-privacy-16x9.jpg 16w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Soul-app-privacy-32x18.jpg 32w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Soul-app-privacy-28x16.jpg 28w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Soul-app-privacy-56x32.jpg 56w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Soul-app-privacy-64x36.jpg 64w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Soul-app-privacy-712x400.jpg 712w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Soul-app-privacy-1000x563.jpg 1000w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Soul-app-privacy-1200x675.jpg 1200w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Soul-app-privacy-560x315.jpg 560w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Soul-app-privacy-365x205.jpg 365w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Soul-app-privacy-818x460.jpg 818w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Soul-app-privacy-711x400.jpg 711w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Soul-app-privacy-418x235.jpg 418w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Soul-app-privacy.jpg 1920w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;caption-attachment-21589&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;If you actually read the privacy policy of some of the apps you use, you might be surprised to see what’s there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The app also noted that it would collect “wellness-related information” such as alcohol usage, injury history, and even menstruation history. Yeah, &lt;em&gt;menstruation history&lt;/em&gt;.  Now I’m no lawyer, but alcohol usage, injury history, and menstruation history sound like stuff that some people might not be too keen on making public. But still, all this for a pair of workout earbuds?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Who else is doing this?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This led me down a rabbit hole of reading privacy policies from some of the biggest headphone manufacturers to see if this was an isolated incident or common practice among giant audio companies. Unfortunately, they all seem to collect data to some extent, though none are as extreme as the example of above. Most seem to only collect the basic data that you provide like name and address. That said, there was one major company that’s collecting a bit more: Bose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don’t remember, Bose already had a fairly mainstream &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.soundguys.com/bose-allegedly-tracks-your-information-and-sells-it-to-third-party-companies-12159/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;data collecting scandal&lt;/a&gt; back in 2017 where the Bose Connect app was found to be tracking what users were listening to and sending that data back to the company to be sold. Think of it like Shazam, but for all the audio that plays through your headphones. Throw in the fact that users were unaware it was even happening, and it became a pretty big deal. Although it has been two years and the heat has simmered down a bit, Bose makes it perfectly clear that this is still happening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to its official &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bose.com/en_us/legal/privacy_policy.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;privacy statement&lt;/a&gt;, which was last updated on September 10th, 2018, they’re able to collect and use this data once you hit “I Agree” during setup:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Usage data, such as time spent using different features/settings of the product, the day and time you used the product, button presses, the media and other external sources to which you connect your product, and, as applicable, your product’s power spectrum, sound pressure level, volume levels, and streaming information (including content stored on system presets, stations played, playlists, artists, albums, songs, or podcasts), time zone, and transactional data enabling digital rights management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Environmental data (e.g., noise level and audio frequencies).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_21588&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; readability=&quot;34&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Bose-Privacy.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img aria-describedby=&quot;caption-attachment-21588&quot; class=&quot;size-large wp-image-21588&quot; src=&quot;https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Bose-Privacy-1024x576.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Privacy policy screenshots of the Bose Connect app. &quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;576&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Bose-Privacy-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Bose-Privacy-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Bose-Privacy-768x432.jpg 768w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Bose-Privacy-16x9.jpg 16w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Bose-Privacy-32x18.jpg 32w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Bose-Privacy-28x16.jpg 28w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Bose-Privacy-56x32.jpg 56w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Bose-Privacy-64x36.jpg 64w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Bose-Privacy-712x400.jpg 712w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Bose-Privacy-1000x563.jpg 1000w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Bose-Privacy-1200x675.jpg 1200w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Bose-Privacy-560x315.jpg 560w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Bose-Privacy-365x205.jpg 365w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Bose-Privacy-818x460.jpg 818w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Bose-Privacy-711x400.jpg 711w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Bose-Privacy-418x235.jpg 418w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Bose-Privacy.jpg 1920w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;caption-attachment-21588&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;While Bose does still collect, opting out is always an option by clicking Menu &amp;gt; Privacy. Or you can just opt out from the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, right after this section, Bose does state in bold lettering that you can opt out whenever you want. They’ve even made the process relatively straightforward and at any point in their app, you’re never more than two clicks away from reading their privacy policy and opting out. I’d prefer them not track what I’m listening to at all, but hey, credit where credit is due.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;left quote_new&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don't normally think of data collection when it comes to headphones, but it's happening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The average person might not complain about privacy because, usually, you get something worthwhile in return. If you let Google track you for a week, you’ll get updates about how long your morning commute to work is going to take. Give location access to a weather app and you might get a notification in the morning reminding you to bring an umbrella because it’s going to rain. Sure, it’s creepy if you think about it too long, but it’s dead useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the flip side, I don’t know what I get in return for letting my headphones know what I’m listening to. Furthermore, I can’t think of a single reason why a pair of workout earbuds need access to someone’s menstrual history. We should just call it what it is because, at that point, it doesn’t feel like a transaction anymore. It’s just spying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Don’t miss out!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also discussed this on the SoundGuys podcast! Check it out below, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.soundguys.com/podcast&quot;&gt;make sure to subscribe&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 14:51:26 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>teddyh</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/PrivacySoul-2.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Headphones are collecting too much personal data</og:title>
<og:description>Agree, Agree, Agree, I agree....wait</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.soundguys.com/headphones-are-collecting-too-much-personal-data-21524/</og:url>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.soundguys.com/headphones-are-collecting-too-much-personal-data-21524/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Basics of Haskell – Code and exercises</title>
<link>https://github.com/raviksharma/bartosz-basics-of-haskell</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/raviksharma/bartosz-basics-of-haskell</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/raviksharma/bartosz-basics-of-haskell&quot;&gt;https://github.com/raviksharma/bartosz-basics-of-haskell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23957388&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23957388&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 203&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 27&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 14:42:55 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>raviksharma</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars2.githubusercontent.com/u/600723?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>raviksharma/bartosz-basics-of-haskell</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/raviksharma/bartosz-basics-of-haskell</og:url>
<og:description>Code and exercises from Bartosz Milewski's Basics of Haskell Tutorial - raviksharma/bartosz-basics-of-haskell</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/raviksharma/bartosz-basics-of-haskell</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A Surprise AWS Bill</title>
<link>https://chrisshort.net/the-aws-bill-heard-around-the-world/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://chrisshort.net/the-aws-bill-heard-around-the-world/</guid>
<description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;scene&quot;&gt;Scene&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was a bright, Saturday morning, July 4, 2020. I had just gotten Max all situated with breakfast and cartoons (Mighty Mike, if you’re curious). Julie was sleeping in like she usually does on every day I have off. I’m an early riser and this is a cherished part of our co-parenting. It gives Max and I time to bond (when he’s not stuffing his face and laughing at cartoons). I sat down with my laptop to plow through the week’s personal email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-e-mail&quot;&gt;The e-mail&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Oh look, the AWS bill, I should have a laugh at that,” I thought to myself. Until recently, it had been pennies a month for some very light SES usage. In February, I moved off Google Cloud back to AWS. The primary motivation was that Google had so intertwined GSuite and GCP IAM that it became overly confusing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with that migration came the CDN for this web site (cdn.chrisshort.net). I mean &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrisshort.net/low-cost-content-delivery-network-cdn/&quot;&gt;a Cloudflare fronted S3 bucket that holds assets deemed too big for git&lt;/a&gt; when I say CDN. It’s not even &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrisshort.net&quot;&gt;chrisshort.net&lt;/a&gt; itself, as it is hosted on Netlify’s CDN and every other static site I own or manage. I’ve been a Cloudflare user for a long time. The CDN is less than 300 files and has existed for over five years on various clouds. Moving it back to AWS from GCP bumped the AWS bill to an average of $23/month. Not too bad given the &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.usefathom.com/share/suwvjwwc/chrisshort.net&quot;&gt;site’s traffic&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-shock&quot;&gt;The shock&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not on this Saturday morning, nope. June 2020’s AWS bill was a heart palpitation causing &lt;strong&gt;$2,657.68&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://chrisshort.net/the-aws-bill-heard-around-the-world/invoice498711077_redacted.jpg&quot;&gt;JPG&lt;/a&gt;). I audibly gasped, “Keep your shit together.” I thought to myself. Max was leaned up against me drinking his milk. I know he could tell something was wrong because he looked at the laptop screen. I only assume when he saw letters and numbers, he thought, “Adult stuff… These cartoons and this Cinnamon Toast Crunch tho.” 2020 being the year that it is and my military history being what it is, I’ve been diagnosed with a panic disorder (on top of the PTSD and physical injuries).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-panic&quot;&gt;The panic&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot; readability=&quot;5.1428571428571&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Good morning, $2700 AWS bill!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Holy shit...&lt;/p&gt;
— Chris Short (@ChrisShort) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ChrisShort/status/1279406322837082114?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;July 4, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I immediately began having a panic attack. As I took the mental steps to mitigate the onset of the panic attack, I started forming a battle plan. Yes, I can switch back to emergency mode, like back in the old days, when something would go bang or boom, and I’d run towards it (it’s not helpful overall, trust me).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, Max: Maslow’s Hierarchy of Needs? Check.&lt;br/&gt;Next, me: As if it was destined, my alert for morning medications went off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Daddy’s gotta grab his meds, bud.” Instinctively, Max leans off me (wow… okay… he’s used to hearing that reminder and statement shortly after that; my brain is now in overdrive). I take everything I need to conquer this while still being able to function cognitively. I refill my coffee and grab a laptop charger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;incident-response&quot;&gt;Incident response&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check the source of truth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s diverged?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do we get things back to normal?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I login to the AWS console, hoping I got some output that was uniquely off this month. Weirder stuff has happened (like &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/message/41926/&quot;&gt;S3 going down&lt;/a&gt;). This bill couldn’t be more out of the norm than ever. This AWS bill is several hundred dollars more than our mortgage! I hit the AWS Billing page and am deeply saddened by what I see:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/1f2dd17bc5d8e1407c22b84f7f981a7ad9888eba/8e235/the-aws-bill-heard-around-the-world/aws-bill-landing-page.png&quot; alt=&quot;AWS Billing landing page showing a $2,657.68 balance&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There it was. &lt;strong&gt;$2,657.68&lt;/strong&gt;, staring at me. “This can’t be legit.” Drilling down even further, it looks like it is indeed legitimate traffic from the cdn.chrisshort.net S3 bucket in us-east-2. In total, &lt;strong&gt;more than 30.6 terabytes of traffic&lt;/strong&gt; had moved out of that one S3 bucket. WHEN?!? Did this just happen? Nope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/3373f05e910b0938aeed4a2975b4b4f48922fdc0/2e223/the-aws-bill-heard-around-the-world/aws-june-2020-data-transfer.png&quot; alt=&quot;AWS data transfer billing break down&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/46294144a86a5d64df074d306386b3024b7d882a/af2d6/the-aws-bill-heard-around-the-world/june-23-24-2020-s3-breakdown.png&quot; alt=&quot;S3 Activity&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;30.6 TB?!?!&lt;/strong&gt; how is that even possible???&lt;br/&gt;$1,011.59 on 23 June 2020.&lt;br/&gt;$1,639.07 on 24 June 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I immediately open a ticket with AWS Support frantically wondering what broke? How is this even possible? Did someone bypass Cloudflare? What the hell is Cloudflare saying?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/6cd3322753f262dc51bbca44a07fef6b19b381e9/52aec/the-aws-bill-heard-around-the-world/cloudflare_june_22_2020.png&quot; alt=&quot;Cloudflare 22 June 2020&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Oh cool, Cloudflare let those 2,700 requests passthrough completely uncached? How is that not anomaly detected as a DDoS??? How is it that barely a fraction of the traffic is cached (more on that later)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/a0f7d1526c44cb74baba13f749f3d5a886bbdadb/6d2b1/the-aws-bill-heard-around-the-world/cloudflare_june_23_2020.png&quot; alt=&quot;Cloudflare 23 June 2020&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Oh, another 4,400 requests the next day… Sweet, baby Jesus. Oh, but you served 9 GB from cache. Thanks, Cloudflare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;help-arrives&quot;&gt;Help Arrives&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently, when you tweet something crazy af, like a $2700 AWS bill, it gets a lot of attention on a quiet holiday morning. A quarter-million people saw the tweet and a third of them interacted with it. It was enough attention that the AWS Support Twitter account was on it before, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/QuinnyPig/status/1186319925901586432&quot;&gt;my friend&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.duckbillgroup.com/&quot;&gt;cloud economist&lt;/a&gt;, Corey Quinn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot; readability=&quot;6.8755020080321&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Oh no! 😰 Sorry to hear about this unpleasant Saturday morning surprise, Chris. Please create a support case so our agents can help get to the bottom of this: &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/weTUnSYLRU&quot;&gt;https://t.co/weTUnSYLRU&lt;/a&gt;. 🕵️‍♀️ ^HG&lt;/p&gt;
— AWS Support (@AWSSupport) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/AWSSupport/status/1279424879566163970?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;July 4, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;Praise Twitter for at least its ability to draw attention to things. I am not sure this would’ve ended up as well as it did without it.
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot; readability=&quot;2.4324324324324&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;und&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/tUrNnXqWMY&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/tUrNnXqWMY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
— HydroxyCoreyQuinn (@QuinnyPig) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/QuinnyPig/status/1279446759664611329?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;July 4, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;I forwarded the bill to Corey almost immediately after seeing it at pre-dawn west coast time. I am forever thankful to Corey for his analysis. When he was ready, Corey sent me a list of things he needed to do an analysis (instead, I created him a regular IAM account with the proper perms 😉 and yes I cleaned up after).
&lt;p&gt;Corey encouraged me to apply a bucket policy that would only allow Cloudflare IP addresses to access anything from the bucket. The theory here is that someone could have been bypassing Cloudflare somehow. But, thankfully, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cloudflare.com/ips/&quot;&gt;Cloudflare publishes their IP blocks&lt;/a&gt; and they don’t change all that often. The Cloudflare support article, &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.cloudflare.com/hc/en-us/articles/360037983412-Configuring-an-Amazon-Web-Services-static-site-to-use-Cloudflare#77nNxWyQf69T1a78gPlCi9&quot;&gt;Configuring an Amazon Web Services static site to use Cloudflare&lt;/a&gt; gives you an example bucket policy to do exactly that. This should become a standard practice for folks. However, it wouldn’t have mattered in this case; more on that later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Corey Quinn’s thread on the topic covers what happened on the AWS side pretty well:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot; readability=&quot;3.5454545454545&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;That's right--it's threading time!&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ChrisShort?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@chrisshort&lt;/a&gt;'s surprise &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/awscloud?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@awscloud&lt;/a&gt; bill of $2700 looks S3 driven... &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/VnXufn24iA&quot;&gt;https://t.co/VnXufn24iA&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/tKLWv5rHtW&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/tKLWv5rHtW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
— HydroxyCoreyQuinn (@QuinnyPig) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/QuinnyPig/status/1280280727133642753?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;July 6, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;”…it’s almost entirely due to us-east-2 data transfer out…”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Now, what caused this? Nobody knows!”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Chris Short isn’t some random fool…” (Might be the nicest thing Corey’s every said about anyone he’s not related to)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;”‘Surprise jackhole, your mortgage isn’t your most expensive bill this month, guess you shoulda enabled billing alarms!’ is crappy, broken, and WOULD NOT HAVE SOLVED THE PROBLEM!”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/QuinnyPig/status/1280289410844471296?s=20&quot;&gt;“I want to be explicitly clear here: Chris Short didn’t do anything wrong!”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;but-wait-there-s-more&quot;&gt;But wait! There’s more!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had tickets in with Cloudflare (1918916) and AWS (7153956931). Cloudflare was the least helpful service I could have imagined given the circumstances. A long term user and on and off customer thinks they were attacked for two days and you don’t lift a finger? If I didn’t have reason enough to move off of Cloudflare, I do now. That’ll be an update for a later blog post. But, if you work for a CDN company and you’re relatively painless to get up and running, I’m interested in hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a very chaotic morning, I take Corey’s advice, disconnect, and enjoy the holiday weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;more-help-arrives&quot;&gt;More Help Arrives&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On July 8th, an astute AWS employee starts doing some digging around and reaches out to me. Because they see this as bafflingly as Corey and I do. How did so few requests generate so much traffic so quickly and then as soon as it appears, it’s gone again? It doesn’t seem like something intentionally malicious either because Cloudflare and AWS let it right on through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;here-s-the-theory&quot;&gt;Here’s the theory&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In hindsight, I made a poor decision to distribute a trial Windows 2019 SQL Server virtual machine images (fully patched with all necessary drivers and VM extensions) in the form of a qcow2 file. Someone became aware of the existence of this VM image. They then stood up hundreds, potentially thousands, of copies this VM using the internet accessible URL. This is, in theory, possible, with something like &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrisshort.net/tags/kubernetes/&quot;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://kubevirt.io/&quot;&gt;Kubevirt&lt;/a&gt;. Given that the disk image becomes a volume mount in the corresponding VMs pod. Spin up enough copies of the VM, a single YAML file can create infinite copies of a VM. If the YAML definition directly referenced the Cloudflare or S3 URL and not a locally cached copy, you can rack up the number of times you pull down an image real quick. The qcow2 image, in this case, was 13.7 GB. But it’s trickier than that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-sharp-edge-of-the-cloud&quot;&gt;The sharp edge of the cloud&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;File this under, “Things I should’ve known but didn’t.” Did you know that “The maximum file size Cloudflare’s CDN caches &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.cloudflare.com/hc/en-us/articles/200172516-Understanding-Cloudflare-s-CDN#:~:text=The%20maximum%20file%20size%20Cloudflare's,request%20caching%20of%20larger%20files.&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;is 512MB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for Free, Pro, and Business customers and 5GB for Enterprise customers.” That’s right, Cloudflare saw requests for a 13.7 GB file and sent them straight to origin every time &lt;em&gt;BY DESIGN&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;Ouch!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suspected these files immediately on July 4 and moved them to an internal work GDrive for the time being. If you need the images, let me know, you’re also a suspect if you ask for them, be warned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re sitting at home doing the math, something might not be adding up. The bandwidth cost is off, there was indeed some legitimate traffic to the bucket in June, of course, But, as it turns out the intrepid AWS employee discovered that 3655 partial GETs to the object might have actually been delivered as full file requests and Cloudflare might have ever done anything with them. Yes, this is a bug somewhere and folks are looking into it. I also suggested that object size limits be a tunable S3 bucket policy. This way, I wouldn’t have even been able to upload the files to the bucket, to begin with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-resolution&quot;&gt;The Resolution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned, I’ve removed the multiple gigabyte files from the bucket the day I got the bill (July 4). &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/QuinnyPig/status/1280282363461726208&quot;&gt;Corey pointed that out here&lt;/a&gt;. That might have hindered the investigation from the AWS side. I won’t be so quick to delete in the future. I will lock files down though. But, let’s face it. Now that I’m aware of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.cloudflare.com/hc/en-us/articles/200172516-Understanding-Cloudflare-s-CDN#:~:text=The%20maximum%20file%20size%20Cloudflare's,request%20caching%20of%20larger%20files.&quot;&gt;512 MB file limit at Cloudflare&lt;/a&gt;, I am moving other larger files in that bucket to &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.org/&quot;&gt;archive.org&lt;/a&gt; for now (and will add them to my supported &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrisshort.net/causes/&quot;&gt;Causes&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long term, I won’t want to store files in multiple places. I don’t feel like archive.org should be my site’s dumping ground since it can turn a profit if it gets popular. archive.org is a stop-gap for two files for the time being. But, I could do some cleanup of that bucket now that I have proper logging enabled (oh and AWS Budget Alerts). I will also be researching user-friendly alternatives to Cloudflare even if it will cost me a few bucks a month. I will also never co-mingle work and personal file sharing EVER again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, AWS did refund all but about $40 of the $2,657.68 original bill. I wonder if I had been with any other provider (CDN included) if I had gotten a refund at all. I suspect smaller vendors wouldn’t have been as forgiving, especially given the global economic climate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;section id=&quot;social-share&quot;&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;h4 class=&quot;see-also&quot;&gt;See also&lt;/h4&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 12:40:02 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>oaf357</dc:creator>
<og:title>The AWS bill heard around the world</og:title>
<og:description>The tale of the July 4th surprise $2700 AWS bill. It is more nuanced than you think and might have exposed a bug.</og:description>
<og:image>https://chrisshort.net/the-aws-bill-heard-around-the-world/june-2020-aws-bill-header.png</og:image>
<og:url>https://chrisshort.net/the-aws-bill-heard-around-the-world</og:url>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://chrisshort.net/the-aws-bill-heard-around-the-world/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Facebook has blocked Dreamwidth</title>
<link>https://andrewducker.dreamwidth.org/3861716.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://andrewducker.dreamwidth.org/3861716.html</guid>
<description>I discovered, about an hour ago, that all of my posts on Facebook which were links to Dreamwidth had vanished. Suddenly gone as if they'd never existed.&lt;p&gt;I checked with Denise (one of the owners of Dreamwidth) to find out if she knew about it, and discovered that Facebook have stuck Dreamwidth on a block list.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With no explanation as to why, no way to contact them, and no appeal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is unbelievably frustrating. And the kind of centralised, autocratic, opaque decision making which I loathe. Tens of thousands of active users, unable to share blog posts with Facebook (which, let's face it, is where most of my friends go for their socialising).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If anyone knows anyone who works at Facebook, do see if you can prod them into getting an explanation...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Edit: All working fine now.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 12:35:24 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>AndrewDucker</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://andrewducker.dreamwidth.org/3861716.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How to effectively evade the GDPR and the reach of the DPA</title>
<link>https://blog.zoller.lu/2020/05/how-to-effectively-evade-gdpr-and-reach.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.zoller.lu/2020/05/how-to-effectively-evade-gdpr-and-reach.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;This is a post in a series of posts :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;As my regular readers know I reluctantly trust anything that isn't tested and battle proof. In the last 2 years, I applied the same logic that I apply to vulnerability research to the Data Privacy environment and proceeded to test a broad range of Data Subject Rights. Expect a few disclosures following this one.&lt;p&gt;In true Information Security Fashion (insiders will understand) have attributed this weakness the ID :&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CDPWE-0001 - Does not designate a Representative in the European Union&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I searched Google for my name an interesting website came up in the results. A company called &quot;Rocket Reach&quot; allowed others to buy access to my personal data. I was intrigued as I have never given any consent for Rocketreach to store (or even sell) my data and I saw no other legal basis for RocketReach processing of my data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Rocket Reach&quot; a data broker that describes it's service as :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot; readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Connect directly with the right decision makers, using the world's largest and most accurate database of emails and direct dials. Real-time verified data for 430 million professionals across 17 million companies, worldwide.Trusted by over 5.0 million users — powering sales, recruiting, and marketing at companies large and small.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prospect, connect and converse with your leads at scale.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Issuing a DSAR&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the &lt;strong&gt;5th of April  2019&lt;/strong&gt;, I asked Rocketreach access to my personal data (Data Subject Access Request) and asked for the purpose and the legal basis of processing. Instead of giving me access to my data and reply adequately, RocketReach decided to &lt;strong&gt;delete/remove all traces of it&lt;/strong&gt; and informed me that it did so the same day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it might be surprising to some, this is actually a common reaction to DSARs when the Data Controller realizes the data they have may have no real legal basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Filing a complaint &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the &lt;strong&gt;05th of April 2019&lt;/strong&gt;, I filed a complaint with the Luxemburgish Data Protection Agency (CNPD). The reference for this complaint is #3018 (For those that want to request information/documents from the CNPD).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Waiting for roughly a year&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&quot;We agree with you but we can't do anything, sorry, move on&quot;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the &lt;strong&gt;6th of March 2020&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;span&gt;1 year!&lt;/span&gt;) the CNPD responded as follows (Original Version on top, the Translated version at the bottom).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot; readability=&quot;48&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;FR&quot;&gt;Monsieur Zoller,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;FR&quot;&gt;La Commission nationale pour la protection des données (CNPD) se permet de revenir vers vous concernant votre réclamation du 5 avril 2019 à l’encontre de la société RocketReach.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;FR&quot;&gt;Dans le cadre de l’instruction de votre réclamation, la société RocketReach nous a communiqué qu’elle considère que ce sont les utilisateurs de ses services, et non elle-même, qui sont les responsables du traitement pour ce qui concerne les données à caractère personnel traitées sur son site internet.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;FR&quot;&gt;Par ailleurs, il ressort également de cette instruction que la société RocketReach est une société située aux Etats-Unis d’Amérique &lt;strong&gt;ne disposant pas d’un représentant dans l’Union au sens de l’article 27 du règlement général sur la protection des données (RGPD).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;FR&quot;&gt;Au sujet des responsables du traitement établis dans des pays tiers, comme les Etats-Unis d’Amérique, nous souhaitons attirer votre attention sur le considérant (116) du RGPD qui précise que:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;« &lt;em&gt;Lorsque des données à caractère personnel franchissent les frontières extérieures de l'Union, cela peut accroître le risque que les personnes physiques ne puissent exercer leurs droits liés à la protection des données, notamment pour se protéger de l'utilisation ou de la divulgation illicite de ces informations. De même, les autorités de contrôle peuvent être confrontées à l'impossibilité d'examiner des réclamations ou de mener des enquêtes sur les activités exercées en dehors de leurs frontières. Leurs efforts pour collaborer dans le contexte transfrontalier peuvent également être freinés par les pouvoirs insuffisants dont elles disposent en matière de prévention ou de recours, par l'hétérogénéité des régimes juridiques et par des obstacles pratiques tels que le manque de ressources. »&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;FR&quot;&gt;Dans le cas de votre réclamation cela signifie que, &lt;strong&gt;bien que nous ne partagions pas le point de vue de RocketReach et que nous sommes au contraire d’avis que cette société est bien à considérer comme responsable du traitement pour les traitements de données à caractère personnel effectués sur son site internet, il nous est impossible de poursuivre plus en avant le traitement de votre réclamation&lt;/strong&gt;. En effet, nous ne disposons pas des pouvoirs de mener des enquêtes et de faire appliquer les décisions que nous serions amenés à prendre sur le territoire des Etats-Unis d’Amérique.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;FR&quot;&gt;Nous sommes dès lors au regret de vous informer que nous considérons qu’il nous est impossible de poursuivre de façon effective le traitement de votre dossier. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;FR&quot;&gt;Veuillez agréer, Monsieur Zoller, l’expression de nos sentiments distingués.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;41&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;English Translation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr. Zoller,&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The National Commission for Data Protection (CNPD) would like to get back to you regarding your complaint of 5 April 2019 against the company RocketReach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rocket Reach has informed us that &lt;strong&gt;it considers that it is the users of its services, and not itself, who are responsible for processing personal data processed on its website&lt;/strong&gt;. Furthermore, it also emerges from this instruction that RocketReach is a company located in the United States of America that does not have a representative in the Union within the meaning of Article 27 of the General Regulation on Data Protection (RGPD). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As regards data controllers established in third countries, such as the United States of America, we would like to draw your attention to recital (116) of the DPMR which states that: 'When personal data crosses the external borders of the Union, this may increase the risk that individuals may not be able to exercise their data protection rights, in particular to protect themselves against unlawful use or disclosure of such information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, supervisory authorities may be faced with the impossibility to investigate complaints or activities outside their borders. Their efforts to work together in the cross-border context may also be hampered by insufficient preventive or remedial powers, heterogeneous legal regimes and practical obstacles such as lack of resources. » &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the case of your complaint, this means that, although &lt;strong&gt;we do not share RocketReach's view and to the contrary believe &lt;span&gt;that RocketReach is the data controller&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for the processing of personal data on its website, &lt;strong&gt;we are unable to take any further action in relation to your complaint.&lt;/strong&gt; We do not have the authority to investigate and enforce any decision we would have to take in the United States of America. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We regret to inform you that we consider it impossible for us to proceed with the processing of your case.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;In Summary -  Rocketreach has &lt;strong&gt;not met the requirement&lt;/strong&gt; of the GDPR to name an EU representative (Art27) to account for the processing of European Personal Data. &lt;strong&gt;In their answer, the CNPD makes it sound like it is optional, it isn't.&lt;/strong&gt; Instead of pursuing Rocketreach locally on that basis alone, the CNPD just gives up arguing it has no jurisdiction in the US.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In other words, just don't designate a representative in Europe, build your business model around the exploitation of data from millions of European data subjects and you are fine?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I  am fully aware that I could engage in legal procedures myself.  That's not in my interest (in this case). The overall question you should ask is: Do we need a European Institution that handles extra-territorial investigations and fines? &lt;strong&gt;Why should it take the time, money, and energy from an individual when the DPA is supposed to defend the rights of the data subjects&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;What the CNPD could have done according to [1]&lt;br/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;to impose a temporary or definitive limitation including a ban on processing;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;to order the suspension of data flows to a recipient in a third country or to an international organisation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;to impose an administrative fine pursuant to Article 83, in addition to, or instead of measures referred to in this paragraph, depending on the circumstances of each individual case;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;to order the controller or processor to bring processing operations into compliance with the provisions of this Regulation, where appropriate, in a specified manner and within a specified period;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;[1] &lt;a href=&quot;https://cnpd.public.lu/en/commission-nationale/pouvoirs.html&quot;&gt;https://cnpd.public.lu/en/commission-nationale/pouvoirs.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h3&gt;  &lt;/h3&gt;
Instead, Rocketreach just continues to sell the personal data of millions of European data subjects like nothing ever happened. Including all of the below :&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-z6piNinfp7c/Xs-0S2Xm-rI/AAAAAAAAA0Q/1YXUi3ANINEUhF9UJebPzPAUW8Oa2U80QCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/trophy1.PNG&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;886&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1542&quot; height=&quot;227&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-z6piNinfp7c/Xs-0S2Xm-rI/AAAAAAAAA0Q/1YXUi3ANINEUhF9UJebPzPAUW8Oa2U80QCLcBGAsYHQ/s400/trophy1.PNG&quot; width=&quot;400&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Members of the CNPD&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-KTvsmbvPPwA/Xs-0sPl_y5I/AAAAAAAAA0Y/3XeiS_j0L6EOxtVkLI2ajjTlyDiKADDIwCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/trophy2.PNG&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;798&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1521&quot; height=&quot;208&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-KTvsmbvPPwA/Xs-0sPl_y5I/AAAAAAAAA0Y/3XeiS_j0L6EOxtVkLI2ajjTlyDiKADDIwCLcBGAsYHQ/s400/trophy2.PNG&quot; width=&quot;400&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Members of the European Data Protection Board&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-LeEhjvJtgmk/Xs-1KUiVvjI/AAAAAAAAA0g/4pXoPjpjssceaGi6UJAOna8guxKQam1EACLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/trophy3.PNG&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;690&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1534&quot; height=&quot;178&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-LeEhjvJtgmk/Xs-1KUiVvjI/AAAAAAAAA0g/4pXoPjpjssceaGi6UJAOna8guxKQam1EACLcBGAsYHQ/s400/trophy3.PNG&quot; width=&quot;400&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;CNIL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;






</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 09:08:06 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>thierryzoller</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://blog.zoller.lu/2020/05/how-to-effectively-evade-gdpr-and-reach.html</og:url>
<og:title>How to effectively evade the GDPR and the reach of the DPA (CDPWE-0001)</og:title>
<og:description>Musings on Information Security and Privacy Risk Management - Thierry Zoller.</og:description>
<og:image>https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-z6piNinfp7c/Xs-0S2Xm-rI/AAAAAAAAA0Q/1YXUi3ANINEUhF9UJebPzPAUW8Oa2U80QCLcBGAsYHQ/w1200-h630-p-k-no-nu/trophy1.PNG</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.zoller.lu/2020/05/how-to-effectively-evade-gdpr-and-reach.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>WebGL Fluid Simulation</title>
<link>https://paveldogreat.github.io/WebGL-Fluid-Simulation/?play</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://paveldogreat.github.io/WebGL-Fluid-Simulation/?play</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://paveldogreat.github.io/WebGL-Fluid-Simulation/?play&quot;&gt;https://paveldogreat.github.io/WebGL-Fluid-Simulation/?play&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23955527&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23955527&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 201&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 48&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 08:47:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>maxraz</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:title>Webgl Fluid Simulation</og:title>
<og:description>A WebGL fluid simulation that works in mobile browsers.</og:description>
<og:url>https://paveldogreat.github.io/WebGL-Fluid-Simulation/</og:url>
<og:image>https://paveldogreat.github.io/WebGL-Fluid-Simulation/logo.png</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://paveldogreat.github.io/WebGL-Fluid-Simulation/?play</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Google reportedly peeks into Android data to gain edge over third-party apps</title>
<link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2020/07/android-user-data-gives-google-edge-over-third-party-apps-report-says/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2020/07/android-user-data-gives-google-edge-over-third-party-apps-report-says/</guid>
<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/android-spying-800x450.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A man laughs at his smartphone while a cartoon characters peaks over his shoulder.&quot;/&gt;&lt;aside id=&quot;social-left&quot; class=&quot;social-left&quot; aria-label=&quot;Read the comments or share this article&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;comment-count-before&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;70 posters participating, including story author&quot; class=&quot;comment-count icon-comment-bubble-down&quot; href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2020/07/android-user-data-gives-google-edge-over-third-party-apps-report-says/?comments=1&quot;&gt;reader comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;a title=&quot;70 posters participating, including story author&quot; class=&quot;comment-count icon-comment-bubble-down&quot; href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2020/07/android-user-data-gives-google-edge-over-third-party-apps-report-says/?comments=1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;comment-count-number&quot;&gt;85&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;with 70 posters participating, including story author&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;share-links&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Share this story&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Google for several years has collected app-usage data collected from Android phones to develop and advance its own competing apps, a new report alleges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project, called Android Lockbox, &quot;collects sensitive Android user data&quot; for use within Google and has been in effect since at least 2013, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theinformation.com/articles/internal-google-program-taps-data-on-rival-android-apps&quot;&gt;The Information reports&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An internal team that tracks the worldwide usage of Google's first-party apps &quot;also has used Lockbox data on third-party apps to show executives how Google services were performing compared to rivals,&quot; sources told The Information. The data was used earlier this month in India, where Google planned to roll out a competitor app to TikTok.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The information is collected through Google Mobile Services, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.android.com/gms/&quot;&gt;collection&lt;/a&gt; of apps and APIs such as Google, Chrome, Gmail, Google Drive, and Google Maps that usually comes pre-installed with Android.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google told The Information that it does access usage data on other Android developers' apps but only through an API that has also been available to third-party developers since 2014. While the API grants developers access to information about phones on which their apps are installed, however, Google has much wider insight into the broad pool of all Android phones globally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Google representative told The Information, &quot;The API doesn't obtain any information about in-app activity and our collection of this data is disclosed to and controllable by users&quot; but did not comment on how Google uses that or any other data to research or develop competitors to other apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sound familiar?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If The Information's allegations are accurate, antitrust regulators are likely to have a whole lot of questions for Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we here at Ars have &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/11/antitrust-101-why-everyone-is-probing-amazon-apple-facebook-and-google/&quot;&gt;explained before&lt;/a&gt;, antitrust law isn't just about monopolies. It's also about a broad bucket of behaviors that are considered &lt;em&gt;anticompetitive&lt;/em&gt; under the law. Using your power as one of the biggest companies in the world to put the squeeze on startups who could eventually become viable, serious competitors is one of those anticompetitive behaviors, and regulators don't like it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Four of the biggest US tech firms—Alphabet (Google), Amazon, Apple, and Facebook—are all under a bevy of state, federal, and international antitrust probes at this moment, investigating whether—and, if so, to what extent—those companies grew and maintained their market power through underhanded, unlawful tactics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook in particular has been scrutinized for using data on competitors in almost exactly the way the new report accuses Google of doing. The social giant used a VPN it acquired, called Onavo, to redirect traffic through Facebook servers, where it could be logged and analyzed. That data let Facebook see what competition apps were growing in popularity so that it could then either buy out those start-ups or launch competitors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of those competitors was Snapchat. Last fall, reports surfaced that Snap for several years kept &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/09/snapchat-reportedly-has-project-voldemort-dossier-on-facebooks-bad-behavior/&quot;&gt;a dossier, called Project Voldemort&lt;/a&gt;, documenting Facebook's attempts first to acquire it and later, after acquisition didn't work, to copy Snapchat's key features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;US investigators are also widely assumed to be probing the way in which Apple can &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2019/09/05/how-apple-uses-its-app-store-copy-best-ideas/&quot;&gt;leverage data from the iOS App Store&lt;/a&gt; to inform its own software development. The EU is also probing the way Apple privileges its first-party apps after Spotify last year &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/03/apples-in-app-purchase-rules-could-violate-european-competition-law/&quot;&gt;filed a complaint&lt;/a&gt; against the company.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 08:25:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pjmlp</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2020/07/android-user-data-gives-google-edge-over-third-party-apps-report-says/</og:url>
<og:title>Google reportedly peeks into Android data to gain edge over third-party apps</og:title>
<og:image>https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/android-spying-760x380.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Google is already under investigation by Congress, DOJ, and 50 state AGs.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2020/07/android-user-data-gives-google-edge-over-third-party-apps-report-says/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>