<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Half of ICOs Die Within Four Months After Token Sales Finalized</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-07-09/half-of-icos-die-within-four-months-after-token-sales-finalized</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-07-09/half-of-icos-die-within-four-months-after-token-sales-finalized</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;title&gt;Terms of Service Violation&lt;/title&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;24&quot;&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;div width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collector-px8fcgygk4.perimeterx.net/api/v1/collector/noScript.gif?appId=PX8FCGYgk4&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;container&quot; readability=&quot;9.4285714285714&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/graphics/assets/img/BB-Logo-2line.svg&quot; width=&quot;310&quot;/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your usage has been flagged as a violation of our &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bloomberg.com/tos&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;terms of service&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For inquiries related to this message please &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bloomberg.com/feedback&quot;&gt;contact support&lt;/a&gt;. For sales inquiries, please visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bloomberg.com/professional/request-demo&quot;&gt;http://www.bloomberg.com/professional/request-demo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;If you believe this to be in error, please confirm below that you are not a robot by clicking &quot;I'm not a robot&quot; below.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Please make sure your browser supports JavaScript and cookies and that you are not blocking them from loading. For more information you can review the Terms of Service and Cookie Policy.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;block_uuid&quot;&gt;Block reference ID:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2018 19:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>chollida1</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/tosv.html?url=L25ld3MvYXJ0aWNsZXMvMjAxOC0wNy0wOS9oYWxmLW9mLWljb3MtZGllLXdpdGhpbi1mb3VyLW1vbnRocy1hZnRlci10b2tlbi1zYWxlcy1maW5hbGl6ZWQ/&amp;uuid=721baa10-8417-11e8-a298-f5b04b1b674e&amp;vid=</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How to Analyze Billions of Records per Second on a Single Desktop PC</title>
<link>https://clemenswinter.com/2018/07/09/how-to-analyze-billions-of-records-per-second-on-a-single-desktop-pc/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://clemenswinter.com/2018/07/09/how-to-analyze-billions-of-records-per-second-on-a-single-desktop-pc/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;This article gives an overview of &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cswinter/LocustDB&quot;&gt;LocustDB&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span id=&quot;0wdRyPWr2HycaA6z0H6AI&quot; class=&quot;abt-citation noselect mceNonEditable&quot; data-reflist=&quot;[&quot; data-footnote=&quot;Clemens Winter, “Cswinter/LocustDB,” GitHub, 2018, https://github.com/cswinter/LocustDB.&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/span&gt;, a new and extremely fast open-source analytics database built in Rust. &lt;a href=&quot;https://clemenswinter.com/2018/07/09/how-to-analyze-billions-of-records-per-second-on-a-single-desktop-pc/&quot;&gt;Part 1&lt;/a&gt; gives some background on analytical query systems and my goals for LocustDB. &lt;a href=&quot;https://clemenswinter.com/2018/07/09/how-to-analyze-billions-of-records-per-second-on-a-single-desktop-pc/2/&quot;&gt;Part 2&lt;/a&gt; presents benchmark results produced on a data set of 1.46 billion taxi rides and demonstrates median speedups of 3.6x over ClickHouse and 2.1x over tuned kdb+. &lt;a href=&quot;https://clemenswinter.com/2018/07/09/how-to-analyze-billions-of-records-per-second-on-a-single-desktop-pc/3/&quot;&gt;Part 3&lt;/a&gt; is an architecture deep dive that follows two SQL statements through the guts of the query engine. &lt;a href=&quot;https://clemenswinter.com/2018/07/09/how-to-analyze-billions-of-records-per-second-on-a-single-desktop-pc/4/&quot;&gt;Part 4&lt;/a&gt; concludes with random learnings, thoughts on Rust, and other incoherent ramblings.&lt;span id=&quot;more-9&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Online analytical processing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply put, online analytical processing (OLAP) involves interactively running queries on often large data sets to gain new insights. To give a concrete example, you might be logging all requests to your website and store fields like the country from which the page was accessed, the accessed url, http status code returned by the website, time it took to service the request, and any number of parameters included in the request. Then one day you get reports of performance issues on your search page and run a query like following to identify specific requests that lead to slow responses:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;EnlighterJSRAW&quot; data-enlighter-language=&quot;sql&quot; data-enlighter-linenumbers=&quot;false&quot;&gt;
SELECT params.search_term, latency
FROM requests
WHERE url = '/search'
AND latency &amp;gt; 10000
AND day = $TODAY
ORDER BY latency DESC
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or you may want to do produce a report on the performance of your website, broken down by various attributes such as url and country. Or someone is trying to break into your systems, and you want to construct some filter that allows you to identify malicious requests and check whether they succeeded. Or one of your pages is returning errors and you want to filter down to and inspect the parameters of those requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Typical OLAP queries have a number of distinguishing features that impose unique design constraints:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Individual queries can be very expensive and may require aggregating trillions of records or more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data is often filtered on or grouped by multiple columns.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Queries are created ad-hoc and are often unique with respect to others queries previously seen by the system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a corollary, elaborate indexing datastructures are often ineffective. Since the number of possible ways to filter or group a dataset grows exponentially with the number of columns, we can only provide precomputed indices/aggregates for a tiny subset of possible queries. The approach taken by LocustDB is to forgo any attempts at complex indexing structures in favor of simple partitioning, performing brute-force scans over large parts of the data set, and then making those scans as fast as hardware allows. The main techniques used to achieve this are caching data in memory, massive parallelism, various optimizations around &lt;a href=&quot;http://db.csail.mit.edu/pubs/abadi-column-stores.pdf&quot;&gt;columnar data storage&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span id=&quot;ueHd8VIcrzXWebmcIQDjF&quot; class=&quot;abt-citation noselect mceNonEditable&quot; data-reflist=&quot;[&quot; data-footnote=&quot;&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://people.freebsd.org/~lstewart/articles/cpumemory.pdf&quot;&gt;general techniques&lt;/a&gt; for high performance computing &lt;span id=&quot;8eg_cwaTw9wwi87tsFHex&quot; class=&quot;abt-citation noselect mceNonEditable&quot; data-reflist=&quot;[&quot; data-footnote=&quot;Ulrich Drepper, “What Every Programmer Should Know About Memory,” What Every Programmer Should Know About Memory, 2007, https://people.freebsd.org/~lstewart/articles/cpumemory.pdf.&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/span&gt;. The trade-off is that simple queries will be relatively inefficient, which restricts throughput to maybe 1000s of queries per second. LocustDB is not the first system designed in this fashion. Notably &lt;a href=&quot;https://research.fb.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/scuba-diving-into-data-at-facebook.pdf&quot;&gt;Scuba&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span id=&quot;SmqnmBjuQBDK5_iIs5eyy&quot; class=&quot;abt-citation noselect mceNonEditable&quot; data-reflist=&quot;[&quot; data-footnote=&quot;&quot;&gt;[4], &lt;/span&gt;a proprietary system used at Facebook, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://clickhouse.yandex/&quot;&gt;ClickHouse&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span id=&quot;JKHn5w6dEpAueyf5XP~DO&quot; class=&quot;abt-citation noselect mceNonEditable&quot; data-reflist=&quot;[&quot; data-footnote=&quot;“ClickHouse DBMS,” ClickHouse — open source distributed column-oriented DBMS, 2009, https://clickhouse.yandex/.&quot;&gt;[5], &lt;/span&gt;an open source column-oriented DBMS developed at Yandex, have successfully taken the same approach. Scuba in particular adds two additional innovations which are not currently offered by any widely available systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Aggressive Compression&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compression is a key tool for speeding up queries reading from disk and for reducing cost. A 2015 paper by Facebook &lt;span id=&quot;UGmosuitf37ZJEv4__dYn&quot; class=&quot;abt-citation noselect mceNonEditable&quot; data-reflist=&quot;[&quot; data-footnote=&quot;&quot;&gt;[6] claims &lt;/span&gt;compression rates of 10x and larger, achieved through automatically applying multiple compression algorithms tailored to different kinds of data. Add to this the complete absence of indexing overhead, and it results in a very cost effective solution. I suspect there exist many low QPS HBase/Cassandra/Elasticsearch/… clusters that could be replaced by a system like Scuba with minimal cost increase (or even significant savings) while providing higher query speeds, more expressive query capabilities and eliminating the need to manually design indices and table schemas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flexible Schemas&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most analytics systems have followed the SQL approach of requiring rigid table schemas that define the type and name of all columns upfront. While this makes a lot of sense for applications using a database for long-term storage of critical data, it is often less useful in an analytics setting where data may be short-lived and data integrity is not as crucial. I believe that foregoing rigid, predefined schemas unlocks a long tail of valuable use cases related to debugging, short lived experiments, prototyping and quick iteration for which setting up or migrating schemas is prohibitively cumbersome. A more subtle benefit is that supporting a flexible schema makes it much easier to support a multitude of compression schemes that may be difficult to retrofit if your code makes more rigid assumptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;LocustDB&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LocustDB originally started out during a Dropbox 2017 hackweek as a clone of Scuba. The prototype was open sourced and I have since continued working on it for fun and profit (minus the profit). So far most of my efforts have been focused on the query engine. It is still incomplete in terms of the breadth of supported query types and operators, but already extremely fast and fairly mature architecturally. Other components include a barely functional SQL(ish) parser, in-memory storage and simple compression schemes. There was support for basic persistence built on top of RocksDB at some point but most of this was killed during a refactor. Other functionality that you might consider important and that does not exist yet include the ability to replicate data and run queries across multiple machines, advanced compression algorithms, and not crashing randomly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://clemenswinter.com/2018/07/09/how-to-analyze-billions-of-records-per-second-on-a-single-desktop-pc/2/&quot;&gt;Part 2: Benchmarks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;robots-nocontent sd-block sd-social sd-social-icon-text sd-sharing&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Share this:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-block sd-like jetpack-likes-widget-wrapper jetpack-likes-widget-unloaded&quot; id=&quot;like-post-wrapper-147584694-9-5b4466fb9acb4&quot; data-src=&quot;https://widgets.wp.com/likes/#blog_id=147584694&amp;amp;post_id=9&amp;amp;origin=clemenswinter.com&amp;amp;obj_id=147584694-9-5b4466fb9acb4&quot; data-name=&quot;like-post-frame-147584694-9-5b4466fb9acb4&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Like this:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;likes-widget-placeholder post-likes-widget-placeholder&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;button&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Like&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;loading&quot;&gt;Loading...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;page-links&quot;&gt;Pages: 1 &lt;a href=&quot;https://clemenswinter.com/2018/07/09/how-to-analyze-billions-of-records-per-second-on-a-single-desktop-pc/2/&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://clemenswinter.com/2018/07/09/how-to-analyze-billions-of-records-per-second-on-a-single-desktop-pc/3/&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://clemenswinter.com/2018/07/09/how-to-analyze-billions-of-records-per-second-on-a-single-desktop-pc/4/&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2018 18:17:55 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>cwinter</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>How to Analyze Billions of Records per Second on a Single Desktop PC</og:title>
<og:url>https://clemenswinter.com/2018/07/09/how-to-analyze-billions-of-records-per-second-on-a-single-desktop-pc/</og:url>
<og:description>Introduction This article gives an overview of LocustDB [1], a new and extremely fast open-source analytics database built in Rust. Part 1 gives some background on analytical query systems and my g…</og:description>
<og:image>https://clemenswinter.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/threadperf2-1.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://clemenswinter.com/2018/07/09/how-to-analyze-billions-of-records-per-second-on-a-single-desktop-pc/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Nissan Admits Internal Emissions-Test Results were Falsified</title>
<link>https://www.wsj.com/articles/nissan-admits-emission-test-data-was-falsified-1531139749</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.wsj.com/articles/nissan-admits-emission-test-data-was-falsified-1531139749</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;TOKYO—Staff at some of Nissan Motor Co.’s Japan plants falsified auto-emissions and fuel-economy data, the company said, in what is the latest data-faking incident among Japanese manufacturers.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It is also the second compliance scandal at Nissan in recent months after it admitted to faults in vehicle inspection procedures. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Staff at four Nissan...
  &lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2018 14:17:54 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>blawson</dc:creator>
<og:title>Nissan Admits Emissions-Test Data Was Falsified</og:title>
<og:description>Staff at some of Nissan Motor’s Japan plants falsified auto-emissions and fuel-economy data, the company said, in what is the latest data-faking incident among Japanese manufacturers.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.wsj.com/articles/nissan-admits-emission-test-data-was-falsified-1531139749</og:url>
<og:image>https://images.wsj.net/im-17339/social</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.wsj.com/articles/nissan-admits-emission-test-data-was-falsified-1531139749</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Simple, correct, fast: in that order</title>
<link>https://drewdevault.com/2018/07/09/Simple-correct-fast.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://drewdevault.com/2018/07/09/Simple-correct-fast.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The single most important quality in a piece of software is simplicity. It’s more important than doing the task you set out to achieve. It’s more important than performance. The reason is straightforward: if your solution is not simple, it will not be correct or fast.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Given enough time, you’ll find that all software which solves sufficiently complex problems is going to (1) have bugs and (2) have performance problems. Software with bugs is incorrect. Software with performance problems is not fast. We will face this fact as surely as we will face death and taxes, and we should prepare ourselves accordingly. Let’s consider correctness first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Complicated software breaks. Simple software is more easily understood and far less prone to breaking: there are less moving pieces, less lines of code to keep in your head, and fewer edge cases. Simple software is more easily tested as well - after all, fewer code paths to run through. Sure, simple software &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; break, and when it does the cause and appropriate solution are often apparent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now let’s consider performance. You may have some suspicions about your bottlenecks when you set out, and you should consider them in your approach. However, when the performance bill comes due, you’re more likely to have overlooked something than not. The only way to find out for sure what’s slow is to measure. Which is easier to profile: a complicated program, or a simple one? Anyone who’s looked at a big enough flame graph knows exactly what I’m talking about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps complicated software once solved a problem. That software needs to be maintained - what is performant and correct today will not be tomorrow. The workload will increase, or the requirements will change. Software is a living thing! When you’re stressed out at 2 AM on Tuesday morning because the server shat itself because your 1,831st new customer pushed the billing system over the edge, do you think you’re well equipped to find the problem in a complex piece of code you last saw a year ago?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you are faced with these problems, you must seek out the simplest way they can be solved. This may be difficult to do: perhaps the problem is too large, or perhaps you were actually considering the solution before considering the problem. Though difficult it may be, it is your most important job. You need to take problems apart, identify smaller problems within them and ruthlessly remove scope until you find the basic problem you can apply a basic solution to. The complex problem comes later, and it’ll be better served by the composition of simple solutions than with the application of a complex solution.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2018 13:16:48 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Sir_Cmpwn</dc:creator>
<og:title>Simple, correct, fast: in that order</og:title>
<og:description>The single most important quality in a piece of software is simplicity. It’s more important than doing the task you set out to achieve. It’s more important than performance. The reason is straightforward: if your solution is not simple, it will not be correct or fast.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://drewdevault.com/2018/07/09/Simple-correct-fast.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Illegal Production and Use of Banned CFC-11 in China&amp;#039;s Foam Blowing Industry</title>
<link>https://eia-global.org/reports/20180709-blowing-it-illegal-production-and-use-of-banned-cfc-11-in-chinas-foam-blowing-industry</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://eia-global.org/reports/20180709-blowing-it-illegal-production-and-use-of-banned-cfc-11-in-chinas-foam-blowing-industry</guid>
<description>&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/278835579?color=f6f9fa&amp;amp;title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://content.eia-global.org/posts/documents/000/000/761/original/Blowing-It_CFC11_Report_EIA.pdf?1531089183&quot;&gt;Download the report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Information obtained by the Environmental Investigation Agency (EIA) demonstrates conclusively that the use of CFC-11 in China’s rigid polyurethane (PU) foam insulation sector, in particular in the building and construction subsector, is widespread and pervasive. CFC-11 is used as a foam blowing agent for the manufacture of molded foam panels and spray foam used for insulation purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EIA has evidence from eighteen companies in ten provinces that they use CFC-11. Detailed discussions with company executives make clear that these are not isolated incidents but instead represent common practice across the industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EIA’s calculations show that emission estimates associated with the level of use reported by these companies can explain the majority of emissions identified in the atmospheric study. In addition there is significant potential for illegal international trade in CFC-11 containing pre-formulated polyols for foam manufacturing in other countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scale of the compliance issue is such that it cannot be treated as a series of isolated incidents. EIA urges the Government of China and the Parties to the Montreal Protocol to acknowledge the scale of this environmental crime and take immediate action to investigate further, implement legislative reform and ensure effective intelligence-led enforcement. Only through urgent and comprehensive action can the Montreal Protocol ensure that it continues to merit its reputation as the most effective global environmental treaty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read the full report &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://content.eia-global.org/posts/documents/000/000/761/original/Blowing-It_CFC11_Report_EIA.pdf?1531089183&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2018 08:21:29 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>comex</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://eia-global.org/reports/20180709-blowing-it-illegal-production-and-use-of-banned-cfc-11-in-chinas-foam-blowing-industry</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: Browsh – A modern, text-based browser</title>
<link>https://www.brow.sh</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.brow.sh</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;home-row&quot; readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Browsh is a fully-modern text-based browser.&lt;/strong&gt; It renders anything that a modern browser can; HTML5, CSS3, JS, video and even WebGL. It can be used from a terminal or from within a normal browser. Its main purpose is to significantly reduce bandwidth and thus both increase browsing speeds and decrease bandwidth costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;home-column tty-screenshot&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.brow.sh/assets/images/browsh-tty.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;home-column in-browser-screenshot&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.brow.sh/assets/images/browsh-html.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;home-row&quot; readability=&quot;8.3475&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;home-column&quot; readability=&quot;7.0204081632653&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Download (v1.2.3)&lt;/h2&gt;
Browsh is available as a small (~2.5MB) static binary on all major platforms. The only dependency is a recent 57+ version of Firefox.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brow.sh/downloads&quot;&gt;Latest version&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/browsh-org/browsh/releases&quot;&gt;Releases archive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;small&gt;A Docker image is also available: &lt;code&gt;`docker pull browsh/browsh`&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;home-column&quot; readability=&quot;9.8611111111111&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Live SSH Demo&lt;/h2&gt;
Just point your SSH client to &lt;em&gt;brow.sh&lt;/em&gt;, eg; &lt;code&gt;`ssh brow.sh`&lt;/code&gt;. No auth needed. The service is for demonstration only, sessions last 5 minutes and are logged.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;small&gt;Note that SSH is actually a very inefficient protocol, for best results install Browsh on your own server along with &lt;a href=&quot;https://mosh.org/&quot;&gt;Mosh&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;home-column&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;In-browser Services&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://html.brow.sh&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;html.brow.sh&lt;/a&gt; Uses very basic graphics and HTML anchor tags. &lt;small&gt;Although this service may appear similar to the terminal client it does not yet have feature parity.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://text.brow.sh&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;text.brow.sh&lt;/a&gt; Uses nothing but pure text, better for usage with `curl`, for instance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;home-row youtube-row&quot; readability=&quot;7.7536585365854&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/zqAoBD62gvo&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;open-blurb&quot; class=&quot;home-column&quot; readability=&quot;10.946341463415&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Donate&lt;/h2&gt;
Browsh is an open source project, currently maintained and funded by &lt;a href=&quot;http://tombh.co.uk&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;one person&lt;/a&gt;. If you would like to see Browsh continue to help those with slow and/or expensive Internet, please consider &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brow.sh/donate&quot;&gt;donating&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2018 02:28:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tombh</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:title>Browsh</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.brow.sh/</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.brow.sh/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Choice of search engine on Android nuked by “Anonymous Coward” (2009)</title>
<link>https://android.googlesource.com/platform/packages/apps/GlobalSearch/+/592150ac00086400415afe936d96f04d3be3ba0c</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://android.googlesource.com/platform/packages/apps/GlobalSearch/+/592150ac00086400415afe936d96f04d3be3ba0c</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;Breadcrumbs&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;Breadcrumbs-crumb&quot; href=&quot;https://android.googlesource.com/?format=HTML&quot;&gt;android&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a class=&quot;Breadcrumbs-crumb&quot; href=&quot;https://android.googlesource.com/platform/&quot;&gt;platform&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a class=&quot;Breadcrumbs-crumb&quot; href=&quot;https://android.googlesource.com/platform/packages/&quot;&gt;packages&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a class=&quot;Breadcrumbs-crumb&quot; href=&quot;https://android.googlesource.com/platform/packages/apps/&quot;&gt;apps&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a class=&quot;Breadcrumbs-crumb&quot; href=&quot;https://android.googlesource.com/platform/packages/apps/GlobalSearch/&quot;&gt;GlobalSearch&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;span class=&quot;Breadcrumbs-crumb&quot;&gt;592150ac00086400415afe936d96f04d3be3ba0c&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;u-monospace Metadata&quot;&gt;
&lt;table readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;1.7966101694915&quot;&gt;&lt;th class=&quot;Metadata-title&quot;&gt;commit&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td&gt;592150ac00086400415afe936d96f04d3be3ba0c&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;[&lt;a href=&quot;https://android.googlesource.com/platform/packages/apps/GlobalSearch/+log/592150ac00086400415afe936d96f04d3be3ba0c&quot;&gt;log&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;[&lt;a href=&quot;https://android.googlesource.com/platform/packages/apps/GlobalSearch/+archive/592150ac00086400415afe936d96f04d3be3ba0c.tar.gz&quot;&gt;tgz&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;th class=&quot;Metadata-title&quot;&gt;author&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Anonymous Coward &amp;lt;nobody@android.com&amp;gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Wed Aug 19 15:44:42 2009 -0700&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;th class=&quot;Metadata-title&quot;&gt;committer&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Anonymous Coward &amp;lt;nobody@android.com&amp;gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Wed Aug 19 15:56:16 2009 -0700&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.22222222222222&quot;&gt;&lt;th class=&quot;Metadata-title&quot;&gt;tree&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://android.googlesource.com/platform/packages/apps/GlobalSearch/+/592150ac00086400415afe936d96f04d3be3ba0c/&quot;&gt;33a5517dcfba62a2652a5b809b71a6c9ff4514cd&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.37037037037037&quot;&gt;&lt;th class=&quot;Metadata-title&quot;&gt;parent&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://android.googlesource.com/platform/packages/apps/GlobalSearch/+/592150ac00086400415afe936d96f04d3be3ba0c%5E&quot;&gt;500413e48c7b96743ea13357aa2fba856edd1c8c&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;[&lt;a href=&quot;https://android.googlesource.com/platform/packages/apps/GlobalSearch/+/592150ac00086400415afe936d96f04d3be3ba0c%5E%21/&quot;&gt;diff&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;u-pre u-monospace MetadataMessage&quot;&gt;
Remove the search engine setting. Hard-code the search engine to Google,
using EnhancedGoogleSearchProvider if available, otherwise GoogleSearch if
available, otherwise throwing a RuntimeException requiring one of these
packages.
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;DiffTree&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://android.googlesource.com/platform/packages/apps/GlobalSearch/+/592150ac00086400415afe936d96f04d3be3ba0c/res/xml/preferences.xml&quot;&gt;res/xml/preferences.xml&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;DiffTree-action DiffTree-action--modify&quot;&gt;[&lt;a href=&quot;https://android.googlesource.com/platform/packages/apps/GlobalSearch/+/592150ac00086400415afe936d96f04d3be3ba0c%5E%21/#F0&quot;&gt;diff&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://android.googlesource.com/platform/packages/apps/GlobalSearch/+/592150ac00086400415afe936d96f04d3be3ba0c/src/com/android/globalsearch/SearchSettings.java&quot;&gt;src/com/android/globalsearch/SearchSettings.java&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;DiffTree-action DiffTree-action--modify&quot;&gt;[&lt;a href=&quot;https://android.googlesource.com/platform/packages/apps/GlobalSearch/+/592150ac00086400415afe936d96f04d3be3ba0c%5E%21/#F1&quot;&gt;diff&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;2 files changed&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;TreeDetail&quot; readability=&quot;2.7794117647059&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;tree: 33a5517dcfba62a2652a5b809b71a6c9ff4514cd&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;FileList&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;FileList-item FileList-item--regularFile&quot; title=&quot;Regular file - Android.mk&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;FileList-itemLink&quot; href=&quot;https://android.googlesource.com/platform/packages/apps/GlobalSearch/+/592150ac00086400415afe936d96f04d3be3ba0c/Android.mk&quot;&gt;Android.mk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;FileList-item FileList-item--regularFile&quot; title=&quot;Regular file - AndroidManifest.xml&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;FileList-itemLink&quot; href=&quot;https://android.googlesource.com/platform/packages/apps/GlobalSearch/+/592150ac00086400415afe936d96f04d3be3ba0c/AndroidManifest.xml&quot;&gt;AndroidManifest.xml&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;FileList-item FileList-item--regularFile&quot; title=&quot;Regular file - MODULE_LICENSE_APACHE2&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;FileList-itemLink&quot; href=&quot;https://android.googlesource.com/platform/packages/apps/GlobalSearch/+/592150ac00086400415afe936d96f04d3be3ba0c/MODULE_LICENSE_APACHE2&quot;&gt;MODULE_LICENSE_APACHE2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;FileList-item FileList-item--regularFile&quot; title=&quot;Regular file - NOTICE&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;FileList-itemLink&quot; href=&quot;https://android.googlesource.com/platform/packages/apps/GlobalSearch/+/592150ac00086400415afe936d96f04d3be3ba0c/NOTICE&quot;&gt;NOTICE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;FileList-item FileList-item--gitTree&quot; title=&quot;Tree - benchmarks/&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;FileList-itemLink&quot; href=&quot;https://android.googlesource.com/platform/packages/apps/GlobalSearch/+/592150ac00086400415afe936d96f04d3be3ba0c/benchmarks/&quot;&gt;benchmarks/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;FileList-item FileList-item--gitTree&quot; title=&quot;Tree - res/&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;FileList-itemLink&quot; href=&quot;https://android.googlesource.com/platform/packages/apps/GlobalSearch/+/592150ac00086400415afe936d96f04d3be3ba0c/res/&quot;&gt;res/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;FileList-item FileList-item--gitTree&quot; title=&quot;Tree - src/&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;FileList-itemLink&quot; href=&quot;https://android.googlesource.com/platform/packages/apps/GlobalSearch/+/592150ac00086400415afe936d96f04d3be3ba0c/src/&quot;&gt;src/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;FileList-item FileList-item--gitTree&quot; title=&quot;Tree - tests/&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;FileList-itemLink&quot; href=&quot;https://android.googlesource.com/platform/packages/apps/GlobalSearch/+/592150ac00086400415afe936d96f04d3be3ba0c/tests/&quot;&gt;tests/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2018 01:54:57 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dreamingincode</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://android.googlesource.com/platform/packages/apps/GlobalSearch/+/592150ac00086400415afe936d96f04d3be3ba0c</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Apple’s Shortcuts will flip the switch on Siri’s potential</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2018/07/08/shortcuts-will-flip-the-switch-for-apple-on-siris-potential-just-not-how-you-think/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2018/07/08/shortcuts-will-flip-the-switch-for-apple-on-siris-potential-just-not-how-you-think/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;article__contributor-byline&quot; readability=&quot;29.05612244898&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;contributor-byline__contributor&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;byline__author-name&quot;&gt;Matthew Cassinelli&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;byline__author-title&quot;&gt;Contributor&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;contributor-byline__bio&quot; readability=&quot;8.4242424242424&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/matthewcassinelli/&quot;&gt;Matthew Cassinelli&lt;/a&gt; is a former member of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://my.workflow.is/&quot;&gt;Workflow&lt;/a&gt; team and works as an independent writer and consultant. He previously worked as a data analyst for VaynerMedia.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/06/04/14-big-announcements-from-apples-annual-developer-conference-wwdc-2018/&quot;&gt;At WWDC&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/&quot;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt; pitched Shortcuts &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/06/04/apple-gives-users-control-of-siri-with-new-shortcuts-and-suggestions-tools/&quot;&gt;as a way to ”take advantage of the power of apps”&lt;/a&gt; and “expose quick actions to Siri.” These will be suggested by the OS, can be given unique voice commands and will even be customizable with a dedicated Shortcuts app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But because this new feature won’t let Siri interpret &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt;, many have been lamenting that Siri didn’t get much better — and is still lacking compared to &lt;a href=&quot;https://assistant.google.com/&quot;&gt;Google Assistant&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07456BG8N&quot;&gt;Amazon Echo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But to ignore Shortcuts would be missing out on the bigger picture. &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/apple/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;apple&quot;&gt;Apple’s&lt;/a&gt; strengths have always been the device ecosystem and the apps that run on them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Shortcuts, both play a major role in how Siri will prove to be a truly useful assistant and not just a digital voice to talk to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;breakout alignnone size-full wp-image-1651193&quot; src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/iOS12_Siri-App-Notifications_06042018.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;1228&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Your Apple devices just got better&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many, voice assistants are a nice-to-have, but not a need-to-have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s undeniably convenient to get facts by speaking to the air, turning on the lights without lifting a finger or triggering a timer or text message — but so far, studies have shown people don’t use much more than these on a regular basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People don’t often do more than that because the assistants aren’t really ready for complex tasks yet, and when your assistant is limited to tasks inside your home or commands spoken into your phone, the drawbacks prevent you from going deep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you prefer Alexa, you get more devices, better reliability and a breadth of skills, but there’s not a great phone or tablet experience you can use alongside your Echo. If you prefer to have &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/google/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;google&quot;&gt;Google’s&lt;/a&gt; Assistant everywhere, you must be all in on the &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/android/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;android&quot;&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt; and Home ecosystem to get the full experience, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plus, with either option, there are privacy concerns baked into how both work on a fundamental level — over the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Apple’s ecosystem, you have Siri on iPhone, iPad, Apple Watch, AirPods, HomePod, CarPlay and any Mac. Add in Shortcuts on each of those devices (except Mac, but they still have Automator) and suddenly you have a plethora of places to execute all your commands entirely by voice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each accessory that Apple users own will get upgraded, giving Siri new ways to fulfill the 10 billion and counting requests people make each month (according to &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.crunchbase.com/person/craig-federighi/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;person&quot; data-entity=&quot;craig-federighi&quot;&gt;Craig Federighi’s&lt;/a&gt; statement onstage at WWDC).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But even more important than all the places &lt;em&gt;where&lt;/em&gt; you can use your assistant is &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; — with Shortcuts, Siri gets even better with each new app that people download. There’s the other key difference: the App Store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;breakout alignnone size-full wp-image-1653398&quot; src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/siri-suggestion-examples.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;521&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Actions are the most important part of your apps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;iOS has always had a vibrant community of developers who create powerful, top-notch applications that push the system to its limits and take advantage of the ever-increasing power these mobile devices have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shortcuts opens up those capabilities to Siri — every action you take in an app can be shared out with Siri, letting people interact right there inline or using only their voice, with the app running everything smoothly in the background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plus, the functional approach that Apple is taking with Siri creates new opportunities for developers to provide utility to people instead of requiring their attention. The suggestions feature of Shortcuts rewards “acceleration,” showing the apps that provide the most time savings and use for the user more often.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This opens the door to more specialized types of apps that don’t necessarily have to grow a huge audience and serve them ads — if you can make something that helps people, Shortcuts can help them use your app more than ever before (and without as much effort). Developers can make a great experience for when people visit the app, but also focus on actually doing something useful too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn’t a virtual assistant that lives in the cloud, but a digital helper that can pair up with the apps uniquely taking advantage of Apple’s hardware and software capabilities to truly improve your use of the device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the most groan-inducing way possible, “there’s an app for that” is back, and more important than ever. Not only are apps the centerpiece of the Siri experience, but it’s their capabilities that extend Siri’s — the better the apps you have, the better Siri can be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;breakout alignnone size-full wp-image-1653381&quot; src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/add-to-siri-screen.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;676&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Control is at your fingertips&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Importantly, Siri gets all of this Shortcuts power while keeping the control in each person’s hands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of the information provided to the system is securely passed along by individual apps — if something doesn’t look right, you can just delete the corresponding app and the information is gone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Siri will make recommendations based on activities deemed relevant by the apps themselves, as well, so over-active suggestions shouldn’t be common (unless you’re way too active in some apps, in which case they added Screen Time for you too).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each of the voice commands is custom per user, as well, so people can ignore their apps suggestions and set up the phrases to their own liking. This means nothing is already “taken” because somebody signed up for the skill first (unless you’ve already used it yourself, of course).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, Shortcuts don’t require the web to work — the voice triggers might not work, but the suggestions and Shortcuts app give you a place to use your assistant voicelessly. And importantly, Shortcuts can use the full power of the web when they need to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This user-centric approach paired with the technical aspects of how Shortcuts works, gives Apple’s assistant a leg up for any consumers who find privacy important. Essentially, Apple devices are only listening for “Hey Siri,” then the available Siri domains plus your own custom trigger phrases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without exposing your information to the world or teaching a robot to understand everything, Apple gave Siri a slew of capabilities that in many ways can’t be matched. With Shortcuts, it’s the apps, the operating system and the variety of hardware that will make Siri uniquely qualified come this fall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plus, the Shortcuts app will provide a deeper experience for those who want to chain together actions and customize their own shortcuts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s lots more under the hood to experiment with, but this will allow anyone to tweak and prod their Siri commands until they have a small army of custom assistant tasks at the ready.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;breakout alignnone size-full wp-image-1653409&quot; src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/siri.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;600&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Hey Siri, let’s get started&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Siri doesn’t know all, can’t perform any task you bestow upon it and won’t make somewhat uncanny phone calls on your behalf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But instead of spending time conversing with a somewhat faked “artificial intelligence,” Shortcuts will help people use Siri as an actual digital assistant — a computer to help them get things done better than they might’ve otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Siri’s new skills extending to each of your Apple products (except for Apple TV and the Mac, but maybe one day?), every new device you get and every new app you download can reveal another way to take advantage of what this technology can offer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This broadening of Siri may take some time to get used to — it will be about finding the right place for it in your life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you go about your apps, you’ll start seeing and using suggestions. You’ll set up a few voice commands, then you’ll do something like kick off a truly useful shortcut from your Apple Watch without your phone connected and you’ll realize the potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a real digital assistant, your apps know how to work with it and it’s already on many of your Apple devices. Now, it’s time to actually make use of it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2018 00:47:36 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>evo_9</dc:creator>
<og:title>Apple’s Shortcuts will flip the switch on Siri’s potential</og:title>
<og:description>At WWDC, Apple pitched Shortcuts as a way to ”take advantage of the power of apps” and &quot;expose quick actions to Siri.” These will be suggested by the OS, can be given unique voice commands and will even be customizable with a dedicated Shortcuts app.</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/siri_shortcut_wwdc.jpg?w=527</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2018/07/08/shortcuts-will-flip-the-switch-for-apple-on-siris-potential-just-not-how-you-think/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2018/07/08/shortcuts-will-flip-the-switch-for-apple-on-siris-potential-just-not-how-you-think/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Inside China’s Dystopian Dreams: A.I., Shame and Lots of Cameras</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/07/08/business/china-surveillance-technology.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2018/07/08/business/china-surveillance-technology.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;40.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;26&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;ZHENGZHOU, China — In the Chinese city of Zhengzhou, a police officer wearing facial recognition glasses spotted a heroin smuggler at a train station.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;In Qingdao, a city famous for its German colonial heritage, cameras powered by artificial intelligence helped the police snatch two dozen criminal suspects in the midst of a big annual beer festival.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;In Wuhu, a fugitive murder suspect was identified by a camera as he bought food from a street vendor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;With millions of cameras and billions of lines of code, China is building a high-tech authoritarian future. Beijing is embracing technologies like facial recognition and artificial intelligence to identify and track 1.4 billion people. It wants to assemble a vast and unprecedented national surveillance system, with crucial help from its thriving technology industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;37&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;19&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“In the past, it was all about instinct,” said Shan Jun, the deputy chief of the police at the railway station in Zhengzhou, where the heroin smuggler was caught. “If you missed something, you missed it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;China is reversing the commonly held vision of technology as a great democratizer, bringing people more freedom and connecting them to the world. In China, it has brought control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;36&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;17&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;In some cities, cameras scan train stations for China’s most wanted. Billboard-size displays show the faces of jaywalkers and list the names of people who don’t pay their debts. Facial recognition scanners guard the entrances to housing complexes. Already, China has an estimated 200 million surveillance cameras — four times as many as the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Such efforts supplement other systems that track internet use and communications, hotel stays, train and plane trips and even car travel in some places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;44&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Even so, China’s ambitions outstrip its abilities. Technology in place at one train station or crosswalk may be lacking in another city, or even the next block over. Bureaucratic inefficiencies prevent the creation of a nationwide network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;For the Communist Party, that may not matter. Far from hiding their efforts, Chinese authorities regularly state, and overstate, their capabilities. In China, even the perception of surveillance can keep the public in line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Some places are further along than others. Invasive mass-surveillance software has been set up in the west to track members of the Uighur Muslim minority and map their relations with friends and family, according to software viewed by The New York Times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“This is potentially a totally new way for the government to manage the economy and society,” said Martin Chorzempa, a fellow at the Peterson Institute for International Economics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“The goal is algorithmic governance,” he added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;36.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;18&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;css-1caa3mc eqpy7av0&quot;&gt;The Shame Game&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The intersection south of Changhong Bridge in the city of Xiangyang used to be a nightmare. Cars drove fast and jaywalkers darted into the street.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Then last summer, the police put up cameras linked to facial recognition technology and a big, outdoor screen. Photos of lawbreakers were displayed alongside their names and government I.D. numbers. People were initially excited to see their faces on the board, said Guan Yue, a spokeswoman, until propaganda outlets told them it was punishment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;43.256529850746&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;31.820895522388&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“If you are captured by the system and you don’t see it, your neighbors or colleagues will, and they will gossip about it,” she said. “That’s too embarrassing for people to take.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;China’s new surveillance is based on an old idea: Only strong authority can bring order to a turbulent country. Mao Zedong took that philosophy to devastating ends, as his top-down rule brought &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2012/09/06/world/asia/06iht-letter06.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;famine&lt;/a&gt; and then the Cultural Revolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;His successors also craved order but feared the consequences of totalitarian rule. They formed a new understanding with the Chinese people. In exchange for political impotence, they would be mostly left alone and allowed to get rich.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;It worked. Censorship and police powers remained strong, but China’s people still found more freedom. That new attitude helped usher in decades of breakneck economic growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Today, that unwritten agreement is breaking down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;China’s economy isn’t growing at the same pace. It suffers from a severe wealth gap. After four decades of fatter paychecks and better living, its people have higher expectations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Xi Jinping, China’s top leader, has moved to solidify his power. Changes to Chinese law mean he could rule longer than any leader since Mao. And he has undertaken a broad corruption crackdown that could make him plenty of enemies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;49.665956313266&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;45.240277037826&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;For support, he has turned to the Mao-era beliefs in the importance of a cult of personality and the role of the Communist Party in everyday life. Technology gives him the power to make it happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“Reform and opening has already failed, but no one dares to say it,” said Chinese historian Zhang Lifan, citing China’s four-decade post-Mao policy. “The current system has created severe social and economic segregation. So now the rulers use the taxpayers’ money to monitor the taxpayers.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Xi has launched a major upgrade of the Chinese surveillance state. China has become the world’s biggest market for security and surveillance technology, with analysts estimating the country will have almost 300 million cameras installed by 2020. Chinese buyers will snap up more than three-quarters of all servers designed to scan video footage for faces, predicts IHS Markit, a research firm. China’s police will &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://politics.caijing.com.cn/20170930/4340032.shtml&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;spend an additional $30 billion&lt;/a&gt; in the coming years on techno-enabled snooping, according to one expert quoted in state media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Government contracts are fueling research and development into technologies that track faces, clothing and even a person’s gait. Experimental gadgets, like facial-recognition glasses, have begun to appear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Judging public Chinese reaction can be difficult in a country where the news media is controlled by the government. Still, so far the average Chinese citizen appears to show little concern. Erratic enforcement of laws against everything from speeding to assault means the long arm of China’s authoritarian government can feel remote from everyday life. As a result, many cheer on new attempts at law and order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“It’s one of the biggest intersections in the city,” said Wang Fukang, a college student who volunteered as a guard at the crosswalk in Xiangyang. “It’s important that it stays safe and orderly.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;css-1caa3mc eqpy7av0&quot;&gt;The Surveillance Start-Up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Start-ups often make a point of insisting their employees use their technology. In Shanghai, a company called Yitu has taken that to the extreme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;49&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;43&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The halls of its offices are dotted with cameras, looking for faces. From desk to break room to exit, employees’ paths are traced on a television screen with blue dotted lines. The monitor shows their comings and goings, all day, everyday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;In China, snooping is becoming big business. As the country spends heavily on surveillance, a new generation of start-ups have risen to meet the demand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Chinese companies are developing globally competitive applications like image and voice recognition. Yitu took first place in a 2017 open contest for facial recognition algorithms held by the United States government’s Office of the Director of National Intelligence. A number of other Chinese companies also scored well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;A technology boom in China is helping the government’s surveillance ambitions. In sheer scale and investment, China already rivals Silicon Valley. Between the government and eager investors, surveillance start-ups have access to plenty of money and other resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;In May, the upstart A.I. company SenseTime raised $620 million, giving it a valuation of about $4.5 billion. Yitu raised $200 million last month. Another rival, Megvii, raised $460 million from investors that included a state-backed fund created by China’s top leadership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;At a conference in May at an upscale hotel in Beijing, China’s security-industrial complex offered its vision of the future. Companies big and small showed off facial-recognition security gates and systems that track cars around cities to local government officials, tech executives and investors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;54&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;53&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Private companies see big potential in China’s surveillance build-out. China’s public security market was valued at more than $80 billion last year but could be worth even more as the country builds its capabilities, said Shen Xinyang, a former Google data scientist who is now chief technology officer of Eyecool, a start-up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“Artificial intelligence for public security is actually still a very insignificant portion of the whole market,” he said, pointing out that most equipment currently in use was “nonintelligent.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Many of these businesses are already providing data to the government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Shen told the group that his company had surveillance systems at more than 20 airports and train stations, which had helped catch 1,000 criminals. Eyecool, he said, is also handing over two million facial images each day to a burgeoning big-data police system called Skynet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;At a building complex in Xiangyang, a facial-recognition system set up to let residents quickly through security gates adds to the police’s collection of photos of local residents, according to local Chinese Communist Party officials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Wen Yangli, an executive at Number 1 Community, which makes the product, said the company is at work on other applications. One would detect when crowds of people are clashing. Another would allow police to use virtual maps of buildings to find out who lives where.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;China’s surveillance companies are also looking to test the appetite for high-tech surveillance abroad. Yitu says it has been expanding overseas, with plans to increase business in regions like Southeast Asia and the Middle East.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;At home, China is preparing its people for next-level surveillance technology. A recent state-media propaganda film called “Amazing China” showed off a similar virtual map that provided police with records of utility use, saying it could be used for predictive policing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;34&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“If there are anomalies, the system sends an alert,” a narrator says, as Chinese police officers pay a visit to an apartment with a record of erratic utility use. The film then quotes one of the officers: “No matter which corner you escape to, we’ll bring you to justice.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;44&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;css-1caa3mc eqpy7av0&quot;&gt;Enter the Panopticon&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;For technology to be effective, it doesn’t always have to work. Take China’s facial-recognition glasses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Police in the central Chinese city of Zhengzhou recently showed off the specs at a high-speed rail station for state media and others. They snapped photos of a policewoman peering from behind the shaded lenses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;But the glasses work only if the target stands still for several seconds. They have been used mostly to check travelers for fake identifications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;China’s national database of individuals it has flagged for watching — including suspected terrorists, criminals, drug traffickers, political activists and others — includes 20 million to 30 million people, said one technology executive who works closely with the government. That is too many people for today’s facial recognition technology to parse, said the executive, who asked not to be identified because the information wasn’t public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The system remains more of a digital patchwork than an all-seeing technological network. Many files still aren’t digitized, and others are on mismatched spreadsheets that can’t be easily reconciled. Systems that police hope will someday be powered by A.I. are currently run by teams of people sorting through photos and data the old-fashioned way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;43.241730279898&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;31.810008481764&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Take, for example, the crosswalk in Xiangyang. The images don’t appear instantaneously. The billboard often shows jaywalkers from weeks ago, though authorities have recently reduced the lag to about five or six days. Officials said humans still sift through the images to match them to people’s identities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Still, Chinese authorities who are generally mum about security have embarked on a campaign to persuade the country’s people that the high-tech security state is already in place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;China’s propagandists are fond of stories in which police use facial recognition to spot wanted criminals at events. An &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://sc.people.com.cn/n2/2018/0525/c345459-31624714.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; in People’s Daily, the Communist Party’s official newspaper, covered a series of arrests made with the aid of facial recognition at concerts of the pop star Jackie Cheung. The piece referenced some of the singer’s lyrics: “You are a boundless net of love that easily trapped me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;In many places, it works. At the intersection in Xiangyang, jaywalking has decreased. At the building complex where Number 1 Community’s facial-recognition gate system has been installed, a problem with bike theft ceased entirely, according to building management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;35&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“The whole point is that people don’t know if they’re being monitored, and that uncertainty makes people more obedient,” said Mr. Chorzempa, the Peterson Institute fellow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;He described the approach as a panopticon, the idea that people will follow the rules precisely because they don’t know whether they are being watched.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;41.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;28&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;In Zhengzhou, police were happy to explain how just the thought of the facial recognition glasses could get criminals to confess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Shan, the Zhengzhou railway station deputy police chief, cited the time his department grabbed a heroin smuggler. While questioning the suspect, Mr. Shan said, police pulled out the glasses and told the man that what he said didn’t matter. The glasses could give them all the information they needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“Because he was afraid of being found out by the advanced technology, he confessed,” said Mr. Shan, adding that the suspect had swallowed 60 small packs of heroin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“We didn’t even use any interrogation techniques,” Mr. Shan said. “He simply gave it all up.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;28.282786885246&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;css-k8fkhk&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carolyn Zhang contributed reporting from Zhengzhou.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-3glrhn&quot; readability=&quot;8.0208333333333&quot;&gt;A version of this article appears in print on , on Page A1 of the New York edition with the headline: With Cameras And A.I., China Closes Its Grip&lt;span&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytreprints.com/&quot;&gt;Order Reprints&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/pages/todayspaper/index.html&quot;&gt;Today’s Paper&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/subscriptions/Multiproduct/lp8HYKU.html?campaignId=48JQY&quot;&gt;Subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2018 20:32:54 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rmason</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/07/08/business/china-surveillance-technology.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Inside China’s Dystopian Dreams: A.I., Shame and Lots of Cameras</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/07/09/world/00china-police-1/00china-police-1-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Beijing is putting billions of dollars behind facial recognition and other technologies to track and control its citizens.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/07/08/business/china-surveillance-technology.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>My favorite apps on F-Droid</title>
<link>http://quaap.com/D/use-fdroid</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://quaap.com/D/use-fdroid</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I often recommend F-Droid to my Android-using friends. &lt;a href=&quot;https://f-droid.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;F-Droid&lt;/a&gt; is an alternative app store which contains only Free and Open Source Software (FOSS). It's great because the apps are almost all not evil. Did you know that a flashlight app &lt;em&gt;doesn't&lt;/em&gt; need access to your contacts, location, and pictures? Did you know that every app doesn't need to serve you ads?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, sometimes the apps aren't as polished, and sometimes they lack some functionality you'd like, but they are much less likely to contain/be malware or spyware. And sometimes they fill a unique niche not filled by anything else. And sometimes they are amazingly good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The apps are some individual's or team's passion projects, and most are not looking to earn money on the apps, they just want to make something they and others would find useful or fun. I wrote several of them myself, and I wrote them because I didn't like what was available commercially, or just had a weird idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, below is a current list of these FOSS apps I use (or have installed for my kids / future use). And again, one of the best features of any of them is that they don't serve you ads, and don't report your location and browsing habits anywhere. And don't steal your data and contact list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To install them, you'll need to go to &lt;a href=&quot;https://f-droid.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;F-Droid&lt;/a&gt; and install the main F-Droid app. When you do that, you'll need to say &quot;yes&quot; or &quot;allow&quot; to the prompts asking if you want to install from unknown sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: there are a huge number of apps I've not tried… These are just the ones I've installed and found useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;system-apps&quot;&gt;System apps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a replacement for the keyboard. It provides a much easier-to-use experience (to me) that the built-in keyboards don't, like easy access to the single quote, for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, full disclosure: I wrote this one. &lt;a href=&quot;http://quaap.com/D/LaunchTime&quot;&gt;LaunchTime&lt;/a&gt; is my replacement homescreen/launcher. I do like it sooo much better than the other homescreens though. Before I wrote it, I struggled greatly with the &quot;app drawer&quot; model used by most launchers. See the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/quaap/LaunchTime/blob/master/README.md&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;LaunchTime page on Github&lt;/a&gt; for a full list of features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This app is designed to reduce the display's effect on your day-night cycle by removing blue light. I don't know about that, but I use it as a &quot;super dimmer&quot; at night and it can run on a schedule, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A replacement for whatever spyware/crapware weather widget came with your phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can display a list of WiFi access points and help you decide on what channel to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adds a &quot;save to a directory&quot; option to the share menus. Run the app by itself first to set a destination directory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A generic search app widget which you can target different search engines. It's pretty slim and mostly useful so you don't have to have some company's widget always running on your phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used this to help me make this list! &lt;img src=&quot;http://quaap.com/D/media/emoticons/smile.png&quot; alt=&quot;smile :)&quot; title=&quot;smile :)&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;graphics&quot;&gt;Graphics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A gallery of you photos, a photo viewer, and a photo editor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Loads up your pictures and automatically detects and blurs faces so that you can share pictures that contain other people/kids easier. You can also manually blur (or unblur) regions of the photo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finger painting/drawing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simple barcode/QR code/etc scanner. Just scans them and adds the code to its history so you can share them via text, email, file, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;reading-and-writing&quot;&gt;Reading and Writing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A super slimmed-down Facebook app. It's just a thin wrapper around facebook's mobile site, but it's great because it allows you to not have the two behemoth Facebook apps (Facebook proper and Messenger) to bog down your phone and gather data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kind of a hybrid notes and checklist app which allows adding all kinds of rich text and pictures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, it's mine again. An almost &lt;em&gt;too&lt;/em&gt; simple epub reader. Very few features, but that's how I like it. (Note: I recently discovered a large number of crashes due to variations on different devices I wasn't able to test. I've fixed these in 0.3.4 which hasn't hit F-Droid yet.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A simple daily journal. Can tie in with your calendar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;utilities&quot;&gt;Utilities&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My very favorite shopping list app. You can manually sort the items (I have mine in ALDI-order), and have multiple lists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your device has a step counter sensor, this app can use it to keep track of your steps, and that's it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An all-you-need app to help you if you do interval training.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very simple app to generate dice rolls. There are other, bigger apps available if you do tabletop gaming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Access data gathered on food products. It can scan an item's UPC barcode and retrieve nutrition info (if available).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A simple text editor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An easy way to record sound files and share them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A music player with a big list of free music and radio streams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A kind of cool music player for mp3s and oggs on you phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tune your guitar, or just entertain a child who likes to see waveforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;View waveforms, or just entertain a child who likes to see waveforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;games-and-toys&quot;&gt;Games and toys&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's just a list of games I occasionally play, or, more likely, my kids play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gamified educational app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Straightforward solitaire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like 30 weird puzzle games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yup 2048.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another tower-defense game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And a bunch more I won't describe, but I found them fun enough to keep (or my kids did).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;end&quot;&gt;End&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that's it. There are hundreds of other apps there which might fit your needs. Try &lt;a href=&quot;https://f-droid.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;it&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2018 20:06:24 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ericdanielski</dc:creator>
<og:title>My favorite apps on F-Droid - [Quaap.com]</og:title>
<og:description>I often recommend F-Droid to my Android-using friends. F-Droid is an alternative app store which contains only Free and Open Source Software (FOSS). It's great because the apps are almost all not evil. Did you know that a flashlight app doesn't need access to your contacts, location, and pictures? Did you know that every app doesn't need to serve you ads?</og:description>
<og:image>http://quaap.com/D/media/logo.png</og:image>
<og:url>http://quaap.com/D/use-fdroid</og:url>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://quaap.com/D/use-fdroid</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>