<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Canada has arrested Huawei’s global chief financial officer in Vancouver</title>
<link>https://www.theglobeandmail.com/canada/article-canada-has-arrested-huaweis-global-chief-financial-officer-in/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theglobeandmail.com/canada/article-canada-has-arrested-huaweis-global-chief-financial-officer-in/</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;Canada has arrested the chief financial officer of China’s Huawei Technologies, who now faces extradition to the United States on suspicion she violated U.S. trade sanctions against Iran.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;Meng Wanzhou, who is also the deputy chair of Huawei’s board and the daughter of company founder Ren Zhengfei, was arrested on Saturday in Vancouver at the request of American law enforcement authorities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;“She is sought for extradition by the United States, and a bail hearing has been set for Friday,” Justice Department spokesman Ian McLeod said in a statement to The Globe and Mail on Wednesday. “As there is a publication ban in effect, we cannot provide any further detail at this time. The ban was sought by Ms. Meng.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;j-f-wrap&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;u-wrapper pb-feature pb-layout-item pb-f-commercial-dfp-ads&quot; id=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;c-ad--flex-gpt-1&quot; class=&quot;c-ad c-ad--inline c-ad--flex&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;c-ad__wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-ad__message&quot;&gt;Story continues below advertisement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;A Canadian law-enforcement source with knowledge of the arrest said the United States is alleging Ms. Meng tried to evade the American embargo against Iran, but provided no further details. The source was granted anonymity by The Globe because they weren’t authorized to speak publicly about the arrest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;U.S. prosecutors in New York have been investigating whether Huawei violated U.S. sanctions in relation to Iran, which was first reported by the Wall Street Journal in April.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;Huawei said in a statement to The Globe that Ms. Meng faces “unspecified charges in the Eastern District of New York” and that she was arrested when she was transferring flights in Canada.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;“The company has been provided with very little information regarding the charges and is not aware of any wrongdoing by Ms. Meng. The company believes the Canadian and U.S. legal systems will ultimately reach a just conclusion,” Huawei said, and added the company “complies with all applicable laws and regulations where it operates, including applicable export control and sanction laws.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;The Chinese embassy in Ottawa strongly protested the arrest of Ms. Meng, saying she had not violated Canadian or U.S. law and demanded her immediate release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;“The Chinese side has lodged stern representations with the U.S. and Canadian side, urged them to immediately correct the wrongdoing and restore the personal liberty of Ms. Meng Wanzhou,” the embassy said in a statement. “We will closely follow the development of the issue and take all measures to resolutely protect the legitimate rights and interests of Chinese citizens.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;Chinese Ambassador Lu Shaye and four high-ranking members of the National People’s Congress also cancelled an appearance before the House of Commons foreign affairs committee scheduled for Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;j-f-wrap&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;u-wrapper pb-feature pb-layout-item pb-f-commercial-dfp-ads&quot; id=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;c-ad--flex-gpt-2&quot; class=&quot;c-ad c-ad--inline c-ad--flex&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;c-ad__wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-ad__message&quot;&gt;Story continues below advertisement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;js-ad-slimcut-wrapper&quot; class=&quot;c-ad c-ad--slimcut u-hidden&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;c-ad__wrapper&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-ad__message&quot;&gt;Story continues below advertisement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;“I haven’t gotten an answer on why they cancelled, but the timing is certainly very curious,” Conservative foreign affairs critic Erin O’Toole said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text c-article-body__text--interstitial&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theglobeandmail.com/world/article-mengs-arrest-sparks-fury-in-china/&quot; class=&quot;c-article-body__link&quot;&gt;Arrest of Huawei’s Meng Wanzhou sparks fury in China&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;The decision by Canadian authorities to detain such a high-profile Chinese citizen – and particularly one sought for extradition to the United States – could hurt Canada-China relations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;Both China and the United States have been asking allies and trading partners to take sides in a trade war and the Trudeau government has spoken enthusiastically of pursuing some sort of trade deal with Beijing now that it has renegotiated a free-trade agreement with the United States and Mexico.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;David Mulroney, a former Canadian ambassador to China, predicted the arrest of Ms. Meng will provoke a backlash in China and hurt Huawei’s efforts to gain business in Western countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;“This is a really big deal. Ms. Meng is by birth and position a member of China’s corporate royalty,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;“Her arrest, on suspicion of violating the Iran sanctions, should be seen as a clear signal that Canada is willing to face China’s fury to do the right thing. That said, it will be portrayed in China as Canada kowtowing to Donald Trump. The arrest also threatens to fatally undermine Huawei’s efforts to portray itself as a reliable infrastructure partner to its remaining supporters in the West.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;j-f-wrap&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;u-wrapper pb-feature pb-layout-item pb-f-commercial-dfp-ads&quot; id=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;c-ad--flex-gpt-3&quot; class=&quot;c-ad c-ad--inline c-ad--flex&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;c-ad__wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-ad__message&quot;&gt;Story continues below advertisement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;The arrest comes as Canada is under intense pressure from the United States to bar the Chinese telecom from participating in next generation 5G mobile networks. The United States and Australia have barred Huawei 5G telecommunications and last week New Zealand blocked the first request from one of its wireless carriers to install the Chinese company’s equipment on its 5G network, citing a “significant network security risk.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;Republican Senator Marco Rubio, a member of the U.S. Senate intelligence committee, lauded Canada for the arrest of Ms. Meng and once again urged Prime Minister Justin Trudeau to bar Huawei from 5G technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;“Huawei has direct ties to the Chinese government and Communist Party, has long posed a serious risk to U.S. national security, and I continue to strongly urge Canada to reconsider Huawei’s inclusion in any aspect of its 5G development, introduction, and maintenance,” Mr. Rubio said in a statement to The Globe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;Mr. Rubio and Democratic Senator Mark Warner wrote to Mr. Trudeau in October to caution that failure to ban Huawei could interfere with intelligence sharing and impair cross-border co-operation in telecommunications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;Republican Senator Ben Sasse, a member of the Senate armed services and banking committees, also praised Canada for the arrest and criticized Huawei as an agent of China’s ruling party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;&quot;China is working creatively to undermine our national security interests, and the United States and our allies can’t sit on the sidelines,” Mr. Sasse said. “Americans are grateful that our Canadian partners have arrested the Chief Financial Officer of a giant Chinese telecom company for breaking U.S. sanctions against Iran.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;j-f-wrap&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;u-wrapper pb-feature pb-layout-item pb-f-commercial-dfp-ads&quot; id=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;c-ad--flex-gpt-4&quot; class=&quot;c-ad c-ad--inline c-ad--flex&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;c-ad__wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-ad__message&quot;&gt;Story continues below advertisement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;Democratic Senator Chris Van Hollen said Huawei and Chinese telecom ZTE represent a fundamental risk to Western national security and called for a comprehensive plan to hold “the Chinese and their state-sponsored entities accountable for gross violations of the law and threats to our security.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;Since at least 2016, U.S. authorities have been reviewing Huawei’s alleged shipping of U.S.-origin products to Iran and other countries in violation of U.S. export and sanctions laws.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;The U.S. Justice Department probe, first reported by the Wall Street Journal, follows a series of actions aimed at stopping or reducing access by Huawei and Chinese smartphone maker ZTE Corp. to the U.S. economy amid allegations the companies could be using their technology to spy on Americans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;The probe is reportedly being run out of the U.S. attorney’s office in Brooklyn, the Wall Street Journal sources said. However, the prosecutor’s office declined to confirm or deny the existence of the investigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;Ms. Meng, 46, who also goes by the name Sabrina, was appointed CFO of Huawei in 2011 and is also one of four deputy chairs. She appears to be being groomed for the top job at Shenzhen-based Huawei, which is now the world’s second-largest maker of telecommunications equipment. Her father was a former engineer in the People’s Liberation Army.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;Reuters reported in 2013 that Ms. Meng served on the board of Hong Kong-based Skycom Tech Co. Ltd. that later attempted to sell embargoed Hewitt Packard computer equipment to Iran’s largest mobile-phone operator. Skycom reportedly has ties to Huawei.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;At least 13 pages of the Skycom proposal were marked “Huawei confidential” and carried Huawei’s logo. Huawei has said neither it nor Skycom provided the HP equipment; HP said it prohibits the sale of its products to Iran.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;U.S. stock futures and Asian shares tumbled on Thursday due to the arrest of Ms. Meng, fanning fears of a fresh flare-up in tensions between the two superpowers. The news came as Washington and Beijing begin three months of negotiations aimed at de-escalating their bruising trade war, which is adding to global investors’ worries over rising U.S. interest rates and other risks to global economic growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;With files from Reuters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 22:06:13 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ericzawo</dc:creator>
<og:title>Canada arrests Huawei’s global chief financial officer in Vancouver</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.theglobeandmail.com/canada/article-canada-has-arrested-huaweis-global-chief-financial-officer-in/</og:url>
<og:description> Meng Wanzhou is facing extradition to the United States on suspicion she violated U.S. trade sanctions against Iran</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://www.theglobeandmail.com/resizer/j8W3qGAZqWkbDdMLbSYVRUaBnb0=/1200x0/filters:quality(80)/arc-anglerfish-tgam-prod-tgam.s3.amazonaws.com/public/WS7YWAWIHZBPZMIMF3SI3M7HKQ.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-CA</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theglobeandmail.com/canada/article-canada-has-arrested-huaweis-global-chief-financial-officer-in/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Pipenv: promises a lot, delivers very little</title>
<link>https://chriswarrick.com/blog/2018/07/17/pipenv-promises-a-lot-delivers-very-little/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://chriswarrick.com/blog/2018/07/17/pipenv-promises-a-lot-delivers-very-little/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pipenv is a Python packaging tool that does one thing reasonably well — application dependency management. However, it is also plagued by issues, limitations and a break-neck development process. In the past, Pipenv’s promotional material was highly misleading as to its purpose and backers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this post, I will explore the problems with Pipenv. Was it really recommended by Python.org? Can everyone — or at least, the vast majority of people — benefit from it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;what-pipenv-does&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve already learned that Pipenv is used to &lt;em&gt;manage application dependencies&lt;/em&gt;. Let’s learn what that term really means.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;application-dependencies&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;toc-backref&quot; href=&quot;https://chriswarrick.com/blog/2018/07/17/pipenv-promises-a-lot-delivers-very-little/#id18&quot;&gt;Application dependencies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chriswarrick.com/blog/2018/07/17/pipenv-promises-a-lot-delivers-very-little/#application-dependencies&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Permalink to this heading&quot;&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is an example use case for Pipenv: I’m working on a website based on Django. I create &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;~/git/website&lt;/tt&gt; and run &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;pipenv install Django&lt;/tt&gt; in that directory. Pipenv:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;simple&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;automatically creates a virtualenv somewhere in my home directory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;writes a Pipfile, which lists Django as my dependency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;installs Django using pip&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;proceeds to write &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;Pipfile.lock&lt;/tt&gt;, which stores the exact version and source file hash &lt;a class=&quot;footnote-reference&quot; href=&quot;https://chriswarrick.com/blog/2018/07/17/pipenv-promises-a-lot-delivers-very-little/#id13&quot; id=&quot;id5&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt; of each package installed (including &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;pytz&lt;/tt&gt;, Django’s dependency).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The last part of the process was the most time consuming. At one point, while locking the dependency versions, Pipenv hangs for 46 seconds. This is one of Pipenv’s notable issues: &lt;strong&gt;it’s slow.&lt;/strong&gt; Of course, this isn’t the only one, but it defintely doesn’t help. Losing 46 seconds isn’t much, but when we get to the longer waits in the timing test section later, we’ll see something that could easily discourage users from using a package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;running-scripts-badly&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;toc-backref&quot; href=&quot;https://chriswarrick.com/blog/2018/07/17/pipenv-promises-a-lot-delivers-very-little/#id19&quot;&gt;Running scripts (badly)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chriswarrick.com/blog/2018/07/17/pipenv-promises-a-lot-delivers-very-little/#running-scripts-badly&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Permalink to this heading&quot;&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But let’s continue with our workflow. &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;pipenv run &lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;django-admin&lt;/span&gt; startproject foobanizer&lt;/tt&gt; is what I must use now, which is rather unwieldy to type, and requires running pipenv even for the smallest things. (The &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;manage.py&lt;/tt&gt; script has &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;/usr/bin/env python&lt;/tt&gt; in its shebang.) I can run &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;pipenv shell&lt;/tt&gt; to get a new shell which runs the &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;activate&lt;/tt&gt; script by default, giving you the worst of both worlds when it comes to virtualenv activation: the unwieldiness of a new shell, and the activate script, which the proponents of the shell spawning dislike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;pipenv shell&lt;/tt&gt; means spawning a new subshell, executing the shell startup scripts (eg. &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;.bashrc&lt;/tt&gt;), and requiring you to exit with &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;exit&lt;/tt&gt; or ^D. If you type &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;deactivate&lt;/tt&gt;, you are working with an extra shell, but now outside of the virtualenv. Or you can use the &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;--fancy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/tt&gt; mode that manipulates &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;$PATH&lt;/tt&gt; before launching the subshell, but it requires a specific shell configuration, in which &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;$PATH&lt;/tt&gt; is not overridden in non-login shells — and also often changing the config of your terminal emulator to run a login shell, as many of the Linux terminals don’t do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, why does all this happen? Because a command cannot manipulate the environment of the shell it spawns. This means that Pipenv must pretend what it does is a reasonable thing instead of a workaround. This can be solved with manual activation using &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;source $(pipenv &lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;--venv)/bin/activate&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/tt&gt; (can be made into a neat alias), or shell wrappers (similar to what virtualenvwrapper does).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;finishing-it-all-up&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;toc-backref&quot; href=&quot;https://chriswarrick.com/blog/2018/07/17/pipenv-promises-a-lot-delivers-very-little/#id20&quot;&gt;Finishing it all up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chriswarrick.com/blog/2018/07/17/pipenv-promises-a-lot-delivers-very-little/#finishing-it-all-up&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Permalink to this heading&quot;&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I want a blog on my site. I want to write them in Markdown syntax, so I run &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;pipenv install Markdown&lt;/tt&gt;, and a few long seconds later, it’s added to both Pipfiles. Another thing I can do is &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;pipenv install &lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;--dev&lt;/span&gt; ipython&lt;/tt&gt; and get a handy shell for tinkering, but it will be marked as a development dependency — so, not installed in production. That last part is an important advantage of using Pipenv.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I’m done working on my website, I commit both Pipfiles to my git repository, and push it to the remote server. Then I can clone it to, say, &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;/srv/website&lt;/tt&gt;. Now I can just &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;pipenv install&lt;/tt&gt; to get all the production packages installed (but not the development ones — Django, pytz, Markdown will be installed, but IPython and all its million dependencies won’t). There’s just one caveat: by default, the virtualenv will still be created in the current user’s home directory. This is a problem in this case, since it needs to be accessible by &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://chriswarrick.com/blog/2016/02/10/deploying-python-web-apps-with-nginx-and-uwsgi-emperor/&quot;&gt;nginx and uWSGI&lt;/a&gt;, which do not have access to my (or root’s) home directory, and don’t have a home directory of their own. This can be solved with &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;export PIPENV_VENV_IN_PROJECT=1&lt;/tt&gt;. But note that I will now need to export this environment variable every time I work with the app in &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;/srv&lt;/tt&gt; via Pipenv. The tool supports loading &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;.env&lt;/tt&gt; files, &lt;strong&gt;but&lt;/strong&gt; only when running &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;pipenv shell&lt;/tt&gt; and &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;pipenv run&lt;/tt&gt;. You can’t use it to configure Pipenv. And to run my app with nginx/uWSGI, I will need to know the exact virtualenv path anyway, since I can’t use &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;pipenv run&lt;/tt&gt; as part of uWSGI configuration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;what-pipenv-doesnt-do&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The workflow I mentioned above looks pretty reasonable, right? There are some deficiencies, but other than that, it seems to work well. The main issue with Pipenv is: &lt;strong&gt;it works with one workflow, and one workflow only.&lt;/strong&gt; Try to do anything else, and you end up facing multiple obstacles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;setup-py-source-distributions-and-wheels&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;toc-backref&quot; href=&quot;https://chriswarrick.com/blog/2018/07/17/pipenv-promises-a-lot-delivers-very-little/#id22&quot;&gt;Setup.py, source distributions, and wheels&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chriswarrick.com/blog/2018/07/17/pipenv-promises-a-lot-delivers-very-little/#setup-py-source-distributions-and-wheels&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Permalink to this heading&quot;&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pipenv only concerns itself with managing dependencies. &lt;strong&gt;It isn’t a packaging tool.&lt;/strong&gt; If you want your thing up on PyPI, Pipenv won’t help you with anything. You still need to write a &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;setup.py&lt;/tt&gt; with &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;install_requires&lt;/tt&gt;, because the Pipfile format only specifies the dependencies and runtime requirements (Python version), there is no place in it for the package name, and Pipenv does not mandate/expect you to install your project. It can come in handy to manage the development environment (as a &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;requirements.txt&lt;/tt&gt; replacement, or something used to write said file), but if your project has a &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;setup.py&lt;/tt&gt;, you still need to manually manage &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;install_requires&lt;/tt&gt;. Pipenv can’t create wheels on its own either. And &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;pip freeze&lt;/tt&gt; is going to be a lot faster than Pipenv ever will be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;working-outside-of-the-project-root&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;toc-backref&quot; href=&quot;https://chriswarrick.com/blog/2018/07/17/pipenv-promises-a-lot-delivers-very-little/#id23&quot;&gt;Working outside of the project root&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chriswarrick.com/blog/2018/07/17/pipenv-promises-a-lot-delivers-very-little/#working-outside-of-the-project-root&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Permalink to this heading&quot;&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another issue with Pipenv is the use of the working directory to select the virtual environment. &lt;a class=&quot;footnote-reference&quot; href=&quot;https://chriswarrick.com/blog/2018/07/17/pipenv-promises-a-lot-delivers-very-little/#id14&quot; id=&quot;id6&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt; Let’s say I’m a library author. A user of my &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;foobar&lt;/tt&gt; library has just reported a bug and attached a &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;repro.py&lt;/tt&gt; file that lets me reproduce the issue. I download that file to &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;~/Downloads&lt;/tt&gt; on my filesystem. With plain old virtualenv, I can easily confirm the reproduction in a spare shell with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;code shell&quot;&gt;
$ ~/virtualenvs/foobar/bin/python ~/Downloads/repro.py
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then I can launch my fancy IDE to fix the bug. I don’t have to &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;cd&lt;/tt&gt; into the project. But with Pipenv, I can’t really do that. If I put the virtualenv in &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;.venv&lt;/tt&gt; with the command line option, I can type &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;~/git/foobar/.venv/bin/python&lt;/span&gt; ~/Downloads/repro.py&lt;/tt&gt;. If I use the centralized directory + hashes thing, Tab completion becomes mandatory, if I haven’t memorized the hash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;code shell&quot;&gt;
$ &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;cd&lt;/span&gt; ~/git/foobar
$ pipenv run python ~/Downloads/repro.py
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if I had two &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;.py&lt;/tt&gt; files, or &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;repro.py&lt;/tt&gt; otherwise depended on being in the current working directory?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;code shell&quot;&gt;
$ &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;cd&lt;/span&gt; ~/git/foobar
$ pipenv shell
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;foobar-Mwd1l2m9&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;$ &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;cd&lt;/span&gt; ~/Downloads
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;foobar-Mwd1l2m9&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;$ python repro.py
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;foobar-Mwd1l2m9&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;$ &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;exit&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;# (not deactivate!)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is becoming ugly fairly quickly.&lt;/strong&gt; Also, with virtualenvwrapper, I can do this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;code shell&quot;&gt;
$ &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;cd&lt;/span&gt; ~/Downloads
$ workon foobar
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;foobar&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;$ python repro.py
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;foobar&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;$ deactivate
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And let’s not forget that Pipenv doesn’t help me to write a &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;setup.py&lt;/tt&gt;, distribute code, or manage releases. It just manages dependencies. And it does it pretty badly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;nikola&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;toc-backref&quot; href=&quot;https://chriswarrick.com/blog/2018/07/17/pipenv-promises-a-lot-delivers-very-little/#id24&quot;&gt;Nikola&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chriswarrick.com/blog/2018/07/17/pipenv-promises-a-lot-delivers-very-little/#nikola&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Permalink to this heading&quot;&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m a co-maintainer of a static site generator, &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://getnikola.com&quot;&gt;Nikola&lt;/a&gt;. As part of this, I have the following places where I need to run Nikola:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;simple&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;~/git/nikola&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;~/git/nikola-site&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;~/git/nikola-plugins&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;~/git/nikola-themes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;~/website&lt;/tt&gt; (this blog)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;/Volumes/RAMDisk/n&lt;/tt&gt; (demo site, used for testing and created when needed, on a &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RAM_drive&quot;&gt;RAM disk&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;That list is long. End users of Nikola probably don’t have a list that long, but they might just have more than one Nikola site. For me, and for the aforementioned users, Pipenv does not work. To use Pipenv, all those repositories would need to live in one directory. I would also need to have a &lt;em&gt;separate&lt;/em&gt; Pipenv environment for &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;nikola-users&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/tt&gt;, because that needs Django. Moreover, the Pipfile would have to be symlinked from &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;~/git/nikola&lt;/tt&gt; if we were to make use of those in the project. So, I would have a &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;~/nikola&lt;/tt&gt; directory just to make Pipenv happy, do testing/bug reproduction on a SSD (and wear it out faster), and so on… Well, I could also use the virtualenv directly. But in that case, Pipenv loses its usefulness, and makes my workflow more complicated. I can’t use &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;virtualenvwrapper&lt;/tt&gt;, because I would need to hack a fuzzy matching system onto it, or memorize the random string appended to my virtualenv name. All because Pipenv relies on the current directory too much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nikola end users who want to use Pipenv will also have a specific directory structure forced on them. What if the site serves as docs for a project, and lives inside another project’s repo? Two virtualenvs, 100 megabytes wasted. Or worse, Nikola ends up in the other project’s Pipfile, which is technically good for our download stats, but not really good for the other project’s contributors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;the-part-where-i-try-to-measure-times&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pipenv is famous for being slow. But how slow is it really? I put it to the test. I used two test environments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;simple&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Remote: a DigitalOcean VPS, the cheapest option (1 vCPU), Python 3.6/Fedora 28, in Frankfurt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Local: my 2015 13” MacBook Pro (base model), Python 3.7, on a rather slow Internet connection (10 Mbps on a good day, and the test was not performed on one of them)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Both were runninng Pipenv 2018.7.1, installed from pip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And with the following cache setups:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;simple&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Removed: &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;~/.cache/pipenv&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/tt&gt; removed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Partial: &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;rm &lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;-rf&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;~/.cache/pipenv/depcache-py*.json&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;~/.cache/pipenv/hash-cache/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kept: no changes done from previous run&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Well, turns out Pipenv likes doing strange things with caching and locking. A look at the Activity Monitor hinted that there is network activity going on when Pipenv displays its &lt;em&gt;Locking [packages] dependencies...&lt;/em&gt; line and hangs. Now, the docs don’t tell you that. The most atrocious example was a local Nikola install that was done in two runs: the first &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;pipenv install Nikola&lt;/tt&gt; run was interrupted &lt;a class=&quot;footnote-reference&quot; href=&quot;https://chriswarrick.com/blog/2018/07/17/pipenv-promises-a-lot-delivers-very-little/#id15&quot; id=&quot;id8&quot;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt; right after it was done installing packages, so the cache had all the necessary wheels in it. The install took 10 minutes and 7 seconds, 9:50 of which were taken by locking dependencies and installing the locked dependencies — so, roughly nine and a half minutes were spent staring at a static screen, with the tool doing &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; in the background — and Pipenv doesn’t tell you what happens in this phase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Updated 2018-07-22: In the pipenv measurements: the first entry is the total time of pipenv executon. The second is the long wait for pipenv to do its “main” job: locking dependencies and installing them. The timing starts when pipenv starts locking dependencies and ends when the prompt appears. The third item is pipenv’s reported installation time. So, pipenv install ⊇ locking/installing ⊇ Pipfile.lock install.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;1&quot; class=&quot;table table-striped table-bordered docutils&quot;&gt;&lt;colgroup&gt;&lt;col width=&quot;4%&quot;/&gt;&lt;col width=&quot;26%&quot;/&gt;&lt;col width=&quot;10%&quot;/&gt;&lt;col width=&quot;10%&quot;/&gt;&lt;col width=&quot;21%&quot;/&gt;&lt;col width=&quot;7%&quot;/&gt;&lt;col width=&quot;7%&quot;/&gt;&lt;col width=&quot;7%&quot;/&gt;&lt;col width=&quot;7%&quot;/&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;&lt;thead valign=&quot;bottom&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th class=&quot;head&quot; rowspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;Task&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class=&quot;head&quot; rowspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;Action&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class=&quot;head&quot; rowspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;Measurement method&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class=&quot;head&quot; rowspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;Environment&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class=&quot;head&quot; rowspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;Cache&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class=&quot;head&quot; colspan=&quot;4&quot;&gt;Times in seconds&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th class=&quot;head&quot;&gt;Attempt 1&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class=&quot;head&quot;&gt;Attempt 2&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class=&quot;head&quot;&gt;Attempt 3&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class=&quot;head&quot;&gt;Average&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;virtualenv&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;time&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Remote&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(not applicable)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.911&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.052&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.914&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.959&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;pip install Nikola&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;time&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Remote&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Removed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11.562&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11.943&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11.773&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11.759&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;pip install Nikola&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;time&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Remote&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Kept&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7.404&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7.681&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7.569&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7.551&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;pipenv install Nikola&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;time&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;Remote&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;Removed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;67.536&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;62.973&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;71.305&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;67.271&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;├─ locking/installing from lockfile&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;stopwatch&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;42.6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;40.5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;39.6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;40.9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;└─ Pipfile.lock install&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;pipenv&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;14&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;14&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;13&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;13.667&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;adding Django to an environment&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;time&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;Remote&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;Kept (only Nikola in cache)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;39.576&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;—&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;—&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;39.576&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;├─ locking/installing from lockfile&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;stopwatch&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;32&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;—&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;—&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;32&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;└─ Pipfile.lock install&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;pipenv&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;14&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;—&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;—&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;14&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;adding Django to another environment&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;time&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;Remote&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;Kept (both in cache)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;37.978&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;—&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;—&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;37.978&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;├─ locking/installing from lockfile&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;stopwatch&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;30.2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;—&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;—&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;30.2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;└─ Pipfile.lock install&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;pipenv&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;14&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;—&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;—&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;14&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;pipenv install Django&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;time&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;Remote&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;Removed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;20.612&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;20.666&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;20.665&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;20.648&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;├─ locking/installing from lockfile&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;stopwatch&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6.6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6.4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6.333&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;└─ Pipfile.lock install&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;pipenv&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;pipenv install Django (new env)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;time&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;Remote&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;Kept&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;17.615&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;—&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;—&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;17.615&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;├─ locking/installing from lockfile&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;stopwatch&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;—&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;—&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;└─ Pipfile.lock install&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;pipenv&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;—&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;—&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;pipenv install Nikola&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;time&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;Remote&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;Partial&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;61.507&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;—&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;—&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;61.507&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;├─ locking/installing from lockfile&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;stopwatch&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;38.40&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;—&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;—&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;38.40&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;└─ Pipfile.lock install&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;pipenv&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;14&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;—&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;—&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;14&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;pipenv install Django&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;time&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;Local&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;Removed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;73.933&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;—&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;—&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;73.933&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;├─ locking/installing from lockfile&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;stopwatch&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;46&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;—&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;—&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;46&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;└─ Pipfile.lock install&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;pipenv&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;—&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;—&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;11&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;virtualenv&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;time&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Local&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(not applicable)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5.864&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;—&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;—&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5.864&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;12&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;pip install Nikola (cached)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;time&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Local&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Kept&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10.951&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;—&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;—&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10.951&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;13&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;pipenv install Nikola&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;time&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;Local&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;Partial, after interruption&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;607.647&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;(10m 7s)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;607.647&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;├─ locking/installing from lockfile&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;stopwatch&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;590.85&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;(9m 50s)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;590.85&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;└─ Pipfile.lock install&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;pipenv&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;14&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;pipenv install&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;time&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Local&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Kept&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;31.399&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;(L/I: 10.51 s)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;31.399&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;the-break-neck-pace-of-pipenv&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good packaging tool is stable. In other words, it doesn’t change often, and it strives to support existing environments. It wouldn’t be fun to re-download everything on your system, because someone decided that &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;/usr&lt;/tt&gt; is now called &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;/stuff&lt;/tt&gt;, and all the files in &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;/usr&lt;/tt&gt; would become forgotten and not removed. Well, this is what Pipenv did:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;1&quot; class=&quot;table table-striped table-bordered docutils&quot;&gt;&lt;colgroup&gt;&lt;col width=&quot;11%&quot;/&gt;&lt;col width=&quot;89%&quot;/&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;&lt;thead valign=&quot;bottom&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th class=&quot;head&quot;&gt;Date/Time (UTC)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class=&quot;head&quot;&gt;Event&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;2017-01-31 22:01&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;v3.2.14 released. &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;pipenv &lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;--three&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/tt&gt; creates &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;./.venv&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/tt&gt; (eg. &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;~/git/foo/.venv&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/tt&gt;). Last version with the original behavior of pipenv.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;2017-02-01 05:36&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;v3.3.0 released. &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;pipenv &lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;--three&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/tt&gt; creates &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;~/.local/share/virtualenvs/foo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/tt&gt; (to be precise, &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;$WORKON_HOME/foo&lt;/tt&gt;).&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;2017-02-01 06:10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/pypa/pipenv/issues/178&quot;&gt;Issue #178&lt;/a&gt; is reported regarding the behavior change.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;2017-02-01 06:18&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Kenneth Reitz responds: “no plans for making it configurable.” and closes the issue.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;2017-02-02 03:05&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Kenneth Reitz responds: “added &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;PIPENV_VENV_IN_PROJECT&lt;/tt&gt; mode for classic operation. Not released yet.”&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;2017-02-02 04:29&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;v3.3.3 released. The default is still uses a “remote” location, but &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;.venv&lt;/tt&gt; can now be used.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;2017-03-02 13:48&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;v3.5.0 released. The new default path is &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;$WORKON_HOME/foo-HASH&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/tt&gt;, eg. &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;~/.local/share/virtualenvs/foo-7pl2iuUI&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/tt&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the course of a month, the location of the virtualenv changed twice. If the user didn’t read the changelog and didn’t manually intervene (also of note, the option name was mentioned in the issue and in v3.3.4’s changelog), they would have a stale &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;.venv&lt;/tt&gt; directory, since the new scheme was adopted for them. And then, after switching to v3.5.0, they would have a stale virtualenv hidden somewhere in their home directory, because pipenv decided to add hashes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, this is not configurable. One cannot disable the hashes in paths, even though &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/pypa/pipenv/issues/589&quot;&gt;users&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/pypa/pipenv/issues/1049&quot;&gt;wanted&lt;/a&gt; to. It would also help people who want to mix Pipenv and virtualenvwrapper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pipenv is a very &lt;strong&gt;opinionated&lt;/strong&gt; tool, and if the dev team changes their mind, the old way is not supported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pipenv moves fast and doesn’t care if anything breaks. As an example, between 2018-03-13 13:21 and 2018-03-14 13:44 (a little over 24 hours), Pipenv had 10 releases, ranging from v11.6.2 to v11.7.3. The &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/pypa/pipenv/blob/25df09c171a548fd71d4df735767bf763a653b83/HISTORY.txt&quot;&gt;changelog&lt;/a&gt; is rather unhelpful when it comes to informing users what happened in each of the releases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extra reading:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;simple&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Pipenv, contrary to popular belief and (now removed) propaganda, is not an officially recommended tool of Python.org. It merely has a tutorial written about it on packaging.python.org (page run by the PyPA).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pipenv solves one use case reasonably well, but fails at many others, because it forces a particular workflow on its users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pipenv does not handle any parts of packaging (cannot produce sdists and wheels). Users who want to upload to PyPI need to manage a &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;setup.py&lt;/tt&gt; file manually, alongside and independently of Pipenv.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pipenv produces lockfiles, which are useful for reproducibility, at the cost of installation speed. The speed is a noticeable issue with the tool. &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;pip freeze&lt;/tt&gt; is good enough for this, even if there are no dependency classes (production vs development) and no hashes (which have minor benefits) &lt;a class=&quot;footnote-reference&quot; href=&quot;https://chriswarrick.com/blog/2018/07/17/pipenv-promises-a-lot-delivers-very-little/#id13&quot; id=&quot;id11&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hatch attempts to replace many packaging tools, but some of its practices and ideas can be questionable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Poetry supports the same niche Pipenv does, while also adding the ability to create packages and improving over many gripes of Pipenv. A notable issue is the use of a custom all-encompassing file format, which makes switching tools more difficult (vendor lock-in).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pip, setup.py, and virtualenv — the traditional, tried-and-true tools — are still available, undergoing constant development. Using them can lead to a simpler, better experience. Also of note, tools like virtualenvwrapper can manage virtualenvs better than the aforementioned new Python tools, because it is based on shell scripts (which can modify the enivironment).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 21:10:23 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>BerislavLopac</dc:creator>
<og:title>Pipenv: promises a lot, delivers very little</og:title>
<og:url>https://chriswarrick.com/blog/2018/07/17/pipenv-promises-a-lot-delivers-very-little/</og:url>
<og:description>Pipenv is a Python packaging tool that does one thing reasonably well. It tries to promote itself as much more than it is.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://chriswarrick.com/blog/2018/07/17/pipenv-promises-a-lot-delivers-very-little/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Internal Tensions at Facebook Are Boiling Over</title>
<link>https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/charliewarzel/facebooks-tensions-zuckerberg-sandberg</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/charliewarzel/facebooks-tensions-zuckerberg-sandberg</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz-image xs-mb4 xs-relative subbuzz-image--outset-both&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-image&quot;&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;flex xs-flex-column&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;subbuzz__attribution js-subbuzz__attribution xs-text-6 xs-block&quot;&gt;BuzzFeed News&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz-text xs-mb4 xs-relative&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-text&quot; readability=&quot;81.070154577883&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a year teeming with scandals and missteps, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/14/technology/facebook-data-russia-election-racism.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Facebook’s&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/ryanmac/emails-show-sheryl-sandberg-aware-facebooks-definers-george&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;latest&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/charliewarzel/facebook-soros-scandal-research&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;fiasco&lt;/a&gt; has inspired a clutter of leaks, finger pointing, and internal conversations about the future of the company and its leadership. And after more than a year of bad press, internal tensions are reaching a boiling point and are now spilling out into public view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tumult is surprising given Facebook’s history as a tight-lipped organization where employees had little incentive to leak information or voice dissent outside the company’s walls. Throughout the crises, Facebook’s CEO Mark Zuckerberg, who maintains majority shareholder control, has proven remarkably immune to outside pressure and criticism — from politicians, investors, and the press — leaving his employees as perhaps his most important stakeholders. Now, as its stock price declines and the company’s mission of connecting the world is challenged, the voices inside are growing louder and public comments, as well as private conversations shared with BuzzFeed News, suggest newfound uncertainty about Facebook’s future direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Internally, the conflict seems to have divided Facebook into three camps: those loyal to Zuckerberg and chief operating officer Sheryl Sandberg; those who see the current scandals as proof of a larger corporate meltdown; and a group who see the entire narrative — including the portrayal of the company’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/ryanmac/soros-facebook-definers-research&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;hiring of communications consulting firm Definers Public Affairs&lt;/a&gt; — as examples of biased media attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s otherwise rational, sane people who’re in Mark’s orbit spouting full-blown anti-media rhetoric, saying that the press is ganging up on Facebook,” a former senior employee told BuzzFeed News. “It’s the bunker mentality. These people have been under siege for 600 days now. They’re getting tired, getting cranky — the only survival strategy is to quit or fully buy in.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a statement to BuzzFeed News, a Facebook spokesperson called this “a challenging time.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We are more determined than ever to continue making progress on the issues we’ve faced,” they said. “People at Facebook are focused on building products that help people connect and have a positive impact in the world.”&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two former employees said the spate of negative reports has cast a shadow over the company in recent weeks. Current and former employees describe a tense and, at times, hostile atmosphere inside the company, one in which both senior employees and even staunch loyalists are contemplating their futures.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz-pullquote xs-relative col xs-col-12 xs-z1 xs-mb4 md-mb2 md-col-5 md-pr4&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-quote&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People are “hoping for a Sundar or Dara moment.”&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz-text xs-mb4 xs-relative&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-text&quot; readability=&quot;78.111990008326&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People are “hoping for a Sundar or Dara moment,” one former senior Facebook employee told BuzzFeed News, referring to past leadership changes at Google and Uber in which founding employees stepped aside from top jobs. A second senior employee echoed the view, suggesting that some inside the ranks are looking for a shakeup to come from the outside. The chatter has made its way outside of the company’s Menlo Park headquarters. “Senior people there know the only way out of this is by hiring a Dara,” a senior executive at a rival company told BuzzFeed News referring to Dara Khosrowshahi, the Uber CEO brought in to replace cofounder Travis Kalanick last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another former senior employee noted a growing sense of paranoia among current employees. “Now, people now have burner phones to talk shit about the company — not even to reporters, just to other employees,” they told BuzzFeed News.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some former workers have been empowered to bypass the press altogether and speak openly about their situations. Last month, Mark S. Luckie, a strategic partner manager for global influencers who quit in November, posted a 2,500-word memo that he had previously sent internally at the company to his personal Facebook to highlight what he saw as the company’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/charliewarzel/former-employee-tells-facebook-in-a-memo-facebook-has-a&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;“black people problem.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“In some buildings, there are more ‘Black Lives Matter’ posters than there are actual black people,” Luckie wrote, adding that “Black employees are commonly told ‘I didn’t know black people worked at Facebook.’” That post later mysteriously disappeared from Facebook after being flagged for violating the social network’s “community standards” before it was later restored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These public protestations may be just the beginning for Facebook. Three former employees who spoke anonymously with BuzzFeed News for fear of retribution said that they did not sign paperwork that included language around nondisparagement, and in some cases forfeited their severance pay, upon departing the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some employees at Facebook are required to sign nondisclosure agreements, preventing them from sharing trade secrets, when they first join and are encouraged to sign nondisparagement agreements upon their departure. By not signing that paperwork on the way out, those employees reserved the right to speak openly about their experiences at the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;“That’s the Sheryl I know”&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz-image xs-mb4 xs-relative xs-mb4 subbuzz-image--align-center&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-image&quot;&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;flex xs-flex-column&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;subbuzz__attribution js-subbuzz__attribution xs-text-6 xs-block&quot;&gt;Drew Angerer / Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz-text xs-mb4 xs-relative&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-text&quot; readability=&quot;65.878729547642&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While chairman and CEO Zuckerberg maintains complete control over Facebook, it’s Sandberg who’s taken the brunt of the blame for the company’s recent scandals. As the person who oversees business operations and Facebook’s policy and communications efforts, the COO came under heavy fire for revelations surrounding her role in the disclosure of Russian disinformation efforts during the 2016 US presidential election, and for her subordinates’ hiring of a public relations consultancy that performed opposition research on billionaire investor George Soros.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sandberg has denied knowledge of the company’s hiring of the public relations firm, Definers Public Affairs, or its political work, but &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/ryanmac/emails-show-sheryl-sandberg-aware-facebooks-definers-george&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;recently admitted that she sent an email&lt;/a&gt; asking for research on Soros after he made public comments about Facebook at the World Economic Forum in January. Facebook maintained that request was independent of what Definers ended up working on regarding Soros later that spring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The external pressure on Sandberg has divided employees across the company. In some &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-11-26/facebook-s-sheryl-sandberg-is-tainted-by-crisis-after-crisis&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;recent stories,&lt;/a&gt; Facebook’s second-in-command has been portrayed as preoccupied with her own legacy, and as an executive who surrounded herself with loyalists and sometimes prioritized her own brand above the company’s interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But some Facebook employees have taken issue with that narrative. Shortly after the publication of a November &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/14/technology/facebook-data-russia-election-racism.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;New York Times story&lt;/a&gt; about Facebook in crisis, many employees posted to the company’s internal communications groups, including one called “Women @ Facebook,” voicing their support for Facebook’s COO and sharing personal experiences of working with or for Sandberg, according to two people who had seen the comments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some Facebook employees have also shared their views publicly. Matt Jacobson, Facebook’s head of market development and one of its longest-serving employees, called the “roughest of news cycles” a “ very personal attack on Sheryl Sandberg as a leader and a human being” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/jake/posts/10108813774387296&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;in an internal note&lt;/a&gt; he later published to his personal Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz-pullquote xs-relative col xs-col-12 xs-z1 xs-mb4 md-mb2 md-col-5 md-pr4&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-quote&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“One does not simply fire the author of &lt;em&gt;Lean In&lt;/em&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz-text xs-mb4 xs-relative&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-text&quot; readability=&quot;102.15711754282&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Schadenfreude runs deep, especially when it comes to someone who has succeeded and brought so many along with her,” he wrote last month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That echoed &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/AdamMGrant/posts/2118380851545995&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a Facebook post by Adam Grant,&lt;/a&gt; the co-author of Sandberg’s second book, &lt;em&gt;Option B&lt;/em&gt;, and a board member at her foundation Lean In. The post, which objected to the so-called vilification of Sandberg’s character, found sympathetic ears among many Facebook employees, including Justin Osofsky, vice president of global operations and corporate development, and vice president of global marketing solutions Carolyn Everson, who thanked Grant for “sharing the real Sheryl Sandberg with the world.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Sheryl's investment in so many others and particularly in causes for women is something I’m witness to daily,” Janelle Gale, Facebook’s vice president of human resources, commented on the post. “That’s the Sheryl I know too.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;“An intense culture of conformity”&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Blind, a semi-public app that allows current and former employees with a company email to post anonymously, Facebook employees on Facebook-related message boards are openly speculating about and arguing over Sandberg’s fate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The board is being questioned for not taking action, but Zuck will side with her like he is spellbound,” one user wrote, asking if the company could find a solution to its leadership struggles. “Shall we have a walkout to let her go like what Google employees did?” another countered, referencing the worker action taken at the search giant in which &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/matthewchampion/google-walkout-sexual-misconduct&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;thousands of employees marched&lt;/a&gt; to protest the company’s policies around sexual harassment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Others argued that bad optics would prevent the company from removing Sandberg, a noted feminist author. “One does not simply fire the author of ‘Lean In’ and pretty much the sole female executive in top leadership,” one Blind user wrote. Another remarked that Sandberg’s personal image was politically polarizing. “Her left-leaning brand has hurt us considerably, we need to mend fences and be seen to be a platform for the left and the right going forward.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discussions across Facebook’s Blind page quickly turn tense at the mention of Sandberg. A user with the username “SherylS” expressed frustration at those in the company revering Sandberg as a women’s icon and leader. “It’s time to stand up to these fake opportunist feminist champions though,” they wrote. “‘Give me opportunities to succeed!! I’m a victim!! Lean in!!” the post read.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the disagreement centers on social justice–minded individuals inside the company, pointing to an internal Facebook Workplace group called “Let’s Fix Facebook”: “Just go read ‘let’s fix Facebook’ for a bit and see all the sjw complainers.” Indeed, some inside Blind’s current and former Facebook employee group debated whether Sandberg was insulated from legitimate criticism due to her defenders “playing the woman card.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Again [it's] the female card that has caused so much damage in such a short time, not just at Facebook,” another poster wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some called Sandberg “a shrewd businesswoman” who would not be intimidated into leaving, while others suggested that Sandberg is bearing the brunt of the criticism that should be directed toward Zuckerberg. “Can’t get anything to stick on Mark? Call the lady COO incompetent,” another user wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz-pullquote xs-relative col xs-col-12 xs-z1 xs-mb4 md-mb2 md-col-5 md-pr4&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-quote&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Can’t get anything to stick on Mark? Call the lady COO incompetent.”&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz-text xs-mb4 xs-relative&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-text&quot; readability=&quot;82&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in Blind posts viewed by BuzzFeed News concerning Facebook’s leadership, Zuckerberg is infrequently mentioned and often only brought up in reference to Sandberg’s future. “Zuck is too sentimental towards her and it’s hurt his judgement of the situation,” one post read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A common narrative across Blind and shared by some current and former senior employee is the notion that Facebook’s troubles have been exaggerated and perpetuated by unjust media coverage. They see the blame cast on the company by the public and the press as reactionary and, in the case of a recent bombshell report by the New York Times, even inaccurate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The media will keep attacking and exposing us with more leaks from the inside...this will all go on until she is gone and there is a shakeup,” one person posted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I still don’t know what has Sheryl done to deserve being fired? The last I checked most allegations seemed like baseless media propaganda. What am I missing?” one wrote, while another suggested that the “media keeps talking about anti semitic conspiracy theories but the articles lack any clear explanation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While only one window into the views of current and former employees, the Blind threads viewed by BuzzFeed News depict a company currently grappling with its culture and issues of loyalty, particularly surrounding Sandberg. Some posts appear even to encourage unwavering, resolute support for leadership during the crisis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I love Sheryl. Because Mark loves Sheryl. This is Mark’s company, not yours. He knows Sheryl better than you do and knows what this company needs better than you do. He gives you so much you get confused in your entitled ass that this is your company,” one user wrote. “I trust Mark. And if Mark drives the company into the ground it’s his company to drive into the ground. Go work somewhere else or go start your own company if you know so much better than him.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not all agree. “Funny, Hitler’s followers said something similar. We all know how that went,” one user replied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Broadly, others seem to be questioning the “sycophantic” nature of the conversations across Facebook’s internal Workplace system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We have an intense culture of conformity,” one user said. “It could be that this pressure to drink the Kool-Aid and to only talk about positive things is a reason behind the large number of leaks we suffer.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz-pullquote xs-relative col xs-col-12 xs-z1 xs-mb4 md-mb2 md-col-5 md-pr4&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-quote&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“2020 will be another shit show.”&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz-text xs-mb4 xs-relative&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-text&quot; readability=&quot;60&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s really seeped in the last few years,” another added. “Election season is always the worst too, 2020 will be another shit show.” A third user added, “In this company, if you tell the truth, you are dead.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, as Facebook's employees debate her future publicly and privately, Sandberg has set her sights on damage control. Still reeling from the revelation that Facebook’s communications and policy team hired a public affairs team to investigate George Soros, Sandberg has been trying to make amends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to two sources, she attempted to call Soros last month, within days of the reports about Definers, and left a message after he didn’t pick up. Soros has yet to call her back because he’s been traveling, a source told BuzzFeed News.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It appears he’ll be traveling for a while,” the source said. ●&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;With reporting from Caroline O’Donovan.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 19:35:38 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>laurex</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/charliewarzel/facebooks-tensions-zuckerberg-sandberg</og:url>
<og:image>https://img.buzzfeed.com/buzzfeed-static/static/2018-12/5/9/enhanced/buzzfeed-prod-web-01/original-3118-1544021140-2.jpg?crop=990:518;0,142</og:image>
<og:title>Mark Zuckerberg's Biggest Problem: Internal Tensions At Facebook Are Boiling Over</og:title>
<og:description>“It’s the bunker mentality. These people have been under siege for 600 days now. They’re getting tired, getting cranky — the only survival strategy is to quit or fully buy in.”</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/charliewarzel/facebooks-tensions-zuckerberg-sandberg</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Send Noncompete Agreements Back to the Middle Ages</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2018-12-05/noncompete-agreements-are-bad-for-employees-and-the-economy</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2018-12-05/noncompete-agreements-are-bad-for-employees-and-the-economy</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2018-12-05/noncompete-agreements-are-bad-for-employees-and-the-economy&quot;&gt;https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2018-12-05/noncompete-agreements-are-bad-for-employees-and-the-economy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18611452&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18611452&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 326&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 147&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 19:15:31 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>adventured</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/tosv2.html?vid=&amp;uuid=289a8560-f92d-11e8-893a-7f28afe8a77e&amp;url=L29waW5pb24vYXJ0aWNsZXMvMjAxOC0xMi0wNS9ub25jb21wZXRlLWFncmVlbWVudHMtYXJlLWJhZC1mb3ItZW1wbG95ZWVzLWFuZC10aGUtZWNvbm9teQ==</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>At 22 years old, Postgres might just be the most advanced database yet</title>
<link>https://arcentry.com/blog/postgres-might-just-be-the-most-advanced-database-ever/#</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://arcentry.com/blog/postgres-might-just-be-the-most-advanced-database-ever/#</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://pbs.twimg.com/profile_images/717729364822134785/APDm2K-o_400x400.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://arcentry.com/blog/postgres-might-just-be-the-most-advanced-database-ever/postgres.svg&quot; alt=&quot;PostgreSQL Logo&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a techy, many of the debates I engage in can be boiled down to just one question: Should we pick the new thing or the proven one? As passionate as this question is discussed, there are a handful of technologies where the answer is easy: Why not both?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Postgres is such a technology. Originally released in 1996 (and effectively developed since 1982), it is now 22 years old - yet in many respects, it is the most modern database management system there is. Not only does it come with a simply mindboggling set of features, but it also transcends being a pure database and evolved into a fully programmable, integrated data environment, complete with its own programming language PL/pgSQL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's any number of marvels one can discuss in regards to Postgres - but for this article, I'd like to shed light on the five extraordinary features that made it our backend of choice for Arcentry:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;pub-sub-messaging&quot;&gt;Pub/Sub Messaging&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Postgres can be used as a clusterable message broker. Granted, it doesn't come with the featureset that purpose-built solutions like RabbitMQ or Kafka offer, but its integration of event-based messaging into the wider data-context makes it extremely valuable. Arcentry's on-premise version, for instance, makes use of this pattern. We use Postgres-Messaging as the backbone for horizontally scalable deployments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever a user makes a change to any diagram, Arcentry issues a request to a server which merges the update into a binary JSON document stored in Postgres. Once the write is confirmed, a trigger emits an event that all other connected servers are subscribed to which in turn forwards the update to its active users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This gives us an easy way to provide horizontally scalable realtime updates with strong consistency - all from a single external dependency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;triggers&quot;&gt;Triggers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Triggers are functions that run before or after data is manipulated. They are a fantastic way to build validation, transformation and derived logic directly into the database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Triggers also present a simple way to extend existing database functionality. For example, take customers asking for an immutable audit log of changes to Arcentry's account table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather than writing an additional query or service endpoint, we simply programmed a trigger into Postgres that runs whenever a row in the accounts table is altered and writes a copy of the current row, complete with timestamp and the userId that initiated the change to a separate audit table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;foreign-data-wrappers&quot;&gt;Foreign Data Wrappers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, it is nice to integrate a user's existing Database into Arcentry - whether to query user accounts or to store document data within an established structure. There is - of course - any number of ways to achieve this, but a particularly convenient one are Postgres' &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.postgresql.org/wiki/Foreign_data_wrappers&quot;&gt;Foreign Data Wrappers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are endpoints that connect Postgres to any number of other data sources, say MongoDB, Redis, MySQL or even CSV or JSON files. As far as the query statement is concerned, these sources are just regular Postgres tables that can be joined, searched, referenced and become an organic part of the database - making Postgres a powerful integration tool and potential access point for data-lake setups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;jsonb&quot;&gt;JSONB&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many databases store JSON or its binary representation, JSONB - and I get that this won't spark too much excitement anymore. But Postgres' manipulation functions make JSON a first class citizen within a table based, relational database. Whether its outputting query results as a nested JSON structure or parsing JSON on the fly, Postgres can handle it beautifully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;add-ons&quot;&gt;Add-ons&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At times, however, neither PL/pgSQL nor Triggers are enough to achieve the functionality one needs. With many other databases this would simply be the end of it - but Postgres is impressively extendable. Writing Postgres Addons is not an easy task (trust me, I tried), but fortunately, many talented engineers have done the work for me and built extensions that turn Postgres into an entirely different product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take for instance &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.postgis.org/&quot;&gt;PostGIS&lt;/a&gt; that turns the Postgres server into a fully fledged spatial database for geographic information systems (GIS).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or how about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pipelinedb.com/&quot;&gt;PipelineDB&lt;/a&gt; that turns Postgres into a timeseries store/ stream processor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's any number of Postgres extensions, tools and GUIs, an overview over which can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dhamaniasad/awesome-postgres&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-granddad-hipster&quot;&gt;A granddad-hipster&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What makes all this truly stand out is the example that Postgres sets: Remaining relevant for 22 years is an almost impossible feat for any software - but keeping a strong focus and investing decades into improving, refining and optimizing an already strong core can create a piece of technology that today is as relevant as it was back in the 1990s.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 17:49:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>max_sendfeld</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://arcentry.com/blog/postgres-might-just-be-the-most-advanced-database-ever/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>&amp;#039;Dark fluid&amp;#039; with negative mass could dominate the universe</title>
<link>https://theconversation.com/bizarre-dark-fluid-with-negative-mass-could-dominate-the-universe-what-my-research-suggests-107922</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://theconversation.com/bizarre-dark-fluid-with-negative-mass-could-dominate-the-universe-what-my-research-suggests-107922</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;It’s embarrassing, but astrophysicists are the first to admit it. Our best &lt;a href=&quot;http://cosmology.berkeley.edu/Education/CosmologyEssays/The_Standard_Cosmology.html&quot;&gt;theoretical model&lt;/a&gt; can only explain 5% of the universe. The remaining 95% is famously made up almost entirely of invisible, unknown material dubbed &lt;a href=&quot;https://theconversation.com/the-experiments-trying-to-crack-physics-biggest-question-what-is-dark-energy-52917&quot;&gt;dark energy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://theconversation.com/from-machos-to-wimps-meet-the-top-five-candidates-for-dark-matter-51516&quot;&gt;dark matter&lt;/a&gt;. So even though there are a billion trillion stars in the observable universe, they are actually extremely rare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two mysterious dark substances can only be inferred from gravitational effects. Dark matter may be an invisible material, but it exerts a gravitational force on surrounding matter that we can measure. Dark energy is a repulsive force that makes the universe expand at an accelerating rate. The two have always been treated as separate phenomena. But my new study, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1712.07962&quot;&gt;published in Astronomy and Astrophysics&lt;/a&gt;, suggests they may both be part of the same strange concept – a single, unified “dark fluid” of negative masses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Negative masses are a hypothetical form of matter that would have a type of negative gravity – repelling all other material around them. Unlike familiar positive mass matter, if a negative mass was pushed, it would accelerate towards you rather than away from you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Negative masses are not a new idea in cosmology. Just like normal matter, negative mass particles would become more spread out as the universe expands – meaning that their repulsive force would become weaker over time. However, studies have shown that the force driving the accelerating expansion of the universe is relentlessly constant. This inconsistency has previously led researchers to abandon this idea. If a dark fluid exists, it should not thin out over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the new study, I propose a modification to Einstein’s theory of general relativity to allow negative masses to not only exist, but to be created continuously. “Matter creation” was already included in an early &lt;a href=&quot;https://theconversation.com/stephen-hawkings-phd-thesis-crashed-its-host-website-heres-what-it-says-in-simple-terms-86351&quot;&gt;alternative theory to the Big Bang&lt;/a&gt;, known as the Steady State model. The main assumption was that (positive mass) matter was continuously created to replenish material as the universe expands. We now know from observational evidence that this is incorrect. However, that doesn’t mean that negative mass matter can’t be continuously created. I show that this assumed dark fluid is never spread too thinly. Instead it behaves exactly like dark energy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;440&quot; height=&quot;260&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/56AIR9ZDv3w?wmode=transparent&amp;amp;start=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also developed a 3D computer model of this hypothetical universe to see if it could also explain the physical nature of dark matter. Dark matter was introduced to explain the fact that galaxies are spinning &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Galaxy_rotation_curve&quot;&gt;much faster than our models predict&lt;/a&gt;. This implies that some additional invisible matter must be present to prevent them from spinning themselves apart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My model shows that the surrounding repulsive force from dark fluid can also hold a galaxy together. The gravity from the positive mass galaxy attracts negative masses from all directions, and as the negative mass fluid comes nearer to the galaxy it in turn exerts a stronger repulsive force onto the galaxy that allows it to spin at higher speeds without flying apart. It therefore appears that a simple minus sign may solve one of the longest standing problems in physics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Is the universe really this weird?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One may argue that this sounds a little far fetched. But while negative masses are bizarre, they are considerably less strange than you may immediately think. For starters, these effects may only seem peculiar and unfamiliar to us, as we reside in a region dominated by positive mass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether physically real or not, negative masses already have a theoretical role in a vast number of areas. Air bubbles in water can be modelled as having a negative mass. Recent laboratory research has also generated particles that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rochester.edu/newscenter/vamivakas-microcavity-negative-mass-generate-lasers-290202/&quot;&gt;behave exactly as they would if they had negative mass&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And physicists are already comfortable with the concept of negative energy density. According to quantum mechanics, &lt;a href=&quot;https://theconversation.com/what-is-nothing-martin-rees-qanda-101498&quot;&gt;empty space is made up of a field of fluctuating background energy&lt;/a&gt; that can be negative in places – giving rise to waves and virtual particles that pop into and out of existence. This can even create a tiny force that can be measured in the lab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new study could help solve many problems in modern physics. String theory, which is our &lt;a href=&quot;https://theconversation.com/stephen-hawking-had-pinned-his-hopes-on-m-theory-to-fully-explain-the-universe-heres-what-it-is-93440&quot;&gt;best hope for unifying&lt;/a&gt; the physics of the quantum world with Einstein’s theory of the cosmos, is currently seen as being incompatible with observational evidence. However, string theory does suggest that the energy in empty space must be negative, which corroborates the theoretical expectations for a negative mass dark fluid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, the team behind the &lt;a href=&quot;http://iopscience.iop.org/article/10.1086/300499/fulltext/&quot;&gt;groundbreaking discovery of an accelerating universe&lt;/a&gt; surprisingly detected evidence for a negative mass cosmology, but took the reasonable precaution of interpreting these controversial findings as “unphysical”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The theory could also solve the problem of measuring the universe’s expansion. This is explained by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://theconversation.com/game-changing-resolution-whose-name-on-the-laws-of-physics-for-an-expanding-universe-102099&quot;&gt;Hubble-Lemaître Law&lt;/a&gt;, the observation that more distant galaxies are moving away at a faster rate. The relationship between the speed and the distance of a galaxy is set by the “Hubble constant”, but measurements of it have continued to vary. This has led to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://theconversation.com/the-universes-rate-of-expansion-is-in-dispute-and-we-may-need-new-physics-to-solve-it-100154&quot;&gt;crisis in cosmology&lt;/a&gt;. Fortunately, a negative mass cosmology mathematically predicts that the Hubble “constant” should vary over time. Clearly, there is evidence that this weird and unconventional new theory deserves our scientific attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Where to go from here&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creator of the field of cosmology, Albert Einstein, did – along with other scientists including Stephen Hawking – consider negative masses. In fact, in 1918 Einstein even wrote that his theory of general relativity &lt;a href=&quot;https://einsteinpapers.press.princeton.edu/vol7-trans/47&quot;&gt;may have to be modified to include them&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite these efforts, a negative mass cosmology could be wrong. The theory seems to provide answers to so many currently open questions that scientists will – quite rightly – be rather suspicious. However, it is often the out-of-the-box ideas that provide answers to longstanding problems. The strong accumulating evidence has now grown to the point that we must consider this unusual possibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The largest telescope to ever be built – &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.skatelescope.org/&quot;&gt;the Square Kilometre Array (SKA)&lt;/a&gt; – will measure the distribution of galaxies throughout the history of the universe. I’m planning to use the SKA to compare its observations to theoretical predictions for both a negative mass cosmology and the standard one – helping to ultimately prove whether negative masses exist in our reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://images.theconversation.com/files/248427/original/file-20181203-194935-1cka8ht.jpg?ixlib=rb-1.1.0&amp;amp;q=45&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;w=754&amp;amp;fit=clip&quot; srcset=&quot;https://images.theconversation.com/files/248427/original/file-20181203-194935-1cka8ht.jpg?ixlib=rb-1.1.0&amp;amp;q=45&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;w=600&amp;amp;h=328&amp;amp;fit=crop&amp;amp;dpr=1 600w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/248427/original/file-20181203-194935-1cka8ht.jpg?ixlib=rb-1.1.0&amp;amp;q=30&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;w=600&amp;amp;h=328&amp;amp;fit=crop&amp;amp;dpr=2 1200w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/248427/original/file-20181203-194935-1cka8ht.jpg?ixlib=rb-1.1.0&amp;amp;q=15&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;w=600&amp;amp;h=328&amp;amp;fit=crop&amp;amp;dpr=3 1800w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/248427/original/file-20181203-194935-1cka8ht.jpg?ixlib=rb-1.1.0&amp;amp;q=45&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;w=754&amp;amp;h=412&amp;amp;fit=crop&amp;amp;dpr=1 754w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/248427/original/file-20181203-194935-1cka8ht.jpg?ixlib=rb-1.1.0&amp;amp;q=30&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;w=754&amp;amp;h=412&amp;amp;fit=crop&amp;amp;dpr=2 1508w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/248427/original/file-20181203-194935-1cka8ht.jpg?ixlib=rb-1.1.0&amp;amp;q=15&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;w=754&amp;amp;h=412&amp;amp;fit=crop&amp;amp;dpr=3 2262w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 1466px) 754px, (max-width: 599px) 100vw, (min-width: 600px) 600px, 237px&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;The Square Kilometre Array may provide answers.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;attribution&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;source&quot;&gt;SKA Project Development Office and Swinburne Astronomy Productions&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;license&quot; href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/&quot;&gt;CC BY-SA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is clear is that this new theory generates a wealth of new questions. So as with all scientific discoveries, the adventure does not end here. In fact, the quest to understand the true nature of this beautiful, unified, and – perhaps polarised – universe has only just begun.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 15:57:15 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pavel_lishin</dc:creator>
<og:title>Bizarre 'dark fluid' with negative mass could dominate the universe – what my research suggests</og:title>
<og:description>Forget about dark matter and dark energy, new research suggests that the existence of 'dark fluid' may solve some of the biggest mysteries in physics.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://images.theconversation.com/files/248811/original/file-20181204-34154-z1obya.jpg?ixlib=rb-1.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=1356&amp;h=668&amp;fit=crop</og:image>
<og:url>http://theconversation.com/bizarre-dark-fluid-with-negative-mass-could-dominate-the-universe-what-my-research-suggests-107922</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://theconversation.com/bizarre-dark-fluid-with-negative-mass-could-dominate-the-universe-what-my-research-suggests-107922</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Facebook&amp;#039;s seized files published by MPs</title>
<link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-46456695</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-46456695</guid>
<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption full-width lead&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                &lt;img class=&quot;js-image-replace&quot; alt=&quot;Facebook documents&quot; src=&quot;https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/320/cpsprodpb/13D3D/production/_104631218_mediaitem104631215.jpg&quot; width=&quot;976&quot; height=&quot;549&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body__introduction&quot;&gt;The UK parliament's fake news inquiry has published a cache of seized Facebook documents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The correspondence &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.parliament.uk/documents/commons-committees/culture-media-and-sport/Note-by-Chair-and-selected-documents-ordered-from-Six4Three.pdf&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link-external&quot;&gt;includes internal emails sent between Mark Zuckerberg and the social network's staff&lt;/a&gt;. The emails were obtained from the chief of a software firm that is suing the tech giant.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;About 250 pages have been published, some of which are marked &quot;highly confidential&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Facebook had objected to their release.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Damian Collins MP, the chair of the parliamentary committee involved, highlighted several &quot;key issues&quot; in an introductory note. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He wrote that:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul class=&quot;story-body__unordered-list&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;Facebook allowed some companies to maintain &quot;full access&quot; to users' friends data even after announcing changes to its platform in 2014/2015 to limit what developers' could see. &quot;It is not clear that there was any user consent for this, nor how Facebook decided which companies should be whitelisted,&quot; Mr Collins wrote&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;Facebook had been aware that an update to its Android app that let it collect records of users' calls and texts would be controversial. &quot;To mitigate any bad PR, Facebook planned to make it as hard as possible for users to know that this was one of the underlying features,&quot; Mr Collins wrote&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;Facebook used data provided by the Israeli analytics firm Onavo to determine which other mobile apps were being downloaded and used by the public. It then used this knowledge to decide which apps to acquire or otherwise treat as a threat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;there was evidence that Facebook's refusal to share data with some apps caused them to fail&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;there had been much discussion of the financial value of providing access to friends' data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;social-embed&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;social-embed-post social-embed-twitter&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;embed embed-twitter&quot; readability=&quot;5.1471321695761&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;embed-region&quot; role=&quot;region&quot; aria-label=&quot;Twitter post by @DamianCollins&quot; readability=&quot;6.0049875311721&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a class=&quot;off-screen jump-link&quot; href=&quot;#jump-linkhttps://twitter.com/DamianCollins/status/1070324910109675525&quot;&gt;Skip Twitter post  by @DamianCollins&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;twitter-wrap&quot; readability=&quot;7.4617737003058&quot;&gt;
                &lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot; readability=&quot;8.55&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;I believe there is considerable public interest in releasing these documents. They raise important questions about how Facebook treats users data, their policies for working with app developers, and how they exercise their dominant position in the social media market.&lt;/p&gt;— Damian Collins (@DamianCollins) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/DamianCollins/status/1070324910109675525?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;December 5, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

            
            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;p class=&quot;off-screen&quot; id=&quot;jump-linkhttps://twitter.com/DamianCollins/status/1070324910109675525&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;End of Twitter post  by @DamianCollins&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In response, Facebook has said that the documents had been presented in a &quot;very misleading manner&quot; and required additional context.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;We stand by the platform changes we made in 2015 to stop a person from sharing their friends' data with developers,&quot; said a spokeswoman.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Like any business, we had many internal conversations about the various ways we could build a sustainable business model for our platform. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;But the facts are clear: we've never sold people's data.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr Zuckerberg has also &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/zuck/posts/10105559172610321&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link-external&quot;&gt;posted a personal response on his Facebook page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;I understand there is a lot of scrutiny on how we run our systems. That's healthy given the vast number of people who use our services around the world, and it is right that we are constantly asked to explain what we do,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;But it's also important that the coverage of what we do - including the explanation of these internal documents - doesn't misrepresent our actions or motives.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;Tactics revealed&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The correspondence includes emails between Facebook and several other tech firms, in which the social network appears to agree to add third-party apps to a &quot;whitelist&quot; of those given permission to access data about users' friends.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This might be used, for example, to allow an app's users to continue seeing which of their Facebook friends were using the same service.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape has-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
                 &lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;Netflix&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    Netflix tapped into Facebook friends lists to let users see what titles their contacts had watched and rated highly
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;They include:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul class=&quot;story-body__unordered-list&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;the dating service Badoo, its spin-off Hot or Not, and Bumble - another dating app that it had invested in&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;the car pick-up service Lyft&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;the video-streaming service Netflix&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;the home rental service Airbnb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, others including the ticket sales service Ticketmaster, Twitter's short-video platform Vine and the connected-cars specialist Airbiquity seem to have been denied the privilege.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Among the emails that have been published are the following extracts:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;Blocking Vine&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;The following concerns a decision to prevent Twitter's short-form video service having access to users' friends lists. It is dated 24 January 2012.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Justin Osofksy&lt;/strong&gt; (Facebook vice president):&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Twitter launched Vine today which lets you shoot multiple short video segments to make one single, 6-second video... Unless anyone raises objections, we will shut down their friends API access today. We've prepared reactive PR, and I will let Jana know our decision.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mark Zuckerberg&lt;/strong&gt; (Facebook chief executive):&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Yup, go for it.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;Android update&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;The following is part of a discussion about giving Facebook's Android app permission to read users' call logs. It is dated 4 February 2015.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Michael LeBeau&lt;/strong&gt; (Facebook product manager):&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;As you know all the growth team is planning on shipping a permissions update on Android at the end of this month. They are going to include the 'read call log' permission... This is a pretty high-risk thing to do from a PR perspective but it appears that the growth team will charge ahead and do it...[The danger is] screenshot of the scary Android permissions screen becomes a meme (as it has in the past), propagates around the web, it gets press attention, and enterprising journalists dig into what exactly the new update is requesting, then write stories about &quot;Facebook uses new Android update to pry into your private life in ever more terrifying ways&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;Data leaks&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;The following is from a discussion in which Mark Zuckerberg mulled the idea of selling developers access to users' friends' data. It is dated October 2012, pre-dating the quiz involved in the Cambridge Analytica scandal. It was sent to Sam Mullin, who was vice president of product management.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mark Zuckerberg&lt;/strong&gt; (Facebook chief executive):&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;It's not at all clear to me here that we have a model that will actually make us the revenue we want at scale. I'm getting more on board with locking down some parts of platform, including friends' data and potentially email addresses for mobile apps. I'm generally sceptical that there is as much data leak strategic risk as you think... I think we leak info to developers but I just can't think of any instances where that data has leaked from developer to developer and caused a real issue for us.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;Membership fees&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;The following is from an email sent by Mark Zuckerberg to several of his executives in which he explains why he does not think making users pay for Facebook would be a good idea. It is dated 19 November 2012.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mark Zuckerberg&lt;/strong&gt; (Facebook chief executive):&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;The question is whether we could charge and still achieve ubiquity. Theoretically, if we could do that, it would be better to get ubiquity and get paid. My sense is there may be some price we could charge that wouldn't interfere with ubiquity, but this price wouldn't be enough to make us real money. Conversely, we could probably make real money of we were willing to sacrifice ubiquity, but that doesn't seem like the right trade here.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
            </description>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 14:53:47 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>AndrewDucker</dc:creator>
<og:title>Facebook chief's emails exposed by MPs</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>More than 200 pages of confidential emails are shared online by Parliament's fake news inquiry.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-46456695</og:url>
<og:image>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/13D3D/production/_104631218_mediaitem104631215.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-GB</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-46456695</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Thieves boosting signal from key fobs inside homes to steal vehicles</title>
<link>https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/toronto/car-thefts-rising-1.4930890</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/toronto/car-thefts-rising-1.4930890</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In late August, Sean Panchal and his wife had just settled down to relax after putting their newborn to bed when they saw car lights through the curtains of their Danforth-area home in Toronto.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;At first, they thought it may be another car going by.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Later, they discovered someone had hopped into their Toyota RAV4 and driven away.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;I sort of went outside to see if I could see anything or see which direction they went, and that was essentially it,&quot; Panchal said.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Later that week, police found the car in a Scarborough parking lot with the plates and all of the vehicle's contents, including two strollers and a car seat, removed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Panchal did get his car replaced through insurance, but months later, he still wonders how the thief got inside.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;placeholder&quot;&gt;

&lt;span&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://i.cbc.ca/1.4930922.1543874161!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/panchal-car.jpg&quot; class=&quot;loaded largeImage&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;leadimage-caption&quot;&gt;Panchal says the thieves completely emptied his car before dumping it in a Scarborough parking lot in suburban Toronto.  (Sean Panchal)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Markham automotive security specialist Jeff Bates, owner of Lockdown Security, wireless key fobs have a role to play in many recent car thefts, with thieves intercepting and rerouting their signals — even from inside homes — to open and steal cars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;We've seen it anecdotally through some of our clients that have come in that have some new vehicles that surprisingly have gotten stolen,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bates said the spike is so great, a local Toronto car dealership selling new Lexus vehicles asked his company to install tracking systems on all high-end SUVs because so many of their vehicles are being stolen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of his customers, who came from the dealership, had his car stolen three times by thieves rerouting the key-fob signal, according to Bates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The increased need for Bates's security services comes as police are seeing a spike in auto thefts across the GTA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Toronto, they're up 30 per cent compared to this time last year. The Toronto Police Service couldn't provide a representative to speak about the rise, but told CBC Toronto they'll hold a news conference on high-end vehicle thefts this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Durham, auto thefts are up 16 per cent this year, and in Halton, there have been 517 cases so far this year, compared to 490 in total last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;placeholder&quot;&gt;

&lt;span&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://i.cbc.ca/1.4930926.1543874209!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/car-thefts.jpg&quot; class=&quot;loaded largeImage&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;leadimage-caption&quot;&gt;Toronto police reported 4,250 auto theft cases by Dec. 3, 2018, compared to 3,358 at this time last year. By year end in 2017, they reported 3,526, as seen above.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Police in Peel and York regions did not have their 2018 auto theft data readily available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Relay thefts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Bates, many of these thieves are using a method called &quot;relay theft.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key fobs are constantly broadcasting a signal that communicates with a specific vehicle, he said, and when it comes into a close enough range, the vehicle will open and start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The way that the thieves are getting around this is they're essentially amplifying that low power signal coming off of the push start fob,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;They will prey upon the general consensus that most people are leaving their key fobs close to the front door of their home and the vehicle will be in the driveway.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thief will bring a device close to the home's door, close to where most keys are sitting, to boost the fob's signal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They leave another device near the vehicle, which receives the signal and opens the car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people don't realize it, Bates said, but the thieves don't need the fob in the car to drive it away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;placeholder&quot;&gt;

&lt;span&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://i.cbc.ca/1.4930928.1543874259!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/relay-theft2.jpg&quot; class=&quot;loaded largeImage&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;leadimage-caption&quot;&gt;The Toronto Police Service's 11 Division posted this photo on Nov. 26 to warn people about relay thefts. (Toronto Police Service)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The vehicle will continue running in perpetuity until it runs out of gas or until you shut it down,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;They do that for safety so that if you lose the key fob or if it loses signal the vehicle doesn't shut down while you're driving, but that right there is part of the vulnerability.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Panchal said he isn't sure thieves used this method to take his car, but he didn't see any signs of forced entry after it was recovered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;It's pretty insane just to think about something like that even happening. I guess that's what they're doing these days, right? If that's what they can do, that's what they will do.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, an Oakville, Ont., man caught his alleged thief on-camera seemingly using the relay theft method, as seen below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;Sebastian Bielawski posted this video in July after waking up to find his Lexus RX 350 2017 had vanished from his Oakville driveway. He believes he's the victim of a relay theft. 0:37&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How to protect your vehicle&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Bates, the automotive industry made a trade-off when it started creating push-start fobs, putting convenience ahead of security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some manufacturers are working to fix the fob vulnerabilities, but there are ways vehicle owners can protect themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first tip, Bates said, is to not keep your keys by the front door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;If you do live in a house, try to leave your keys either upstairs or … as far away from the vehicle as possible,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The other thing that you can do is there are products out there that you can put your key fob into,&quot; such as a faraday cage — a box used to block radio signals — a key pouch, which works similarly, or even a steel box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bates said it's important to look at solutions, considering more and more vehicles are being equipped with remote start fobs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I think it's going to continue to happen and I don't think we've seen the end of it. I think it's going to be even more and more prevalent.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 14:30:55 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>colinprince</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/toronto/car-thefts-rising-1.4930890</og:url>
<og:title>Auto theft on the rise in Toronto area, and a security expert thinks he knows why | CBC News</og:title>
<og:image>https://i.cbc.ca/1.4930919.1543877311!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/16x9_620/relay-theft.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Auto thefts are on the rise across the Greater Toronto Area, by 30 per cent in the city alone, and wireless key fobs may have a role to play.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/toronto/car-thefts-rising-1.4930890</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Measuring the “Filter Bubble”: How Google is influencing what you click</title>
<link>https://spreadprivacy.com/google-filter-bubble-study/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://spreadprivacy.com/google-filter-bubble-study/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Over the years, there has been &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ted.com/talks/eli_pariser_beware_online_filter_bubbles&quot;&gt;considerable&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/2016/11/filter-bubble-destroying-democracy/&quot;&gt;discussion&lt;/a&gt; of Google's &quot;filter bubble&quot; problem. Put simply, it's the manipulation of your search results based on your personal data. In practice this means links are moved up or down or added to your Google search results, necessitating the &lt;em&gt;filtering&lt;/em&gt; of other search results altogether. These editorialized results are informed by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quora.com/What-does-Google-know-about-me/answer/Gabriel-Weinberg&quot;&gt;the personal information Google has on you&lt;/a&gt; (like your search, browsing, and purchase history), and puts you in a &lt;em&gt;bubble&lt;/em&gt; based on what Google's algorithms think you're most likely to click on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The filter bubble is particularly pernicious when searching for political topics. That's because undecided and inquisitive voters turn to search engines to conduct basic research on candidates and issues in the critical time when they are forming their opinions on them. If they’re getting information that is swayed to one side because of their personal filter bubbles, then this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.politico.com/magazine/story/2015/08/how-google-could-rig-the-2016-election-121548&quot;&gt;can have a significant effect&lt;/a&gt; on political outcomes in aggregate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in 2012 we ran a study showing Google's filter bubble may have significantly influenced the 2012 U.S. Presidential election by inserting tens of millions of more links for Obama than for Romney in the run-up to that election. Our research inspired an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/SB10001424052970203347104578099122530080836&quot;&gt;independent study by the Wall Street Journal&lt;/a&gt; (paywall):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Wall Street Journal examination found that the search engine often customizes the results of people who have recently searched for &quot;Obama&quot;—but not those who have recently searched for &quot;Romney.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, after the 2016 U.S. Presidential election and other recent elections, there is justified new interest in examining the ways people can be influenced politically online. In that context, we conducted another study to examine the state of Google's filter bubble problem in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;summaryoffindings&quot;&gt;Summary of Findings&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2018/09/17/google-tests-changes-to-its-search-algorithm-how-search-works.html&quot;&gt;Google has claimed&lt;/a&gt; to have taken steps to reduce its filter bubble problem, but our latest research reveals a very different story. Based on a study of individuals entering identical search terms at the same time, we found that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Most participants saw results unique to them. These discrepancies could not be explained by changes in location, time, by being logged in to Google, or by Google testing algorithm changes to a small subset of users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On the first page of search results, Google included links for some participants that it did not include for others, even when logged out and in private browsing mode.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Results within the news and videos infoboxes also varied significantly. Even though people searched at the same time, people were shown different sources, even after accounting for location.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Private browsing mode and being logged out of Google offered very little filter bubble protection. These tactics simply do not provide the anonymity most people expect. In fact, it's simply not possible to use Google search and avoid its filter bubble.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://spreadprivacy.com/content/images/2018/11/filter-bubble-overview-3.png&quot; class=&quot;kg-image&quot; alt=&quot;Visualization of three differing Google search results for the query 'gun control'.&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;For those interested in more details, we've written out everything below, as well as provided the underlying data and code. We hope this work encourages further study of this important issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;methodology&quot;&gt;Methodology&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We asked &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/DuckDuckGo/status/1009618814164537344&quot;&gt;volunteers&lt;/a&gt; in the U.S. to search for &quot;gun control&quot;, &quot;immigration&quot;, and &quot;vaccinations&quot; (in that order) at 9pm ET on Sunday, June 24, 2018. Volunteers performed searches first in private browsing mode and logged out of Google, and then again not in private mode (i.e., in &quot;normal&quot; mode). We compiled 87 complete result sets — 76 on desktop and 11 on mobile. Note that we restricted the study to the U.S. because different countries have different search indexes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During analysis of the search results, we only looked at websites' top-level domains, for example &lt;em&gt;www.cdc.gov/features/vaccines-travel&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;www.cdc.gov/vaccines/adults&lt;/em&gt; would both be treated as just &lt;em&gt;cdc.gov&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;finding1mostpeoplesawresultsuniquetothemevenwhenloggedoutandinprivatebrowsingmode&quot;&gt;Finding #1: Most people saw results unique to them, even when logged out and in private browsing mode.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To count variants of results, we noted the order of the major elements: the organic (regular) links, the news (Top Stories) infobox, and the videos infobox. We ignored ads, sections containing related searches, and other infoboxes. There were variations in these too, but we didn't consider them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A quick note on ordering of links: You might think that as long as the same links are shown to users, the ordering of them is relatively unimportant, but that's not the case. A given link gets only about &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hughewilliams.com/2012/04/12/clicks-in-search/&quot;&gt;half as many clicks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; as the link before it and &lt;em&gt;twice as many clicks&lt;/em&gt; as the link after it. In other words, link ordering matters a lot because people click on the first link much more than the second, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The amount of variations we saw for each search term is listed below. For this part of the study, we excluded mobile results because the number of infoboxes displayed can vary significantly between mobile and desktop. That's why it says 76 participants instead of the overall total of 87. We also controlled for location (more on that below).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Private browsing mode (and logged out):&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&quot;gun control&quot;: 62 variations with 52/76 participants (68%) seeing unique results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;immigration&quot;: 57 variations with 43/76 participants (57%) seeing unique results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;vaccinations&quot;: 73 variations with 70/76 participants (92%) seeing unique results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Normal mode:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&quot;gun control&quot;: 58 variations with 45/76 participants (59%) seeing unique results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;immigration&quot;: 59 variations with 48/76 participants (63%) seeing unique results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;vaccinations&quot;: 73 variations with 70/76 participants (92%) seeing unique results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://spreadprivacy.com/content/images/2018/11/serp-variants-2.png&quot; class=&quot;kg-image&quot; alt=&quot;Visualization of unique search results shown for the search query 'gun control'.&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;With no filter bubble, one would expect to see very little variation of search result pages — nearly everyone would see the same single set of results. That's not what we found.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, most people saw results unique to them. We also found about the same variation in private browsing mode and logged out of Google vs. in normal mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, some search result variation is expected due to two factors that we controlled for. First, search results can change over time, such as the inclusion of time-sensitive links. We controlled for this factor by having everyone search at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, search results can change by location, such as the inclusion of local news articles. We controlled for this factor by checking all links by hand for this possibility, comparing them to the city and state of the volunteer. We saw very few local links for &lt;em&gt;gun control&lt;/em&gt; (1 organic link, 1 news infobox link) and &lt;em&gt;immigration&lt;/em&gt; (0), though more for &lt;em&gt;vaccinations&lt;/em&gt; (15 organic links, 4 news infobox links).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To control for these local links, we replaced all of them with the same placeholder — localdomain.com for organic links and &quot;Local Source&quot; for infoboxes — in all of our analysis. This adjustment means two users whose results only differed by a different local domain in the same slot would not count as different. Interestingly, this adjustment didn't affect overall variation significantly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another reason you might expect some variation is testing of the search algorithm, where you show slightly different results to different people. In that case, you'd expect to see most people seeing the same results, with a few people seeing slight differences. What we saw, by contrast, was most people seeing different results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;finding2googleincludedlinksforsomeparticipantsthatitdidnotincludeforothers&quot;&gt;Finding #2: Google included links for some participants that it did not include for others.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google search results typically have ten organic links. While the ordering of those links really matters (i.e. link #1 gets ~40% of clicks, link #2 ~20%, link #3 ~10% and so on), we also wanted to know how many different domains were being displayed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With no filter bubble, one would expect to see this total to be around ten. We saw significantly more. In private browsing mode, logged out of Google, and with local domains replaced with &lt;em&gt;localdomain.com&lt;/em&gt;, here are the totals:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&quot;gun control&quot;: 19 different domains&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;immigration&quot;: 15 different domains&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;vaccinations&quot;: 22 different domains&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://spreadprivacy.com/content/images/2018/11/domain-occurrences-2.png&quot; class=&quot;kg-image&quot; alt=&quot;Visualization of domains appearing in organic search results per person.&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;As you can see this clearly in the visualization above, some people were shown a very unusual set of results relative to the other participants, offered some domains seen by no-one else. If you were one of these people, you would have no way of knowing what you're missing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;finding3wesawsignificantvariationwithinthenewsandvideosinfoboxes&quot;&gt;Finding #3: We saw significant variation within the News and Videos infoboxes.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also wanted to look at variation within the news (Top Stories) and videos infoboxes. We also saw significant variation within those, even though there are only three slots available. Again, these are for private browsing mode, logged out of Google, and with local domains replaced with &quot;Local Source&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;News infobox:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&quot;gun control&quot;: 3 variations from 5 sources, appearing for 75/76 people. The most common variation was seen by 69 people (90%).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;immigration&quot;: 6 variations from 7 sources, appearing for 76/76 people. The most common variation was seen by 35 people (46%).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;vaccinations&quot;: 2 variations from 3 sources, appearing for 2/76 people. Each variation was seen by one person (1%).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Videos infobox:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&quot;gun control&quot;: 12 variations from 7 sources, appearing for 75/76 people. The most common variation was seen by 24 people (32%).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;immigration&quot;: 6 variations from 6 sources, appearing for 75/76 people. The most common variation was seen by 42 people (55%).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;vaccinations&quot;: Not shown in the search results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;As an example, the Videos infobox for the &quot;immigration&quot; query showed the following six variations. As with organic search results, the ordering matters here because the second and third slots get far fewer clicks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Today, MSNBC, NBC News (shown to 42 participants)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MSNBC, Today, NBC News (shown to 26 participants)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Today, MSNBC, MSNBC (shown to 4 participants)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MSNBC, Today, Today (shown to 1 participant)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New York Times, CNN, MSNBC (shown to 1 participant)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Today, MSNBC, RealClearPolitics (shown to 1 participant)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Remember, we had people search at the same time, and we changed all local-links to the be same, so this variation is not explained by time or location. And again, some people were real outliers; in fact, some didn't see the infoboxes at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;finding4privatebrowsingmodeandbeingloggedoutofgoogleofferedalmostzerofilterbubbleprotection&quot;&gt;Finding #4: Private browsing mode and being logged out of Google offered almost zero filter bubble protection.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we saw the variation in private browsing mode (also known as incognito mode) and logged out of Google as about the same as in normal mode. Most people expect both being logged out and going &quot;incognito&quot; to provide some anonymity. Unfortunately, this is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://spreadprivacy.com/is-private-browsing-really-private/&quot;&gt;common misconception&lt;/a&gt; as websites use IP addresses and &lt;a href=&quot;https://spreadprivacy.com/browser-fingerprinting/&quot;&gt;browser fingerprinting&lt;/a&gt; to identify people that are logged out or in private browsing mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If search results were more anonymous in these states, then we would expect everyone's private browsing mode results to be similar. That's not what we saw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To test this more rigorously, we took the organic results, excluding ads and infoboxes, and:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Assigned each domain a letter (e.g. A for nytimes.com, B for wsj.com, etc.).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Made a string of letters for each person's results, e.g. ABDFJKMSL.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compared these strings to see how similar they were to each other.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;To do this comparison we counted domain changes between different sets of search results, reducing the differences to a number. For example, ABC -&amp;gt; ACB is one change. (Technically, we used a letter to represent each domain within each search result and calculated the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Damerau%E2%80%93Levenshtein_distance&quot;&gt;Damerau-Levenshtein edit distance&lt;/a&gt; between them.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://spreadprivacy.com/content/images/2018/11/edit-distances1-2.png&quot; class=&quot;kg-image&quot; alt=&quot;Visualization showing how edit distances are calculated to measure the difference between strings.&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;We saw that when randomly comparing people's private modes to each other, there was more than double the variation than when comparing someone's private mode to their normal mode:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;gun control:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Average of normal and private browsing mode (same user): 1.03&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Average of private browsing mode (random user): 2.89&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Average of private browsing mode (five closest users): 2.65&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;immigration:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Average of normal and private browsing mode (same user): 1.38&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Average of private browsing mode (random user): 3.28&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Average of private browsing mode (five closest users): 2.80&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;vaccinations:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Average of normal and private browsing mode (same user): 2.23&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Average of private browsing mode (random user): 4.97&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Average of private browsing mode (five closest users): 4.25&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://spreadprivacy.com/content/images/2018/11/edit-distances2-1.png&quot; class=&quot;kg-image&quot; alt=&quot;Visualization showing that there's little difference in results between searching in normal mode and private browsing mode.&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;We often hear of confusion that private browsing mode enables anonymity on the web, but this finding demonstrates that Google tailors search results regardless of browsing mode. People should not be lulled into a false sense of security that so-called &quot;incognito&quot; mode makes them anonymous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;studydataandcode&quot;&gt;Study Data and Code&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data is available for download in two parts: &lt;a href=&quot;https://duckduckgo.com/download/duckduckgo-filter-bubble-study-2018_participants.xls&quot;&gt;Basic non-identifiable participant data&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://duckduckgo.com/download/duckduckgo-filter-bubble-study-2018_raw-search-results.xls&quot;&gt;raw data from the search results&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The code that we wrote to analyze the data is open source and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/duckduckgo/filter-bubble-study&quot;&gt;available on our GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For more privacy advice, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/duckduckgo&quot;&gt;follow us on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; get our &lt;a href=&quot;https://duckduckgo.com/newsletter&quot;&gt;privacy crash course&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 14:14:02 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>The_Reto</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Measuring the Filter Bubble: How Google is influencing what you click</og:title>
<og:description>Does Google show you different search results based on your personal info, even when signed out and in so-called &quot;incognito&quot; mode? We ran a study to find out.</og:description>
<og:url>https://spreadprivacy.com/google-filter-bubble-study/</og:url>
<og:image>https://spreadprivacy.com/content/images/2018/11/filter-bubble-header-3.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://spreadprivacy.com/google-filter-bubble-study/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Guide to scaling engineering organizations</title>
<link>https://stripe.com/atlas/guides/scaling-eng</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://stripe.com/atlas/guides/scaling-eng</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;At Stripe, we think a lot about scale. As we’ve scaled our products to process billions of dollars a year for millions of businesses, we’ve also needed to scale our engineering team. There’s a temptation for fast-growing companies to build their engineering team as quickly as possible. However, there are risks with rapid growth that include creating silos, diminishing user impact per engineer over time, and limiting ability to change &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; you work quickly to respond to changing user needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve deliberately chosen to add engineers at a slower rate than the growth of of our user base and instead take an iterative approach to recruiting and developing our team. We were able to keep teams small, invest more in each person, and nimbly change our ways of working as needs changed. Since what works for fifty engineers may not work for ten or a thousand, we’ve built a culture of feedback and iterative thinking that enables us to continually make changes as we grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This guide talks through some of the things we’ve learned along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;continuously-evolve-your-process&quot;&gt;Continuously evolve your process&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every company’s recruiting process and hiring needs are unique. When I first joined Stripe, we had just one dedicated technical recruiter supporting dozens of referrals and new applicants. Since then, we’ve improved, added, or replaced almost every part of the recruiting process and nearly quadrupled the size of our engineering team. I’ve found our processes run well for about 6-9 months before we need to update them. In order to safely experiment and evolve your recruiting process you need to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Define a recruiting plan to meet organizational needs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build consistency into your recruiting process to ensure efficiency and fairness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Never lose sight of candidate experience: no matter the outcome, you should leave a positive impression of your company and team&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Revisit your recruiting process on a regular basis to measure progress and make changes as needed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;build-a-consistent-recruiting-platform&quot;&gt;Build a consistent recruiting platform&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consistent recruiting increases efficiency, prevents bias, and raises the hiring bar. It’s important to clearly define the process you use to identify, evaluate, and hire candidates; the more consistency you introduce, the more you can rely on predictable outcomes, use data to understand what’s working well and change the things that aren’t. We run regular training sessions for new hiring managers alongside our recruiting team. Clear documentation helps train new managers and share best practices, even for small details like when to email candidates and how written offers get sent. Every hiring manager, recruiter, and interviewer is aware of what they’re responsible for in the interview pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Training sessions are valuable for all levels of experience; even new managers who have led recruiting initiatives at other companies remark how useful it is to learn exactly how Stripe approaches hiring. This is as much about consistency as it is making your own team feel confident and effective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://stripe.com/img/v3/atlas/guide/scaling-eng/recruiting-process.png&quot; class=&quot;expandable&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Document your recruiting practices to ensure your team uses a consistent process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The design of our interview process is drawn from industry studies and our own best practices. Our questions seek to understand how people approach real world problems, rather than testing for esoteric skills you might demonstrate on a whiteboard. During the &lt;em&gt;Bug Squash&lt;/em&gt; engineering interview, candidates and interviewers sit side-by-side to solve a real historical bug in an open-source project while working in the candidate’s programming language of choice. For engineering managers, we use &lt;em&gt;Team Role Plays&lt;/em&gt; to simulate working through issues during a one-on-one conversation with a teammate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We standardize questions using written rubrics that define exactly how to run each interview, evaluate those questions consistently, and compare scores across candidates. A good rubric outlines the goals of the interview and provides clear criteria to evaluate the candidate’s performance. Before an interview, every interviewer reads the rubric to understand what skills they will assess. For each skill, we provide examples of how candidates with different levels of proficiency might respond. We also integrate rubrics directly into our applicant tracking system so interviewers can consistently reference them as they’re providing feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s an example of a rubric we use to evaluate how effectively a candidate can communicate:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;document-snippet&quot;&gt;
&lt;section&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Communications skills&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;snippet&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Do they answer questions clearly?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do they provide specific details about their work, especially when prompted, vs. generalities and just describing the work of the team/company?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are they able to process prompts and feedback during the conversation?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scoring the interview&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;snippet&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;The candidate’s communication is scattered, erratic, or otherwise unclear. The candidate does not provide details or specifics, even when asked, or talks exclusively about things other than their personal work and contributions. The candidate may not be able to enter an effective two-way conversation with the interviewer, for example ignoring requests to change the subject.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The candidate’s communication is not consistently clear. They provide details in some but not all cases when asked, or the details they do provide do not back their higher-level points, or most details are about something other than their own work. The candidate may be an inconsistent partner in the two-way conversation, for example by rambling for a long time with some answers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The candidate’s communication is consistently clear, making high-level points and substantiating them with specific examples and details. They effectively engage in a two way conversation with the interviewer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Candidate is extremely clear and provides specific details supporting their general claims. The candidate communicates their personal trajectory and impact as well as the relation to projects / teams / companies they were working on. The candidate fluidly adapts to the conversation and prompts of the interviewer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to building clear rubrics, we began &lt;a href=&quot;https://rework.withgoogle.com/guides/unbiasing-raise-awareness/steps/watch-unconscious-bias-at-work/&quot;&gt;unconscious bias&lt;/a&gt; training to maintain consistency and objectivity. We also incorporated our standardized questions into a new &lt;strong&gt;Candidate Review&lt;/strong&gt; process we use to give feedback to interviewers and hiring managers once interviews are completed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Candidate Review is a recurring meeting with a set of experienced reviewers that’s used to examine all interview results. In each session, reviewers read over results, give feedback to individual interviewers, and identify ways we can improve the overall process. Reviewers don’t second guess decisions, but do ensure that everyone leaves sufficiently detailed feedback and makes decisions based only on information we see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Candidate Review started small, and I personally attended every session for six months to help train new reviewers, read feedback, and learn from first-hand observations. It was amazing to see what a difference we were able to make in a short amount of time. Engineers appreciated knowing someone was personally reading their notes, and we quickly saw the quality and consistency of feedback improve–both in level of detail and adherence to rubrics. Crucially, this helped us make several improvements to the interviews themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;define-clear-hiring-goals-and-effective-processes&quot;&gt;Define clear hiring goals and effective processes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clear goals enable you to measure success and make the right changes to your process when needed. If you rely primarily on a passive funnel of inbound applicants and referrals, you can end up hiring whoever walks through the door rather than who you really need right now. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For years after Stripe launched, we hired primarily generalist engineers who could work efficiently across the stack. As we tackled more specialized problems, such as scaling our secure credential storage infrastructure and building international mobile payment flows, we had to change our approach to attract the specialists we then needed. As a hiring manager for frontend specialists, I’d frequently meet candidates who would tell me, “Stripe doesn’t need any frontend engineers, you’re an API company.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In one interview, I was explaining how we work on problems beyond API development but it was clear I was quickly losing the candidate’s interest; clearly they just couldn’t visualize what they’d work on if they joined. I ran to grab my laptop and spent 30 minutes showing them live demos of our web and mobile dashboards. My pitch worked: they immediately began to ask questions and make product suggestions. Shortly afterwards, they interviewed and joined the company. This experience inspired us to design a new candidate experience for frontend engineers that didn’t require improvisation. Today we have many frontend engineers across Stripe–some are embedded directly on product teams and others build shared components and infrastructure that empower everyone to write better frontend code quickly and easily. As you expand into different product areas, it’s important to bring the same structure you initially built for generalists and tailor it to more specialized roles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We started with a small number of roles (infrastructure, front-end engineering) to understand how to retool our recruiting operations one at a time. We now hire across many different pipelines, ranging from &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/jobs/positions/android-engineer&quot;&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/jobs/positions/machine-learning-engineer-seattle&quot;&gt;machine learning&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/jobs/positions/engineer-infrastructure-security&quot;&gt;security&lt;/a&gt;. These changes have steadily increased our offer acceptance rates and we now have specialists in every pipeline. Each detail affects every part of the recruiting process, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Posting different job descriptions publicly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deciding which recruiters are staffed against which roles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating specialized interview questions, rubrics, and candidate preparation guides for each role&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;We recently launched &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/elements&quot;&gt;Elements&lt;/a&gt;, our UI toolkit for payment flows. The Elements team benefited from the collective experience of specialists spanning security, front-end engineering, and user experience to tackle an extensive list of challenges: secure isolation of card details with iframes, resolving browser-specific bugs, adding internationalization, incorporating modern JavaScript API design, and optimizing conversion flows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;create-a-great-candidate-experience&quot;&gt;Create a great candidate experience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interview process defines every candidate’s first impression of how your company and engineering teams operate. We strive to provide a great experience for everyone, no matter how well they perform in their interviews. We’ve developed some best practices that provide consistent touch points at each step in the process, help people prepare, set appropriate expectations, and give every person who comes on site the same chance of interviewing successfully and showing their best work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To better understand our recruiting funnel, we recently conducted a private poll across several recruiting teams in the SF Bay Area. Based on these benchmarks, recruiting funnels for these teams have an acceptance rate between 12-20% from the onsite interview to an accepted offer. Most companies focus on meeting, then optimizing these numbers. It’s easy to forget that for every hire, four to seven people go work at other companies and take their interview experience with them–this means there’s a small army of people out there who implicitly represent your company and what you stand for, even if you never talk to them again. You are very likely to hire people from your candidates’ social and professional networks; if you leave a great impression, even those who don’t go on to work for your team can help generate great referrals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://stripe.com/img/v3/atlas/guide/scaling-eng/candidate-experience.png&quot; class=&quot;expandable&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;The interview process may be the only time someone interacts with your company, so create a great experience for every candidate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before the interview, we share written guides to help them understand &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/us/jobs/candidate-info&quot;&gt;Stripe’s culture&lt;/a&gt; and prepare for the interview. Engineers choose from a number of different programming languages and can use their own laptop and development environment. Afterwards, we send follow-up anonymous surveys to candidates to learn more about their experience and identify ways for us to improve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://stripe.com/img/v3/atlas/guide/scaling-eng/survey.png&quot; class=&quot;expandable&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;We use &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cultureamp.com/&quot;&gt;Culture Amp&lt;/a&gt; surveys to close the feedback loop with interview candidates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We speak with every candidate after they interview, even the ones that don’t end up working at Stripe. For those who don’t accept our offer, we schedule a call to understand their choice and how they felt about the role. When we don’t extend an offer, recruiters give candidates personalized feedback to help them learn from their experience. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Across the board, our surveys have shown that candidates have a good experience interviewing at Stripe: those without offers rate their experience an average of 4.1 out of 5 on the questions above (and people who do get offers average 4.5). Even more striking, candidates who don’t join Stripe often go on to refer their friends and colleagues to us later. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tips and exercises&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Write rubrics for your most commonly asked interview questions and integrate them into your applicant tracking system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write and share an interview prep guide with incoming candidates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setup a quick survey to learn about the interview experience and ways to improve it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;spin-up-your-new-hires-effectively&quot;&gt;Spin up your new hires effectively&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Growing teams work incredibly hard to hire new employees, but can overlook helping new teammates succeed once they start. Joining a high-growth startup can be an intimidating experience, and without guidance, new hires have to work twice as hard to learn what they need to be productive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Stripe’s early days, we made the mistake of not investing enough in onboarding. Employees defined their ramping up period as a sink-or-swim experience. When I first joined Stripe, several teammates described this lack of support as a test–they assumed it was the company’s way of evaluating everyone again after they started. That was not the case, but by not investing enough in an onboarding program, we implicitly said that people were on their own; it’s easy to turn mistakes into accidental company norms. Today, we invest significant time and energy in onboarding and helping all new hires grow their impact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;invest-in-dedicated-training-and-onboarding-programs&quot;&gt;Invest in dedicated training and onboarding programs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first few months are critical for new hires. Asking an engineer to build a feature in their first week is tempting, but investing in onboarding and training makes for happier and more productive teammates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For all new employees, we developed Stripe 101: a general onboarding program that connects new hires across the company. In just a few weeks, people learn about Stripe by attending classes, meeting with our co-founders, building a Stripe integration, and answering support tickets. They also get an early opportunity to collaborate with people in many different functions at the company. This operates at impressive scale, with over thirty sessions led by eighty-two instructors from across the organization. Last year, over two hundred Stripe employees went through the program. Employee surveys show that Stripe 101 is a positive experience and extraordinarily effective in sharing key information with them:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;100% of new Stripe employees were able to summarize the function of at least three Stripe products by the end of Stripe 101.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;94.5% of new Stripe employees felt their first week at Stripe was a positive experience and felt the 101 curriculum was an effective use of time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;90% of new Stripe engineers understood the components of the Stripe stack by the end of the program.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New hires also graduate with an immediate network of peers who work in different functions across Stripe. This helps them navigate the organization in a personal way as they tackle projects later in their career at the company–for example, when building a new feature, they may already know someone on the User Ops or Sales teams they can ask for early feedback.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stripe 101 is helpful for general-purpose knowledge, but we saw the need for an additional onboarding experience for new engineers. They enjoyed meeting people across the company, but were anxious to spend time with technical teams and diving into code. We developed a new program to introduce them to our technical stack by solving a practical problem in our main application codebase. We called it &lt;strong&gt;/dev/start&lt;/strong&gt; and started with a small pilot, featuring a handful of new engineers, volunteer mentors, projects pulled from team backlogs, and one-on-one feedback. Within months, it expanded to multiple organizations and was soon used for all of engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, we group new hires into temporary virtual teams for 3-4 weeks. Teams work with a dedicated mentor to learn about our development process while shipping a concrete tool or product improvement. Experienced Stripe engineers gain project leadership and mentorship experience by serving as mentors–they sit with the team, break the project down into tractable tasks, answer both technical and product questions, review code, and serve as a bridge to the rest of engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://stripe.com/img/v3/atlas/guide/scaling-eng/devstart.jpg&quot; class=&quot;expandable&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;/dev/start connects mentors with new hires to support their onboarding experience as they work on a group project (and everyone receives a limited edition T-shirt).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;dont-forget-about-soft-skills-and-culture&quot;&gt;Don’t forget about soft skills and culture&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jstor.org/stable/2666999?origin=JSTOR-pdf&amp;amp;seq=1#page_scan_tab_contents&quot;&gt;Psychological safety&lt;/a&gt; is the shared belief by team members that it’s safe to take risks and share knowledge to support one another. In Google’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://rework.withgoogle.com/print/guides/5721312655835136/&quot;&gt;Project Aristotle&lt;/a&gt;, a study to understand the secrets of effective teams, psychological safety was identified as the most important factor to team success. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We aim to create this safety by writing guides to culture and group norms; we cover both general communication and team-specific practices. Stripe 101 includes a class called &lt;em&gt;Communicating at Stripe&lt;/em&gt; that describes company mailing lists, best practices for email, and bug trackers, but also non-obvious communication patterns like how to schedule meetings. Norms for calendars may seem like common sense, but carry key cultural knowledge: understanding them can help people avoid embarrassing scheduling errors or discover important events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Engineering teams provide specialized guides for specific tools (e.g. GitHub or JIRA) or common practices like code review. These act as a source of truth and allow teams to collaboratively agree on their processes upfront, reducing ongoing debate or confusion. Self-serve documentation also decreases our reliance on oral tradition, helping us scale more quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;document-snippet&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Email at Stripe&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;snippet&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Use email for non-urgent messages. If you need a quick response that can’t wait until your recipient checks their email, use Slack.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you’re going to be out of the office (OOO), consider putting up an autoresponder to tell people your response timeline and who’s covering for you. This is not required, and we leave it to your judgment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You should send a shipped@ email when wrapping up a unit of work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You shouldn’t lurk into people’s threads unnecessarily. Read to your heart’s content, but is your active lurking warranted? If you can meaningfully contribute, by all means politely chime in on list; if not, don’t impede others’ progress.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;no-margin&quot;&gt;Open communication at Stripe only works if we create and promote an environment that feels safe to all Stripe employees. Lurking in unnecessarily and making someone feel self-conscious is a disincentive to communicate openly. Do, however, gently nudge others—especially newer Stripe employees—to stay the course and use lists. It may not always be comfortable, and it does require some courage, but the benefits are worth the perceived risk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;This is one example of a guide we use to help new employees understand our communication norms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tips and exercises&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Pilot 1-2 onboarding classes that give an overview of your company and products.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write a culture or group-norm-oriented guide for your team, e.g. how to email, calendar, and complete code reviews.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;invest-in-the-team-you-have&quot;&gt;Invest in the team you have&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Employee happiness often depends on two factors: whether they know the impact of their work and feel autonomy in the decisions they make every day. Beyond this, successful teams need to provide structure to keep team members engaged for the long-term. They need to actively listen to feedback, define clear paths for personal growth, and train leaders to best support their teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After hiring and onboarding new employees, companies can either focus on short-term output or the long-term productivity of their teams. At high-growth companies, conditions change rapidly and early decisions can have lasting impact, even as it gets harder to remember how decisions were made in the first place. Early employees can carry disproportionately more knowledge than new hires, be most effective at getting things done, and be the company’s greatest mentors through understanding both the technical context and how to navigate the organization. At the same time, they can start to feel overloaded or trapped in one part of the company or technical stack. Collaborate with your early employees to avoid this trap by building the right supporting structure for your team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;dont-mistake-productivity-for-engagement&quot;&gt;Don’t mistake productivity for engagement&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an early manager at a previous company, I was supporting a collaborative, highly productive team. One day, a long-tenured engineer arrived at our one-on-one and quietly handed me a letter of resignation. He’d been consistently delivering high-quality work, taking on challenging projects, and even mentoring new hires and interns. When I asked him why he was leaving, he said he no longer felt challenged–while he knew he was doing important work for the company, he couldn’t see any way to both increase his impact and learn new skills. I now call this the &lt;em&gt;surprise resignation&lt;/em&gt;, when people feel stuck in a local maximum and conclude it’s easier to leave the company for an exciting opportunity rather than take on a new but seemingly less-impactful role within it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I soon realized that while I hadn’t noticed any warning signs, a simple conversation about his career aspirations would have revealed his concern. People stay engaged when they feel a personal sense of growth, and you can support this by looking beyond day-to-day productivity and asking the right questions. Twice a year, we send out an employee survey called StripeSat to measure engagement. Here are some questions we asked in our last survey that we look at carefully:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Do you have opportunities at work to learn and grow? What would you like to learn or get better at?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do you see yourself working at Stripe in three years? Why or why not?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do you believe there are good career opportunities at Stripe (e.g. stretch assignments, increased responsibility, and internal mobility)? If not, what opportunities would excite you?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;create-supported-paths-for-mobility-and-learning&quot;&gt;Create supported paths for mobility and learning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Helping people discover new opportunities and create independent projects enables them to shape their story and role at the company. At Stripe, we create internal resources to advertise new teams, encourage employees to rotate onto new projects, and run hackathons to foster creativity. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People use rotations to learn a new language, explore a different part of our stack, and in some cases permanently switch teams. In the past six months, over a dozen engineers rotated between projects as disparate as iOS mobile development, core payment API features, and machine learning applications. We also highlight roles that would benefit most from internal transfers–for example, bootstrapping a new team or tackling a complex technical problem. Highlighting these challenges helps direct longest-tenured engineers towards projects where they can provide the most help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trying something new doesn’t need to take weeks of planning or a new team; we also run internal hackathons to encourage building new tools and products. At a recent hackathon, eighty people participated across multiple offices, and we shipped seven projects to both internal and external users, including right-to-left language support in Stripe Elements and internal tools for employee productivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://stripe.com/img/v3/atlas/guide/scaling-eng/seating-chart.png&quot; class=&quot;expandable&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Hackathons help us create great internal tools like this seating chart on Stripe’s internal company directory. Read more about how we use &lt;em&gt;Home&lt;/em&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/blog/stripe-home&quot;&gt;this blog post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;ask-for-feedback-and-respond-to-it&quot;&gt;Ask for feedback and respond to it&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As companies grow, responding to employee feedback requires both a scalable approach and listening carefully to individuals. Employees recognize problems at companies all the time, but don’t always know how to translate what they’re seeing into effective change. We respond to employee feedback with three steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;bottom-margin&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Identify the problem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design a way to collect structured feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Address the feedback, deliver the results&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two years ago, engineers consistently described our development environment as slow and inefficient. To address this, we formed a team of experienced Stripe engineers focused on the internal developer experience. Despite their intuition and expertise, they had trouble identifying the most impactful projects. The team launched a Developer Experience survey to guide their work, including questions such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;In the last week, how many hours did you lose due to problems with your development process?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With our tools or infrastructure, what are 1-2 things we could do to make you more productive?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the codebase you work in, what’s harder than it should be?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The survey results showed us the most common request (by a factor of two!) was for a faster and more reliable edit-sync-test loop. The team took this to heart and tackled a series of projects to improve the speed and reliability of syncing, reloading, and testing code. In the next round a few months later, results showed satisfaction in these areas had improved by 50 to 80%. This created a positive feedback loop between the team and their users, and helped engineers feel heard. Since then, we’ve run Developer Experience surveys every quarter and continue to learn from the results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tips and exercises&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Create an internal job board that highlights specific teams in need or roles for experienced internal transfers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop a hackathon pilot program: this could be over a range of time, like hack-a-month or hack-weeks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implement a company survey and identify one project you can take on in response to the feedback.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As organizations evolve, how you scale your team has an enormous impact on your culture, productivity, and employee engagement, and subsequently the success of the business. At quickly growing companies, conditions change rapidly and what’s working well today may not hold up tomorrow. While these practices have helped us scale thus far, we’ll continue iterating and develop new ones as we grow. We hope these lessons are helpful to you in your scaling journey and are excited to share what we discover along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;cta&quot; readability=&quot;1.6060606060606&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sound interesting?&lt;/strong&gt; Join the Stripe engineering team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/jobs?ref=scaling-eng#engineering&quot; class=&quot;common-Button common-Button--default&quot;&gt;View Openings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;aside class=&quot;collect-email-guide&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;mask-container container-lg&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;collect-email-partial&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;collect-success column&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;icon&quot; src=&quot;https://stripe.com/img/v3/common/success.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Green checkmark&quot;/&gt;&lt;h3 class=&quot;common-BodyTitle&quot;&gt;Thank you!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;common-BodyText&quot;&gt;We sent an email to &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;common-BodyText&quot;&gt;Check your inbox to confirm your email address and we’ll let you know when we publish our next guide. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/atlas/guides&quot; class=&quot;common-Link common-Link--arrowL&quot;&gt;Return to guides&lt;/a&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 13:55:02 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>joeyespo</dc:creator>
<og:title>Stripe Atlas: Guide to scaling engineering organizations</og:title>
<og:url>https://stripe.com/atlas/guides/scaling-eng</og:url>
<og:description>Lessons learned from scaling Stripe's engineering team.</og:description>
<og:image>https://stripe.com/img/v3/atlas/guide/social.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://stripe.com/atlas/guides/scaling-eng</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>