<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>The Airbnbs</title>
<link>https://blog.ycombinator.com/the-airbnbs/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.ycombinator.com/the-airbnbs/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;To celebrate Airbnb’s IPO and to help future founders, I thought it might be useful to explain what was special about Airbnb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What was special about the Airbnbs was how earnest they were. They did nothing half-way, and we could sense this even in the interview. Sometimes after we interviewed a startup we’d be uncertain what to do, and have to talk it over. Other times we’d just look at one another and smile. The Airbnbs’ interview was that kind. We didn’t even like the idea that much. Nor did users, at that stage; they had no growth. But the founders seemed so full of energy that it was impossible not to like them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That first impression was not misleading. During the batch our nickname for Brian Chesky was The Tasmanian Devil, because like the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=StG2u5qfFRg&amp;amp;t=2m27s&quot;&gt;cartoon character&lt;/a&gt; he seemed a tornado of energy. All three of them were like that. No one ever worked harder during YC than the Airbnbs did. When you talked to the Airbnbs, they took notes. If you suggested an idea to them in office hours, the next time you talked to them they’d not only have implemented it, but also implemented two new ideas they had in the process. “They probably have the best attitude of any startup we’ve funded” I wrote to Mike Arrington during the batch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They’re still like that. Jessica and I had dinner with Brian in the summer of 2018, just the three of us. By this point the company is ten years old. He took a page of notes about ideas for new things Airbnb could do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What we didn’t realize when we first met Brian and Joe and Nate was that Airbnb was on its last legs. After working on the company for a year and getting no growth, they’d agreed to give it one last shot. They’d try this Y Combinator thing, and if the company still didn’t take off, they’d give up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any normal person would have given up already. They’d been funding the company with credit cards. They had a &lt;em&gt;binder&lt;/em&gt; full of credit cards they’d maxed out. Investors didn’t think much of the idea. One investor they met in a cafe walked out in the middle of meeting with them. They thought he was going to the bathroom, but he never came back. “He didn’t even finish his smoothie,” Brian said. And now, in late 2008, it was the worst recession in decades. The stock market was in free fall and wouldn’t hit bottom for another four months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why hadn’t they given up? This is a useful question to ask. People, like matter, reveal their nature under extreme conditions. One thing that’s clear is that they weren’t doing this just for the money. As a money-making scheme, this was pretty lousy: a year’s work and all they had to show for it was a binder full of maxed-out credit cards. So why were they still working on this startup? Because of the experience they’d had as the first hosts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When they first tried renting out airbeds on their floor during a design convention, all they were hoping for was to make enough money to pay their rent that month. But something surprising happened: they enjoyed having those first three guests staying with them. And the guests enjoyed it too. Both they and the guests had done it because they were in a sense forced to, and yet they’d all had a great experience. Clearly there was something new here: for hosts, a new way to make money that had literally been right under their noses, and for guests, a new way to travel that was in many ways better than hotels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That experience was why the Airbnbs didn’t give up. They knew they’d discovered something. They’d seen a glimpse of the future, and they couldn’t let it go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They knew that once people tried staying in what is now called “an airbnb,” they would also realize that this was the future. But only if they tried it, and they weren’t. That was the problem during Y Combinator: to get growth started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Airbnb’s goal during YC was to reach what we call &lt;a href=&quot;http://paulgraham.com/ramenprofitable.html&quot;&gt;ramen profitability&lt;/a&gt;, which means making enough money that the company can pay the founders’ living expenses, if they live on ramen noodles. Ramen profitability is not, obviously, the end goal of any startup, but it’s the most important threshold on the way, because this is the point where you’re airborne. This is the point where you no longer need investors’ permission to continue existing. For the Airbnbs, ramen profitability was $4000 a month: $3500 for rent, and $500 for food. They taped this goal to the mirror in the bathroom of their apartment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way to get growth started in something like Airbnb is to focus on the hottest subset of the market. If you can get growth started there, it will spread to the rest. When I asked the Airbnbs where there was most demand, they knew from searches: New York City. So they focused on New York. They went there &lt;a href=&quot;http://paulgraham.com/ds.html&quot;&gt;in person&lt;/a&gt; to visit their hosts and help them make their listings more attractive. A big part of that was better pictures. So Joe and Brian rented a professional camera and took pictures of the hosts’ places themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This didn’t just make the listings better. It also taught them about their hosts. When they came back from their first trip to New York, I asked what they’d noticed about hosts that surprised them, and they said the biggest surprise was how many of the hosts were in the same position they’d been in: they needed this money to pay their rent. This was, remember, the worst recession in decades, and it had hit New York first. It definitely added to the Airbnbs’ sense of mission to feel that people needed them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In late January 2009, about three weeks into Y Combinator, their efforts started to show results, and their numbers crept upward. But it was hard to say for sure whether it was growth or just random fluctuation. By February it was clear that it was real growth. They made $460 in fees in the first week of February, $897 in the second, and $1428 in the third. That was it: they were airborne. Brian sent me an email on February 22 announcing that they were ramen profitable and giving the last three weeks’ numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I assume you know what you’ve now set yourself up for next week,” I responded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brian’s reply was seven words: “We are not going to slow down.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 17:24:22 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>todsacerdoti</dc:creator>
<og:title>The Airbnbs</og:title>
<og:url>https://blog.ycombinator.com/the-airbnbs/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>To celebrate Airbnb's IPO and to help future founders, I thought it might be useful to explain what was special about Airbnb.</og:description>
<og:image>https://blog.ycombinator.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/the-airbnbs.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.ycombinator.com/the-airbnbs/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Cydia, the original app store, sues Apple on antitrust grounds</title>
<link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2020/12/10/cydia-apple-lawsuit/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2020/12/10/cydia-apple-lawsuit/</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font--body font-copy gray-darkest ma-0 pb-md&quot;&gt;“Were it not for Apple’s anticompetitive acquisition and maintenance of an illegal monopoly over iOS app distribution, users today would actually be able to choose how and where to locate and obtain iOS apps, and developers would be able to use the iOS app distributor of their choice,” the lawsuit alleges. The lawsuit was filed in federal court in Northern California and Cydia is represented by Quinn Emanuel Urquhart and Sullivan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;14.698795180723&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font--body font-copy gray-darkest ma-0 pb-md&quot;&gt;Apple is facing an onslaught of lawsuits and scrutiny from lawmakers and regulators around the world for the way it allegedly uses its power to maintain its dominant position over its App Store. Epic Games, the maker of “Fortnite,” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2020/08/13/fortnite-apple-app-store/?itid=lk_inline_manual_8&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;sued Apple&lt;/a&gt; in August for allegedly monopolistic behavior, and a coalition of software developers taking on Apple’s power has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2020/10/22/apple-coalition-antitrust-app-store/?itid=lk_inline_manual_8&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;been growing&lt;/a&gt; in membership. Apple is facing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2020/05/28/tile-tells-vestager-investigate-apple-antitrust-violations/?itid=lk_inline_manual_8&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;investigations in Europe&lt;/a&gt;, spurred by music streaming service Spotify and other competitors, over allegedly anti-competitive behavior. And in the United States, lawmakers scolded Apple and its peers in &lt;a href=&quot;https://judiciary.house.gov/uploadedfiles/competition_in_digital_markets.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a report&lt;/a&gt; on the power of large Silicon Valley companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font--body font-copy gray-darkest ma-0 pb-md&quot;&gt;Apple spokesman Fred Sainz said the company will review the lawsuit and denied that the company is a monopoly. It says it faces competition from Google’s Android operating system, which is used by competing handset makers like Samsung and Google itself. And Apple says it must tightly control the way software is installed on the iPhone to protect its customers from inadvertently downloading viruses and other security threats and from installing apps that invade its customers’ privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font--body font-copy gray-darkest ma-0 pb-md&quot;&gt;The Cydia lawsuit represents a new kind of challenge to Apple’s power. While Epic, Spotify and other companies say they are victims of Apple’s alleged App Store monopoly, they aren’t direct competitors to the App Store itself. Cydia, which was popular in the early days of the iPhone, offers a real-world example of what competition might look like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;13.398773006135&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font--body font-copy gray-darkest ma-0 pb-md&quot;&gt;The App Store has been a huge success for Apple, generating around $15 billion a year in revenue, according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://loupventures.com/apples-game-of-app-store-chess/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;analysts’ estimates&lt;/a&gt;. While the sum represents only a small portion of the company’s roughly $275 billion in total revenue, it has become an important springboard for the company’s fast-growing services business, which could help the company through slowing growth of iPhone sales. Apple generally takes a 30 percent cut of revenue earned by app developers on its platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font--body font-copy gray-darkest ma-0 pb-md&quot;&gt;The App Store’s success has come least in part because of the way it controls the software on iPhones and iPads. Unlike the company’s Mac computers, which allow customers to install software in a variety of ways, including via the Mac App Store, other competing app stores and directly from websites, the iPhone’s software prohibits all methods of software distribution except one: the Apple App Store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font--body font-copy gray-darkest ma-0 pb-md&quot;&gt;Apple must approve every app that is available for the iPhone, and software developers must abide by a long list of rules that define exactly what an iPhone app can and can’t do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font--body font-copy gray-darkest ma-0 pb-md&quot;&gt;It wasn’t always that way. Jay Freeman was consulting as a software developer in Santa Barbara, Calif., when the iPhone launched in 2007.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font--body font-copy gray-darkest ma-0 pb-md&quot;&gt;When a colleague bought Freeman an iPhone, he tested it out and was at first disappointed, he said in an interview. The phone lacked features like cutting and pasting text, and the ability to send text messages to more than one person at a time. The iPhone offered no way for its owners to install new software, such as games or alternative Web browsers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font--body font-copy gray-darkest ma-0 pb-md&quot;&gt;Still, the iPhone’s potential as a truly mobile, Internet-connected computer had quickly captured the attention of software developers who began tinkering with it. One of Freeman’s friends convinced him that, instead of complaining about the iPhone’s lack of software, he should get to work and create software of his own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font--body font-copy gray-darkest ma-0 pb-md&quot;&gt;Freeman quickly found himself at the center of a burgeoning community of developers building new features atop the iPhone. Those additions required removing software barriers on the phone so that new applications would run on the operating system, much like a traditional computer. The act of getting past the phone’s restrictions in this way became known as “jailbreaking.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font--body font-copy gray-darkest ma-0 pb-md&quot;&gt;Freeman wanted to make jailbreaking and installing new software easy, even for customers with little technical knowledge. The effort resulted in Cydia, an app store where customers could install games and features, including the ability to cut and paste text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div readability=&quot;11.696821515892&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font--body font-copy gray-darkest ma-0 pb-md&quot;&gt;Freeman said that Cydia, which he named after an &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Codling_moth&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;agricultural pest&lt;/a&gt; that affects fruit crops, was an immediate hit. There were so many people using it that he estimates half of early iPhone customers must have been “jailbreaking” their phones to take advantage of the additional features it offered. In 2010, Freeman &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/economy/once-the-hobby-of-tech-geeks-iphone-jailbreaking-now-a-lucrative-industry/2011/04/01/AFBJ0VpC_story.html?itid=lk_inline_manual_28&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;told The Washington Post&lt;/a&gt; that Cydia had 4.5 million people searching for apps every week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font--body font-copy gray-darkest ma-0 pb-md&quot;&gt;In 2008, Apple came out with its own version, called simply “The App Store.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;10.371972318339&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font--body font-copy gray-darkest ma-0 pb-md&quot;&gt;Apple also began adding additional protections to the phone’s operating system and warning its customers that jailbreaking their phones could put them at risk of security vulnerabilities. Sainz reiterated the warning in a statement Thursday. Freeman said he remembers seeing physical signs in Apple retail stores with such warnings. Freeman says the security risks are overblown. Such downloads are similar to those on a PC, which could include software that invades a user’s privacy or gathers their data. And even Apple-approved apps can &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2019/05/28/its-middle-night-do-you-know-who-your-iphone-is-talking/?itid=lk_inline_manual_32&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;expose customers to privacy risks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font--body font-copy gray-darkest ma-0 pb-md&quot;&gt;“Morally speaking, it’s your phone and you should be able to do whatever you want with it,” Freeman said. “You should get to decide which applications you put on it, and you should be able to decide where you get those applications from.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font--body font-copy gray-darkest ma-0 pb-md&quot;&gt;“The ability of people to jailbreak and put their own software on devices is an important one that has allowed people to do a lot of cool and interesting things,” said Kurt Opsahl, deputy executive director and general counsel of the Electronic Frontier Foundation, a nonprofit technology advocacy group that helped gain the legal exception for jailbreaking. Opsahl said that, with only one app store to install software on iPhones, he’s concerned about whether the process for installing apps is fair. “How are they going to use that monopoly power?” he asked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;12.490196078431&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font--body font-copy gray-darkest ma-0 pb-md&quot;&gt;After losing its argument in front of the Copyright Office, Apple continued its attempts to stop Cydia. It made jailbreaking more difficult by adding more barricades against outside software being installed on the phone. At the same time, Apple &lt;a href=&quot;https://ios.gadgethacks.com/how-to/60-ios-features-apple-stole-from-jailbreakers-0188093/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;added new features&lt;/a&gt; that had previously been available on Cydia. Apple’s Control Center, its bubble notifications and the ability to immediately respond to text messages on the home screen all originated on Cydia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font--body font-copy gray-darkest ma-0 pb-md&quot;&gt;According to the lawsuit, Apple used “coercive” terms to try to prevent Apple customers from using Cydia or any alternative means to install software and discouraged developers from using services like Cydia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font--body font-copy gray-darkest ma-0 pb-md&quot;&gt;Cydia’s revenue peaked in 2011 and 2012, when it brought in about $10 million, Freeman said. Cydia, like Apple, charged Apple developers a commission on sales. In 2013, as Apple’s own App Store gained more power and prominence, Cydia’s business began to dry up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font--body font-copy gray-darkest ma-0 pb-md&quot;&gt;Apple also began hiring former “jailbreakers” to work on its security team. Freeman said some of those people were his friends, and he said those discussions were awkward. “When Robin Hood is willing to go work for the sheriff of Nottingham because they have cool crossbows, it’s like, ‘What were you doing?’ ” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;8.2460732984293&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font--body font-copy gray-darkest ma-0 pb-md&quot;&gt;Jailbreaking an iPhone has become so difficult that many in the jailbreaking community have essentially thrown in the towel and moved on, and some have declared the practice &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en/article/8xa4ka/iphone-jailbreak-life-death-legacy&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;essentially dead&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font--body font-copy gray-darkest ma-0 pb-md&quot;&gt;Freeman is still working in software development but spends less time on Cydia, which still exists but is far less popular than it once was. He is head of technology for a privacy software company called Orchid and he is an elected official in California, serving on the board of the Isla Vista Community Services District in Santa Barbara County.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font--body font-copy gray-darkest ma-0 pb-md&quot;&gt;Freeman’s attorneys at Quinn Emanuel, the same law firm that represented Samsung in its blockbuster patent war with Apple, say that now is finally the time for Cydia to take on Apple in court.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font--body font-copy gray-darkest ma-0 pb-md&quot;&gt;“The legal climate for this claim has been changing,” said Stephen Swedlow, the lead attorney for Cydia. Swedlow said he’s been watching other lawsuits, including the one filed by Epic, and he believes Cydia could be the “perfect claimant” for an antitrust case against Apple. Swedlow said that if the suit is successful, Cydia would aim to once again compete with Apple, this time without the need for jailbreaking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;11.605363984674&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font--body font-copy gray-darkest ma-0 pb-md&quot;&gt;Swedlow filed an antitrust case against Facebook last week on behalf of people who use the social network, and Quinn Emanuel is representing Blix, a maker of email software, in another &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2019/10/04/apple-sued-by-app-developer-alleged-patent-infringement-antitrust-violation/?itid=lk_inline_manual_52&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;antitrust case against Apple&lt;/a&gt;, which was recently dismissed in federal court.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;font--body font-copy gray-darkest ma-0 pb-md&quot;&gt;Other lawsuits point out that Apple has no competitors when it comes to iOS app distribution. But Cydia was that competitor, Swedlow says. And it had millions of followers. Then, he said, Apple took anti-competitive measures to snuff Cydia out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>saurik</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2020/12/10/cydia-apple-lawsuit/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php?src=https://arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/Y55VTBRZPII6XKWZRFMSE4UAYQ.jpg&amp;w=1440</og:image>
<og:title>The ‘app store’ before there was an App Store wants to liberate your iPhone … again</og:title>
<og:description>Cydia allowed iPhone owners to install apps before there was ever an App Store. Apple successfully pushed Cydia into oblivion, but the company's founder, Jay Freeman, is fighting back in a new lawsuit that aims to free iPhones from Apple's control.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2020/12/10/cydia-apple-lawsuit/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>New Relic to open-source Pixie’s eBPF observability platform</title>
<link>https://blog.pixielabs.ai/pixie-new-relic/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.pixielabs.ai/pixie-new-relic/</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;MuiTypography-root MuiTypography-body1&quot;&gt;We are excited to announce that we signed a &lt;a class=&quot;MuiTypography-root jss3 MuiTypography-body1&quot; href=&quot;http://blog.newrelic.com/product-news/pixie-developer-first-observability&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;definitive agreement&lt;/a&gt; to join New Relic -- an outcome we certainly never predicted after only just two years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MuiTypography-root MuiTypography-body1&quot;&gt;New Relic’s focus on the developer is legendary. When New Relic's Founder/CEO, Lew Cirne, first started tinkering around with Pixie and participating in our community, we noticed an alignment in our visions for the future of observability, as well as echoes of New Relic’s developer-centric roots in Pixie. Joining New Relic will provide us with an unprecedented opportunity to reach millions of developers faster by open-sourcing a self-managed version of Pixie in the upcoming months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MuiTypography-root MuiTypography-body1&quot;&gt;When we started Pixie in 2018, Kubernetes was rapidly gaining traction. We felt that a new approach to observability was needed due to the new, fundamental challenges in observing distributed, ephemeral systems. We founded Pixie in order to provide instant, flexible observability for developers like ourselves who were building applications on Kubernetes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MuiTypography-root MuiTypography-body1&quot;&gt;However, we knew that the most developer-friendly version of Pixie must be open-source. In a forward-looking move, New Relic is giving us the opportunity to open-source Pixie and focus on providing world-class observability to all developers. The developer community is a core element of New Relic’s vision, and Pixie’s open-source offering will be a key part of that initiative and the primary area of focus for the Pixie team going forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MuiTypography-root MuiTypography-body1&quot;&gt;We are so excited to begin working with New Relic on our shared vision for the future of observability. In the coming months, we’ll be jointly committing our roadmap in the following initiatives:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;MuiTypography-root MuiTypography-body1&quot; readability=&quot;35.5&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;jss4&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MuiTypography-root MuiTypography-body1&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pixie Core&lt;/strong&gt;: An open-source and self-managed version of Pixie which we will release to the CNCF sandbox early next year. As part of the process, we look forward to speaking with you about this at Kubecon-EU on May’21. Due to Pixie’s and New Relic’s commitment to open standards, we also plan to build out integrations with OpenTelemetry, Prometheus, and Grafana.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;jss4&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MuiTypography-root MuiTypography-body1&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pixie By New Relic&lt;/strong&gt;: Our current Pixie Community offering will continue as a hosted version of Pixie Core and existing New Relic One customers will soon get instant access to Pixie data with a few clicks. Their existing experiences will be augmented with the metrics, logs, events, and application traces that Pixie automatically provides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;jss4&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MuiTypography-root MuiTypography-body1&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pixie by New Relic, Enterprise Edition&lt;/strong&gt;: Industry-specific solutions for sectors such as Media, Telecommunications, and Government that allow enterprise customers to install Pixie entirely inside production clusters while meeting compliance, data security, support, and performance requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;MuiTypography-root MuiTypography-body1&quot;&gt;Finally, our journey is just beginning. We are a team of 12 people with a huge vision to reach every Kubernetes developer. As we embark on this part of our journey, we encourage anyone passionate about open source, Kubernetes, and observability to apply to join us &lt;a class=&quot;MuiTypography-root jss3 MuiTypography-body1&quot; href=&quot;https://pixielabs.ai/careers/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MuiTypography-root MuiTypography-body1&quot;&gt;You can try out Pixie &lt;a class=&quot;MuiTypography-root jss3 MuiTypography-body1&quot; href=&quot;https://work.withpixie.ai/auth/signup?UTM=PXNR&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, learn more about us &lt;a class=&quot;MuiTypography-root jss3 MuiTypography-body1&quot; href=&quot;https://pixielabs.ai/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and ping us anytime on our Pixienaut community slack.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 16:08:50 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>htroisi</dc:creator>
<og:title>Accelerating the Pixie community with New Relic</og:title>
<og:description>We are excited to announce that we signed a definitive agreement to join New Relic -- an outcome we certainly never predicted after only just two years. New…</og:description>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url></og:url>
<og:image>/static/aa3ab584229602773289bfdd1fd3b5ad/a7ebc/hero-image.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.pixielabs.ai/pixie-new-relic/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Facebook being investigated in Germany for tying Oculus use to Facebook accounts</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/facebook-hit-with-antitrust-probe-for-tying-oculus-use-to-facebook-accounts/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/facebook-hit-with-antitrust-probe-for-tying-oculus-use-to-facebook-accounts/</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/facebook&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;facebook&quot;&gt;Facebook’s&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/facebook-antitrust-state-attorneys-general/&quot;&gt;bad week&lt;/a&gt; just got worse: It’s being investigated in Germany for linking usage of its VR product, Oculus, to having a Facebook account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tech giant raised the hackles of the VR community this summer when it &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oculus.com/blog/a-single-way-to-log-into-oculus-and-unlock-social-features/&quot;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; it would be merging users of the latest Oculus kit onto a single Facebook account — and would end support for existing &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/oculus-vr&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;oculus-vr&quot;&gt;Oculus&lt;/a&gt; account users by 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New users were immediately required to have a Facebook account in order to log in and access content for the virtual reality kit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/25/facebook-changes-name-of-its-annual-vr-event-and-its-overall-ar-vr-organization/&quot;&gt;August&lt;/a&gt; Facebook also announced that it was changing the name of the VR business it acquired &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2014/03/25/facebook-to-buy-oculus-vr-maker-of-the-rift-headset-for-around-2b-in-cash-and-stock/?_ga=2.118783051.351571251.1607268348-1757155993.1533833482&quot;&gt;back in 2014&lt;/a&gt; for around $2 billion — and had allowed to operate separately — to “&lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/facebook-reality-labs&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;facebook-reality-labs&quot;&gt;Facebook Reality Labs&lt;/a&gt;“, signalling the assimilation of Oculus into its wider social empire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Related: The last of Oculus’ original co-founders left the company &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/13/facebook-is-losing-its-last-oculus-co-founder/&quot;&gt;last year&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In recent years Facebook has been pushing to &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/25/facebook-is-building-a-new-social-layer-for-oculus-headsets/&quot;&gt;add a “social layer” to the VR platform&lt;/a&gt; — but the heavy-handed requirement for Oculus users to have a Facebook account has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/2020/08/19/oculus-vr-headsets-will-soon-require-a-facebook-account-and-that-sucks/&quot;&gt;not proved popular with gamers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now antitrust authorities are taking an interest in the move.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Germany’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bundeskartellamt.de/SharedDocs/Meldung/EN/Pressemitteilungen/2020/10_12_2020_Facebook_Oculus.html&quot;&gt;Federal Cartel Office&lt;/a&gt; (aka, the Bundeskartellamt) said today that it’s instigated abuse proceedings against Facebook to examine the linkage between Oculus VR products and its eponymous social network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a statement, its president, Andreas Mundt, said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the future, the use of the new Oculus glasses requires the user to also have a Facebook account. Linking virtual reality products and the group’s social network in this way could constitute a prohibited abuse of dominance by Facebook. With its social network Facebook holds a dominant position in Germany and is also already an important player in the emerging but growing VR (virtual reality) market. We intend to examine whether and to what extent this tying arrangement will affect competition in both areas of activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The FCO has another “abuse of dominance proceeding” ongoing against Facebook — related to how it combines user data for ad profiling in a privacy-hostile way, which the authority contends is an abuse of Facebook’s market dominance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/23/antitrust-case-against-facebooks-super-profiling-back-on-track-after-german-federal-court-ruling/&quot;&gt;case&lt;/a&gt; is seen as highly innovative in how it combines privacy and antitrust concerns so is being closely watched.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latest FCO proceeding against Facebook comes at an awkward time for the tech giant, which has been hit with a &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/facebook-antitrust-state-attorneys-general/&quot;&gt;massive antitrust lawsuit from 46 U.S. States&lt;/a&gt; — accusing it of suppressing competition through monopolistic business practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As antitrust regulators have stepped up their scrutiny of Zuckerberg’s empire in recent years, Facebook has responded aggressively: Announcing a plan to consolidate its messaging products onto a single technical backend, as well as &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/04/facebook-branding/&quot;&gt;adding Facebook branding to its acquisitions&lt;/a&gt; — in an apparent bid to make it harder for competition regulators to order a break up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/05/facebook-is-pivoting/&quot;&gt;PR has also sought to cloak the “single backend” move by claiming it will increase user privacy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet the states’ antitrust case against the company includes filings that show a Facebook executive discussing using moments of perceived increased competition for its business as an opportunity to decrease user privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, uh, awkward….&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed breakout&quot; readability=&quot;8.356940509915&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-width=&quot;550&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot; readability=&quot;10.86402266289&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Last year &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/DinaSrinivasan?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@DinaSrinivasan&lt;/a&gt; theorized that Facebook's monopoly has allowed it to degrade user privacy. The AG lawsuit adopts her theory—and, amazingly, it uncovered internal emails suggesting FB was consciously basing privacy decisions on the degree of competition it faced. &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/43eh6IeQfF&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/43eh6IeQfF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Gilad Edelman (@GiladEdelman) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/GiladEdelman/status/1336837161065263105?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;December 10, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reached for comment on the FCO Oculus proceeding, a Facebook spokesperson sent us this statement: “While Oculus devices are not currently available for sale in Germany, we will cooperate fully with the Bundeskartellamt and are confident we can demonstrate that there is no basis to the investigation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tech giant has used a series of legal tactics to block the FCO’s earlier order against “superprofiling” users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/26/facebook-succeeds-in-blocking-german-fcos-privacy-minded-order-against-combining-user-data/&quot;&gt;Last year&lt;/a&gt; Facebook successfully applied to block the order banning it from combining user data. However, Germany’s Federal Court of Justice reversed the decision of the Higher Regional Court — confirming the FCO’s order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although, the hearing on the main proceeding is still pending at the Düsseldorf Higher Regional Court — currently scheduled for March 26, 2021 (after being postponed from a date in November).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook also responded to the Federal Court of Justice ruling by filing another emergency appeal against the FCO’s order — succeeding for a second time in blocking the order against combining user data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The FCO says it does not have a route to appeal this preliminary block on points of law — meaning it’s had to lodge a complaint with the Federal Court of Justice, which it did on December 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a statement, Mundt criticized Facebook for resorting to “legal remedies” to block the order, which he said is delaying relief for consumers and competitors vis-à-vis Facebook’s abusive practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The fact that Facebook has resorted to various legal remedies is not surprising in view of the significance which our proceedings have for the group’s business model. Nevertheless, the resulting delay in proceedings is of course regrettable for competition and consumers,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This is the second time that the Higher Regional Court has preliminarily granted an emergency appeal filed by Facebook. The deadline imposed on Facebook for implementing our demands has again been suspended. As in our view the reasons for this are not sustainable, we have immediately filed a complaint with the Federal Court of Justice. We want the clock to be ticking again for Facebook.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook using courts to block attempts to hold its business model accountable for violating regional laws is par for the course in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tech giant has recently succeeded in blocking a preliminary order from Ireland’s Data Protection Commission to suspend personal data transfers to the U.S. by &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/11/facebook-seeks-fresh-legal-delay-to-block-order-to-suspend-its-transatlantic-data-transfers/&quot;&gt;applying for a judicial review of the regulator’s process&lt;/a&gt;, for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/04/30/facebook-is-trying-to-block-schrems-ii-privacy-referral-to-eu-top-court/&quot;&gt;sought to block&lt;/a&gt; Irish courts from referring the Schrems II case, which underpins that decision, to the CJEU in the first place — though it did not succeed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In public remarks in &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/23/facebook-denies-it-will-pull-service-in-europe-over-data-transfer-ban/&quot;&gt;September&lt;/a&gt;, Facebook VP Nick Clegg claimed it’s taking that legal action not to defend its own business model but to “try to send a signal that this is a really big issue for the whole European economy, for all small and large companies that rely on data transfers” — which he suggested would be “absolutely disastrous” for the EU as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 13:44:09 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Liriel</dc:creator>
<og:title>Facebook hit with antitrust probe for tying Oculus use to Facebook accounts – TechCrunch</og:title>
<og:description>Facebook’s bad week just got worse: It’s being investigated in Germany for linking usage of its VR product, Oculus, to having a Facebook account. The tech giant raised the hackles of the VR community this summer when it announced it would be merging users of the latest Oculus kit onto a…</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Oculus-Quest-Lifestyle-1.jpg?w=600</og:image>
<og:url>https://social.techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/facebook-hit-with-antitrust-probe-for-tying-oculus-use-to-facebook-accounts/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/facebook-hit-with-antitrust-probe-for-tying-oculus-use-to-facebook-accounts/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A former Uber engineer&amp;#039;s disaster story</title>
<link>https://twitter.com/StanTwinB/status/1336890442768547845</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://twitter.com/StanTwinB/status/1336890442768547845</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;So this smaller core team of Design, Product, and Architecture went off in a room for with their new functional/reactive patterns, new language, and new app for a few months. Everything went well. The architecture relied heavily on the advanced language features of Swift.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 13:29:44 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>epaga</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mobile.twitter.com/StanTwinB/status/1336890442768547845</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: After 2.5 years on my side project, it has hit £500/month revenue</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25372464</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25372464</guid>
<description>&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.58823529411765&quot;&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=&quot;#FF6600&quot;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;pagespace&quot; title=&quot;Show HN: After 2.5 years on my side project, it has hit &amp;#xA3;500/month revenue&quot;&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.0635091496233&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;fatitem&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.2195909580194&quot;&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing&quot; id=&quot;25372464&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;title&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25372464&quot; class=&quot;storylink&quot;&gt;Show HN: After 2.5 years on my side project, it has hit £500/month revenue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.71052631578947&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;subtext&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;score&quot; id=&quot;score_25372464&quot;&gt;487 points&lt;/span&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/user?id=gigamick&quot; class=&quot;hnuser&quot;&gt;gigamick&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;age&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25372464&quot;&gt;13 hours ago&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span id=&quot;unv_25372464&quot;/&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/hide?id=25372464&amp;amp;goto=item%3Fid%3D25372464&quot;&gt;hide&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://hn.algolia.com/?query=Show%20HN%3A%20After%202.5%20years%20on%20my%20side%20project%2C%20it%20has%20hit%20%C2%A3500%2Fmonth%20revenue&amp;amp;sort=byDate&amp;amp;dateRange=all&amp;amp;type=story&amp;amp;storyText=false&amp;amp;prefix&amp;amp;page=0&quot; class=&quot;hnpast&quot;&gt;past&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/fave?id=25372464&amp;amp;auth=4d9651dcc7bce52693f7c246b3b30d317a2ab677&quot;&gt;favorite&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25372464&quot;&gt;248 comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9.242912371134&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;11.675257731959&quot;&gt;It's been a long slow hog and I almost gave up a few times (more than a few) but when covid hit this year it gave me some time to really focus on my product. There were stupid user journey things that I knew needed fixed. There were some features I knew needed added. And I knew the pricing was wrong.
&lt;p&gt;I spent some hardcore time working on these things back in March / April and since then my MRR has continued to grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My product is SongBox (&lt;a href=&quot;https://songbox.rocks&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://songbox.rocks&lt;/a&gt;) - it's an alternative to things like bandcamp and soundcloud for creators who need to share audio files privately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm at a stage now where I've bottomed out all the work I've wanted to do and I'm looking for a fresh round of feedback. Would love you guys to check it out and see what you can think of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.71604938271605&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;yclinks&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsguidelines.html&quot;&gt;Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsfaq.html&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/lists&quot;&gt;Lists&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/HackerNews/API&quot;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/security.html&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/legal/&quot;&gt;Legal&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Apply to YC&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Contact&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 11:19:15 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>gigamick</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25372464</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Burnt $72k testing Firebase and Cloud Run and almost went bankrupt</title>
<link>https://blog.tomilkieway.com/72k-1/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.tomilkieway.com/72k-1/</guid>
<description>&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the story of how close we came to shutting down before even launching our first product, how we survived, and the lessons we learnt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;In March, 2020, when COVID hit the world, our startup Milkie Way too was hit with a big blow and almost shut down. &lt;strong&gt;We burnt $72,000 while exploring and internally testing Cloud Run with Firebase within a few hours.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In November 2019, after having the idea, I started developing &lt;strong&gt;Announce &lt;a href=&quot;https://annc.in&quot;&gt;https://announce.today&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. The goal was to create an “MVP”, a functional V1 of the product, and for this reason our code was based on a simple stack. We used JS, Python and deployed our product on Google App engine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Announce on Desktop&lt;/em&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.tomilkieway.com/assets/images/post_images/anc-first-look.png&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having a very small team, our focus was on writing code, designing the UI and getting product ready. I spent minimal time in Cloud management, just enough to make us go live, and have basic development flow (cicd) going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the V1 web application, user experience was not the smoothest, but we just wanted to make a product that some of our users could experiment with, while we built a better version of Announce. With Covid hitting the world, we thought it was the best time to make a difference as Announce could be used by the governments to make announcements world wide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wouldn’t it be cool to have some rich data on the platform even if users don’t create content to begin with? This thought that led to another project, called &lt;strong&gt;Announce-AI&lt;/strong&gt;. It’s purpose was to create rich content for Announce automatically. Rich data == events, safety warnings like earthquakes, and possibly local relevant news.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;some-technical-details&quot;&gt;Some Technical Details&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To begin developing Announce-AI, we used Cloud Functions. As our bot scraping the web was fairly young, we believed light weight Cloud functions were the way to go. However, as we decided to scale, we ran into troubles because Cloud Functions have a timeout of ~9 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this time we learn about Cloud Run, which then had a big free usage tier! Without understanding it completely, I asked my team to deploy a “test” Announce AI function on Cloud Run, and see it’s performance. The goal was to play around with Cloud Run, so we can learn and explore it really fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.tomilkieway.com/assets/images/72K/cloud-run.jpg&quot; width=&quot;80%&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Google Cloud Run&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To keep it simple, as our experiment was for a very small site, we used Firebase for database, as Cloud Run doesn’t have any storage, and deploying on SQL server, or any other DB for a test run would have been an over kill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I created a new GCP project ANC-AI Dev, set up $7 Cloud Billing budget, kept Firebase Project on the Free (Spark) plan. The worst case we imagined was exceeding the daily free Firestore limits if we faltered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some code modifications, we deployed the code, ran it by making few requests in middle of the day manually and then left it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;nightmare-begins&quot;&gt;Nightmare Begins&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything went fine on the day of test, and we got back to developing Announce. Next day after working, I went for a quick nap in late afternoon. On waking up I read few emails from Google Cloud, all sent within few minutes of each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;First Email: Auto upgrade of our Firebase Project&lt;/em&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.tomilkieway.com/assets/images/72K/auto-upgrade.jpg&quot; width=&quot;80%&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Second Email: Budget Exceeded&lt;/em&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.tomilkieway.com/assets/images/72K/budget.jpg&quot; width=&quot;80%&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily my card had a spending limit of $100 preset. This led to declining the charges, and Google suspending all our accounts with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Third email: Card was declined&lt;/em&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.tomilkieway.com/assets/images/72K/card-declined.jpg&quot; width=&quot;80%&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I jumped out of the bed, logged into Google Cloud Billing, and saw a bill for ~$5,000. Super stressed, and not sure what happened, I clicked around, trying to figure out what was happening. I also started thinking of what may have happened, and how we could “possibly” pay the $5K bill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem was, every minute the bill kept going up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After 5 minutes, the bill read $15,000, in 20 mins, it said $25,000. I wasn’t sure where it would stop. Perhaps it won’t stop?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After two hours, it settled at a little short of $72,000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By this time, my team and I were on a call, I was in a state of complete shock and had absolutely no clue about what we would do next. We disabled billing, closed all services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because we used same company card across all our GCP Projects, all our accounts and projects were suspended by Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;nightmare-continues&quot;&gt;Nightmare Continues&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This happened on Friday evening, March 27th, 3 days before we had planned V1 of Announce to go live. Our product development was dead as Google suspended all our projects as they were tied to same credit card. My morale was as low as it could be, and the future of our company was unsure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.tomilkieway.com/assets/images/72K/suspended.jpg&quot; width=&quot;80%&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;All our Cloud Projects were suspended; development stopped&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once my mind made peace with this new reality, at midnight I sat down to actually investigate what happened. I started writing a document detailing all the investigations… I called this document: “Chapter 11”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two of my team members who were in this experiment also stayed up all night investigating and trying to make sense of what had happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next morning on Saturday, March 28th, I called and emailed over a dozen law firms to book an appointment / have a chat with some attorney. All of them were away, but I was able to get response from one of them over email. Because the details of the incident are so complicated even for engineers, explaining this to an attorney in plain english was a challenge of its own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a bootstrapped company, there was no way for us to come up with $72K.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By this time, I was well versed with Chapter 7 and Chapter 11 of Bankruptcy and mentally prepared of what could come next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;some-breather--gcp-loopholes&quot;&gt;Some Breather : GCP Loopholes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the Saturday after sending emails to lawyers, I started reading more and going through every single page in GCP Documentation. We did make mistakes, but it didn’t make sense that Google let us spend $72K without even making a payment on the project before!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.tomilkieway.com/assets/images/72K/firebasegcp.jpg&quot; width=&quot;80%&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;GCP and Firebase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;1-automatic-upgrade-of-firebase-account-to-paid-account&quot;&gt;1. Automatic Upgrade of Firebase Account to Paid Account&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We never anticipated this, nor was this ever displayed while signing up for Firebase. Our GCP project had billing connected to have Cloud Run execute, but Firebase was under Free plan (Spark). GCP just out of the blue upgraded it, and charged us for the amount it needed to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turns out this is their process as “Firebase and GCP are deeply integrated”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;2-billing-limits-dont-exist-budgets-are-at-least-a-day-late&quot;&gt;2. Billing “Limits” don’t exist. Budgets are at least a day late.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GCP Billing is actually delayed by at least a day. In most of their documentation Google suggests using Budgets and auto shut-off cloud function. Well guess what, by the time the cut off function would trigger, or the Cloud Users be notified, the damage would’ve probably been done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Billing takes about a day to be synced, and that’s why we noticed the charges the next day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;3-google-was-supposed-to-charge-us-100-not-72k&quot;&gt;3. Google was supposed to charge us $100, not $72K!&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As our account had not made any payment thus far, GCP should’ve first made charge for $100 as &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/billing/docs/how-to/billing-cycle#find-threshold-amount&quot;&gt;per billing info&lt;/a&gt;, and on non-payment, stopped the services. But it didn’t. I understood the reason later, but it’s still not the user’s fault!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first billing charge made to our account was of ~ $5,000. The next one for $72,000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.tomilkieway.com/assets/images/72K/automatic-payments.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Billing threshold for our account was $100&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;4-dont-rely-on-firebase-dashboard&quot;&gt;4. Don’t rely on Firebase Dashboard!&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not just Billing, but even Firebase Dashboard took more than 24 hours to update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As per Firebase Console documentation, the Firebase console dashboard numbers may differ ‘slightly’ from Billing reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our case, it differed by &lt;strong&gt;86,585,365.85 %&lt;/strong&gt;, or 86 million percentage points. Even when the bill was notified to us, Firebase Console dashboard still said 42,000 read+writes for the month (below the daily limit).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;new-day-new-challenge&quot;&gt;New Day, New Challenge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having been a Googler for ~6.5 years and written dozens of project documents, incident reports, and what not, I knew how to put the case for Google team when they would come back to work in 2 days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.tomilkieway.com/assets/images/72K/googleplex.jpg&quot; width=&quot;40%&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Last day at Google&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another task was to understand our mistake, and devise our product development strategy. Not everyone on the team knew what was going on, but it was quite clear that we were in some big trouble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a Googler I had experienced teams making mistakes costing Google millions of dollars, but the Google culture saves the employees (except engineers have to write a long incident report). This time, there was no Google. Our own limited capital and our hard work, was at complete stake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;This post is already getting long, so I’ll continue the details of how we managed to make this blunder, how we survived, and what did we learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.tomilkieway.com/72k-2/&quot;&gt;Part 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 10:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>bharatsb</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://blog.tomilkieway.com/72k-1/</og:url>
<og:title>We Burnt $72K testing Firebase + Cloud Run and almost went Bankrupt [Part 1]</og:title>
<og:description></og:description>
<og:image>https://blog.tomilkieway.com/assets/images/72K/72K.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.tomilkieway.com/72k-1/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Facebook Messenger, Instagram and WhatsApp Outage</title>
<link>https://developers.facebook.com/status/dashboard/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://developers.facebook.com/status/dashboard/</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.facebook.com/status/dashboard/&quot;&gt;https://developers.facebook.com/status/dashboard/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25372309&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25372309&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 389&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 230&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 10:52:49 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>iag</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://developers.facebook.com/status/dashboard/?_fb_noscript=1</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>French watchdog fines Google, Amazon for breaching cookies rules</title>
<link>https://fr.reuters.com/article/idUSKBN28K0NA</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://fr.reuters.com/article/idUSKBN28K0NA</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;ArticleBody-byline-container-3H6dy&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Byline-byline-1sVmo ArticleBody-byline-10B7D&quot;&gt;By &lt;a class=&quot;TextLabel__text-label___3oCVw TextLabel__black-to-orange___23uc0 TextLabel__serif___3lOpX Byline-author-2BSir&quot; href=&quot;https://fr.reuters.com/journalists/mathieu-rosemain&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Mathieu Rosemain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ArticleBody-read-time-and-social-2VOIr&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;TextLabel__text-label___3oCVw TextLabel__gray___1V4fk TextLabel__small-all-caps-spaced-out___3O9H4 ReadTime-read-time-1s3CG ArticleBody-read-time-29pGN&quot;&gt;3 MINUTES DE LECTURE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;PARIS (Reuters) -France’s data privacy watchdog has handed out its biggest ever fine of 100 million euros ($121 million) to Alphabet’s Google for breaching the country’s rules on online advertising trackers (cookies).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FILE PHOTO: A Google sign is shown at one of the company's office complexes in Irvine, California, U.S., July 27, 2020. REUTERS/Mike Blake&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;The CNIL said on Thursday it had also fined e-commerce giant Amazon 35 million euros for breaking the same rules,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;The regulator found the companies’ French websites didn’t seek the prior consent of visitors before advertising cookies - small pieces of data stored while navigating on the Web - were saved on computers, it said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;Google and Amazon also failed to provide clear information to internet users about how the firms intended to make use of such online trackers and how visitors to their French websites could refuse any use of the cookies, the watchdog said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;The CNIL rejected the companies’ arguments that it had no right to impose the sanctions because their respective European headquarters are in Ireland and Luxembourg - two countries perceived by some data privacy advocacy groups as being lenient toward Silicon Valley companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;The CNIL said Google’s fine had to be paid for the most part by its U.S. entity Google LLC (60 million euros) and the rest by EU-based Google Ireland Limited (40 million).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;Amazon’s fine has to be paid by its Luxembourg-based entity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;The CNIL said the companies had three months to change the information banners. If they fail to do so, they will face an additional fine of 100,000 euros per day until they comply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;The financial penalty against Google is the biggest ever issued by the CNIL, a spokesman for the watchdog said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;The previous record fine of 50 million euros also targeted the U.S. tech giant for breaching EU data privacy rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;“We stand by our record of providing upfront information and clear controls, strong internal data governance, secure infrastructure, and above all, helpful products,” Google said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;“Today’s decision under French ePrivacy laws overlooks these efforts and doesn’t account for the fact that French rules and regulatory guidance are uncertain and constantly evolving.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;Amazon said separately it disagreed with CNIL’s decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;“We continuously update our privacy practices to ensure that we meet the evolving needs and expectations of customers and regulators and fully comply with all applicable laws in every country in which we operate,” it said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;($1 = 0.8269 euros)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;4.6993006993007&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Attribution-attribution-Y5JpY&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reporting by Mathieu Rosemain; Writing by Matthieu Protard; Editing by Mark Potter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 10:36:55 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>hadrien01</dc:creator>
<og:title>French watchdog fines Google, Amazon for breaching cookies rules</og:title>
<og:description>France's data privacy watchdog has handed out its biggest ever fine of 100 million euros ($121 million) to Alphabet's Google for breaching the country's rules on online advertising trackers (cookies).</og:description>
<og:image>https://static.reuters.com/resources/r/?m=02&amp;d=20201210&amp;t=2&amp;i=1544144226&amp;r=LYNXMPEGB90BW&amp;w=800</og:image>
<og:url>https://fr.reuters.com/article/us-google-privacy-france-idUSKBN28K0NA</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>fr</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://fr.reuters.com/article/idUSKBN28K0NA</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Wall Street Begins Trading Water Futures as a Commodity</title>
<link>https://e360.yale.edu/digest/wall-street-begins-trading-water-futures-as-a-commodity</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://e360.yale.edu/digest/wall-street-begins-trading-water-futures-as-a-commodity</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article__images&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article__image-wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;js-enlarge&quot; href=&quot;https://e360.yale.edu/assets/site/CaliforniaCentralValley_Flickr_web.jpg&quot; data-caption=&quot;Fields in California's Central Valley agricultural region.&quot; data-credit=&quot;California Department of Food and Agriculture&quot;&gt;&lt;img sizes=&quot;(min-width: 1450px) 617px, (min-width: 1000px) 460px, (min-width: 600px) 60vw, 100vw&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/site/CaliforniaCentralValley_Flickr_web.jpg 836w, /assets/site/_200xAUTO_stretch_center-center/CaliforniaCentralValley_Flickr_web.jpg 200w, /assets/site/_400xAUTO_stretch_center-center/CaliforniaCentralValley_Flickr_web.jpg 400w, /assets/site/_600xAUTO_stretch_center-center/CaliforniaCentralValley_Flickr_web.jpg 600w, /assets/site/_800xAUTO_stretch_center-center/CaliforniaCentralValley_Flickr_web.jpg 800w&quot; src=&quot;https://e360.yale.edu/assets/site/_400xAUTO_stretch_center-center/CaliforniaCentralValley_Flickr_web.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Fields in California's Central Valley agricultural region.&quot; class=&quot;article__image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article__figcaption-p&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;article__caption&quot;&gt;Fields in California's Central Valley agricultural region.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;article__credit&quot;&gt;California Department of Food and Agriculture&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;68.910510510511&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wall Street has begun trading water as a commodity, like gold or oil. The country’s first water market launched on the Chicago Mercantile Exchange this week with $1.1 billion in contracts tied to water prices in California, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-12-06/water-futures-to-start-trading-amid-growing-fears-of-scarcity?sref=oUjKJw8m&quot;&gt;Bloomberg News reported&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The market allows farmers, hedge funds, and municipalities to hedge bets on the future price of water and water availability in the American West. The new trading scheme was announced in September, prompted by the region’s worsening heat, drought, and wildfires fueled by climate change. There were two trades when the market went live Monday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Climate change, droughts, population growth, and pollution are likely to make water scarcity issues and pricing a hot topic for years to come,” RBC Capital Markets managing director and analyst Deane Dray &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-12-06/water-futures-to-start-trading-amid-growing-fears-of-scarcity?sref=oUjKJw8m&quot;&gt;told Bloomberg&lt;/a&gt;. “We are definitely going to watch how this new water futures contract develops.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proponents argue the new market will clear up some of the uncertainty around water prices for farmers and municipalities, helping them budget for the resource. But some experts say treating water as a tradable commodity puts a basic human right into the hands of financial institutions and investors, a dangerous arrangement as climate change alters precipitation patterns and increases water scarcity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What this represents is a cynical attempt at setting up what’s almost like a betting casino so some people can make money from others suffering,” Basav Sen, climate justice project director at the Institute for Policy Studies, &lt;a href=&quot;https://earther.gizmodo.com/wall-street-s-new-water-market-is-the-latest-sign-we-re-1845824408?utm_campaign=Hot%20News&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;_hsmi=102252068&amp;amp;_hsenc=p2ANqtz--AP1LywJ3h9IP6wc77Xn-XnmmI7RMrZRQ6NwK6h8WJ6BPOWGUJH46jS-koLDVz7GlPD4mhPKLBgMqgzmUu5_hHBhi9wb0thNZTuCoLxNRz-41rjzY&amp;amp;utm_content=102252068&amp;amp;utm_source=hs_email&quot;&gt;told Earther&lt;/a&gt;. “My first reaction when I saw this was horror, but we’ve also seen this coming for quite some time.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 08:42:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>thread_id</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:title>Wall Street Begins Trading Water Futures as a Commodity</og:title>
<og:url>https://e360.yale.edu/digest/wall-street-begins-trading-water-futures-as-a-commodity</og:url>
<og:description></og:description>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://e360.yale.edu/digest/wall-street-begins-trading-water-futures-as-a-commodity</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>