<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>ACLU sues Homeland Security over &amp;#039;stingray&amp;#039; cell phone surveillance</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/11/aclu-cbp-ice-stingray-surveillance/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/11/aclu-cbp-ice-stingray-surveillance/</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot;&gt;One of the largest civil liberties groups in the U.S. is suing two Homeland Security agencies for failing to turn over documents it requested as part of a public records request about a controversial cell phone surveillance technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/american-civil-liberties-union&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;american-civil-liberties-union&quot;&gt;American Civil Liberties Union&lt;/a&gt; filed suit against Customs and Border Protection (CBP) and Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) in federal court on Wednesday after the organization claimed the agencies “failed to produce records” relating to cell site simulators — or “stingrays.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stingrays impersonate cell towers to trick cell phones into connecting to them, allowing its operator to collect unique identifiers from the device and determine their location. The devices are used for surveillance, but also ensnare &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/08/28/stingray-cell-phone-surveillance-devices-may-interfere-with-911-calls-senator-says/&quot;&gt;all other devices in their range&lt;/a&gt;. It’s believed newer, more advanced devices can intercept all the phone calls and text messages in range.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A government oversight report in 2016 said both CBP and ICE collectively spent $13 million on buying dozens of stingrays, which the agencies used to “locate people for arrest and prosecution,” the ACLU said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But little else is known about stingray technology because the cell phone snooping technology is sold exclusively to police departments and federal agencies under strict non-disclosure agreements with the device manufacturer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ACLU filed a Freedom of Information Act request in 2017 to learn more about the technology and how it’s used, but both agencies failed to turn over any documents, it said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The civil liberties organization said there is evidence to suggest that records exist, but has “exhausted all administrative remedies” to obtain the documents. Now it wants the courts to compel the agencies to turn over the records, “not only to shine a light on the government’s use of powerful surveillance technology in the immigration context, but also to assess whether its use of this technology complies with constitutional and legal requirements and is subject to appropriate oversight and control,” the filing said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The group wants the agencies’ training materials and guidance documents, and records to show where and when stingrays were deployed across the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CBP spokesperson Nathan Peeters said the agency does not comment on pending litigation as a matter of policy. A spokesperson for ICE did not comment.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 19:56:49 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mindgam3</dc:creator>
<og:title>ACLU sues Homeland Security over ‘stingray’ cell phone surveillance – TechCrunch</og:title>
<og:description>One of the largest civil liberties groups in the U.S. is suing two Homeland Security agencies for failing to turn over documents it requested as part of a public records request about a controversial cell phone surveillance technology. The American Civil Liberties Union filed suit against Customs a…</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/GettyImages-464375166.jpg?w=600</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2019/12/11/aclu-cbp-ice-stingray-surveillance/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/11/aclu-cbp-ice-stingray-surveillance/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A Thread about Internet Archive&amp;#039;s “Silent Killer”</title>
<link>https://twitter.com/textfiles/status/1204428311553642496</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://twitter.com/textfiles/status/1204428311553642496</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Could we mitigate this cost? Sure, we could scale back, not do certain types of websites, halt crawls, end some of these all-consuming saving projects. But based on the letters, references and news articles we've seen, that would not be a good idea for the world at large.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 17:22:35 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>danso</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mobile.twitter.com/textfiles/status/1204428311553642496</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Jack Dorsey Wants to Decentralize Twitter</title>
<link>https://decrypt.co/14386/jack-dorsey-wants-to-decentralize-twitter.</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://decrypt.co/14386/jack-dorsey-wants-to-decentralize-twitter.</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://decrypt.co/8358/bitcoins-price-rise-linked-to-proliferation-of-twitter-scams&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;sc-htpNat cLnQmm&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; CEO Jack Dorsey has revealed he wants to create an open standard for &lt;a href=&quot;https://decrypt.co/?post_type=post&amp;amp;p=5728&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot; class=&quot;sc-htpNat cLnQmm&quot;&gt;decentralized&lt;/a&gt; social media. And the goal will be to have Twitter conform to that standard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;&lt;span class=&quot;css-901oao css-16my406 r-1qd0xha r-ad9z0x r-bcqeeo r-qvutc0&quot;&gt;Twitter is funding a small independent team of up to five open source architects, engineers, and designers to develop an open and decentralized standard for social media. The goal is for Twitter to ultimately be a client of this standard,&quot; Dorsey &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jack/status/1204766078468911106&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;sc-htpNat cLnQmm&quot;&gt;tweeted&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twitter's CTO Parag Agrawal will be leading the team, which will be called Bluesky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dorsey highlighted some of the problems that the current swathe of centralized social media sites face, such as addressing misleading information. He also said that many of these sites promote controversy rather than healthy conversation. This could be summed up as some of the problems of Web2—the current Web we use today.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Instead he pointed to the principle of decentralization, and key technologies, such as blockchain, as the solution. These are generally seen as the building blocks of Web3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;&lt;span class=&quot;css-901oao css-16my406 r-1qd0xha r-ad9z0x r-bcqeeo r-qvutc0&quot;&gt;Finally, new technologies have emerged to make a decentralized approach more viable. Blockchain points to a series of decentralized solutions for open and durable hosting, governance, and even monetization. Much work to be done, but the fundamentals are there,&lt;/span&gt;&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, Dorsey acknowledged there will be a tough road ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;&lt;span class=&quot;css-901oao css-16my406 r-1qd0xha r-ad9z0x r-bcqeeo r-qvutc0&quot;&gt;There are MANY challenges to make this work that Twitter would feel right becoming a client of this standard. Which is why the work must be done transparently in the open, not owned by any single private corporation, furthering the open &amp;amp; decentralized principles of the internet.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, Dorsey hopes that the work will go beyond the creation of an open standard for decentralized social media, building a community around it too. He added that it may take several years to accomplish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;sc-jzJRlG jUBHpE&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Rebuilding social media&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, how would a decentralized version of a social media app solve such problems?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several ways in which Web3 technology, such as blockchain, could help address the problems with social media sites that we see today. For a start, centralized platforms have a lot of control over what data is seen, with algorithms deciding which content gets exposed. This type of system has been criticized for promoting one type of content over another, as Facebook and Google have been &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2018/dec/04/google-facebook-anti-conservative-bias-claims&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;sc-htpNat cLnQmm&quot;&gt;accused of&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a decentralized social media, there would be no central control, no team of people deciding what content should be shown to who. If the network did use any algorithms to sort content, they would be publicly available. This would give all news equal opportunity to go viral.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sc-hMqMXs sc-cpmKsF gHUPEg&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sc-gzVnrw sc-gPzReC bWlAB&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sc-hMqMXs gRUCSd&quot;&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;sc-jzJRlG sc-eXNvrr fhcYbm&quot;&gt;Experience Web 3.0.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;sc-hSdWYo sc-kQsIoO UzSFK&quot;&gt;Be the first to get Decrypt Members. A new type of account built on blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;button color=&quot;#745FDE&quot; class=&quot;sc-bxivhb cuQDeU sc-cMljjf gUZXin&quot;&gt; Early access&lt;/button&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, there's the issue of personal data. With a decentralized social media, the hope would be that each person would have complete control over their own data and decide who they want to share it with. This would work against the monetization of personal data. &lt;a href=&quot;https://decrypt.co/10241/inside-eys-radical-plan-to-get-major-businesses-using-ethereum&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;sc-htpNat cLnQmm&quot;&gt;Steps are already being made&lt;/a&gt; towards private blockchain transactions, which help to control user data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, this begs the questions: Who would develop a decentralized social media and how would they make any money out of it? For a start, many teams are working in the crypto space on projects that won't necessarily make money. Some just want to create decentralized technology that fulfils a need in society. But for those that do want to make money, the advent of blockchain technology makes it very easy for digital payments to be integrated into a decentralized app, such as a decentralized Twitter—offering potential means of monetization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As &lt;em&gt;Decrypt&lt;/em&gt; has reported before, several of the problems with Web2 come from all the content being free. Even micropayments for sharing information would go some way to stop spam and to make people produce valuable content. In October, David Waterhouse, CEO at Orchid, &lt;a href=&quot;https://decrypt.co/10293/a-look-at-orchids-decentralized-vpn-what-it-means-for-web3&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;sc-htpNat cLnQmm&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt;, &quot;You could argue a lot of the bad things about the internet are because things are free. Spam, right? If you had to pay to send emails, spam wouldn’t be necessary.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, even centralized apps are using decentralized technology to encourage better content on social media. For example, on social media app &lt;a href=&quot;https://decrypt.co/10091/taking-ethereum-mainstream-social-media-app-pepo-goes-live-at-devcon-5&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;sc-htpNat cLnQmm&quot;&gt;Pepo&lt;/a&gt;, when you press the like button, you send a micropayment to someone, rewarding them for creating good content. There are a lot of possibilities for Dorsey to explore with this technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, a decentralized version of Twitter has been created once before, known as Peepeth. It runs on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://decrypt.co/?post_type=post&amp;amp;p=5726&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot; class=&quot;sc-htpNat cLnQmm&quot;&gt;Ethereum&lt;/a&gt; blockchain. However, despite key figures of the Ethereum community, such as Ethereum co-founder Vitalik Buterin, trying it out, it struggled to gain much traction. Will Dorsey's plan for Twitter catch hold instead?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 14:46:14 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>sanefive</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://decrypt.co/14386/jack-dorsey-wants-to-decentralize-twitter</og:url>
<og:title>Jack Dorsey wants to decentralize Twitter - Decrypt</og:title>
<og:description>The Twitter CEO has put forth a vision for a more decentralized version of social media, leading with his own platform.</og:description>
<og:image>https://screenshot.dmedia.cloud/capture/aHR0cHM6Ly9kZWNyeXB0LmNvL3NjcmVlbnNob3QvMTQzODYvP3NlbGVjdG9yPS5wb3N0Q2FyZC1TdHlsZWRDYXJkJmhlaWdodD00NzBweCZ3aWR0aD05MDBweA==.png</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://decrypt.co/14386/jack-dorsey-wants-to-decentralize-twitter</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Learning at work is work, and we must make space for it</title>
<link>https://sloanreview.mit.edu/article/learning-for-a-living/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://sloanreview.mit.edu/article/learning-for-a-living/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;entry-summary entry-summary-paywall&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learning at work &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; work, and we must make space for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;aside class=&quot;article-ad ad-300&quot; id=&quot;piano-sidebar&quot;/&gt;&lt;aside class=&quot;article-ad ad-300 ad-300x250&quot;&gt;&lt;h6&gt;advertisement&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;div-gpt-ad-1555620904589-0&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-sidebar&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://sloanreview.mit.edu/content/uploads/2019/11/MAG-Petriglieri-Learning-2400-300x300.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;attribution&quot;&gt;Image courtesy of Davide Bonazzi/theispot.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The event was running over, the car was waiting, but the keynote speaker did not seem to mind. He was enjoying fielding questions from a large auditorium packed to the rafters with executives, aspiring entrepreneurs, and management students. “Get ready for an age in which we are all in tech,” he had told them, “whether you work in the tech industry or not.” The moderator called for one last question. “What’s the best way to get ready?” a woman asked. “Be great at learning,” he said without hesitation. “The moment you stop learning is the moment you begin to die.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calls for learning have long been common at corporate retreats, professional conferences, and similar gatherings. But with the furious pace of change that technology has brought to business and society, they have become more urgent.&lt;a id=&quot;reflink1&quot; class=&quot;reflink&quot; href=&quot;https://sloanreview.mit.edu/article/learning-for-a-living/#ref1&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt; Leaders in every sector seem to agree: Learning is an imperative, not a cliché. Without it, careers derail and companies fail. Talented people flock to employers that promise to invest in their development whether they will stay at the company or not.&lt;a id=&quot;reflink2&quot; class=&quot;reflink&quot; href=&quot;https://sloanreview.mit.edu/article/learning-for-a-living/#ref2&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt; And companies spend heavily on it. By one estimate, in 2018, corporate outlays on learning and development initiatives topped $200 billion.&lt;a id=&quot;reflink3&quot; class=&quot;reflink&quot; href=&quot;https://sloanreview.mit.edu/article/learning-for-a-living/#ref3&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the lofty statements and steep investments, however, learning &lt;em&gt;at&lt;/em&gt; work remains complicated. People are ambivalent about it, if not outright resistant. We want to learn, but we worry that we might not like what we learn. Or that learning will cost us too much. Or that we will have to give up cherished ideas.&lt;a id=&quot;reflink4&quot; class=&quot;reflink&quot; href=&quot;https://sloanreview.mit.edu/article/learning-for-a-living/#ref4&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt; There is often some shame involved in learning something new as an adult, a mentor told me at the start of my career. What if, in the process, we’re found lacking? What if we simply cannot pick up the knowledge and skills we need? I have spent two decades studying adult learning, helping companies design and deploy learning initiatives, and teaching and coaching thousands of high potentials and executives all over the world. And I have found that mentor’s words to be wise: Nothing truly novel, nothing that matters, is ever learned with ease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, most organizations are not as hospitable to learning as their rhetoric suggests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;article id=&quot;paywall-sidebar-callout-a&quot; class=&quot;m-paywall&quot;&gt;&lt;aside class=&quot;m-paywall-out&quot;&gt;&lt;h5 class=&quot;signin-paywall&quot;&gt;Already a member? &lt;a href=&quot;https://sloanreview.mit.edu/edit-profile/&quot; class=&quot;marketing-click p-login&quot; id=&quot;Sign_in[paywall]&quot;&gt;Sign In&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Not a member? &lt;a href=&quot;https://sloanreview.mit.edu/subscribe/&quot; class=&quot;marketing-click&quot; id=&quot;Subscribe[paywall]&quot;&gt;Sign Up Today!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/article&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;article-authors&quot; class=&quot;l-ref-block article-authors--inside&quot;&gt;
&lt;aside&gt;&lt;h5&gt;About the Author&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gianpiero Petriglieri (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/gpetriglieri&quot;&gt;@gpetriglieri&lt;/a&gt;) is an associate professor of organizational behavior at INSEAD and an expert on leadership and learning in the workplace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 14:30:15 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>sarapeyton</dc:creator>
<og:title>Learning for a Living</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://sloanreview.mit.edu/article/learning-for-a-living/</og:url>
<og:image>https://sloanreview.mit.edu/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/MAG-Petriglieri-Learning-1200x627.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Learning at work is work, and we can make it easier.</og:description>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://sloanreview.mit.edu/article/learning-for-a-living/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>S&amp;P 500 Buybacks Now Outpace All R&amp;D Spending in the US</title>
<link>https://thesoundingline.com/sp-500-buybacks-now-outpace-all-rd-spending-in-the-us/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://thesoundingline.com/sp-500-buybacks-now-outpace-all-rd-spending-in-the-us/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Submitted by Taps Coogan on the 17th of June 2019 to The Sounding Line.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enjoy The Sounding Line? Click &lt;a href=&quot;https://thesoundingline.com/taps-coogan-email-subscription-now-available/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to subscribe.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The United States engaged in roughly &lt;a href=&quot;https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/Y694RC1Q027SBEA#0&quot;&gt;$608 billion worth of research and development in 2018&lt;/a&gt;. That figure includes R&amp;amp;D by all entities in the US, from universities to private and public corporations. During the same year, corporations in the S&amp;amp;P 500 spent &lt;a href=&quot;http://press.spglobal.com/2019-03-25-S-P-500-Q4-2018-Buybacks-Set-4th-Consecutive-Quarterly-Record-at-223-Billion-2018-Sets-Record-806-Billion&quot;&gt;$806 billion buying back their own stock&lt;/a&gt;. In other words, the 500 largest companies in the US are now spending 33% more on their stock buyback programs than the entire country is investing in R&amp;amp;D. Cumulatively, buybacks have now outpaced R&amp;amp;D investment for the last five years. From 2014 through 2018, total R&amp;amp;D investment in the US was roughly $2.736 trillion whereas S&amp;amp;P 500 buybacks totaled $2.978 trillion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://thesoundingline.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/image-6.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://thesoundingline.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/image-6-1024x637.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-36358&quot; srcset=&quot;https://thesoundingline.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/image-6-1024x637.png 1024w, https://thesoundingline.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/image-6-300x187.png 300w, https://thesoundingline.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/image-6-768x478.png 768w, https://thesoundingline.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/image-6-400x249.png 400w, https://thesoundingline.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/image-6-1320x821.png 1320w, https://thesoundingline.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/image-6.png 1602w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we have &lt;a href=&quot;https://thesoundingline.com/dividends-and-buybacks-now-larger-than-total-reported-earnings-for-the-entire-sp-500/&quot;&gt;recently noted&lt;/a&gt;, the accelerating pace of stock buybacks has made corporations the largest and only significant net purchaser of stocks for the last five years. Furthermore, S&amp;amp;P 500 dividends and buybacks have exceeded total reported earnings for the S&amp;amp;P 500 over the last five years and even exceeded the total increase in S&amp;amp;P 500 market capitalization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;quads-location quads-ad2&quot; id=&quot;quads-ad2&quot;&gt;&lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-4401495442679385&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;2384793605&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;/&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://thesoundingline.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/image-5.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://thesoundingline.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/image-5.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-35086&quot; srcset=&quot;https://thesoundingline.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/image-5.png 661w, https://thesoundingline.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/image-5-300x261.png 300w, https://thesoundingline.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/image-5-400x347.png 400w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 661px) 100vw, 661px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, we are in the midst of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://thesoundingline.com/post-financial-crisis-has-seen-the-largest-increase-in-commercial-indebtedness-on-record/&quot;&gt;largest increase in commercial indebtedness on record&lt;/a&gt;. Combined, corporate debt securities and commercial and industrial loans have increased by over $3.7 trillion since the Financial Crisis, a record for any expansion, both in absolute dollars and relative to the GDP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://thesoundingline.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/image-2.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://thesoundingline.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/image-2-1024x586.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-36072&quot; srcset=&quot;https://thesoundingline.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/image-2-1024x586.png 1024w, https://thesoundingline.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/image-2-300x172.png 300w, https://thesoundingline.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/image-2-768x440.png 768w, https://thesoundingline.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/image-2-400x229.png 400w, https://thesoundingline.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/image-2-1320x756.png 1320w, https://thesoundingline.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/image-2.png 1502w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://thesoundingline.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/image-1.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://thesoundingline.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/image-1-1024x586.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-36071&quot; srcset=&quot;https://thesoundingline.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/image-1-1024x586.png 1024w, https://thesoundingline.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/image-1-300x172.png 300w, https://thesoundingline.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/image-1-768x440.png 768w, https://thesoundingline.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/image-1-400x229.png 400w, https://thesoundingline.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/image-1-1320x756.png 1320w, https://thesoundingline.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/image-1.png 1502w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the massive ‘investment’ corporations have made in their own equity, the need to sustain higher share prices with ever more buybacks creates a feedback loop that is drowning out real investment. All the while, corporations are burdening themselves with historic levels of debt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If borrowing conditions ever tighten and companies have to focus on cleaning up their balance sheets, there is going to be a historic reckoning for financial markets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;quads-location quads-ad2&quot; id=&quot;quads-ad2&quot;&gt;&lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-4401495442679385&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;2384793605&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;/&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Would you like to be notified when we publish a new article on The Sounding Line? &lt;a href=&quot;https://thesoundingline.com/taps-coogan-email-subscription-now-available/&quot;&gt;Click here to subscribe for free&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;quads-location quads-ad4&quot; id=&quot;quads-ad4&quot;&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 14:25:43 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>baronmunchausen</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>S&amp;P 500 Buybacks Now Outpace All R&amp;D Spending in the US - The Sounding Line</og:title>
<og:description>Given the massive 'investment' corporations have made in their own equity, the need to sustain higher share prices with ever more buybacks creates a feedback loop that is drowning out real investment</og:description>
<og:url>https://thesoundingline.com/sp-500-buybacks-now-outpace-all-rd-spending-in-the-us/</og:url>
<og:image>https://thesoundingline.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/image-6.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://thesoundingline.com/sp-500-buybacks-now-outpace-all-rd-spending-in-the-us/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Twitter funding a team to develop an open standard for social media</title>
<link>https://twitter.com/jack/status/1204766078468911106</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://twitter.com/jack/status/1204766078468911106</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;We’d expect this team not only to develop a decentralized standard for social media, but to also build open community around it, inclusive of companies &amp;amp; organizations, researchers, civil society leaders, all who are thinking deeply about the consequences, positive and negative.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 14:17:57 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>andreigheorghe</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mobile.twitter.com/jack/status/1204766078468911106</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ultrasound destroys 80 percent of prostate cancers in one-year study</title>
<link>https://newatlas.com/medical/ultrasound-destroys-prostate-cancers-one-year-study/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://newatlas.com/medical/ultrasound-destroys-prostate-cancers-one-year-study/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Treating prostate cancer through traditional means such as surgery or radiotherapy carries certain risks, with some patients experiencing impotence, urinary problems and bowel trouble, among other unwanted side effects. Safer and less invasive treatment options could soon be on the table, however, including a novel MRI-guided ultrasound technique that eliminated significant cancers in 80 percent of subjects in a year-long study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new technique is called MRI-guided transurethral ultrasound ablation (TULSA) and has been under development for a number of years. The minimally invasive technology involves a rod that enters the prostate gland via the urethra and emits highly controlled sound waves in order to heat and destroy diseased tissue, while leaving healthy tissue unharmed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These waves come from 10 heating elements built into the length of the rod to treat the entire prostate gland. An algorithm controls which of these elements emit the sound waves at any one time, along with their shape, direction and strength. All of this takes place within an MRI scanner, allowing doctors to keep a close eye on which tissues are being heated and by how much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Enhancement&quot; data-align-center=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Enhancement-item&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;TULSA uses a rod inserted into the prostate to target diseased tissue with soundwaves&quot; width=&quot;1440&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;https://assets.newatlas.com/dims4/default/113ee64/2147483647/strip/true/crop/2560x1440+0+0/resize/1440x810!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fassets.newatlas.com%2F3f%2F37%2Fd4fb021f46058ab2034151678ab1%2Fscreen-shot-2019-12-04-at-3.26.48%20pm%20%282%29.png&quot; data-lazy-load=&quot;true&quot; src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;Figure-content&quot; readability=&quot;34&quot;&gt;TULSA uses a rod inserted into the prostate to target diseased tissue with soundwaves
&lt;p&gt;Radiological Society of North America&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Unlike with other ultrasound systems on the market, you can monitor the ultrasound ablation process in real time and get immediate MRI feedback of the thermal dose and efficacy,&quot; says study co-auhor Steven S. Raman, M.D., professor of radiology and urology at the University of California at Los Angeles. &quot;It's an outpatient procedure with minimal recovery time.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Raman and his team recently put TULSA to the test in a study involving 115 men with low- or intermediate-risk prostate cancer that was confined to the gland. The TULSA treatment was administered to the whole gland for an average time of 51 minutes, with the cancers then reassessed 12 months later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These follow-up observations revealed some hugely promising results. “Clinically significant cancer” was totally eliminated in 80 percent of the subjects a year after the TULSA treatment. Sixty-five percent of the subjects exhibited no evidence of cancer at all in their biopsies, while prostate-specific antigen (PSA), the key biomarker for prostate cancer, was reduced by a median of 95 percent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No bowel complications were reported, while the group reported low rates of severe toxicity, low rates of impotence and close to no incontinence (involuntary urine loss from the bladder). Additionally, the technique can be used to treat other benign conditions, such as prostate enlargement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;There are two very unique things about this system,&quot; says Raman. &quot;First, you can control with much more finesse where you're going to treat, preserving continence and sexual function. Second, you can do this for both diffuse and localized prostate cancer and benign diseases, including benign hyperplasia.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scientists are now working towards further studies to support these exciting results. With TULSA already approved for clinical use in Europe, and having recently received FDA pre-market clearance as safe and effective for prostate treatment in the US, the hope is that it could reach clinical use stateside in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scientists presented the research results at this week’s annual meeting of the Radiological Society of North America. An abstract is available &lt;a class=&quot;Link&quot; href=&quot;https://press.rsna.org/pressrelease/2019_resources/2129/abstract.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-cms-ai=&quot;0&quot;&gt;online here&lt;/a&gt;, while the animation below offers a look at TULSA in action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Enhancement&quot; data-align-center=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Enhancement-item&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;VideoEnhancement&quot; data-video-disable-history=&quot;&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe id=&quot;YouTubeVideoPlayer-f51be6a2869e94084a3cc69336c44c440&quot; role=&quot;application&quot; title=&quot;YouTube embedded video player&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/oMzAFjrdnBE?enablejsapi=1&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Novel ultrasound treatment for prostate cancer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a class=&quot;Link&quot; href=&quot;https://press.rsna.org/timssnet/media/pressreleases/14_pr_target.cfm?id=2129&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-cms-ai=&quot;0&quot;&gt;Radiological Society of North America&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 13:47:52 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>howard941</dc:creator>
<og:title>Ultrasound destroys 80 percent of prostate cancers in one-year study</og:title>
<og:url>https://newatlas.com/medical/ultrasound-destroys-prostate-cancers-one-year-study/</og:url>
<og:image>https://assets.newatlas.com/dims4/default/155f308/2147483647/strip/true/crop/6000x3150+0+2694/resize/1200x630!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fassets.newatlas.com%2F67%2F57%2Fc03a23394253b6214dcf749f4a80%2Fdepositphotos-47467769-xl-2015.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Treating prostate cancer through traditional means such as surgery or radiotherapy carries certain risks, with some patients experiencing impotence, urinary problems and bowel trouble, among other unwanted side effects. Safer and less invasive treatment options could soon be on the table, however,…</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://newatlas.com/medical/ultrasound-destroys-prostate-cancers-one-year-study/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why the ‘Queen of Shitty Robots’ Renounced Her Crown</title>
<link>https://www.wired.com/story/simone-giertz-build-what-you-want/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.wired.com/story/simone-giertz-build-what-you-want/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;asset-embed__asset-container&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;responsive-asset asset-embed__responsive-asset responsive-asset--invisible&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;pHaving abandoned shitty robots Giertz is now working on a video series about going to space.p &quot; class=&quot;responsive-image__image&quot; src=&quot;https://media.wired.com/photos/5de5718f2acb7d00082c40a3/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/WI010120_FF_Simone20_04.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://media.wired.com/photos/5de5718f2acb7d00082c40a3/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/WI010120_FF_Simone20_04.jpg 1600w, https://media.wired.com/photos/5de5718f2acb7d00082c40a3/master/w_1280%2Cc_limit/WI010120_FF_Simone20_04.jpg 1280w, https://media.wired.com/photos/5de5718f2acb7d00082c40a3/master/w_1024%2Cc_limit/WI010120_FF_Simone20_04.jpg 1024w, https://media.wired.com/photos/5de5718f2acb7d00082c40a3/master/w_768%2Cc_limit/WI010120_FF_Simone20_04.jpg 768w, https://media.wired.com/photos/5de5718f2acb7d00082c40a3/master/w_640%2Cc_limit/WI010120_FF_Simone20_04.jpg 640w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caption__text&quot;&gt;Having abandoned shitty robots, Giertz is now working on a video series about going to space.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption__credit&quot;&gt;Photograph: Joe Pugliese&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the spring of 2017&lt;/strong&gt;, Giertz started to notice that her right eyelid was swollen. A fan on Twitter even commented on it: “What happened to your right eye? It's like a bump above the eyelid.” A year later, in April 2018, the eye started to ache. MRI scans revealed a noncancerous meningioma growing on the front of her brain. The tumor, which she nicknamed Brian, was remarkable chiefly because of its size: 4.6 centimeters across.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Plot twist,” Giertz says in a subdued voice during a YouTube dispatch about the golf-ball-sized growth at the time. “I don't even like golf. But I like my brain a lot.” Her face crumbles on camera, and she starts to cry, faced with the reality of potentially losing sight in one eye, being paralyzed on one side of her face, or suffering a stroke. By the end of the video, Giertz is joking about eye patch designs and ponders sending the excavated tumor into space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I ask Giertz about the decision to go public with her diagnosis, she says she's “very external” in how she processes things. “I wanted to tell absolutely everyone. Friends, colleagues, Lyft drivers, waitresses—absolutely everyone,” she says. “Seeing how other people reacted to it became a way for me to navigate the situation when I didn't really trust my own thoughts and feelings.” Her mother echoes this: “I think that was the best thing she could do. Why should you hide something like that? Her audience likes her.” But an internet audience is not the same as a group of real-life friends, something Giertz would become more aware of as her treatment went on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, Giertz might not have anticipated how drawn out the process would become. On the day of her surgery, she chronicled her pre-op jitters, posting a 59-second video just before having her skull cut open, closing out with “I hope you're having a good day” and her signature “Byeee.” After a nine-hour surgery (“Shortest day of my life,” she says), Giertz began her recovery process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doctors weren't able to remove the entirety of the tumor, due to its proximity to other critical structures in her head. What remained of Brian grew, and much more quickly than anyone anticipated. Eight months after the surgery, in January 2019, Giertz announced that her brain tumor was back. She had T-shirts made with an imprint of her holey brain and began selling them in an online Teespring store. But it's clear in the video announcing the tumor's resurgence that Giertz is crestfallen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the campaign for 2018 was to evict Brian, Giertz says, the goal of 2019 was to burn Brian through radiation therapy. This required rounds of treatment that would sap her of energy, making it difficult for the typically healthy, yoga-practicing, meditating, mostly vegan Giertz to even get out of bed. In her non-vlogging moments, Giertz felt vulnerable and alone, despite her many fans expressing support. Her family had flown in for her surgery, and her mother returned for her radiation treatments, but at some point they all went back to Sweden. Giertz had to ask her Bay Area friends, like her main collaborator, Marcos Ramirez, for help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;pullquote-embed&quot; readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pullquote-embed__content&quot;&gt;“Did I tell you that my brain has filled out?” Giertz says, as casually as if she had told me she was taking next Friday off.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Giertz's prognosis is good. But Brian has already altered her life deeply. “When you're young and reckless, you think you're never going to need people,” Giertz tells me at the wine-country workshop on that warm day in June. “But that was the first time in my life I've really, genuinely needed people.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a lot of ways, this required Giertz to embrace a role reversal. “She looks out for everyone on set,” says Laura Kampf, the YouTuber who collaborated with Giertz on the Pussy Grabs Back robot. “She's always worried that someone is hungry or didn't sleep enough.” I see this instinct as well. As I continue to meet with Giertz over a period of six months, she starts probing into how I'm doing and at one point says with a straight face that she's writing a magazine profile on me too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“There've been times when I was working with people, and she's called me up and said, ‘Hey, when you weren't looking that person was kind of shitty to someone else on the crew, and I thought you should know that,’ ” Savage says. “Her values are just never not present in all the things that she's doing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Giertz lets me sit in on one of her many doctor's visits, provided that I agree not to record audio, take photos, or share the name of her ophthalmologist. (At one point, she texts me, “Asking for a friend: Is it really naive to let a journalist come along to a doctor's appointment?”) Most people in the waiting room are octogenarians, and the still-youthful Giertz, in her faded black jeans, blue denim jacket, and ponytail, won't sit unless everyone else has a seat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After she is moved into an examination room, a doctor comes in and goes over Giertz's most recent scans. Her optical nerve doesn't look stressed, which is good, he says. The internal swelling has gone down, and he doesn't see evidence of persistent pressure on the nerve. The bigger concern is long-term damage, something Giertz has mentioned before. She doesn't know, and might not know for a decade, whether the tumor and subsequent radiation will have a lasting effect on her hormones and pituitary gland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The doctor says he's going to run through some additional procedures today, to determine if Giertz's eye might offer up other subtle indicators of what her long-term recovery will look like. While the doctor and a nurse are examining the scans, Giertz turns to me and says, “Did I tell you that my brain has filled out?” as casually as if she had told me she was thinking of taking next Friday off, or that her neighbor had adopted a puppy. Recent scans show that there's been regrowth in the chunk of her brain that had been pushed aside when the giant tumor had taken up residence in her eye vault. “One side is still a little floofy,” she says. “But I was so, so happy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;asset-embed__asset-container&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;responsive-asset asset-embed__responsive-asset responsive-asset--invisible&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;pFollowing radiation treatment for her brain tumor Giertz turned her customfit radiation mask into a wall lamp with LEDs...&quot; class=&quot;responsive-image__image&quot; src=&quot;https://media.wired.com/photos/5de57235b4ac1c00080cd506/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/WI010120_FF_Simone20_05.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://media.wired.com/photos/5de57235b4ac1c00080cd506/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/WI010120_FF_Simone20_05.jpg 1600w, https://media.wired.com/photos/5de57235b4ac1c00080cd506/master/w_1280%2Cc_limit/WI010120_FF_Simone20_05.jpg 1280w, https://media.wired.com/photos/5de57235b4ac1c00080cd506/master/w_1024%2Cc_limit/WI010120_FF_Simone20_05.jpg 1024w, https://media.wired.com/photos/5de57235b4ac1c00080cd506/master/w_768%2Cc_limit/WI010120_FF_Simone20_05.jpg 768w, https://media.wired.com/photos/5de57235b4ac1c00080cd506/master/w_640%2Cc_limit/WI010120_FF_Simone20_05.jpg 640w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caption__text&quot;&gt;Following radiation treatment for her brain tumor, Giertz turned her custom-fit radiation mask into a wall lamp, with LEDs shining through the translucent resin. The video of her making the mask has been viewed over a million times.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption__credit&quot;&gt;Photograph: Joe Pugliese&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In July 2019&lt;/strong&gt;, Giertz shared a blog post on Patreon explaining why she was no longer making shitty robot videos. Her energy had been limited since her surgery, she wrote, “so I have tried my best to only spend it on things I really want to do. And for now, that has not been shitty robots.” I ask her whether Brian helped mark this turning point for her. The answer is yes, but also no. Even before the brain tumor, Giertz says, she was starting to feel like “it was harder and harder to come up with ideas. I was always concerned that it was eventually going to be like beating a dead horse, and that the joke was going to be over and I didn't have anywhere else to go.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abandoning shitty robots was definitely detrimental to the success of her channel, she says, as beneficial as it may be for her well-being. Giertz has never really succumbed to the pressures of the internet content machine. She publishes her YouTube videos weeks, sometimes even months, apart from each other. A video with millions of views is sometimes followed by one with a few hundred thousand. Her Patreon dispatches are slightly more consistent but take different forms. Sometimes they're videos. Sometimes they're simply blog posts, like the one explaining why she wasn't building shitty robots anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“She's doing it exactly right,” Kampf says. “I think the brain tumor slowed her down, but it made the community around her so much stronger, and I think she's completely unattached from the pressure of uploading on a regular basis.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Giertz acknowledges that there are plenty of creators who produce more than she does, and that she may be sacrificing views in exchange for what she calls a healthier relationship with YouTube. Basically, by not producing as many videos, YouTube's system may not be bubbling her videos to the top of watch lists as much as it would for creators who post a video every week, or even every day. “The algorithm, it's a black hole,” she says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;callout callout--inset-left callout--has-top-border callout--content-type--asset-embed&quot; readability=&quot;26.234234234234&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sign Up Today&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;asset-embed__asset-container&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;responsive-asset asset-embed__responsive-asset responsive-asset--invisible&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Sign Up for WIRED's Longreads Newsletter&quot; class=&quot;responsive-image__image&quot; src=&quot;https://media.wired.com/photos/5d7ac5680a30b000089d5b2a/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Carve_Longreads%252520newsletter_new.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://media.wired.com/photos/5d7ac5680a30b000089d5b2a/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Carve_Longreads%252520newsletter_new.jpg 1600w, https://media.wired.com/photos/5d7ac5680a30b000089d5b2a/master/w_1280%2Cc_limit/Carve_Longreads%252520newsletter_new.jpg 1280w, https://media.wired.com/photos/5d7ac5680a30b000089d5b2a/master/w_1024%2Cc_limit/Carve_Longreads%252520newsletter_new.jpg 1024w, https://media.wired.com/photos/5d7ac5680a30b000089d5b2a/master/w_768%2Cc_limit/Carve_Longreads%252520newsletter_new.jpg 768w, https://media.wired.com/photos/5d7ac5680a30b000089d5b2a/master/w_640%2Cc_limit/Carve_Longreads%252520newsletter_new.jpg 640w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She won't say much else about YouTube, even as the platform faces continuing scrutiny for facilitating the spread of misinformation, toxic content, and harmful videos, and for its management (or mismanagement) of all of the above. “I think social media platforms are trying to be responsible, but there are also definitely instances where they try to make it seem like they're being responsible, and for revenue or profit they're doing another thing,” Giertz says cryptically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the car on the way back to San Francisco from her doctor's appointment, Giertz asks me if she can read aloud a draft of something she's been working on. She's nervous about it, she says, and later she'll corner a top newspaper executive at a media confab to try to convince him to print it. It's an open letter to YouTube creators, urging them to reconsider taking sponsor money from fossil fuel companies. Giertz won't call out the YouTubers by name, but she'll speak candidly about what she sees as hypocrisy at a systemic level. “Oil companies trying to convince us that they're green is the gaslighting effort of the century,” Giertz tweeted in November.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every time I talk to Giertz, she's hatching plans. One day over lunch in San Francisco, she is forlorn because the shipments of her Every Day Calendar—a habit-tracking wall calendar that raised more than half-a-million dollars on Kickstarter—arrived at her workshop damaged. She plans to ship them to customers in December, and her old fear of failure has let itself in again. A few weeks later she tells me she's going to build a coffee table made of matchsticks. (When it reaches the end of its useful life, you can just light it on fire.) When I call her again in October to ask about her post-Truckla plans, Giertz head fakes and tells me about her puzzle project. She's building a solid white puzzle with one piece missing, which she wants to ship to provoke the cringey feeling creators have when something is incomplete. The puzzle box reads, “499/500 pieces included.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of these embody what Giertz calls exploratory building—a grown-up version of playtime. I get the sense that they're important to her, fulfilling that inner drive. I also get the sense that they're projects to fill time while she's incubating bigger ideas. Like Truckla.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;iframe-embed__container&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; sandbox=&quot;allow-scripts allow-popups allow-same-origin&quot; class=&quot;iframe-embed__content&quot; title=&quot;Embedded Frame&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/jKv_N0IDS2A&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her Truckla project has been, by almost all metrics, a success. At over 10 million views, it's her most popular video to date. More important, it proved that a new formula was feasible for Giertz; that she could invest as long as a year on a project and people would respond to it all the more. Even Elon Musk, who has trailed Giertz in his efforts to launch an EV pickup truck, took note of the video. He invited her to his own &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/story/electric-tesla-pickup-truck-announcement-specs-cost-photos/&quot;&gt;“Cybertruck” unveiling in late November&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was all so encouraging that for a while last summer, Giertz flirted with the idea of moving to Los Angeles to launch a video series about building cars, almost ditching her San Francisco workshop for a much larger space in Tinseltown. Later, she scrapped that idea as she set her sights on something even bigger. Now she's in contract negotiations with a media company—she refuses to say which one—to make a TV show in space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or … at least a TV show &lt;em&gt;about&lt;/em&gt; space. Giertz alternates between saying “about” and “in” when she's talking about the show she wants to make. I point out that the preposition matters. Will she film this TV series from orbit? Or would the videos just chronicle what it might take to get there? Hopefully both, she says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This thread of space exploration has been running through her work for years: the DIY astronaut training, the zero-gravity flight, locking herself in confined spaces for days, publicly fantasizing about blasting her brain tumor into orbit. I ask her why going to space captivates her so much. “Because it's such a worthy goal,” she says. “I started studying physics because I wanted to be an astronaut. Now I want to show a flawed human going to space.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the new Simone Giertz, accepting her own flaws and embracing grand, non-shitty designs are of a piece. “There are so many things that are amazing that are not perfect. And there are so many things that are perfect that are fucking boring,” she says. “Perfect is a corset. It doesn't let you breathe. It doesn't let you roll around. It's a small pen to be in.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Space is pretty much the opposite of all that (notwithstanding all those confined capsules). For Giertz, getting there is more a matter of when than if. When I ask if she has a planned timeline for liftoff, she replies, “I mean, I have time next weekend.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hair and makeup by Amy Lawson and Miranda Gulyash&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article appears in the January issue. &lt;a href=&quot;https://subscribe.wired.com/subscribe/splits/wired/WIR_Edit_Hardcoded?source=ArticleEnd_CMlink&quot;&gt;Subscribe now&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Let us know what you think about this article. Submit a letter to the editor at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:mail@wired.com&quot;&gt;mail@wired.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 09:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pluma</dc:creator>
<og:description>YouTuber Simone Giertz gave up wildly popular but barely functioning machines and confronted her fears of imperfection (while facing her own mortality and making an awesome Truckla EV).</og:description>
<og:image>https://media.wired.com/photos/5deea70796ca060009b5210c/191:100/w_1280,c_limit/simonegiertz_web.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Why the ‘Queen of Shitty Robots’ Renounced Her Crown</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.wired.com/story/simone-giertz-build-what-you-want/</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.wired.com/story/simone-giertz-build-what-you-want/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>FUSE for macOS is no longer open source</title>
<link>https://colatkinson.site/macos/fuse/2019/09/29/osxfuse/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://colatkinson.site/macos/fuse/2019/09/29/osxfuse/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;FUSE for macOS (or, the kernel extension formerly known as osxfuse) is a project dating back to 2011. It in turn is based on even older projects, such as MacFUSE, the Linux FUSE module, and even some code open sourced by Apple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until 2017, the project was open source, released under an amalgamation of the fairly permissive licenses of its various ancestors. But its maintainer, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bfleischer&quot;&gt;Benjamin Fleischer&lt;/a&gt;, decided to change that. While several releases have been published since then, only the binary blobs are provided, leaving Fleischer as the only person with access to the complete source. For some previous discussion, check &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/osxfuse/osxfuse/issues/590&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://groups.google.com/forum/#!msg/osxfuse-group/_5PBFQ_BQB8/z1mu2H0rFAAJ&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/osxfuse/osxfuse/issues/616&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some choice moments for those without the energy for programmer drama:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The osxfuse-3.9.0 tag shows an empty directory: https://github.com/osxfuse/osxfuse/tree/osxfuse-3.9.0&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Checking out with git also produces an empty directory. The archives from there releases page are also empty, i.e. https://github.com/osxfuse/osxfuse/archive/osxfuse-3.9.0.zip&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s on purpose. If you are using FUSE for macOS for a commercial software project, feel free to contact me via email. You can find my email on my GitHub page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;– &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/osxfuse/osxfuse/issues/590#issuecomment-492226726&quot;&gt;@bfleischer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever written a single line of kernel code or debugged a massively parallel file system? Trust me, that’s a big deal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;– &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/osxfuse/osxfuse/issues/590#issuecomment-501809602&quot;&gt;@bfleischer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is simply too much work for one person in addition to a full-time job&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then drop it and let someone else maintain it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;– &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/osxfuse/osxfuse/issues/590#issuecomment-503318278&quot;&gt;@pmetzger&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s right, we’ve got ourselves a new season of &lt;em&gt;The Real Housewives of GitHub!&lt;/em&gt; That being said, this actually is a pretty serious issue, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pmetzger&quot;&gt;@pmetzger&lt;/a&gt;, as a maintainer for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.macports.org/&quot;&gt;MacPorts&lt;/a&gt;, has every right to be concerned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may also notice that I’ve only linked to random GitHub issues and mailing list posts. That’s because this licensing change hasn’t been noted in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/osxfuse/osxfuse/blob/master/README.md&quot;&gt;README&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/osxfuse/osxfuse/blob/master/LICENSE.txt&quot;&gt;LICENSE&lt;/a&gt; files of the repo–that is, the most obvious (i.e. only) places that people check for these sorts of things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll get into why, and how, this happened. But first, some background.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FUSE stands for &lt;strong&gt;F&lt;/strong&gt;ilesystem in &lt;strong&gt;Use&lt;/strong&gt;rspace, and the name pretty much tells the whole story. It’s a Linux kernel module that allows developers to implement a filesystem outside of the kernel, just like a normal application. This vastly simplifies the development process, since you have access to all of the normal libraries and utilities you use in desktop development. It was mainlined way back in 2005, and even then it wasn’t a new concept&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:hurd&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://colatkinson.site/macos/fuse/2019/09/29/osxfuse/#fn:hurd&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some notable FUSEs are Google Drive’s File Stream&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:gdrive&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://colatkinson.site/macos/fuse/2019/09/29/osxfuse/#fn:gdrive&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, sshfs, Keybase’s KBFS, and ntfs-3g. The point is, this is a piece of technology that has been used and abused endlessly, and that a ton of projects depend on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned earlier, since shortly after FUSE was created, people have wanted their filesystems to run on other operating systems. Windows, bizarrely enough, seems to get far more love here, with Dokan, Dokany, and WinFsp filling the void.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Support for macOS, however, has been… limited, despite the fact that it and Linux have far more similar sets of file operations thanks to POSIX. MacFUSE was started at Google in 2007 and, from what I can tell, was abandoned sometime around 2009. osxfuse was then forked from it around 2011, and has been the only solution for running your FUSE on macOS since then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;osxfuse is, by necessity, a kernel module (or “kext” in Apple land). Using the BSD VFS interface, it presents itself as a traditional filesystem driver, and then forwards filesystem operations across the kernel boundary to the FUSE. At this high level, it operates very similarly to FUSE on Linux, though obviously there are some differences at the lower levels. Since it’s a kext, shipping it to users requires some special provisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now this may come as a shock to some of you, but Apple &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; doesn’t seem to like it when third party developers change just about anything about their UX. For instance, they only added an API for adding badge icons to Finder in 2014–and that was only because Dropbox just kept reverse engineering it anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deploying a kext requires it be signed using a special Kernel Extension Signing Certificate, which can only be acquired from Apple. Getting one of these certs requires going through a fairly rigorous application process. And of course, at the end of it all, you can be denied with no real recourse. Basically, your project lives and dies at the will of Apple–a markedly different approach from what you’re used to if you’re used to the Linux and Windows approaches to third-party kernel modules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now here’s the kicker: Benjamin Fleischer has one of these certificates for osxfuse. In fact, if you google his name, the vast majority of the results are confused users asking why they’re being prompted about installing software by ol’ Benny. What can I say, the man’s a celebrity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So to quickly summarize:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;osxfuse is used by tons of companies,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and essentially none of them push fixes upstream.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fleischer has been the sole maintainer for years.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He also hasn’t been paid a penny for this work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He also holds a magical, aluminum unibody certificate that prevents most people from forking his module.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The current codebase is permissively licensed, so he can do with it what he will.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t exactly take a rocket surgeon to see where this is going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple has apparently made some pretty significant changes to kernel modules in the upcoming macOS Catalina. And according to our subject matter expert, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/osxfuse/osxfuse/issues/595&quot;&gt;they’re pretty gnarly&lt;/a&gt; to support. Fortunately, osxfuse 3.10 has support for Catalina!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there’s a catch. If you go to download this &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/osxfuse/osxfuse/releases/tag/osxfuse-3.10.0&quot;&gt;release&lt;/a&gt;, you’ll notice a bit of text in the release notes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The license has changed. Starting with this release, redistributions bundled with commercial software are not allowed without specific prior written permission. Please contact Benjamin Fleischer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last public source code release was in 2017. Now, two years later, just a few short months before the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RGB8QgwxZqw&quot;&gt;Fucking Catalina Release Mixer&lt;/a&gt;, Fleischer could finally get his.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Apple does Apple things and heavily restricts third-party developers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fleischer, having dealt with malarkey like this for close to a decade, realizes he doesn’t get paid enough for this shit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He makes the repo closed source in 2017, but doesn’t mention this to anyone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In 2019, after making a bunch of critical changes to the code, he quietly announces that the licensing terms of the project are now different.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At this stage in the proceedings, companies’ choices are to pay up or tell their users that they can’t use the hot new version of macOS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;As far as monetization strategies go, love it or hate it, you’ve got to give the guy props.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Uh… probably? As I mentioned, &lt;em&gt;most&lt;/em&gt; of the code is under BSD-style licenses. The command line utility to actually mount the damn thing is under the Apple Public Source License, which has a “soft copyleft.” But in theory, if no further changes are made to this part of the code, it already meets the requirements for source code distribution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I’m not a lawyer (yada yada this shouldn’t be considered legal advice), but it seems like all of this is perfectly above board.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many open source projects take the approach of dual licensing with the GPL. This seems to hit the requirements pretty closely. Noncommercial, open source software can use the module for free. And companies or individuals who want to distribute the software in a proprietary project have to pay up. As an example in the same space, this is the strategy used by WinFsp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s possible that things get weird given Apple’s code signing requirements, so I’m not 100% sure if this strategy would work–that’s more an issue for the FSF’s lawyers than some random programmer on the internet. But the point is, there are probably other options than closing the source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well… nothing, really. Mr. Fleischer has come to a determination that keeping the project open source is not a situation that benefits him. And that’s unfortunate, but at a certain point I really can’t fault him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The software which he has maintained for the past eight or so odd years has been of enormous benefit to the software community as a whole. Instead of just being a Linux-only thing, FUSE became a &lt;em&gt;de facto&lt;/em&gt; standard for quickly spinning up a filesystem that does cool and useful things for users. This was in part due to his work, as well as the work of many others over the course of years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While some of this may have come off as harsh, it’s really not Fleischer with whom we should take issue. He wouldn’t be the first maintainer to have gripes with the ways in which his labor is taken advantage of; nor is he likely to be the last. Mongo created the SSPL due to similar issues, and Redis Labs added a clause to its license forbidding companies from selling (parts of) its software. Now while osxfuse is in a &lt;em&gt;slightly&lt;/em&gt; different domain than these datastores, the root cause is the same: companies often reap far more from FOSS than they sow upstream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All that aside: it would be super cool for osxfuse to be open sourced again, but I don’t know if I can see that happening in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The free and open source software movements have done amazing things for the world, and while I respect the decisions made in this case, I certainly hope this doesn’t become the new normal. In the meantime, consider sending a couple bucks to the maintainer of your favorite project. And maybe use a copyleft license next time you release some code, so that when some random company wants to use it, you can finesse a cut of the action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While in isolation this might seem like a minor issue, if looked at as a symptom of a deeper problem… &lt;em&gt;Trust me, it’s a big deal.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h3&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 06:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>khc</dc:creator>
<og:title>osxfuse is no longer open source</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>And what that means for the rest of us.</og:description>
<og:url>https://colatkinson.site/macos/fuse/2019/09/29/osxfuse/</og:url>
<og:image>https://colatkinson.site/assets/img/osxfuse.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://colatkinson.site/macos/fuse/2019/09/29/osxfuse/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Speeding Up the Rust Compiler</title>
<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/nnethercote/2019/12/11/how-to-speed-up-the-rust-compiler-one-last-time-in-2019/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.mozilla.org/nnethercote/2019/12/11/how-to-speed-up-the-rust-compiler-one-last-time-in-2019/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I last wrote &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/nnethercote/2019/10/11/how-to-speed-up-the-rust-compiler-some-more-in-2019/&quot;&gt;in October&lt;/a&gt; about my work on speeding up the Rust compiler. With the year’s end approaching, it’s time for an update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Doc comments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/65750&quot;&gt;#65750&lt;/a&gt;: Normal comments are stripped out during parsing and not represented in the AST. But doc comments have semantic meaning (`&lt;code&gt;/// blah&lt;/code&gt;` is equivalent to the attribute &lt;code&gt;#[doc=&quot;blah&quot;]&lt;/code&gt;) and so must be represented explicitly in the AST. Furthermore:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;In a multi-line doc comment using &lt;code&gt;///&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;//!&lt;/code&gt; comment markers every separate line is treated as a separate attribute;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multi-line doc comments using &lt;code&gt;///&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;//!&lt;/code&gt; markers are very common, much more so than those using &lt;code&gt;/** */&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;/*! */&lt;/code&gt; markers, particularly in the standard library where doc comment lines often outnumber code lines;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The AST representation of attributes is quite expensive, partly because it retains the original tokens for complex reasons involving procedural macros.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a result, doc comments had a surprisingly high cost. This PR introduced a special, cheaper representation for doc comments, giving wins on many benchmarks, some in excess of 10%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Token streams&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/65455&quot;&gt;#65455:&lt;/a&gt; This PR avoided some unnecessary conversions from &lt;code&gt;TokenTree&lt;/code&gt; type to the closely related &lt;code&gt;TokenStream&lt;/code&gt; type, avoiding allocations and giving wins on many benchmarks of up to 5%. It included one of the most &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/65455/commits/a6eef299d3b0ca24f8ffc0c3dc03283c09ec7945&quot;&gt;satisfying commits&lt;/a&gt; I’ve made to rustc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.mozilla.org/nnethercote/2019/12/11/how-to-speed-up-the-rust-compiler-one-last-time-in-2019/screenshot_2019-12-10-avoid-unnecessary-tokentree-to-tokenstream-conversions-by-nnethercote-%c2%b7-pull-request-65455-%c2%b7-rus/&quot; rel=&quot;attachment wp-att-3219&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-3219&quot; src=&quot;https://ffp4g1ylyit3jdyti1hqcvtb-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/nnethercote/files/2019/12/Screenshot_2019-12-10-Avoid-unnecessary-TokenTree-to-TokenStream-conversions-by-nnethercote-%C2%B7-Pull-Request-65455-%C2%B7-rus....png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of the satisfying commit, as viewed on GitHub&quot; width=&quot;1291&quot; height=&quot;321&quot; srcset=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/nnethercote/files/2019/12/Screenshot_2019-12-10-Avoid-unnecessary-TokenTree-to-TokenStream-conversions-by-nnethercote-·-Pull-Request-65455-·-rus....png 1291w, https://blog.mozilla.org/nnethercote/files/2019/12/Screenshot_2019-12-10-Avoid-unnecessary-TokenTree-to-TokenStream-conversions-by-nnethercote-·-Pull-Request-65455-·-rus...-252x63.png 252w, https://blog.mozilla.org/nnethercote/files/2019/12/Screenshot_2019-12-10-Avoid-unnecessary-TokenTree-to-TokenStream-conversions-by-nnethercote-·-Pull-Request-65455-·-rus...-600x149.png 600w, https://blog.mozilla.org/nnethercote/files/2019/12/Screenshot_2019-12-10-Avoid-unnecessary-TokenTree-to-TokenStream-conversions-by-nnethercote-·-Pull-Request-65455-·-rus...-768x191.png 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1291px) 100vw, 1291px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up to 5% wins by changing only three lines. But what intricate lines they are! There is a lot going on, and they’re probably incomprehensible to anyone not deeply familiar with the relevant types. My eyes used to just bounce off those lines. As is typical for this kind of change, the commit message is substantially longer than the commit itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s satisfying partly because it shows my knowledge of Rust has improved, particularly &lt;code&gt;Into&lt;/code&gt; and iterators. (One thing I worked out along the way: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/blob/c27f7568bc74c418996892028a629eed5a7f5f00/src/libcore/iter/traits/iterator.rs#L1477-L1479&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;collect&lt;/code&gt; is just another name for &lt;code&gt;FromIterator::from_iter&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.) Having said that, now that a couple of months have passed, it still takes me effort to remember how those lines work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But even more so, it’s satisfying because it wouldn’t have happened had I not repeatedly simplified the types involved over the past year. They used to look like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
pub struct TokenStream { kind: TokenStreamKind };
pub enum TokenStreamKind {
    Empty,
    Tree(TokenTree),
    JointTree(TokenTree),
    Stream(RcVec&amp;lt;TokenStream&amp;gt;),
}
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Note the recursion!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After multiple simplifying PRs (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/56737&quot;&gt;#56737&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/57004&quot;&gt;#57004&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/58476&quot;&gt;#57486&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/58476&quot;&gt;#58476&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/65261&quot;&gt;#65261&lt;/a&gt;), they now look like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
pub struct TokenStream(pub Lrc&amp;lt;Vec&amp;lt;TreeAndJoint&amp;gt;&amp;gt;);
pub type TreeAndJoint = (TokenTree, IsJoint);
pub enum IsJoint { Joint, NonJoint }
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Note the lack of recursion!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn’t set out to simplify the type for speed, I just found it ugly and confusing. But now it’s simple enough that understanding and optimizing intricate uses is much easier. When those three lines appeared in a profile, I could finally understand them. Refactoring FTW!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(A third reason for satisfaction: I found the inefficiency using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/nnethercote/2019/04/17/a-better-dhat/&quot;&gt;improved DHAT&lt;/a&gt; I worked on earlier this year. Hooray for nice tools!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/65641&quot;&gt;#65641&lt;/a&gt;: This was a nice follow-on from the previous PR. &lt;code&gt;TokenStream&lt;/code&gt; had custom impls of the &lt;code&gt;RustcEncodable&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;RustcDecodable&lt;/code&gt; traits. These were necessary when &lt;code&gt;TokenStream&lt;/code&gt; was more complicated, but now that it’s much simpler the derived impls suffice. As well as simplifying the code, the PR won up to 3% on some benchmarks because the custom impls created some now-unnecessary intermediate structures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/65198&quot;&gt;#65198&lt;/a&gt;: David Tolnay &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/issues/65080&quot;&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; that basic concatenation of tokens, as done by many procedural macros, could be exceedingly slow, and that operating directly on strings could be 100x faster. This PR removed quadratic behaviour in two places, both of which duplicated a token vector when appending a new token. (Raise a glass to the excellent &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.rust-lang.org/std/rc/struct.Rc.html#method.make_mut&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Rc::make_mut&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; function, which I used in both cases.) The PR gave some very small (&amp;lt; 1%) speed-ups on the standard benchmarks but sped up a microbenchmark that exhibited the problem by over 1000x, and made it practical for procedural benchmarks to use tokens. I also &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang-nursery/rustc-perf/pull/516&quot;&gt;added David’s microbenchmark to rustc-perf&lt;/a&gt; to avoid future regressions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;unicode_normalization&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/65260&quot;&gt;#65260&lt;/a&gt;: This PR added a special-case check to skip an expensive function call in a hot function, giving a 7% win on the &lt;code&gt;unicode_normalization&lt;/code&gt; benchmark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/65480&quot;&gt;#65480&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;code&gt;LexicalResolver::iterate_until_fixed_point()&lt;/code&gt; was a hot function that iterated over some constraints, gradually removing them until none remain. The constraints were stored in a &lt;code&gt;SmallVec&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;retain&lt;/code&gt; was used to remove the elements. This PR (a) changed the function so it stored the constraints in an immutable &lt;code&gt;Vec&lt;/code&gt; and then used a &lt;code&gt;BitSet&lt;/code&gt; to record which which constraints were still live, and (b) inlined the function at its only call site. These changes won another 7% on &lt;code&gt;unicode_normalization&lt;/code&gt;, but only after I had sped up &lt;code&gt;BitSet&lt;/code&gt; iteration with some micro-optimizations in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/65425&quot;&gt;#65425&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/66537&quot;&gt;#66537&lt;/a&gt;: This PR moved an expensive function call after a test and early return that is almost always taken, giving a 2% win on &lt;code&gt;unicode_normalization&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Miscellanous&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/66408&quot;&gt;#66408&lt;/a&gt;: The &lt;code&gt;ObligationForest&lt;/code&gt; type has a vector of obligations that it processes in a fixpoint manner. Each fixpoint iteration involves running an operation on every obligation, which can cause new obligations to be appended to the vector. Previously, newly-added obligations would not be considered until the next fixpoint iteration. This PR changed the code so it would consider those new obligations in the iteration in which they were added, reducing the number of iterations required to reach a fixpoint, and winning up to 8% on a few benchmarks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/66013&quot;&gt;#66013&lt;/a&gt;: The Rust compiler is designed around a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rustc-guide/blob/master/src/query.md&quot;&gt;demand-driven query system&lt;/a&gt;. Query execution is memoized: when a query is first invoked the compiler will perform the computation and store the result in a hash table, and on subsequent invocations the compiler will return the result from the hash table. For the parallel configuration of rustc this hash table experiences a lot of contention, and so it is &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shard_(database_architecture)&quot;&gt;sharded&lt;/a&gt;; each query lookup has two parts, one to get the shard, and one within the shard. This PR changed things so that the key was only hashed once and the hash value reused for both parts of the lookup, winning up to 3% on the single-threaded configuration of parallel compiler. (It had no benefit for the non-parallel compiler, which is what currently ships, because it does not use sharding.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/66012&quot;&gt;#66012&lt;/a&gt;: This PR removed the &lt;code&gt;trivial_dropck_outlives&lt;/code&gt; query from the query system because the underlying computation is so simple that it is faster to redo it whenever necessary than to look up the result in the query hash table. This won up to 1% on some benchmarks, and possibly more for the parallel compiler, due to the abovementioned contention over the query hash table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/65463&quot;&gt;#65463&lt;/a&gt;: The function &lt;code&gt;expand_pattern()&lt;/code&gt; caused many arena allocations where a 4 KiB arena chunk was allocated that only ever held a single small and short-lived allocation. This PR avoided these, reducing the number of bytes allocated by up to 2% for various benchmarks, though the effect on runtime was minimal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/66540&quot;&gt;#66540&lt;/a&gt; – This PR changed a &lt;code&gt;Vec&lt;/code&gt; to a &lt;code&gt;SmallVec&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;Candidate::match_pairs&lt;/code&gt;, reducing allocation rates for a tiny speed win.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;symbols&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The compiler has an &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/String_interning&quot;&gt;interned string&lt;/a&gt; type called &lt;code&gt;Symbol&lt;/code&gt; that is widely used to represent identifiers and other strings. The compiler also had two variants of that type, confusingly called &lt;code&gt;InternedString&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;LocalInternedString&lt;/code&gt;. In a series of PRs (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/65426&quot;&gt;#65426&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/65545&quot;&gt;#65545&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/65657&quot;&gt;#65657&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/65776&quot;&gt;#65776)&lt;/a&gt; I removed &lt;code&gt;InternedString&lt;/code&gt; and minimized the functionality and uses of &lt;code&gt;LocalInternedString&lt;/code&gt; (and also renamed it as &lt;code&gt;SymbolStr&lt;/code&gt;). This was made possible by Matthew Jasper’s work  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/64623&quot;&gt;eliminating gensyms&lt;/a&gt;. The changes won up to 1% on various benchmarks, but the real benefit was code simplicity, as issue &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/issues/60869&quot;&gt;#60869&lt;/a&gt; described. Like the &lt;code&gt;TokenStream&lt;/code&gt; type I mentioned above, these types had &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/60815#issuecomment-492850353&quot;&gt;annoyed&lt;/a&gt; me for some time, so it was good to get them into a nicer state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Progress&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The storage of historical benchmark data changed recently, which (as far as I can tell) makes comparisons to versions earlier than early November difficult. Nonetheless, &lt;a href=&quot;https://perf.rust-lang.org/compare.html?start=2019-11-07&amp;amp;end=2019-12-07&amp;amp;stat=wall-time&quot;&gt;wall-time results for the past month&lt;/a&gt; (2019-11-07 to 2019-12-08) cover the second half of that period, and they are generally good, as the following screenshot shows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.mozilla.org/nnethercote/2019/12/11/how-to-speed-up-the-rust-compiler-one-last-time-in-2019/screenshot_2019-12-10-rustc-performance-data/&quot; rel=&quot;attachment wp-att-3220&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-3220&quot; src=&quot;https://ffp4g1ylyit3jdyti1hqcvtb-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/nnethercote/files/2019/12/Screenshot_2019-12-10-rustc-performance-data.png&quot; alt=&quot;Walltime results from perf.rust-lang.org showing lots of benchmark improvements&quot; width=&quot;684&quot; height=&quot;2040&quot; srcset=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/nnethercote/files/2019/12/Screenshot_2019-12-10-rustc-performance-data.png 684w, https://blog.mozilla.org/nnethercote/files/2019/12/Screenshot_2019-12-10-rustc-performance-data-252x752.png 252w, https://blog.mozilla.org/nnethercote/files/2019/12/Screenshot_2019-12-10-rustc-performance-data-600x1789.png 600w, https://blog.mozilla.org/nnethercote/files/2019/12/Screenshot_2019-12-10-rustc-performance-data-515x1536.png 515w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 684px) 100vw, 684px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, lots of improvements (green), some in the double digits, and only a small number of regressions (red). It’s a good trend, and it’s not just due to the PRs mentioned above.  For example, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.rust-lang.org/inside-rust/2019/12/02/const-prop-on-by-default.html&quot;&gt;MIR constant propagation&lt;/a&gt; won 2-10% in a lot of cases. It duplicates an optimization that LLVM also does, but performs it earlier in the pipeline when there’s less code. This saves time because it makes LLVM’s job easier, and it also helps the code quality of debug builds where the LLVM constant propagation isn’t run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Final words&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of the above improvements (and most of the ones in my previous posts) I found by profiling with Cachegrind, Callgrind, DHAT, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/nnethercote/2018/07/24/ad-hoc-profiling/&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;counts&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, but there are plenty of other profilers out there. I encourage anyone who has interest and even slight familiarity with profiling (or a willingness to learn) to give it a try. The Rust compiler is an easy target, profiling-wise, because it’s a batch program that is mostly single-threaded and almost deterministic. (Compare it to Firefox, for example, which is interactive, multi-threaded, and highly non-deterministic.) Give it a go!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 03:20:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>staktrace</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.mozilla.org/nnethercote/2019/12/11/how-to-speed-up-the-rust-compiler-one-last-time-in-2019/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>