<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Is it time to treat sugar like smoking?</title>
<link>https://www.bbc.com/news/health-48499195</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bbc.com/news/health-48499195</guid>
<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption full-width lead&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                &lt;img class=&quot;js-image-replace&quot; alt=&quot;white chocolate&quot; src=&quot;https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/320/cpsprodpb/65B6/production/_105483062_whitechocolate.jpg&quot; width=&quot;976&quot; height=&quot;549&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body__introduction&quot;&gt;Over the past decade, smoking has become marginalised and stigmatised.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;From the smoking ban in 2007 to the introduction of plain packaging a decade later, everything has been done to discourage people from taking up the habit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And there are signs sugar is heading the same way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sugary drinks are already taxed - and now a leading think tank has even suggested sweets, snacks and sugary drinks should be wrapped in plain packaging to make them less appealing, given the excess consumption of the sweet stuff.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-portrait no-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;The call has been made by the Institute for Public Policy Research (IPPR) in a new report. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;IPPR director Tom Kibasi believes it could make a real difference.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Plain packaging would help us all to make better choices and reduce the hassle of pester power for busy parents,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He wants to see it adopted alongside a range of other measures, including a ban on junk food advertising.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That is something that has already been looked at by ministers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But would plain packaging be a step too far?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;Industry against the move&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Industry has been quick to object, with trade body the Food and Drink Federation arguing that branding is a &quot;fundamental commercial freedom&quot; and &quot;critical to competition&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The same sort of arguments were put forward by the tobacco industry, but successive governments have still increasingly shown an appetite to get tough.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, the government has not ruled the idea of plain packaging for sugar products entirely.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Instead, the Department of Health and Social Care is saying it is waiting to hear what England's chief medical officer, Prof Dame Sally Davies, has to say.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why? There is a recognition that bold moves are needed if the ambition to halve the child obesity rate by 2030 is to be achieved.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dame Sally has been asked to review the steps that are being taken to ensure no stone is left unturned.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In fact, she has already suggested that another measure floated by the IPPR - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/health-48461028&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;extending the tax on sugary drinks to other unhealthy foods - is a real option&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And she is said to be open to the idea of plain packaging, which of course would be an even more radical step.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape has-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
                 &lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;PA&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    All cigarettes must be sold in plain green packaging with health warnings
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;But what is clear from the last decade is that the unlikely can soon become likely.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;During the early noughties, health campaigners and academic bodies were pushing and pushing for a ban on smoking in public places to be introduced.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Time after time, the government poured cold water on the move.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But then things slowly began to change once Patricia Hewitt became health secretary, paving the way for even more radical measures.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The approach seems to be working - smoking rates have fallen by a third in just over 10 years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some of the credit is clearly because of the growth of vaping as an alternative.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But tough public health tactics have no doubt played some part. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Evidence from Australia - the first nation to introduce plain packaging for tobacco products - suggests a quarter of the subsequent reduction in smoking rates could be attributed to the move.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the debate rages about obesity, expect to hear much more about the merits of radical action on sugar.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/nicktriggle&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;Read more from Nick&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/nicktriggle&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link-external&quot;&gt;Follow Nick on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            </description>
<pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2019 17:09:51 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>notlukesky</dc:creator>
<og:title>Is it time to treat sugar like smoking?</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>A leading think tank is suggesting plain packaging should be adopted for sugary foods.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.bbc.com/news/health-48499195</og:url>
<og:image>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/65B6/production/_105483062_whitechocolate.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bbc.com/news/health-48499195</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Practical Deep Learning for Coders</title>
<link>https://course.fast.ai/index.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://course.fast.ai/index.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Looking for the older 2018 courses?&lt;/strong&gt;: This site covers the new 2019 deep learning course. The 2018 courses have been moved to: &lt;a href=&quot;http://course18.fast.ai&quot;&gt;course18.fast.ai&lt;/a&gt;. Note that the 2019 edition of part 2 (&lt;em&gt;Cutting Edge Deep Learning&lt;/em&gt;) is not yet available, so you’ll need to use the 2018 course for now (the 2019 edition will be available in June 2019).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;getting-started&quot;&gt;Getting started&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome! If you’re new to all this deep learning stuff, then don’t worry—we’ll take you through it all step by step. We do however assume that you’ve been coding for at least a year, and also that (if you haven’t used Python before) you’ll be putting in the extra time to learn whatever Python you need as you go. (For learning Python, we have a list of &lt;a href=&quot;https://forums.fast.ai/t/recommended-python-learning-resources/26888&quot;&gt;python learning resources&lt;/a&gt; available.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might be surprised by what you &lt;em&gt;don’t&lt;/em&gt; need to become a top deep learning practitioner. You need one year of coding experience, a GPU and appropriate software (see below), and that’s it. You don’t need much data, you don’t need university-level math, and you don’t need a giant data center. For more on this, see our article: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fast.ai/2017/11/16/what-you-need/&quot;&gt;What you need to do deep learning&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The easiest way to get started is to just start watching the first video right now! On the sidebar just click “Lessons” and then click on lesson 1, and you’ll be on your way. If you want an overview of the topics that are covered in the course, have a look at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fast.ai/2019/01/24/course-v3/&quot;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;using-a-gpu&quot;&gt;Using a GPU&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To do nearly everything in this course, you’ll need access to a computer with an NVIDIA GPU (unfortunately other brands of GPU are not fully supported by the main deep learning libraries). However, we don’t recommend you buy one; in fact, even if you already have one, we don’t suggest you use it just yet! Setting up a computer takes time and energy, and you want all your energy to focus on deep learning right now. Therefore, we instead suggest you rent access to a computer that already has everything you need preinstalled and ready to go. Costs can be as little as US$0.25 per hour while you’re using it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most important thing to remember: &lt;strong&gt;when you’re done, shut down your server&lt;/strong&gt;. You will be renting a distant computer, not running something on your own. It’s not enough to close your browser or turn off your own PC, those will merely sever the connection between your device and this distant server, not shut down the thing for which you’re paying. You have to shut this server down using the methods described in the guides below. Otherwise, you’ll be charged for all the time it runs and get surprised with a nasty bill!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some great choices of platforms. Click the link for more information on each, and setup instructions. Currently, our recommendations are (see below for details):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;If you’ve used a command line before: Google Compute Platform, because they provide $300 free credit, and have everything pre-installed for you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you want to avoid the command-line, try Salamander, which works great and don’t cost much&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you don’t have a credit card to sign up for the above services, use Colab, which is free, but has a few minor rough edges and incompatibilities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h4 id=&quot;ready-to-run-one-click-jupyter&quot;&gt;Ready to run: “One-click” Jupyter&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are the easiest to use; they’ve got all the software, data, and lessons preinstalled for you. They’re a little less flexible than “full servers” (below), but are the simplest way to get started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://course.fast.ai/start_salamander.html&quot;&gt;Salamander&lt;/a&gt; (instant approval; no installation required; includes full terminal access; $0.38 an hour; $75 free credit for students)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://course.fast.ai/start_colab.html&quot;&gt;Colab&lt;/a&gt;; (instant approval, requires minimal installation, free)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://course.fast.ai/start_gradient.html&quot;&gt;Paperspace Gradient&lt;/a&gt;; (instant approval, no installation required, $0.59 an hour; $10 free credit)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://course.fast.ai/start_sagemaker.html&quot;&gt;SageMaker&lt;/a&gt;; (requires wait for approval, not quite “one click”… but pretty close, $1.26 an hour + storage)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://course.fast.ai/start_kaggle.html&quot;&gt;Kaggle Kernels&lt;/a&gt;; (Instant Launch, No setup required, Free, not always up to date and not as well supported by fast.ai)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://course.fast.ai/start_floydhub.html&quot;&gt;Floydhub&lt;/a&gt;; (instant approval, no installation required, $1.20/hour + $9.00/month (100GB storage), 2 hours free credit)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://course.fast.ai/start_crestle.html&quot;&gt;Crestle&lt;/a&gt;; (instant approval, no installation required, $0.78 an hour (CPU), $2.40 an hour (GPU)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h4 id=&quot;ready-to-run-full-servers&quot;&gt;Ready to run: Full servers&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;some-installation-required&quot;&gt;Some installation required&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also have instructions for using these platforms, but they don’t have everything preinstalled yet:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For those starting out, we highly recommend a Jupyter Notebooks platform (Option 1)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Notebooks are the easiest way to start writing python code and experimenting with deep learning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Renting a Cloud Server (Option 2) requires environment configuration and setup.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Building a PC requires environment setup and more up-front money.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;(When we release Part 2 of the course, we will go into more specific details and benefits on both building a PC and renting a server.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;jupyter-notebook&quot;&gt;Jupyter notebook&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve finished the steps in one of the guides above, you’ll be presented with a screen like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://course.fast.ai/images/jupyter.png&quot; class=&quot;screenshot&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the jupyter notebook environment, where you’ll be doing nearly all your work in the course, so you’ll want to get very familiar with it! You’ll be learning a bit about it during the course, but you should probably spend a moment to try out the notebook tutorial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your first task, then, is to open this notebook tutorial! To do so, click &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;nbs&lt;/code&gt; and then &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;dl1&lt;/code&gt; in jupyter, where you’ll then see all the lesson notebooks. First, tick the little box on the left of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;00_notebook_tutorial.ipynb&lt;/code&gt; then click duplicate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://course.fast.ai/images/duplicate.png&quot; class=&quot;screenshot&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You want to avoid modifying the original course notebooks as you will get conflicts when you try to update this folder with GitHub (the place where the course is hosted). But we also want you to try a lot of variations of what is shown in class, which is why we encourage you to use duplicates of the course notebooks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Launch your copy of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;00_notebook_tutorial.ipynb&lt;/code&gt; and follow the instructions!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you’re done, &lt;strong&gt;remember to shut down your server&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;our-forums&quot;&gt;Our forums&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Got stuck? Want to know more about some topic? Your first port of call should be &lt;a href=&quot;https://forums.fast.ai/&quot;&gt;forums.fast.ai&lt;/a&gt;. There are thousands of students and practitioners asking and answering questions there. That means that it’s likely your question has already been answered! So click the little magnifying glass in the top right there, and search for the information you need; for instance, if you have some error message, paste a bit of it into the search box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The forum software we use is called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.discourse.org/about&quot;&gt;Discourse&lt;/a&gt;. When you first join, it will show you some tips and tricks. There is also this &lt;a href=&quot;https://forums.episodeinteractive.com/t/a-quick-how-to-for-discourse/48/1&quot;&gt;handy walk-thru&lt;/a&gt; provided by another Discourse forum (not affiliated with fast.ai).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;pytorch-and-fastai&quot;&gt;PyTorch and fastai&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We teach how to train &lt;a href=&quot;https://pytorch.org/&quot;&gt;PyTorch&lt;/a&gt; models using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.fast.ai&quot;&gt;fastai&lt;/a&gt; library. These two pieces of software are deeply connected—you can’t become really proficient at using fastai if you don’t know PyTorch well, too. Therefore, you will often need to refer to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://pytorch.org/docs/stable/index.html&quot;&gt;PyTorch docs&lt;/a&gt;. And you may also want to check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://discuss.pytorch.org/&quot;&gt;PyTorch forums&lt;/a&gt; (which also happen to use Discourse).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, to discuss fastai, you can use our forums, and be sure to look through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.fast.ai&quot;&gt;fastai docs&lt;/a&gt; too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t worry if you’re just starting out—little, if any, of those docs and forum threads will make any sense to you just now. But come back in a couple of weeks and you might be surprised by how useful you find them…&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2019 15:20:12 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>samrohn</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://course.fast.ai/index.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A restaurant owner who asked for 1-star Yelp reviews</title>
<link>https://thehustle.co/botto-bistro-1-star-yelp/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://thehustle.co/botto-bistro-1-star-yelp/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;In 2014, chef Davide Cerretini advertised a special that would forever change his fate: Anyone who left his restaurant a 1-star review on Yelp would get 25% off a pizza.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See, his Bay Area-based Italian joint, Botto Bistro, was at a crossroads. Like many small businesses, it was enslaved to the whims of online reviewers, whose public dispatches could make or break its reputation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He’d had enough: It was time to pry the stars from the “cold, grubby hands of Yelpers” and take control of his own destiny.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the move would set Cerretini at the center of a long-standing battle between Yelp and disgruntled business owners — a battle including cries of “extortion,” review manipulation, and predatory advertising tactics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A young chef’s journey&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Born to vineyard operators in Collemontanino, Italy, Cerretini enjoyed a childhood of culinary delights — home-cooked meals, pure ingredients, and simple cuisine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the mid-’90s, he immigrated to America to try his hand in the restaurant trade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After years toiling in backroom kitchens, he went in with a partner and opened his first restaurant, Cacciucco Cucina Toscana, in Sausalito, California. With his gregarious personality and “Italian charm,” Cerretini became a staple of the community and established strong ties with loyal customers. Business was booming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/XID5hLqN224wW4o2loNPnEacVSQouRx3p3SWJiZ3NdfUdffMHlc6vVJLVzzX1TmAiIxmcsiSJxTYQZRfChKewk5YEwtQIld5xgoxVMMUcTWdreNviT2fPATn4K1RaBh7dtuuCoBV&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;2500&quot; height=&quot;462&quot;/&gt;&lt;em&gt;A young Cerretini takes a drink with his grandfather in Italy (via Davide Cerretini)&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, the recession hit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of 2008, Cerretini lost everything and was forced to sell off his restaurant for a small sum of cash. “I thought everything was over,” he says. “Then, I found this little place in Richmond, California.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new location was everything he wanted: It was cheap, close to his loyal customers, and, best of all, unpretentious. He called it Botto Bistro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Botto goes digital&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a restaurateur, Cerretini had been an early adopter of Yelp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Launched in 2004 by former PayPal employee Jeremy Stoppelman, the platform’s user-submitted &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RPRDZgYSZ_c&quot;&gt;5-star rating system&lt;/a&gt; quickly became an integral part of every small business’s online footprint. As Cerretini knew, a mere half-star difference in a restaurant’s rating could increase peak-hours foot traffic by as much as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.huffpost.com/entry/yelp-study-ratings-restaurant-reservations_n_1861720?guccounter=1&amp;amp;guce_referrer=aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuZ29vZ2xlLmNvbS8&amp;amp;guce_referrer_sig=AQAAAIx5Npt4Q1lsm2RY4zFeqf0zKvA1PaBHJdWHIhhgbb8wN5W01rf0vR6fIMppe846evHG-MJbwzTjXa0bY9JCp8fRs0HRdYsA6dFfQKdKAKIpUWIyobx4BVZJi0aOkzdtV-3S7yjXMLvnCWDA80mq1fPW7gdgLcSzsXnPJ455hr0I&quot;&gt;19%&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the time Botto Bistro opened its doors in 2009, Yelp boasted some &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eater.com/2014/8/5/6177213/yelp-turns-10-from-startup-to-online-review-dominance&quot;&gt;26m unique visitors&lt;/a&gt; per month. And whether intentionally or not, the platform had entrenched itself as the controller of every small business’s online reputation — and fate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/Zhs7jv4zSMJMVn1VFtneZwKDikYNiYA_j140dMODS42J7LoqxXVOD7HF-VUfVQSeAOXzF56Cxt1-r98FxkCFueBALEb8WM6RqjURePao50WFKv8Kg7qZZzbXDMP5Ij194LbNopxS&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;2500&quot; height=&quot;432&quot;/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cerretini in his early restauranting days (Craig Lee / San Francisco Examiner)&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the months after Botto Bistro’s grand opening, Cerretini began receiving dozens of calls from Yelp salespeople, who implored him to buy ads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Cerretini, when he rebuffed these offers, he’d often notice that freshly posted 5-star reviews would be removed from his page — often no less than 24 hours after getting off the phone with a Yelp rep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I came from Italy, and know exactly what mafia extortion looks like,” he says. “Yelp was manipulating reviews and hoping I would pay a protection fee. I didn’t come to America and work for 25 years to be extorted by some idiot in Silicon Valley.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Faced with undulating star ratings, Cerretini resulted to a devious measure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I wrote myself 5-star reviews,” he admits. “I wasn’t a good guy. I was writing fake ones to replace the &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; ones they removed.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Documented records shared with &lt;em&gt;The Hustle&lt;/em&gt; by a Yelp spokesperson tell a fuller story of Cerretini’s actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under the alias “Babghanoush I,” Cerretini posted 13 fake positive reviews for Botto Bistro, as well as fake critical reviews of neighboring restaurants — sometimes going so far as to disparage fellow owners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yelp rebuffed Cerretini’s extortion claims, instead attributing the removal of positive Botto Bistro reviews to the platform’s algorithm, which routinely filters reviews based on a number of criteria (which are not public). These “filtered” reviews are still visible to customers, but do not factor into a business’s overall star rating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/lwFuwmK525Rq9qo980Kwey7CnFuAqJ5CTn8e81z71_qz_1JhfgSSls77XexfYfL6MBYye25f1UOHJJ-81SEPX2T_w70pKxY3GLuATCttNRJeA9-oIo1GWh2cs2Y42XStTNiPtqgz&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;2500&quot; height=&quot;462&quot;/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cerretini poses in front of his Richmond, California restaurant (via Davide Cerretini)&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually, Cerretini relented, plunking down $270 per month to advertise his business on Yelp. But after 6 months, he found the service “useless” and cancelled it. Once again, his star rating plummeted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the spring of 2014, after turning down another Yelp salesperson, Cerretini claims that four 5-star reviews were filtered from his page, and three 1-star reviews were suddenly catapulted to the top of the page. For the chef, this was the final straw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Those 1-star reviews were from people who never even set foot in my restaurant,” says Cerretini. “One complained about our waiters… we didn’t even &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; waiters!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cerretini began to realize that Yelp was “completely controlling [his] reputation.” And after mulling things over, he decided it was time for more extreme measures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good meal? Leave us 1 star on Yelp!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time, Cerretini had a reputation for being snarky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the vein of &lt;a href=&quot;https://priceonomics.com/the-worst-waiter-in-history/&quot;&gt;Edsel Ford Fong&lt;/a&gt; (who gained a reputation in 1960s San Francisco for being the ‘World’s Rudest Waiter’), his sassy attitude with diners was part of his appeal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He maintained a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bottobistro.com/HALLOFSHAME.html&quot;&gt;Hall of Shame&lt;/a&gt; featuring facetious Yelp Eliters (or “Village Idiots”). He compiled idiotic customer inquiries (e.g. “Do you sell burgers?”) and sent out a newsletter of the “Stupidest Questions of the Month.” He posted an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bottobistro.com/FAQ.html&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt; on his website stating that the customer is not, in fact, always right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To loyal diners, it was Davide being Davide; to transient Yelpers, it was 1-star service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soon, he came to a realization: “What if I don’t give a shit about reputation? What if I take away their power by actually making it worse?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One morning in September of 2014, he placed a simple sign in front of Botto Bistro: &lt;em&gt;Give us a one star review on Yelp and get 25% off any pizza! Hate us on Yelp.&lt;/em&gt; (The discount was later increased to 50%.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/yBVkBJLVoVw02bs5BO_WCv8anDzg_LAB-2s6-CHXN_SkVjIxRp2CD9bMmF0Q71BAHGtIhJaIgO3GtTY75y-eKOQErY0G-Rd-ihKgNVz0kgUtAntOJ2X4ysjHEQpvNwkVA_lDX_KD&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;2500&quot; height=&quot;575&quot;/&gt;&lt;em&gt;A news producer films Botto Bistro’s ad in 2014 (via Davide Cerretini)&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I knew the people at Yelp were going to hate me, but that’s exactly what I wanted,” says Cerretini. “I didn’t want them in there anyway.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His protest came at a perfect time. Days earlier, the 9th U.S. Circuit Court of Appeals had &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/court-rules-yelp-can-manipulate-reviews-2014-9&quot;&gt;ruled&lt;/a&gt; that Yelp had the right to manipulate reviews, and its advertising tactics were a form of “hard bargaining” — not extortion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Small business owners were furious, and they were looking for a vigilante hero.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Delicious food priced fairly. One star.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning, Cerretini pulled into his parking lot and was greeted by an “avalanche” of journalists, fellow restaurant owners, and supporters. They all wanted to know the same thing: &lt;em&gt;How did it feel to just… not care about reviews?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That Friday, Cerretini did more business than he typically did in an entire month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I had to ask the restaurant community for help, extra pizza dough,” he laughs. “It was an absolute madhouse. I’d never seen anything like it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most supporters refused to take the discount, but were thrilled to write a review and partake in what they deemed to be a grassroots, anti-Yelp uprising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a few days’ time, Botto Bistro’s Yelp page attracted more than 2,300 1-star ratings (95% of its total reviews) extolling the good food, proper service, and rustic ambiance. “Botto Bistro sucks,” wrote one reviewer. “Delicious food priced fairly. One star.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This earned the restaurant the distinction of being the worst-rated restaurant on Yelp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/RMrD8OD7Je74oVj5bYiRiWNA2na1qoAQvxVP7lTn4h1hC9XDDOCocBoFKnE9WiGzcUNcHUvVXICs1CMObNapHiz5x12B8UU4Zy-E3VGp0MyjO50G76BXBT9Vvbj1Q06vqvWwbROa&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;2500&quot; height=&quot;573&quot;/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Botto Bistro attracted more than 2,300 1-star reviews (Botto Bistro Yelp page, via Wayback Machine)&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I got thousands and thousands of letters, thousands of emails a day,” says Cerretini. “People were sending me boxes of chocolates, cash, checks. Business owners from all over the country stopped by to thank me and write a bad review.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yelp was none too pleased about Cerretini’s newfound fame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chef soon received a threatening email from a member of Yelp support, claiming he was exchanging reviews for “incentives” (a discount on pizza) — a clear violation of the platform’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yelp.com/static?p=tos&amp;amp;country=US&quot;&gt;Terms of Service&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cerretini replied with mocking language, then posted both emails publically on social media, further stoking his followers’ Yelp hatred.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/4mq1lJ71mg7XVEXaOWhNn8H3BBTzD4vmFttID9B5aqhNXGEeYcOydPim-iJZ-6vlymKoayNSD_acqdtUgm7xio1ykjcR8O-QoyurGxFBI3vIv5EexclsCxXezajnZr7BXKrPqdr0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;2500&quot; height=&quot;907&quot;/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Emails between Yelp and Cerretini, edited for brevity (via Davide Cerretini)&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the press continued, Cerretini positioned himself as an anti-Yelp spokesman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It wasn’t about the discount, or the pizza, or even the reviews,” he says. “It was about the general public saying enough is enough. They no longer wanted to be surrounded by Yelpers’ bullshit.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The uprising&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cerretini wasn’t the only one to act on this sentiment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In isolated bids to circumvent the “oppression” of online reviews, business owners have plunked “NO YELPERS” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eater.com/2015/10/29/9636754/arizona-restaurant-war-against-yelpers-south-park-yelp&quot;&gt;signs&lt;/a&gt; in their windows, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eater.com/2015/3/3/8140395/restaurant-owner-shames-entitled-yelpers-on-instagram&quot;&gt;shamed&lt;/a&gt; rude reviewers on Instagram, and launched &lt;a href=&quot;http://yelp-sucks.com/&quot;&gt;anti-Yelp websites&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dan Neves, a waiter at a fine dining establishment in Austin, Texas, created &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/groups/848796005457291/?ref=bookmarks&quot;&gt;YELP BULLIES EXPOSED&lt;/a&gt;, a private Facebook group that tracks down rude Yelpers and sends them a one-pound bag of animal feces procured from &lt;a href=&quot;http://poopsenders.com&quot;&gt;poopsenders.com&lt;/a&gt;. In a little over a month, the group has attracted 278 members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I’ve had friends get fired over bad Yelp reviews, even if the review was untrue,” says Neves. “If you cost someone her job, the least I can do is send you a pound of shit… elephant shit, rhino shit, dog shit — any other type of shit I can get my hands on.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While business owners say Yelp is a “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/groups/265587273598721/?ref=bookmarks&quot;&gt;Mafia&lt;/a&gt;” that extorts them by manipulating star ratings, Yelp brushes this off a “conspiracy theory” trotted out by “fringe commentators.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This saga played out publicly a few weeks ago, with the release of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Billion-Dollar-Bully-Davide-Cerretini/dp/B07QV5RQTZ/ref=sr_1_1?crid=2LCFJXTZIF2B3&amp;amp;keywords=billion+dollar+bully&amp;amp;qid=1559880983&amp;amp;s=instant-video&amp;amp;sprefix=billion+dollar+bully%2Caps%2C247&amp;amp;sr=1-1&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Billion Dollar Bully&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a long-anticipated documentary about this alleged extortion. In response to the film, Yelp purchased billiondollarbully.com and directed it to a landing page (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yelp.com/extortion&quot;&gt;yelp.com/extortion&lt;/a&gt;) categorically dispelling the claims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/VEZSLkpAi01Id09yzQTYWXomlCWyDvY2aX-P_WRJDDctNJtB3qRr1w5gTBpW-4vLbBVdhqRPHB5zBznmSFvZWHBqbUuC49p2HoG13PT5vSEzGTLcADxMpYr7xsRHjQ5PFY15-zYJ&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;2500&quot; height=&quot;575&quot;/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cerretini poses with a list of Botto Bistro’s rules (via Davide Cerretini)&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Yelp spokesperson we spoke with says the extortion claims are really just a “misconception” about how Yelp’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yelp-support.com/article/What-is-Yelp-s-recommendation-software?l=en_US&quot;&gt;recommendation software&lt;/a&gt; works. To back up this claim, the company often notes that every &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/2015/11/people-keep-suing-yelp-over-its-reviews-and-keep-losing/&quot;&gt;class-action lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; and FTC investigation against them has been ruled in their favor or dropped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The truth is likely somewhere in the middle. Yelp is undeniably aggressive in its sales tactics (according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yelp-ir.com/overview/default.aspx&quot;&gt;earnings reports&lt;/a&gt;, 85% of its ad revenue comes from small businesses) and reviews on the platform do, indeed, frequently fluctuate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But despite legions of anecdotal evidence from business owners, the linkage between these two things ultimately can’t be proven without transparency around Yelp’s filtering algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The 1-star chef&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, Cerretini has forged a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.davidecerretini.com/&quot;&gt;career&lt;/a&gt; out of his 1-star publicity: He does private cooking classes and events that run up to $3,000 a pop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the aftermath of his press, he’s become a celebrity in the restaurant scene — a Davide who went up against a tech Goliath and emerged self-empowered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I’m the only person who beat them at their own game,” he says. “I left a black mark on that company. I trolled them. I humiliated them. And now, they avoid me like the plague.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yelp says that Cerretini is giving himself too much credit. Botto Bistro is an atomic particle in an ecosystem that contains 185m reviews. A member of the company called the act of defiance a publicity stunt that had a negligible impact on the platform’s operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the chef still enjoys immunity: On occasion, he’ll screw around by changing his listed business hours, or renaming Botto Bistro “The Worst Chinese Food in the World.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Most people are not ready to stop caring about reviews — it’s a big risk,” he says. “But I’d rather sit alone in my restaurant then get business from Yelpers.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Share and discuss&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;br clear=&quot;all&quot;/&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;6.44&quot;&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;8.28&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thehustle.co/&quot; onclick=&quot;ga('send', 'event', 'nav', 'advertorial', 'ps');&quot;&gt;Sign up here&lt;/a&gt; for our daily news email to get all the non-political news you never knew you needed. All it takes is 5 minutes and BOOM, you're smarter.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br clear=&quot;all&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2019 13:13:28 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kull</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>The restaurant owner who asked for 1-star Yelp reviews</og:title>
<og:description>How one small business owner flipped the online review ecosystem on its head.</og:description>
<og:url>https://thehustle.co/botto-bistro-1-star-yelp/</og:url>
<og:image>https://thehustle.co/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/share-1.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://thehustle.co/botto-bistro-1-star-yelp/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Blender Is Free Software</title>
<link>https://code.blender.org/2019/06/blender-is-free-software/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://code.blender.org/2019/06/blender-is-free-software/</guid>
<description>&lt;h2&gt;Blender is Free Software. It is free to use for everyone. Free to use for any purpose, also commercially. Blender is free to share with others, it is free to study Blender’s sources and free to make new versions.&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Blender is free, forever.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This freedom is what makes the GNU GPL license so powerful and it is why it’s much more than “open source”. The license simply prevents anyone to put restrictions on Blender. That protects users as well as everyone who contribute to Blender.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you decide to contribute to Blender, whether as Python script or as C++ code, you are required to agree on this freedom. You can keep all rights of your own work, but if you publish or sell or share Blender code, you do it under the same conditions, just as Free as Blender is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The GPL has often be called infectious. I think that’s a negative and misleading frame. Proprietary code is infectious in ways too (try to use proprietary code in your work and face the consequences). Best is to keep the public and open domain entirely separated from your private proprietary domain. And really, both domains can live well together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can create bridges between the domains. This is how Blender can work with other proprietary tools or engines. The bridges (if using Blender code) have to be fully GPL compatible. The closed software such bridges lead to can not be bundled, it’s up to your own – or the user’s – concern to connect it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past years, developing and selling Blender add-ons grew into quite a big market. We’ve all seen fantastic &amp;amp; powerful scripts doing amazing things. Great add-on coders indeed. But also: what an incredible API these C developers made for Blender!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blender’s scripting API is an integral part of the software. Blender add-ons work, look and feel like Blender features. And as with any other Blender feature that means – it has to be free, free and free forever! Paying for an add-on can only mean access to the add-on download service… offering it to you as GNU GPL. Your freedom as a user and developer is guaranteed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve always interpreted Free Software and the GNU GPL as a means, not a goal. It just works fantastic for Blender. I’m not going to blame proprietary programs for not opening up. But I also won’t accept proprietary business to pollute our open domain. Live, and let live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you think you ‘suffer from piracy’ or find it hard to do business with Free Software? Just distinguish yourselves with the proven successful free/open source business model: provide docs, training, content, frequent updates and support. Your customers will love you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I expect that all add-on developers recognize and respect this concept. Since 2002 dozens – maybe even hundreds – of people have devoted years of their life to making Blender open and free to use for everyone. This massive effort has made it a strong and exciting program where add-ons can become massively successful. You’re standing on the shoulders of giants!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This can only work if we create a level playing field for everyone. Nobody’s code is more important than another’s. Nobody cuts a corner of the Blender play field to claim it as their territory. Nobody will plant trees here where you can’t climb in or enjoy its fruits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Complete. Free. Forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;has-small-font-size&quot;&gt;Please note: I’m not a lawyer and not a license expert. Just sharing how I see this complex matter. Hopefully it helps understanding Blender’s license better. Thanks for reading!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2019 11:55:23 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kiki_jiki</dc:creator>
<og:title> Blender is Free Software — Blender Developers Blog</og:title>
<og:description>Developer musings on Blender</og:description>
<og:url>https://code.blender.org/2019/06/blender-is-free-software/</og:url>
<og:image>https://code.blender.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/358c5f7e8c1b769fb45337fac08b0e4d-l-500x200.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://code.blender.org/2019/06/blender-is-free-software/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Hundreds of thousands take to Hong Kong streets against controversial bill</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/politics/article/3013725/hong-kong-edge-crowds-gather-ultimate-showdown-against</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/politics/article/3013725/hong-kong-edge-crowds-gather-ultimate-showdown-against</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/politics/article/3013725/hong-kong-edge-crowds-gather-ultimate-showdown-against&quot;&gt;https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/politics/article/3013725/hong-kong-edge-crowds-gather-ultimate-showdown-against&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20138546&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20138546&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 243&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 39&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2019 11:31:16 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>cow9</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/politics/article/3013725/hong-kong-edge-crowds-gather-ultimate-showdown-against</og:url>
<og:title>As it happened: How protest march against extradition bill turned ugly</og:title>
<og:description>Mob storms metal barricades, police respond with batons and pepper spray</og:description>
<og:image>https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_image_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/2019/06/10/whatsapp_image_2019-06-10_at_01.44.00_0.jpeg?itok=o-YM-ZpH</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/politics/article/3013725/hong-kong-edge-crowds-gather-ultimate-showdown-against</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>AWS costs every programmer should know</title>
<link>https://david-codes.hatanian.com/2019/06/09/aws-costs-every-programmer-should-now.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://david-codes.hatanian.com/2019/06/09/aws-costs-every-programmer-should-now.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The title for this blog post is a direct reference to &lt;a href=&quot;https://people.eecs.berkeley.edu/~rcs/research/interactive_latency.html&quot;&gt;Latency Numbers Every Programmer Should Know&lt;/a&gt;. There are several versions of those numbers available now, and I could not find the original author with certainty. Some people attribute the original numbers to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jeffdean&quot;&gt;Jeff Dean&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When working on a project that will reach a certain scale, you need to balance several concerns. What assumptions am I making and how do I confirm them? How can I get to market quickly? Will my design support the expected scale?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the issues associated with scale, is the cost of your infrastructure. Cloud providers allow you to provisions thousands of CPUs and store terabytes of data at the snap of a finger. But that comes at a cost, and what is negligible for a few thousand users might become a burning hole in your budget when you reach millions of users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, I’m going to list reference numbers I find useful to keep in mind when considering an architecture. Those numbers are not meant for accurate budget estimation. They’re here to help you decide if your design makes sense or is beyond what you could ever afford. So consider the orders of magnitude and relative values rather than the absolute values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also consider that your company may get discounts from AWS, and those can make a massive difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s the cost of a CPU these days? I used the wonderful &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ec2instances.info/&quot;&gt;ec2instances.info&lt;/a&gt; interface to extract the median price of a vCPU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can get the source data out of &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/powdahound/ec2instances.info/blob/master/www/instances.json&quot;&gt;their Github repo&lt;/a&gt;. I copied it and processed it using a python script &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dhatanian/aws-ec2-costs&quot;&gt;that you can find on Github&lt;/a&gt;. All prices are for the eu-west-1 region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Median monthly cost&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;1 modern vCPU (4 AWS ECUs)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;58 $/month&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;With 1 year convertible reservation (all up front)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;43 $/month&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;With 3 years convertible reservation (all up front)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;30 $/month&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;With spot pricing (estimated)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;30 $/month&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I estimated spot pricing based on anecdotal data I got from various sources. As the prices vary within a day and I could not find a reliable data source for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AWS represents the computing power of its machines in Elastic Compute Units, and 4 ECUs represent more or less the power of a modern CPU. So the prices above are for one CPU or core, not one instance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s the price of 1 ECU in $ per hour across all instance types I looked at:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://david-codes.hatanian.com/assets/posts/2019-06-09-aws-costs-every-programmer-should-now.md/ecu-memory-cost.png&quot; alt=&quot;Price of 1 ECU in $ per hour&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here’s how on-demand compares with 1 year and 3 year reservations (both convertible, upfront payments):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://david-codes.hatanian.com/assets/posts/2019-06-09-aws-costs-every-programmer-should-now.md/ondemand-vs-reserved.png&quot; alt=&quot;How many more reserved instances can you pay for the same price as on-demand&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So you want low latency, high throughput and are planning to store everything in Redis? Then on top of those CPU costs, you’ll need to pay for RAM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used the same approach to extract the median price of 1GB of RAM on EC2. Elasticache is more or less twice as expensive for on-demand but prices drop quite quickly when looking at reserved instances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Median monthly cost&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;1 GB RAM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10 $/month&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;1 GB RAM 1 year convertible reservation (all up front)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8 $/month&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;1 GB RAM 3 years convertible reservation (all up front)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5 $/month&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;SSD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.11 $/month&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Hard Disk&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.05 $/month&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;S3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.02 $/month&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;S3 Glacier&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.004 $/month&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2019 10:54:49 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dizzih</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://david-codes.hatanian.com/2019/06/09/aws-costs-every-programmer-should-now.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Opera, Brave, Vivaldi to ignore Chrome&amp;#039;s anti-ad-blocker changes</title>
<link>https://www.zdnet.com/article/opera-brave-vivaldi-to-ignore-chromes-anti-ad-blocker-changes-despite-shared-codebase/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.zdnet.com/article/opera-brave-vivaldi-to-ignore-chromes-anti-ad-blocker-changes-despite-shared-codebase/</guid>
<description>&lt;span class=&quot;img aspect-set&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://zdnet1.cbsistatic.com/hub/i/2019/06/09/49716a81-5167-4939-861a-4c23be67bac5/2a5b1a850c1c34b09c5fbae0df1f44b3/adblocker.jpg&quot; class=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;ad blocker&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite sharing a common Chromium codebase, browser makers like Brave, Opera, and Vivaldi don't have plans on crippling support for ad blocker extensions in their products -- as Google is currently planning on doing within Chrome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The three browsers makers have confirmed to &lt;em&gt;ZDNet&lt;/em&gt;, or in public comments, of not intending to support a change to the extensions system that Google plans to add to Chromium, the open-source browser project on which Chrome, Brave, Opera, and Vivaldi are all based on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Manifest V3 scandal&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.chromium.org/2018/10/trustworthy-chrome-extensions-by-default.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Google announced plans to modify the Chromium extension system&lt;/a&gt; last October when the browser maker said it would develop a new set of standards -- collectively known as Manifest V3 -- that will modify how extensions work on top of the Chromium codebase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took extension developers a few months to understand how intrusive the Manifest V3 modifications were, but they did eventually realize that Google was planning to replace one of the main technology through which extensions interacted with website requests, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zdnet.com/article/google-chrome-could-soon-kill-off-most-ad-blocker-extensions/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;in favor of one that was far inferior&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially, it was thought that extensions which provided ad-blocking services would be the ones impacted the most, but it was later also discovered that e&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zdnet.com/article/chrome-api-update-will-kill-a-bunch-of-other-extensions-not-just-ad-blockers/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;xtensions for antivirus products, parental control enforcement, and various privacy-enhancing services were also affected&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users protested against Google's decision, and the company came under heavy criticism from the public -- with many users accusing it of trying to sabotage ad-blocking extensions that were cutting into Google's advertising business profits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zdnet.com/article/google-backtracks-on-chrome-modifications-that-would-have-crippled-ad-blockers/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Google backtracked on the change&lt;/a&gt; a month later, in mid-February, but it appears that the promise to keep the old extension technology intact was just a lie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;sharethrough-top&quot; data-component=&quot;medusaContentRecommendation&quot; data-medusa-content-recommendation-options=&quot;{&amp;quot;promo&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;promo_ZD_recommendation_sharethrough_top_in_article_desktop&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;spot&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;dfp-in-article&amp;quot;}&quot;&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the end of May, Google made a new announcement in which it said that the old technology that ad blockers were relying on would &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zdnet.com/article/google-still-plans-to-cripple-ad-blocking-in-chrome-but-enterprises-will-be-exempt/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;only be available for Chrome enterprise users&lt;/a&gt;, but not for regular users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time, Chrome developers seem intent on plowing through with their decision, with the Manifest V3 changes being scheduled to go live in January 2020, when ad blocker extensions would see their ability to block ads greatly diminished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The move has angered Chrome users beyond belief, with many vowing to switch browsers, and many setting their eyes on Firefox, whose developers have been working to transform and rebrand the former fan-favorite into a privacy-first product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Google's planned Manifest V3 changes are being added to the Chromium base, meaning they'll also likely impact other Chromium-based browsers as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Brave&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an email to &lt;em&gt;ZDNet&lt;/em&gt; on Friday, Brendan Eich, CEO of Brave Software, said the Brave browser plans to support the old extension technology that Google is currently deprecating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;To respond on the declarativeWebRequest change (restricting webRequest in full behind an enterprise policy screen), we will continue to support webRequest for all extensions in Brave,&quot; Eich told &lt;em&gt;ZDNet&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, Brave itself supports a built-in ad blocker, that users can utilize as an alternative to any extension.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, Eich told &lt;em&gt;ZDNet&lt;/em&gt; that Brave would continue to support uBlock Origin and uMatrix, the two extensions developed by Raymond Hill, the Chrome extension developer who's been highlighting Google's plans to sabotage Chrome ad blockers for the past months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Opera&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;ZDNet&lt;/em&gt; also received a similar statement from Opera, another browser vendor which uses the Chromium codebase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;We might also consider keeping the referenced APIs working, even if Chrome doesn't, but again, this is not really an issue for the more than 300 million people who have chosen Opera,&quot; an Opera spokesperson told us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is because, just like Brave, Opera also ships with a built-in ad blocker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;All the Opera browsers, both on mobile and PC, come with an ad blocker that users can choose to enable,&quot; the spokesperson said. &quot;This means that Opera users aren't really exposed to these changes - unlike users of most other browsers.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further, this ad blocker is very configurable because it also allows users to import custom domain lists, so users can block any advertising domain they want, giving them full control of what types of ads they can see, or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Vivaldi&lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Vivaldi, another pretty popular Chromium-based browser, published a blog post on Monday &lt;a href=&quot;https://vivaldi.com/blog/chromium-ad-blockers-choice/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;affirming its support for giving users a choice&lt;/a&gt; -- even if the company has not yet decided how it will proceed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;How we tackle the API change depends on how Google implements the restriction,&quot; said Petter Nilsen, Senior Developer at Vivaldi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Once the change is introduced to Chromium, believe me when I say that there are many, many possible scenarios. Restoring the API could be one of them. We've restored functionality before,&quot; Nilsen said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;If the API is removed altogether and no decent alternative is implemented, we might look into creating a limited extensions store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The good news is that whatever restrictions Google adds, at the end we can remove them. Our mission will always be to ensure that you have the choice,&quot; Nilsen added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Microsoft Edge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only major browser maker who did not respond to our request for comment on this issue was Microsoft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company announced last year it was ditching its proprietary EdgeHTML browser engine for a Chromium port of Edge, which is currently in public testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft's plans in regards to Google's Manifest V3 changes are currently unknown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;More browser coverage:&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2019 07:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>snaky</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.zdnet.com/article/opera-brave-vivaldi-to-ignore-chromes-anti-ad-blocker-changes-despite-shared-codebase/</og:url>
<og:title>Opera, Brave, Vivaldi to ignore Chrome's anti-ad-blocker changes, despite shared codebase | ZDNet</og:title>
<og:description>Other browser makers don't seem to be on board with Google's decision to neuter its extensions API, and essentially, ad blockers.</og:description>
<og:image>https://zdnet2.cbsistatic.com/hub/i/r/2019/06/09/49716a81-5167-4939-861a-4c23be67bac5/thumbnail/770x578/116c31bcd742f2e5e70822146dbd2081/adblocker.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.zdnet.com/article/opera-brave-vivaldi-to-ignore-chromes-anti-ad-blocker-changes-despite-shared-codebase/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Open Source Seed Initiative</title>
<link>https://osseeds.org/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://osseeds.org/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Today, only a handful of companies account for most of the world’s commercial breeding and seed sales. Increasingly, patenting and restrictive contracts are used to enhance the power and control of these companies over the seeds and the farmers that feed the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patented and protected seeds cannot be saved, replanted, or shared by farmers and gardeners. And because there is no research exemption for patented material, plant breeders at universities and small seed companies cannot use patented seed to create the new crop varieties that should be the foundation of a just and sustainable agriculture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inspired by the free and open source software movement that has provided alternatives to proprietary software, OSSI was created to free the seed – to make sure that the genes in at least some seed can never be locked away from use by intellectual property rights. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2019 05:16:16 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ciconia</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:title>Open Source Seed Initiative</og:title>
<og:description>Free the Seed!</og:description>
<og:url>https://osseeds.org/</og:url>
<og:image>https://i1.wp.com/osseeds.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/cropped-Slide1.jpg?fit=512%2C512&amp;ssl=1</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://osseeds.org/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Huawei Accused of Technology Theft</title>
<link>https://www.npr.org/2019/06/08/730898429/huawei-accused-of-technology-theft</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.npr.org/2019/06/08/730898429/huawei-accused-of-technology-theft</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;storytext&quot; readability=&quot;58&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huawei has become one of the world's biggest manufacturers of cellphones and high-end telecom equipment. Its rise has come with multiple accusations of technology theft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div aria-label=&quot;Transcript&quot; readability=&quot;148.65097588978&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SCOTT SIMON, HOST:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Chinese company Huawei has become one of the world's telecom giants. And there are questions about how it got there, including accusations that it stole technology to get ahead. The Trump administration has now banned U.S. companies from using that equipment in its 5G infrastructure and recently laid out rules that would prevent American firms from doing business with Huawei. Few of those companies have been open about their past work with the Chinese company, but NPR's Emily Feng found that one was willing to talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EMILY FENG, BYLINE: It all began with a few missing pieces of glass - not just any kind of glass, however. Adam Khan, the CEO of AKHAN Semiconductor, explains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ADAM KHAN: We made this world's first demonstration of a nanocrystalline diamond-based device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FENG: Layman's translation - Khan made diamond-coated glass, and hype brought clients knocking. One of them was China's Huawei. They wanted the glass for their smartphone screens. Khan knew horror stories about companies having their tech copied by their Chinese partners. Diamond-coated components have military applications as well, so Khan knew his tech couldn't leave the U.S. without government permission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KHAN: And also we were very forthright from the beginning that we can't allow this to ever be manufactured in China directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FENG: So after months of haggling, AKHAN Semiconductors sent Huawei's San Diego office a sample of its diamond glass last March with the promise that Huawei keep it in the U.S. and return it in 60 days. Instead, not only did Khan get the sample back after more than four months but...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KHAN: Immediately picking up the parcel and you could hear the broken glass, you know, we knew there was an issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FENG: Someone had blasted a laser at the glass to reverse engineer it. Shards were missing. Looking back, Khan says he should have known.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KHAN: At the very first meeting that we had in their San Diego facility, you know, they semi-jokingly were saying you should leave your samples behind. And we kind of laughed and said, yeah, that's not going to happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KATE O'KEEFFE: This culture really stems from the top and that senior people in the company are really the ones directing that everyone comply with this goal of getting technology by any means.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FENG: Kate O'Keeffe is a Wall Street Journal reporter who's collected multiple stories of alleged IP theft at Huawei. Among the cases she looked at - the 2010 suit in which Motorola sued Huawei for stealing trade secrets. The companies settled out of court. Then in 2014, T-Mobile sued Huawei for copying a phone-testing robot named Tappy. Huawei later paid millions in damages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O'KEEFFE: When we looked at the indictment in the Tappy the robot case where we saw Huawei's employees here in the U.S. actually fighting back against these orders from management, management just wasn't satisfied with that and forced them to carry on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FENG: Khan knew of these cases. So after he got back the box with the broken glass, he decided to partner with the FBI. Under their instruction, Khan called Huawei's San Diego office last December. To Khan's surprise, the Huawei employee, a woman named Angel Han, admitted the glass had been sent to China in violation of U.S. export control laws.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KHAN: They didn't seem bashful or reserved in making that comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FENG: And then suggested they meet at Nevada's annual Consumer Electronics Show to seal the deal. So in January, Khan and the FBI headed to Las Vegas. The Venetian Hotel in Las Vegas is a glitzy resort and casino with canals snaking through it. It also would be the site of Khan's confrontation with Huawei. FBI agents were close by. Khan's Huawei contact, Angel Han, met him there with her colleague. The tone was cheerful until Khan brought up the missing glass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KHAN: That's really when the tone and the emotion did a 180 on their part. Angel had become very distressed, very worried immediately as soon as I mentioned the sample, asking, you know, is the U.S. government listening?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FENG: The meeting abruptly ended. Khan never heard from Huawei again, except for one almost unbelievable email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KHAN: Stating that they would like to test our materials and that we can bring them to their San Diego facility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FENG: The FBI raided Huawei's San Diego facility in late January. The agency did not respond to requests for comment on the investigation, which is still underway. Huawei declined to comment for this story. Khan, meanwhile, is determined to move on. He is accelerating his plans to bring his diamond-coated glass to market, but he couldn't help himself from looking back just once. A few weeks ago, he drove past Huawei's San Diego office. The Huawei sign had disappeared. Emily Feng, NPR News.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;disclaimer&quot;&gt;Copyright © 2019 NPR. All rights reserved. Visit our website &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/about-npr/179876898/terms-of-use&quot;&gt;terms of use&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/about-npr/179881519/rights-and-permissions-information&quot;&gt;permissions&lt;/a&gt; pages at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org&quot;&gt;www.npr.org&lt;/a&gt; for further information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;disclaimer&quot;&gt;NPR transcripts are created on a rush deadline by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.verb8tm.com/&quot;&gt;Verb8tm, Inc.&lt;/a&gt;, an NPR contractor, and produced using a proprietary transcription process developed with NPR. This text may not be in its final form and may be updated or revised in the future. Accuracy and availability may vary. The authoritative record of NPR’s programming is the audio record.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2019 23:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tooltalk</dc:creator>
<og:title>Huawei Accused Of Technology Theft</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.npr.org/2019/06/08/730898429/huawei-accused-of-technology-theft</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Huawei has become one of the world's biggest manufacturers of cellphones and high-end telecom equipment. Its rise has come with multiple accusations of technology theft.</og:description>
<og:image>https://media.npr.org/include/images/facebook-default-wide.jpg?s=1400</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.npr.org/2019/06/08/730898429/huawei-accused-of-technology-theft</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>iOS 13 now shows you a map of where apps have been tracking you</title>
<link>https://9to5mac.com/2019/06/08/ios-13-location-permissions/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://9to5mac.com/2019/06/08/ios-13-location-permissions/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Apple continued its strong focus on privacy with the announcement of &lt;a href=&quot;http://9to5mac.com/guides/ios-13&quot;&gt;iOS 13 this week&lt;/a&gt;. The update includes several new privacy features, including a more detailed view of how apps have been using your location in the background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-596602&quot;/&gt; &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle author_ad&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-4344806526196296&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;3606871832&quot;/&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;th9bdd40d3 th3d1fbd3e&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;th9ade9252&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7&quot; class=&quot;thdbacd56e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;th94487b68 th0fe49b63&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;th9ade9252&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;th41e2e1c7 th849f4783&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;th9ade9252&quot; data-thd408249d=&quot;https://amzn.to/2D5kLGG&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/9to5mac.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/6/2018/02/sylvania-homekit-strips.jpg?resize=300%2C250&amp;amp;quality=82&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot;/&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Sylvania HomeKit Light Strip&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;th0aa6e2a0 thcf745b90&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;th9ade9252&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7&quot; class=&quot;thdbacd56e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see in the screenshots above, iOS 13 presents popup notifications when an app is using your location in the background. The notification also shows a map of the location data a specific app has tracked. The above screenshots show location data tracked by the Tesla app as well as the Apple Store app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to showing the map, the notification also presents the app’s reasoning for needing background location access. This is Tesla’s explanation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tesla uses your location to show your proximity to your vehicle (while the app is open), and to optimize phone key on your support vehicles (while the app is in the background).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the explanation for the Apple Store app:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll provide you with relevant products, features, and services depending on where you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple says that you’ll get periodic pop-ups like this in iOS 13, giving you the option to continue to give a specific app background access to your location, or to change it to “only while using.” iOS 13 also includes a new option to allow applications access to location “just once,” as opposed to having to give constant access when using an app or continuous background access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The “Allow Once” option is considered a temporary authorization, with the app prompting again the next time it’s opened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideally, the new pop-up reminder notifications with map will make users more aware of how often apps are tracking them in the background. In certain instances, always allowing location access makes more sense – such as Tesla – but the developer explanations will have to convince users of that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple also says that tvOS does not support the “Always” option, while it is also not needed by watchOS. macOS does not have Always or WhenInUse because prompting the user is automatic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;iOS 13 also cracks down on developers using Bluetooth and WiFi network details to estimate a user’s location. On stage at WWDC on Monday, Craig Federighi says that iOS 13 is “shutting the door on that abuse.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/2wxWnYJ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone wp-image-595144&quot; title=&quot;MacStadium Private Cloud for Mac&quot; src=&quot;https://9to5mac.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/6/2020/09/MacStadiumBanner-750x150.jpg?quality=82&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=750&quot; alt=&quot;MacStadium Private Cloud for Mac&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;150&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/c/9to5mac?sub_confirmation=1&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Subscribe to 9to5Mac on YouTube for more Apple news:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;embed-youtube&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe class=&quot;youtube-player&quot; type=&quot;text/html&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;563&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/vDiQsI18Zk4?version=3&amp;amp;rel=0&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;autohide=2&amp;amp;showsearch=0&amp;amp;showinfo=1&amp;amp;iv_load_policy=1&amp;amp;wmode=transparent&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2019 23:24:06 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>notlukesky</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>iOS 13 cracks down on location permission settings - 9to5Mac</og:title>
<og:description>Apple continued its intense focus with the announcement of iOS 13 this week with a handful of new location permissions. Here's what you need to go.</og:description>
<og:url>https://9to5mac.com/2019/06/08/ios-13-location-permissions/</og:url>
<og:image>https://9to5mac.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/6/2019/06/ios-13-locations.jpg?resize=1024,576</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://9to5mac.com/2019/06/08/ios-13-location-permissions/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>