<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Flash Animations Live Forever at the Internet Archive</title>
<link>http://blog.archive.org/2020/11/19/flash-animations-live-forever-at-the-internet-archive/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://blog.archive.org/2020/11/19/flash-animations-live-forever-at-the-internet-archive/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Great news for everyone concerned about the Flash end of life planned for end of 2020: &lt;strong&gt;The Internet Archive is now emulating Flash animations, games and toys in our software collection.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;has-text-align-center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.org/details/flash_loituma&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-21711&quot; src=&quot;http://blog.archive.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Loituma.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot;&gt;Utilizing an in-development Flash emulator called &lt;a href=&quot;https://ruffle.rs/&quot;&gt;Ruffle&lt;/a&gt;, we have added Flash support to the Internet Archive’s Emularity system, letting a subset of Flash items play in the browser as if you had a Flash plugin installed. While Ruffle’s compatibility with Flash is less than 100%, it will play a very large portion of historical Flash animation in the browser, at both a smooth and accurate rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.org/details/softwarelibrary_flash_showcase&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We have a showcase of the hand-picked best or representative Flash items in this collection.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; If you want to try your best at combing through a collection of over 1,000 flash items uploaded so far, &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.org/details/softwarelibrary_flash&quot;&gt;here is the link.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You will not need to have a flash plugin installed&lt;/strong&gt;, and the system works in all browsers that support &lt;a href=&quot;https://webassembly.org/&quot;&gt;Webassembly&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many people: See you later! Enjoy the Flash stuff!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot;&gt;Others might get this far down and ask “And what exactly is Flash?” or even “I haven’t thought about Flash in a very long time.” For both of these groups, let’s talk about Flash and what it represented in the 1990s and 2000s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Short History of of the Rise of Flash&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.org/details/flash_breaking_the_bank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://blog.archive.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/flash_breaking_the_bank_screenshot.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-21724&quot; srcset=&quot;http://blog.archive.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/flash_breaking_the_bank_screenshot.png 550w, http://blog.archive.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/flash_breaking_the_bank_screenshot-300x218.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 550px) 100vw, 550px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the early 1990s, web browsers were incredibly powerful compared to what came before – with simple files written in HTML that could generate documents that were mixing images and text, as well as providing links to other websites, it felt like nothing for computers had ever had this level of ease and flexibility. It really did change everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But people didn’t stay in a state of wonder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It quickly became a request, then a demand, then a mission to allow animation, sound, and greater audio/video flexibility into webpages. A huge range of companies were on a mission to make this happen. While looking back it might seem like one or two tried, it was actually a bunch of companies, but out of the wreckage of experimentation and effort came a couple big winners: &lt;strong&gt;Shockwave&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Flash&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flash had once been called SmartSketch in 1993, which was rewritten as FutureWave, and was actually a challenger to Shockwave until purchased by Macromedia, who handled creation software and playback software for both products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flash had many things going for it – the ability to compress down significantly made it a big advantage in the dial-up web era. It could also shift playback quality to adjust to a wide variety of machines. Finally, it was incredibly easy to use – creation software allowed a beginner or novice to make surprisingly complicated and flexible graphic and sound shows that ran beautifully on web browsers without requiring deep knowledge of individual operating systems and programming languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.org/details/flash_Caramelldansen&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://blog.archive.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/flash_Caramelldansen_screenshot.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-21725&quot; width=&quot;330&quot; height=&quot;330&quot; srcset=&quot;http://blog.archive.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/flash_Caramelldansen_screenshot.jpg 600w, http://blog.archive.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/flash_Caramelldansen_screenshot-300x300.jpg 300w, http://blog.archive.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/flash_Caramelldansen_screenshot-150x150.jpg 150w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 330px) 100vw, 330px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From roughly 2000 to 2005, Flash was the top of the heap for a generation of creative artists, animators and small studios. Literally thousands and thousands of individual works were released on the web. Flash could also be used to make engaging menu and navigation systems for webpages, and this was used by many major and minor players on the Web to bring another layer of experience to their users. (There were, of course, detractors and critics of use of Flash this way – accessibility was a major issue and the locked-in nature of Flash as a menu system meant it was extremely brittle and prone to errors on systems as time went on.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This period was the height of Flash. Nearly every browser could be expected to have a “Flash Plugin” to make it work, thousands of people were experimenting with Flash to make art and entertainment, and an audience of millions, especially young ones, looked forward to each new release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, cracks appeared on the horizon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.org/details/kick_a_ball_flash&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://blog.archive.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/kick_a_ball_flash_screenshot-1024x739.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-21726&quot; width=&quot;409&quot; height=&quot;294&quot; srcset=&quot;http://blog.archive.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/kick_a_ball_flash_screenshot-1024x739.png 1024w, http://blog.archive.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/kick_a_ball_flash_screenshot-300x217.png 300w, http://blog.archive.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/kick_a_ball_flash_screenshot-768x554.png 768w, http://blog.archive.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/kick_a_ball_flash_screenshot-624x450.png 624w, http://blog.archive.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/kick_a_ball_flash_screenshot.png 1118w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 409px) 100vw, 409px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Downfall of Flash&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Macromedia was acquired by Adobe in 2005, who renamed Flash to Adobe Flash and began extensive upgrades and changes to the Flash environment. Flash became a near operating system in itself. But these upgrades brought significant headaches and security problems. Backwards compatibility became an issue, as well as losing interest by novice creators. Social networks and platforms became notably hostile to user-created artworks being loaded in their walled gardens.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It all came to a head in 2010, when Apple CEO Steve Jobs released an open letter called &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thoughts_on_Flash&quot;&gt;“Thoughts on Flash”&lt;/a&gt;. The letter was criticized and received strong condemnation from Adobe, and Apple ultimately backed off their plan (although work was done to support alternate tools).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The call-out, even if not initially successful, ended the party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In November of 2011, Adobe announced it was ending support of Flash for mobile web browsers, and in 2017, announced it was discontinuing Flash altogether for 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flash’s final death-blow was the introduction of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTML5&quot;&gt;HTML 5&lt;/a&gt; in 2014. With its ground-up acknowledgement of audio and video items being as important as text and images, HTML 5 had significant support for animation, sound and video at the browser level. This mean increased speed, compatibility, and less concern about a specific plugin being installed and from what source – audio/video items &lt;em&gt;just worked&lt;/em&gt; and Flash, while still used in some quarters and certainly needed to view older works, stopped being the go-to approach for web designers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.org/details/flash_createawolfv2&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://blog.archive.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/flash_createawolfv2_screenshot.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-21727&quot; width=&quot;422&quot; height=&quot;357&quot; srcset=&quot;http://blog.archive.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/flash_createawolfv2_screenshot.png 672w, http://blog.archive.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/flash_createawolfv2_screenshot-300x254.png 300w, http://blog.archive.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/flash_createawolfv2_screenshot-624x529.png 624w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 422px) 100vw, 422px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What Are We Losing When We Lose Flash?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like any container, Flash itself is not as much of a loss as all the art and creativity it held. Without a Flash player, flash animations don’t work. It’s not like an image or sound file where a more modern player could still make the content accessible in the modern era. If there’s no Flash Player, there’s nothing like Flash, which is a tragedy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you’ll see in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.org/details/softwarelibrary_flash&quot;&gt;collection at the Archive&lt;/a&gt;, Flash provided a gateway for many young creators to fashion near-professional-level games and animation, giving them the first steps to a later career. Companies created all sorts of unique works that became catchphrases and memes for many, and memories they can still recall. Flash also led to unusual side-paths like “advergames”, banners that played full games to entice you to buy a product. Clones of classic arcade games abounded, as well as truly twisted and unique experiences unfettered by needing a budget or committee to come to reality. A single person working in their home could hack together a convincing program, upload it to a huge clearinghouse like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newgrounds.com/&quot;&gt;Newgrounds&lt;/a&gt;, and get feedback on their work. Some creators even made entire series of games, each improving on the last, until they became full professional releases on consoles and PCs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.org/details/minutemaid-mahjong&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://blog.archive.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/mmmahjong.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-21730&quot; srcset=&quot;http://blog.archive.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/mmmahjong.png 650w, http://blog.archive.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/mmmahjong-300x205.png 300w, http://blog.archive.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/mmmahjong-624x427.png 624w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 650px) 100vw, 650px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why We Emulate Flash&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet Archive has moved aggressively in making a whole range of older software run in the browser over the past decade. We’ve done this project, The Emularity, because one of our fundamental tenets is &lt;em&gt;Access Drives Preservation&lt;/em&gt;; being able to immediately experience a version of the software in your browser, while not perfect or universal, makes it many times more likely that support will arrive to preserve these items.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Flash is in true danger of sinking beneath the sea, because of its depending on a specific, proprietary player to be available. As Adobe Flash is discontinued, many operating systems will automatically strip the player out of the browser and system. (As of this writing, it is already coming to fruition a month before the end-of-life deadline.) More than just dropping support, the loss of the player means the ability of anyone to experience Flash is dropping as well. Supporting Ruffle is our line in the sand from oblivion’s gaze.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.org/details/peanut-butter-jelly-time&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://blog.archive.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/peanut-butter-jelly-time_screenshot-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-21729&quot; srcset=&quot;http://blog.archive.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/peanut-butter-jelly-time_screenshot-1.png 523w, http://blog.archive.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/peanut-butter-jelly-time_screenshot-1-300x171.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 523px) 100vw, 523px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Credit Where Due&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project is by no means an Internet Archive-only production, although assistance from Dan Brooks, James Baicoianu, Tracey Jacquith, Samuel Stoller and Hank Bromley played a huge part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://ruffle.rs&quot;&gt;Ruffle Team&lt;/a&gt; has been working on their emulator for months and improving it daily. (Ruffle welcomes new contributors for the project at &lt;a href=&quot;https://ruffle.rs&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;ruffle.rs&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The BlueMaxima Flashpoint Project has been working for years to provide a desktop solution to playable web animation and multimedia, including Flash. Clocking in at nearly 500 gigabytes of data and growing, the project is located here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://bluemaxima.org/flashpoint/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;https://bluemaxima.org/flashpoint/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A shout-out to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Guy-Sowden&quot;&gt;Guy Sowden&lt;/a&gt;, who first drafted the inclusion of Ruffle in the Emularity before it was refined elsewhere; your efforts set the ball rolling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally, a huge thanks to the community of Flash creators whose creative and wonderful projects over the years led to inspiration in its preservation. We hope you’ll like your new, permanent home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bonus Section: Adding Your Own Flash Animations to the Archive!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.org/details/flash_badger&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://blog.archive.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/flash_badger_screenshot.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-21717&quot; srcset=&quot;http://blog.archive.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/flash_badger_screenshot.jpg 960w, http://blog.archive.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/flash_badger_screenshot-300x169.jpg 300w, http://blog.archive.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/flash_badger_screenshot-768x432.jpg 768w, http://blog.archive.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/flash_badger_screenshot-624x351.jpg 624w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the creators, artists and collectors who have .swf files from the era of Flash and would like to see them uploaded to the Archive and working like our collection, here’s some simple instructions to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please note: Ruffle is a developing emulator, and compatibility with SWF files is continually improving but is not perfect. &lt;a href=&quot;https://ruffle.rs/demo/&quot;&gt;They have provided a test environment here&lt;/a&gt; to see if your SWF file will work. Please take the time to test before uploading to the Archive.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Archive looks for one mediatype setting (&lt;strong&gt;software&lt;/strong&gt;) and two metadata pairs set (&lt;em&gt;emulator&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;emulator_ext&lt;/em&gt;) to know whether an item can be run in the Ruffle emulator. Here are those two settings:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;emulator&lt;/strong&gt; set to &lt;strong&gt;ruffle-swf&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;emulator_ext&lt;/strong&gt; set to &lt;strong&gt;swf&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The emulator only works with a single SWF file at the moment, &lt;strong&gt;which should have no spaces in it&lt;/strong&gt;. With all these conditions in place, the swf item should be offered up to play and the emulator should work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When uploading to the Archive, accurate or complete descriptions, title, creation date, are all optional but strongly encouraged to provide context for users. Additionally, if you create an image file (jpg, png or gif) and name it &lt;em&gt;itemname_screenshot.ext,&lt;/em&gt;, like &lt;strong&gt;itemname_screenshot.png&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; it will become the official screenshot and thumbnail for the item. Notice how we named things here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.org/download/flash_loituma&quot;&gt;https://archive.org/download/flash_loituma&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re here to help you if you run into any snags or issues. There’s no other location on the internet that does things quite this way, so if you do run into problems, feel free to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:jason@textfiles.com&quot;&gt;mail Jason Scott&lt;/a&gt; about tech support and whatever assistance can be given will be provided.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 20:44:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tosh</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Flash Animations Live Forever at the Internet Archive - Internet Archive Blogs</og:title>
<og:description>Great news for everyone concerned about the Flash end of life planned for end of 2020: The Internet Archive is now emulating Flash animations, games and toys in our software collection. Utilizing an in-development Flash emulator called Ruffle, we have added Flash support to the Internet Archive’s Emularity system, letting a subset of Flash items […]</og:description>
<og:url>http://blog.archive.org/2020/11/19/flash-animations-live-forever-at-the-internet-archive/</og:url>
<og:image>http://blog.archive.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Loituma.gif</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://blog.archive.org/2020/11/19/flash-animations-live-forever-at-the-internet-archive/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>1MB Club</title>
<link>https://1mb.club/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://1mb.club/</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;meta charset=&quot;UTF-8&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;viewport&quot; content=&quot;width=device-width, initial-scale=1.0&quot;/&gt;&lt;title&gt;1MB Club&lt;/title&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;description&quot; content=&quot;An exclusive membership for web pages weighing less than 1 megabyte&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; href=&quot;style.css&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot;/&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;23.565730055193&quot;&gt;
&lt;header readability=&quot;14.080717488789&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The internet has become a &lt;em&gt;bloated mess&lt;/em&gt;. Massive javascript libraries. Countless client-side queries. Overly complex frontend frameworks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These things are a &lt;strong&gt;cancerous growth&lt;/strong&gt; on the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we can make a difference - no matter how small it may seem. &lt;em&gt;1MB Club&lt;/em&gt; is a growing collection of performance-focused web pages found across the internet. The one and only rule for a web page to qualify as a member:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Total resources downloaded client-side must not exceed 1 megabyte&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;That's it. If you would like to suggest a web page to add to this collection, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bradleytaunt/1mb-club&quot;&gt;open a ticket in the official Github repo&lt;/a&gt;. The site will be reviewed and, if applicable, added to the list below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/header&gt;&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;November 19, 2020&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This collection is very small right now, but my hope is to keep growing this list as a solid resource for those looking for performance-based web pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;footer readability=&quot;1.6666666666667&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;A small side-project by &lt;a href=&quot;https://uglyduck.ca&quot;&gt;Bradley Taunt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Maintained with ♥ for a performant web&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 17:22:26 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>bradley_taunt</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://1mb.club/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Arecibo telescope, on the brink of collapse, will be dismantled</title>
<link>https://www.sciencemag.org/news/2020/11/famed-arecibo-telescope-brink-collapse-will-be-dismantled</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.sciencemag.org/news/2020/11/famed-arecibo-telescope-brink-collapse-will-be-dismantled</guid>
<description>&lt;input type=&quot;hidden&quot; id=&quot;newsletterInterstitial&quot; name=&quot;&quot; value=&quot;3&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;entity entity-paragraphs-item paragraphs-item-image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure__head&quot;&gt;&lt;img sizes=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.sciencemag.org/sites/default/files/styles/inline__450w__no_aspect/public/arecibowide_1280p.jpg?itok=k9F3kM7k&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.sciencemag.org/sites/default/files/styles/inline__450w__no_aspect/public/arecibowide_1280p.jpg?itok=k9F3kM7k 1w, https://www.sciencemag.org/sites/default/files/styles/inline__699w__no_aspect/public/arecibowide_1280p.jpg?itok=BlyUCIH6 700w, https://www.sciencemag.org/sites/default/files/styles/article_main_image_-_1280w__no_aspect_/public/arecibowide_1280p.jpg?itok=HPskKBx5 1280w&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption__text&quot; readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A second cable break on 7 November tore through the Arecibo telescope’s dish panels and brought the suspended instrument platform to the verge of collapse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;Arecibo Observatory/University of Central Florida&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;header class=&quot;article__header article__header--inline&quot; readability=&quot;25.807339449541&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;byline byline--article&quot;&gt;By &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencemag.org/author/daniel-clery&quot;&gt;Daniel Clery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;time&gt;Nov. 19, 2020 , 11:30 AM&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/header&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Arecibo telescope’s long and productive life has come to an end. The National Science Foundation (NSF) announced today it will decommission the iconic radio telescope in Puerto Rico following two cable breaks in recent months that have brought the structure to near collapse. The 57-year-old observatory, a survivor of numerous hurricanes and earthquakes, is now in such a fragile state that attempting repairs would put staff and workers in danger. “This decision was not an easy one to make,” Sean Jones, NSF’s assistant director for mathematical and physical sciences, said at a news briefing today. “We understand how much Arecibo means to [the research] community and to Puerto Rico.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ralph Gaume, director of NSF’s astronomy division, said at the briefing the agency wants to preserve other instruments at the site, as well as the visitor and outreach center. But they are under threat if the telescope structure collapses. That would bring the 900-ton instrument platform, suspended 137 meters above the 305-meter-wide dish, crashing down. Flailing cables could damage other buildings on the site, as could the three support towers if they fell, too. “There is a serious risk of an unexpected and uncontrolled collapse,” Gaume said. “A controlled decommissioning gives us the opportunity to preserve valuable assets that the observatory has.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the next few weeks, engineering firms will develop a plan for a controlled dismantling. It may involve releasing the platform from its cables explosively and letting it fall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Arecibo telescope has been widely used by astrophysicists as well as atmospheric and planetary scientists since the early 1960s. For many years it was the main instrument involved in listening for messages from extraterrestrial civilizations, and its striking looks won it a supporting role in feature films.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The observatory has been battered by the elements over the years, most recently by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencemag.org/news/2017/09/hurricane-damage-threatens-arecibo-observatory-s-future&quot;&gt;Hurricane Maria in 2017&lt;/a&gt; and an earthquake and aftershocks in December 2019. It’s unknown whether those stresses contributed to the cable failures, the first of which occurred &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencemag.org/news/2020/08/arecibo-radio-telescope-goes-dark-after-snapped-cable-shreds-dish&quot;&gt;on 10 August&lt;/a&gt;. An auxiliary cable, installed in the 1990s when 300 tons of new instruments were added to the suspended platform, broke away from its socket at one end, damaging some instruments and gashing the surface of the dish below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entity entity-paragraphs-item paragraphs-item-image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure__head&quot;&gt;&lt;img sizes=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.sciencemag.org/sites/default/files/styles/inline__450w__no_aspect/public/arecibocloseup_1200p_0.jpg?itok=JrUP1bKz&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.sciencemag.org/sites/default/files/styles/inline__450w__no_aspect/public/arecibocloseup_1200p_0.jpg?itok=JrUP1bKz 1w, https://www.sciencemag.org/sites/default/files/styles/inline__699w__no_aspect/public/arecibocloseup_1200p_0.jpg?itok=JT9F9RNc 700w, https://www.sciencemag.org/sites/default/files/styles/article_main_image_-_1280w__no_aspect_/public/arecibocloseup_1200p_0.jpg?itok=F7QRofwA 1280w&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption__text&quot; readability=&quot;34&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On 7 November, a main suspension cable (seen hanging down) broke free from its support tower at the Arecibo Observatory. Engineers had already noticed the cable’s wires were degraded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;Arecibo Observatory/University of Central Florida&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Engineers investigating the break ordered a replacement cable and others to lend support. During their studies, they noticed that one of the 12 main suspension cables—one connected to the same tower as the failed auxiliary cable—had a dozen broken wires around its exterior. Because these 9-centimeter-thick cables are made up of 160 wires, they thought it had enough capacity to shoulder the extra load.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencemag.org/news/2020/11/second-cable-breaks-puerto-rico-s-arecibo-telescope&quot;&gt;But on 7 November, that cable broke&lt;/a&gt;. The University of Central Florida (UCF), which leads the consortium managing the facility for NSF, already had three engineering firms on-site assessing the first break. They quickly set about analyzing the safety of the whole structure. NSF sent another firm and the Army Corps of Engineers. Of the five, three said the only way forward was a controlled decommissioning. If one main cable was operating below its design capacity, “now all the cables are suspect,” said Ashley Zauderer, NSF’s program director for the Arecibo Observatory. If one of three remaining main cables connected to the impaired tower also failed, the engineers concluded, the platform would collapse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NSF has, in recent years, been seeking to reduce its commitment to the Arecibo Observatory and, in taking over its management, UCF has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencemag.org/news/2018/02/iconic-arecibo-radio-telescope-saved-university-consortium&quot;&gt;shouldered more of the financial burden&lt;/a&gt;. But Gaume stated: “This decision has nothing to do with the scientific merits of Arecibo Observatory. It is all about safety.” The facility still has powerful and unique capabilities that researchers rely on, he said. “I’m confident of the resilience of the astrophysics community,” he added, and NSF is working with some of its other facilities to take up some of the studies that have been halted.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 16:48:32 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>LUmBULtERA</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.sciencemag.org/news/2020/11/famed-arecibo-telescope-brink-collapse-will-be-dismantled</og:url>
<og:title>Famed Arecibo telescope, on the brink of collapse, will be dismantled</og:title>
<og:description>National Science Foundation decides to decommission iconic radio observatory</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.sciencemag.org/sites/default/files/styles/article_main_large/public/arecibowide_1280p.jpg?itok=sQQkpI1R</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.sciencemag.org/news/2020/11/famed-arecibo-telescope-brink-collapse-will-be-dismantled</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Full text search on 400M US court cases</title>
<link>https://www.judyrecords.com/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.judyrecords.com/</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.judyrecords.com/&quot;&gt;https://www.judyrecords.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25150702&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25150702&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 315&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 123&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 15:52:28 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>richardbarosky</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.judyrecords.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Rust 1.48</title>
<link>https://blog.rust-lang.org/2020/11/19/Rust-1.48.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.rust-lang.org/2020/11/19/Rust-1.48.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Nov. 19, 2020 · The Rust Release Team&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;144.96298970933&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Rust team is happy to announce a new version of Rust, 1.48.0. Rust is a programming language that is empowering everyone to build reliable and efficient software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have a previous version of Rust installed via rustup, getting Rust 1.48.0 is as easy as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-console&quot;&gt;rustup update stable
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don't have it already, you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rust-lang.org/tools/install&quot;&gt;get &lt;code&gt;rustup&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; from the appropriate page on our website, and check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/blob/master/RELEASES.md#version-1480-2020-11-19&quot;&gt;detailed release notes for 1.48.0&lt;/a&gt; on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What's in 1.48.0 stable&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The star of this release is Rustdoc, with a few changes to make writing documentation even easier! See the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/blob/master/RELEASES.md#version-1480-2020-11-19&quot;&gt;detailed release notes&lt;/a&gt; to learn about other changes not covered by this post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Easier linking in rustdoc&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rustdoc, the library documentation tool included in the Rust distribution, lets you write documentation in Markdown. This makes it very easy to use, but also has some pain points. Let's say that you are writing some documentation for some Rust code that looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-rust&quot;&gt;pub mod foo {
    pub struct Foo;
}

pub mod bar {
    pub struct Bar;
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have two modules, each with a struct inside. Imagine we wanted to use these two structs together; we may want to note this in the documentation. So we'd write some docs that look like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-rust&quot;&gt;pub mod foo {
    /// Some docs for `Foo`
    ///
    /// You may want to use `Foo` with `Bar`.
    pub struct Foo;
}

pub mod bar {
    /// Some docs for `Bar`
    ///
    /// You may want to use `Bar` with `Foo`.
    pub struct Bar;
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's all well and good, but it would be really nice if we could link to these other types. That would make it much easier for the users of our library to navigate between them in our docs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem here is that Markdown doesn't know anything about Rust, and the URLs that rustdoc generates. So what Rust programmers have had to do is write those links out manually:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-rust&quot;&gt;pub mod foo {
    /// Some docs for `Foo`
    ///
    /// You may want to use `Foo` with [`Bar`].
    ///
    /// [`Bar`]: ../bar/struct.Bar.html
    pub struct Foo;
}

pub mod bar {
    /// Some docs for `Bar`
    ///
    /// You may want to use `Bar` with [`Foo`].
    ///
    /// [`Foo`]: ../foo/struct.Foo.html
    pub struct Bar;
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that we've also had to use relative links, so that this works offline. Not only is this process tedious, and error prone, but it's also just wrong in places. If we put a &lt;code&gt;pub use bar::Bar&lt;/code&gt; in our crate root, that would re-export &lt;code&gt;Bar&lt;/code&gt; in our root. Now our links are wrong. But if we fix them, then they end up being wrong when we navigate to the &lt;code&gt;Bar&lt;/code&gt; that lives inside the module. You can't actually write these links by hand, and have them all be accurate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this release, you can use some syntax to let rustdoc know that you're trying to link to a type, and it will generate the URLs for you. Here's two different examples, based off of our code before:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-rust&quot;&gt;pub mod foo {
    /// Some docs for `Foo`
    ///
    /// You may want to use `Foo` with [`Bar`](crate::bar::Bar).
    pub struct Foo;
}

pub mod bar {
    /// Some docs for `Bar`
    ///
    /// You may want to use `Bar` with [`crate::foo::Foo`].
    pub struct Bar;
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first example will show the same text as before; but generate the proper link to the &lt;code&gt;Bar&lt;/code&gt; type. The second will link to &lt;code&gt;Foo&lt;/code&gt;, but will show the whole &lt;code&gt;crate::foo::Foo&lt;/code&gt; as the link text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a bunch of options you can use here. Please see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.rust-lang.org/stable/rustdoc/linking-to-items-by-name.html&quot;&gt;&quot;Linking to items by name&quot;&lt;/a&gt; section of the rustdoc book for more. There is also a post on Inside Rust &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.rust-lang.org/inside-rust/2020/09/17/stabilizing-intra-doc-links.html&quot;&gt;on the history of this feature&lt;/a&gt;, written by some of the contributors behind it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Adding search aliases&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/75740/&quot;&gt;You can now specify &lt;code&gt;#[doc(alias = &quot;&amp;lt;alias&amp;gt;&quot;)]&lt;/code&gt; on items to add search aliases when searching through &lt;code&gt;rustdoc&lt;/code&gt;'s UI.&lt;/a&gt; This is a smaller change, but still useful. It looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-rust&quot;&gt;#[doc(alias = &quot;bar&quot;)]
struct Foo;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this annotation, if we search for &quot;bar&quot; in rustdoc's search, &lt;code&gt;Foo&lt;/code&gt; will come up as part of the results, even though our search text doesn't have &quot;Foo&quot; in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An interesting use case for aliases is FFI wrapper crates, where each Rust function could be aliased to the C function it wraps. Existing users of the underlying C library would then be able to easily search the right Rust functions!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Library changes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most significant API change is kind of a mouthful: &lt;code&gt;[T; N]: TryFrom&amp;lt;Vec&amp;lt;T&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; is now stable. What does this mean? Well, you can use this to try and turn a vector into an array of a given length:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-rust&quot;&gt;use std::convert::TryInto;

let v1: Vec&amp;lt;u32&amp;gt; = vec![1, 2, 3];

// This will succeed; our vector has a length of three, we're trying to
// make an array of length three.
let a1: [u32; 3] = v1.try_into().expect(&quot;wrong length&quot;);

// But if we try to do it with a vector of length five...
let v2: Vec&amp;lt;u32&amp;gt; = vec![1, 2, 3, 4, 5];

// ... this will panic, since we have the wrong length.
let a2: [u32; 3] = v2.try_into().expect(&quot;wrong length&quot;);
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the last release, we talked about the standard library being able to use const generics. This is a good example of the kinds of APIs that we can add with these sorts of features. Expect to hear more about the stabilization of const generics soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, five new APIs were stabilized this release:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following previously stable APIs have now been made &lt;code&gt;const&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/blob/master/RELEASES.md#version-1480-2020-11-19&quot;&gt;detailed release notes&lt;/a&gt; for more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Other changes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are other changes in the Rust 1.48.0 release: check out what changed in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/blob/master/RELEASES.md#version-1480-2020-11-19&quot;&gt;Rust&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/cargo/blob/master/CHANGELOG.md#cargo-148-2020-11-19&quot;&gt;Cargo&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust-clippy/blob/master/CHANGELOG.md#rust-148&quot;&gt;Clippy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Contributors to 1.48.0&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people came together to create Rust 1.48.0. We couldn't have done it without all of you. &lt;a href=&quot;https://thanks.rust-lang.org/rust/1.48.0/&quot;&gt;Thanks!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 14:41:47 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pietroalbini</dc:creator>
<og:title>Announcing Rust 1.48.0 | Rust Blog</og:title>
<og:description>Empowering everyone to build reliable and efficient software.</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.rust-lang.org/static/images/rust-social-wide.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.rust-lang.org/2020/11/19/Rust-1.48.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Google to end the “top stories carousel” benefit to AMP next spring</title>
<link>https://themarkup.org/google-the-giant/2020/11/19/as-antitrust-pressure-mounts-google-to-pull-back-benefit-to-news-sites-that-adopted-its-preferred-mobile-technology</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://themarkup.org/google-the-giant/2020/11/19/as-antitrust-pressure-mounts-google-to-pull-back-benefit-to-news-sites-that-adopted-its-preferred-mobile-technology</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Four years after &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.amp.dev/2016/02/24/amping-up-in-google-search/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;offering special placement&lt;/a&gt; in a “top stories carousel” in search results to entice publishers to use a format it created for mobile pages, called AMP, Google announced last week that it will end that preferential treatment &lt;a href=&quot;https://webmasters.googleblog.com/2020/11/timing-for-page-experience.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;in the spring&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We will prioritize pages with great page experience, whether implemented using AMP or any other web technology, as we rank the results,” Google said in a blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company had indicated in 2018 that it would drop the preference eventually. Last week’s announcement of a concrete timeline comes less than a month after the Department of Justice called Google a “monopoly gatekeeper to the internet” in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/justice-department-sues-monopolist-google-violating-antitrust-laws&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; alleging antitrust violations and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2020/11/13/google-critics-lobby-eus-vestager-to-take-tougher-antitrust-action.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;as pressure mounts&lt;/a&gt; on officials in the European Union, which has already fined Google more than $9 billion for antitrust violations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I did always think AMP posed antitrust concerns,” said Sally Hubbard, author of the book &lt;em&gt;“&lt;/em&gt;Monopolies Suck” and an antitrust expert with the Open Markets Institute. “It’s, ‘If you want to show up on the top of the search results, you have to play by our rules, you have to use AMP.’ ”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google spokesperson Meghann Farnsworth did not address the timing of the change but said AMP is not dead, saying the company is “fully committed to AMP as a technology.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She said AMP continues to be required for certain features that “are not technically possible” without it, such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://webmasters.googleblog.com/2019/07/helping-publishers-and-users-get-more.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;“swipe to visit”&lt;/a&gt; in Google Images, and that it’s “preferred” in the “for you” feed in Google’s news reading app, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.google/products/search/introducing-google-discover/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Google Discover&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever prompted the timing of the change, some news sites are relieved that they won’t have to keep using Google’s preferred mobile standard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are encouraged to see Google beginning to outline a path away from AMP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;cite&gt;Robin Berjon, The New York Times&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We are encouraged to see Google beginning to outline a path away from AMP,” Robin Berjon, head of data governance at The New York Times, said in a written statement in response to questions from The Markup. “It’s important Google addresses the core challenge with the format, so that it is no longer a requirement for news products and performance ranking.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;News publishers and others have been &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.politico.eu/article/google-amp-accelerated-mobile-pages-competition-antitrust-margrethe-vestager-mobile-android/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;griping about AMP&lt;/a&gt; for years. Some called it Google’s attempt to exert the same kind of control over the larger web that Facebook exerts over posts in its closed system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s because AMP is more than just a set of formatting rules. Once a website sets up an AMP page, Google copies it and stores it on Google servers. When users click on the link for an AMP page in search results—or its news reading app—Google serves up that cached version from its servers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“AMP keeps users within Google’s domain and diverts traffic away from other websites for the benefit of Google,” read a 2018 &lt;a href=&quot;http://ampletter.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;open letter&lt;/a&gt; signed by more than 700 technologists and advocates. “At a scale of billions of users, this has the effect of further reinforcing Google’s dominance of the Web.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nearly nine in 10 internet searches in the U.S. are completed on Google, according &lt;a href=&quot;https://gs.statcounter.com/search-engine-market-share/all/united-states-of-america&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;Statcounter&lt;/a&gt;. The second most popular search engine, Microsoft’s Bing, has only seven percent of the market, less than one in 10 U.S. searches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An engineer at a major news publication who asked not to be named because the publisher had not authorized an interview said Google’s size is what led publishers to use AMP.  Chinese search engine Baidu launched an initiative similar to AMP called MIP, which did not gain traction among U.S. publishers. Bing also uses AMP, but lacks the leverage that Google has over publishers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If [only] Bing did it, you would be like, ‘No it’s fine.’ Nobody would use it,” the engineer said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;article-card article-card--has-image article-card--right&quot; role=&quot;complementary&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article-card__art&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mrkp-static-production.themarkup.org/uploads/2020/07/syw-fallback-360x203.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;article-card__img&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article-card__content&quot; readability=&quot;32.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article-card__content-inner&quot; readability=&quot;35&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article-card-type&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;article-card-type__series&quot;&gt;Show Your Work&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;article-card-type__series&quot;&gt;Google the Giant&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;article-card__headline&quot;&gt;How We Analyzed Google’s Search Results&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article-card__subhead&quot;&gt;Novel categorizations and “staining” techniques uncovered how much space on the search results page Google dedicates to itself&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;time class=&quot;article-card__date&quot; datetime=&quot;2020-07-28T08:00:00&quot;&gt;July 28, 2020 08:00 ET&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;p&gt;In an &lt;a href=&quot;https://themarkup.org/google-the-giant/2020/07/28/how-we-analyzed-google-search-results-web-assay-parsing-tool&quot;&gt;analysis&lt;/a&gt; published by The Markup earlier this year of 15,269 popular searches on Google, we found that AMP-enabled results appeared often, taking up more than 13 percent of the first results page. Google took another 41 percent of the page for its own products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time, Google spokesperson Lara Levin called The Markup’s methodology “flawed and misleading.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hubbard, of the Open Markets Institute, said she expects state attorneys general who have been investigating Google and other major tech companies to file a lawsuit looking at how Google uses search to direct people to its own properties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some industry experts now speculate that the change to the top stories carousel &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.searchmetrics.com/us/is-this-the-end-of-amp/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;may ultimately make the AMP format obsolete&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The initiative, which originally stood for Accelerated Mobile Pages, restricts the size and functionality of a mobile website in the name of speed and user experience. It’s sometimes &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.searchenginejournal.com/amp-seo-everything-you-need-to-know/375931/#close&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;referred&lt;/a&gt; to as putting the web “on a diet.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the news industry struggled over the past decade, with dropping newspaper subscription rates and ad revenue and plateauing online traffic &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pewresearch.org/fact-tank/2020/04/28/10-charts-about-americas-newsrooms/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;leading to massive job losses&lt;/a&gt;, many publishers adopted AMP in hopes that it would help their bottom lines. Most of the roughly 2,000 members of the News Media Alliance, a trade organization that represents newspapers, use it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“They don’t really feel there is a choice,” said Danielle Coffey, the group’s general counsel and senior vice president.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her opinion is widely shared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We essentially have a coercion by Google upon publishers to allow people to host their content,” said Andrew Betts, a former member of the Technical Architecture Group at the international web standards organization W3C, who has written about his &lt;a href=&quot;https://trib.tv/2019/05/28/cake-or-death-amp-and-the-worrying-power-dynamics-of-the-web/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;concerns with AMP&lt;/a&gt;. “And publishers who decide they don’t want that to happen because they want to serve their own content, thanks very much, will not ever appear in the first set of search results.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some cases, it’s existentially problematic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;cite&gt;Andrew Betts, formerly with W3C&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“That’s a big deal,” he added. “In some cases, it’s existentially problematic.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Google executive once referred to AMP as an “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2018/3/8/17095078/google-amp-accelerated-mobile-page-announcement-standard-web-packaging-urls&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;altruistic&lt;/a&gt;” effort to make the web better. In its response to written questions for the record last year from Rep. David Cicilline (D-RI), who chairs the House Judiciary antitrust subcommittee, Google said the top stories carousel on mobile required AMP for technical reasons. But Google links to its cached AMP version of a page, when it exists, appear on all parts of mobile search results, not simply that carousel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AMP makes the mobile web more standardized, enabling stories or just excerpts to be embedded and displayed outside of the websites where they were originally published. This feature is potentially useful as Google displays more and more content in curated “modules” on the search results page, an &lt;a href=&quot;https://themarkup.org/google-the-giant/2020/07/28/google-search-results-prioritize-google-products-over-competitors&quot;&gt;unpopular practice&lt;/a&gt; in its own right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many news sites report that switching to AMP has increased their web traffic, in large part due to the increased exposure in the top stories carousel. But the financial benefits and reader loyalty haven’t necessarily followed the added clicks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The News Media Alliance published &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newsmediaalliance.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Final-Alliance-White-Paper-June-18-2020.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a white paper&lt;/a&gt; in June that said its members reported that AMP pages bring in less revenue and convert fewer readers to subscribers. One news organization said visitors to stories delivered in AMP read fewer articles per visit—what the alliance referred to as “one and done.” Another discovered that the number of subscribers per million readers was 39 percent lower for readers that came in through an AMP link.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;pull-number pull-number--right&quot; role=&quot;complementary&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;pull-number__content&quot; readability=&quot;34&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;pull-number__figure&quot;&gt;39%&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;pull-number__description&quot;&gt;Fewer readers became subscribers if they came to the site through AMP, according to one member of the News Media Alliance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Farnsworth, the Google spokesperson, replied that others have found financial success with AMP, and pointed to a lifestyle website, linking to a write-up in an AMP &lt;a href=&quot;https://amp.dev/success-stories/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;success stories page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“There are various factors that affect the monetization potential of any page,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The costs of supporting AMP can also be significant for some publishers, said Coffey, of the News Media Alliance. “For our smaller guys, it’s somewhat difficult just because they don’t always have the resources to be able to put into formatting content in a specific way, and there’s also just the cost associated with opportunity cost” of spending time on that instead of something else, she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And AMP sometimes causes issues that publishers lack the power to fix on their own. In one prominent example, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ampproject/amphtml/issues/24910&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;publishers discovered&lt;/a&gt; there was no way to allow users to opt out of having their data sold, a requirement under the California Consumer Privacy Act, which went into effect this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google says it doesn’t consider AMP a factor in “search ranking,” though it has said page-loading &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/search/docs/guides/about-amp&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;speed is a factor&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A coalition of publishers, including The New York Times, The Washington Post, Gannett, and others, proposed last month that tech and media companies collaborate on an &lt;a href=&quot;https://discourse.wicg.io/t/proposal-content-aggregation-technology/4941&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;alternative&lt;/a&gt; to AMP that would allow platforms to aggregate web content without “leveraging market power” to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matt Dorville, SEO manager for BuzzFeed, said he’s “skeptical” about using AMP once Google stops requiring it for the top stories carousel. He plans to do extensive testing to ensure abandoning the format doesn’t kill the site’s traffic and will monitor the choices of other major players who use AMP, like Axios and The Guardian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You never really want to be the first person out the gate making these changes,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 13:42:47 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>CPLX</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>As Antitrust Pressure Mounts, Google to Pull Back Benefit to News Sites That Adopted Its Preferred Mobile Technology – The Markup</og:title>
<og:description>Will the AMP format die as a result?</og:description>
<og:image>https://mrkp-static-production.themarkup.org/uploads/2020/11/google-ny-1200x628.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://themarkup.org/google-the-giant/2020/11/19/as-antitrust-pressure-mounts-google-to-pull-back-benefit-to-news-sites-that-adopted-its-preferred-mobile-technology</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>YouTube will now show ads on all videos even if creators don’t want them</title>
<link>https://www.forbes.com/sites/johnkoetsier/2020/11/18/youtube-will-now-show-ads-on-all-videos-even-if-creators-dont-want-them/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.forbes.com/sites/johnkoetsier/2020/11/18/youtube-will-now-show-ads-on-all-videos-even-if-creators-dont-want-them/</guid>
<description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://specials-images.forbesimg.com/imageserve/5fb5effc793ef2435a2190a4/960x0.jpg?fit=scale&quot; alt=&quot;YouTube on a smartphone&quot; data-height=&quot;2289&quot; data-width=&quot;3858&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;color-body light-text&quot;&gt;YouTube on a smartphone&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;small&gt;STRF/STAR MAX/IPx&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YouTube just changed its rules on video monetization, and YouTube creators aren’t happy. Essentially, Google will now show ads on all videos, even if their creators don’t want ads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And creators won’t get a penny.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s all in a new section of YouTube’s terms of service called “Right to Monetize.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Starting today we’ll begin slowly rolling out ads on a limited number of videos from channels not in YouTube Partner Program,” the company &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/youtube/thread/83733719?hl=en&amp;amp;msgid=83733719&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot; title=&quot;https://support.google.com/youtube/thread/83733719?hl=en&amp;amp;msgid=83733719&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot; data-ga-track=&quot;ExternalLink:https://support.google.com/youtube/thread/83733719?hl=en&amp;amp;msgid=83733719&quot; aria-label=&quot;says&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-ga-track=&quot;ExternalLink:https://support.google.com/youtube/thread/83733719?hl=en&amp;amp;msgid=83733719&quot;&gt;says&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. “This means as a creator that’s not in YPP, you may see ads on some of your videos. Since you’re not currently in YPP, you won’t receive a share of the revenue from these ads.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;YPP is the YouTube Partner Program which video creators and influencers can belong to if they have more than 1,000 subscribers and 4,000 hours of viewed content in the last 12 months.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Membership in YPP makes you eligible for revenue shares from YouTube based on ads shown on your videos, but many don’t meet the qualifications.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;“This is nuts,”&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MastarMedia/status/1329167265875496963&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot; title=&quot;https://twitter.com/MastarMedia/status/1329167265875496963&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot; data-ga-track=&quot;ExternalLink:https://twitter.com/MastarMedia/status/1329167265875496963&quot; aria-label=&quot;says&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-ga-track=&quot;ExternalLink:https://twitter.com/MastarMedia/status/1329167265875496963&quot;&gt;says&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;one large YouTube creator with over 3.5 million subscribers. “If you're a small channel, struggling to grow and haven't yet gotten monetization, YouTube will run ads now and take 100% of the profit from your work.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;recirc-module seo&quot; data-type=&quot;standard&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;recirc-module-body&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MORE FOR YOU&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Others, like Forbes senior contributor &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/ethansiegel/?&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot; title=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/ethansiegel/?&quot; data-ga-track=&quot;InternalLink:https://www.forbes.com/sites/ethansiegel/?&quot; aria-label=&quot;Ethan Siegel&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-ga-track=&quot;InternalLink:https://www.forbes.com/sites/ethansiegel/?&quot;&gt;Ethan Siegel&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;simply don’t want ads on their videos, leaving them ads-free for people to enjoy. That option will no longer be available in the new YouTube terms of service.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This latest move comes hot on the heels of what YouTube creators say is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/johnkoetsier/2020/11/06/youtube-bug-cutting-creator-pay-50-or-more-youtubers-becoming-desperate/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot; title=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/johnkoetsier/2020/11/06/youtube-bug-cutting-creator-pay-50-or-more-youtubers-becoming-desperate/&quot; data-ga-track=&quot;InternalLink:https://www.forbes.com/sites/johnkoetsier/2020/11/06/youtube-bug-cutting-creator-pay-50-or-more-youtubers-becoming-desperate/&quot; aria-label=&quot;bug that cost them weeks of revenue&quot;&gt;bug that cost them weeks of revenue&lt;/a&gt;, but that Google refuses to acknowledge: a sudden and unilateral declaration that 100% of their video views were from “invalid traffic” overnight, before returning to standard levels of monetization — at least for some — a couple of weeks later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If you're monetizing ads on our small channels then at the very least you should give us a cut for our hard efforts,” &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Magnetrex/status/1329126855241154561&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot; title=&quot;https://twitter.com/Magnetrex/status/1329126855241154561&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot; data-ga-track=&quot;ExternalLink:https://twitter.com/Magnetrex/status/1329126855241154561&quot; aria-label=&quot;says&quot;&gt;says&lt;/a&gt; the creator behind &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/TheBoobTube&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot; title=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/TheBoobTube&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot; data-ga-track=&quot;ExternalLink:https://www.youtube.com/TheBoobTube&quot; aria-label=&quot;The Boob Tube&quot;&gt;The Boob Tube&lt;/a&gt; (which is about TV, not a part of the human anatomy). “Simple as that.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;embed-base link-embed embed-7&quot; href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/johnkoetsier/2020/11/06/youtube-bug-cutting-creator-pay-50-or-more-youtubers-becoming-desperate/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-ga-track=&quot;forbesEmbedly:https://www.forbes.com/sites/johnkoetsier/2020/11/06/youtube-bug-cutting-creator-pay-50-or-more-youtubers-becoming-desperate/&quot; aria-label=&quot;YouTube Bug Cutting Creator Pay 50% Or More; YouTubers Becoming Desperate&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;link-embed__info&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;link-embed__provider&quot;&gt;MORE FROM FORBES&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;link-embed__title&quot;&gt;YouTube Bug Cutting Creator Pay 50% Or More; YouTubers Becoming Desperate&lt;/span&gt;&lt;small class=&quot;link-embed__byline&quot;&gt;By &lt;span class=&quot;link-embed__author&quot;&gt;John Koetsier&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For smaller YouTube creators being ad-free can be a competitive advantage as they climb the long hill to having a monetizable YouTube channel with a reasonable amount of revenue. Viewers get to enjoy their videos mostly distraction-free, and the creators can focus on growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that option is gone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, from YouTube’s perspective, it’s hosting and streaming videos for free. There are significant costs to running YouTube — remember how long it took for YouTube to become profitable — and bandwidth isn’t free. That’s understandable. The obvious question is, however: if you’re going to monetize smaller channels, why not simply change the partner program to give smaller creators a cut of the revenue?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;embed-base link-embed link-embed--long-title embed-5&quot; href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/johnkoetsier/2020/10/05/2-million-creators-make-6-figure-incomes-on-youtube-instagram-twitch-globally/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-ga-track=&quot;forbesEmbedly:https://www.forbes.com/sites/johnkoetsier/2020/10/05/2-million-creators-make-6-figure-incomes-on-youtube-instagram-twitch-globally/&quot; aria-label=&quot;2 Million Creators Make 6-Figure Incomes On YouTube, Instagram, Twitch Globally&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;link-embed__info&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;link-embed__provider&quot;&gt;MORE FROM FORBES&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;link-embed__title&quot;&gt;2 Million Creators Make 6-Figure Incomes On YouTube, Instagram, Twitch Globally&lt;/span&gt;&lt;small class=&quot;link-embed__byline&quot;&gt;By &lt;span class=&quot;link-embed__author&quot;&gt;John Koetsier&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One YouTuber has a solution, but YouTube won’t like it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“YouTubers need some kind of union,” &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/aculee_/status/1329150967829336064&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot; title=&quot;https://twitter.com/aculee_/status/1329150967829336064&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot; data-ga-track=&quot;ExternalLink:https://twitter.com/aculee_/status/1329150967829336064&quot; aria-label=&quot;says&quot;&gt;says&lt;/a&gt; Brax. “I’m not sure how that would work or anything but they can’t just keep getting away with killing off small creators like this.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a worthwhile thought. Larger creators with millions of followers have some clout with sharing platforms like YouTube and Instagram, but smaller creators lack any meaningful amount of power. And yet, with millions now earning some level of income by creating digital content — and starting to rely on that income — it might be an idea whose time has come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The core challenge for creators: they are essentially modern sharecroppers, entirely at the mercy of the big platforms. A union with the power to strike — and potentially remove a significant amount of new content from YouTube or TikTok or Instagram — could redress the balance of power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The perennial challenge: actually creating one among such a diverse and widespread population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full disclosure&lt;/strong&gt;: I have a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/c/johnkoetsier&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot; title=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/c/johnkoetsier&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot; data-ga-track=&quot;ExternalLink:https://www.youtube.com/c/johnkoetsier&quot; aria-label=&quot;small channel on YouTube&quot;&gt;small channel on YouTube&lt;/a&gt;. It is in the partner program, and I theoretically make a small amount of money from it (under $100/month) though I have not yet collected any payments as I have been far too lazy to input my financial details.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 13:25:33 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>patrickaljord</dc:creator>
<og:title>YouTube Will Now Show Ads On All Videos Even If Creators Don’t Want Them</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.forbes.com/sites/johnkoetsier/2020/11/18/youtube-will-now-show-ads-on-all-videos-even-if-creators-dont-want-them/</og:url>
<og:image>https://thumbor.forbes.com/thumbor/fit-in/1200x0/filters%3Aformat%28jpg%29/https%3A%2F%2Fspecials-images.forbesimg.com%2Fimageserve%2F5fb5effc793ef2435a2190a4%2F0x0.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>&quot;This ... does not entitle you to any payments,&quot; Google says.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.forbes.com/sites/johnkoetsier/2020/11/18/youtube-will-now-show-ads-on-all-videos-even-if-creators-dont-want-them/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Beirut Port Explosion</title>
<link>https://forensic-architecture.org/investigation/beirut-port-explosion</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://forensic-architecture.org/investigation/beirut-port-explosion</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://forensic-architecture.org/investigation/beirut-port-explosion&quot;&gt;https://forensic-architecture.org/investigation/beirut-port-explosion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25149177&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25149177&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 880&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 138&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 13:21:15 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>AliCollins</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://forensic-architecture.org/investigation/beirut-port-explosion</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Notepad++ 7.9.1 – pour Samuel Paty</title>
<link>https://notepad-plus-plus.org/news/v791-pour-samuel-paty/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://notepad-plus-plus.org/news/v791-pour-samuel-paty/</guid>
<description>&lt;a href=&quot;https://notepad-plus-plus.org/news/v791-pour-samuel-paty/#main&quot;&gt;skip to content&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#13;
    &lt;svg&gt;&lt;symbol id=&quot;bookmark&quot; viewbox=&quot;0 0 40 50&quot;&gt;&lt;g transform=&quot;translate(2266 3206.2)&quot;&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;m-2262.2-3203.4-.2331 42.195 16.319-16.318 16.318 16.318.2331-42.428z&quot;/&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&quot;w3c&quot; viewbox=&quot;0 0 127.09899 67.763&quot;&gt;&lt;text font-size=&quot;83&quot; letter-spacing=&quot;-12&quot; y=&quot;67.609352&quot; x=&quot;-26.782778&quot;&gt;W3C&lt;/text&gt;&lt;text font-size=&quot;83&quot; y=&quot;67.609352&quot; x=&quot;153.21722&quot; font-weight=&quot;bold&quot;&gt;SVG&lt;/text&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;m33.695.377 12.062 41.016 12.067-41.016h8.731l-19.968 67.386h-.831l-12.48-41.759-12.479 41.759h-.832l-19.965-67.386h8.736l12.061 41.016 8.154-27.618-3.993-13.397h8.737z&quot;/&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;m91.355 46.132c0 6.104-1.624 11.234-4.862 15.394-3.248 4.158-7.45 6.237-12.607 6.237-3.882 0-7.263-1.238-10.148-3.702-2.885-2.47-5.02-5.812-6.406-10.022l6.82-2.829c1.001 2.552 2.317 4.562 3.953 6.028 1.636 1.469 3.56 2.207 5.781 2.207 2.329 0 4.3-1.306 5.909-3.911 1.609-2.606 2.411-5.738 2.411-9.401 0-4.049-.861-7.179-2.582-9.399-1.995-2.604-5.129-3.912-9.397-3.912h-3.327v-3.991l11.646-20.133h-14.062l-3.911 6.655h-2.493v-14.976h32.441v4.075l-12.31 21.217c4.324 1.385 7.596 3.911 9.815 7.571 2.22 3.659 3.329 7.953 3.329 12.892z&quot;/&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;m125.21 0 1.414 8.6-5.008 9.583s-1.924-4.064-5.117-6.314c-2.693-1.899-4.447-2.309-7.186-1.746-3.527.73-7.516 4.938-9.258 10.13-2.084 6.21-2.104 9.218-2.178 11.978-.115 4.428.58 7.043.58 7.043s-3.04-5.626-3.011-13.866c.018-5.882.947-11.218 3.666-16.479 2.404-4.627 5.954-7.404 9.114-7.728 3.264-.343 5.848 1.229 7.841 2.938 2.089 1.788 4.213 5.698 4.213 5.698l4.94-9.837z&quot;/&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;m125.82 48.674s-2.208 3.957-3.589 5.48c-1.379 1.524-3.849 4.209-6.896 5.555-3.049 1.343-4.646 1.598-7.661 1.306-3.01-.29-5.807-2.032-6.786-2.764-.979-.722-3.486-2.864-4.897-4.854-1.42-2-3.634-5.995-3.634-5.995s1.233 4.001 2.007 5.699c.442.977 1.81 3.965 3.749 6.572 1.805 2.425 5.315 6.604 10.652 7.545 5.336.945 9.002-1.449 9.907-2.031.907-.578 2.819-2.178 4.032-3.475 1.264-1.351 2.459-3.079 3.116-4.108.487-.758 1.276-2.286 1.276-2.286l-1.276-6.644z&quot;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&quot;tag&quot; viewbox=&quot;0 0 177.16535 177.16535&quot;&gt;&lt;g transform=&quot;translate(0 -875.2)&quot;&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;m159.9 894.3-68.79 8.5872-75.42 77.336 61.931 60.397 75.429-76.565 6.8495-69.755zm-31.412 31.835a10.813 10.813 0 0 1 1.8443 2.247 10.813 10.813 0 0 1 -3.5174 14.872l-.0445.0275a10.813 10.813 0 0 1 -14.86 -3.5714 10.813 10.813 0 0 1 3.5563 -14.863 10.813 10.813 0 0 1 13.022 1.2884z&quot;/&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&quot;balloon&quot; viewbox=&quot;0 0 141.73228 177.16535&quot;&gt;&lt;g transform=&quot;translate(0 -875.2)&quot;&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;m68.156 882.83-.88753 1.4269c-4.9564 7.9666-6.3764 17.321-5.6731 37.378.36584 10.437 1.1246 23.51 1.6874 29.062.38895 3.8372 3.8278 32.454 4.6105 38.459 4.6694-.24176 9.2946.2879 14.377 1.481 1.2359-3.2937 5.2496-13.088 8.886-21.623 6.249-14.668 8.4128-21.264 10.253-31.252 1.2464-6.7626 1.6341-12.156 1.4204-19.764-.36325-12.93-2.1234-19.487-6.9377-25.843-2.0833-2.7507-6.9865-7.6112-7.9127-7.8436-.79716-.20019-6.6946-1.0922-6.7755-1.0248-.02213.0182-5.0006-.41858-7.5248-.22808l-2.149-.22808h-3.3738z&quot;/&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;m61.915 883.28-3.2484.4497c-1.7863.24724-3.5182.53481-3.8494.63994-2.4751.33811-4.7267.86957-6.7777 1.5696-.28598 0-1.0254.20146-2.3695.58589-5.0418 1.4418-6.6374 2.2604-8.2567 4.2364-6.281 7.6657-11.457 18.43-12.932 26.891-1.4667 8.4111.71353 22.583 5.0764 32.996 3.8064 9.0852 13.569 25.149 22.801 37.517 1.3741 1.841 2.1708 2.9286 2.4712 3.5792 3.5437-1.1699 6.8496-1.9336 10.082-2.3263-1.3569-5.7831-4.6968-21.86-6.8361-33.002-.92884-4.8368-2.4692-14.322-3.2452-19.991-.68557-5.0083-.77707-6.9534-.74159-15.791.04316-10.803.41822-16.162 1.5026-21.503 1.4593-5.9026 3.3494-11.077 6.3247-15.852z&quot;/&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;m94.499 885.78c-.10214-.0109-.13691 0-.0907.0409.16033.13489 1.329 1.0675 2.5976 2.0723 6.7003 5.307 11.273 14.568 12.658 25.638.52519 4.1949.24765 14.361-.5059 18.523-2.4775 13.684-9.7807 32.345-20.944 53.519l-3.0559 5.7971c2.8082.76579 5.7915 1.727 8.9926 2.8441 11.562-11.691 18.349-19.678 24.129-28.394 7.8992-11.913 11.132-20.234 12.24-31.518.98442-10.02-1.5579-20.876-6.7799-28.959-.2758-.4269-.57803-.86856-.89617-1.3166-3.247-6.13-9.752-12.053-21.264-16.131-2.3687-.86369-6.3657-2.0433-7.0802-2.1166z&quot;/&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;m32.52 892.22c-.20090-.13016-1.4606.81389-3.9132 2.7457-11.486 9.0476-17.632 24.186-16.078 39.61.79699 7.9138 2.4066 13.505 5.9184 20.562 5.8577 11.77 14.749 23.219 30.087 38.74.05838.059.12188.1244.18052.1838 1.3166-.5556 2.5965-1.0618 3.8429-1.5199-.66408-.32448-1.4608-1.3297-3.8116-4.4602-5.0951-6.785-8.7512-11.962-13.051-18.486-5.1379-7.7948-5.0097-7.5894-8.0586-13.054-6.2097-11.13-8.2674-17.725-8.6014-27.563-.21552-6.3494.13041-9.2733 1.775-14.987 2.1832-7.5849 3.9273-10.986 9.2693-18.07 1.7839-2.3656 2.6418-3.57 2.4409-3.7003z&quot;/&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;m69.133 992.37c-6.2405.0309-12.635.76718-19.554 2.5706 4.6956 4.7759 9.935 10.258 12.05 12.625l4.1272 4.6202h11.493l3.964-4.4516c2.0962-2.3541 7.4804-7.9845 12.201-12.768-8.378-1.4975-16.207-2.6353-24.281-2.5955z&quot;/&gt;&lt;rect ry=&quot;2.0328&quot; height=&quot;27.746&quot; width=&quot;22.766&quot; y=&quot;1017.7&quot; x=&quot;60.201&quot;/&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&quot;info&quot; viewbox=&quot;0 0 41.667 41.667&quot;&gt;&lt;g transform=&quot;translate(-37.035 -1004.6)&quot;&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;m76.25 1030.2a18.968 18.968 0 0 1 -23.037 13.709 18.968 18.968 0 0 1 -13.738 -23.019 18.968 18.968 0 0 1 23.001 -13.768 18.968 18.968 0 0 1 13.798 22.984&quot;/&gt;&lt;g transform=&quot;matrix(1.1146 0 0 1.1146 -26.276 -124.92)&quot;&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;m75.491 1039.5v-8.7472&quot;/&gt;&lt;path transform=&quot;scale(-1)&quot; d=&quot;m-73.193-1024.5a2.3719 2.3719 0 0 1 -2.8807 1.7142 2.3719 2.3719 0 0 1 -1.718 -2.8785 2.3719 2.3719 0 0 1 2.8763 -1.7217 2.3719 2.3719 0 0 1 1.7254 2.8741&quot;/&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&quot;warning&quot; viewbox=&quot;0 0 48.430474 41.646302&quot;&gt;&lt;g transform=&quot;translate(-1.1273 -1010.2)&quot;&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;m25.343 1012.3-22.14 37.496h44.28z&quot;/&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;m25.54 1027.7v8.7472&quot;/&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;m27.839 1042.8a2.3719 2.3719 0 0 1 -2.8807 1.7143 2.3719 2.3719 0 0 1 -1.718 -2.8785 2.3719 2.3719 0 0 1 2.8763 -1.7217 2.3719 2.3719 0 0 1 1.7254 2.8741&quot;/&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&quot;menu&quot; viewbox=&quot;0 0 50 50&quot;&gt;&lt;rect height=&quot;10&quot; width=&quot;50&quot; y=&quot;0&quot; x=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;rect height=&quot;10&quot; width=&quot;50&quot; y=&quot;20&quot; x=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;rect height=&quot;10&quot; width=&quot;50&quot; y=&quot;40&quot; x=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&quot;link&quot; viewbox=&quot;0 0 50 50&quot;&gt;&lt;g transform=&quot;translate(0 -1002.4)&quot;&gt;&lt;g transform=&quot;matrix(.095670 0 0 .095670 2.3233 1004.9)&quot;&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;m452.84 192.9-128.65 128.65c-35.535 35.54-93.108 35.54-128.65 0l-42.881-42.886 42.881-42.876 42.884 42.876c11.845 11.822 31.064 11.846 42.886 0l128.64-128.64c11.816-11.831 11.816-31.066 0-42.9l-42.881-42.881c-11.822-11.814-31.064-11.814-42.887 0l-45.928 45.936c-21.292-12.531-45.491-17.905-69.449-16.291l72.501-72.526c35.535-35.521 93.136-35.521 128.64 0l42.886 42.881c35.535 35.523 35.535 93.141-.001 128.66zm-254.28 168.51-45.903 45.9c-11.845 11.846-31.064 11.817-42.881 0l-42.884-42.881c-11.845-11.821-11.845-31.041 0-42.886l128.65-128.65c11.819-11.814 31.069-11.814 42.884 0l42.886 42.886 42.876-42.886-42.876-42.881c-35.54-35.521-93.113-35.521-128.65 0l-128.65 128.64c-35.538 35.545-35.538 93.146 0 128.65l42.883 42.882c35.51 35.54 93.11 35.54 128.65 0l72.496-72.499c-23.956 1.597-48.092-3.784-69.474-16.283z&quot;/&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&quot;doc&quot; viewbox=&quot;0 0 35 45&quot;&gt;&lt;g transform=&quot;translate(-147.53 -539.83)&quot;&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;m149.38 542.67v39.194h31.354v-39.194z&quot;/&gt;&lt;g transform=&quot;matrix(.098003 0 0 .098003 133.69 525.96)&quot;&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;m220 252.36h200&quot;/&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;m220 409.95h200&quot;/&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;m220 488.74h200&quot;/&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;m220 331.15h200&quot;/&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&quot;tick&quot; viewbox=&quot;0 0 177.16535 177.16535&quot;&gt;&lt;g transform=&quot;translate(0 -875.2)&quot;&gt;&lt;rect transform=&quot;rotate(30)&quot; height=&quot;155&quot; width=&quot;40&quot; y=&quot;702.99&quot; x=&quot;556.82&quot;/&gt;&lt;rect transform=&quot;rotate(30)&quot; height=&quot;40&quot; width=&quot;90.404&quot; y=&quot;817.99&quot; x=&quot;506.42&quot;/&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wrapper&quot;&gt;
      &lt;header class=&quot;intro-and-nav&quot; role=&quot;banner&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;
      &lt;a class=&quot;logo&quot; href=&quot;https://notepad-plus-plus.org/&quot; aria-label=&quot;Notepad++ home page&quot;&gt;&amp;#13;
        &lt;img src=&quot;https://notepad-plus-plus.org/images/logo.svg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;p class=&quot;library-desc&quot;&gt;&amp;#13;
        &amp;#13;
          &lt;a href=&quot;https://notepad-plus-plus.org/downloads/v7.9.1/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current Version 7.9.1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#13;
        &amp;#13;
      &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;nav id=&quot;patterns-nav&quot; class=&quot;patterns&quot; role=&quot;navigation&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;vh&quot;&gt;Main navigation&lt;/h2&gt;&amp;#13;
  &lt;button id=&quot;menu-button&quot; aria-expanded=&quot;false&quot;&gt;&amp;#13;
    &lt;svg viewbox=&quot;0 0 50 50&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot;&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#menu&quot;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&amp;#13;
    Menu&amp;#13;
  &lt;/button&gt;&amp;#13;
  &amp;#13;
  &lt;ul id=&quot;patterns-list&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;pattern&quot;&gt;&amp;#13;
      &amp;#13;
      &amp;#13;
      &amp;#13;
      &amp;#13;
      &lt;a href=&quot;https://notepad-plus-plus.org/&quot;&gt;&amp;#13;
        &lt;svg class=&quot;bookmark-icon&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; viewbox=&quot;0 0 40 50&quot;&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#bookmark&quot;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;text&quot;&gt;Home&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#13;
      &lt;/a&gt;&amp;#13;
    &lt;/li&gt;&amp;#13;
  &amp;#13;
    &lt;li class=&quot;pattern&quot;&gt;&amp;#13;
      &amp;#13;
      &amp;#13;
      &amp;#13;
      &amp;#13;
      &lt;a href=&quot;https://notepad-plus-plus.org/downloads/&quot;&gt;&amp;#13;
        &lt;svg class=&quot;bookmark-icon&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; viewbox=&quot;0 0 40 50&quot;&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#bookmark&quot;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;text&quot;&gt;Download&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#13;
      &lt;/a&gt;&amp;#13;
    &lt;/li&gt;&amp;#13;
  &amp;#13;
    &lt;li class=&quot;pattern&quot;&gt;&amp;#13;
      &amp;#13;
      &amp;#13;
      &amp;#13;
      &amp;#13;
      &lt;a href=&quot;https://notepad-plus-plus.org/news/&quot;&gt;&amp;#13;
        &lt;svg class=&quot;bookmark-icon&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; viewbox=&quot;0 0 40 50&quot;&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#bookmark&quot;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;text&quot;&gt;News&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#13;
      &lt;/a&gt;&amp;#13;
    &lt;/li&gt;&amp;#13;
  &amp;#13;
    &lt;li class=&quot;pattern&quot;&gt;&amp;#13;
      &amp;#13;
      &amp;#13;
      &amp;#13;
      &amp;#13;
      &lt;a href=&quot;https://notepad-plus-plus.org/online-help/&quot;&gt;&amp;#13;
        &lt;svg class=&quot;bookmark-icon&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; viewbox=&quot;0 0 40 50&quot;&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#bookmark&quot;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;text&quot;&gt;Online Help&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#13;
      &lt;/a&gt;&amp;#13;
    &lt;/li&gt;&amp;#13;
  &amp;#13;
    &lt;li class=&quot;pattern&quot;&gt;&amp;#13;
      &amp;#13;
      &amp;#13;
      &amp;#13;
      &amp;#13;
      &lt;a href=&quot;https://notepad-plus-plus.org/resources/&quot;&gt;&amp;#13;
        &lt;svg class=&quot;bookmark-icon&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; viewbox=&quot;0 0 40 50&quot;&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#bookmark&quot;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;text&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#13;
      &lt;/a&gt;&amp;#13;
    &lt;/li&gt;&amp;#13;
  &amp;#13;
    &lt;li class=&quot;pattern&quot;&gt;&amp;#13;
      &amp;#13;
      &amp;#13;
      &amp;#13;
      &amp;#13;
      &lt;a href=&quot;https://notepad-plus-plus.org/index.xml&quot;&gt;&amp;#13;
        &lt;svg class=&quot;bookmark-icon&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; viewbox=&quot;0 0 40 50&quot;&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#bookmark&quot;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;text&quot;&gt;RSS&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#13;
      &lt;/a&gt;&amp;#13;
    &lt;/li&gt;&amp;#13;
  &amp;#13;
    &lt;li class=&quot;pattern&quot;&gt;&amp;#13;
      &amp;#13;
      &amp;#13;
      &amp;#13;
      &amp;#13;
      &lt;a href=&quot;https://notepad-plus-plus.org/donate/&quot;&gt;&amp;#13;
        &lt;svg class=&quot;bookmark-icon&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; viewbox=&quot;0 0 40 50&quot;&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#bookmark&quot;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;text&quot;&gt;Donate&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#13;
      &lt;/a&gt;&amp;#13;
    &lt;/li&gt;&amp;#13;
  &amp;#13;
    &lt;li class=&quot;pattern&quot;&gt;&amp;#13;
      &amp;#13;
      &amp;#13;
      &amp;#13;
      &amp;#13;
      &lt;a href=&quot;https://notepad-plus-plus.org/author/&quot;&gt;&amp;#13;
        &lt;svg class=&quot;bookmark-icon&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; viewbox=&quot;0 0 40 50&quot;&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#bookmark&quot;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;text&quot;&gt;Author&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#13;
      &lt;/a&gt;&amp;#13;
    &lt;/li&gt;&amp;#13;
  &amp;#13;
  &lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/nav&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;&amp;#13;
&lt;/header&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;main-and-footer&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div&gt;
          
  &lt;main id=&quot;main&quot;&gt;&amp;#13;
    &lt;p&gt;2020-11-02&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://notepad-plus-plus.org/assets/images/SamuelPaty.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



Notepad++ v7.9.1:

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://notepad-plus-plus.org/downloads/v7.9.1&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://notepad-plus-plus.org/news/images/downloadLogo.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&amp;#13;
  &lt;/main&gt;&lt;footer role=&quot;contentinfo&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#13;
    &lt;label for=&quot;themer&quot;&gt;&amp;#13;
      dark theme: &lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;themer&quot; class=&quot;vh&quot;/&gt;&lt;span aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;/&gt;&amp;#13;
    &lt;/label&gt;&amp;#13;
  &lt;/p&gt;&amp;#13;
  &amp;#13;
&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&amp;#13;
    </description>
<pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 12:26:31 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>speedgoose</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://notepad-plus-plus.org/news/v791-pour-samuel-paty/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Google Publishes Latest Linux Patches So Only Trusted Tasks Share a Core</title>
<link>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Google-Core-Scheduling-v9</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Google-Core-Scheduling-v9</guid>
<description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;LINUX KERNEL -- &quot; src=&quot;https://www.phoronix.com/assets/categories/linuxkernel.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;100&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Google engineer Joel Fernandes sent out the ninth version of their &quot;core scheduling&quot; patches for the Linux kernel that allows for allowing only trusted tasks to run concurrently on the same CPU core -- in cases where Hyper Threading is involved to safeguard the system against the possible security exploits.&lt;p&gt;Core Scheduling has been a popular topic since vulnerabilities like MDS and L1TF have come to light. Core Scheduling aims to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=DO-Continues-Core-Scheduling&quot;&gt;make Hyper Threading safer&lt;/a&gt; and by only letting trusted tasks share a CPU core is a reasonable safeguard for still leaving Hyper Threading active on servers rather than disabling it in the name of security. DigitalOcean, Oracle, Google, and other major x86_64 players have all been interested in core scheduling and working on different solutions in order to keep HT/SMT active. Particularly for the major cloud server providers having to disable HT/SMT would be a big blow to their models.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=Google-ASI-LPC-2020-Collab&quot;&gt;Core Scheduling has made good progress this year&lt;/a&gt; and Google engineers are seemingly hopeful their solution will be mainlined. The v9 patches posted today are re-based against the latest Linux Git code while addressing previously raised issues/feedback. There is &quot;hope that this version is acceptable to be merged&quot; pending no new issues being raised.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;THis core scheduling implementation mitigates user-space to user-space attacks as well as user-space to kernel-space attacks. The patches do not change any default kernel scheduler behavior but require tagged cgroups for laying out the trusted tasks that can share a core when it comes to evaluating whether a task can be placed on a sibling thread.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.phoronix.com/image-viewer.php?id=2020&amp;amp;image=core_scheduling_v9_lrg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.phoronix.net/image.php?id=2020&amp;amp;image=core_scheduling_v9_med&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;Outside of the security context, core scheduling can be useful for real-time purposes and other performance sensitive applications where wanting better control over SMT usage. Joel mentioned, &quot;&lt;em&gt;ChromeOS testing shows 300% improvement in keypress latency on a Google docs key press with Google hangout test (the maximum latency drops from 150ms to 50ms for keypresses).&lt;/em&gt;&quot; But depending upon the configuration and workload it's still quite possible for core scheduling to eat into the overall system performance but generally should not be as bad as disabling SMT/HT.&lt;p&gt;More details on this Core Scheduling v9 work via &lt;a href=&quot;https://lore.kernel.org/lkml/20201117232003.3580179-1-joel@joelfernandes.org/&quot;&gt;the kernel mailing list&lt;/a&gt;. This core scheduling implementation in its current form amounts to just over four thousand lines of new code.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 10:49:27 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rbanffy</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Google-Core-Scheduling-v9</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>