<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>The US Is Preparing to Prosecute Julian Assange</title>
<link>https://www.wsj.com/articles/u-s-is-optimistic-it-will-prosecute-assange-1542323142</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.wsj.com/articles/u-s-is-optimistic-it-will-prosecute-assange-1542323142</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;is-lead-inset&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div data-layout=&quot;header&amp;#10;              &quot; data-layout-mobile=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&amp;#10;        media-object&amp;#10;        type-InsetMediaIllustration&amp;#10;          header&amp;#10;  article__inset&amp;#10;        article__inset--type-InsetMediaIllustration&amp;#10;          article__inset--lead&amp;#10;  &quot;&gt;
      
      
          
    &lt;div class=&quot;media-object-image enlarge-image renoImageFormat-GR img-header article__inset__image&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot;&gt;
    
      
      &lt;div data-mobile-ratio=&quot;65.2174%&quot; data-layout-ratio=&quot;65.2174%&quot; data-subtype=&quot;photo&quot; class=&quot;image-container  responsive-media article__inset__image__image&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img srcset=&quot;https://si.wsj.net/public/resources/images/B3-CK116_assang_D_20181115171956.jpg 140w,&amp;#10;https://si.wsj.net/public/resources/images/B3-CK116_assang_G_20181115171956.jpg 540w,&amp;#10;https://si.wsj.net/public/resources/images/B3-CK116_assang_GR_20181115171956.jpg 860w,&amp;#10;https://si.wsj.net/public/resources/images/B3-CK116_assang_M_20181115171956.jpg 1260w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 140px) 100px,&amp;#10;(max-width: 540px) 500px,&amp;#10;(max-width: 860px) 820px,&amp;#10;1260px&quot; src=&quot;https://si.wsj.net/public/resources/images/B3-CK116_assang_GR_20181115171956.jpg&quot; data-enlarge=&quot;https://si.wsj.net/public/resources/images/B3-CK116_assang_M_20181115171956.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;WikiLeaks founder Julian Assange walks onto the balcony of the Ecuadorean Embassy in London. &quot; title=&quot;WikiLeaks founder Julian Assange walks onto the balcony of the Ecuadorean Embassy in London. &quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
      &lt;div class=&quot;wsj-article-caption article__inset__image__caption&quot; itemprop=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;
          &lt;span class=&quot;wsj-article-caption-content&quot;&gt;WikiLeaks founder Julian Assange walks onto the balcony of the Ecuadorean Embassy in London. &lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;span class=&quot;wsj-article-credit article__inset__image__caption__credit&quot; itemprop=&quot;creator&quot;&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;wsj-article-credit-tag&quot;&gt;
              Photo: 
            &lt;/span&gt;
        Kirsty Wigglesworth/Associated Press
          &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      &lt;/div&gt; 
    &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;clearfix byline-wrap&quot;&gt;


    

        
    &lt;div class=&quot;byline article__byline&quot;&gt;
    
    
        &lt;span&gt;By&lt;/span&gt;
    
              &lt;div class=&quot;author mobile-scrim hasMenu&quot; data-scrim=&quot;{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;author&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;header&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Aruna Viswanatha&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;subhead&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;The Wall Street Journal&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;list&amp;quot;:[{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;bio&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.wsj.com/news/author/8250&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Biography&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;twitter&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;http://twitter.com/aviswanatha&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;@aviswanatha&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;email&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;mailto:aruna.viswanatha@wsj.com&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;aruna.viswanatha@wsj.com&amp;quot;}]}&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemprop=&quot;author&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Person&quot;&gt;
                  &lt;span class=&quot;name&quot; itemprop=&quot;name&quot;&gt;Aruna Viswanatha&lt;/span&gt; and 
                  &lt;/div&gt;

              

    &lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;time class=&quot;timestamp article__timestamp flexbox__flex--1&quot;&gt;
      Nov. 15, 2018 6:05 p.m. ET
    &lt;/time&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  

  &lt;div class=&quot;article-content &quot;&gt;

      &lt;p&gt;The Justice Department is preparing to prosecute WikiLeaks founder Julian Assange and is increasingly optimistic it will be able to get him into a U.S. courtroom, according to people in Washington familiar with the matter.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;Over the past year, U.S. prosecutors have discussed several types of charges they could potentially bring against Mr. Assange, the people said. Mr. Assange has lived in the Ecuadorean embassy in London since receiving political asylum from the South American country in 2012. &lt;/p&gt;




      




      &lt;p&gt;The people familiar with the case wouldn’t describe whether discussions were under way with the U.K. or Ecuador about Mr. Assange, but said they were encouraged by recent developments.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;div class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;Ecuador’s relationship with Mr. Assange &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/ecuador-punishes-wikileaks-founder-in-london-embassy-for-political-meddling-1522261732?mod=article_inline&quot; class=&quot;icon none&quot;&gt;has deteriorated sharply&lt;/a&gt; since last year’s election of President Lenin Moreno, who has described him as a “stone in our shoe” and said his continued presence at the embassy is unsustainable. &lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;An indictment from special counsel Robert Mueller that portrayed WikiLeaks as a tool of Russian intelligence for releasing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/mueller-probe-indicts-12-russians-in-hacking-of-democratic-national-committee-1531498286?mod=article_inline&quot; class=&quot;icon none&quot;&gt;thousands of hacked Democratic emails&lt;/a&gt; during the 2016 presidential campaign has made it more difficult for Mr. Assange to mount a defense as a journalist. Public opinion of Mr. Assange in the U.S. has dropped since the campaign. &lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;Prosecutors have considered publicly indicting Mr. Assange to try to trigger his removal from the embassy, the people said, because a detailed explanation of the evidence against Mr. Assange could give Ecuadorean authorities a reason to turn him over. &lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;The exact charges Justice Department might pursue remain unclear, but they may involve the Espionage Act, which criminalizes the disclosure of national defense-related information.&lt;/p&gt;






      &lt;div data-layout=&quot;header&amp;#10;              &quot; data-layout-mobile=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&amp;#10;        media-object&amp;#10;        type-InsetMediaVideo&amp;#10;          header&amp;#10;    scope-web|mobileapps&amp;#10;  article__inset&amp;#10;        article__inset--type-InsetMediaVideo&amp;#10;            article__inset--header&amp;#10;  &quot;&gt;
      
      
      
          &lt;div class=&quot;media-object-video article__inset__video media-object-video--standard&quot;&gt;
        
    &lt;div class=&quot;wsj-article-caption article__inset__video__caption&quot;&gt;
            Special Counsel Robert Mueller’s investigators are scrutinizing comments that Trump adviser Roger Stone made about WikiLeaks before the 2016 election. WSJ’s Shelby Holliday breaks down the timeline. Photo: Getty Images.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      &lt;/div&gt; 




      &lt;p&gt;In an interview last week, the head of the Justice Department’s national security division, John Demers, declined to comment on the possibility of prosecuting Mr. Assange, saying, “On that, I’ll just say, ‘we’ll see.’”&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;Ecuador has been looking to improve relations with the U.S., hosting Vice President Mike Pence in 2018 amid interest in increasing trade.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;Ecuador’s Foreign Relations Ministry declined to comment. This month, Foreign Relations Minister José Valencia told a radio station the government hadn’t received an extradition request for Mr. Assange. &lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;Mr. Assange has clashed with his Ecuadorean hosts over internet access, visitors, his cat and other issues. Last month, he sued Ecuador over the conditions of his confinement. At a hearing last month, at which a judge rejected Mr. Assange’s claims, Mr. Assange said he expected to be forced out of the embassy soon.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;A lawyer for Mr. Assange, Barry Pollack, said he hadn’t heard a prosecution was in the works.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;“We have heard nothing from authorities suggesting that a criminal case against Mr. Assange is imminent,” Mr. Pollack said. “Prosecuting someone for publishing truthful information would set a terrible and dangerous precedent.”&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;The U.S. hasn’t publicly commented on whether it has made, or plans to make, any extradition request. Any extradition request from the U.S. would likely go to British authorities, who have an outstanding arrest warrant for Mr. Assange related to a Swedish sexual assault case. Sweden has since dropped the probe, but the arrest warrant stands.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;Any extradition and prosecution would involve multiple sensitive negotiations within the U.S. government and with other countries.&lt;/p&gt;




      




      &lt;p&gt;Mr. Moreno, who was vice president when the country granted Mr. Assange asylum, likely wants to avoid being blamed if the WikiLeaks founder is imprisoned and has repeatedly said he wouldn’t hand him over to a country with the death penalty. Ecuador &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/ecuador-grants-citizenship-to-wikileaks-founder-julian-assange-1515698914?mod=article_inline&quot; class=&quot;icon none&quot;&gt;granted Mr. Assange citizenship&lt;/a&gt; in December, thinking he could then leave the embassy if he had diplomatic status, but the British government said that wouldn’t protect him from arrest if he stepped outside the building. &lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;The Justice Department has investigated Mr. Assange for years, beginning in 2010 after disclosures by WikiLeaks of thousands of classified Afghan War reports and other material, for which former Army intelligence analyst Chelsea Manning was found guilty at a court-martial.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;Under the Obama administration, then-Attorney General Eric Holder drew a distinction between WikiLeaks and news organizations, saying WikiLeaks didn’t deserve the same First Amendment protections. Investigators, however, were unable to uncover evidence that Mr. Assange had induced Ms. Manning to leak the documents and didn’t bring a prosecution.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;President Trump has sent conflicting messages about Mr. Assange, saying “I love WikiLeaks” during the 2016 campaign and praising the group after its disclosures of the hacked Democratic National Committee emails.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;Longtime Trump adviser Roger Stone told an associate earlier this year he was working to get Mr. Assange a blanket pardon from Mr. Trump, according to text messages reviewed by The Wall Street Journal. He wrote editorials and publicly advocated for such a pardon, though he told the Journal that he had never discussed his efforts with the president.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;Secretary of State Mike Pompeo, however, said last year when he was CIA director that WikiLeaks is akin to a foreign “hostile intelligence service” and a U.S. adversary. Then-Attorney General Jeff Sessions said Mr. Assange’s arrest was a “priority.”&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;The Trump Justice Department has considered several potential cases against Mr. Assange, including prosecuting him in connection with the cables Ms. Manning provided and his more recent involvement in the DNC disclosures. Prosecutors have also considered tying Mr. Assange to foreign intelligence services, people familiar with the discussions said.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;Mr. Mueller obtained an indictment earlier this year against a dozen Russian officers accused of hacking into Democrats’ computer networks and staging the release of the documents, including through WikiLeaks, during the 2016 campaign.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;After a series of criminal cases against Russian and other foreign intelligence officers, U.S. officials have grown more comfortable with disclosing the sensitive material required for such prosecutions, people familiar with the matter said. Prosecutors would need to rely on such evidence if they wanted to portray Mr. Assange as an agent of a foreign government.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;In October, a judge threw out the lawsuit Mr. Assange had filed against Ecuador to prevent the government from implementing stricter rules for his stay.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;Ecuador issued a written document saying that while at the embassy, Mr. Assange is prohibited from political activities that could affect Ecuador’s relations with other nations. It also said the embassy would provide Mr. Assange with Wi-Fi, but he had to pay for phone calls and other communication. &lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;His visitors would need to provide the embassy with information about cellphones and social media activities, the government said.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;The rules also include housekeeping duties Ecuador says are needed to create a “harmonious relationship” between Mr. Assange and embassy staff. Mr. Assange and his guests will need to clean the bathroom, the document said, and the WikiLeaks founder must feed and clean up after his cat.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;“Ecuador hasn’t violated the rights of anyone,” Attorney General Íñigo Salvador said after the court ruling. “It has provided asylum to Mr. Assange, and he should comply with the rules to live harmoniously inside Ecuador’s public installations in London.”&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;Assange’s attorneys said they would appeal the ruling.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;Ecuador issued its rules seven months after the Foreign Relations Ministry cut Mr. Assange’s internet connection at the embassy in response to his criticism of Britain on social media for expelling Russian diplomats for the poisoning of a former Russian spy.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p class=&quot;articleTagLine&quot;&gt;—Dustin Volz and Shelby Holliday contributed to this article.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Write to &lt;/strong&gt;Aruna Viswanatha at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:Aruna.Viswanatha@wsj.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;icon &quot;&gt;Aruna.Viswanatha@wsj.com&lt;/a&gt; and Ryan Dube at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:ryan.dube@dowjones.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;icon &quot;&gt;ryan.dube@dowjones.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;/div&gt;



  &lt;/div&gt;


    &lt;p class=&quot;printheadline&quot;&gt;
      Appeared in the November 16, 2018, print edition as 'Prosecutors More Confident Assange Will Get U.S. Trial.'
    &lt;/p&gt;




</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 23:10:27 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mises</dc:creator>
<og:title>U.S. Is Optimistic It Will Prosecute Assange</og:title>
<og:description>The Justice Department is preparing to prosecute WikiLeaks founder Julian Assange and is increasingly optimistic it will be able to get him into a U.S. courtroom, according to people in Washington familiar with the matter.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.wsj.com/articles/u-s-is-optimistic-it-will-prosecute-assange-1542323142</og:url>
<og:image>https://si.wsj.net/public/resources/images/B3-CK116_assang_SOC_20181115171956.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.wsj.com/articles/u-s-is-optimistic-it-will-prosecute-assange-1542323142</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Tulsa Remote</title>
<link>https://tulsaremote.com/#hero</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://tulsaremote.com/#hero</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;2 BR Avg. Rent - $658 Tulsa vs. $3,519 SF&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 BR Avg. Rent - $658 Tulsa vs. $4,088 New York&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 BR Avg. Rent - $658 Tulsa vs. $2,449 LA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 BR Avg. Rent - $658 Tulsa vs. $2,111 DC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 BR Avg. Rent - $658 Tulsa vs. $2,069 Seattle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 BR Avg. Rent - $658 Tulsa vs. $2,669 Boston&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 BR Avg. Rent - $658 Tulsa vs. $1,475 Denver&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 BR Avg. Rent - $658 Tulsa vs. $2,415 Portland&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 BR Avg. Rent - $658 Tulsa vs. $2,248 San Diego&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 BR Avg. Rent - $658 Tulsa vs. $1,500 Chicago&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 BR Avg. Rent - $658 Tulsa vs. $1,184 Austin&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 21:30:22 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Aloha</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://tulsaremote.com</og:url>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:title>Tulsa Remote</og:title>
<og:image>https://icbbmp4zdg-flywheel.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/themes/tulsa-remote/fbog.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Tulsa Remote is a one-year program that offers a $10,000 grant and additional benefits to eligible remote workers who move to and work from Tulsa.</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://tulsaremote.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>‘I Don’t Really Want to Work for Facebook.’ Say Some Computer Science Students</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/15/technology/jobs-facebook-computer-science-students.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/15/technology/jobs-facebook-computer-science-students.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;css-u5vfum StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ebnwsw e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;BERKELEY, Calif. — A job at Facebook sounds pretty plum. The interns make &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.glassdoor.com/Intern-Salary/Facebook-Internship-Salary-E40772.htm&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;around $8,000 a month&lt;/a&gt;, and an entry-level software engineer makes about &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.payscale.com/research/US/Job=Software_Engineer/Salary/7162591b/Facebook-Inc-Entry-Level&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;$140,000 a year&lt;/a&gt;. The food is free. There’s a walking trail with indigenous plants and a juice bar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ebnwsw e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;But the tone among highly sought-after computer scientists about the social network is changing. On a recent night at the University of California, Berkeley, as a group of young engineers gathered to show off their tech skills, many said they would avoid taking jobs at the social network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ebnwsw e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“I’ve heard a lot of employees who work there don’t even use it,” said Niky Arora, 19, an engineering student, who was recently invited to a Facebook recruiting event at the company’s headquarters in Menlo Park, Calif. “I just don’t believe in the product because like, Facebook, the baseline of everything they do is desire to show people more ads.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ebnwsw e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Emily Zhong, 20, a computer science major, piped up. “Surprisingly, a lot of my friends now are like, ‘I don’t really want to work for Facebook,’” she said, citing “privacy stuff, fake news, personal data, all of it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m2ozyi&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;css-u5vfum StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ebnwsw e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“Before it was this glorious, magical thing to work there,” said Jazz Singh, 18, also studying computer science. “Now it’s like, just because it does what you want doesn’t mean it’s doing good.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ebnwsw e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;As Facebook has been rocked by &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/14/technology/facebook-data-russia-election-racism.html?action=click&amp;amp;module=inline&amp;amp;pgtype=Homepage&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;scandal after scandal&lt;/a&gt;, some young engineers are souring on the company. Many are still taking jobs there, but those who do are doing it a little more quietly, telling their friends that they will work to change it from within or that they have carved out more ethical work at a company whose reputation has turned toxic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ebnwsw e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Facebook, which employs more than 30,000 full-time workers around the world, said, “In 2018, we’ve hired more engineers than ever before.” The company added, “We continue to see strong engagement and excitement within the engineering community at the prospect of joining our company.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m2ozyi&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-wrapper&quot; class=&quot;css-79elbk ehw59r11&quot;&gt;

&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-children&quot; class=&quot;css-1a48zt4 ehw59r111&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1xdhyk6 e1vv25i80&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1afaoz0&quot;&gt;Image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;css-1m50asq&quot; src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/11/16/business/16FBRECRUITING04/merlin_146347992_30ca4fd0-bebc-4ed4-8d04-206e0ca41bf6-articleLarge.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;disable=upscale&quot; srcset=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/11/16/business/16FBRECRUITING04/merlin_146347992_30ca4fd0-bebc-4ed4-8d04-206e0ca41bf6-articleLarge.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 600w,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/11/16/business/16FBRECRUITING04/merlin_146347992_30ca4fd0-bebc-4ed4-8d04-206e0ca41bf6-jumbo.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 683w,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/11/16/business/16FBRECRUITING04/merlin_146347992_30ca4fd0-bebc-4ed4-8d04-206e0ca41bf6-superJumbo.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 1366w&quot; sizes=&quot;((min-width: 600px) and (max-width: 1004px)) 84vw, (min-width: 1005px) 60vw, 100vw&quot; itemprop=&quot;url&quot; itemid=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/11/16/business/16FBRECRUITING04/merlin_146347992_30ca4fd0-bebc-4ed4-8d04-206e0ca41bf6-articleLarge.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;disable=upscale&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e1olku6u0&quot;&gt;Niky Arora, 19, a student at Berkeley, said she was skeptical about working for Facebook, which invited her to a recruiting event recently. “I’ve heard a lot of employees who work there don’t even use it,” she said.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e18m0s9i0&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1afaoz0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Max Whittaker for The New York Times&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-u5vfum StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ebnwsw e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The changing attitudes are happening beyond Facebook. Across Silicon Valley, tech recruiters said job applicants in general were asking more hard questions during interviews, wanting to know specifically &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/10/07/technology/tech-workers-ask-censorship-surveillance.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;what they would be asked to do&lt;/a&gt; at the company. Career coaches said they had tech employees reaching out to get tips on handling moral quandaries. The questions include “How do I avoid a project I disagree with?” and “How do I remind my bosses of the company mission statement?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m2ozyi&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-u5vfum StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ebnwsw e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“Employees are wising up to the fact that you can have a mission statement on your website, but when you’re looking at how the company creates new products or makes decisions, the correlation between the two is not so tightly aligned,” said David Chie, the head of Palo Alto Staffing, a tech job placement service in Silicon Valley. “Everyone’s having this conversation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ebnwsw e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;When engineers apply for jobs, they are also doing it differently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ebnwsw e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“They do a lot more due diligence,” said Heather Johnston, Bay Area district president for the tech job staffing agency Robert Half. “Before, candidates were like: ‘Oh, I don’t want to do team interviews. I want a one-and-done.’” Now, she added, job candidates “want to meet the team.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ebnwsw e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“They’re not just going to blindly take a company because of the name anymore,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ebnwsw e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Yet while many of the big tech companies have been hit by a change in public perception, Facebook seems uniquely tarred among young workers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ebnwsw e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“I’ve had a couple of clients recently say they’re not as enthusiastic about Facebook because they’re frustrated with what they see happening politically or socially,” said Paul Freiberger, president of Shimmering Careers, a career counseling group based in San Mateo, Calif. “It’s privacy and political news, and concern that it’s going to be hard to correct these things from inside.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ebnwsw e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Chad Herst, a leadership and career coach based in San Francisco since 2008, said that now, for the first time, he had clients who wanted to avoid working for big social media companies like Facebook or Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ebnwsw e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“They’re concerned about where democracy is going, that social media polarizes us, and they don’t want to be building it,” Mr. Herst said. “People really have been thinking about the mission of the company and what the companies are trying to achieve a little more.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m2ozyi&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-wrapper&quot; class=&quot;css-79elbk ehw59r11&quot;&gt;

&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-children&quot; class=&quot;css-1a48zt4 ehw59r111&quot;&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e1olku6u0&quot;&gt;Cal Hacks 5.0 drew about 2,200 software engineering students from around the country.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e18m0s9i0&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1afaoz0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Max Whittaker for The New York Times&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-u5vfum StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ebnwsw e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;He said one client, a midlevel executive at Facebook, wanted advice on how to shift her group’s work to encourage users to connect offline as well. But she found resistance internally to her efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m2ozyi&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-u5vfum StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ebnwsw e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“She was trying to figure out: ‘How do I politic this? How do I language this?’” Mr. Herst said. “And I was telling her to bring up some of Mark Zuckerberg’s past statements about connecting people.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ebnwsw e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;On the recent evening at the University of California, Berkeley, around 2,200 engineering students from around the country gathered for Cal Hacks 5.0 — a competition to build the best apps. The event spanned a weekend, so teenage competitors dragged pillows around with them. The hosts handed out 2,000 burritos as students registered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ebnwsw e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;It was also a hiring event. Recruiters from Facebook and Alphabet set up booths (free sunglasses from Facebook; $200 in credit to the Google Cloud platform from Alphabet).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ebnwsw e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;In the auditorium, the head of Y Combinator, a start-up incubator and investment firm, gave opening remarks, recommending that young people avoid jobs in big tech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ebnwsw e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“You get to program your life on a totally different scale,” said Michael Seibel, who leads Y Combinator. “The worst thing that can happen to you is you get a job at Google.” He called those jobs “$100,000-a-year welfare” — meaning, he said, that workers can get tethered to the paycheck and avoid taking risks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ebnwsw e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The event then segued to a word from the sponsor, Microsoft. Justin Garrett, a Microsoft recruiter who on his LinkedIn profile calls himself a senior technical evangelist, stepped onstage, laughing a little.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m2ozyi&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-wrapper&quot; class=&quot;css-79elbk ehw59r11&quot;&gt;

&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-children&quot; class=&quot;css-1a48zt4 ehw59r111&quot;&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e1olku6u0&quot;&gt;Calvin Nguyen, a student at San Jose State University, worked at the hackathon on building an app to minimize food waste.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e18m0s9i0&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1afaoz0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Max Whittaker for The New York Times&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-u5vfum StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ebnwsw e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“So, Michael’s a tough guy to follow, especially when you work for one of those big companies,” Mr. Garrett said. “He called it welfare. I like to call it tremendous opportunity.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ebnwsw e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Then students flooded into the stadium, which was filled with long tables of computers where they would stay and compete. In the middle of the scrum, three friends joked around. Caleb Thomas, 21, was gently made fun of because he had accepted an internship at Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ebnwsw e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“Come on, guys,” Mr. Thomas said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ebnwsw e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“These are the realities of how the business works,” said Samuel Resendez, 20, a computer science student at the University of Southern California.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ebnwsw e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;It turned out Mr. Resendez had interned at Facebook in the summer. Olivia Brown, 20, head of Stanford’s Computer Science and Social Good club and an iOS intern at Mozilla, called him out on it. “But you still worked at Facebook, too,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ebnwsw e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“Well, at least I signed before Cambridge Analytica,” Mr. Resendez said, a little bashful about the &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/03/17/us/politics/cambridge-analytica-trump-campaign.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;data privacy and election manipulation scandal that rocked the company this year&lt;/a&gt;. “Ninety-five percent of what Facebook is doing is delivering memes.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ebnwsw e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Ms. Brown said a lot of students criticize Facebook and talk about how they would not work there, but ultimately join. “Everyone cares about ethics in tech before they get a contract,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m2ozyi&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-u5vfum StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ebnwsw e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Ms. Brown said she thought that could change soon, though, as the social stigma of working for Facebook began outweighing the financial benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ebnwsw e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“Defense companies have had this reputation for a long time,” she said. “Social networks are just getting that.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m2ozyi&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 19:51:26 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>JumpCrisscross</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/15/technology/jobs-facebook-computer-science-students.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>‘I Don’t Really Want to Work for Facebook.’ So Say Some Computer Science Students.</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/11/16/business/16FBRECRUITING05/16FBRECRUITING05-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>A job at Facebook is plum. But at a recent university hackathon, some young engineers showed a changing attitude toward working at the social network.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/15/technology/jobs-facebook-computer-science-students.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Estimating the chances of something that hasn’t happened yet</title>
<link>https://www.johndcook.com/blog/2010/03/30/statistical-rule-of-three/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.johndcook.com/blog/2010/03/30/statistical-rule-of-three/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Suppose you’re proofreading a book. If you’ve read 20 pages and found 7 typos, you might reasonably estimate that the chances of a page having a typo are 7/20. But what if you’ve read 20 pages and found no typos. Are you willing to conclude that the chances of a page having a typo are 0/20, i.e. the book has absolutely no typos?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To take another example, suppose you are testing children for perfect pitch. You’ve tested 100 children so far and haven’t found any with perfect pitch. Do you conclude that children don’t have perfect pitch? You know that some do because you’ve heard of instances before. Your data suggest perfect pitch in children is at least rare. But how rare?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;rule of three&lt;/strong&gt; gives a quick and dirty way to estimate these kinds of probabilities. It says that if you’ve tested &lt;em&gt;N&lt;/em&gt; cases and haven’t found what you’re looking for, a reasonable estimate is that the probability is less than 3/&lt;em&gt;N&lt;/em&gt;. So in our proofreading example, if you haven’t found any typos in 20 pages, you could estimate that the probability of a page having a typo is less than 15%. In the perfect pitch example, you could conclude that fewer than 3% of children have perfect pitch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that the rule of three says that your probability estimate goes down in proportion to the number of cases you’ve studied. If you’d read 200 pages without finding a typo, your estimate would drop from 15% to 1.5%. But it doesn’t suddenly drop to zero. I imagine most people would harbor a suspicion that that there may be typos even though they haven’t seen any in the first few pages. But at some point they might say “I’ve read so many pages without finding any errors, there must not be any.” The situation is a little different with the perfect pitch example, however, because you may know before you start that the probability cannot be zero.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the sight of math makes you squeamish, you might want to stop reading now. Just remember that if you haven’t seen something happen in &lt;em&gt;N&lt;/em&gt; observations, a good estimate is that the chances of it happening are less than 3/&lt;em&gt;N&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What makes the rule of three work? Suppose the probability of what you’re looking for is &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt;. If we want a 95% confidence interval, we want to find the largest &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; so that the probability of no successes out of &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; trials is 0.05, i.e. we want to solve (1-&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;em&gt;&lt;sup&gt;n&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt; = 0.05 for &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt;. Taking logs of both sides, &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; log(1-&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt;) = log(0.05) ≈ -3. Since log(1-&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt;) is approximately –&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; for small values of &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt;, we have &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; ≈ 3/&lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The derivation above gives the frequentist perspective. I’ll now give the Bayesian derivation of the same result. Then you can say “&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; is probably less than 3/&lt;em&gt;N&lt;/em&gt;” in clear conscience since Bayesians are allowed to make such statements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suppose you start with a uniform prior on &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt;. The posterior distribution on &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; after having seen 0 successes and &lt;em&gt;N&lt;/em&gt; failures has a beta(1, &lt;em&gt;N&lt;/em&gt;+1) distribution. If you calculate the posterior probability of &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; being less than 3/&lt;em&gt;N&lt;/em&gt; you get an expression that approaches 1 – exp(-3) as &lt;em&gt;N&lt;/em&gt; gets large, and 1 – exp(-3) ≈ 0.95.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;http://sites.google.com/site/alessandrogentilini/regola-del-tre-in-statistica&quot;&gt;Italian&lt;/a&gt; translation of this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.johndcook.com/blog/bayesian-consulting/&quot; class=&quot;gtmbayes&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.johndcook.com/Bayes_consulting2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Click to learn more about Bayesian statistics consulting&quot; width=&quot;542&quot; height=&quot;451&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Related posts&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 19:38:37 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>devy</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.johndcook.com/blog/2010/03/30/statistical-rule-of-three/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>SpaceX just got FCC approval to launch 7,518 satellites</title>
<link>https://www.fastcompany.com/90268592/elon-musks-spacex-just-got-fcc-approval-to-launch-7518-satellites</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.fastcompany.com/90268592/elon-musks-spacex-just-got-fcc-approval-to-launch-7518-satellites</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;13.684931506849&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soon, SpaceX will have more satellites circling the earth than anyone else. The FCC just gave Elon Musk’s company permission to launch more than 7,000 satellites (or for fans of specificity, &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.fcc.gov/public/attachments/DOC-354775A1.pdf&quot;&gt;7,518 satellites&lt;/a&gt;) into space. The satellites will fill the night sky as part of the company’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fastcompany.com/40533738/spacex-falcon-9-launch&quot;&gt;Starlink program&lt;/a&gt;, which aims to provide satellite-based broadband internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;24.135245901639&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-11-15/elon-musk-s-spacex-wins-fcc-approval-to-launch-7-000-satellites&quot;&gt;According to &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, since there are currently fewer than 2,000 operating satellites, SpaceX’s new additions will dominate space. That will help the company create its “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fastcompany.com/90259755/report-elon-musk-fired-a-bunch-of-spacex-execs-in-starlink-shakeup&quot;&gt;constellation of satellites&lt;/a&gt;” to provide internet services to rural locations, but it will also create a lot of traffic in the stars. So much traffic that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fastcompany.com/40541918/critics-on-the-left-and-right-say-ajit-pais-fcc-is-hurting-poor-people&quot;&gt;FCC Chairman Ajit Pai&lt;/a&gt; had no choice but to reference the 2013 film &lt;em&gt;Gravity&lt;/em&gt; in which the world lost George Clooney due to space junk. To help fight a space junk traffic jam, while approving SpaceX’s applications, the agency also voted on a variety of space-related matters, including debris rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The FCC’s approval of the plan isn’t particularly surprising&lt;/strong&gt;. Back in March, it made SpaceX the first U.S.-based company to receive a license to construct, deploy, and operate its own satellite constellation. SpaceX has said it plans to begin launches next year, and soon we’ll all be able to wish upon a satellite (for faster internet).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-wrapper ad-wrapper--native_recommendationlink&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-wrapper--ad-unit-wrap&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;advertisement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 18:52:33 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>crunchlibrarian</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Elon Musk’s SpaceX just got FCC approval to launch 7,518 satellites</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.fastcompany.com/90268592/elon-musks-spacex-just-got-fcc-approval-to-launch-7518-satellites</og:url>
<og:description>Don’t wish on a star. Wish on a SpaceX satellite.</og:description>
<og:image>https://images.fastcompany.net/image/upload/w_1280,f_auto,q_auto,fl_lossy/wp-cms/uploads/2018/11/p-1-elon-muskand8217s-spacex-just-got-fcc-approval-to-launch-7518-satellites.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.fastcompany.com/90268592/elon-musks-spacex-just-got-fcc-approval-to-launch-7518-satellites</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Sleep Apnea Patients Rely on a CPAP Machine Hacker</title>
<link>https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/xwjd4w/im-possibly-alive-because-it-exists-why-sleep-apnea-patients-rely-on-a-cpap-machine-hacker</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/xwjd4w/im-possibly-alive-because-it-exists-why-sleep-apnea-patients-rely-on-a-cpap-machine-hacker</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Weakest Link is Motherboard's third annual theme week dedicated to the future of hacking and cybersecurity. &lt;a href=&quot;https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/topic/the-weakest-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Follow along&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Listen to Motherboard’s new hacking podcast, CYBER, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/cyber/id1441708044?mt=2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Christy Lynn was tired all the time, and, after months of trying to diagnose the problem, one of her doctors thought they’d figured out why.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I didn’t fit any of the descriptions for sleep apnea,” she told me on a phone call. “I’m a woman, I wasn’t overweight. No one would have thought to test me, except I was seeing a doctor who had a similar medical history.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lynn, who lives in rural Arizona, did an at-home oximetry test, which tests blood oxygen levels, and then a sleep study. She was diagnosed with a difficult-to-treat form of sleep apnea, a disorder in which patients suddenly stop breathing for periods of time while they sleep that most often affects overweight men. She was given a continuous positive airway pressure (CPAP) machine and face mask—which blows air down a patient’s windpipe to keep the airways open—and sent home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But a year-and-a-half and three sleep doctors later, her symptoms hadn’t improved. Her Apnoea-Hypopnea Index (AHI), which refers to the number of times she stopped breathing per night, was “horrible.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“None of the doctors could get my AHI down and none of them seemed particularly concerned about it, to be honest,” she said. She started Googling for help, and came across a forum called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cpaptalk.com/CPAP-Sleep-Apnea-Forum.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CPAPtalk.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the forum, users were talking about a piece of software called “SleepyHead.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The free, &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/sleepyhead/sleepyhead-code&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;open-source&lt;/a&gt;, and definitely not FDA-approved &lt;a href=&quot;https://sleepyhead.jedimark.net&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;piece of software&lt;/a&gt; is the product of thousands of hours of hacking and development by a lone Australian developer named Mark Watkins, who has helped thousands of sleep apnea patients take back control of their treatment from overburdened and underinvested doctors. The software gives patients access to the sleep data that is already being generated by their CPAP machines but generally remains inaccessible, hidden by proprietary data formats that can only be read by authorized users (doctors) on proprietary pieces of software that patients often can’t buy or download. SleepyHead and community-run forums like CPAPtalk.com and &lt;a href=&quot;http://apneaboard.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ApneaBoard.com&lt;/a&gt; have allowed patients to circumvent medical device manufacturers, who would prefer that the software not exist at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I cannot tell you enough how different my CPAP experience is with this software. It’s the difference between night and day,” Lynn said. “I’m possibly alive because it exists.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;*&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article__media&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://video-images.vice.com/_uncategorized/1542304334204-J9xkHx4.png?resize=320:*&quot; alt=&quot;1542304334204-J9xkHx4&quot; class=&quot;col-12-xs&quot; data-src=&quot;https://video-images.vice.com/_uncategorized/1542304334204-J9xkHx4.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Image: SleepyHead&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most modern CPAP machines create reams of data while they’re being used. They track things like average air pressure, AHI, average use per night, mask leak rates, “flow limitation index,” and other statistics about what the machine is doing and the patient’s sleep quality. Generally, the data is stored on an SD card, which a patient takes to their doctor once every six months (some new devices also transmit data wirelessly to an app; the data available on apps, patients told me, is rarely as thorough as what the machine is actually collecting.) This data can be used to alter a patient’s treatment; increasing or lowering pressure thresholds and other settings on the machine can lead to better outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But many doctors, several SleepyHead users told me, take a passing glance at the numbers and send patients on their way. Several &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.atsjournals.org/doi/full/10.1164/rccm.201508-1544ED&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;academic reviews&lt;/a&gt; of the industry have found that there is a shortage of sleep specialists, which means that few doctors can give patients the personalized care that many of them want; a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4582060/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;2015 paper by the American Academy of Sleep Medicine&lt;/a&gt; found a “substantial shortage of board-certified sleep medicine providers,” and noted that “parts of the United States are grossly underserved or not served at all.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thomas Penzel, a sleep physiologist who is the scientific lead of the European Sleep Research Society, told me in an email that he “believes any bright patient can do what they want”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“A patient might modify the pressure if they know what they’re doing. Some of our patients have modified pressure themselves,” he added. “If things go wrong, they may end up dead in their bed. This is their own risk. CPAP is not a toy but a medical treatment.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He agreed that most sleep apnea patients around the world are underserved: “Doctors don’t listen and don’t have time anywhere in the world.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Your doctor says bring in your chip or card, and they read it, but they don’t read it for diagnostics. They read it for insurance compliance to make sure you’re actually using it,” Steve Levine, a SleepyHead user from California, told me on the phone. “Everybody is trying to get you in and out the door, and take some profit from your pocket.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article__pull-quote&quot;&gt;&quot;I became increasingly disgusted at how the CPAP industry is using and abusing people&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some CPAP machines allow patients to see rudimentary data on the screens of the machines themselves, but very few machines actually give patients access to all the data that’s being collected. One popular CPAP manufacturer, ResMed, makes data analysis software called ResScan, which, because of federal law, is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.resmed.com/us/en/healthcare-professional/products/monitoring-and-data-management/resscan.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;only available to medical professionals&lt;/a&gt; or “on the order of a physician.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This walled-garden approach to sleep apnea treatment and CPAP user data has resulted in the creation of the DIY world of CPAP hacking and settings modification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much of the discussion at CPAPtalk.com and ApneaBoard.com, the latter of which has roughly 71,000 members, centers around SleepyHead, which decodes the data created by CPAP machines and allows ordinary patients to access it. The software decodes the data quite literally: Watkins has painstakingly hacked and cracked the proprietary data formats for each individual CPAP machine that the software supports. These data formats are intended to only be read by the manufacturers’ own software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article__media&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://video-images.vice.com/_uncategorized/1542304726085-Screen-Shot-2018-11-15-at-125808-PM.png?resize=320:*&quot; alt=&quot;1542304726085-Screen-Shot-2018-11-15-at-125808-PM&quot; class=&quot;col-12-xs&quot; data-src=&quot;https://video-images.vice.com/_uncategorized/1542304726085-Screen-Shot-2018-11-15-at-125808-PM.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Image: ApneaBoard&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“All machines have antitamper signing/checksumming built into the data formats, some more elaborate than others,” Watkins told me in a Facebook message. “Hacking the file formats is a complicated process that requires known data to compare against, this often means flipping settings in the machine menus or working of PDF reports generated from commercial software with known data sets, which have to first be begged for and collected from people with access to the machine and software.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watkins started the SleepyHead project seven years ago because he was interested in the “forbidden secrets” of his CPAP machine’s SD card. Since he first got started, SleepyHead has become a lifeline for the sleep apnea community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“As time progressed, I became increasingly disgusted at how the CPAP industry is using and abusing people, and it became apparent there was a serious need for a freely available, data focused, all-in-one CPAP analysis tool,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;*&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digital rights management and technical protection measures implemented to keep the owners of devices from accessing them have grown common across a wide swath of industries; the problem that CPAP users face is similar to one faced by farmers who &lt;a href=&quot;https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/xykkkd/why-american-farmers-are-hacking-their-tractors-with-ukrainian-firmware&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;want to repair their John Deere tractors&lt;/a&gt;, by people who &lt;a href=&quot;https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/43npdn/keurig-boycott-hannity-environment&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;own Keurig coffee machines&lt;/a&gt; that will only brew authorized coffee pods, and by &lt;a href=&quot;https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/xw9bwd/1201-exemptions-right-to-repair&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;independent electronics repair professionals&lt;/a&gt; who are increasingly locked out of &lt;a href=&quot;https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/kbjm8e/iphone-7-home-button-unreplaceable-repair-software-lock&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;iPhones&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/yw9qk7/macbook-pro-software-locks-prevent-independent-repair&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;MacBooks&lt;/a&gt;, servers, air conditioning systems, &lt;a href=&quot;https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/vbxk3b/appliance-companies-are-lobbying-against-right-to-repair&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;vacuum cleaners, and internet of things devices&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CPAP users like Watkins are part of a new push by patients to take control of their own data; activist Hugo Campos &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oro19-l5M8k&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;gave a TEDx talk in 2011&lt;/a&gt; about his fight to gain access to the data generated by his pacemaker, while a DIY group &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nightscout.info/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;called Nightscout&lt;/a&gt; has launched an unsanctioned app that breaks DRM in order to allow parents to remotely monitor their diabetic child’s glucose monitors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Medical device companies have generally not been very happy about this new DIY movement, but what Watkins is doing with SleepyHead &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; legal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article__media&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://video-images.vice.com/_uncategorized/1542304743877-Screen-Shot-2018-11-15-at-125412-PM.png?resize=320:*&quot; alt=&quot;1542304743877-Screen-Shot-2018-11-15-at-125412-PM&quot; class=&quot;col-12-xs&quot; data-src=&quot;https://video-images.vice.com/_uncategorized/1542304743877-Screen-Shot-2018-11-15-at-125412-PM.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Image: SleepyHead&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2015, Campos’s Coalition for Medical Device Researchers &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.copyright.gov/1201/2014/petitions/Berkman_Center_1201_Initial_Submission_2014.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;petitioned the Librarian of Congress&lt;/a&gt; and the US Copyright Office to create an exemption to the Digital Millennium Copyright Act—the most important law governing software copyright—that would allow patients to legally hack medical devices for security research and to gain access to the data that it generates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article__pull-quote&quot;&gt;The medical industry argued that &quot;patients directly accessing the data on their devices may not understand the format of the data or may misinterpret the data. Such data access rights can be exercised (and already are provided) through health care providers&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Campos “was tracking his Pacemaker data on a Google Spreadsheet—not an ideal patient care situation,” Andrew Sellars, who at the time was a lawyer at Harvard’s Berkman Center for Internet and Society and represented Campos, told me on the phone. “The pacemaker transmits data to a base station. His idea was to intercept that signal as it’s taken off the pacemaker in order to find out what his heart was doing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Medical device companies vehemently fought Campos and Sellars’s petition: “The medical device manufacturers took the position that the data is formatted in such a way that it’s protected, copyrighted information that’s protected by the DMCA,” Sellars, who is now director of the Boston University/MIT Technology &amp;amp; Cyberlaw Clinic, added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AdvaMed, a trade organization that lobbies on behalf of the medical device industry, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.copyright.gov/1201/2015/comments-032715/class%2027/AdvaMed_Class27_1201_2014.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;told the copyright office in a petition to block&lt;/a&gt; Campos’s request that “patients directly accessing the data on their devices may not understand the format of the data or may misinterpret the data. Such data access rights can be exercised (and already are provided) through health care providers having the appropriate tools and training to collect and protect patient data without compromising the safety and longevity of his or her device.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article__media&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://video-images.vice.com/_uncategorized/1542304854056-shutterstock_498393739.jpeg?resize=320:*&quot; alt=&quot;1542304854056-shutterstock_498393739&quot; class=&quot;col-12-xs&quot; data-src=&quot;https://video-images.vice.com/_uncategorized/1542304854056-shutterstock_498393739.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Image: Shutterstock&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The organization also argued that an exemption that legalized patient data access would put patients’ health and privacy at risk and could “accelerate battery drain.” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.copyright.gov/1201/2015/comments-032715/class%2027/LifeScience_Alley_Class27_1201_2014.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Medical Alley Association&lt;/a&gt;—another medical device manufacturer trade group—argued that “allowing this exemption will directly interfere with the doctor-patient relationship—in effect inducing patients to make decisions without the support of their doctor.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article__pull-quote&quot;&gt;&quot;Apnea Board freely distributes CPAP Clinician Manuals and publicizes the ‘secrets’ of these CPAP machines to our members so they can educate themselves and take control of their own sleep apnea therapy if they so choose&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The FDA, meanwhile, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.copyright.gov/1201/2015/USCO-letters/FDA_Letter_to_USCO_re_1201.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;told the Copyright Office&lt;/a&gt; at the time that any device that was user-modified could not be marketed or resold without FDA approval, and that if any modified machine hurt a patient, the agency could have trouble determining whether it was the device manufacturer’s fault or the software modifier’s fault. But ultimately, the FDA did not try to stop the exemption from going through: “FDA recommends that the final rule explain that nothing in the rule will affect the regulation of products that fall within the jurisdiction of other federal agencies.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a major win for consumers, the Librarian of Congress &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.copyright.gov/fedreg/2015/80fr65944.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;granted the exemption&lt;/a&gt;, which legalized not only Campos’s attempts to gain access to his pacemaker data, but also the type of hacking that Watkins is doing with SleepyHead. Earlier this year, the exemption was renewed, and no medical device manufacturers (nor anyone else) attempted to stop it. AdvaMed declined to comment for this article. Medical Alley did not respond to a request for comment in time for publication; none of the CPAP manufacturers I contacted responded to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;*&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But just because hacking CPAP machines to gain access to the data is now &lt;em&gt;legal&lt;/em&gt; doesn’t mean that medical device manufacturers have to make it easy. Watkins says that, without leaked documentation, hacking a new data format (and most manufacturers have their own formats) can take hundreds of hours. He uses a hexadecimal editor called Synalize It! to analyze the data formats and reverse engineer data against verified data that is shared with Watkins from friendly insiders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s been my experience that getting documentation out of manufacturers without a NDA is like getting blood out of stone,” Watkins said. “Most [manufacturers] have completely ignored my emails, some have even expressed displeasure at my efforts.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article__media&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://video-images.vice.com/_uncategorized/1542304762647-Screen-Shot-2018-11-15-at-125824-PM.png?resize=320:*&quot; alt=&quot;1542304762647-Screen-Shot-2018-11-15-at-125824-PM&quot; class=&quot;col-12-xs&quot; data-src=&quot;https://video-images.vice.com/_uncategorized/1542304762647-Screen-Shot-2018-11-15-at-125824-PM.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Image: ApneaBoard&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CPAP patients regularly ask Watkins to hack new machines for them, and it’s gotten to the point where Watkins has had to basically stop development of the core software in order to spend time supporting new machines. Though he has done most of the software development and hacking, others in the community have helped with specific projects, and there are occasionally group hacking efforts to figure out the data format for a particularly difficult machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Contec oximeters were fun, the ‘Protocol 7’ hack was an all-nighter team effort by myself, and a couple of other hackers supplying me with serial port captures, helping break protocols with python code, and testing the importer I wrote and tweaked it in SleepyHead,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thousands of hours of development work has been tough on Watkins—he said he regularly suffers from spells of burnout, and development on SleepyHead has gone in fits and starts depending on his own health and job situation (he is currently looking for paid development work.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I've been on the sidelines away from the workforce as a stay at home dad, which while it has been beneficial to the SleepyHead project and my daughter, it hasn't exactly been so beneficial for my family's long term wellbeing,” he said. “Over the past seven years I've been mostly supported by my wife who's been patient with me and supportive of my project activity, but now my health has improved a lot and my daughter is old enough, I've really got no choice but to put family responsibilities ahead and return to work. Until I get into a rhythm with that and find some suitable paid work that fits my circumstances, I'll have to pause SleepyHead development for a while.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said his dream would be to create an open-source, easily repairable, DRM-free CPAP machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I'm pleased others have found it genuinely helpful, their words of encouragement, donations, data samples, and willingness for patience despite slow development have helped keep me motivated,” he said. “I'm proud of my accomplishments so far, despite it being difficult doing this without any kind of commercial backing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article__media&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://video-images.vice.com/_uncategorized/1542304872174-shutterstock_537317164.jpeg?resize=320:*&quot; alt=&quot;1542304872174-shutterstock_537317164&quot; class=&quot;col-12-xs&quot; data-src=&quot;https://video-images.vice.com/_uncategorized/1542304872174-shutterstock_537317164.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Image: Shutterstock&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a new machine is hacked and added to SleepyHead’s list of supported machines, it’s documented in a Facebook group and on CPAPtalk and Apnea Board, which also play a crucial role for patients: The userbase on those forums helps new patients make sense of the data that SleepyHead is spitting out. It also helps patients decide what tweaks to make to their treatment and has information about how to actually make those changes on the machines (treatment modification menus are often hidden and are supposed to be accessed only by doctors.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Apnea Board’s primary goal is to promote ‘patient empowerment’ (where the patient takes a more active role in their own sleep apnea treatment),” SuperSleeper, who founded the forum in 2004, told me in a private forum message. “Quite simply, the sleep apnea industry as a whole is overwhelmed and cannot provide the one-on-one follow-up service that many CPAP users need. They're very good at creating ‘billable events’ (for a sleep study, a doctor's visit, or the sale of a CPAP machine and supplies), but they have little time and not enough of a financial incentive to help with ongoing detailed questions and problems that many CPAP users have.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;article__pull-quote&quot;&gt;&quot;I would be devastated if I lost the software. If it quit working, I don’t know what I would do.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apnea Board has become a bastion of information and self-taught sleep apnea experts; the forum features a private section in which users can download user manuals and, in some cases, leaked manuals that are intended for doctors. These manuals teach users how to get into the “clinician menu” where they’re able to modify their CPAP’s settings to tailor their treatment in coordination with what SleepyHead is telling them about their treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Apnea Board freely distributes CPAP Clinician Manuals and publicizes the ‘secrets’ of these CPAP machines to our members so they can educate themselves and take control of their own sleep apnea therapy if they so choose,” SuperSleeper told me. “Once one knows these ‘secrets,’ it's relatively easy to get into and program the ‘Clinician Menu’ of most CPAP machines, although increasingly, manufacturers are making it more difficult for patients to do that, and a bit of ‘hacking’ might become necessary with some machines.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both Levine and Lynn say that the combination of SleepyHead and the forums has completely changed their lives and their treatments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“When you’re first diagnosed, you feel alone,” Levine said. “On the forum, people say ‘hey, this is what happened to me last night, and this is what I did. What do you recommend?’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lynn said that, when her doctors analyzed her numbers, they were looking at an average of her last six months, and not individual nights that may have been harder than others: “They’re not drilling down to where your problems are happening.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I can see the numbers every day on SleepyHead and I can tweak my settings,” she said. “I’ve been upping my exhale pressure to get my numbers down. I feel a lot better than I did when I was first diagnosed. I have more energy, I sleep better.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several people with sleep apnea I spoke to said that any concern that altering their treatment is dangerous is misplaced; many said they believe it’s fear-mongering by doctors and device manufacturers, and all of them stressed that they would never make modifications without fully understanding how the machines work and what the data is telling them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lynn said that treating herself is the only option that’s ever worked, and it’s the only option she has.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I’m 62 years old and I don’t have health insurance because I can’t afford it and I’m self employed,” she said. “I would be devastated if I lost the software. If it quit working, I don’t know what I would do.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 18:17:20 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>runesoerensen</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Why Sleep Apnea Patients Rely on a CPAP Machine Hacker</og:title>
<og:image>https://video-images.vice.com/articles/5bedaf10772de20006344379/lede/1542303561210-cpap-machines.png?crop=1xw:1xh;center,center&amp;resize=1200:*</og:image>
<og:url>https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/xwjd4w/im-possibly-alive-because-it-exists-why-sleep-apnea-patients-rely-on-a-cpap-machine-hacker</og:url>
<og:description>An Australian hacker has spent thousands of hours hacking the DRM that medical device manufacturers put on CPAP machines to create a free tool that lets patients modify their treatment.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/xwjd4w/im-possibly-alive-because-it-exists-why-sleep-apnea-patients-rely-on-a-cpap-machine-hacker</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Airtable raises $100M at a $1.1B valuation</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2018/11/15/airtable-maker-of-a-coding-platform-for-non-techies-raises-100m-at-a-1-1b-valuation/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2018/11/15/airtable-maker-of-a-coding-platform-for-non-techies-raises-100m-at-a-1-1b-valuation/</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot;&gt;If &lt;a href=&quot;https://customerworld.typepad.com/swami_weblog/2006/11/data_is_the_new.html&quot;&gt;data is the new oil&lt;/a&gt;, you might think of apps are the cars that need it to move. Now, a startup that has built a platform to let everyone — not just those with technical expertise — make and drive their own “cars” has raised a significant round of funding to grow its business. &lt;a href=&quot;http://Airtable.com&quot;&gt;Airtable&lt;/a&gt; — which uses a simple interface built on spreadsheets and other tools familiar to knowledge workers as a frontend to produce apps and other web-based experiences — has raised $100 million in funding to expand its business with more talent and offices outside the US. Along with the funding, the company has now catapulted to a $1.1 billion valuation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Catapult is the key word here: according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://my.pitchbook.com/profile/100744-84/company/profile#board-members&quot;&gt;PitchBook&lt;/a&gt; the company was only valued at $152 million in its last round — eight months ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/airtable&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;airtable&quot;&gt;Airtable’s&lt;/a&gt; tools are now in use by some 80,000 businesses today, the company said, representing a real growth spurt. To put that into some context, when the company &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/15/airtable-raises-52m-to-give-non-coders-tools-to-build-complex-software/&quot;&gt;raised $52 million&lt;/a&gt; eight months ago, it said it had only &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20180315005387/en/Airtable-Raises-52-Million-Launches-Airtable-Blocks&quot;&gt;30,000 customers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This latest round — a Series C — was led by Josh Kushner at Thrive Capital, Peter Fenton at Benchmark, and Philippe and Thomas Laffont at Coatue Management. Delphine Arnault, Emily Weiss, Alexa Von Tobel, Sarah Smith, Dan Rose, and previous investors CRV and Caffeinated Capital also participated — bringing the total raised by Airtable to $170 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Howie Liu, the CEO who co-founded Airtable with Emmett Nicholas (now CTO) and Andrew Ofstad, said that the initial idea for the product came out of their own experience. The tech world had already identified that many tools for building apps and other products were potentially too technical for the vast majority of knowledge workers in the tech industry (who might not have coding experience), but the solutions in the market for making things like apps were still “too expensive and complicated to use.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The vision was to democratise the value proposition,” he said. A database, the founders decided, “in its most flexible form, can be customised to what you need, and that would be better than using someone else’s existing database model.”&lt;/p&gt;
[gallery ids=&quot;1747138,1747139,1747140,1747142,1747143&quot;]
&lt;p&gt;Airtable is not the only company that has identified the problem and tried to solve it by building powerful macros under the hood of otherwise standard-looking database interfaces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/05/16/dashdash-a-platform-to-create-web-apps-using-only-spreadsheet-skills-nabs-8m-led-by-accel/&quot;&gt;DashDash&lt;/a&gt; is building a similar concept out of Europe focused specifically on spreadsheets, and we’re even seeing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hanhaa.com/microsoft-build-2018/&quot;&gt;Microsoft and partners&lt;/a&gt; building more functionality into the world’s leading spreadsheet provider, Excel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Indeed, that’s not seen as stiff competition, but a sign for Airtable’s investors of just how much opportunity there is in the space. “&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;il&quot;&gt;Airtable&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;has established itself as the leader in what will become a very large market,” Josh Kushner, managing partner at Thrive Capital, said in a statement.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the important aspects of Airtable is its Slack-like approach to the task of using its platform to build things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company has a platform called Blocks that not only lets its users bring in data from a number of sources, but also to select a number of different kinds of outputs for how and where would like the data to be used, whether it is in a marketing campaign across text messaging, an AI-based bot, or a VR experience. Liu confirmed for me that for now Excel is not one of its integration partners, for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another notable point is that Airtable is yet another example of how the most promising startups are racking up funding in rapid rounds at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just yesterday, no less than four different startups — &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/11/14/servicetitan-raises-165m-for-its-home-services-software-now-valued-at-1-65b/&quot;&gt;Service Titan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/11/14/software-robot-startup-uipath-expands-series-c-to-265m-at-a-3b-valuation/&quot;&gt;UiPath&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/11/14/nikola-trucking/&quot;&gt;Nikola&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/11/14/sam-nabs-12m-for-cybersecurity-aimed-at-home-routers-and-devices-connected-to-them/&quot;&gt;SAM&lt;/a&gt; — announced rounds of funding coming on the heels of fundraising mere months earlier. It’s a sign of how the market is very hot at the moment: VCs and other investment firms have raised fuelled by large sums of cash that now need to be put to use, and they are all looking for strong bets to do just that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast-growing startups in areas that are on the rise present safe harbours to these investors, and with tens and hundreds of billions of dollars at these funds still in play, we’ll probably continue to witness this funding trend for some time to come.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 16:56:24 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kbyatnal</dc:creator>
<og:title>Airtable, maker of a coding platform for non-techies, raises $100M at a $1.1B valuation</og:title>
<og:description>If data is the new oil, you might think of apps are the cars that need it to move. Now, a startup that has built a platform to let everyone — not just those with technical expertise — make and drive their own “cars” has raised a significant round of funding to grow its busin…</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/page-designer.png?w=628</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2018/11/15/airtable-maker-of-a-coding-platform-for-non-techies-raises-100m-at-a-1-1b-valuation/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2018/11/15/airtable-maker-of-a-coding-platform-for-non-techies-raises-100m-at-a-1-1b-valuation/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Krisp.ai – Mute background noise during your calls</title>
<link>https://krisp.ai/index.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://krisp.ai/index.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;advantage-container&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;flex flex-align-items-center flex-justify-center icon&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://krisp.ai/images-new/advantage-privacy-icon.svg&quot; alt=&quot;More Privacy&quot; width=&quot;50px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;headline&quot;&gt;More Privacy in Calls&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take calls from wherever you want without being embarrassed for the crying baby noise or airport announcement in the background. No one will know where you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;advantage-container&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;flex flex-align-items-center flex-justify-center icon&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://krisp.ai/images-new/advantage-comfort-icon.svg&quot; alt=&quot;More Comfort&quot; width=&quot;70px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;headline&quot;&gt;Seamless Calls&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When network conditions are bad our voice chops out and sounds annoying. With Krisp you can take calls from anywhere you want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;advantage-container&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;flex flex-align-items-center flex-justify-center icon&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://krisp.ai/images-new/advantage-gets-better-icon.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Gets Better&quot; width=&quot;50px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;headline&quot;&gt;Better Over Time&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like wine Krisp gets better over time as it keeps adapting to your voice. The more Krisp adapts to your voice the better it gets suited to filter out other voices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 16:41:23 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>nyxtom</dc:creator>
<og:title>Mute Background Noise</og:title>
<og:description>Take calls from wherever you want without being embarassed for a background noise.</og:description>
<og:image>img/meta-sm-image.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>https://krisp.ai/</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://krisp.ai/index.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Facebook reportedly discredited critics by linking them to George Soros</title>
<link>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2018/nov/14/facebook-george-soros-pr-firm-discredit-critics-crisis</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2018/nov/14/facebook-george-soros-pr-firm-discredit-critics-crisis</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Facebook hired a PR firm that attempted to discredit the company’s critics by claiming they were agents of the billionaire George Soros, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/14/technology/facebook-data-russia-election-racism.html?action=click&amp;amp;module=Top%20Stories&amp;amp;pgtype=Homepage&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;New York Times&lt;/a&gt; reported on Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soros is a Jewish philanthropist who is the frequent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2018/oct/24/george-soros-antisemitism-bomb-attacks&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;subject of antisemitic conspiracy theories&lt;/a&gt;. At the same time, the social media company urged the Anti-Defamation League to object to a cartoon used by anti-Facebook protesters over its resemblance to antisemitic tropes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;News of Facebook’s aggressive attempts to undermine critics came in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/14/technology/facebook-data-russia-election-racism.html?action=click&amp;amp;module=Top%20Stories&amp;amp;pgtype=Homepage&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;damning&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/14/technology/facebook-data-russia-election-racism.html?action=click&amp;amp;module=Top%20Stories&amp;amp;pgtype=Homepage&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; by the New York Times, detailing how Facebook executives have struggled to manage the numerous and severe challenges confronting the company, all while lashing out at critics and perceived enemies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;element element-rich-link element--thumbnail element-rich-link--not-upgraded&quot; data-component=&quot;rich-link&quot; data-link-name=&quot;rich-link-1 | 1&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rashad Robinson, the executive director of one of the groups targeted by the PR campaign, Color of Change, called the antisemitic smear “outrageous and concerning”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amid growing pressure from lawmakers over its role in Russian interference in the 2016 presidential election, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/facebook&quot; data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; increasingly turned to Definers Public Affairs, a Washington DC based political consultancy founded by Republican operatives and specializing in opposition research, according to the report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of Definers’ tactics was to publish dozens of negative articles about other tech companies, including Google and Apple, in order to try to distract attention from Facebook’s public relations woes. Definers published the content on NTKNetwork.com, a website that looks like a news site but is actually run by the PR firm. The narratives pushed on NTK Network were often picked up by conservative sites such as Breitbart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another tactic was to cast Soros as the driving force behind groups critical of Facebook. The firm circulated a research document connecting Soros to “a broad anti-Facebook movement”, the Times reported, and pressed reporters to look into financial links between Soros and groups such as Freedom from Facebook and Color of Change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soros, who was born in Hungary in 1930 and made a vast fortune as an investor, is a major funder of liberal and pro-democratic causes. He has long been the target of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2018/oct/24/george-soros-antisemitism-bomb-attacks&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;antisemitic attacks from the rightwing fringes&lt;/a&gt;, but such conspiracy mongering has been increasingly adopted by mainstream Republicans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The anti-Soros drumbeat reached something of a fever pitch in the weeks before the midterm elections, as conservative politicians and news outlets advanced &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2018/oct/19/trump-migrant-caravan-mexico-border-democrat-blame-no-evidence&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;baseless allegations&lt;/a&gt; that he was behind a caravan of Central American migrants traveling through Mexico. Soros was one of the targets of a rash of mail bombs that were sent to critics of Donald Trump in October.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;u-responsive-ratio&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;gu-image&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; alt=&quot;George Soros has been the frequent target of antisemitic conspiracy theories.&quot; src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/9606bcd60831fe29cf2a71d533af5ca597023b01/0_267_4000_2400/master/4000.jpg?width=300&amp;amp;quality=85&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=51f2a82542fdc3e1efc13edfc1d4d4c6&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

George Soros has been the frequent target of antisemitic conspiracy theories. Photograph: Bloomberg/Bloomberg via Getty Images
&lt;p&gt;Joe Gabriel Simonson, a reporter for the rightwing news site the Daily Caller, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/SaysSimonson/status/1062824861884653568&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;tweeted&lt;/a&gt; on Wednesday that he had been urged to include “bring up Soros/‘Soros tactics’” in an article about Facebook earlier this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The PR guy did keep bringing up Soros,” Simonson wrote. “This was like 6 months ago too so it was even odder.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robinson, whose organization has run online &lt;a href=&quot;https://act.colorofchange.org/sign/facebook_audit?source=coc_main_website&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;campaigns criticizing Facebook&lt;/a&gt; over racial discrimination in housing ads, privacy and surveillance, racist hate speech, and other issues, said he was deeply troubled by the report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This narrative has really dangerous antisemitic undertones about Jewish people controlling the world,” Robinson told the Guardian by phone. “It’s also deeply anti-black – the idea that our strategies, our ideas, our vision are somehow built off some puppet master … That Facebook would employ a rightwing firm to say that is deeply troubling.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Color of Change is a not-for-profit civil rights organization. It receives some money from Soros, Robinson said, in addition to many other funders, including Facebook co-founder Dustin Moskovitz’s foundation, the Open Philanthropy Project. Robinson also said that over the past year, he has been asked numerous times by journalists about funding from Soros.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“No one at the end of a call says, ‘Are you funded by the Ford Foundation?’” Robinson said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook did not respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soros has been openly critical of Facebook and Google. “The internet monopolies have neither the will nor the inclination to protect society against the consequences of their actions,” he &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/business/2018/jan/25/george-soros-facebook-and-google-are-a-menace-to-society&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;said in a speech&lt;/a&gt; at the World Economic Forum in Davos in January. “That turns them into a menace and it falls to the regulatory authorities to protect society against them.”&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 16:12:48 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>nsedlet</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://www.theguardian.com/technology/2018/nov/14/facebook-george-soros-pr-firm-discredit-critics-crisis</og:url>
<og:description>Facing a string of crises, Facebook hired a PR firm to push conspiracy theories about the billionaire, the New York Times reports</og:description>
<og:image>https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/6e3d18224580fa0df8f40eab30e94c8f12da34de/0_104_3500_2101/master/3500.jpg?width=1200&amp;height=630&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;overlay-align=bottom%2Cleft&amp;overlay-width=100p&amp;overlay-base64=L2ltZy9zdGF0aWMvb3ZlcmxheXMvdGctZGVmYXVsdC5wbmc&amp;s=cc8dac8cad59c6926ffb6a059ae71b86</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Facebook reportedly discredited critics by linking them to George Soros</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2018/nov/14/facebook-george-soros-pr-firm-discredit-critics-crisis</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A cheaper, smaller Raspberry Pi 3 is now available</title>
<link>https://www.engadget.com/2018/11/15/a-cheaper-smaller-raspberry-pi-3-is-now-available/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.engadget.com/2018/11/15/a-cheaper-smaller-raspberry-pi-3-is-now-available/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The new board incorporates most of the improvements made to its B+ brother, taking it down to a lower price point ($25/£23) and shrinking the board down to 65x56mm, the size of a HAT (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/introducing-raspberry-pi-hats/&quot;&gt;hardware attached on top&lt;/a&gt;), an add-on board. The A+ features a 1.4GHz 64-bit quad-core ARM Cortex-A53 CPU, 512MB LPDDR2 SDRAM, dual-band 802.11ac wireless LAN and Bluetooth 4.2/BLE, plus improved USB mass storage boosting and thermal management. Plus, like its sibling, the whole board is certified as a radio module under &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.engadget.com/2017/12/26/fcc-approves-first-wireless-power-at-a-distance-charging-syste/&quot;&gt;FCC rules&lt;/a&gt;, which will significantly reduce the cost of conformance testing Raspberry Pi–based products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They're smart enhancements, but ultimately the board is a pared-back version of its predecessors, and a lower price tag will make it -- and the Raspberry Pi Foundation ethos of promoting computer science in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.engadget.com/2018/03/26/raspberry-pi-projects/&quot;&gt;schools and developing countries&lt;/a&gt; -- more accessible to all. The launch marks the end of the 3+ platform. As the company explains in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/new-product-raspberry-pi-3-model-a/&quot;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;, whatever it does next will be less of an evolution as it explores new core silicon on a new process node with new memory technology. &quot;So 3A+ is about closing things out in style,&quot; it says, &quot;answering one of our most frequent customer requests, and clearing the decks so we can start to think seriously about what comes next.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;t-meta c-gray-4&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Presenter: Dana Wollman&lt;br/&gt;Script: Michael Morris&lt;br/&gt;Script Editor: Dana Wollman&lt;br/&gt;Camera: Kiel Perez&lt;br/&gt;Editor: Chris Schodt&lt;br/&gt;Producer: Michael Morris&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 14:59:16 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>gmiller123456</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.engadget.com/2018/11/15/a-cheaper-smaller-raspberry-pi-3-is-now-available/</og:url>
<og:title>A cheaper, smaller Raspberry Pi 3 is now available</og:title>
<og:description>The enhanced features of the Raspberry Pi 3B+ in a smaller form and smaller price.</og:description>
<og:image>https://o.aolcdn.com/images/dims?resize=1200%2C630&amp;crop=1200%2C630%2C0%2C0&amp;quality=80&amp;image_uri=https%3A%2F%2Fimg.vidible.tv%2Fprod%2F2018-11%2F15%2F5beddd2b007d0c451d3d8bf0%2F5beddd81a00f30563c248762_o_U_v1.jpg&amp;client=amp-blogside-v2&amp;signature=65d33833bf933522451f8c587ffaba3f34df5569</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.engadget.com/2018/11/15/a-cheaper-smaller-raspberry-pi-3-is-now-available/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>