<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Sharrows, the bicycle infrastructure that doesn’t work and nobody wants</title>
<link>https://macwright.com/2020/12/04/sharrows.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://macwright.com/2020/12/04/sharrows.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;San Francisco was poised to make a big improvement in its central transit system: the &lt;a href=&quot;http://bettermarketstreetsf.org/index.html&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Better Market Street&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; plan. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Market_Street_(San_Francisco)&quot;&gt;Market Street&lt;/a&gt; is one of the major transit arteries of the city, the route that people ride to commute from the Mission and the Haight to downtown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s also a high-injury corridor, and the city aimed to fix that by creating a grade-separated bike lane and lots of new and improved infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Better market plan&quot; src=&quot;https://macwright.com/images/2020-12-04-sharrows-better-market-plan.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After years of community input and design, the plan was to introduce a separate lane for bikes, sidewalk improvements, separated lanes for buses, and more. It was pretty inspiring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Post-pandemic revised plan&quot; src=&quot;https://macwright.com/images/2020-12-04-sharrows-post-pandemic-revised-plan.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the budget collapse caused by COVID-19 scaled back the project radically, and now we’re considering sharrows instead of separated bicycle lanes. The plan includes what you see above: a double-wide lane where bicyclists perilously “share the road” with taxis, delivery trucks, and city vehicles. It’s what we call &lt;a href=&quot;https://bummermarketstreet.com/&quot;&gt;Bummer Market Street&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I decided to look into the main anti-feature of this plan for cyclists: the sharrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-a-sharrow&quot;&gt;What’s a sharrow?&lt;/h2&gt;
Sharrow symbols from the MUTCD, Sacramento study, SF Study, and Florida study
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sharrow&lt;/em&gt; is a portmanteau of “shared” and “arrow.” It’s a particular symbol that combines a bicycle icon with an arrow or house icon. Initially, the bicycle was &lt;em&gt;inside&lt;/em&gt; the arrow, like it was in a little house, but recently it’s next to the arrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sharrow symbols are painted on streets or applied with thermoplastic decals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of a sharrow is to &lt;em&gt;encourage good bicyclist and driver behavior&lt;/em&gt;. Sharrows have no legal significance. They encourage cyclists to take the lane, but cyclists are permitted to do that anyway, on any street. Sharrows are supposed to make motorists aware of cyclists. When drivers kill people in sharrows, there aren’t any additional consequences. The consequences for hitting people with cars are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2013/11/10/opinion/sunday/is-it-ok-to-kill-cyclists.html&quot;&gt;minimal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Denver sharrow&quot; src=&quot;https://macwright.com/images/2020-12-04-sharrows-denver-sharrow.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/jessicajuriga/5066431139&quot;&gt;A sharrow in Denver, Colorado / photo by Jess J&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;James Mackay invented the sharrow in 1993 in Denver, in hopes that it would legitimize bicycles on the road, encourage cyclists to take the center of the lane, and reduce wrong-way cycling:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was hoping the shared lane marking would legitimize the presence of bicyclists, reinforce the correct direction of travel and assign lane position, including the correct approach to an intersection and fill an intermediate niche where typical bike lane markings might not necessarily fit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;4.983606557377&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I was hoping it overall would provide a step in the right direction towards legitimizing the presence of bicycling and reinforcing bicycle usage. - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thebicyclestory.com/2016/03/episode-4-a-brief-history-of-the-american-sharrow/&quot;&gt;The Bicycle Story: James Mackay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-are-sharrows-supposed-to-do&quot;&gt;What are sharrows supposed to do?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a really important question, because the answer isn’t simply “to protect people.” San Francisco and many other cities have versions of Vision Zero, the idea that traffic deaths should be reduced to zero.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sharrows aren’t a general-purpose tool: their applicability and goal is quite specific.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mutcd.fhwa.dot.gov/htm/2009r1r2/part9/part9c.htm&quot;&gt;According to the MUTCD&lt;/a&gt;, sharrows may be used to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Assist bicyclists with lateral positioning in a shared lane with on-street parallel parking in order to reduce the chance of a bicyclist’s impacting the open door of a parked vehicle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assist bicyclists with lateral positioning in lanes that are too narrow for a motor vehicle and a bicycle to travel side by side within the same traffic lane.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alert road users of the lateral location bicylists are likely to occupy within the traveled way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encourage safe passing of bicyclists by motorists, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduce the incidence of wrong-way bicycling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;The purpose of sharrows is thus pretty tied to the problem of &lt;em&gt;dooring&lt;/em&gt;, in which drivers don’t look out of their rear-view window before swinging open their doors. Behavioral solutions to dooring, like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dooring#Dutch_Reach&quot;&gt;Dutch Reach&lt;/a&gt;, haven’t caught on in America because it’s America.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;A sharrow in Oakland, California&quot; src=&quot;https://macwright.com/images/2020-12-04-sharrows-a-sharrow-in-oakland-california.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/walkingsf/4920881091&quot;&gt;A sharrow in Oakland, California / photo by Eric Fischer&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://nacto.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/Shared-Lane-Markings-When-and-Where-to-Use-Them.pdf&quot;&gt;SFMTA&lt;/a&gt; proposed additional use-cases for sharrows: Hills, Narrow Streets, Discontinued Bike Lane due to Roadway Narrowing, Discontinued Bike Lane for Right Turn Lane, Lane Drop for Right Turn Only Lane, Double Turn Lanes, Double Turn Lanes with Bike Box, Route Finding, Roundabouts or Traffic Circles, Along Separated Bikeways, and Space for Only One Bike Lane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None of this describes the Market Street plan, which would be a double-sharrow in a scenario with no on-street parking. The SFTMA also advises that sharrows are not meant to replace bike lanes, and in this case they are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;does-anyone-want-sharrows&quot;&gt;Does anyone want sharrows?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sharrows is are tools for improving combined car traffic and bicycle traffic. It’s apparent from all data that bicyclists do not want car traffic near them.&lt;/p&gt;
Separate bike lanes from car traﬃcRepairing potholesLess automobile traﬃcMore bike paths and trails oﬀ-streetMore secure indoor parkingBetter education for motorists0%20%40%60%80%
&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;a href=&quot;https://nacto.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/City-of-Toronto-Cycling-Study-Tracking-Report-1999-and-2009.pdf&quot;&gt;2009 City of Toronto study&lt;/a&gt;, 77% of bicyclists said that to “separate bike lanes from car traffic” would improve cycling “a great deal”, more than any other change. Columbus, Ohio asked in 2008 what infrastructure cyclists would want to see, and 85% of respondents referred to bicycle lanes, with only 76% seeing a benefit to shared-use paths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bicycle advocacy organizations also don’t want sharrows: the new Better Market Street plans were &lt;a href=&quot;https://sfbike.org/news/the-fights-not-over-for-a-better-market-street/&quot;&gt;immediately panned by the SF Bicycle Coalition&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;do-sharrows-inform-drivers-of-the-presence-of-bicyclists&quot;&gt;Do sharrows inform drivers of the presence of bicyclists?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a few sources of data here. Let’s look at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://nacto.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/San-Franciscos-Shared-Lane-Pavement-Markings-Improving-Bicycle-Safety.pdf&quot;&gt;San Francisco Shared Lane Marking Study&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The majority of the drivers surveyed claimed not to notice the markings. Since the sample size of drivers was so small, the results do not provide conclusive findings. -p13&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do drivers understand the markings?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of the motorists that responded, two out of the seven that noticed the markings understood that the marking indicate that they should allow more room for cyclists. p14&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a study from Brookline, MA. Do drivers notice markings there?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of the motorists surveyed, only 21% noticed the markings and were at least 70% confident that the markings indicated a preferred zone for bicycling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Casual observations from Warren Vermont:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Casual verbal survey of approximately 200 local citizens and 50 bicyclists led to conclusion that bicyclists felt the symbols were too small to be effective and local drivers rarely noticed them. The Vermont DOT decided to not encourage their use, to not replace them, and to not include them in future plans&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do cyclists understand the symbols? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Xp1gN8xsz3o&quot;&gt;Here’s a news report about how they don’t&lt;/a&gt;. The city of Fremont had to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-qg6cpG7Zeg&quot;&gt;publish a video about how to use sharrows&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;do-sharrows-make-streets-safer&quot;&gt;Do sharrows make streets safer?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A striking commonality in the sharrow research is that safety is not clearly measured. Proxies to safety are measured: cyclists riding in the center of the lane, in the right direction, not on sidewalks, and sometimes the distance from cars to bikes. The Texas study does an impressive amount of statistical reasoning about passing events &amp;amp; horizontal positioning on the street. But actual safety is not rigorously measured.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one study that directly studies the effectiveness of bicycle sharrows &lt;em&gt;for safety&lt;/em&gt; is called &lt;a href=&quot;https://trid.trb.org/view/1393928&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Relative (In)Effectiveness of Bicycle Sharrows on Safety Outcomes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a quick read, but the killer line is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results suggest that not only are sharrows not as safe as bike lanes, but they could be more dangerous than doing nothing at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This probably isn’t the question you care about, right? Proper horizontal positioning isn’t one of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.visionzerosf.org/&quot;&gt;Vision Zero SF&lt;/a&gt; goals. Bicyclists don’t talk that much about proper horizontal positioning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But nevertheless: proper horizontal positioning is one of the key goals of sharrows. Three of the five goals outlined in the MUTCD are different kinds of proper horizontal positioning. The first goal of San Francisco’s study was horizontal positioning. Most of the sharrow-related data collected is about horizontal positioning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Ferenchak &amp;amp; Marshall note, there is mixed evidence for horizontal positioning in correctly-painted sharrows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amusingly, though, there are a lot of sharrows that don’t even encourage cyclists to take the center of the lane, because they’re painted in the “door zone”: exactly the area that cyclists are supposed to stay away from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Door-zone sharrow in Chicago&quot; src=&quot;https://macwright.com/images/2020-12-04-sharrows-door-zone-sharrow-in-chicago.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/walkingsf/38067633996&quot;&gt;A sharrow in Chicago that has been painted exactly in the 'door zone' which sharrows are supposed to keep bicycles out of / photo by Eric Fischer&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-dont-sharrows-go-away&quot;&gt;Why don’t sharrows go away?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not the first to point out the uselessness of sharrows. The In(effectiveness) study by Ferenchak and Marshall got airtime on &lt;a href=&quot;https://usa.streetsblog.org/2016/01/14/study-sharrows-dont-make-streets-safer-for-cycling/&quot;&gt;Streetsblog&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/article/sharrows-shared-lane-markings-street-cyslists-may-hurt-help/&quot;&gt;99 Percent Invisible&lt;/a&gt;. The bicycle coalition immediately &lt;a href=&quot;https://sfbike.org/news/the-fights-not-over-for-a-better-market-street/&quot;&gt;opposed San Francisco’s new sharrows&lt;/a&gt;. Ferenchak and Marshall &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2046043018300583&quot;&gt;expanded their research with additional data&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One defense of sharrows is that they’re &lt;em&gt;part of a larger strategy&lt;/em&gt;: why not have all the tools in the toolbox? This is sort of like justifying the addition of some homeopathics in your ambulance medical kit. Sure, you have it now, but it’s not going to do anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-sharrows-snuck-into-transit-planning&quot;&gt;How sharrows snuck into transit planning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sharrows started as a brutal compromise. The creator of the sharrow, James Mackay, essentially said that it was a bare-minimum way to do &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; for cycling in a city that didn’t want to do anything:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of it was the city of Denver’s reluctance to do much of anything for bicycles. So I figured, this would be a less expensive approach versus the conventional bike lane markings. A lot of the agencies don’t want to do anything involving change or spending money for bicycles. I was always under pressure to do less as the Denver bicycle planner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this form, as a temporary measure in the evolution of cities away from cars, sharrows made sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And sharrows &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; successful, to some degree, at encouraging cyclists to avoid the “door zone.” And those small, measurable improvements in ‘horizontal positioning’ bought the sharrow’s way into transit device standards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then cities started pushed sharrows in all sorts of scenarios that needed bike lanes, not a temporary, toothless symbol on the asphalt. And since they’re cheap and don’t disrupt car traffic, they caught on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But sharrows have overreached and underperformed. Any cyclist knows that interacting with cars seems dangerous and &lt;em&gt;is dangerous&lt;/em&gt;. A sharrow, a subtle symbol without legal weight, doesn’t seem like it’ll help. And there’s no evidence that disproves that common-sense conclusion: cyclists ask for separated lanes because they feel safer and they &lt;em&gt;are safer&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s time to relegate sharrows to quiet side streets and let them fade into the asphalt. If you’re in San Francisco, sign the &lt;a href=&quot;https://bummermarketstreet.com/&quot;&gt;Bummer Market Street Petition&lt;/a&gt; to say that we need infrastructure that’s actually focused on safety.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 20:04:44 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Tomte</dc:creator>
<og:type>blog</og:type>
<og:image>https://macwright.com/images/2020-12-04-sharrows-thumbnail-image.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://macwright.com/2020/12/04/sharrows.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>U.S. Treasury breached by hackers backed by foreign government – sources</title>
<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-cyber-amazon-com-exclsuive/u-s-treasury-breached-by-hackers-backed-by-foreign-government-sources-idUSKBN28N0PG</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-cyber-amazon-com-exclsuive/u-s-treasury-breached-by-hackers-backed-by-foreign-government-sources-idUSKBN28N0PG</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;ArticleBody-byline-container-3H6dy&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Byline-byline-1sVmo ArticleBody-byline-10B7D&quot;&gt;By &lt;a class=&quot;TextLabel__text-label___3oCVw TextLabel__black-to-orange___23uc0 TextLabel__serif___3lOpX Byline-author-2BSir&quot; href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/journalists/christopher-bing&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Christopher Bing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ArticleBody-read-time-and-social-2VOIr&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;TextLabel__text-label___3oCVw TextLabel__gray___1V4fk TextLabel__small-all-caps-spaced-out___3O9H4 ReadTime-read-time-1s3CG ArticleBody-read-time-29pGN&quot;&gt;5 Min Read&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;WASHINGTON (Reuters) - Hackers believed to be working for Russia have been monitoring internal email traffic at the U.S. Treasury Department and an agency that decides internet and telecommunications policy, according to people familiar with the matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FILE PHOTO: A hooded man holds a laptop computer as cyber code is projected on him in this illustration picture taken on May 13, 2017. REUTERS/Kacper Pempel/Illustration&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;There is concern within the U.S. intelligence community that the hackers who targeted Treasury and the Commerce Department’s National Telecommunications and Information Administration used a similar tool to break into other government agencies, according to four people briefed on the matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;The people did not say which other agencies, but late Sunday Austin, Texas-based IT company SolarWinds said software updates it released in March and June of this year may have been surreptitiously tampered with in a “highly-sophisticated, targeted and manual supply chain attack by a nation state.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;SolarWinds stopped short of saying the hack at Treasury occurred via them, but two of the people familiar with the investigation said the company was believed to be the channel by which the hackers got in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;A representative for SolarWinds did not immediately return messages seeking comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;SolarWinds says on its website that its customers inlcude most of America’s Fortune 500 companies, all top ten U.S. telecommunications providers, all five branches of the U.S. military, the State Department, the National Security Agency, and the Office of President of the United States.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;Three of the people familiar with the investigation said Russia is currently believed to be behind the attack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;Two of the people said that the breaches are connected to a broad campaign that also involved the recently disclosed hack on FireEye, a major U.S. cybersecurity company with government and commercial contracts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;“The United States government is aware of these reports and we are taking all necessary steps to identify and remedy any possible issues related to this situation,” said National Security Council spokesman John Ullyot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;The hack is so serious it led to a National Security Council meeting at the White House on Saturday, said one of the people familiar with the matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;The Commerce Department confirmed there was a breach at one of its agencies in a statement. “We have asked the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency and the FBI to investigate, and we cannot comment further at this time.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;‘HUGE CYBER ESPIONAGE CAMPAIGN’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;The breach presents a major challenge to the incoming administration of President-elect Joe Biden as officials investigate what information was stolen and try to ascertain what it will be used for. It is not uncommon for large scale cyber investigations to take months or years to complete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;“This is a much bigger story than one single agency,” said one of the people familiar with the matter. “This is a huge cyber espionage campaign targeting the U.S. government and its interests.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;Hackers broke into the NTIA’s office software, Microsoft’s Office 365. Staff emails at the agency were monitored by the hackers for months, sources said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;A Microsoft spokesperson did not immediately respond to a request for comment. Neither did a spokesman for the Treasury Department.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;The hackers are “highly sophisticated” and have been able to trick the Microsoft platform’s authentication controls, according to a person familiar with the incident, who spoke on condition of anonymity because they were not allowed to speak to the press.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;“This is a nation state,” said a different person briefed on the matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;The full scope of the breach is unclear. The investigation is still its early stages and involves a range of federal agencies, including the FBI, according to three of the people familiar with the matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;A spokesperson for the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency said they have been “working closely with our agency partners regarding recently discovered activity on government networks. CISA is providing technical assistance to affected entities as they work to identify and mitigate any potential compromises.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;The FBI and U.S. National Security Agency did not immediately respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;There is some indication that the email compromise at NTIA dates back to this summer, although it was only recently discovered, according to a senior U.S. official.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;7.0639534883721&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Attribution-attribution-Y5JpY&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reporting by Christopher Bing, Jack Stubbs, Joseph Menn, and Raphael Satter; Editing by Chris Sanders and Daniel Wallis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 19:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>re_re</dc:creator>
<og:title>Suspected Russian hackers spied on U.S. Treasury emails - sources</og:title>
<og:description>Hackers believed to be working for Russia have been monitoring internal email traffic at the U.S. Treasury Department and an agency that decides internet and telecommunications policy, according to people familiar with the matter.</og:description>
<og:image>https://static.reuters.com/resources/r/?m=02&amp;d=20201213&amp;t=2&amp;i=1544421210&amp;r=LYNXMPEGBC0F6&amp;w=800</og:image>
<og:url>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-cyber-treasury-exclsuive-idUSKBN28N0PG</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-cyber-amazon-com-exclsuive/u-s-treasury-breached-by-hackers-backed-by-foreign-government-sources-idUSKBN28N0PG</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>ARM MacBook vs. Intel MacBook: A SIMD Benchmark</title>
<link>https://lemire.me/blog/2020/12/13/arm-macbook-vs-intel-macbook-a-simd-benchmark/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://lemire.me/blog/2020/12/13/arm-macbook-vs-intel-macbook-a-simd-benchmark/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://lemire.me/blog/2020/12/11/arm-macbook-vs-intel-macbook/&quot;&gt;In my previous blog post&lt;/a&gt;, I compared the performance of my new ARM-based MacBook Pro with my 2017 Intel-based MacBook Pro. I used a number parsing benchmark. In some cases, the ARM-based MacBook Pro was nearly twice as fast as the older Intel-based MacBook Pro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that the Apple M1 processor is a breakthrough in the laptop industry. It has allowed Apple to sell the first ARM-based laptop that is really good. It is not just the chip, of course. It is everything around it. For example, I fully expect that most people who buy these new ARM-based laptops to never realize that they are not Intel-based. The transition is that smooth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am excited because I think it will drive other laptop to rethink their designs. You can buy a thin laptop from Apple with a 20-hour battery life and the ability to do intensive computations like a much larger and heavier laptop would.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(This blog post has been updated after a corrected a methodological mistake. I was running the Apple M1 processor under x64 emulation.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet I did not think that the new Apple processor is better than Intel processors in all things. One obvious caveat is that I am comparing the Apple M1 (a 2020 processor) with an older Intel processor (released in 2017). But I thought that even the older Intel processors can have an edge over the Apple M1 in some tasks and I wanted to make this clear. I did not think it was controversial. Yet I was criticized for making the following remark:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some respect, the Apple M1 chip is far inferior to my older Intel processor. The Intel processor has nifty 256-bit SIMD instructions. The Apple chip has nothing of the sort as part of its main CPU. So I could easily come up with examples that make the M1 look bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This rubbed many readers the wrong way. They pointed out that ARM processors do have 128-bit SIMD instructions called NEON. They do. In some ways, the NEON instruction set is nicer than the x64 SSE/AVX one. Recent Apple ARM processors have four execution units capable of SIMD processing while Intel processors only have three. Furthermore, the Intel execution units have more restrictions. Thus 64-bit ARM NEON routines will outperform comparable SSE2 (128-bit SIMD) Intel routines despite the fact that they both work over 128-bit registers. In fact, &lt;a href=&quot;https://lemire.me/blog/2019/07/10/parsing-json-using-simd-instructions-on-the-apple-a12-processor/&quot;&gt;I have a blog post making this point by using the iPhone’s processor&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it does not follow that the 128-bit ARM NEON instructions are generally a match for the 256-bit SIMD instructions Intel and AMD offer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us test out the issue. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://simdjson.org&quot;&gt;simdjson library&lt;/a&gt; offers SIMD-heavy functions to minify JSON and validate UTF-8 inputs. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lemire/Code-used-on-Daniel-Lemire-s-blog/blob/master/2020/12/benchmark.cpp&quot;&gt;I wrote a benchmark program&lt;/a&gt; that loads a file in memory and then repeatedly calls the minify and validate function, looking for the best possible speed. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lemire/Code-used-on-Daniel-Lemire-s-blog/tree/master/2020/12&quot;&gt;Anyone with a MacBook and Xcode should be able to reproduce my results&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vectorized UTF-8 validation algorithm is described in &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/pdf/2010.03090.pdf&quot;&gt;Validating UTF-8 In Less Than One Instruction Per Byte&lt;/a&gt; (published in Software: Practice and Experience).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The simdjson library relies on an abstraction layer so that functions are implemented using higher-level C++ which gets translated into efficient SIMD intrinsic functions specific to the targeted system. That is, we are not comparing different hand-tuned assembly functions. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/simdjson/simdjson/blob/master/src/generic/stage1/utf8_lookup4_algorithm.h&quot;&gt;You can check out the UTF-8 validation code for yourself online&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us look at the results:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th/&gt;
&lt;th&gt;minify&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;UTF-8 validate&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Apple M1 (2020 MacBook Pro)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6.6 GB/s&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;33 GB/s&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Intel Kaby Lake (2017 MacBook Pro)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7.7 GB/s&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;29 GB/s&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Intel/M1 ratio&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;As you can see, the older Intel processor is slightly superior to the Apple M1 in the minify test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, it is only one set of benchmarks. There are many confounding factors. Did the algorithmic choices favour the AVX2 ISA? It is possible. Thankfully all of the source code is available so any such bias can be assessed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 18:34:16 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>todsacerdoti</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://lemire.me/blog/2020/12/13/arm-macbook-vs-intel-macbook-a-simd-benchmark/</og:url>
<og:title>ARM MacBook vs Intel MacBook: a SIMD benchmark</og:title>
<og:description>In my previous blog post, I compared the performance of my new ARM-based MacBook Pro with my 2017 Intel-based MacBook Pro. I used a number parsing benchmark. In some cases, the ARM-based MacBook Pro was nearly twice as fast as the older Intel-based MacBook Pro. I think that the Apple M1 processor is a breakthrough … Continue reading ARM MacBook vs Intel MacBook: a SIMD benchmark</og:description>
<og:image>https://lemire.me/img/portrait2018facebook.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://lemire.me/blog/2020/12/13/arm-macbook-vs-intel-macbook-a-simd-benchmark/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The fraying of the U.S. global currency reserve system</title>
<link>https://www.lynalden.com/fraying-petrodollar-system/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.lynalden.com/fraying-petrodollar-system/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;featured-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-reserve-currency-feature.png&quot; alt=&quot;The Fraying of the US Global Currency Reserve System&quot; class=&quot;entry-image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Published December 2, 2020&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since autumn of 2019, I’ve been bearish on the dollar, meaning I have a longish-term outlook towards a weaker dollar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This view began forming when the Federal Reserve cut interest rates in summer 2019, and then the view solidified with a catalyst after an overnight repo rate spike in September 2019 forced the Fed to begin supplying repo liquidity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my October 2, 2019 article, “&lt;a href=&quot;https://seekingalpha.com/article/4294621-crowded-trade&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;The Most Crowded Trade&lt;/a&gt;“, I said to look for a weaker dollar in 2020, and also stated that the Fed would likely start expanding its balance sheet by buying Treasuries in 2020 or perhaps as early as that quarter in 2019 due to oversupply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Days later, the Fed indeed &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-10-11/fed-to-start-buying-60b-of-treasury-bills-a-month-from-oct-15&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; that they will begin buying Treasuries, and as of this writing well over a year later, they haven’t stopped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s the dollar index since my October article, having fallen from about 99 to 92:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-11225&quot; src=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/petrodollar-since-october.png&quot; alt=&quot;Petrodollar Since October&quot; width=&quot;1229&quot; height=&quot;535&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/petrodollar-since-october.png 1229w, https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/petrodollar-since-october-300x131.png 300w, https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/petrodollar-since-october-1024x446.png 1024w, https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/petrodollar-since-october-768x334.png 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1229px) 100vw, 1229px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chart Source: StockCharts.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going forward over the next 3-5 years, I still expect many currencies including the dollar to continue to devalue vs hard assets, and for the dollar to probably be among the weaker major currencies during that timeframe (with occasional counter-rallies against that trend, as is natural).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it may or may not continue to be, so far this view has been correct. The dollar index is weaker now than it was in October 2019, but it’s still a process playing out. We had a curveball to the outlook from the pandemic in the first half of 2020 that temporarily spiked the dollar, but that merely added massive volatility to the structural forces playing out, rather than changing their direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t have a firm opinion about the next 3-6 months, because there are plenty of solvency issues between now and when things might start normalizing in the spring or summer of 2021, and dollar shorts are getting crowded at the moment, but as we look into late 2021 and into 2022, I remain with a dollar bearish outlook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking my view a step further, evidence shows that the global monetary system as currently structured is gradually re-aligning itself, and this fact will have important ramifications for investments over the long run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article explores some of those concepts, ranging from the fraying of the existing petrodollar system (for all of its stakeholders, both for US interests and foreign interests), to central bank digital currencies, to a total restructuring of the global monetary system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s inherently a challenging subject, because for decades there have been many unsophisticated calls for a “dollar collapse” always right around the corner that never materialize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, this isn’t one of those calls; it’s a quantitative look at the nearly 50-year history of this current global monetary system as structured since the early 1970’s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article places an emphasis on where the bottlenecks and problems have been forming in the system, explains why a continued weak dollar over a 3-5 year period remains my base case, and shows why some of these growing pains seem to be leading to a new re-ordering of the global monetary system over this decade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Article Chapters:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/fraying-petrodollar-system#structure&quot;&gt;The Structure of the Global Monetary System&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Gold Standard Pre-1944&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bretton Woods System 1944-1971&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Petrodollar System 1974-Present&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/fraying-petrodollar-system#cycle&quot;&gt;The Great Petrodollar Bull/Bear Cycle&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Causes for the Cycle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1980s Dollar Cycle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1990s/2000s Dollar Cycle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2010s/2020s Dollar Cycle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/fraying-petrodollar-system#fraying&quot;&gt;The Fraying of the Petrodollar System&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;A System Without a Purpose&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shrinking US Share of Global GDP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multi-Currency International Trade&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;China Subverting the System&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eating Our Own Cooking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Triffin’s Dilemma Unfolds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/fraying-petrodollar-system#intermediate&quot;&gt;The Intermediate-Term Outlook&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The Dollar vs Other Currencies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/fraying-petrodollar-system#long&quot;&gt;The Long-Term Outlook&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The Slow Restructuring Option&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Fast Restructuring Option&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/fraying-petrodollar-system#next&quot;&gt;What the Next System Looks Like&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Decentralized Energy Pricing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Digital Global Bancor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Digital Regional Bancors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gold as a Reserve Asset&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bitcoin as a Reserve Asset&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/fraying-petrodollar-system#summary&quot;&gt;Summary Thoughts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;structure&quot;&gt;The Structure of the Global Monetary System&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather than being a haphazard mess, international trade and exchange rates have a certain structure to them, built and enforced by the hegemonic powers that exist during a given era.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, at any given time, an empire or set of powerful countries work together to enforce a rules-based global order on how international trade works, and how it is priced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, there is inherently an economic entropy within any system, as order gradually frays into disorder. Global monetary systems can be long-lasting, but not permanent. As the global center of power shifts over time, and as bottlenecks and imperfections in the system grow to unsustainable levels resulting in increasing levels of disorder, a system gradually or abruptly gets re-ordered into another system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ironically, it’s often not an external threat that brings down the existing order; it’s the flaws within the system that, left unchecked, eventually expand enough to bring it down and necessitate a re-ordering, either from the same ruling regime or from a new regime that displaces it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past century, for example, the world went from a gold standard system, to the Bretton Woods system, to the petrodollar system. Each system mostly unraveled from within rather than being brought down externally, and each time one system transitioned to another, a significant and widespread currency devaluation occurred.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gold Standard (pre-1944)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For much of human existence, economies were based on trade. Furs for oysters, olive oil for spices, labor for bread, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mining of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/precious-metals-investing/&quot;&gt;precious metals like gold and silver&lt;/a&gt; made that simpler, and these metals have been considered money for thousands of years. With precious metals, you could turn a specific commodity (like furs) into a universal commodity (like gold and silver, which are rare, long-lasting, and able to be broken into small measurable units), to buy whatever you want at a later date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From there, paper currency and credit was added as a more convenient layer onto gold. Gold itself could be held securely in vaults, and paper slips representing a share of that gold could be used as mediums of exchange. Sometimes they were issued by private banks, and in modern times they were generally issued by sovereign governments. In this sense, governments would issue paper currency that is backed by gold held in central bank vaults.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From that point, we saw the rise of global reserve currencies, referring to either paper or precious metal currencies of trading or military empires that were recognized and accepted in many countries outside their own homeland. The Roman Empire was an ancient example. More recently, the Dutch Empire was a notable example, followed by the United Kingdom, and now the United States. In the 1800s and early 1900s, the United Kingdom had the mantle of the most globally recognized currency, although it existed within a system of many currencies being backed by gold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During these centuries, the center of global power mostly rested within Europe with its precise epicenter shifting over time, and wars within Europe played a large role in its eventual replacement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under this gold standard system, exchange rates between currencies still shifted over time for various reasons, with the balance of payments being a key variable. My article “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/trade-deficit/&quot;&gt;Why Trade Deficits Matter&lt;/a&gt;” goes into detail on why that is the case. The crux of it is that whenever a country began persistently importing more than it was exporting, it risked having gold flow out of the country and risked economic stagnation within the homeland. Ultimately, however, this state would usually be self-correcting because a recession would eventually devalue the currency, which would make their exports more competitive and imports more expensive, and thus re-align their export and import balance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the later stages of this system, all major nations devalued their currencies sharply and reset or suspended their gold pegs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-8637&quot; src=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/currency-debasement-1930s.png&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 374px) 100vw, 374px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/currency-debasement-1930s.png 374w, https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/currency-debasement-1930s-300x245.png 300w&quot; alt=&quot;Currency Debasement in the 1930s&quot; width=&quot;374&quot; height=&quot;305&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chart Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/its-time-look-more-carefully-monetary-policy-3-mp3-modern-ray-dalio/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Bridgewater Associates&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The winners of the world wars devalued their currencies less than the losers, but everyone devalued. This was partly from the wars, but also just as much from the end of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/fiscal-and-monetary-policy/&quot;&gt;long-term debt cycle&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bretton Woods System (1944-1971)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most recent handover of global reserve currency status gradually began after World War I, and was finalized in the later stages of World War II. As a result of the wars and the rise of the American economy, the center of global power shifted from Europe (and particularly the United Kingdom) to the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the 1930’s, the United States government made gold ownership illegal and forced citizens to sell their gold to the government, which allowed the government to build up huge gold reserves. Then, in order to keep gold safe during the war, many countries shipped their gold to the United States. So, the United States had its own massive gold stockpile, and also served as the global gold custodian for many allies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As World War II unfolded, while Europe and east Asia were devastated by the war, the United States homeland was barely touched, and the US became the world’s largest creditor nation in the process. At that point, the Bretton Woods system was established, whereby the United States backed its dollar by gold, and dozens of other countries pegged their currencies to the dollar, and thus also had a gold standard by association. Many countries held US Treasuries, as a form of reserve collateral that was “good as gold”. The dollar was not redeemable to US citizens for gold, but it was redeemable to foreign governments for gold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this time, the United States also began laying the groundwork for its alliance with Saudi Arabia, which would come into play with the next system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This period also saw the rise of the “eurodollar market”, referring to the dollar market that exists between banks and other entities outside of the United States and outside of the Federal Reserve’s jurisdiction, primarily centered in Europe but extending throughout the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the Bretton Woods system and the following petrodollar system, the United States obtained a near-global lock on the international money system. Previous empire currencies never obtained that complete of a financial lock on the world, and thus were never true “global reserve” currencies but instead were just “widely recognized and dominant” currencies. So the 1944-present status of the dollar as the global reserve currency is not perfectly comparable to pre-1944 periods of other global reserve currencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This period was rather unique, in other words. It was the first time technology allowed the entire world to be connected together enough for a truly global war to happen, and for a truly global monetary system to come in its wake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, after only a decade, the Bretton Woods system began to fray. The United States began running large fiscal deficits and experiencing mildly rising inflation levels, first for the late 1960s domestic programs, and then for the Vietnam War. The United States began to see its gold reserves shrink, as other countries began to doubt the backing of the dollar and therefore redeem dollars for gold instead of comfortably holding dollars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This chart shows US gold reserves as measured in metric tonnes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-11160&quot; src=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-us-gold-reserevs-bullionstar.png&quot; alt=&quot;Dollar Crisis Gold Reserves&quot; width=&quot;651&quot; height=&quot;409&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-us-gold-reserevs-bullionstar.png 651w, https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-us-gold-reserevs-bullionstar-300x188.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 651px) 100vw, 651px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chart Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bullionstar.com/blogs/koos-jansen/second-thoughts-us-official-gold-reserve-audits/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Bullionstar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, the numbers show that from inception, it was already on an unstable path. The US began the system with more gold than foreign liabilities, but that gap quickly began closing within the first few years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the late-1950s, US external liabilities exceeded US gold reserves. By the mid-1960s, the subset of US external liabilities that were owed to foreign officials exceeded US gold reserves, which was the true crossover point where the system became troubled. And by 1971, the system broke down and was defaulted on by the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-11185&quot; src=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-bretton-woods-failure.png&quot; alt=&quot;Dollar Crisis Bretton Woods Failure&quot; width=&quot;613&quot; height=&quot;532&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-bretton-woods-failure.png 613w, https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-bretton-woods-failure-300x260.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 613px) 100vw, 613px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chart Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bis.org/publ/work684.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;BIS Working Papers No 684&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The system had an underlying flaw that when left unaddressed brought the system down. It was never truly sustainable as designed. There was no way that the US could maintain enough gold to back all of its currency for domestic use, and simultaneously back enough currency for expanding global use as well (which was the part that was redeemable).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some economists such as Robert Triffin, explicitly warned about this problem to Congress and the business world in what became known as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Triffin_dilemma&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Triffin dilemma&lt;/a&gt;. It was a foreseeable problem, in other words. The same thing happened to the United Kingdom in the early 1900s, prior to World War I.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Keynes saw the problem ahead of time too, and proposed an alternate system called the Bancor, where an international unit of account based on gold and a basket of major currencies would be used to settle balances of trade and would be held as a central bank reserve asset. This would be an inherently more balanced system, with a neutral settlement mechanism rather than centering everything on the currency of one country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, politics often wins out over math, at least at first, and the Bretton Woods system won over other ideas. Something like the Bancor idea was enacted on the side by the IMF as well, with units called SDRs that are a basket of major currencies and are still held by central banks, but it never had enough support to catch on in more than a limited way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually in 1971, math came back with a vengeance on the Bretton Woods system, and Richard Nixon ended the convertibility of dollars to gold, and thus ended the Bretton Woods system. The closing of gold convertibility was proposed to be temporary at the time, but it ultimately became permanent. Rather than shifting to another country, though, the United States was able to re-order the global monetary system with itself still in the center, in the next system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, all major currencies including the dollar devalued radically vs gold and other hard assets in the 1970’s. This continued the trend of major currency devaluations happening whenever the global monetary system gets re-ordered. Usually the same forces that break the system, also break the currency itself. When that happens, the quantity of broad money supply goes up significantly, and the purchasing power of existing debts gets partially inflated away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Petrodollar System (1974-Present)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beginning in 1971 after the breakdown of the Bretton Woods system, currencies around the world all became fiat currencies, and the global monetary system became less ordered. This was the first time in human history that this happened, where all currencies in the world at the same time were rendered into unbacked paper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A “fiat” is an absolute decree from a person or institution in command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fiat currency is a monetary system whereby there is nothing of value in the currency itself; it’s just paper, cheap metal coins, or digital bits of information. It has value because the government declares it to have value and that it is legal tender to pay all things including taxes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A country can enforce the usage of a fiat currency as a medium of exchange and unit of account within their country by making all taxes payable only in that currency, or by enacting other laws to add friction to, or in some cases outright ban, other mediums of exchange and units of account. If their currency has a big enough problem, though, as is the case for many emerging markets, a black market will develop for other mediums of exchange, such as foreign currency or hard assets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A fiat currency can face particular problems when trying to be used outside of its home country. Why should businesses and governments in other countries accept pieces of paper, which can be printed endlessly by a foreign government and have no firm backing, as a form of payment for their valuable goods and services? Without a real backing, what is it worth? Why would you sell oil to foreigners for paper?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the early 1970’s, there were a variety of geopolitical conflicts including the Yom Kippur War and the OPEC oil embargo. In 1974, however, the United States and Saudi Arabia &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2016-05-30/the-untold-story-behind-saudi-arabia-s-41-year-u-s-debt-secret&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;reached an agreement&lt;/a&gt;, and from there, the world was set on the petrodollar system; a clever way to make a global fiat currency system work decently enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We think of this as normal now, but this five decade period of global fiat currency is unusual and unique in the historical sense. Imagine trying to architect a way to make an all-fiat currency system work on the global stage for the first time in human history. In doing so, you have to somehow convince or force the whole world to trade valuable things for foreign pieces of paper with no guarantee from the paper-issuing governments that those papers are worth anything in particular, in relation to an amount of gold or other hard assets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the petrodollar system, Saudi Arabia (and other countries in OPEC) sell their oil exclusively in dollars in exchange for US protection and cooperation. Even if France wants to buy oil from Saudi Arabia, for example, they do so in dollars. Any country that wants oil, needs to be able to get dollars to pay for it, either by earning them or exchanging their currency for them. So, non oil-producing countries also sell many of their exports in dollars, even though the dollar is completely fiat foreign paper, so that they can get dollars for which to buy oil from oil-producing countries. And, all of these countries store excess dollars as foreign-exchange reserves, which they mostly put into US Treasuries to earn some interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In return, the United States uses its unrivaled blue-water navy to protect global shipping lanes, and preserve the geopolitical status quo with military action or the threat thereof as needed. In addition, the United States basically has to run persistent trade deficits with the rest of the world, to get enough dollars out into the international system. Many of those dollars, however, get recycled into buying US Treasuries and stored as foreign-exchange reserves, meaning that a large portion of US federal deficits are financed by foreign governments compared to other developed nations that mostly rely on domestic financing. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/quantitative-easing-mmt-inflation/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;This article&lt;/a&gt; explains why foreign financing can feel great while it’s happening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The petrodollar system is creative, because it was one of the few ways to make everyone in the world accept foreign paper for tangible goods and services. Oil producers get protection and order in exchange for pricing their oil in dollars and putting their reserves into Treasuries, and non-oil producers need oil, and thus need dollars so they can get that oil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This leads to a disproportionate amount of global trade occurring in dollars relative to the size of the US economy, and in some ways, means that the dollar is backed by oil, without being explicitly pegged to oil at a defined ratio. The system gives the dollar a persistent global demand from around the world, while other fiat currencies are mostly just used internally in their own countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This chart is two years old, but things haven’t changed much since then. What it shows is that even though the United States represented only about 11% of global trade and 24% of global GDP in early 2018, the dollar’s share of global economic activity was far higher at 40-60% depending on what metric you look at, and this gap represents its status as the global reserve currency, and the key currency for global energy pricing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-5616&quot; src=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-current-exposure.png&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 650px) 100vw, 650px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-current-exposure.png 650w, https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-current-exposure-300x96.png 300w&quot; alt=&quot;Dollar Crisis Inevitable? Current Exposure Chart&quot; width=&quot;650&quot; height=&quot;208&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chart Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-10-03/the-tyranny-of-the-u-s-dollar&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The inherent flaw of the petrodollar system, much like the inherent flaw with the Bretton Woods system, is that as previously mentioned, the United States needs to run persistent trade deficits, and is another version of the Triffin dilemma again. This can work for decades but can’t work forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-11161&quot; src=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-us-trade-balance.png&quot; alt=&quot;Dollar Crisis US Trade Balance&quot; width=&quot;691&quot; height=&quot;379&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-us-trade-balance.png 691w, https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-us-trade-balance-300x165.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 691px) 100vw, 691px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chart Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://tradingeconomics.com/united-states/balance-of-trade&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Trading Economics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of drawing down our gold reserves, however, we gradually draw down our domestic manufacturing base and it gets replaced piece-by-piece in foreign countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When most other countries run trade deficits, they eventually have a big enough currency devaluation so that their exports become more competitive and importing becomes more expensive, which usually prevents multi-decade extremes from building up. However, because the petrodollar system creates persistent international demand for the dollar, it means the US trade deficit never is allowed to correct and balance itself out. The trade deficit is held open persistently by the structure of the global monetary system, which creates a permanent imbalance, and is the flaw that eventually, after a long enough timeline, brings the system down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other flaw in the system is that it incentivizes mercantilism. This means it incentivizes various trade partners to maximize their exports and minimize their imports by manipulating their currencies to weak levels. Since currencies around the world are fiat with floating exchange rates, many countries try to keep their own currencies weak, so that they have a positive trade balance with the United States and other trading partners. They don’t want their own currencies to be so weak that their citizens can’t import things, but they want their currencies to be weak enough so that their exports are very competitive and the importing power is not very strong, so that they can run trade surpluses. This allows a country to rapidly build up industrial production, and accumulate dollars and reserves. As the global reserve currency, the United States is basically excluded from this option, so we’re the ones left holding the bag of persistent trade deficits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of us, particularly near the top of the income ladder, directly or indirectly benefit from this system. Americans who work around finance, government, healthcare, and technology get many of the benefits of living in the hegemonic power, without the drawbacks. On the other hand, Americans who make physical products tend not to benefit, because they lost their jobs or had their incomes suppressed, and thus haven’t benefited from the gains. And outside of the United States, exporting countries benefit from the system, while countries that don’t like how the global monetary system is structured don’t have much recourse to do anything about it, unless they get big enough like Russia and China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;cycle&quot;&gt;The Great Petrodollar Bull/Bear Cycle&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because exchange rates are free-floating since 1971 within the petrodollar system, the dollar can strengthen or weaken against other currencies significantly, and other currency pairs can strengthen or weaken relative to each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever the dollar begins to take a dip, we get a host of superficial articles from financial media about the “potential loss of the dollar’s global reserve status”, but that’s not how it works. Conversely, if an analyst such as myself brings up that the dollar may decrease markedly vs other major currencies, one of the comments or pushback they’ll get is “but the US is the global reserve currency.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need to treat those concepts separately. The dollar indeed has had two huge bear market drawdowns of 40%+ vs a basket of other major currencies within this existing monetary system, without losing global reserve currency status. Being a dollar bear within the existing petrodollar system (and having no opinion about the petrodollar system ending), is not identical to someone who thinks the petrodollar system as currently structured is coming to an end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This chart is the dollar index since the early 1970’s when the petrodollar system began. The chart compares the dollar vs a basket of major currencies, and shows the three major cycles it has gone through (click &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/petrodollar-dollar-index-cycle.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for a bigger view):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-11226&quot; src=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/petrodollar-dollar-index-cycle.png&quot; alt=&quot;Petrodollar Cycle&quot; width=&quot;1228&quot; height=&quot;536&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/petrodollar-dollar-index-cycle.png 1228w, https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/petrodollar-dollar-index-cycle-300x131.png 300w, https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/petrodollar-dollar-index-cycle-1024x447.png 1024w, https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/petrodollar-dollar-index-cycle-768x335.png 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1228px) 100vw, 1228px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chart Source: StockCharts.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dollar index broke below its 50-month moving average this year, and that 50-month moving average itself now has a slight downward tilt. Could it have another one of those dollar down-legs like it had after the previous two major cycle tops? Sure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, let’s separate being a dollar bear from being someone who thinks the global monetary system will change structurally. The two don’t necessarily go hand in hand, although they can. It’s important to treat those ideas independently, because even though I do hold both of those views over different timeframes, they aren’t the same view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, the dollar being the world’s reserve currency doesn’t necessarily protect it from major swings relative to other currencies. In fact, the depth to which the dollar is plugged into the global financial system arguably gives it bigger swings than it otherwise would have, both to the upside and downside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Causes for the Cycle&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dollar cycle is based on major shifts in monetary and fiscal policy, as well as the resulting capital flows for global money that wants to chase whatever area of the world is doing well. Underlying all of this is the global monetary system as currently structured, i.e. the petrodollar system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I discussed in my February 2020 article, “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/global-dollar-short-squeeze/&quot;&gt;The Global Dollar Short Squeeze&lt;/a&gt;” and in my April 2020 article, “&lt;a href=&quot;https://seekingalpha.com/article/4336136-40-trillion-problem&quot;&gt;The $40 Trillion Problem&lt;/a&gt;“, governments and companies outside of the United States have a lot of dollar-denominated debt ($13 trillion at a minimum according to the BIS), but also have even more dollar-denominated assets (around $42 trillion according to the IMF and US BEA). These debts and assets were built up over decades due to those countries running trade surpluses with the United States, and from the dollar being used for the majority of global financing deals, especially for emerging markets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That dollar-denominated debt represents a consistent source of demand for dollars to service those debts. So, if recessions happen, or dollar-based global trade slows down, there can become a scramble for dollars which can be in short supply outside of the United States, causing an international dollar spike. This happened in March 2020 as the pandemic sharply diminished global trade, and oil prices collapsed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In that sense, the petrodollar system reinforced itself over time. At first, countries needed dollars so that they could get oil. After decades of that, with so much international financing happening in dollars, now countries need dollars so they can service their dollar-denominated debts. So, the dollar is backed by both oil and dollar-denominated debts, and it’s a very strong self-reinforcing network effect. Importantly, most of those debts aren’t owed to the United States (despite being denominated in dollars), but rather are owed to other countries. For example, China makes many dollar-based loans to developing countries, as do Europe and Japan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the dollar strengthens relative to emerging market countries’ local currencies, it acts as a sort of quantitative tightening for those countries because their dollar-denominated debts go up in local currency terms relative to their assets and cash flows, which can be particularly brutal during recessions. That’s one of the key reasons why emerging market assets and economies are riskier and more volatile than developed market economies; their dollar-denominated borrowings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, a weakening dollar can be like quantitative easing for them, as it eases their debt load relative to their local-currency cash flows and assets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, dollar-denominated assets, especially ones held by foreign governments and central banks (acquired from years of trade and current account surpluses), represent collateral with which those countries can defend their currencies, or represent assets that they can sell in order to get dollars to support their obligations if need be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During a weak dollar period, there is often a global economic boom, and nations around the world including the United States have a period of growth and prosperity. If nations are smart, they start building up big foreign exchange reserves with their dollar inflows. Within this petrodollar system, that has meant buying US Treasury securities. Countries also often use that period to take out dollar-based loans, which comes back to bite them later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During a strong dollar period, the global economy often slows, and nations get squeezed by dollar-denominated debts. They buy far fewer Treasuries, if any, and might even sell some to get dollars to service dollar-denominated debts or manage their currency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result, we see a clear pattern between dollar strength and the percent of US federal debt held by the foreign sector. Whenever the dollar enters one of its big bull runs, foreigners start to get squeezed, global growth slows (including US growth, due to the interconnection of the global economy), and foreigners slow down or stop their purchases of US debt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This chart shows the trade-weighted dollar index in blue (with a newer index in red spliced onto it, due to the fact that the longer-running index discontinued at the start of 2020), and the percent of US federal debt held by the foreign sector in green:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-11163&quot; src=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-index-vs-foreign-UST.png&quot; alt=&quot;Dollar Index vs Foreign Treasury Holdings&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-index-vs-foreign-UST.png 700w, https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-index-vs-foreign-UST-300x193.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chart Source: St. Louis Fed&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the chart shows, each of the three major dollar index bull runs were accompanied by a sharp reduction in the percentage of US federal debt held by the foreign sector. The United States was still issuing debt, but foreigners weren’t buying much of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lack of buying by foreigners forces the US to fund its own federal deficits, meaning either its private sector or increasingly the Federal Reserve itself had to buy Treasuries, and that eventually leads to a dovish shift in US monetary policy, which plays a role in weakening the dollar and starting the cycle anew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a second chart, we can compare the dollar index to US corporate profits, which shows that corporate profits go flat in dollar terms for a number of years every time there is one of the big dollar bull runs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-11165&quot; src=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-index-vs-corporate-profits-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Dollar Index vs Corporate Profits&quot; width=&quot;728&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-index-vs-corporate-profits-2.png 728w, https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-index-vs-corporate-profits-2-300x185.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chart Source: St. Louis Fed&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, as we all know, the global economy is interconnected. The US usually runs into economic problems when the dollar strengthens, just like certain other parts of the world. In a strong dollar environment, US exports become less competitive, and the overall global trade environment becomes sluggish, resulting in domestic stagnation within the US as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 1980s dollar spike occurred in an environment with less global debt, so it required deliberate intervention to reverse. The second and third dollar spikes occurred in environments with more debt in the US and elsewhere, and thus were more self-correcting without global coordination, by unilateral shifts in monetary policy by the US Federal Reserve to protect the US Treasury market and stimulate the domestic economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1980s Dollar Cycle&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dollar was weak in the 1970’s after going off the gold standard, and the United States and many other countries experienced rapid consumer price inflation. In the early 1980s, the new Fed chairman Paul Volcker jacked up interest rates to quell inflation. At the same time, Ronald Reagan ran large fiscal deficits by cutting taxes and increasing spending, which contributed to an economic boom. This combination of tight monetary policy and loose fiscal policy tends to be strong for a currency while it lasts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first half of the 1980s saw rapid strengthening in the dollar. This contributed to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Latin_American_debt_crisis&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Latin American debt crisis&lt;/a&gt;; emerging markets in Latin America were unable to pay dollar-denominated debts back, resulting in defaults, recessions, and currency crises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Debts within the United States were very low, so interest rates could be kept high by Volcker for a long time, which added a lot of fuel to the dollar bull run. The dollar eventually reached an apex in 1985, when the United States and four other major countries (Germany, Japan, United Kingdom, and France) agreed to deliberately weaken the dollar in an event called the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Plaza_Accord&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Plaza Accord&lt;/a&gt; so that American and European exports would be more competitive vs Japanese exports, which were dominating global trade at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the dollar fell in the late 1980s and the yen strengthened markedly, money flooded into Japan, which along with their overall strong economy, led to the massive well-known Japanese equity and real estate bubble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1990s/2000s Dollar Cycle&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Soviet Union fell in 1991, leaving the United States as the world’s sole superpower, and led to a period of opening markets and rapid globalization. In the early 1990s, the United States had a recession, and saw a period of declining interest rates, and the dollar was weak overall. Emerging markets had a strong period until the mid-1990s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At that point, the United States’ economy began to do well and raised interest rates, beginning the second dollar bull run. In addition, the US baby boom generation reached its peak working age, resulting in the highest level of labor participation in US history:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-11162&quot; src=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-us-labor-force-participation.png&quot; alt=&quot;Dollar Crisis US Labor Force Participation&quot; width=&quot;728&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-us-labor-force-participation.png 728w, https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-us-labor-force-participation-300x185.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chart Source: St. Louis Fed&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the second half of the 1990s, the United States entered a tech boom/bubble period, and the dollar spiked. Several emerging markets encountered serious dollar-denominated debt problems, resulting in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/1997_Asian_financial_crisis&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;1997 Asian financial crisis&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/1998_Russian_financial_crisis&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;1998 Russian financial crisis&lt;/a&gt;. Emerging markets, as a whole, suffered. It mirrored the 1980s Latin American debt crisis, but with its epicenter in southeast Asia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason that some emerging markets suffer more than others during a given cycle, has to do with the amount of dollar-denominated debt they have relative to the amount of foreign-exchange reserves they have. The most vulnerable nations for a financial crisis are the emerging markets that have high dollar-denominated debts and low foreign-exchange reserves, while those with the opposite situation of high reserves and low debts are well-fortified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By 2000, the US dotcom equity bubble began to collapse, and the Fed cut interest rates. In the years that followed throughout the 2000s decade, the dollar weakened notably, and emerging markets had a massive boom period. The acronym “BRIC” became popular, referring to the idea that Brazil, Russia, India, and China, due to large populations and massive growth rates, would become increasingly important on the global economic stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2010s/2020s Dollar Cycle&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dollar remained weak for a while, although it had a brief spike around the 2008/2009 global financial crisis as oil prices fell and a global recession occurred. The Fed, in particular, did three major rounds of quantitative easing, but those ended in late 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Between 2014 and 2015, as the Fed shifted to tighter monetary policy by putting an end to QE, the dollar quickly strengthened, resulting in the third major dollar bull run. Several emerging markets subsequently encountered a severe recession from 2014-2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2016, the dollar reached a peak, and there were talks of a secret &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.marketwatch.com/story/did-central-bankers-make-a-secret-deal-to-drive-markets-this-rumor-says-yes-2016-03-18&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Shanghai Accord&lt;/a&gt; to weaken the dollar, in reference to the well-known Plaza Accord of 1985. The dollar indeed weakened significantly throughout 2017, and the world encountered “global synchronized growth” as it was called, where the United States, Europe, Japan, and emerging markets all did quite well together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In early 2018, the Fed began quantitative tightening (reducing the size of its balance sheet), and the dollar began re-strengthening. From peak to trough, the dollar only had a 12% drawdown from its peak, and never achieved one of those massive 40% dollar declines like the previous two cycles. By mid-2018, global growth began to slow in the US and the rest of the world. The dollar weakness was a fake-out, in other words. It was still a strong dollar period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Argentina and Turkey in particular began experiencing currency crises. They were the vulnerable ones, with lots of dollar-denominated debt and little foreign-exchange reserves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, the countries that suffered in the late 1990s dollar bull run, such as Thailand, South Korea, Malaysia, and Russia, learned their lesson from last time around, and came into this cycle with a ton of foreign-exchange reserves and less dollar-denominated debt, which is the opposite of the situation they all had in the 1990s. They were fortified against a strong dollar this time around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By summer 2019, the Fed began cutting interest rates in the face of slowing economic growth. In September 2019, the overnight lending rate in the US banking system spiked, leading the Fed to begin supplying repo liquidity, and then eventually to buying T-bills and expanding its balance sheet, which marked the end of quantitative tightening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was an example of the system correcting itself, or more specifically, forcing US policymakers to correct it. A strong dollar contributed to slowing global GDP growth, including in the United States, which led the Fed to cut rates. And, with foreigners not buying enough Treasuries for years due to the dollar being so strong, the US domestic balance sheets became increasingly stuffed with Treasuries and couldn’t keep buying more, so the Fed had to shift from quantitively tightening to quantitative easing to begin buying a ton of Treasuries, which floods the system with liquidity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dollar began weakening again from there, as expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the COVID-19 pandemic hit in early 2020, which halted global trade and contributed (along with a structural oil oversupply issue) to a collapse in oil prices. The dollar quickly spiked, foreigners began outright selling Treasuries and other US assets to get dollars, causing the Treasury market to become very illiquid and “ceasing to function effectively” as the Fed described it. In response to this, the Fed cut rates to zero and performed massive quantitative easing, and the US federal government performed massive fiscal stimulus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dollar began weakening again, and from there, it remains to be seen what the next chapter will be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;fraying&quot;&gt;The Fraying of the Petrodollar System&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I explained before, each global monetary system begins to suffer from a form of entropy, where order falls into disorder as inherent flaws in the system manifest themselves over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the Bretton Woods system, the flaw was the persistent reduction in US gold reserves against a growing amount of external liabilities, leading to an eventual inability to maintain the convertibility of dollars into gold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the petrodollar system, the flaw is the persistent trade deficits that the US has to run with the rest of the world in order to supply the world with dollars that they must use for energy pricing. The US ends up outsourcing large portions of its industrial base, and in the process builds up a massive deficit in its net international investment position as the foreign sector owns an increasing share of US assets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, the flaw in the Bretton Woods system was about the United States’ capital account, whereas the flaw in the petrodollar system is about the United States’ current account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A detailed 2017 paper by the BIS called “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bis.org/publ/work684.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Triffin: dilemma or myth?&lt;/a&gt;” examines the validity of Triffin’s dilemma from multiple angles, agrees with aspects and disagrees with other aspects, and re-states it and re-applies it in multiple scenarios. In that paper is a good summary of what this updated “current account Triffin dilemma” proposes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;24&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most common version of Triffin shifts his thesis from the capital account to the current account. It posits that the reserve currency country must run, or at least does run, persistent current account deficits to provide the rest of the world with reserves denominated in its currency (Zhou (2009), Camdessus and Icard (2011), Paul Volcker in Feldstein (2013), Prasad (2013)). “In doing so, it becomes more indebted to foreigners until the risk-free asset ceases to be risk-free” (Financial Times Lexicon (no date)).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[…]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As applied to the United States, the current account version of Triffin runs as follows. The global accumulation of dollar reserves requires the United States to run a current account deficit. Since desired reserves rise with world nominal GDP, which is growing faster than US nominal GDP, the growth of dollar reserves will raise US external indebtedness unsustainably. Either the United States will not run the current account deficits, leading to an insufficiency of global reserves. Or US indebtedness will rise without limit, undermining the value of the dollar and the reserves denominated in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then in the end, the paper concludes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there is much to argue with Triffin and those who invoke his dilemma, there is no arguing the dilemmas posed by a national currency that is used globally as store of value, unit of account and means of payment. “The reserve currency is a global public good, provided by a single country, the US on the basis of domestic needs” (Campanella (2010)). Padoa-Schioppa emphasises the awkwardness of national control from a global perspective. But the global use of the dollar can pose dilemmas to the United States. How should the Federal Reserve respond to instability in the markets for $10.7 trillion in dollar debt of nonbanks outside the United States or in a like amount of forward contracts requiring dollar payments?The central bank ignores such instability at the peril of possible turmoil in US dollar markets that does not stop at the border – even if the floating rate index for dollar debts is brought back from London to New York. Yet the Federal Reserve responds to such instability at the peril of seeming to overreach its mandate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Issues arising from one country’s supplying most of the world’s reserve currency are not going away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A System Without a Purpose&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a while, the petrodollar system made a degree of sense, despite its trade-balance flaws. Unable to maintain gold backing in the previous system, policymakers managed to give order to an all-fiat system. The United States was the biggest economy in the world and the biggest importer of commodities, so our currency was the only one “big enough” to be used for the global oil trade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, as macro analyst &lt;a href=&quot;https://fftt-llc.com/index.php&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Luke Gromen&lt;/a&gt;, who in recent years has specialized in analyzing the petrodollar system and the US fiscal situation, has pointed out that the first two decades of the petrodollar system overlapped with the Cold War. So, the system helped strengthen US hegemonic power in a divided world. Love it or hate it, the geopolitical intentions of the system architects were clear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the 1990s onwards after the Soviet Union fell, as Gromen and others have argued, the system has made less sense, and has resulted in more US military involvement than need be (to put it lightly) as the US indirectly seeks to defend its hegemonic role without a clear direction or identity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, China is now the world’s largest importer of commodities, rather than the United States. It’s challenging to maintain a system of all oil and most commodities being priced worldwide in US dollars if there is a bigger global trade partner and importer of oil and commodities than the United States. The United States still has an unrivaled military reach, but its other justifications for the existing system are diminishing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shrinking US Share of Global GDP&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite all of this, China can’t replace the United States as the holder of the sole global reserve currency. Not even close. No single country can. And here’s why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the aftermath of World War II, the United States represented over 40% of global GDP. By the time the Bretton woods system ended and the petrodollar system began, the United States still represented 35% of global GDP. It has since fallen to only 20-25% of global GDP:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-11166&quot; src=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-us-gdp-world.png&quot; alt=&quot;US GDP Percent of Global GDP&quot; width=&quot;650&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-us-gdp-world.png 650w, https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-us-gdp-world-300x185.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 650px) 100vw, 650px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that’s nominal GDP (i.e. priced in dollars), so it is tied in part to dollar strength. If the dollar does have another bear cycle, this would be down to maybe 20%. And based on purchasing power parity (which more closely tracks commodity consumption), the US represents only 15% of global GDP. That’s still pretty good for a country with 4% of the world’s population, but really not enough to maintain the petrodollar system indefinitely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The global energy market, and more broadly international trade, is now too big to be priced primarily in the currency of a country that represents this small of a share of global GDP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine if the entire world tried to price energy exclusively in Swiss francs; there simply wouldn’t be enough of them out there for that to work. The petrodollar situation is not that extreme of course, since the United States is far larger than Switzerland, but the point is, as the US economy represents a smaller and smaller share of global GDP over time, it becomes increasingly unable to supply enough dollars for the world to price all energy in dollars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s no country or currency group big enough to do that alone anymore. Not the United States, not China, not the European Union, and not Japan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The United States was uniquely able to do it for decades in the aftermath of World War II as most other nations were decimated and the US share of global GDP became unusually high. However, as the world grows and becomes more multi-polar over time, with no individual country representing a domineering share of global GDP like the US used to, the global monetary system itself also requires more decentralization to work properly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we’re starting to see that happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multi-Currency International Trade&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Bloomberg &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-08-12/russia-ditches-the-dollar-for-bulk-of-its-exports-to-china&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;reported this year&lt;/a&gt;, exports from Russia to China have quickly de-dollarized over the past few years into a more diverse basket of currencies:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-11167&quot; src=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-share-russia-china.png&quot; alt=&quot;Dollar Share Russia China&quot; width=&quot;631&quot; height=&quot;353&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-share-russia-china.png 631w, https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-share-russia-china-300x168.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 631px) 100vw, 631px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chart Source: Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Six years ago, Russian exports to China were over 98% dollar based. As of early 2020, it’s only 33% dollar-based, 50% euro-based, and 17% with their own currencies. And importantly, Russia’s exports are significantly energy-based and commodity-based, which gets to the heart of the petrodollar system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, the article shows that Russian exports to Europe have become increasingly euro-based as well. Six years ago, Russian exports to Europe were 69% dollar-based and 18% euro-based. Now they’re 44% dollar-based and 43% euro-based.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plus, Bloomberg &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-08-04/putin-s-pledge-to-ditch-the-dollar-is-slowly-becoming-a-reality&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;reported back in 2019&lt;/a&gt; that Russia has been achieving similar results with India as well, with a remarkable drop from nearly 100% of exports to only 20% of exports being priced in dollars:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-11168&quot; src=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-share-russia-india.png&quot; alt=&quot;Dollar Share Russia India&quot; width=&quot;625&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-share-russia-india.png 625w, https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-share-russia-india-300x180.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 625px) 100vw, 625px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chart Source: Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn’t the first time this sort of thing was attempted. Back in 2000, Saddam Hussein &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2000/WORLD/meast/10/30/iraq.un.euro.reut/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;began selling oil priced in the newly-created euro&lt;/a&gt;. A couple years later, the United States invaded Iraq and removed Hussein from power based on allegations of Iraq possessing weapons of mass destruction. These allegations turned out to be untrue, and Iraq quickly went back to selling oil in dollars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is disputed to what extent Iraq’s decision to sell oil in euros factored into US decisions to enter the war, but what can be said is this. There is no shortage of malevolent dictators in the world, but that’s the one that we spent &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Casualties_of_the_Iraq_War&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;4,500 American soldier lives&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/us-taxpayers-spent-8000-each-2-trillion-iraq-war-study-2020-2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;$2 trillion in US funds&lt;/a&gt; to take out, and that’s without getting into the destruction on the Iraqi side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.congress.gov/congressional-record/2006/02/15/house-section/article/H318-2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;detailed speech&lt;/a&gt; by then-Representative Ron Paul to Congress in 2006 about Iraq and the euro, and broader themes about the petrodollar system as it relates to US foreign policy, including policy towards Venezuela and Iran. Although he’s a controversial political figure, regardless of what side of the political spectrum someone is on, I think that’s a speech worth being familiar with on the historical record.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, when major powers like China, Russia, and India begin pricing things outside of the dollar-based system and using their currencies for trade, including for energy in some cases, the US can’t realistically intervene militarily, and instead can only intervene with sanctions or trade disputes and other forms of geopolitical pressure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The latest hot spot has been multiple rounds and threats of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-11-11/nord-stream-2-sanctions-to-be-included-in-u-s-defense-bill&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;US sanctions&lt;/a&gt; for companies involved in the Nord Stream 2 pipeline from Russia to Germany, which if completed would strengthen Russia’s gas supply system to Europe. Both the United States executive branch and legislative branch have been quite fixated on that project. A number of US senators, for example, sent a letter warning of “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-08-07/u-s-threat-of-crushing-measures-on-gas-pipeline-angers-berlin&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;crushing and potentially fatal legal and economic sanctions&lt;/a&gt;” against Germany’s port operator involved with the project. German officials have pushed back, saying such sanctions threaten European sovereignty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another hotspot has been the US sanctions against Iran. Europe, India, and China all have trade relations with Iran and want to trade with them, and all of them are major energy importers whereas Iran is an energy producer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Europe created INSTEX in 2019, a special purpose vehicle to avoid US sanctions on Iran. The vehicle facilitates trade outside of the SWIFT system and outside of the dollar system more broadly. It has been &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dw.com/en/europe-and-iran-complete-first-instex-deal-dodging-us-sanctions/a-52966842&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;successfully tested&lt;/a&gt;, but barely used. Similarly, India has long had constructive trade with Iran, despite religious/cultural differences that often cause issues between India and its neighbor Pakistan and territorial disputes in Kashmir, but the Iran-India trade partnership has been constrained in 2020 due to a combination of US sanctions and COVID-19. China has a number of strategic energy partnerships and trade agreements with Iran as well, but US sanctions along with COVID-19 also threw a curveball into their trade situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;China is Subverting the Petrodollar System&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the past seven years, China has been using the petrodollar system against the United States. The petrodollar system encourages mercantilist nations to run trade surpluses with the United States and recycle those dollars into buying US Treasuries, but after a while of doing this, China started taking their dollar surpluses and investing in other foreign assets instead. This topic has been reported on by petrodollar experts like Luke Gromen and others for quite some time, but is not widely followed in the broad sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Early on in the days of the petrodollar system, Europe and the Middle East were the biggest trading partners and ran trade surpluses with the United States. They accumulated a lot of dollars, and reinvested those dollars into Treasuries. Then, Japan’s quick rise led them to become the next big trading partner and center of global growth. They took the baton and ran big trade surpluses with the United States, and again, reinvested those dollars into Treasuries. Then, with the stagnation of Japan and the rise of China, China became the biggest trading partner with the United States, ran big trade surpluses with the United States, and reinvested those dollars into Treasuries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All was well, except for the Americans who wanted to make things, or any folks, American or foreign, who were on the wrong side of military adventurism. The wheels of the petrodollar system kept functioning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then, China broke the wheels. Back in 2013, China declared that it was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2013-11-20/pboc-says-no-longer-in-china-s-favor-to-boost-record-reserves&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;no longer in their interest&lt;/a&gt; to keep accumulating Treasuries. They kept running huge trade surpluses with the United States, and had dollars still coming in, but they would no longer recycle those to fund US fiscal deficits by buying Treasuries. As per the linked Bloomberg article:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s no longer in China’s favor to accumulate foreign-exchange reserves,” Yi Gang, a deputy governor at the central bank, said in a speech organized by China Economists 50 Forum at Tsinghua University yesterday. The monetary authority will “basically” end normal intervention in the currency market and broaden the yuan’s daily trading range, Governor Zhou Xiaochuan wrote in an article in a guidebook explaining reforms outlined last week following a Communist Party meeting. Neither Yi nor Zhou gave a timeframe for any changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, China now holds fewer US Treasuries than they did seven years ago, even though they kept increasing their trade surplus with the United States through 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, they launched the Belt and Road initiative in 2013. China began aggressively lending dollar-based loans for infrastructure projects to developing countries in Asia, Africa, Latin America, and Eastern Europe, and providing their infrastructure-building capabilities as well, because infrastructure has long been one of China’s technical specialties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of those foreign loans, if defaulted on, mean that China gains ownership of the infrastructure. So, whether the loans are successful or not, China gains access to commodity deals, trading partners, and hard assets around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a map of global Chinese funding (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-subversion-china-global-loans.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;and here’s a bigger view&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-11169&quot; src=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-subversion-china-global-loans.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dollar Subversion Chinese Loans&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height=&quot;623&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-subversion-china-global-loans.jpg 1200w, https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-subversion-china-global-loans-300x156.jpg 300w, https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-subversion-china-global-loans-1024x532.jpg 1024w, https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-subversion-china-global-loans-768x399.jpg 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chart Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.visualcapitalist.com/global-chinese-financing-is-fueling-megaprojects/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Visual Capitalist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the US runs big trade deficits with the rest of the world (and especially China), but now rather than funneling those dollar trade surpluses back into financing US fiscal deficits, China uses its incoming dollars to finance hard asset projects around the world, and increase their global reach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this stage, instead of just blue-collar labor in America being hurt by the system, the geopolitical ambitions of United States hegemony are also subverted. As far as Americans were concerned, for 40+ years the petrodollar system used to work for the top half of the income spectrum but not really the bottom half, and now it neither particularly works for the top half nor the bottom half. It’s now a system without a purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s an old quote from Charlie Munger that goes, “show me the incentives and I’ll show you the outcome.” As clever as the design of the petrodollar system was in the 1970s, China’s subversion of the fraying petrodollar system was just as clever. The flaws of the system basically ask for it to happen eventually, and it’s mathematics and Triffin’s dilemma coming home to roost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a geopolitical standpoint, we can see why China would want to do it. The western powers severely damaged China in the 1800s &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Opium_Wars&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Opium Wars&lt;/a&gt; which contributed in part to the next 150 years of Chinese destabilization and stagnation, and now having regained a degree of organization and power, China isn’t playing nice with the global system as structured by those western powers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chinese officials have said on numerous occasions that their reliance on the dollar system is a security risk for them. Having &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.visualcapitalist.com/china-u-s-worlds-trading-partner/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;surpassed&lt;/a&gt; the United States as the world’s largest trading partner and world’s biggest importer of commodities, China increasingly has an interest in being able to acquire commodities and perform global trade without dollars, which as we see with trading partners like Russia, or with China’s yuan-based oil futures contract, they’re increasingly able to do with small steps at a time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, the United States faces increasing populism in its own country, as the persistent trade deficit becomes an increasingly political issue to fix. Plus, US officials have routinely pointed out the security risk of having so much critical supplies made outside of the country, which became even more apparent during COVID-19.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trap solution is for US policymakers to try to narrow the trade deficit by getting other countries to buy more American goods, but that’s like putting a Band-Aid on a gunshot wound. The deeper problem is that the global monetary system as currently structured simply doesn’t work well with that goal; it’s inherently designed at its core to run with persistent trade deficits to get dollars out into the world and enforce dollar-only global energy pricing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back on March 2, 2018, President Trump tweeted that “trade wars are good and easy to win”. Since then, the US trade deficit increased, rather than decreased. Trade wars are very difficult for the US to win within the petrodollar system as currently structured. The US can close its trade deficit over time, but not without changing the global monetary system from its current structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So on one hand, US policymakers do what they can with military action or sanctions against those that would sell energy in a currency other than dollars, and try to maintain the dollar lock on global energy markets wherever possible. On the other hand, the US wants to fix its deepening trade deficit, even though that trade deficit is what gets dollars out into the world for use by countries to sell oil in dollars or acquire dollars to buy oil. It’s an incoherent strategy, and it runs deep in US political culture, rather than tied to any one politician.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the entropy of trade deficits chips away at the existing system from within, China uses the system against the system’s owner, populism rises in the US and elsewhere, and countries throughout Eurasia gradually build non-dollar payment channels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eating Our Own Cooking&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of this year, the US Federal Reserve (blue line) now owns more Treasuries than all foreign central banks combined (orange line):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-11171&quot; src=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-fed-vs-foreign-cb.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dollar Crisis Fed UST Holdings vs Foreign CB Holdings&quot; width=&quot;680&quot; height=&quot;510&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-fed-vs-foreign-cb.jpg 680w, https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-fed-vs-foreign-cb-300x225.jpg 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chart Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.biancoresearch.com/visitor-home/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Bianco Research&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s not exactly how the “global reserve” currency is supposed to work. It’s like a restaurant chef eating her own cooking more than her customers do. This is what other non-global-reserve countries look like. Within one year, the Fed went from owning half as much Treasuries as foreign central banks combined, to more than them combined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As previously described, countries can only keep buying Treasuries if global dollar liquidity conditions are good. A strong dollar halts foreign accumulation of Treasuries. In addition, any impact to trade, such as a pandemic and associated economic shutdowns that crater oil demand and import/export volumes, threatens that whole system. And China isn’t recycling dollars into Treasuries for aforementioned strategic reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it relates to the Treasury market, in addition to not buying much Treasuries over the past five years of this strong dollar environment, some countries began rapidly selling Treasuries in March and April of this year at the height of the global shutdown and liquidity crisis. Leading into the pandemic, long-duration Treasuries rallied as investors flocked into them and drove their yields down, but at the worst point in the liquidity crisis as the dollar index spiked to 103, even Treasuries sharply sold off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Fed described the problem in their emergency March meeting and their subsequent April meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s March:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;14.175531914894&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Treasury market, following several consecutive days of deteriorating conditions, market participants reported an acute decline in market liquidity. A number of primary dealers found it especially difficult to make markets in off-the-run Treasury securities and reported that this segment of the market had ceased to function effectively. This disruption in intermediation was attributed, in part, to sales of off-the-run Treasury securities and flight-to-quality flows into the most liquid, on-the-run Treasury securities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;–&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.federalreserve.gov/monetarypolicy/fomcminutes20200315.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;March 2020 FOMC Meeting Minutes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here are two snippets from April:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;18.518003273322&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Treasury markets experienced extreme volatility in mid-March, and market liquidity became substantially impaired as investors sold large volumes of medium- and long-term Treasury securities. Following a period of extraordinarily rapid purchases of Treasury securities and agency MBS by the Federal Reserve, Treasury market liquidity gradually improved through the remainder of the intermeeting period, and Treasury yields became less volatile. Although market depth remained exceptionally low and bid-ask spreads for off-the-run securities and long-term on-the-run securities remained elevated, bid-ask spreads for short-term on-the-run securities fell close to levels seen earlier in the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several participants remarked that a program of ongoing Treasury securities purchases could be used in the future to keep longer-term yields low. A few participants also noted that the balance sheet could be used to reinforce the Committee’s forward guidance regarding the path of the federal funds rate through Federal Reserve purchases of Treasury securities on a scale necessary to keep Treasury yields at short- to medium-term maturities capped at specified levels for a period of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;–&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.federalreserve.gov/monetarypolicy/fomcminutes20200429.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;April 2020 FOMC Meeting Minutes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here’s what they did. The red line is 10-year Treasury yields. The blue line is the weekly rate of Treasury security purchases by the Fed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-10070&quot; src=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/newsletter-2020-8-soft-yield-curve-control.png&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 748px) 100vw, 748px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/newsletter-2020-8-soft-yield-curve-control.png 748w, https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/newsletter-2020-8-soft-yield-curve-control-300x180.png 300w&quot; alt=&quot;Soft Yield Curve Control&quot; width=&quot;748&quot; height=&quot;450&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chart Source: St. Louis Fed&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More importantly than the yield spike itself in March was the fact that the Treasury market became illiquid, with wide bid/ask spreads. It wasn’t functioning properly, let alone yields going up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since then, the Fed has gradually tapered their Treasury security buying program from those extreme $75 billion-per-day highs, although they are still buying at a rate that rivals previous instances of QE, at $80 billion worth of Treasuries per month. The Fed remains the biggest buyer of US fiscal deficits, in other words. The dollar weakened from its March highs, but is still at a relatively strong part in the historic cycle, and as such, the foreign sector isn’t recycling many of their dollars into accumulating Treasuries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s what happens when there is $13 trillion in dollar-denominated debt in the world, and plenty of dollar-funding needs, while dollars simply aren’t being supplied in sufficient quantity to the world. Foreigners begin selling some of their $42 trillion in dollar-denominated assets to get dollars, and that crashes US markets along with everything else, which forces the Fed to step in, print dollars to buy what they sell, and open dollar swap lines to foreign central banks, until sufficient global dollar liquidity is restored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Triffin’s Dilemma Unfolds&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, this gets back to the question of whether the United States should even want to try to maintain the petrodollar system, if it could.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As previously shown, the US trade balance is a mess:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-11161&quot; src=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-us-trade-balance.png&quot; alt=&quot;Dollar Crisis US Trade Balance&quot; width=&quot;691&quot; height=&quot;379&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-us-trade-balance.png 691w, https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-us-trade-balance-300x165.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 691px) 100vw, 691px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chart Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://tradingeconomics.com/united-states/balance-of-trade&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Trading Economics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The US net international investment position has absolutely collapsed, with the US having gone from being the world’s largest creditor nation to the world’s largest debtor nation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-11172&quot; src=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-niip.png&quot; alt=&quot;Net International Investment Position&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;320&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-niip.png 700w, https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-niip-300x137.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chart Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.principles.com/the-changing-world-order/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Ray Dalio, The Changing World Order&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The net international investment position of a country measures how much foreign assets they own, minus how much of their assets that foreigners own, and the chart above shows it as a percentage of GDP. As of this year, the United States owns $29 trillion in foreign assets, while foreigners own $42 trillion in US assets, including US government bonds, corporate bonds, stocks, and real estate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a result of accumulated US trade deficits (and on the other side, accumulated trade surpluses by the foreign sector), and now puts the US at one of the weakest positions in the world in terms of this metric. This was as of 2019, and it has gotten worse since then:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-11177&quot; src=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-niip-countries.png&quot; alt=&quot;Dollar Crisis NIIP Countries&quot; width=&quot;515&quot; height=&quot;369&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-niip-countries.png 515w, https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-niip-countries-300x215.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 515px) 100vw, 515px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Data Sources: IMF and various central banks&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wealth concentration in the US is now higher than just about any other developed nation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-11175&quot; src=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-wealth-concentration.png&quot; alt=&quot;Global Reserve Currency Wealth Concentration&quot; width=&quot;548&quot; height=&quot;463&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-wealth-concentration.png 548w, https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-wealth-concentration-300x253.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 548px) 100vw, 548px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chart Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.credit-suisse.com/about-us/en/reports-research/global-wealth-report.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Credit Suisse 2020 Wealth Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The top 1% have as much as the bottom 90%, which is a lot more concentration than 30-40 years ago:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-11176&quot; src=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/newsletter-2020-wealth-share-1-vs-90-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;678&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/newsletter-2020-wealth-share-1-vs-90-1.png 678w, https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/newsletter-2020-wealth-share-1-vs-90-1-300x199.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 678px) 100vw, 678px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chart Source: St. Louis Fed&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The United States is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.visualcapitalist.com/ranked-the-social-mobility-of-82-countries/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;ranked #27&lt;/a&gt; in the world for social mobility, which puts it at the bottom range of developed countries. For Americans, their family of birth dictates their lifetime economic potential more-so than other advanced peers. With a few exceptions, we have to go down into emerging/developing markets to find lower social mobility scores than the United States has.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Median American wages decoupled from productivity since the 1970’s, and that gap was arbitraged by those at the top thanks to offshoring/automation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-11174&quot; src=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-productivity-vs-wages.png&quot; alt=&quot;Productivity vs Wages&quot; width=&quot;631&quot; height=&quot;470&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-productivity-vs-wages.png 631w, https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-productivity-vs-wages-300x223.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 631px) 100vw, 631px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chart Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epi.org/productivity-pay-gap/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;EPI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, the median American male has trouble affording the expenses for a family that he could easily afford decades ago. Either an above-median income is required, or two incomes are required, because the median income just doesn’t support a family like it used to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-11178&quot; src=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-income-vs-expenses.png&quot; alt=&quot;Dollar Crisis Income vs Expenses&quot; width=&quot;609&quot; height=&quot;615&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-income-vs-expenses.png 609w, https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-income-vs-expenses-297x300.png 297w, https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-income-vs-expenses-150x150.png 150w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 609px) 100vw, 609px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chart Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/2020/02/24/this-chart-is-best-explanation-middle-class-finances-you-will-ever-see/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Washington Post, Oren Cass&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, there has been a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2018/01/22/heres-how-much-ceo-pay-has-increased-compared-to-yours-over-the-years.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;rapid increase in CEO pay&lt;/a&gt; over the past four decades. CEOs used to make 20x as much as the average worker in 1965, and that ratio moved up to 59x by 1989, 122x by 1995, and in recent decades has been well over 200x as much as the average worker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the 2019 Credit Suisse Wealth Report, although the United States is wealthy per capita, because that wealth is so concentrated, the median American net worth (which represents the 50th percentile- the middle person on the spectrum) is actually lower than the median net worth of most other advanced countries. We squeezed our middle and working classes harder than most other countries:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-11198&quot; src=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/petrodollar-us-median-net-worth.png&quot; alt=&quot;U.S. Median Net Worth&quot; width=&quot;586&quot; height=&quot;334&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/petrodollar-us-median-net-worth.png 586w, https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/petrodollar-us-median-net-worth-300x171.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 586px) 100vw, 586px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Data Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.credit-suisse.com/about-us/en/reports-research/global-wealth-report.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Credit Suisse 2019 Wealth Databook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s no wonder that populism is on the rise, both from the right and the left. Folks sense something isn’t working but differ on what they think the causes and solutions are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, the petrodollar system and the associated fiscal policy is fraying under its own inherent flaws over decades, which again gets back to the Triffin dilemma that to maintain a global reserve currency, you need to export an increasing amount of your valuable assets like gold reserves or your industrial base. That cost inherently makes these sorts of systems long-lasting but not permanent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, having the global reserve currency is an exorbitant privilege, because the benefits of hegemonic power outweigh the costs of maintaining the system. Over time, however, the upside benefits stay relatively static, while the costs keep compounding over time, until the costs outweigh the benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And from there, the value of the system depends on who you ask. Folks who are often on the higher end of the income spectrum who worked in finance, government, healthcare, or technology benefitted from this system, since they obtained many of the benefits of globalization and none of the drawbacks. Folks who are often on the lower end of the income spectrum, specifically those that make physical things, are the ones that benefitted least and gave the most up, since their jobs were outsourced and automated at a faster rate than other developed countries. But now with China also undermining the structure of the system, even the geopolitical/hegemonic benefits for the political class are subverted as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the system frays, it’s easy to point to external nations as the cause of this fraying. When they begin pricing things outside of the dollar-based system, or employing mercantilist currency policies, or building pipelines, or deciding to do something with their dollar surpluses other than reinvest them in US Treasuries, it can seem as though they are undermining an otherwise sound system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In reality, those external actions are a symptom of the more underlying flaws in the system: the fact that the United States is no longer big enough as a share of global GDP to supply enough dollars to fund global energy markets and global trade, the fact that the United States has to run persistent trade deficits to get dollars out into the system, and the fact that an all-fiat global currency system incentivizes mercantilist currency manipulation by many countries to generate trade surpluses against the US wherever possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether there are major changes to the system or not, I think probabilities lead to a weakening dollar in the years ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, another down leg on this dollar chart, even if the overall system structure doesn’t change much:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-11226&quot; src=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/petrodollar-dollar-index-cycle.png&quot; alt=&quot;Petrodollar Cycle&quot; width=&quot;1228&quot; height=&quot;536&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/petrodollar-dollar-index-cycle.png 1228w, https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/petrodollar-dollar-index-cycle-300x131.png 300w, https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/petrodollar-dollar-index-cycle-1024x447.png 1024w, https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/petrodollar-dollar-index-cycle-768x335.png 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1228px) 100vw, 1228px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chart Source: StockCharts.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Dollar vs Other Currencies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people ask why would the US dollar weaken more than other major currencies if all of them are printing a lot of money. What causes these big bear markets in the dollar?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, just because the US Federal Reserve turns dovish, doing plenty of QE and keeping interest rates at zero, why would the dollar be weak vs the euro, yen, pound, or other countries that are acting similarly dovish? It’s easy to argue that it should weaken against hard assets (and indeed, that’s probably the easier long-term trade), but why should it weaken vs other fiat?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first answer to that question has to do with magnitude. All major countries are acting similarly, but not at the same magnitude. US fiscal deficits as a percentage of GDP were larger than most advanced peers before the pandemic hit, and are larger than most advanced peers during this pandemic as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a chart I had in my November 2020 newsletter about the US federal deficit, showing that it’s the first time in modern history where the United States had a rising deficit (both in absolute terms and as a percentage of GDP) during the later years of an economic expansion:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-10882&quot; src=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/newsletter-2020-11-structural-deficit.png&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 678px) 100vw, 678px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/newsletter-2020-11-structural-deficit.png 678w, https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/newsletter-2020-11-structural-deficit-300x199.png 300w&quot; alt=&quot;Structural Deficit&quot; width=&quot;678&quot; height=&quot;450&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chart Source: St. Louis Fed&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, while Japan and Europe and China have positive trade balances and current accounts, the US has the aforementioned Triffin dilemma issue of structural trade and current account deficits. Here’s a chart I put together in 2019 using data from late 2018, showing that pre-pandemic, the US had the biggest twin deficit among major developed nations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-11181&quot; src=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-global-twin-deficits.png&quot; alt=&quot;Twin Deficits&quot; width=&quot;520&quot; height=&quot;421&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-global-twin-deficits.png 520w, https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-global-twin-deficits-300x243.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 520px) 100vw, 520px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Data Source: Trading Economics, various central banks&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, when US monetary policy also turns dovish as it did in 2019, the dollar has plenty of room to decline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second answer to that question has to do with valuation. Suppose a value stock had a price/earnings ratio of 10x, and you expect 5% earnings growth this year. And suppose a growth stock had a price/earnings ratio of 30x, and you expect 15% earnings growth this year. What happens if, despite expectations, the value stock only grows earnings by 4%, and the growth stock only grows earnings by 7%? Due to high valuation and the bigger relative gap vs what was priced in, the overvalued growth stock has a lot further to fall in that scenario than the value stock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dollar is specifically propped up in a bullish cycle due to tons of offshore dollar-denominated debts, structural scarcity for dollars outside of the United States to service those debts, and a decade of capital inflows to the United States. Now, in an environment where all countries including the US create massive liquidity and create more currency units, the currency that was specifically overvalued due to scarcity relative to required demand (the dollar) is the one that has the furthest to fall, because that specific scarcity/liquidity problem that was propping it up gets addressed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trade deficits imply an overvalued currency (too much importing power, uncompetitive export pricing), and trade surpluses imply an undervalued currency (too little importing power, and overly competitive export pricing). Mercantilist countries can manipulate their currency to keep those trade surpluses open for a while, and the global reserve currency can go decades with trade deficits, but when monetary policy stops pushing against these inherent trade forces, exchange rates have a tendency to push back towards the direction of balanced trade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the US is in a strong dollar cycle, has a big trade deficit, and then cuts interest rates and shifts from quantitative tightening to quantitative easing, the dollar has plenty of room to weaken compared to currencies of developed nations that already have trade surpluses (i.e. undervalued currencies), even though the dollar is the global reserve currency. We saw that happen this year, so the question is whether it will continue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plus, US stocks are more expensive than many other nations, even when adjusting for sector differences. So, if US equity indices can’t continue their period of outperformance, capital could start flowing elsewhere, which also weakens the currency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usually, due to equity valuations and shifts in policy, whatever equity region outperformed in one decade tends not to be the same one that outperforms in the next decade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-11182&quot; src=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-international-cycle.png&quot; alt=&quot;International Outperformance Cycle&quot; width=&quot;592&quot; height=&quot;431&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-international-cycle.png 592w, https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-international-cycle-300x218.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 592px) 100vw, 592px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chart Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ishares.com/us/strategies/international-etfs&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;iShares&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Risks to this view: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within a multi-year outlook, there will likely be occasional counter-rallies where the dollar outperforms other currencies, or even outperforms gold, despite being within a declining trend. So, maintaining a clarity of time horizon is important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar to how the pandemic was a 6-month curveball towards my view of a weaker dollar in the first half of 2020, there are other tail risks that could temporarily derail the outlook as well. An economic slowdown this winter, before the vaccines achieved widespread penetration and change consumer behavior? A sovereign debt or banking crisis in Europe, centered on southern European countries? A famine in China? A currency crisis in a big emerging market like Brazil? Some sort of unexpected military engagement between major powers?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any of those outcomes could cause a temporary spike in the dollar, similar to the spike that occurred in March. An outlook can be firm for structural reasons, but still needs to adapt as data change. That’s why I write newsletters and research reports regularly; things change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of inevitability, the eventual issue with southern European sovereign debt is one that should cause investors a lot of concern in the long run. The euro has structural issues of its own, with a monetary union but no fiscal union, although that’s a subject for another article. The euro has a lot of problems, but being overvalued isn’t one of them. In this strong dollar period, Europe has run persistent trade and current account surpluses:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-11193&quot; src=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-euro-area-trade-surplus.png&quot; alt=&quot;Euro Area Trade Surplus&quot; width=&quot;682&quot; height=&quot;366&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-euro-area-trade-surplus.png 682w, https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-euro-area-trade-surplus-300x161.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 682px) 100vw, 682px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chart Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://tradingeconomics.com/euro-area/balance-of-trade&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Trading Economics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A weaker dollar vs the euro, if it happens, could indeed reduce Europe’s trade surplus with the United States. But the corresponding emerging market boom that would likely come along with a weaker dollar, would open up other trading avenues for them as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;long&quot;&gt;The Long-Term Outlook&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The further we look out, the more we can think about a structural shift away from the petrodollar system itself rather than just another dollar cycle within the system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Slow Restructuring Option&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A structural change could happen gradually, as it already is happening. If an increasing share of global trade, particularly within Eurasia and particularly regarding energy and commodities, keeps shifting towards euros, yuan, and rubles and away from the dollar, then the system can become more decentralized over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, we could argue that the petrodollar system peaked in 2000, has been in a steady-state for the past 20 years since then, and is now potentially facing decline. This chart shows currencies held as a share of total central bank reserves:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-11183&quot; src=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-petrodollar-system-peak.png&quot; alt=&quot;Petrodollar System Peak&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;305&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-petrodollar-system-peak.png 700w, https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-petrodollar-system-peak-300x131.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chart Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.principles.com/the-changing-world-order/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Ray Dalio, The Changing World Order&lt;/a&gt;, purple annotations by Lyn Alden&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another way of looking at it is that it peaked in 2013 when foreigners owned a record high percentage of US debt, and China declared that it was no longer in their interest to keep accumulating Treasuries. Since then, the percent of Treasuries owned by the foreign sector has diminished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a base case, I expect this gradual outcome to continue happening, whether the United States participates or not, as various major powers continue to increase their usage of non-dollar payment systems over time, and an increasing percentage of US federal debt becomes owned by the Federal reserve and the US commercial banking system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Regional_Comprehensive_Economic_Partnership&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;RCEP trade agreement&lt;/a&gt; between many Asia Pacific nations, which creates the largest trade bloc in history, could further accelerate that trend, and new technologies including blockchains and domestic government-issued digital currencies, open up novel opportunities for new payment networks as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Fast Restructuring Option&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, a structural change could happen with a shock and stepwise change, like the end of the Bretton Woods system. This can happen in a few ways, but becomes more probable if the United States decides to actively promote a change rather than defend the status quo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the legislative side, the United States could reverse some policies that I described in “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/tax-shift/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;The Big Tax Shift&lt;/a&gt;” which would make onshore labor more competitive. This would include things like cutting payroll taxes or performing similar measures, and re-arranging other spending and taxing priorities, to emphasize some degree of industrial onshoring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the Treasury/Fed side, the easiest way would be through foreign-exchange reserves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Countries manage their currencies primarily with their foreign-exchange reserves, which consist of foreign currencies in the form of sovereign bonds, and gold. In some cases they also own foreign equities and other assets. These foreign-exchange reserves held by central banks around the world have multiple purposes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;They act as savings; a way for a central bank to be able to pay external obligations if necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a country’s own currency weakens (which makes imports more expensive, and in crisis situations can lead to major devaluation), their central bank can sell some of its foreign-exchange reserves and buy its own currency. This reduces supply and increases demand for their own currency, strengthening it. The bigger the reserves compared to the country’s monetary supply or GDP, the more “ammunition” they have to defend the value of their currency if needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a country’s own currency strengthens too much (which can be bad for export-driven countries), their central bank can print units of their own currency and use it to buy foreign-exchange reserves. This weakens their currency and increases their reserves for later.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Because the dollar is the axiom of the current global monetary system, Treasuries are the biggest component of most countries’ foreign-exchange reserves. The US itself doesn’t have much foreign exchange reserves. Emerging markets often have the biggest reserves, since they need them the most, but a handful of developed nations also have huge reserves as well, and just about every country has more reserves as a percentage of GDP than the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This chart shows foreign-exchange reserves as a percentage of GDP for dozens of countries, as of spring of this year when I assembled it. In terms of comparative magnitude for most countries, it hasn’t changed much since then:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-11195&quot; src=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-fx-reserves.png&quot; alt=&quot;FX Reserves&quot; width=&quot;554&quot; height=&quot;367&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-fx-reserves.png 554w, https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/dollar-crisis-fx-reserves-300x199.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 554px) 100vw, 554px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Data Source: TradingEconomics.com, various central bank websites&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the United States, this number includes our official gold reserves at this year’s gold prices, and gold indeed represents the vast majority of US reserves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Eurozone countries, the European Central bank also has another layer of reserves as well in addition to the individual country reserves on the chart, so the numbers on the chart for Eurozone countries mildly understate the total direct and indirect reserves relative to GDP for the euro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The US could devalue the dollar any time it wants by printing dollars to buy foreign assets or gold, and build more sizable foreign-exchange reserves in the process, which would be in line with other peer nations. With a nominal GDP of over $20 trillion, for each 5% of foreign exchange reserves as a % of GDP they want to have, the United States would need to print and spend over $1 trillion. So, adding a 10%-of-GDP reserve would cost over $2 trillion, especially as the dollar devalues in the process of building that reserve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s one of the potential endgame scenarios for how the United States could choose to abruptly end this system as currently structured. It could decide to cease being the axiom of the global monetary system and simply move to being the biggest individual player in the system by acquiring foreign-exchange reserves, devaluing its currency in the process, adopt various fiscal changes to promote on-shoring, and begin promoting rather than fighting the trend of energy and other commodities being sold in a handful of major currencies around the world rather than just the dollar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In doing so, it would sacrifice some of its international hegemony in favor of more industrial competitiveness and higher domestic economic vibrancy. The dollar would still be “a” reserve currency, and still the largest individual one, but wouldn’t be “the” reserve currency like it is now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Risks to this view:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big macro shifts have a tendency to take longer to play out than logic would suggest. These sorts of things don’t change easily, so predicting a sharp change to the global monetary system just around the corner is always going to be improbable, even if one day, one of those improbable things happens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m focusing on monitoring the slow option: the continued progress or setbacks of non-dollar exports/imports between major powers, particularly regarding energy and other commodities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I prefer “win/win” bets for long time horizons. Scarce assets, particularly industrial commodities, are historically cheap. Plenty of high-quality equities inside and outside of the United States are reasonably-priced. Alternatives like Bitcoin also offer asymmetric outcomes even with small allocations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this stage in the long-term debt cycle, currency devaluation of some kind or another is likely in the 2020’s decade, both for the dollar and other currencies, so having exposure to scarce assets could do well, regardless of what the global monetary system looks like at any given time based on the decisions of policymakers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;next&quot;&gt;What the Next System Looks Like&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What the next system will look like is an open question. I’ve seen multiple proposals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever form it takes, it’ll be decentralized in the sense that it won’t be completely tied to any one country’s currency, since no country is big enough for that anymore. It’ll be based around neutral reserve assets, and/or a more regional-reserve model based on a handful of key country currencies, with an expanded variety of payment channels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decentralized Energy Pricing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the heart of all of these systems would be the fact that the dollar would no longer be the world’s only currency for energy pricing. The euro, yuan, and perhaps a few others, or a neutral reserve currency, could be used in trade agreements to buy oil, gas, and various commodities, which unlocks the prospect for more global trade and reserve holdings in those currencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even without a major structural change or the formal adoption of a new system, this is already gradually emerging throughout Eurasia, as shown earlier in this article as other large currencies are increasingly used between trading partners including for energy. And as I previously described, the United States, if it felt the current system was no longer in its best interest, could accelerate this shift at any time by building foreign-exchange reserves and/or supporting other non-dollar payment systems for energy and commodities rather than opposing them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this sense, the world moves from a “global reserve currency” to a handful of “regional reserve currencies”. It doesn’t require new technology or new neutral currency units to do this, but it does require the continued development and usage of non-dollar payment systems. In addition, central banks can hold more gold as a reserve asset (which they already have been doing over the past five years) in this scenario, since it’s a neutral currency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alongside this trend, countries are increasingly launching or researching digital versions of their own fiat currencies, called central bank digital currencies “CBDCs”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to this base outlook, there are some additional layers that could be added on top, described in the following sections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Digital Global Bancor&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A number of policymakers have resurrected the idea of the Bancor as a neutral reserve currency for international trade, which already exists in diminished fashion as the IMF SDR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mark Carney, who was Governor of the Bank of England at the time, made &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/business/2019/aug/23/mark-carney-dollar-dominant-replaced-digital-currency&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;headlines&lt;/a&gt; in 2019 when he said at the annual Jackson Hole Symposium (in the United States right in front of US Federal Reserve officials) that the dollar is too dominant, and that a new digital currency could be used for international trade to fix some of the problems in the existing system. Coming from the head of the central bank of one of the United States’ closest allies, this was interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dollar’s influence on global financial conditions could similarly decline if a financial architecture developed around the new [digital currency] and it displaced the dollar’s dominance in credit markets. By reducing the influence of the US on the global financial cycle, this would help reduce the volatility of capital flows to emerging market economies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-Mark Carney, Former Governor of BOE, 2019&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carney also mentioned the Libra in more positive tones than many other policymakers have. Facebook made headlines earlier that year with the proposal of the Libra; a digital currency that would consist of a basket of multiple currencies. The idea of the Libra is basically a stablecoin Bancor issued by a massive private corporation rather than a supra-government entity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would ironically be a form of centralized decentralization. In other words, it’s a centralized agreement to create and use a unit of trade that is neutral and not tied to any one country’s currency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem with this proposal for a global digital Bancor, like a supra-government version of the Libra rather than a privately-issued one, is that it requires a lot of international cooperation and agreement to use it, something like a new Bretton Woods agreement. So, while certainly possible, something like that appears unlikely in such a fractured geopolitical system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Digital Regional Bancors&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A less ambitious form of a global digital Bancor idea is one or a set of regional Bancors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, suppose that the 15 nations of Asia Pacific’s new RCEP trade agreement agree to create and use some neutral digital currency between themselves. They’re already in a trading bloc, so organizing something like that is potentially more realistic than organizing something on a global scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then maybe a few other nations like Russia would be willing to accept that trading bloc’s Bancor as payment for oil and gas and other commodities like they do for the euro? Russia’s biggest commercial bank, Sberbank, has already experimented with blockchain technology and is an avid investor in tech companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blockchain technology creates new options for decentralized international payments, linked to a specific fiat currency or basket of fiat currencies weighted by a specific metric. This is the application of software to the relatively outdated global banking system; potentially a much more liquid medium for trade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, the largest commodity companies in the world, BHP, Vale, and Rio Tinto, all completed blockchain sales of iron ore to Chinese firms. Singapore banks were involved with the transactions as well. Singapore also hosted the counterparties that tested blockchain transactions with Sberbank of Russia. Technology can lead to all sorts of new payment channels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Referring to the recent exponential usage of existing private stablecoins on crypto exchanges, Nic Carter, the first crypto analyst at Fidelity, co-founder of blockchain analytics firm Coin Metrics, and who works at a blockchain venture fund, &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@nic__carter/nine-bitcoin-charts-already-at-all-time-highs-78abbfe82804&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;had this to say&lt;/a&gt; about stablecoin efficiency:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, capital existing in tokenized fiat format tends to enter the crypto industry but not leave. This is because crypto rails are fundamentally more convenient, more globalized, and less encumbered than traditional payment and settlement rails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-Nic Carter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adding governments to the mix to create regional multi-currency stablecoins i.e. regional Bancors for the purpose of international trade, could potentially make use of similar technology on a larger scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gold Standard&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some gold investors believe that countries will return to a similar system as existed pre-1944, with central banks storing large amounts of gold and backing their currencies with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While no country would willingly go on a gold standard at this point (since it limits their ability to run big deficits and grow the money supply, and goes against the current incentive of having weak currencies to be competitive in global trade and generate trade surpluses), some countries could turn to it in a time of crisis to stabilize a currency during a period of inflation, if something breaks down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year, the Dutch central bank &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dnb.nl/betalingsverkeer/goud/index.jsp&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;stated&lt;/a&gt; that gold could be used to collateralize a collapsed financial system and start over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;18&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shares, bonds and other securities: there is a risk to everything. If things go wrong, prices can fall. But, crisis or not, a bar of gold always holds value. Central banks such as DNB have therefore traditionally had a lot of gold in stock. After all, gold is the ultimate nest egg: the trust anchor for the financial system. If the entire system collapses, the gold supply will provide collateral to start over. Gold gives confidence in the strength of the central bank’s balance sheet. That gives a safe feeling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-DNB, 2019, translated to English&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a more benign way, a few years ago India’s central bank began issuing &lt;a href=&quot;https://m.rbi.org.in/Scripts/FAQView.aspx?Id=109&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;sovereign gold bonds&lt;/a&gt; on behalf of the government of India. These are government securities denominated in grams of gold. They pay lower interest rates than normal Indian sovereign bonds, because they eliminate currency risk. The government’s benefit is that they get to borrow at a lower yield. The investors’ benefit is that they get a more conservative investment, tied to gold prices instead of India’s currency, and can earn positive yield on gold exposure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether currencies are ever backed by gold in a broad sense again, central banks can hold gold as a reserve asset within any sort of global monetary system, such as the above-mentioned decentralized energy pricing system, or alongside digital currency baskets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bitcoin as a Reserve Asset&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dismissed by many, there is a fervent group of proponents for the idea that Bitcoin’s network effect is too strong to stop, and that it will continue to expand exponentially until it eats the global financial system, i.e. hyper-bitcoinization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a decentralized and open source project, adopted by many programmers and proponents around the world, many intelligent people have dedicated their careers to Bitcoin. It’s hard to find a more voracious group of people than those in the Bitcoin community, and increasingly over time, Wall Street money has poured in as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, Bitcoin has defied most expectations, growing from zero into a $350+ billion market cap digital asset in a little over a decade in an algorithmic price pattern that has rivaled the speed of even the most successful tech companies:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-11228&quot; src=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/petrodollar-bitcoin-market-cap.png&quot; alt=&quot;Bitcoin Market Capitalization&quot; width=&quot;650&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/petrodollar-bitcoin-market-cap.png 650w, https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/petrodollar-bitcoin-market-cap-300x185.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 650px) 100vw, 650px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plus, there are countless businesses such as exchanges, lenders, custodians, security solutions, and more that exist in the ecosystem around it. Additional technologies have wrapped Bitcoin in other blockchain layers for use as collateral in other digital asset protocols and decentralized finance applications as well, or to increase Bitcoin’s scaling potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To use a Game of Thrones analogy, as the leaders of the Seven Kingdoms feud among themselves in order to control the Iron Throne and subsequently rule all of Westeros, a small but exponentially growing threat of inhuman White Walkers quietly builds from Beyond the Wall, far outside of the luxurious castles, seeking to supplant the established system and render their petty human squabbles over the throne moot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-11220&quot; src=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/petrodollar-bitcoin-got.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bitcoin Night King&quot; width=&quot;669&quot; height=&quot;747&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/petrodollar-bitcoin-got.jpg 669w, https://www.lynalden.com/wp-content/uploads/petrodollar-bitcoin-got-269x300.jpg 269w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 669px) 100vw, 669px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back to the present, Bitcoin’s adoption as a store of value has indeed spread worldwide in a niche sense. Consumers in many developing countries with currency weakness have used it as a store of value, and people in many developed countries have used it as a speculative growth asset. Lately, publicly-traded companies on major exchanges have bought it, Square’s Cash App lets users buy it, Paypal lets users buy it, and successful investors like Cathie Woods, Bill Miller, Paul Tudor Jones, and Stanley Druckenmiller are bullish on it. Fidelity began researching it in 2014, began mining it in 2015, and continues to build out their institutional-grade custody and trade execution solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are also some emerging state-based uses for Bitcoin. In 2019 and increasingly in 2020, Iran has &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.bitcoin.com/iran-bitcoin-sanctions-inflation/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;turned to Bitcoin&lt;/a&gt; as a potential tool for performing international trade despite its sanctioned isolation. Bitcoin is verifiable, provable, requires no trust or cooperation other than agreement between parties to use it, and works well for large irreversible international transactions. Iran can subsidize Iranian Bitcoin miners with electricity resources, buy the bitcoins they generate, and use those bitcoins for international trade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if it never reaches the scale that some Bitcoin proponents believe it might, it could still be used as part of a global monetary system, either as an additional neutral reserve asset, or by smaller isolated countries that make use of some of its features with relatively little way for other nations to stop them from doing so, as Iran seems to be doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of seeing where this goes, we just have to see whether it keeps adding zeros to its market capitalization, or if it eventually fails to gain market value during one of its halving cycles and hits a saturation point somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the Bitcoin community has different views of what the asset means; there is no unified vision within the community, but rather a set of different views for the long-term potential of the protocol. Some view it as the world’s future money, while others view it as digital gold, a store of value, or a bank in cyberspace that will exist alongside sovereign-issued currencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, Michael Saylor, the billionaire founder and first CEO of a public company on a major exchange to invest corporate funds in Bitcoin as its treasury reserve asset (to the tune of hundreds of millions of dollars), has stated that he doesn’t view Bitcoin as a currency, but rather as a digital savings bank:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;25&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-901oao css-16my406 r-1qd0xha r-ad9z0x r-bcqeeo r-qvutc0&quot;&gt;Bitcoin is not a currency, nor is it a payment network. It is a bank in cyberspace, run by incorruptible software, offering a global, affordable, simple, &amp;amp; secure savings account to billions of people that don’t have the option or desire to run their own hedge fund.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-Michael Saylor, 11/12/2020&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-901oao css-16my406 r-1qd0xha r-ad9z0x r-bcqeeo r-qvutc0&quot;&gt;This is why Bitcoin&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;css-901oao css-16my406 r-1qd0xha r-ad9z0x r-bcqeeo r-qvutc0&quot;&gt;should be neither a currency, nor a payment network. The principles of humility &amp;amp; harmony dictate that we should allow technology partners to provide for payments, &amp;amp; defer to governments on matters of currency. BTC&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;css-901oao css-16my406 r-1qd0xha r-ad9z0x r-bcqeeo r-qvutc0&quot;&gt;is a purely engineered Store of Value.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-Michael Saylor, 11/19/2020&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world goes through periods of geopolitical order and disorder, and with that, comes the construction and subsequent fraying of the global monetary system each time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More troublesome, the inherent flaw of having the global reserve currency, in a theme that goes back to economist Robert Triffin from over half a century ago, is that in order to maintain the global reserve currency, the country must supply the world with its currency via structural deficits in one form or another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, the hegemonic benefits of being the reserve currency nation outweigh the costs, but as the benefits stay relatively static and the costs compound over time, eventually the costs outweigh the benefits and the system becomes unsustainable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, a system constructed around the US dollar decades ago when the US was 35% of global GDP, doesn’t work as well when the US is only, say, 20% of global GDP. It’s not about how big the US military is to keep its hegemonic status; it’s about whether the global monetary system as currently structured is still mathematically viable, and whether it even still supports the interests of the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put simply, there is a natural economic entropy to global reserve currency status, because inherent flaws in the system continue compound until they reach a breaking point. The challenge, of course, is identifying ahead of time where that breaking point is. A change in the global monetary system doesn’t necessarily mean bad things for the United States (indeed, the United Kingdom had an economic boom in the post-war years after it lost reserve currency status), but it does mean making a trade-off between international interests and domestic interests, and re-aligning trade as needed to obtain the desired balance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My base case is that going forward over the next several years, the global economy will, more likely than not, encounter the third dollar bear cycle of this current petrodollar system. If so, assets such as global equities, quality residential real estate, precious metals, industrial commodities, and alternatives such as Bitcoin, are likely to do well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From there, the global monetary system is gradually becoming more decentralized, in the sense that alternate payment systems and alternate currency settlements among trading partners are growing in use. This is indeed a more structural shift towards a new system. It could happen slowly, as it already is, or it could accelerate if the US itself also shifts out of the fraying system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Related Articles:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 16:18:38 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>paulsb</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.lynalden.com/fraying-petrodollar-system/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>If-then-else had to be invented</title>
<link>https://github.com/ericfischer/if-then-else/blob/master/if-then-else.md</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/ericfischer/if-then-else/blob/master/if-then-else.md</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4A94JsWTXXw&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1951835/53196872-e0f17880-35cd-11e9-86ce-f832c4d3e00e.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1951835/53196872-e0f17880-35cd-11e9-86ce-f832c4d3e00e.png&quot; alt=&quot;01&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi, I'm Eric. I'm here to talk about what seems like an absurd idea: that if-then-else had to be invented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1951835/53196889-ed75d100-35cd-11e9-8d4c-c5fbf76c2dfc.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1951835/53196889-ed75d100-35cd-11e9-8d4c-c5fbf76c2dfc.png&quot; alt=&quot;02&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If-then-else is how we talk about conditions in programming languages: if something is true, then do a thing, else do a different thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's just English, right? Except that it isn't. I can't use &quot;else&quot; as a conjunction in normal speech, only in computer programs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where did this &lt;code&gt;else&lt;/code&gt; come from? It's a mystery. It's too microscopic a detail to have made it into books on the history of programming languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1951835/53279381-bb936600-36c4-11e9-83ae-53858a8319a2.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1951835/53279381-bb936600-36c4-11e9-83ae-53858a8319a2.png&quot; alt=&quot;03&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It doesn't seem to have come from surveys or legal proceedings or algorithms as they were written before there were computers. You find &quot;if yes&quot; and &quot;if no&quot; and &quot;if however&quot;, but not &quot;else&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1951835/53196928-03839180-35ce-11e9-87e5-6a99846479ec.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1951835/53196928-03839180-35ce-11e9-87e5-6a99846479ec.png&quot; alt=&quot;05&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first computer to be able to perform different instructions depending on the result of a previous calculation seems to have been the Eniac. In 1946, Haskell Curry and Willa Wyatt wrote this report describing a program to invert a function. They used the name &quot;discrimination&quot; for the facility of making a decision based on which of two numbers was larger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1951835/53196947-0c746300-35ce-11e9-8db7-2e8f0fc2e1d8.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1951835/53196947-0c746300-35ce-11e9-8db7-2e8f0fc2e1d8.png&quot; alt=&quot;06&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Eniac did not have an instruction called &quot;discriminate.&quot; It was programmed by wires and dials on plugboards, and the control panel for the instruction that made a calculation for a decision was connected by physical wires to the instructions that could follow it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soon computers began to have enough memory that programs could be stored in memory instead of wired together. Instead of a physical sequence of instructions, there was a numerical sequence. A few special instructions could cause the computer to jump to a different point in the sequence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1951835/53197002-27df6e00-35ce-11e9-82b4-8f0085b79a31.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1951835/53197002-27df6e00-35ce-11e9-82b4-8f0085b79a31.png&quot; alt=&quot;07&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, for example, is the conditional jump instruction from one of the first commercially produced computers. It checked whether the last number calculated was negative. If so, it diverted the flow of control to some specified location in memory; otherwise, it let control continue to the next instruction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was meant for a specific usage pattern: if you wanted to do a task, say, 10 times, your program counted how many times it had done it so far and then subtracted 10. If the result was negative, the task wasn't done, so it jumped back to do another round.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1951835/53197024-3037a900-35ce-11e9-9813-dc2f2d5a5c2b.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1951835/53197024-3037a900-35ce-11e9-9813-dc2f2d5a5c2b.png&quot; alt=&quot;08&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea was carried forward into the first higher-level programming languages, like Halcombe Laning and Neal Zierler's language for Whirlwind. Their conditional jump worked the same way, except that the numbered steps of the program were algebraic expressions, not single machine instructions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1951835/53197039-362d8a00-35ce-11e9-8099-b1597edc5f97.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1951835/53197039-362d8a00-35ce-11e9-8099-b1597edc5f97.png&quot; alt=&quot;09&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first popular programming language, Fortran, generalized the idea by specifying jumps to three locations at once, depending on whether a calculation was negative, zero, or positive, and gave it the name &quot;if.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The three-way &quot;if&quot; was more powerful than just checking for a negative, but was probably more confusing, because every decision meant a discontinuity in the control flow instead of programmers only having to think about the normal case that continued on and the unusual case that jumped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1951835/53197053-3ded2e80-35ce-11e9-9fb6-d46dcb793984.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1951835/53197053-3ded2e80-35ce-11e9-9fb6-d46dcb793984.png&quot; alt=&quot;10&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flow-Matic, Grace Murray Hopper's predecessor to COBOL, made the three-way if a little easier to think about by talking about comparing two numbers instead of about the signs of numbers. It introduced the name &quot;otherwise&quot; for the case where the comparison wasn't what you were looking for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1951835/53220700-bf6aae00-361a-11e9-835d-27b359b4fb14.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1951835/53220700-bf6aae00-361a-11e9-835d-27b359b4fb14.png&quot; alt=&quot;algol&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All these programming languages were associated with one particular computer from one particular manufacturer. In 1958, two American and German computing organizations began a joint project to develop a standard machine-independent language, one that would be natural for people to talk about rather than natural to implement on some particular machine. Each group brought a draft proposal to the joint conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1951835/53227239-9524ea80-3632-11e9-927e-16e887a186a4.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1951835/53227239-9524ea80-3632-11e9-927e-16e887a186a4.png&quot; alt=&quot;11&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The German authors made two big conceptual leaps in their formulation of the &quot;if&quot; statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first was to let the conditional be controlled by any boolean expression rather than giving special priority to the less-than/equal/greater-than form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1951835/53197069-46456980-35ce-11e9-97a5-fd646c4bee15.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1951835/53197069-46456980-35ce-11e9-97a5-fd646c4bee15.png&quot; alt=&quot;11&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second big leap was that instead of causing an abrupt jump in the flow of control, their &quot;if&quot; statement only caused the flow to be temporarily diverted. At the end of the condition, whether the condition had been true or false, the program would resume at the &quot;always&quot; statement at the end of the block. The only difference would be whether the subsidiary statements had been performed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The example on screen shows two &quot;ifs&quot; in a single block, and you might think that the second one was intended to work as an &quot;else if&quot; does now. But they expected all the conditions to be evaluated, even if one had already been found to be true. So if the statements controlled by the first changed a value that the second comparison depended upon, both blocks of statements might execute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1951835/53197081-4d6c7780-35ce-11e9-92f7-f60bc220301f.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1951835/53197081-4d6c7780-35ce-11e9-92f7-f60bc220301f.png&quot; alt=&quot;12&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where the German proposal did have something like &quot;else&quot; was in a second, entirely different, conditional form called &quot;case.&quot; Unlike &quot;case&quot; as we know it now, their &quot;case&quot; was another way of writing boolean conditions, with the conditions set apart in a separate block from the statements they controlled. It sounds like they thought this form would be easier for more complicated comparisons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here is the first appearance of the world &quot;else,&quot; for the case where none of the other cases apply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1951835/53197096-54938580-35ce-11e9-8371-15fd57575ab1.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1951835/53197096-54938580-35ce-11e9-8371-15fd57575ab1.png&quot; alt=&quot;13&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why did they call it &quot;else?&quot; They don't say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What they do say is that this document was originally written in German and hastily translated into English. I think a carefully-chosen German word was probably translated as an archaic English word and then never revisited. Unfortunately we do not have the original German text to consult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1951835/53197793-cd471180-35cf-11e9-8fd5-7b032e01228d.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1951835/53197793-cd471180-35cf-11e9-8fd5-7b032e01228d.png&quot; alt=&quot;14&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The American proposal also had the idea of controlling statements by boolean expressions. It didn't even have an &quot;if&quot; keyword. Instead, if an expression was followed by an arrow, the expression controlled the statements that followed the arrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The notation doesn't make it obvious, but unlike the German block of ifs, in the American form, if one expression in a block evaluated to true, it did short-circuit and skip the following expressions, like &quot;else if&quot; does now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1951835/53197122-62e1a180-35ce-11e9-9f26-63c87e6687b4.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1951835/53197122-62e1a180-35ce-11e9-9f26-63c87e6687b4.png&quot; alt=&quot;15&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two organizations held a joint meeting and merged their proposals into a single document that they called the International Algebraic Language. Before long the language would be renamed to Algol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &quot;if&quot; statement in the combined document looks a lot like the German proposal, but eliminates the &quot;always&quot; statement to end the block. Instead, each &quot;if&quot; stands alone, and if you want multiple statements to be controlled by the same expression, you can use &quot;begin&quot; and &quot;end&quot; to group them together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is nothing like &quot;else&quot; in this formulation of &quot;if.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1951835/53197134-6aa14600-35ce-11e9-9312-9332ca7b8184.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1951835/53197134-6aa14600-35ce-11e9-9312-9332ca7b8184.png&quot; alt=&quot;16&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, Algol 58 also had a second conditional form, called &quot;if either.&quot; In this form, you could say &quot;or if&quot; to do the same thing as we now do with &quot;else if.&quot; But there is nothing equivalent to &quot;else&quot; by itself, without another &quot;if.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1951835/53197144-71c85400-35ce-11e9-99ac-1ed3f1dc165c.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1951835/53197144-71c85400-35ce-11e9-99ac-1ed3f1dc165c.png&quot; alt=&quot;17&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story gets muddy the next year, when several papers about Algol were presented at a conference. One of them was the paper where John Backus, who had previously led the Fortran project, introduced the idea of formal grammars for programming languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Algol as he describes it doesn't have the &quot;if either&quot; conditional form. Instead, it has a keyword called &quot;converge,&quot; which makes the top-level &quot;ifs&quot; inside its block behave like &quot;else ifs.&quot; It is not clear whether this was meant as an idea for a better &quot;if either,&quot; or whether it was an earlier idea that had already been rejected in favor of &quot;if either.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1951835/53197164-7bea5280-35ce-11e9-92eb-6dd24abf3967.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1951835/53197164-7bea5280-35ce-11e9-92eb-6dd24abf3967.png&quot; alt=&quot;18&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Either way, &quot;if either&quot; would soon be replaced. In 1957 John McCarthy at MIT had written a proposal for the project that became LISP, another extremely old programming language that still survives today. His proposal introduced the idea of the conditional expression, as opposed to the conditional statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The important distinction is that an expression must always have a value, while a statement can simply not be performed if the condition that controls it is not true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So his &quot;if function&quot; always ends with a clause called &quot;otherwise&quot; that gives the value of the expression when none of the other conditions have evaluated to true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1951835/53279391-c817be80-36c4-11e9-8fa5-fd1df6942fdf.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1951835/53279391-c817be80-36c4-11e9-8fa5-fd1df6942fdf.png&quot; alt=&quot;20&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;McCarthy's conditional expressions inspired Klaus Samelson to clean up and unify Algol's two separate conditional models at the end of 1959. He eliminated the entire &quot;if either&quot; form, leaving only the plain &quot;if,&quot; but added a clause called &quot;else&quot; that would be performed when the expression controlling the corresponding &quot;if&quot; had been false.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You could chain conditions together with &quot;else if,&quot; just like the previous &quot;if either&quot; had allowed with &quot;or if,&quot; but you could also use &quot;else&quot; by itself for a final set of statements that would run if none of the conditions had been true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1951835/53197180-83116080-35ce-11e9-85c2-ff53a345a4e5.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1951835/53197180-83116080-35ce-11e9-85c2-ff53a345a4e5.png&quot; alt=&quot;20&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;If-then-else&quot; was the single conditional form that appeared in the Algol 60 report the next year, and is the form that almost all subsequent programming languages have followed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although it seems clear to us now, it was hard for people in 1960 to think about, and the report spends a page and a half explaining how it works, including this arrow diagram.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1951835/53197193-899fd800-35ce-11e9-9605-2da38f85c006.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1951835/53197193-899fd800-35ce-11e9-9605-2da38f85c006.png&quot; alt=&quot;21&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned, the use of &quot;else&quot; as a conjuction sounds strange. Christopher Strachey's CPL programming language is the grandparent of C and therefore the ancestor of most current programming languages, and he refused to use &quot;else,&quot; calling it &quot;ignorantly incorrect English.&quot; He thought we should write &quot;test … then … or&quot; instead, which also doesn't sound very natural, and didn't catch on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1951835/53197217-91f81300-35ce-11e9-863b-5a017834f510.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1951835/53197217-91f81300-35ce-11e9-863b-5a017834f510.png&quot; alt=&quot;22&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The MAD programming language also went its own way. It was known for its extremely long keywords, and in addition to using &quot;whenever&quot; instead of &quot;if,&quot; it used &quot;otherwise&quot; instead of &quot;else&quot; and &quot;or whenever&quot; instead of &quot;else if.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is worth noting the indentation in the MAD manual's example. It took years before most other programming languages adopted this style of indenting conditions, even though it now seems unimaginable to do it any other way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1951835/53279397-d1089000-36c4-11e9-8582-fa90f64837a7.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1951835/53279397-d1089000-36c4-11e9-8582-fa90f64837a7.png&quot; alt=&quot;24&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But even while CPL and MAD shunned the word &quot;else,&quot; they kept the form and only changed the vocabulary. Language designers still search for the perfect way to write a &lt;code&gt;for&lt;/code&gt; loop, but the quest for the perfect conditional form seems to have ended in 1959. Thank you Klaus Samelson, for giving us a tool to think with and a word to puzzle over.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 12:43:11 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>fanf2</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars2.githubusercontent.com/u/1951835?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>ericfischer/if-then-else</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/ericfischer/if-then-else</og:url>
<og:description>!!Con West 2019 talk. Contribute to ericfischer/if-then-else development by creating an account on GitHub.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/ericfischer/if-then-else/blob/master/if-then-else.md</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Goodreads plans to retire API access, disables existing API keys</title>
<link>https://joealcorn.co.uk/blog/2020/goodreads-retiring-API</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://joealcorn.co.uk/blog/2020/goodreads-retiring-API</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;In news that surprises nobody, Goodreads last week quietly announced the deprecation of their public APIs. And I mean really quietly – the only people who were told about this were those unfortunate enough to have their existing &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.stephanieawilkinson.com/posts/2020-12-10-yonderbook-and-goodreads/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;API keys disabled&lt;/a&gt; without warning. Other than a small banner at the top of the API docs which mentions vague “plans to retire these tools”, nobody else appears to have heard anything from Goodreads, including those whose API keys remain active. So far it seems any key unused for 30 days has been disabled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://joealcorn.co.uk/assets/img/posts/2020/12/deprecated.png&quot; alt=&quot;Deprecation notice on Goodreads API documentation&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this is an “announcement” much in the way a windshield announces its presence to bugs on a highway, and with the same consequences: dead bugs. Some developers have taken to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/topic/show/21788520-api-deprecation&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;API discussion boards&lt;/a&gt; and blogs, but the overall impression I’m getting is grim acceptance. Really the surprising thing is how long it took them: Amazon has been in charge at Goodreads for almost 8 years now, and I think we’ve all been expecting this to come at some point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why now? What’s changed? Well, the fact is the market’s changing – and Goodreads isn’t. Alternative options are starting to emerge, and since Goodreads has forgotten how to innovate, it wants to use its market position to stifle innovation instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sad thing is it really only hurts the hobbyist projects and Goodreads users themselves. Anybody seriously attempting to compete with Goodreads is well aware of the Amazon-shaped elephant in the room and is likely prepared. It’s the users and the hackers that this move will harm, and if anything it further reinforces the need for viable alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally I’m going to continue pouring my efforts into building &lt;a href=&quot;https://beta.readng.co?utm_source=joealcorn.co.uk&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;readng&lt;/a&gt;. I’m already using it to keep track of my reads &amp;amp; collections, along with a few thousand beta testers. I’m really excited by our plans and think we have the right team to execute, but we also need a shift in consumer behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The web has to mature beyond advertising as a business model. For this to happen people are going to have to open their wallets, pay for the services they use, and support independent businesses. That’s how we build a web where indies can thrive - one that’s more village centre than financial centre. I think the shift is underway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;PS: &lt;a href=&quot;https://beta.readng.co/user/joe?utm_source=joealcorn.co.uk&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;here’s my own readng profile&lt;/a&gt;. You should probably use our Goodreads importer while our API key works, huh?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 11:07:56 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>buttscicles</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://joealcorn.co.uk/blog/2020/goodreads-retiring-API</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: An anti-book recommendation tool, to help you escape your echo chamber</title>
<link>https://abooklikefoo.com/escape/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://abooklikefoo.com/escape/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;SearchApp_Intro BreakBookBubbleAppreact__EmptyNotice-sc-154ogu3-0 iuILKS&quot; readability=&quot;18.593457943925&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Escape your literary echo chamber! 📚&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Break the Bubble&lt;/em&gt; allows you to find out which books you are statistically &lt;strong&gt;unlikely&lt;/strong&gt; to read. The more narrow your reading tastes are, the more you will be challenged by the results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start your search by entering a book you &lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;do&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; like. You'll then be asked to enter a second book. Etc. The more books you add, the more accurate we can be in discovering these anti-correlations and odd new reading possibilities!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try out these examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How does it work?&lt;/strong&gt;: Briefly, for each book entered we find the rarest but highest rated intersections and provide those to you. The query can be summarised as: which highly rated books are least read (and enjoyed) by people who've also read the books I have? To find out more about the recommendation engine generally, visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://abooklikefoo.com/&quot;&gt;the homepage&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Note: this is an experimental feature of &lt;a href=&quot;https://abooklikefoo.com/&quot;&gt;A Book Like Foo&lt;/a&gt; and was created by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/padolsey&quot;&gt;James Padolsey&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your query is taking a while. 😱 Sorry about that, but it's not long now! We're leaving no book unturned in order to find you your perfect matches. 🤓&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 09:05:16 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>padolsey</dc:creator>
<og:title>A Book Like Foo</og:title>
<og:description>Book recommendations that don't suck. Magically disambiguate your weird taste in books, and see what worlds may unfurl before you.</og:description>
<og:image>/dist/prev.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>https://abooklikefoo.com</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://abooklikefoo.com/escape/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why radio receivers won’t tune 800-900 MHz</title>
<link>https://computer.rip/2020-11-28%20the%20verboten%20band.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://computer.rip/2020-11-28%20the%20verboten%20band.html</guid>
<description>&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; 2020-11-28 the verboten band&lt;/strong&gt;

To start: yes, long time no see. Well, COVID-19 has been like that. Some days I
feel accomplished if I successfully check my email. I finally managed to clear
out a backlog of an entire handfull of things that needed thoughtful responses,
though, and so here I am, screaming into the void instead of at anyone in
particular.

That said, let's talk a bit about radios. It is probably unsurprising by now
that I have a long-running interest in radio and especially digital radio
communications---but people who come to radio from all kinds of different
perspectives run into one odd problem: the curious refusal of any receiver
to tune to certain frequencies in the 800-900MHz range.

A lot of people have a general knowledge that this has to do with some kind of
legal prohibition on reception of cellular phones. That's roughly correct, but
to fully explain the matter requires going into some depth on two different
topics: FCC regulation of radio devices, and the development of cellular
phones. The first sounds more boring, so let's hit that one first.

Generally speaking, most electronic products manufactured or imported into the
United States are subject to regulation by the Federal Communications
Commission. Specifically, they generally require an &quot;Equipment Authorization&quot;
from the FCC prior to being marketed. For purposes of this regulatory scheme,
electronic devices can be broadly divided into two categories: intentional
radiators and unintentional radiators.

An intentional radiator is something that is specifically intended to broadcast
a radio signal, like, say, a cellular phone. Intentional radiators must be
certified to comply with the specific Part of the FCC regulations relevant to
the service for which they will be used. For example, cellular phones must be
certified against Part 27, Wireless Communications Service, among others. The
exact process varies by the part and can be involved, but it generally
involves the manufacturer paying a certified test lab to perform certain tests
and complying with various other filing requirements which include placing a
label on the device which specifies its FCC approval. Device manufacturers
must file with the FCC a description of how this label will appear before they
receive approval to market the device, which is why the rough designs of
unreleased devices are sometimes revealed by the rough drawings in these
filings---tech journalists will watch these to get the dimensions of new
iPhones, for example.

By the way, when I say the &quot;FCC Regulations,&quot; if you want to follow along at
home these are promulgated as 47 CFR. So Part 27, for example, refers to 47 CFR
27. The ever lovely Cornell LII has the whole thing for your entertainment:
https://www.law.cornell.edu/cfr/text/47. There's some reading for when you need
help falling asleep.

But that's all besides the point, I'm more interested in talking about
unintentional radiators, devices which are not intended to produce RF radiation
but may still do so as a result of the operation of the electronics---this is
generally called a spurious emission, which is basically any RF emitted by
accident. These devices are certified under Part 15 of the FCC regulations[1],
and so are sometimes called &quot;Part 15 devices.&quot; Part 15 essentially limits the
type and amplitude of spurious emissions to prevent random devices causing
harmful interference due to defects in their designs.

What would we call a radio *receiver*, then? It is explicitly a radio device,
but is not intended to transmit anything. As a result, radio receivers are Part
15 devices. Most of Part 15 is very general and doesn't really say anything
specific about radio devices, it just limits spurious emissions and other
design standards. However, 15.121 gets a great deal more specific in
discussing &quot;Scanning receivers.' A scanning receiver is specifically defined
earlier in the regulation as a device capable of tuning to two or more frequency
bands in the range of 30-960Mhz. This has the fun result that nothing for the
GHz range is technically a scanner, but for practical reasons this doesn't
matter too much.

So what's in 15.121? This is:

47 CFR 15.121(a): ... scanning receivers and frequency converters designed or
marketed for use with scanning receivers, shall: (1) Be incapable of operating
(tuning), or readily being altered by the user to operate, within the frequency
bands allocated to the Cellular Radiotelephone Service in part 22 of this
chapter (cellular telephone bands). ... (b) Be designed so that the tuning,
control and filtering circuitry is inaccessible. The design must be such that
any attempts to modify the equipment to receive transmissions from the Cellular
Radiotelephone Service likely will render the receiver inoperable. 

The rest of paragraph (a) gives a pretty long clarification of &quot;readily being
altered by the user,&quot; and it's amusing to think of a bunch of FCC characters
sitting around a table trying to think up every alteration that is easy.
Jumper wires and reprogramming micro-controllers are both right out.

It gets even better:

47 CFR 15.121(b): ... scanning receivers shall reject any signals from the
Cellular Radiotelephone Service frequency bands that are 38 dB or lower based
upon a 12 dB SINAD measurement, which is considered the threshold where a
signal can be clearly discerned from any interference that may be present. 

So, here's this actual weird rule about scanners. Scanners are specifically
prohibited from being able to tune to any bands allocated to the Part 22
Cellular Radiotelephone Service. This raises questions, and as you can imagine
from the way I got here, I am about to spend a long time answering them.

When the FCC says &quot;Cellular Radiotelephone Service,&quot; they aren't talking about
cell phones in general. The CRS as I'll call it refers to a *very specific*
cellular service, and that is AMPS.

AMPS, the Advanced Mobile Phone System, is the most common in the US of the
&quot;1G&quot; cellular services. Most carriers that were around when it was offered
called it &quot;Analog&quot; service, and indeed, AMPS was entirely analog. And, due to
an odd detail of the regulation, large cellular carriers were *required* to
offer AMPS service until 2008, long after AMPS phones were no longer produced.
You may have had a candy bar phone back when you would occasionally see an &quot;A&quot;
for analog service, but I hope not into the late 2000s.

There are a few things that we might infer from AMPS being an analog service.
One of those things is that it probably did not employ strong encryption. In
fact, AMPS employed no scrambling or enciphering of any kind. Your phone
conversations were just flapping in the wind for anyone to hear. This posed a
major practical problem for carriers in the '90s as it was discovered that it
was not particularly difficult to intercept the call setup process from an AMPS
phone and swipe its identification numbers, allowing you to basically steal
someone else's cellular service. You can imagine that this was popular with
certain criminals with a need for untraceable but convenient communications.

There was also a problem for consumers: their phone conversations could be
fairly easily overheard. There were a number of ways to do this, using any
radio scanner that covered that band for example. One particularly well-known
option was a particular model of phone, the Oki 900, that had an unusually
open design (in terms of modifiability) that led to reverse engineered and
modified firmware being developed that made eavesdropping on other people's
calls just, well, a feature it had.

The scale of this problem was fairly large, and it was fairly well known. For
example, let's turn to *my* favorite source of late-night reading, newspaper
archives. A lovely piece in the 30 May 1990 issue of The News and Observer,
from Raleigh NC, takes the cheesy headline &quot;Monitoring Megahertz&quot; and goes
into some depth on the issue.

&quot;I've heard men call their wives and tell them they'll be home late, then call
their girl friends,&quot; quipped one electronics store owner who had &quot;accidentally&quot;
eavesdropped on cellular calls using a scanner. We've all fat-fingered our
ways into someone else's affairs I'm sure, pun intended. Another person said
&quot;when you look at the fact that there are how many thousands of people out
there who know my name, my mailing address and my salary...I put cellular
eavesdropping down as being no different from that.&quot; In the face of technology,
even in 1990, people had begun to abandon their privacy.

Cellular carriers were not so happy about this, viewing it as an embarrassment
to their operation. I have heard before that cellular carriers went so far as
to lobby for banning scanners entirely, although I am not aware of much hard
evidence of this. What they did do was convince congress to stick an extra few
paragraphs onto an otherwise only tangentially related bit of legislation
called the Telephone Disclosure and Dispute Resolution Act of 1992. This has
largely to do with abusive 1-900 numbers, which is its whole own topic in
telephone regulation that I ought to take on sometime. But it also brought
along just a bit more, an extra section that was subsequently amended several
times at the behest of cellular carriers. Let's read part of it, as amended,
and with some editing for readability.

The Commission shall prescribe and make effective regulations denying equipment
authorization for any scanning receiver that is capable of---(A) receiving
transmissions in the frequencies allocated to the domestic cellular radio
telecommunications service, (B) readily being altered by the user to receive
transmissions in such frequencies, or (C) being equipped with decoders that
convert digital cellular transmissions to analog voice audio.

Well, we've made it full circle: we've seen the regulation, and we've seen the
legislation that kicked the FCC to write the regulation. But how does this
translate today? Things get a bit weird there.

You see, the FCC seems to have (sensibly) interpreted the legislation as
applying directly to the Cellular Radiotelephone Service, even though the
legislation actually uses the term &quot;domestic cellular radio communications
service&quot; which seems almost equally lively to have been (1) intended to be more
general in its applicability or (2) a result of someone drafting legislation
having read &quot;Cellular Radiotelephone Service&quot; in the FCC regulations but then
forgetting exactly how it was worded.

The Cellular Radiotelephone Service was allocated 824-849MHz and later
869-894MHz. That's it. You see, all of the digital cellular systems we use
today are considered completely different services from Cellular Radiotelephone
(usually called Wireless Communications Service although the details get
complex). As a result, and to this day, those two sections in the 800MHz band
are verboten to scanners, and nothing else.

And about those frequencies... after the requirement for AMPS service ended,
all US carriers ceased AMPS operations. The old AMPS bands remain allocated for
cellular service, and Verizon and a couple of smaller carriers use the same
frequencies for digital cellular services, which employ encryption and cannot
be intercepted by radio scanners. The prohibition on tuning scanners to these
frequencies no longer makes any sense, especially since this ban has never been
extended to the AWS, PCS, and WCS bands that are more widely used by modern
cellular phones.

My suspicion is that the fact that this regulation was mandated by congress
makes it difficult for the FCC to remove or modify, even though it no longer
makes technical sense. Unless congress finds some time for minutiae we are
unlikely to see a change in this rule.

In general, the whole thing is sort of bizarre. Broadly speaking, it is legal
to listen in on any radio communications in the US, but cellular phones have
repeatedly gotten a special carve-out.

Repeatedly? That's right. The whole AMPS band and scanners rule is the only
specific *technical* regulation, but the Electronic Communications Privacy Act
of 1986 had actually already made it illegal to intercept or listen in on
cellular calls, and this remains true to the present day... but there was
virtually no enforcement, and that hasn't really changed to this day.

And of course the whole thing has always felt like a farce. The solution to the
poor (or rather nonexistent) security design of AMPS was never legislation, but
cellular carriers and the congress will be damned if they didn't try. In
practice, the rule swept the entire eavesdropping problem under the rug for
some years, allowing carriers to continue operating the insecure AMPS system
for far longer than they should have (...but exactly as long as the FCC
required them to).

Because listening to the modern digital cellular modes wouldn't be particularly
interesting or useful anyway, and this rule doesn't really deter anyone with
the motivation and ability to decode those modes anyway, there are two lasting
impacts of this rather particular rule:

1) SDRs and other receivers made today must implement this particular and
peculiar restriction in order to receive US equipment authorization, which is
probably part of the reason that a lot of SDRs... don't.

2) To comply with the specifics of the regulation about rejection, many
receivers use a notch filter around 850MHz in their frontend. This means that
reception throughout the 800-900MHz range is particularly poor, a real
irritation as various public agencies and private agencies (especially
railroads) use land-mobile radios elsewhere in the 800-900Mhz range.

Basically, more than a decade after any of this made sense, we're all still
hassling with it.

[1] Part 15 is actually a lot more general and unintentional radiators are
specifically discussed under 47 CFR 15.101, but everyone just says Part 15.
&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 00:32:26 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jtakkala</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://computer.rip/2020-11-28%20the%20verboten%20band.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>SCOTUS rules you may sue government agents for damages when they violate rights</title>
<link>https://ij.org/press-release/u-s-supreme-court-rules-unanimously-you-may-sue-government-agents-for-damages-when-they-violate-your-individual-rights/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://ij.org/press-release/u-s-supreme-court-rules-unanimously-you-may-sue-government-agents-for-damages-when-they-violate-your-individual-rights/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Arlington, Va.&lt;/strong&gt;—In a unanimous opinion issued today by the U.S. Supreme Court, and authored by Associate Justice Clarence Thomas, the Court ruled in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.supremecourt.gov/opinions/20pdf/19-71_qol1.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tanzin v. Tanvir&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that individuals may seek damages as a remedy when federal officers violate their rights. The opinion closely tracks an amicus brief submitted by the Institute for Justice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case involved FBI agents who retaliated against Muslim-Americans and green-card holders who followed the dictates of their faith and refused to cooperate with the FBI by spying on their own communities. As a result of their refusal to cooperate, these individuals were placed on the No Fly List, which caused significant hardship, such as the inability to travel to visit family or for work. Luckily, Congress provided a statutory authorization to sue for violations of religious rights, allowing a plaintiff to receive “appropriate relief against the government.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not surprisingly, in the lawsuit against the FBI agents, the government argued that the words “appropriate relief” do not include damages. According to the government, damages might be an appropriate remedy against private actors, but damages should not be allowed if the person who violated your rights happens to work for the government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Institute for Justice filed an amicus brief arguing against this radical notion. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.supremecourt.gov/DocketPDF/19/19-71/132799/20200212125602641_Brief%20of%20Amicus%20Curiae%20Institute%20for%20Justice.pdf&quot;&gt;IJ’s brief&lt;/a&gt; outlined how suits for damages against government officials are the historical cornerstone of government accountability, how damages are often the only way to vindicate constitutional rights, and how none of the government’s policy justifications against damages have a basis in reality. IJ further explained that matters of policy should be left to Congress, not courts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a unanimous opinion, the Supreme Court agreed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the Court, “in the context of suits against Government officials, damages have long been awarded as appropriate relief.” And that has been true not only for state and local officials, but also federal officials, like those employed by the FBI. Moreover, the Court highlighted that damages are important because they are often the only remedy available. For example, for one of the plaintiffs, Muhammad Tanvir, who lost his job because of his placement on the No Fly List, it is damages or nothing. Finally, in response to the government’s argument that policy favors denying a damages remedy against government officials, Justice Thomas, just like Justice Story two centuries before him, emphasized that it is the job of Congress to engage in policy making: “[T]here are no constitutional reasons why we must do so in its stead.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The Court today has provided its full-throated endorsement of damages as a necessary and historic mechanism for constitutional accountability,” said Scott Bullock, IJ’s president and general counsel. “In doing so, the Court also reiterated its support for the foundational principles of this country, such as that damages can be awarded to check the government’s power and that it is Congress’ job to engage in policy making. The Court’s job is to interpret the law, not to do policy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IJ’s support for the individuals who sued the government in this case is part of its &lt;a href=&quot;https://ij.org/issues/project-on-immunity-and-accountability/&quot;&gt;Project on Immunity and Accountability&lt;/a&gt;, which is devoted to the simple idea that government officials are not above the law; if citizens must follow the law, then the government must follow the Constitution. IJ’s recent U.S. Supreme Court case &lt;a href=&quot;https://ij.org/case/brownback-v-king/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Brownback v. King&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is also a part of this Project. It similarly asks the Court to stay true to this nation’s original promise by allowing James King—an innocent college student who was brutally beaten by police—his day in court, to hold accountable the government workers who violated his constitutional rights and to seek damages for the harm they caused him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#  #  #&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE&lt;/strong&gt;:   &lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;To arrange interviews&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; on this subject, journalists may call John Kramer, IJ’s vice president for communications, at (703) 682-9323 ext. 205.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 21:31:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>apsec112</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>U.S. Supreme Court Rules Unanimously You May Sue Government Agents for Damages When They Violate Your Individual Rights - Institute for Justice</og:title>
<og:description>Arlington, Va.—In a unanimous opinion issued today by the U.S. Supreme Court, and authored by Associate Justice Clarence Thomas, the Court ruled in Tanzin v. Tanvir that individuals may seek damages as a remedy when federal officers violate their rights. The opinion closely tracks an amicus brief submitted by the Institute for Justice. The case…</og:description>
<og:url>https://ij.org/press-release/u-s-supreme-court-rules-unanimously-you-may-sue-government-agents-for-damages-when-they-violate-your-individual-rights/</og:url>
<og:image>https://ij.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/Supreme_Court-DRW_5047-683x1024.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://ij.org/press-release/u-s-supreme-court-rules-unanimously-you-may-sue-government-agents-for-damages-when-they-violate-your-individual-rights/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>I Hacked into Facebook&amp;#039;s Legal Department Admin Panel</title>
<link>https://alaa.blog/2020/12/how-i-hacked-facebook-part-one/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://alaa.blog/2020/12/how-i-hacked-facebook-part-one/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;We’ve been in this pandemic since  March and once the pandemic started I was having plenty of free time, And I need to use that time wisely, So I’ve decided to take the OSWE certification and I finished the exam on 8 of August, after that, I took a couple of weeks to recover from the OSWE exam, then in the med of September, I said you know what? I did not register my name in the Facebook hall of fame for 2020 as I do every year. okay, let’s do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I never found a vulnerability on one of Facebook subdomains, and I took a look at some writeups and I saw one writeup in one of Facebook subdomains which It got all my attention It was a great write up you can check it out &lt;a href=&quot;https://ysamm.com/?p=280&quot;&gt;[HTML to PDF converter bug leads to RCE in Facebook server.]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So after reading this writeup now I took a good idea about how many vulnerabilities I could find in such a huge web app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So my main target was https://legal.tapprd.thefacebook.com and my goal was RCE or something similar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ran some fuzzing tools just to get the full endpoints of this web app and I took a 2 hours nap and watched a movie, Then I got back to see the results okay I got some good results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dirs found with a 403 response:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;line-numbers&quot;&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-markup&quot;&gt;
Dirs found with a 403 response:

/tapprd/
/tapprd/content/
/tapprd/services/
/tapprd/Content/
/tapprd/api/
/tapprd/Services/
/tapprd/temp/
/tapprd/logs/
/tapprd/logs/portal/
/tapprd/logs/api/
/tapprd/certificates/
/tapprd/logs/auth/
/tapprd/logs/Portal/
/tapprd/API/
/tapprd/webroot/
/tapprd/logs/API/
/tapprd/certificates/sso/
/tapprd/callback/
/tapprd/logs/callback/
/tapprd/Webroot/
/tapprd/certificates/dkim/
/tapprd/SERVICES/
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, I think this result is very enough to support my previous theory about how huge this application, Then I started to read the javascript files to see how the website works and what methods it uses ..etc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I noticed a way to bypass the redirection into the Login SSO, https://legal.tapprd.thefacebook.com/tapprd/portal/authentication/login and after analyzing the login page, I noticed this endpoint&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;/tapprd/auth/identity/user/forgotpassword&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and after doing some fuzzing on the user endpoint I’ve noticed another endpoint which its &lt;strong&gt;/savepassword  &lt;/strong&gt;and it was expecting a POST request, Then after reading the javascript files I knew how the page work, there should be a generated token and xsrf token.. etc The idea that first came to me okay, Lets test it and see if it will work I tried to change manually using burp suite but I got an error, the error &lt;em&gt;was execution this operation failed&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I said okay, this might be because the email is wrong or something? let’s get an admin email, Then I started to put random emails in a list to make a wordlist and after that, I used the intruder and I said let’s see what will happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got back after a couple of hours I found the same error results plus one other result, This one was 302 redirect to the login page, I said wow, I’ll be damned if this worked Haha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let’s get back to see what I’ve done here, I sent random requests using intruder with a CSRF token and random emails with a new password to this endpoint &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;/savepassword&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and one of the results was 302 redirect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_128&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot;&gt;&lt;img aria-describedby=&quot;caption-attachment-128&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot; wp-image-128&quot; src=&quot;https://alaa.blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/redirect-login.png&quot; alt=&quot;fbredtrect&quot; width=&quot;989&quot; height=&quot;446&quot; srcset=&quot;https://alaa.blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/redirect-login.png 1671w, https://alaa.blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/redirect-login-300x135.png 300w, https://alaa.blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/redirect-login-1024x461.png 1024w, https://alaa.blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/redirect-login-768x346.png 768w, https://alaa.blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/redirect-login-1536x692.png 1536w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 989px) 100vw, 989px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p id=&quot;caption-attachment-128&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Redirect&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now I went to the login page and I put the login email and the new password and BOOM I logged in Successfully into the application and I can enter the admin panel 🙂&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;alignnone wp-image-129&quot; src=&quot;https://alaa.blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/fblegal-admin.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;882&quot; height=&quot;468&quot; srcset=&quot;https://alaa.blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/fblegal-admin.png 1785w, https://alaa.blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/fblegal-admin-300x159.png 300w, https://alaa.blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/fblegal-admin-1024x543.png 1024w, https://alaa.blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/fblegal-admin-768x407.png 768w, https://alaa.blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/fblegal-admin-1536x815.png 1536w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 882px) 100vw, 882px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I read the hacker report who found RCE before using the PDF and they gave him a reward of 1000$ only so I said okay, let’s make a good Impact here and a perfect exploit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote a quick and simple script to exploit this vulnerability with python you put the email and the new password and the script will change the password.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-136&quot; src=&quot;https://alaa.blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Exploit1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;983&quot; height=&quot;123&quot; srcset=&quot;https://alaa.blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Exploit1.png 983w, https://alaa.blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Exploit1-300x38.png 300w, https://alaa.blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Exploit1-768x96.png 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 983px) 100vw, 983px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Impact here was so high because the Facebook workers used to login with their workplace accounts, Which mean they’re using their Facebook accounts access token, and maybe if another attacker wanted to exploit this it might give him the ability to gain access to some Facebook workers accounts .. etc &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I reported the vulnerability and the report triaged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And on 2 of October, I received a bounty of 7500$ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;alignnone wp-image-130&quot; src=&quot;https://alaa.blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/reward.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;654&quot; height=&quot;171&quot; srcset=&quot;https://alaa.blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/reward.png 696w, https://alaa.blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/reward-300x78.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 654px) 100vw, 654px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed exploiting this vulnerability so much, so I said that’s not enough, this is a weak script! let’s dig more and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I found two more vulnerabilities on the same application, But we will talk about the other vulnerabilities in the Part two writeup 🙂&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;sexy-author-bio&quot; class=&quot;alaa-abdulridha&quot;&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;sab-gravatar&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://alaa.blog/author/alaaabdulridha/&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://alaa.blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/aaaaaaaaaa-150x150.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;100&quot; alt=&quot;Alaa Abdulridha&quot; class=&quot;avatar avatar-100 wp-user-avatar wp-user-avatar-100 photo avatar-default&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;sab-description&quot;&gt;My name is Alaa Abdulridha I'm a computer engineering student and cybersecurity researcher I'm interested in web application pen-testing and game development, also I'm interested in some bug bounty programs, I like a lot of things such as reverse engineering, reading the others code to learn and then to find my own exploits and teaching it to you, Do you want to know more about me? &lt;a href=&quot;https://alaa.blog/whoami/&quot;&gt;Click Here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 20:17:12 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>hackerpain</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://alaa.blog/2020/12/how-i-hacked-facebook-part-one/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>