<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Inheritance Often Doesn&amp;#039;t Make Sense</title>
<link>https://www.sicpers.info/2018/03/why-inheritance-never-made-any-sense/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.sicpers.info/2018/03/why-inheritance-never-made-any-sense/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;There are three different types of inheritance going on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ontological&lt;/em&gt; inheritance is about specialisation: this thing is a specific variety of that thing (a football &lt;em&gt;is a&lt;/em&gt; sphere &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; it has this radius)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abstract data type&lt;/em&gt; inheritance is about substitution: this thing behaves in all the ways that thing does &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; has this behaviour (this is the Liskov substitution principle)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Implementation&lt;/em&gt; inheritance is about code sharing: this thing takes &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; of the properties of that thing &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; overrides or augments them in this way. The inheritance in my post &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sicpers.info/2018/03/on-inheritance/&quot;&gt;On Inheritance&lt;/a&gt; is this type and &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; this type of inheritance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;These are three different, and frequently irreconcilable, relationships. Requiring any, or even all, of them, presents no difficulty. However, requiring &lt;em&gt;one mechanism&lt;/em&gt; support any two or more of them is asking for trouble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A common counterexample to OO inheritance is the relationship between a square and a rectangle. Geometrically, a square &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; a specialisation of a rectangle: every square is a rectangle, not every rectangle is a square. For all s in Squares, s is a Rectangle and width of s is equal to height of s. As a type, this relationship is reversed: you can use a rectangle everywhere you can use a square (by having a rectangle with the same width and height), but you cannot use a square everywhere you can use a rectangle (for example, you can’t give it a different width and height).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice that this is incompatibility between the inheritance directions of the &lt;em&gt;geometric properties&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;abstract data type properties&lt;/em&gt; of squares and rectangles; two dimensions which are completely unrelated to each other and indeed to any form of software implementation. We have so far said nothing about implementation inheritance, so haven’t even considered writing software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smalltalk and many later languages use single inheritance for implementation inheritance, because multiple inheritance is &lt;em&gt;incompatible&lt;/em&gt; with the goal of implementation inheritance due to the diamond problem (traits provide a &lt;em&gt;reliable&lt;/em&gt; way for the incompatibility to manifest, and leave resolution as an exercise to the reader). On the other hand, single inheritance is &lt;em&gt;incompatible&lt;/em&gt; with ontological inheritance, as a square is both a rectangle and an equilateral polygon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Smalltalk blue book describes inheritance &lt;em&gt;solely&lt;/em&gt; in terms of implementation inheritance:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A subclass specifies that its instances will be the same as instances of another class, called its &lt;em&gt;superclass&lt;/em&gt;, except for the differences that are explicitly stated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice what is missing: no mention that a subclass instance must be able to replace a superclass instance everywhere in a program; no mention that a subclass instance must satisfy all conceptual tests for an instance of its superclass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Inheritance&lt;/em&gt; was never a problem: trying to use &lt;em&gt;the same tree&lt;/em&gt; for &lt;em&gt;three different concepts&lt;/em&gt; was the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Favour composition over inheritance” is basically giving up on implementation inheritance. We can’t work out how to make it work, so we’ll avoid it: get implementation sharing by delegation instead of by subclassing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eiffel, and particular disciplined approaches to using languages like Java, tighten up the “inheritance is subtyping” relationship by relaxing the “inheritance is re-use” relationship (if the same method appears twice in unrelated parts of the tree, you have to live with it, in order to retain the property that every subclass is a subtype of its parent). This is fine, as long as you don’t try to &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; model the problem domain using the inheritance tree, but much of the OO literature recommends that you do by talking about domain-driven design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traits approaches tighten up the “inheritance is specialisation” relationship by relaxing the “inheritance is re-use” relationship (if two super categories both provide the same property of an instance of a category, neither is provided and you have to write it yourself). This is fine, as long as you don’t try to &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; treat subclasses as covariant subtypes of their superclasses, but much of the OO literature recommends that you do by talking about Liskov Substitution Principle and how a type in a method signature means that type &lt;em&gt;or any subclass&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What the literature &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; do, I believe, is say “here are the three types of inheritance, focus on any one of them at a time”. I also believe that the &lt;em&gt;languages&lt;/em&gt; should support that (obviously Smalltalk, Ruby and friends &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; support that by not having any type constraints).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;If I’m using inheritance as a code sharing tool, it should not be assumed that my subclasses are also subtypes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If I am using subtypes to tighten up interface contracts, I should be not only &lt;em&gt;allowed&lt;/em&gt; to mark a class anywhere in the tree as a subtype of another class anywhere in the tree, but &lt;em&gt;required&lt;/em&gt; to do so: once again, it should not be assumed that my subclasses are also subtypes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If I need to indicate conceptual specialisation via classes, this should &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; not be assumed to follow the inheritance tree. I should be not only &lt;em&gt;allowed&lt;/em&gt; to mark a class anywhere in the tree as a subset of another class, but &lt;em&gt;required&lt;/em&gt; to do so: once again, it should not be assumed that my subclasses are also specialisations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your domain model is not your object model. Your domain model is not your abstract data type model. Your object model is not your abstract data type model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now inheritance is easy again.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 06:22:42 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>signa11</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Why inheritance never made any sense</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.sicpers.info/2018/03/why-inheritance-never-made-any-sense/</og:url>
<og:description>There are three different types of inheritance going on. Ontological inheritance is about specialisation: this thing is a specific variety of that thing (a football is a sphere and it has this radi…</og:description>
<og:image>https://s0.wp.com/i/blank.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.sicpers.info/2018/03/why-inheritance-never-made-any-sense/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Suspending Cambridge Analytica and SCL Group from Facebook</title>
<link>https://newsroom.fb.com/news/h/suspending-cambridge-analytica/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://newsroom.fb.com/news/h/suspending-cambridge-analytica/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/paul.grewal.186&quot;&gt;Paul Grewal&lt;/a&gt;, VP &amp;amp; Deputy General Counsel&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are suspending Strategic Communication Laboratories (SCL), including their political data analytics firm, Cambridge Analytica, from Facebook. Given the public prominence of this organization, we want to take a moment to explain how we came to this decision and why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We Maintain Strict Standards and Policies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Protecting people’s information is at the heart of everything we do, and we require the same from people who operate apps on Facebook. In 2015, we learned that a psychology professor at the University of Cambridge named Dr. Aleksandr Kogan lied to us and violated our &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.facebook.com/policy&quot;&gt;Platform Policies&lt;/a&gt; by passing data from an app that was using Facebook Login to SCL/Cambridge Analytica, a firm that does political, government and military work around the globe. He also passed that data to Christopher Wylie of Eunoia Technologies, Inc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like all app developers, Kogan requested and gained access to information from people after they chose to download his app. His app, “thisisyourdigitallife,” offered a personality prediction, and billed itself on Facebook as “a research app used by psychologists.” Approximately 270,000 people downloaded the app. In so doing, they gave their consent for Kogan to access information such as the city they set on their profile, or content they had liked, as well as more limited information about friends who had their privacy settings set to allow it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although Kogan gained access to this information in a legitimate way and through the proper channels that governed all developers on Facebook at that time, he did not subsequently abide by our rules. By passing information on to a third party, including SCL/Cambridge Analytica and Christopher Wylie of Eunoia Technologies, he violated our platform policies. When we learned of this violation in 2015, we removed his app from Facebook and demanded certifications from Kogan and all parties he had given data to that the information had been destroyed. Cambridge Analytica, Kogan and Wylie all certified to us that they destroyed the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Breaking the Rules Leads to Suspension&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several days ago, we received reports that, contrary to the certifications we were given, not all data was deleted. We are moving aggressively to determine the accuracy of these claims. If true, this is another unacceptable violation of trust and the commitments they made. We are suspending SCL/Cambridge Analytica, Wylie and Kogan from Facebook, pending further information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are committed to vigorously enforcing our policies to protect people’s information. We will take whatever steps are required to see that this happens. We will take legal action if necessary to hold them responsible and accountable for any unlawful behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How Things Have Changed&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are constantly working to improve the safety and experience of everyone on Facebook. In the past five years, we have made significant improvements in our ability to detect and prevent violations by app developers. Now all apps requesting detailed user information go through our &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.facebook.com/docs/facebook-login/review/what-is-login-review&quot;&gt;App Review process&lt;/a&gt;, which requires developers to justify the data they’re looking to collect and how they’re going to use it – before they’re allowed to even ask people for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2014, after hearing feedback from the Facebook community, we made an update to ensure that each person decides what information they want to share about themselves, including their friend list. This is just one of the many ways we give people the tools to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/help/792552774106866&quot;&gt;control their experience&lt;/a&gt;. Before you decide to use an app, you can review the permissions the developer is requesting and choose which information to share. You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/settings?tab=applications&quot;&gt;manage or revoke&lt;/a&gt; those permissions at any time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On an ongoing basis, we also do a variety of manual and automated checks to ensure compliance with our policies and a positive experience for users. These include steps such as random audits of existing apps along with the regular and proactive monitoring of the fastest growing apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We enforce our policies in a variety of ways — from working with developers to fix the problem, to suspending developers from our platform, to pursuing litigation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 01:20:26 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ilamont</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://s0.wp.com/wp-content/themes/vip/fb-newsroom/assets/bin/images/fb-opengraph.png</og:image>
<og:title>Suspending Cambridge Analytica and SCL Group from Facebook | Facebook Newsroom</og:title>
<og:description>Protecting people’s information is at the heart of everything we do.</og:description>
<og:url>https://newsroom.fb.com/news/2018/03/suspending-cambridge-analytica/</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://newsroom.fb.com/news/2018/03/suspending-cambridge-analytica/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>GrayKey iPhone unlocker poses serious security concerns</title>
<link>https://blog.malwarebytes.com/security-world/2018/03/graykey-iphone-unlocker-poses-serious-security-concerns/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.malwarebytes.com/security-world/2018/03/graykey-iphone-unlocker-poses-serious-security-concerns/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Ever since the case of the San Bernadino shooter pitted Apple against the FBI over the unlocking of an iPhone, opinions have been split on providing backdoor access to the iPhone for law enforcement. Some felt that Apple was aiding and abetting a felony by refusing to create a special version of iOS with a backdoor for accessing the phone’s data. Others believed that it’s impossible to give backdoor access to law enforcement without threatening the security of law-abiding citizens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an interesting twist, the battle ended with the FBI dropping the case after finding a third party who could help. At the time, it was theorized that the third party was Cellebrite. Since then it has become known that Cellebrite— an Israeli company—does provide iPhone unlocking services to law enforcement agencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cellebrite, through means currently unknown, provides these services at $5,000 per device, and for the most part this involves sending the phones to a Cellebrite facility. (Recently, Cellebrite has begun providing in-house unlocking services, but those services are protected heavily by non-disclosure agreements, so little is known about them.) It is theorized, and highly likely, that Cellebrite knows of one or more iOS vulnerabilities that allow them to access the devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In late 2017, word of a new iPhone unlocker device started to circulate: &lt;a href=&quot;https://graykey.grayshift.com/&quot;&gt;a device called GrayKey&lt;/a&gt;, made by a company named Grayshift. Based in Atlanta, Georgia, Grayshift was founded in 2016, and is a privately-held company with fewer than 50 employees. Little was known publicly about this device—or even whether it was a device or a service—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/thomasbrewster/2018/03/05/apple-iphone-x-graykey-hack/#2d003cdb2950&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;until recently&lt;/a&gt;, as the GrayKey website is protected by a portal that screens for law enforcement affiliation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Forbes, the GrayKey iPhone unlocker device is marketed for in-house use at law enforcement offices or labs. This is drastically different from Cellebrite’s overall business model, in that it puts complete control of the process in the hands of law enforcement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to an anonymous source, we now know what this mysterious device looks like, and how it works. And while the technology is a good thing for law enforcement, it presents some significant security risks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How it works&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GrayKey is a gray box, four inches wide by four inches deep by two inches tall, with two lightning cables sticking out of the front.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.malwarebytes.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/GrayKey.png&quot; data-rel=&quot;lightbox-0&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;22343&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://blog.malwarebytes.com/security-world/2018/03/graykey-iphone-unlocker-poses-serious-security-concerns/attachment/graykey/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://blog.malwarebytes.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/GrayKey.png&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1798,862&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;GrayKey&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://blog.malwarebytes.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/GrayKey-300x144.png&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://blog.malwarebytes.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/GrayKey-600x288.png&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-22343&quot; src=&quot;https://blog.malwarebytes.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/GrayKey-600x288.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;288&quot; srcset=&quot;https://blog.malwarebytes.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/GrayKey-600x288.png 600w, https://blog.malwarebytes.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/GrayKey-300x144.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two iPhones can be connected at one time, and are connected for about two minutes. After that, they are disconnected from the device, but are not yet cracked. Some time later, the phones will display a black screen with the passcode, among other information. The exact length of time varies, taking about two hours in the observations of our source. It can take up to three days or longer for six-digit passcodes, according to Grayshift documents, and the time needed for longer passphrases is not mentioned. Even disabled phones can be unlocked, according to Grayshift.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.malwarebytes.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/GrayKey-unlocked-iPhone.png&quot; data-rel=&quot;lightbox-1&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;22344&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://blog.malwarebytes.com/security-world/2018/03/graykey-iphone-unlocker-poses-serious-security-concerns/attachment/graykey-unlocked-iphone/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://blog.malwarebytes.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/GrayKey-unlocked-iPhone.png&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1656,1560&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;GrayKey unlocked iPhone&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://blog.malwarebytes.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/GrayKey-unlocked-iPhone-300x283.png&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://blog.malwarebytes.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/GrayKey-unlocked-iPhone-600x565.png&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-22344&quot; src=&quot;https://blog.malwarebytes.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/GrayKey-unlocked-iPhone-600x565.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;565&quot; srcset=&quot;https://blog.malwarebytes.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/GrayKey-unlocked-iPhone-600x565.png 600w, https://blog.malwarebytes.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/GrayKey-unlocked-iPhone-300x283.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the device is unlocked, the full contents of the filesystem are downloaded to the GrayKey device. From there, they can be accessed through a web-based interface on a connected computer, and downloaded for analysis. The full, unencrypted contents of the keychain are also available for download.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.malwarebytes.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/GrayKey-filesystem-download.png&quot; data-rel=&quot;lightbox-2&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;22345&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://blog.malwarebytes.com/security-world/2018/03/graykey-iphone-unlocker-poses-serious-security-concerns/attachment/graykey-filesystem-download/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://blog.malwarebytes.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/GrayKey-filesystem-download.png&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2418,1224&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;GrayKey filesystem download&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://blog.malwarebytes.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/GrayKey-filesystem-download-300x152.png&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://blog.malwarebytes.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/GrayKey-filesystem-download-600x304.png&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-22345&quot; src=&quot;https://blog.malwarebytes.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/GrayKey-filesystem-download-600x304.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;304&quot; srcset=&quot;https://blog.malwarebytes.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/GrayKey-filesystem-download-600x304.png 600w, https://blog.malwarebytes.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/GrayKey-filesystem-download-300x152.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As can be seen in the screenshot above, the GrayKey works on the latest hardware, and at least on iOS up to 11.2.5 (which was likely the most current system at the time this image was captured).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The GrayKey device itself comes in two “flavors.” The first, a $15,000 option, requires Internet connectivity to work. It is strictly geofenced, meaning that once it is set up, it cannot be used on any other network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, there is also a $30,000 option. At this price, the device requires no Internet connection whatsoever and has no limit to the number of unlocks. It will work for as long as it works; presumably, until Apple fixes whatever vulnerabilities the device relies on, at which time updated phones would no longer be unlockable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The offline model does require token-based two-factor authentication as a replacement for geofencing for ensuring security. However, as people often write passwords on stickies and put them on their monitors, it’s probably too much to hope that the token will be kept in a separate location when the GrayKey is not being used. Most likely, it will be stored nearby for easy access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Implications&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For law enforcement, this is undoubtedly a boon. However, historically, similar stories involving cracking the iPhone haven’t turned out so well. Consider, for example, the case of the IP-Box, a similar device that was once used to access the contents of iPhones running older versions of iOS. The utility of the original IP-Box ended in iOS 8.2, which gave rise to the IP-Box 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the IP-Box 2 became widely available and was almost exclusively used illegitimately, rather than in law enforcement. Today, various IP-Boxes can still be found being sold through a variety of websites, even including Amazon. Anyone who wants such a device can get one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.malwarebytes.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/IP-Box.png&quot; data-rel=&quot;lightbox-3&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;22348&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://blog.malwarebytes.com/security-world/2018/03/graykey-iphone-unlocker-poses-serious-security-concerns/attachment/ip-box/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://blog.malwarebytes.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/IP-Box.png&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;746,574&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;IP-Box&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://blog.malwarebytes.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/IP-Box-300x231.png&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://blog.malwarebytes.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/IP-Box-600x462.png&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-22348&quot; src=&quot;https://blog.malwarebytes.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/IP-Box-600x462.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;462&quot; srcset=&quot;https://blog.malwarebytes.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/IP-Box-600x462.png 600w, https://blog.malwarebytes.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/IP-Box-300x231.png 300w, https://blog.malwarebytes.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/IP-Box.png 746w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happens if the GrayKey becomes commonplace in law enforcement? The cheaper model isn’t much of a danger if stolen—unless it’s stolen prior to setup—but at 4″x 4″x 2″, the unlimited model could be pocketed fairly easily, along with its token, if stored nearby. Once off-site, it would continue to work. Such a device could fetch a high price on the black market, giving thieves the ability to unlock and resell stolen phones, as well as access to the high-value data on those phones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worse, consider the implications of what is done to the phone itself. It is currently not known how the process works, but it’s obvious there is some kind of jailbreak involved. (A jailbreak involves using a vulnerability to unlock a phone, giving access to the system that is not normally allowed.) What happens to the device once it is released back to its owner? Is it still jailbroken in a non-obvious way? Is it open to remote access that would not normally be possible? Will it be damaged to the point that it really can’t be used as intended anymore, and will need to be replaced? It’s unknown, but any of these are possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also don’t know what kind of security is present on the networked GrayKey device. Could it be remotely accessed? Could data be intercepted in transit? Is the phone data stored on the device strongly encrypted, weakly encrypted, or is it not even encrypted at all? We don’t know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most people probably won’t get too excited about a criminal’s phone or data. However, let’s keep in mind one of the fundamental principles of the US judicial system: suspects are innocent until proven guilty. Should suspects be susceptible to these kinds of searches by law enforcement?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further, not all phones analyzed by law enforcement belong to suspects. In one digital forensics lab in 2014, around one-third of the devices analyzed were given to the authorities with explicit consent, by alleged victims or witnesses, to assist in the investigation. In such cases, a passcode would likely be given, but it’s possible it didn’t get passed on to the forensic technician. It’s also possible the technician may prefer to use the GrayKey to analyze the device regardless of availability of the passcode, due to the copious amounts of data it can generate from the device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means that many innocent people’s phones will end up being analyzed using a GrayKey device. What happens if their phones are given back in a vulnerable state, or their data is handled insecurely? That is not only a threat to the individual, but a liability for the police.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.malwarebytes.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Grayshift.png&quot; data-rel=&quot;lightbox-4&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;22347&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://blog.malwarebytes.com/security-world/2018/03/graykey-iphone-unlocker-poses-serious-security-concerns/attachment/grayshift/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://blog.malwarebytes.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Grayshift.png&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;820,434&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Grayshift&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://blog.malwarebytes.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Grayshift-300x159.png&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://blog.malwarebytes.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Grayshift-600x318.png&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-22347&quot; src=&quot;https://blog.malwarebytes.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Grayshift-600x318.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;318&quot; srcset=&quot;https://blog.malwarebytes.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Grayshift-600x318.png 600w, https://blog.malwarebytes.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Grayshift-300x159.png 300w, https://blog.malwarebytes.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Grayshift.png 820w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Who should we trust?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For most people in the US, law enforcement agents are people to be trusted. Obviously, this can’t be true in all cases, people being people, but let’s start from that assumption. Unfortunately, even if the agents themselves are completely trustworthy, sources in law enforcement have said that the computer systems used by law enforcement in the US are often quite poorly secured. Is it a good idea to trust sensitive data, some of which will come from the phones of innocent US citizens, to insecure systems?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Little is known about Grayshift or its sales model at this point. We don’t know whether sales are limited to US law enforcement, or if it is also selling in other parts of the world. Regardless of that, it’s highly likely that these devices will ultimately end up in the hands of agents of an oppressive regime, whether directly from Grayshift or indirectly through the black market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s also entirely possible, based on the history of the IP-Box, that Grayshift devices will end up being available to anyone who wants them and can find a way to purchase them, perhaps by being reverse-engineered and reproduced by an enterprising hacker, then sold for a couple hundred bucks on eBay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An iPhone typically contains all manner of sensitive information: account credentials, names and phone numbers, email messages, text messages, banking account information, even credit card numbers or social security numbers. All of this information, even the most seemingly innocuous, has value on the black market, and can be used to steal your identity, access your online accounts, and steal your money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The existence of the GrayKey isn’t hugely surprising, nor is it a sign that the sky is falling. However, it does mean that an iPhone’s security cannot be ensured if it falls into a third party’s hands.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 21:35:30 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>conductor</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>GrayKey iPhone unlocker poses serious security concerns - Malwarebytes Labs</og:title>
<og:description>GrayKey, an iPhone unlocker, is secretly being marketed to law enforcement. Thanks to an anonymous source, we now know how the device works—and the danger it presents to security.</og:description>
<og:url>https://blog.malwarebytes.com/security-world/2018/03/graykey-iphone-unlocker-poses-serious-security-concerns/</og:url>
<og:image>https://blog.malwarebytes.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/shutterstock_320041463.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.malwarebytes.com/security-world/2018/03/graykey-iphone-unlocker-poses-serious-security-concerns/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Japan’s Prisons Are a Haven for Elderly Women</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2018-03-16/japan-s-prisons-are-a-haven-for-elderly-women</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2018-03-16/japan-s-prisons-are-a-haven-for-elderly-women</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Every aging society faces distinct challenges. But Japan, with the world’s oldest population (27.3 percent of its citizens are 65 or older, almost twice the share in the U.S.), has been dealing with one it didn’t foresee: senior crime. Complaints and arrests involving elderly people, and women in particular, are taking place at rates above those of any other demographic group. Almost 1 in 5 women in Japanese prisons is a senior. Their crimes are usually minor—9 in 10 senior women who’ve been convicted were found guilty of shoplifting.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Why have so many otherwise law-abiding elderly women resorted to petty theft? Caring for Japanese seniors once fell to families and communities, but that’s changing. From 1980 to 2015, the number of seniors living alone increased more than sixfold, to almost 6 million. And a 2017 survey by Tokyo’s government found that more than half of seniors caught shoplifting live alone; 40 percent either don’t have family or rarely speak with relatives. These people often say they have no one to turn to when they need help.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;lazy-img-325225809&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/ixs8sfqT3Wpw/v0/60x-1.png&quot; data-native-src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/ixs8sfqT3Wpw/v0/-1x-1.png&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img__image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even women with a place to go describe feeling invisible. “They may have a house. They may have a family. But that doesn’t mean they have a place they feel at home,” says Yumi Muranaka, head warden of Iwakuni Women’s Prison, 30 miles outside Hiroshima. “They feel they are not understood. They feel they are only recognized as someone who gets the house chores done.”&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Elderly women are also often economically vulnerable—nearly half of those 65 or older who live alone also live in poverty relative to the broader population, for example, compared with 29 percent of men. “My husband died last year,” one inmate says. “We didn’t have any children, so I was all alone. I went to a supermarket to buy vegetables, and I saw a package of beef. I wanted it, but I thought it would be a financial burden. So I took it.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Neither the government nor the private sector has established an effective rehabilitation program for seniors, and the costs to keep them in prison are rising fast. Expenses associated with elder care helped push annual medical costs at correctional facilities past 6 billion yen (more than $50 million) in 2015, an 80 percent increase from a decade before. Specialized workers have been hired to help older inmates with bathing and toileting during the day, but at night these tasks are handled by guards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At some facilities, being a correctional officer has come to resemble being a nursing-home attendant. Satomi Kezuka, a veteran officer at Tochigi Women’s Prison, about 60 miles north of Tokyo, says her duties now include dealing with incontinence. “They are ashamed and hide their underwear,” she says of the inmates. “I tell them to bring it to me, and I will have it washed.” More than a third of female correctional officers quit their jobs within three years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2016, Japan’s parliament passed a law aiming to ensure that recidivist seniors get support from the country’s welfare and social-service systems. Since then, prosecutor’s offices and prisons have worked closely with government agencies to get senior offenders the assistance they need. But the problems that lead these women to seek the relative comfort of jail lie beyond the system’s reach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;lazy-img-325272950&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/i2v9Pf4PRyUs/v1/60x-1.jpg&quot; data-native-src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/i2v9Pf4PRyUs/v1/-1x-1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img__image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I was 84 when I came to prison for the first time.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photographer: Shiho Fukada&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;section-break&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ms. F, 89&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Has stolen rice, strawberries, cold medicine&lt;br/&gt;Second term, sentenced to a year and a half&lt;br/&gt;Has a daughter and a grandchild&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I was living alone on welfare. I used to live with my daughter’s family and used all my savings taking care of an abusive and violent son-in-law.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;lazy-img-325272985&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iMBQDhr0yjlw/v2/60x-1.jpg&quot; data-native-src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iMBQDhr0yjlw/v2/-1x-1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img__image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;news-figure-caption-text caption&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photographer: Shiho Fukada&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;section-break&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ms. A, 67&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Has stolen clothing&lt;br/&gt;First term, sentenced to two years, three months&lt;br/&gt;Has a husband, two sons, and three grandchildren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I shoplifted more than 20 times, all clothes, not expensive ones, mostly on sale on the street. It’s not that I was in need of money. The first time I shoplifted, I didn’t get caught. I learned that I could obtain what I wanted without paying for it, which I found fun, amusing, exciting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“My husband has been supportive. He writes me regularly. My two sons are angry—my three grandchildren don’t know I’m here. They think I’m hospitalized.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;lazy-img-325273010&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/igFTgTI3wyBk/v2/60x-1.jpg&quot; data-native-src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/igFTgTI3wyBk/v2/-1x-1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img__image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;news-figure-caption-text caption&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photographer: Shiho Fukada&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;section-break&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ms. T, 80&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Has stolen cod roe, seeds, a frying pan&lt;br/&gt;Fourth term, sentenced to two and a half years&lt;br/&gt;Has a husband, a son, and a daughter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“When I was young, I didn’t think about stealing. All I thought about was working hard. I worked at a rubber factory for 20 years and then as a care worker at a hospital. Money was always tight, but we still got to send our son to college.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“My husband had a stroke six years ago and has been bedridden ever since. He also has dementia and suffers from delusions and paranoia. It was a lot to take care of him physically and emotionally because of my old age. But I couldn’t talk about my stress with anyone because I was ashamed.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I was imprisoned for the first time when I was 70. When I shoplifted, I had money in my wallet. Then I thought about my life. I didn’t want to go home, and I had nowhere else to go. Asking for help in prison was the only way. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“My life is much easier in prison. I can be myself and breathe, however temporarily. My son tells me I’m ill and I should be hospitalized in a mental institution and take it easy. But I don’t think I’m ill. I think my anxiety drove me to steal.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;lazy-img-325273015&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/irZwvOR3hf3I/v2/60x-1.jpg&quot; data-native-src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/irZwvOR3hf3I/v2/-1x-1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img__image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;news-figure-caption-text caption&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photographer: Shiho Fukada&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;section-break&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ms. N, 80&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Has stolen a paperback, croquettes, a hand fan&lt;br/&gt;Third term, sentenced to three years, two months&lt;br/&gt;Has a husband, two sons, and six grandchildren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I was alone every day and feeling very lonely. My husband gave me a lot of money, and people always told me how lucky I was, but money wasn’t what I wanted. It didn’t make me happy at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The first time I shoplifted was about 13 years ago. I wandered into a bookstore in town and stole a paperback novel. I was caught, taken to a police station, and questioned by the sweetest police officer. He was so kind. He listened to everything I wanted to say. I felt I was being heard for the first time in my life. In the end, he gently tapped on my shoulder and said, ‘I understand you were lonely, but don’t do this again.’ &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I can’t tell you how much I enjoy working in the prison factory. The other day, when I was complimented on how efficient and meticulous I was, I grasped the joy of working. I regret that I never worked. My life would have been different.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I enjoy my life in prison more. There are always people around, and I don’t feel lonely here. When I got out the second time, I promised that I wouldn’t go back. But when I was out, I couldn’t help feeling nostalgic.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;lazy-img-325273880&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iGPo53G332N4/v2/60x-1.jpg&quot; data-native-src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iGPo53G332N4/v2/-1x-1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img__image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;news-figure-caption-text caption&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photographer: Shiho Fukada&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;section-break&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ms. K, 74&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Has stolen Coca-Cola, orange juice&lt;br/&gt;Third term, sentence undisclosed&lt;br/&gt;Has a son and a daughter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I was living on welfare. It was hard. When I’m released, I will manage to live with 1,000 yen [$9] a day. I don’t have anything to look forward to outside.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;lazy-img-325273001&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iJzM4M60_eeY/v2/60x-1.jpg&quot; data-native-src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iJzM4M60_eeY/v2/-1x-1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img__image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;news-figure-caption-text caption&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photographer: Shiho Fukada&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;section-break&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ms. O, 78&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Has stolen energy drinks, coffee, tea, a rice ball, a mango&lt;br/&gt;Third term, sentenced to one year, five months&lt;br/&gt;Has a daughter and a grandson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Prison is an oasis for me—a place for relaxation and comfort. I don’t have freedom here, but I have nothing to worry about, either. There are many people to talk to. They provide us with nutritious meals three times a day. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“My daughter visits once a month. She says ‘I don’t feel sorry for you. You’re pathetic.’ I think she’s right.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This reporting was supported by the Pulitzer Center on Crisis Reporting and the International Women’s Media Foundation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 19:28:03 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>adventured</dc:creator>
<og:description>Lonely seniors are shoplifting in search of the community and stability of jail.</og:description>
<og:image>https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/ia7u6CVfzNiY/v0/1200x630.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Japan’s Prisons Are a Haven for Elderly Women</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2018-03-16/japan-s-prisons-are-a-haven-for-elderly-women</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2018-03-16/japan-s-prisons-are-a-haven-for-elderly-women</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Bus Lane Blocked, He Trained His Computer to Catch Scofflaws</title>
<link>https://mobile.nytimes.com/2018/03/15/nyregion/bike-lane-blocked-new-york.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://mobile.nytimes.com/2018/03/15/nyregion/bike-lane-blocked-new-york.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;top-wrapper&quot; class=&quot;ResponsiveAd-topAd--3uZAv&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;top-slug&quot; class=&quot;ResponsiveAd-hide--3eu5-&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advertisement&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;css-nefupu e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Alex Bell hates it when the designated bike lane he is pedaling down is blocked. So, too, do many cycling New Yorkers. But Mr. Bell hates it so much that he has tried to do something about it: Three years ago he &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.labsbell.com/blog/VsUPS&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;css-1dccl0s eo5o5yb0&quot;&gt;sued U.P.S.&lt;/a&gt;, targeting the delivery company’s trucks for blocking his bike path, a case he lost that is in its second round of appeals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-nefupu e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Now Mr. Bell is trying another tack — the 30-year-old computer scientist who lives in Harlem has created a prototype of a machine-learning algorithm that studies footage from a traffic camera and tracks precisely how often bike lanes are obstructed by delivery trucks, parked cars and waiting cabs, among other scofflaws. It is a piece of data that transportation advocates said is missing in the largely anecdotal discussion of how well the city’s bus and bike lanes do or do not work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-nefupu e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;At a time of intense criticism of New York’s poorly performing public transportation, Mr. Bell has expanded his study to also look at the flow of bus lanes in a city where the fleet operated by the Metropolitan Transportation Authority inches along at an average speed of seven miles per hour, making it the slowest major bus system in the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-nefupu e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The blocking of bus and bike lanes has become a sore spot among transportation advocates who believe the city’s enforcement efforts are inadequate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-nefupu e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Bell’s project focused on one city block — St. Nicholas Avenue between 145th and 146th Streets — over the course of 10 days. His preliminary findings were stark: Using traffic-camera footage trained on one bus stop and two bike lanes (one for traveling north, the other for heading south), Mr. Bell found that the bus stop was blocked 57 percent of the time, while the bike lanes were blocked 40 percent of the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;ResponsiveMedia-captionText--2WFdF Media-captionText--2e27a&quot;&gt;Images from Mr. Bell’s experiment show vehicles stopped in bus stops.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ResponsiveMedia-credit--3F-q_ Media-credit--1ZFho&quot; itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;accessibility-visuallyHidden--OUeHR&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Alex Bell&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-nefupu e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“Everyone keeps talking about the bus lanes being blocked, and buses being so slow I could just say, ‘Oh they are so blocked, it’s so bad,’ — but that’s not very helpful,” Mr. Bell said in an interview. “I thought to myself, ‘How could you show to everyone that bus stops and bike lanes are routinely blocked?’ ”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-nefupu e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;As the city has rolled out a total of 101 miles of specially designated bus lanes throughout the city, keeping them clear has emerged as a major challenge — what good is a bus-only pathway if it is blocked by an idling car, mail truck or even a police officer? The same goes for the 435 miles of unprotected bike lanes that are painted green and lace New York’s streetscape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-nefupu e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;But no data exists that captures the scope of the problem in a quantifiable way. In its absence, biking and transit advocates have taken matters into their own hands, posting photos of offenders, including government and police vehicles, on social media as a way of countering the problem through &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/copsinbikelanes?lang=en&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;css-1dccl0s eo5o5yb0&quot;&gt;public shaming&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-nefupu e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The enforcement that does exist through the use of cameras is slim: Just 12 of the city’s 317 bus routes have cameras mounted on objects like streetlights that are similar to red-light cameras. Any plan to add more such cameras must be approved by the State Legislature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-nefupu e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Enforcement along bus lanes and bike paths is primarily the responsibility of the Police Department. Last year, police officers issued over 2,000 moving violations to vehicles traveling in bus lanes, about 24,000 parking tickets for blocking lanes and about 79,000 parking tickets for impeding bike lanes. Data does not exist for moving violations in bike lanes, which the police began tracking this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-nefupu e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;While those numbers seem impressive, advocates believe it barely touches the severity of the problem. “Based on anyone’s observation, bus lanes in New York are chronically blocked,’’ said Paul Steely White, the executive director of Transportation Alternatives, a bicycling advocacy organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;ResponsiveMedia-captionText--2WFdF Media-captionText--2e27a&quot;&gt;Mr. Bell said he was motivated to figure out a way to illustrate a problem that he routinely encounters. “I thought to myself,’' he said, ‘How could you show to everyone that bus stops and bike lanes are routinely blocked?’”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ResponsiveMedia-credit--3F-q_ Media-credit--1ZFho&quot; itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;accessibility-visuallyHidden--OUeHR&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Christopher Lee for The New York Times&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-nefupu e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Andy Byford, the president of New York City Transit, has met with the Police Department to encourage the agency to increase its vigilance. Blocking the bus lane, “is selfish, and it’s unacceptable,” Mr. Byford said in a recent interview aboard a bus that was forced to swerve in and out of a designated bus lane to avoid parked vans and idling taxis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-nefupu e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“I get that people have to deliver things, but the bus lane should be for the buses, period,” Mr. Byford said, adding that the transit agency is developing a plan to improve bus service that may include adding front-facing cameras mounted on buses, a measure that other cities have taken to strengthen enforcement of bus-only lanes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-nefupu e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Increasing the number of bus and bike lanes, but under-enforcing the rules to keep them unimpeded, “is one of these programs that ratchets up New Yorker sincere cynicism about government doing the right thing,” Mr. White said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-nefupu e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;To gather actual data on how often blockages occur, Mr. Bell downloaded 10 days of publicly available video from a Department of Transportation camera mounted on a traffic light at the corner of 145th Street and St. Nicholas Avenue. Then he fed over 2,000 images of different types of vehicles, like trucks, buses and cars into his computer, training it to identify what exactly was blocking the way. In the case of bus stops, for example, Mr. Bell adjusted the computer program so that it was able to differentiate between buses that are supposed to be there from vehicles that were sitting there illegally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-nefupu e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;His work took about three weeks. After the programming was complete, it took the computer about a day to crunch though the 10 days of footage. Mr. Bell’s program only measured the percentage of time the lanes on his test block were obstructed, but from that he said he was able to extrapolate actual numbers and calculated about 850 vehicles blocking the bike lane and over 1,000 in the bus lane. He has made the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Bellspringsteen/OurCamera&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;css-1dccl0s eo5o5yb0&quot;&gt;source code&lt;/a&gt; he developed to monitor the lanes free and publicly available online in the hope that it will be picked up and used to amplify the extent of the issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-nefupu e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“I want to raise up New York City,” said Mr. Bell, who grew up on the Upper West Side, and attended Horace Mann School and Columbia University. “I never want to live anywhere else, but we have big problems. We have big problems especially when it comes to transportation. I am hoping that just seeing the data will help it be less ignorable.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-of-article&quot; readability=&quot;26.059523809524&quot;&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;elementStyles-printInformation--2VtfI elementStyles-toneNews--sRTft&quot; readability=&quot;7.29&quot;&gt;A version of this article appears in print on , on Page A21 of the New York edition with the headline: Not in His Bike Lane: An Algorithm for Getting Even&lt;span&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytreprints.com/&quot;&gt;Order Reprints&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/pages/todayspaper/index.html&quot;&gt;Today’s Paper&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/subscriptions/Multiproduct/lp8HYKU.html?campaignId=48JQY&quot;&gt;Subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;bottom-wrapper&quot; class=&quot;ResponsiveAd-bottomAd--1hHJW ResponsiveAd-storyBodyAd--35v2w&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;bottom-slug&quot; class=&quot;ResponsiveAd-adSlug--3H3QM&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advertisement&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 17:12:43 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>sethbannon</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/03/15/nyregion/bike-lane-blocked-new-york.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Bus Lane Blocked, He Trained His Computer to Catch Scofflaws</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/03/16/nyregion/16LANES1/00lanes1-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Cars parked in bus and bike lanes are Alex Bell’s scourge. To fight back, he created a computer program to figure out how often lanes are blocked.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mobile.nytimes.com/2018/03/15/nyregion/bike-lane-blocked-new-york.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Game of Everything, Part 1: Making Civilization</title>
<link>https://www.filfre.net/2018/03/the-game-of-everything-part-1-making-civilization/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.filfre.net/2018/03/the-game-of-everything-part-1-making-civilization/</guid>
<description>&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If my gravestone says, “Sid Meier, developed Civilization,” I’m happy with that. It’s a game I’m happy to be known for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Sid Meier&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_3308&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2018/03/the-game-of-everything-part-1-making-civilization/meier-2/&quot; rel=&quot;attachment wp-att-3308&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-3308&quot; src=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/meier-170x300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;170&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/meier-170x300.jpg 170w, https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/meier.jpg 386w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 170px) 100vw, 170px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Sid Meier&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During Sid Meier’s astonishingly productive first ten years as a designer and programmer, games poured out of him in such a jumble that even his colleagues at MicroProse Software could have trouble keeping straight what all he was working on at any given time. At the beginning of 1990, for instance, he had no fewer than three ambitious projects on the boil. He and his protege Bruce Shelley were finishing up &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2017/03/railroad-tycoon&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Railroad Tycoon&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; with justifiable enthusiasm. The same pair was, with considerably less enthusiasm, returning to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2017/03/whats-the-matter-with-covert-action&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Covert Action&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, one of the rare Meier designs that he could just never quite get to work to his satisfaction. And then — because what else should a recently married game designer spend his evenings doing? — Meier had embarked on a third project on his own time, a game he was already calling &lt;em&gt;Civilization&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like &lt;em&gt;Railroad Tycoon&lt;/em&gt; before it, &lt;em&gt;Civilization&lt;/em&gt; was born out of Meier’s abiding fascination with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2016/06/simcity-part-1-will-wrights-city-in-a-box&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;SimCity&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The programmer and simulation designer inside him recognized Will Wright’s so-called “software toy” to be a stunning achievement, yet the purer game designer within him was always a bit frustrated by the aimlessness of the experience. Thus &lt;em&gt;Railroad Tycoon&lt;/em&gt; had attempted to take some of the appeal of &lt;em&gt;SimCity&lt;/em&gt; and “gameify” it by adding computerized opponents and a concrete ending date. It had succeeded magnificently on those terms, but Meier wasn’t done building on what Wright had wrought. In fact, his first conception of &lt;em&gt;Civilization&lt;/em&gt; cast it as a much more obvious heir to &lt;em&gt;SimCity&lt;/em&gt; than even &lt;em&gt;Railroad Tycoon&lt;/em&gt; had been. Whereas &lt;em&gt;SimCity&lt;/em&gt; had let the player build her own functioning city, &lt;em&gt;Civilization&lt;/em&gt; would let her build a whole network of them, forming a country — or, as the game’s name would imply, a civilization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This, then, was the first of three conceptual layers which would eventually make up the game of &lt;em&gt;Civilization&lt;/em&gt; that the world would come to know. Meier abstracted away most of the details of the individual cities, letting the player decide only on which key buildings were built, whilst boiling each city down to a handful of numbers detailing its population, its economy, and its quality of life. This being a country rather than a city simulator, the spaces between the cities were just as important as the urban centers themselves. Mier thus made it possible to irrigate the countryside, to build roads to facilitate commerce, to build mines for digging up the raw materials needed by the centers of industry. At this early stage, &lt;em&gt;Civilization&lt;/em&gt;, later to be hailed as the most iconic exemplar of turn-based grand-strategy games, ran in real time, like &lt;em&gt;SimCity&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Railroad Tycoon&lt;/em&gt; before it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around March of 1990, after working on &lt;em&gt;Civilization&lt;/em&gt; for some months completely alone, Mier began to include Bruce Shelley in the role of sounding board. Shelley worked a standard eight-to-five day at MicroProse most of the time, while Meier hewed to a typical hacker’s schedule, showing up at noon or shortly before and working late into the evening. Each night, before he went home, he’d leave a disk on Shelley’s chair with the latest version of &lt;em&gt;Civilization&lt;/em&gt;. The next morning, when Shelley arrived at work, he’d play it for an hour or so in order to give Meier his feedback. For perhaps as long as a year, Shelley was literally the only person allowed to play the nascent &lt;em&gt;Civilization&lt;/em&gt;, under strict instructions to ignore the pleas of his colleagues peering over his shoulder. It was, to say the least, an unorthodox model of game development, but it somehow worked for these two unique personalities. Far from remaining just a glorified play-tester for very long, Shelley got deeper and deeper into the design. As he did so, &lt;em&gt;Civilization&lt;/em&gt; started to become something else entirely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The switch from a real-time to a turn-based approach was made quite early on, possibly even before those disks started appearing on Bruce Shelley’s chair. It would be wonderful to know the details behind the decision, but neither Meier nor Shelley can recall much of the specifics. It’s likely, however, that the change was made when Meier and Shelley — or Meier alone — started mulling over how to prevent &lt;em&gt;Civilization&lt;/em&gt; from falling into the &lt;em&gt;SimCity&lt;/em&gt; trap of becoming more of a software toy than a game in the traditional sense. The obvious way to gameify the experience was to include competing civilizations, just as &lt;em&gt;Railroad Tycoon&lt;/em&gt; had included competing robber barons. But conflicts between civilizations, unlike conflicts between business interests, always have looming over them the prospect of that ultimate diplomatic arbiter: war. So, including competing civilizations seemed to demand that a whole new layer of wargame strategy be mated to the existing game of city and country development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meier, who somehow found time to remain an avid player of strategy games when he wasn’t developing them, had for years been playing one called &lt;em&gt;Empire&lt;/em&gt;, a design so old that it had been born on a big DEC PDP-10 rather than a microcomputer. &lt;em&gt;Empire&lt;/em&gt; has a complicated pre-commercial history, which is complicated further by the fact that at least three mostly or entirely separate games were given the name over the course of the 1970s. But the most relevant version for our purposes was created by Walter Bright, a 20-year-old student at the California Institute of Technology, in 1977. Bright himself later ported it to microcomputers, efforts which culminated in him selling the game to a small publisher called Interstel, who made something of a specialty out of pulling hoary old classics out of the dustbin of 1970s institutional computing, giving them a coat of spit and polish, and introducing them to the home-computer-owning public. (Their first game, 1984’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mobygames.com/game/star-fleet-i-the-war-begins&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Star Fleet I: The War Begins!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, had done the same thing for the old mainframe &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2014/12/simon-schusters-treks-to-nowhere&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Star Trek&lt;/em&gt; game&lt;/a&gt;.) It was &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mobygames.com/game/empire-wargame-of-the-century&quot;&gt;Interstel’s version of &lt;em&gt;Empire&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, published in 1987 with the subtitle &lt;em&gt;Wargame of the Century&lt;/em&gt;, that Sid Meier knew best.&lt;em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a time when companies like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2016/03/joel-billings-and-ssi&quot;&gt;SSI&lt;/a&gt; were publishing bafflingly complicated wargames in the name of faithfulness to history, &lt;em&gt;Empire&lt;/em&gt; stood out for its elegant simplicity; it was more &lt;a href=&quot;https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/181/risk&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Risk&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; than &lt;a href=&quot;https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/1035/squad-leader&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Squad Leader&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. A world on which to play is chosen or, more commonly, generated randomly for each game. You begin in possession of a single city surrounded by just eight visible squares of the 5684 of them that make up the map; the rest of the world remains a mystery. Each city can be assigned to build one of a handful of armies, aircraft, and ships, each of which demands a set number of turns to bring to completion. Your first objective must be to build a unit in your first city and set out to explore the map as quickly as possible, taking possession of any neutral cities you discover. But eventually you run into the units and cities of your competitors, whereupon you all duke it out, leaving the last person left standing as the winner. Simplicity really is the watchword throughout. The military units, for instance, have their capabilities abstracted into just a handful of numbers: a movement speed, an attack rating, a defense rating, a damage rating describing the number of hits required to destroy it. Combat occurs when one player drives a unit into a square occupied by an enemy unit, whereupon the computer throws a virtual die, runs the result through an equation, and announces the outcome of the battle. A certain kind of player lauds &lt;em&gt;Empire&lt;/em&gt; as a &lt;em&gt;pure&lt;/em&gt; strategy game, a balanced challenge which rewards purely strategic thinking instead of muddying the issue with the superiority of Nazi optics versus the better armor of Allied tanks and all the rest. (Of course, another kind of player, of a more &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2011/07/the-rise-of-experiential-games&quot;&gt;experiential bent&lt;/a&gt;, finds it utterly uninteresting for the same reason.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_3314&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2018/03/the-game-of-everything-part-1-making-civilization/empire/&quot; rel=&quot;attachment wp-att-3314&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-3314&quot; src=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/empire.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/empire.png 600w, https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/empire-300x225.png 300w, https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/empire-500x375.png 500w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Issuing orders to a unit in Empire…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_3316&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2018/03/the-game-of-everything-part-1-making-civilization/civ_022-2/&quot; rel=&quot;attachment wp-att-3316&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-3316&quot; src=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/civ_022-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/civ_022-1.png 600w, https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/civ_022-1-300x225.png 300w, https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/civ_022-1-500x375.png 500w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;…and doing the same thing in &lt;em&gt;Civilization&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s really no delicate way to put this: confirming the old adage that good artists borrow while great ones steal, Sid Meier pretty much ripped off &lt;em&gt;Empire&lt;/em&gt; wholesale and transported it into his burgeoning &lt;em&gt;Civilization&lt;/em&gt;. The unknown map just begging to be revealed, the combat system, even many of the specific commands a player could issue to her units… all arrived virtually unchanged in &lt;em&gt;Civilization&lt;/em&gt;, to such an extent that anyone who had played &lt;em&gt;Empire&lt;/em&gt; — and Bruce Shelley, for one, certainly had — would immediately know what to do. Where Meier did make changes, it was generally to simplify &lt;em&gt;Empire&lt;/em&gt;‘s already hugely abstracted approach to wargaming yet further. For example, he removed the damage rating from his units altogether in favor of a one-hit-and-you’re-done model. (This would lead to one of the more indelible images of &lt;em&gt;Civilization&lt;/em&gt; in the cultural memory: that of a Roman phalanx destroying, thanks to a lucky roll of the virtual die, a platoon of modern tanks.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By this point, Meier and Shelley had a fairly credible game already, a version of &lt;em&gt;Empire&lt;/em&gt; grafted to a city-building game of economic development which determined how many and what sorts of military units the player could produce and support. Said units were confined to the ancient era: legionnaires, phalanxes, chariots, cavalry. Shelley remembers the two of them discussing the fact that, should worse come to worst, they could probably just polish up what they had and release it as a beer-and-pretzels strategy game of the Punic Wars or something. Yet neither one was at all inclined to do so; to turn &lt;em&gt;Civilization&lt;/em&gt; into a just another conquer-the-world game would be to lose some palpable if unarticulated sense of &lt;em&gt;otherness&lt;/em&gt; that had been lurking within the project from the very beginning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_3312&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;41&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2018/03/the-game-of-everything-part-1-making-civilization/civ_1_advances_chart/&quot; rel=&quot;attachment wp-att-3312&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-3312&quot; src=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/civ_1_advances_chart-300x93.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;186&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/civ_1_advances_chart-300x93.jpg 300w, https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/civ_1_advances_chart-768x238.jpg 768w, https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/civ_1_advances_chart-1024x317.jpg 1024w, https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/civ_1_advances_chart-500x155.jpg 500w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Civilization&lt;/em&gt;‘s Advances Chart is one of the most awe-inspiring documents I’ve ever encountered in my life. Colloquially referred to as the “tech tree,” it actually encompasses much more than that name would imply. It’s rather an endlessly fascinating chronicle of human progress, of what begot what, not just in the realm of technology but in those of art, culture, thought… in &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt;. I love it so much that I very nearly started another blog just to explore its interconnections. Yes, really.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The moment when they discovered their game’s true reason for existing came when they conjured up the “Advances Chart,” a timeline of scientific, technological, and cultural advancements up which the player could guide her civilization. With this idea, the third and most defining layer of the game fell into place. Not only did it change the game, it also changed the nature of the design process. The pair’s afternoons were soon filled by discussions — and occasional arguments — ranging back and forth across the timeline of progress. Others inside MicroProse’s cramped offices found these discussions so fascinating that they couldn’t help listening in, to the detriment of their own productivity. Shelley remembers making one proposal that wouldn’t ultimately make it into the game, for introducing a technology no less plebeian than the stirrup to the Advances Chart. “Why the stirrup?” asked a baffled Meier. Well, explained Shelley, horse-borne warfare didn’t instantly begin when people began riding horses; if you hit someone with a lance while riding without stirrups you’d wind up pushing yourself right off the horse. Knights in shining armor, massed cavalry charges, cowboys and Indians… the humble stirrup, just as much as the domestication of horses, had been the key to all of it. These were the sorts of insights &lt;em&gt;Civilization&lt;/em&gt; was now giving its designers, as it soon would its players as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond the starting slate of seven possibilities for research, the Advances Chart was based on prerequisites: to research Mysticism required one to already have discovered Ceremonial Burial, to research Chivalry required one to have Horseback Riding and Feudalism. The prerequisites were partially based on gameplay considerations, but at least as often teased out real, sometimes subtle linkages between the great achievements of humanity. Why, for instance, should Democracy require Literacy? Because a functioning democracy requires a literate population able to read for themselves and make responsible decisions from a position of knowledge, that’s why. Why should Labor Unions require Mass Production? Because the awful working conditions in factories provided the impetus for organizing and collectively demanding better conditions from the moneyed interests who owned the factories, that’s why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to form such connections, Meier and Shelley spent hours poring over history books, trying to understand what begot what and why. They were undoubtedly punching above their weight in trying to wrestle into place so all-encompassing a document as the &lt;em&gt;Civilization&lt;/em&gt; Advances Chart — who wouldn’t be? — but they were helped by the fact that both had been dedicated readers of history for years, amassing substantial personal libraries.&lt;sup id=&quot;rf1-3307&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2018/03/the-game-of-everything-part-1-making-civilization/#fn1-3307&quot; title=&quot;Soren Johnson, who many years later worked as co-designer of Civilization III and lead designer of Civilization IV, remembers Meier loaning him some reference books near the beginning of his involvement with the franchise, telling him that they might be good resources to use in refining or expanding the Advances Charts of the earlier games. Flipping through the books, he noticed underlined phrases like “ceremonial burial.” With a start, he realized that he had in his hands a history book that had itself become a piece of history: one of Sid Meier’s original sources for the original Civilization.&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; And when said personal libraries failed them, they could take advantage of the location of MicroProse’s offices in suburban Baltimore by making the short drive to one of the Smithsonian museums or the Library of Congress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meier and Shelley didn’t, as would have been all too easy for two old grognards like them, limit their research to the realm of the military, nor for that matter to the military-industrial complex. As some of the examples I’ve already named illustrate, they really did try to encompass &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt; on their Advances Chart, including philosophy, the arts, even the slow march of human rights toward true equality. They resisted the natural urge to dismiss or belittle those things which fell outside the compass of their usual interests. Here, another Shelley anecdote is telling. Very late in the game’s development, he asked one of MicroProse’s artists, who given the company’s usual product portfolio was accustomed to drawing pictures of soldiers, tanks and airplanes, to draw a picture of Michelangelo’s David statue for the &lt;em&gt;Civilization&lt;/em&gt; manual. Why on earth do you want a picture of &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt;, asked the artist. Shelley admitted that he was no great art historian or even art enthusiast. But, he said, people who are those things have told me via their books that this statue is very, very important — even, some of them might say, one of the great achievements of human civilization — and I respect their point of view. That noble broad-mindedness became an essential part of &lt;em&gt;Civilization&lt;/em&gt;‘s personality, keeping it from becoming just another min-max-ing exercise in conflict management. I &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2018/02/dr-brain&quot;&gt;recently praised&lt;/a&gt; the &lt;em&gt;Dr. Brain&lt;/em&gt; series of educational games from Sierra for their unwillingness to be confined to a single topic, for the implicit argument they make that &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; fields of human endeavor are equally worthy. Vastly different though it is as a game, &lt;em&gt;Civilization&lt;/em&gt; manifests the same spirit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the time the Advances Chart extended to roughly the present day, the simple mechanisms Meier and Shelley had built the game around were finally beginning to break down. Meier remembers the introduction of aircraft units, which demanded that some ugly special rules be grafted onto the heretofore beautifully simple &lt;em&gt;Empire&lt;/em&gt;-derived military layer, as a particular inflection point, a sign to the two designers that it was about time to wrap things up. He recalls introducing pollution to the game at least partly as a way of sending the same signal to the player.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, the spirit of the Advances Chart would clash horribly with a game which could be won only by conquering the world. What could become an alternative endgame for the player who preferred building to conquering? It was Shelley who suggested the perfect builder’s path to victory: advancing all the way to the end of the Advances Chart would allow you to build and launch a spaceship for Alpha Centauri, thus inaugurating the next great phase of humanity’s existence. Granted, it didn’t quite make sense in the context of the rest of the advances chart, which otherwise confined itself to things that had already been discovered or that hopefully would be in the fairly near future. &lt;em&gt;Civilization&lt;/em&gt; would offer no explanation of how humanity would go from Robotics, (Apollo-style) Space Flight, and Plastics to bridging the 4.37 light years that separate our solar system from its closest neighbor — a leap that could require a whole other Advances Chart at least as big as the one Meier and Shelley already had to actually bring to fruition in any sort of grounded way. One could argue that a voyage to Mars might have made a better final goal, but Meier and Shelley clearly wanted something audacious, and audacious a trip to Alpha Centauri certainly is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now it only remained for the two designers to glue their three layers of gameplay into a coherent whole. On the surface, this seemed far from a simple task. The issues of scaling they faced would have defeated many a designer: military operations took place on a scale of days and weeks, construction projects played out on a scale of months and years, while cultures moved up the Advances Chart only over a time frame of decades and centuries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My regular readers may recall that this same pair of designers had faced an only slightly less extreme version of this clash of time and scale with &lt;em&gt;Railroad Tycoon&lt;/em&gt;. There the question had been how to integrate the operational aspect of the game — also known as the “model-railroading” aspect — with the business of running a real railroad over a period of years and decades. They solved the problem, you may recall, by effectively ignoring it, by running the entire game on the macro time scale of the business layer and just letting the operational layer deal with it. This meant that individual trains could take months between leaving one station and arriving at another, and that major transportation corridors like Boston to New York might be served by just two or three train departures per &lt;em&gt;year&lt;/em&gt;. You could rationalize all of this as an abstraction of the hundreds of trains that were really running over these tracks, or you could just not think about it at all. The point was that it led to a fun game that captured the &lt;em&gt;spirit&lt;/em&gt; of its subject matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Faced with the same problem in &lt;em&gt;Civilization&lt;/em&gt;, Meier and Shelley took the exact same approach. The game would run on a time frame appropriate to the theme of human progress on the grand scale. Each turn would represent fully twenty years from 4000 BC to 1000 AD, followed by ten years until 1500, five years until 1750, two years until 1850, and one year thereafter; the shortening spans of time would depict the steadily accelerating pace of progress as the world lurched toward modernity. This had some extremely weird implications for the &lt;em&gt;Empire&lt;/em&gt;-derived military game in particular: it meant that battles could conceivably span centuries —  the Trojans and the Greeks had nothing on this lot! — and wars could potentially span millennia. For that matter, it meant that just marching a phalanx from one side of one’s country to the other could require a couple of centuries in itself. You can, once again, choose to rationalize this as an abstraction of reality, or you can just not think about it. Yet again, the point is that it’s fun and that it &lt;em&gt;works&lt;/em&gt; for the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the three layers of the design thus welded together, the rest of the game we’ve come to know as &lt;em&gt;Civilization&lt;/em&gt; fell into place. Meier and Shelley turned to the history books again to select fifteen current or historical cultures for inclusion, from the Americans to the Zulus, one of which the player could choose to play, the others of which would serve as potential rival civilizations. Fairly rudimentary artificial intelligence came in for this last group, with the behavior of each rival civilization’s leader defined on an axis of three values, from “militaristic” to “civilized,” from “aggressive” to “friendly,” from “expansionist” to “perfectionist.” An extremely rudimentary diplomatic model came in, with geopolitical relations boiled down to make war or make peace, demand tribute or pay tribute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final indelible piece of the &lt;em&gt;Civilization&lt;/em&gt; experience arrived in the form of “Wonders of the World,” special structures which only one civilization would be allowed to build in one city in the course of an entire game. Each would confer some tangible benefit, but just as important would be the bragging rights of having constructed the Pyramids of Giza or the Great Wall of China. While the idea and the name were obviously inspired by the Seven Wonders of the Ancient World, Meier and Shelley wound up using only four of the Seven. The balance of the list was filled out with seventeen other landmark achievements, many of them not actually physical structures at all: Magellan’s circumnavigation of the world, Darwin’s theory of evolution, the United Nations, the Apollo moon landings, even — reaching now into the realm of wishful thinking — a cure for cancer. Just as had happened with the Advances Chart, the list of Wonders became far more wide-ranging than one would have any right to expect. How many other grognards would have taken the time to single out women’s suffrage as one of the Wonders of the World?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other designers — some of them great ones — had occasionally dreamed about a game of this scale and scope, but none had ever come close to bringing the dream to fruition. At the very same time that Meier and Shelley were working on &lt;em&gt;Civilization&lt;/em&gt;, two other hugely admired designers were coincidentally each working on a similarly themed project of their own, only to be forced to scale it back dramatically. Dan Bunten&lt;sup id=&quot;rf2-3307&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2018/03/the-game-of-everything-part-1-making-civilization/#fn2-3307&quot; title=&quot;Dan Bunten began living as the woman Danielle Bunten Berry shortly after the publication of Global Conquest. As per my usual editorial policy on these matters, I refer to her as “he” and by her original name only to avoid historical anachronisms and to stay true to the context of the times.&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; wound up with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mobygames.com/game/dos/global-conquest&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Global Conquest&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a competent but less than earth-shaking conquer-the-world strategy game, while Chris Crawford wound up with a game every bit as unfun as its title would imply: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mobygames.com/game/global-dilemma-guns-or-butter&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Global Dilemma: Guns or Butter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why, we might ask, did &lt;em&gt;Civilization&lt;/em&gt; turn out differently? A big piece of the reason must be Sid Meier’s unwavering commitment to &lt;em&gt;fun&lt;/em&gt; as the final arbiter in game design, as summed up in his longstanding maxim of “Fun trumps history.” Meier, Bunten, and Crawford actually met on at least one occasion to discuss the games of everything they each had in progress. Crawford’s recollections of that meeting are telling, even if they’re uttered more in a tone of condemnation than approbation: “Sid had a very clear notion: he was going to make it fun. He didn’t give a damn about anything else; it was going to be fun. He said, ‘I have absolutely no reservation about fiddling with realism or anything, so long as I can make it more fun.'”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But another, less obvious piece of the puzzle is inherent to the way that &lt;em&gt;Civilization&lt;/em&gt; was developed. Imagine yourself in the shoes of a designer who’s just decided to make a game about everything. How do you even begin? What rules, what mechanics, what interface can you possibly employ? It is, needless to say, a daunting prospect. Game design being an art of the possible, you inevitably begin to pare away at your grand vision, trying to arrive at some core which you can actually hope to implement. In the process, though, you also begin cutting into the &lt;em&gt;soul&lt;/em&gt; of the idea, until you arrive at a dispiriting shadow of it like &lt;em&gt;Global Conquest&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;The Global Dilemma&lt;/em&gt;. Sid Meier, by contrast, never really &lt;em&gt;decided&lt;/em&gt; to make a game about everything at all; his design just kind of went there on its own. Thus while Bunten and Crawford were cutting back on their ambitions, Meier was expanding on his. Rather than arriving as an immaculate conception, &lt;em&gt;Civilization&lt;/em&gt; was allowed to grow into itself, employing rules, mechanics, and interfaces which had already been proven on smaller scales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A persistent question surrounding &lt;em&gt;Civilization&lt;/em&gt; the computer game — and one that has come to have urgent legal relevance — has been the influence of an &lt;a href=&quot;https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/71/civilization&quot;&gt;earlier game with the same name&lt;/a&gt;, a board game designed by Francis Tresham and self-published in 1980, then re-published under the Avalon Hill imprint in 1982. The theme of the board game matches that of the computer game — the advancement of human civilization from its formative stages — but the two diverge dramatically in many ways. The board game, for instance, ends in approximately 250 BC, while, as already noted, the computer game stretches into the near future. Mechanically as well, the two games are quite different; the board game doesn’t have anything like the computer game’s Advances Chart, instead using decks of cards for the purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seasoned grognards that they were, Meier and Shelley could hardly not have been acquainted with the Avalon Hill game, which enjoyed considerable popularity in its day among the hardcore wargame crowd who were willing to devote the five or six hours that a complete playthrough of it usually required. Yet Meier — who, it should be noted, has always been very transparent about the inspirations for his games — has claimed to have played the board game only once in his life, and not to have had it in mind at all when he started making the computer game. Shelley, who worked at Avalon Hill prior to coming to MicroProse, admits to slightly more familiarity, but likewise dismisses the notion of having borrowed anything more than certain themes and a name, the latter apparently with no regard to what had come before. Sid Meier could be, much to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2015/03/microproses-simulation-industrial-complex-or-the-ballad-of-sid-and-wild-bill&quot;&gt;MicroProse head “Wild” Bill Stealey’s&lt;/a&gt; chagrin, extremely naive about matters of business and intellectual property, and simply stuck the obvious name on his own game without ever thinking about what conflicts it might create.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stealey was no grognard, and thus had no idea about the name’s history until MicroProse had already begun advance promotion of their take on &lt;em&gt;Civilization&lt;/em&gt;. It was at this point that a very unhappy Eric Dott, the president of Avalon Hill, called him up and said, “Wild Bill, &lt;em&gt;Civilization&lt;/em&gt; is my game. You’re stealing it.” Further complicating the situation was the fact that the same two men had had very nearly same conversation barely a year before, when MicroProse had published &lt;em&gt;Railroad Tycoon&lt;/em&gt;. Dott had been convinced then that the game in question bore suspicious similarities to the Avalon Hill board game &lt;a href=&quot;https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/421/1830-railways-robber-barons&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;1830: Railways &amp;amp; Robber Barons&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, ironically also a Francis Tresham design, and one on which Bruce Shelley had done some work during his time at the company. Stealey had been able to smooth things over then, but now here they were again, and with what seemed a much more clear-cut case of trademark infringement at that. To make matters that much worse, Avalon Hill was about to unveil a whole new, even more complicated version of the original &lt;em&gt;Civilization&lt;/em&gt; board game, under the name of &lt;a href=&quot;https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/177/advanced-civilization&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Advanced Civilization&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and was thus particularly unenthused about having a computer game with the same name confusing the issue at this of all junctures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wild Bill can best explain what happened next in his own inimitable style:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;20&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I had lunch with Eric. I bought him lunch because I was buttering him up. I said, “Eric, I apologize. I didn’t know Sid was doing this, but I think it’s going to be a good game. I think we won’t sell near as many as you sell as boxed games.” You know, one of those games you buy in a box and play on a table — tabletop games. “What if I put a card in every one of the games that says, ‘Get $5 off Civilization from Avalon Hill,’ and you do the same for me?'” After two or three glasses of wine, he agreed — one of his bigger mistakes. He would have made a lot more money if he had said, “Okay, give me 10 percent of it.” All he got was a card in the game box. If he had 10 percent of Civilization, Avalon Hill would still be around today, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, the presence of those cards in the boxes did nothing to ease the confusion surrounding these two very different games with the same name. To this day, there are many who believe Sid Meier’s &lt;em&gt;Civilization&lt;/em&gt; to be merely a computerized version of the board game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stealey and Dott’s gentleman’s agreement wouldn’t keep the lawyers at bay forever; the issue would be revisited again, with major consequences for all involved. But that would be only years in the future, and thus must be fodder for a &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; later article of mine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the time Stealey and Dott had their tête-à-tête, the duo of Meier and Shelley had long since begun including their colleagues in the &lt;em&gt;Civilization&lt;/em&gt; development and play-testing process. The game had a split reputation inside MicroProse. The technical and creative staff, almost to a person, loved it, was convinced that this was not just another game, not even just another very good Sid Meier game, but a true landmark in the offing for their company and for their industry. And yet the more businesslike side of the company, taking their cue from the man at the top of the food chain, was rather less enthused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fact of the matter was that Wild Bill Stealey wasn’t capable of getting truly, personally enthused over &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; game that wasn’t a military flight simulator. Just as had happened with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2015/07/pirates&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pirates!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Railroad Tycoon&lt;/em&gt;, Sid Meier’s two earlier masterpieces, he never quite seemed to grasp what his star designer was on about with &lt;em&gt;Civilization&lt;/em&gt;, couldn’t seem to understand why he preferred to spend his time on a high-falutin’ project like this one instead of, say, &lt;em&gt;F-15 Strike Eagle III&lt;/em&gt;. Yet Meier, whose confidence in himself had grown with every game of his that MicroProse published, was no longer a designer to whom Stealey could dictate directions; the last gasp of &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; had been his reluctantly finishing up &lt;em&gt;Covert Action&lt;/em&gt; at Stealey’s insistence. Faced with that reality, Stealey duly provided &lt;em&gt;Civilization&lt;/em&gt; with the artists and other resources Meier and Shelley needed to finish it, announced the game to the press (thus leading to that fateful lunchtime truce with Eric Dott), and even ran some modest pre-release advertisements. But he wasn’t overly generous with the &lt;em&gt;Civilization&lt;/em&gt; development team; certainly the finished game is no graphical feast, with a look that verges at times on amateurish. Shelley in particular has described his frustration with feeling perpetually under-appreciated by MicroProse’s management. The final insult came when, after shipping their staggeringly ambitious game in December of 1991, he and Meier saw their bonuses cut because they had done so six weeks late, missing the bulk of the Christmas buying season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever Stealey personally thought of &lt;em&gt;Civilization&lt;/em&gt;, his ambivalence is by no means the only explanation for the relative lack of resources at his star designer’s disposal. Meier, who had co-founded MicroProse with Stealey back in 1982, had seven years later made a conscious decision to step back from the roller-coaster ride that running a company alongside Wild Bill was always doomed to be. In 1989, he had convinced Stealey to buy him out so he could focus strictly on designing games, becoming a “super contractor” for what had once been his own company. Still, nothing could entirely insulate him and Shelley and their latest game from an unstable situation around them. The fact was that MicroProse was in a rather precarious position as Meier and Shelley were finishing their latest masterpiece. The problems reached back to 1988, when Stealey, having seen his company clear $1 million in profit the previous year, embarked on two major new initiatives that pushed them well outside their comfort zone of military simulations for American home computers. Neither of them would have a happy ending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the new initiatives was an aggressive expansion into the European market, including a new branch office in Britain and the purchase of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2015/05/fire-and-rain&quot;&gt;Firebird and Rainbird labels&lt;/a&gt; from British Telecom. In principle, opening a MicroProse subsidiary in Britain was a smart, even visionary move to get in on the second biggest computer-game market in the world, but the move was horribly mismanaged from the start, collapsing into chaos in the summer of 1989, when Stealey flew to Britain to personally accuse a managing director of embezzling £200,000 from the company coffers. The purchase of Firebird and Rainbird, on the other hand, didn’t make much sense even at the time as anything other than expansion for expansion’s sake — their collection of action games and old-school text adventures didn’t sit terribly well beside the MicroProse catalog — and quickly turned out to be a bust, with both labels, which had enjoyed considerable respect at the time of the purchase, disappearing entirely by 1991 under a cloud of yet more transatlantic miscommunication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_3309&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2018/03/the-game-of-everything-part-1-making-civilization/stealey-2/&quot; rel=&quot;attachment wp-att-3309&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-3309&quot; src=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/stealey-221x300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;221&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/stealey-221x300.jpg 221w, https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/stealey.jpg 233w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 221px) 100vw, 221px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Wild Bill Stealey with his ill-fated &lt;em&gt;F-15 Strike Eagle&lt;/em&gt; arcade game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it was the other big initiative of 1988 that was closest to Wild Bill Stealey’s flyboy heart. Frustrated by the limitations of the personal computers which ran his beloved flight simulators, he concocted a scheme to build his own hardware in order to do them justice. Gene Lipkin, a former executive with the original Atari, took charge of a project to build coin-op versions of MicroProse’s games for arcades, beginning with &lt;em&gt;F-15 Strike Eagle&lt;/em&gt;, their most successful game of all. The arcade version of that game, which was unveiled in 1990, could draw 60,000 polygons per second to its huge 27-inch screen at a time when the average PC-based MicroProse simulator was pushing about 1500. But, impressive though the hardware may have been, the whole project was profoundly ill-conceived from a business perspective. Like its microcomputer equivalent, the arcade version of &lt;em&gt;F-15 Strike Eagle&lt;/em&gt; was a deep, fairly realistic game that would require some time even to fully understand, much less master. That was fine for home-computer software, but totally at odds with the quick thrills typically offered by arcade quarter-munchers. The extended play time, the complex missions which the player had to earn the right to play… none of it made any sense whatsoever as an arcade game. Even the First Gulf War, which was being televised live every night on CNN and creating a voracious appetite for flight simulators on home computers, couldn’t save it. It flopped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As all of these misbegotten ventures ran their course, the losses piled up at MicroProse: $1.4 million in 1988, $300,000 in 1989, $600,000 in 1990. In 1991, Stealey decided that the best way to clear all of his failed ventures off the books and start moving forward again was to launch an IPO. On October 3, 1991, just as Meier and Shelley and their helpers were in the midst of the final mad scramble to finish &lt;em&gt;Civilization&lt;/em&gt;, MicroProse issued 2 million shares at an initial price of $9 each. It was, to say the least, an unconventional move; companies normally launch IPOs when things are going well, not when they’re going poorly.&lt;sup id=&quot;rf3-3307&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2018/03/the-game-of-everything-part-1-making-civilization/#fn3-3307&quot; title=&quot;MicroProse had become a distributor of “affiliated labels,” smaller publishers who paid for access to their distribution network, in the late 1980s. In the run-up to the IPO, trying to make their bottom line look better, they abruptly stopped paying such labels for the games they sold. Among the publishers that were nearly undone by this move was Legend Entertainment. In light of episodes like this, it’s perhaps not a big surprise that, while Sid Meier was universally liked and respected, Bill Stealey’s reputation within his industry was, at best, mixed.&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; For MicroProse, it would prove only the most short-lived of bandages on a series of financial wounds Stealey would only continue to inflict on his company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2018/03/the-game-of-everything-part-1-making-civilization/235215-sid-meier-s-civilization-dos-front-cover-png/&quot; rel=&quot;attachment wp-att-3313&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-3313&quot; src=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/235215-sid-meier-s-civilization-dos-front-cover.png-256x300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;256&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/235215-sid-meier-s-civilization-dos-front-cover.png-256x300.jpg 256w, https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/235215-sid-meier-s-civilization-dos-front-cover.png-768x901.jpg 768w, https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/235215-sid-meier-s-civilization-dos-front-cover.png-500x587.jpg 500w, https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/235215-sid-meier-s-civilization-dos-front-cover.png.jpg 800w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 256px) 100vw, 256px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, &lt;em&gt;Civilization&lt;/em&gt; did come out that December, in a nice-looking box, with a fat manual (largely written by Shelley) and a pull-out insert for that magnificent Advances Chart. No one, of course — not even the game’s designers or its most zealous devotees among MicroProse’s creative staff — had any idea of what it would ultimately come to mean for its industry or its art form. Certainly no one could have dreamed that &lt;em&gt;Civilization&lt;/em&gt; would still be going strong as I write these words more than a quarter of a century later, that it would become the sort of game quite likely to go on for as long as our own civilization exists to sustain it. “We knew it was a fun game,” remembers Meier, “but there had been no historical example of a [computer] game that had that kind of longevity at that point. We didn’t have a sense that this was going to be &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; different from the other games we had made. We thought it was good and creative and had new ideas in it, but had it flopped we would not have been shocked.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the lead of its designers, gamers at large for the most part regarded &lt;em&gt;Civilization&lt;/em&gt; as merely the latest release from the highly respected Sid Meier, albeit perhaps one with an unusually intriguing premise. Most of the initial reviews showed no inkling of the game’s ultimate importance, although they were universally positive. The one reviewer who did seem to grasp the game’s timeless quality was Alan Emrich. Writing in his usual affected style for &lt;em&gt;Computer Gaming World&lt;/em&gt;, the journal of record for hardcore strategy gamers, he concluded his review by saying that “a new Olympian in the genre of god games has truly emerged, and &lt;em&gt;Civilization&lt;/em&gt; is likely to prove itself the greatest discovery in computer entertainment since the wheel.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But most importantly, &lt;em&gt;Civilization&lt;/em&gt; sold quite well following its release, spending several months among the top ten sellers in the industry, rising once or twice as high as the number-three spot. Whatever he personally thought of Sid Meier’s recent esoteric project choices, Wild Bill Stealey couldn’t complain about the commercial performance of this, his latest effort, which earned back all of the money it had cost to make it in fairly short order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then, something else started to happen. After those first several months were over, when sales of any other computer game could normally be expected to fall off a cliff, they did no such thing in the case of &lt;em&gt;Civilization&lt;/em&gt;. Month after month, &lt;em&gt;Civilization&lt;/em&gt; kept right on selling. It became that rarest of beasts in what was becoming an ever more ephemeral, hits-driven industry: a perennial. Over the course of its first four and a half years on the market, it sold 850,000 copies, while becoming a huge influence on a whole new generation of ambitious turn-based grand-strategy games. Sid Meier and Bruce Shelley had never made a sequel in their careers, and never had any inkling that this latest game of theirs would spawn a franchise, much less a genre — much less, for some players, a veritable lifestyle. But when MicroProse bowed to their customers’ demands and belatedly returned to the well in 1996 with &lt;em&gt;Civilization II&lt;/em&gt;, the die was well and truly cast. Publishers, designers, and technology might come and go, but &lt;em&gt;Civilization&lt;/em&gt; was forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;strong&gt;Sources:&lt;/strong&gt; the books &lt;em&gt;Civilization, or Rome on 640K A Day&lt;/em&gt; by Johnny L. Wilson and Alan Emrich, &lt;em&gt;Game Design: Theory &amp;amp; Practice&lt;/em&gt; by Richard Rouse III, and &lt;em&gt;Gamers at Work: Stories Behind the Game People Play&lt;/em&gt; by Morgan Ramsay; &lt;em&gt;PC Review&lt;/em&gt; of August 1992; &lt;em&gt;A.C.E.&lt;/em&gt; of May 1990; &lt;em&gt;Computer Gaming World&lt;/em&gt; of January 1988, June 1989, September 1990, December 1990, November 1991, December 1991, and April 1992; Origin Systems’s internal newsletter &lt;em&gt;Point of Origin&lt;/em&gt; from October 25 1991, March 27 1992, June 5 1992, and August 14 1992; Soren Johnson’s interviews with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.idlethumbs.net/designernotes/episodes/bruce-shelley&quot;&gt;Bruce Shelley&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.idlethumbs.net/designernotes/episodes/sid-meier-part-2/&quot;&gt;Sid Meier&lt;/a&gt;. My huge thanks go to Soren for providing me with the raw audio of his Sid Meier interview months before it went up on his site, thus giving me a big leg up on my research.)&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 16:55:18 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>doppp</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.filfre.net/2018/03/the-game-of-everything-part-1-making-civilization/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>China to bar people with bad &amp;#039;social credit&amp;#039; from planes, trains</title>
<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-china-credit/china-to-bar-people-with-bad-social-credit-from-planes-trains-idUSKCN1GS10S</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.reuters.com/article/us-china-credit/china-to-bar-people-with-bad-social-credit-from-planes-trains-idUSKCN1GS10S</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;first-p_2htdt&quot;&gt;SHANGHAI (Reuters) - China said it will begin applying its so-called social credit system to flights and trains and stop people who have committed misdeeds from taking such transport for up to a year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;container_2pnvl&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;container_1tVQo&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;


&lt;span class=&quot;caption_KoNH1&quot;&gt;Passengers wait to board trains ahead of the Chinese Lunar New Year, at Nanjing Railway Station in Jiangsu province, China January 31, 2018. China Daily via REUTERS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;People who would be put on the restricted lists included those found to have committed acts like spreading false information about terrorism and causing trouble on flights, as well as those who used expired tickets or smoked on trains, according to two statements issued on the National Development and Reform Commission’s website on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Those found to have committed financial wrongdoings, such as employers who failed to pay social insurance or people who have failed to pay fines, would also face these restrictions, said the statements which were dated March 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;It added that the rules would come into effect on May 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The move is in line with President’s Xi Jinping’s plan to construct a social credit system based on the principle of “once untrustworthy, always restricted”, said one of the notices which was signed by eight ministries, including the country’s aviation regulator and the Supreme People’s Court.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;China has flagged plans to roll out a system that will allow government bodies to share information on its citizens’ trustworthiness and issue penalties based on a so-called social credit score.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;However, there are signs that the use of social credit scoring on domestic transport could have started years ago. In early 2017, the country’s Supreme People’s Court said during a press conference that 6.15 million Chinese citizens had been banned from taking flights for social misdeeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;container_28wm1&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;attribution_o4ojT&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;content_27_rw&quot;&gt;Reporting by SHANGHAI Newsroom and Brenda Goh; Editing by Kim Coghill&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 16:47:12 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>samaysharma</dc:creator>
<og:title>China to bar people with bad 'social credit' from planes, trains</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-china-credit/china-to-bar-people-with-bad-social-credit-from-planes-trains-idUSKCN1GS10S</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>China said it will begin applying its so-called social credit system to flights and trains and stop people who have committed misdeeds from taking such transport for up to a year.</og:description>
<og:image>https://s3.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;d=20180316&amp;t=2&amp;i=1241539822&amp;w=1200&amp;r=LYNXNPEE2F0NL</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-china-credit/china-to-bar-people-with-bad-social-credit-from-planes-trains-idUSKCN1GS10S</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Adrian Lamo has died</title>
<link>http://www.zdnet.com/article/adrian-lamo-hacker-dies/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.zdnet.com/article/adrian-lamo-hacker-dies/</guid>
<description>&lt;span class=&quot;img aspect-set&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://zdnet1.cbsistatic.com/hub/i/r/2018/03/16/ad57d4bd-7b32-4fa8-9da9-2c3bba8139ed/resize/770xauto/1e7b27d5b8eca09211d0eaf25e83a605/adrian-lamo-jpg.jpg&quot; class=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;auto&quot; width=&quot;770&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;(Image: file photo)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adrian Lamo, a well-known hacker, has died at 37.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His father, Mario, posted a brief tribute to his son in a Facebook group on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&quot;With great sadness and a broken heart I have to let know all of Adrian's friends and acquittances that he is dead. A bright mind and compassionate soul is gone, he was my beloved son,&quot; he wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CNET:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnet.com/news/hacker-adrian-lamo-37-has-passed-away/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Hacker Adrian Lamo, who turned in Chelsea Manning, dies at 37&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zdnet.com/article/adrian-lamo-wikileaks-and-what-it-means-to-be-a-patriot/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Adrian Lamo, Wikileaks, and what it means to be a patriot&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zdnet.com/pictures/claims-to-fame-high-profile-hackers-and-what-happened-next/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Claims to fame: High-profile hackers and what happened next&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zdnet.com/article/homeless-hacker-says-hell-accept-plea-bargain/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;'Homeless hacker' says he'll accept plea bargain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When contacted by &lt;em&gt;ZDNet&lt;/em&gt; on Friday, Mario said: &quot;It is true, with great sadness.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A second family member, Andres, also posted about Lamo's death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The coroner for Sedgwick County, where Lamo lived, confirmed his death, but provided no further details. Circumstances surrounding Lamo's death are not immediately known.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;sharethrough-top&quot; data-component=&quot;medusaContentRecommendation&quot; data-medusa-content-recommendation-options=&quot;{&amp;quot;promo&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;promo_ZD_recommendation_sharethrough_top_in_article_desktop&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;spot&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;dfp-in-article&amp;quot;}&quot;&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;p&gt;A neighbor who found his body said he had been dead for some time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Colombian-American hacker, who resided in Wichita, Kansas, first rose to notoriety in the early-2000s by hacking into systems at &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;, Microsoft, and Yahoo, which he was subsequently convicted for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lamo was more recently widely known for his involvement in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zdnet.com/article/oh-the-humanity-lamo-and-manning-chat-logs-released/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;passing information&lt;/a&gt; on whistleblower Chelsea Manning, a former US Army soldier who befriended Lamo. In an internet chat, Manning told Lamo that she had downloaded and burned classified files to a disk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lamo, with help from two friends in military intelligence, informed the US military of the breach. Manning was later arrested and sentenced to 35 years in prison. Her sentence was later commuted by President Barack Obama, and she was released last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2011/dec/15/hacker-adrian-lamo-bradley-manning-wikileaks&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;an interview with &lt;em&gt;The Guardian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in 2011, Lamo said his actions caused him &quot;lasting regret.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;relatedContent alignNone&quot; readability=&quot;7.7336683417085&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@zackwhittaker/how-to-contact-me-securely-38dc5c5bc756&quot; data-omniture-track=&quot;moduleClick&quot; data-omniture-track-data=&quot;{&amp;quot;moduleInfo&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;pinbox&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;pageType&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;article&amp;quot;}&quot;&gt;Contact me securely&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;dek&quot;&gt;Zack Whittaker can be reached securely on Signal and WhatsApp at 646-755–8849, and his PGP fingerprint for email is: 4D0E 92F2 E36A EC51 DAAE 5D97 CB8C 15FA EB6C EEA5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;read-more&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@zackwhittaker/how-to-contact-me-securely-38dc5c5bc756&quot; data-omniture-track=&quot;moduleClick&quot; data-omniture-track-data=&quot;{&amp;quot;moduleInfo&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;pinbox&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;pageType&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;article&amp;quot;}&quot;&gt;Read More&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;relatedContent alignNone&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;heading&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;int&quot;&gt;ZDNET INVESTIGATIONS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 15:54:34 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ad_hominem</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>http://www.zdnet.com/article/adrian-lamo-hacker-dies/</og:url>
<og:title>Hacker Adrian Lamo dies at 37</og:title>
<og:description>The coroner confirmed Lamo's death, but the circumstances of his passing are not yet known.</og:description>
<og:image>https://zdnet4.cbsistatic.com/hub/i/r/2018/03/16/ad57d4bd-7b32-4fa8-9da9-2c3bba8139ed/thumbnail/770x578/34267f1ce816aad605935a3ef3c812d9/adrian-lamo-jpg.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.zdnet.com/article/adrian-lamo-hacker-dies/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Airbus moves 130k employees from Microsoft Office to GSuite</title>
<link>https://www.geekwire.com/2018/google-picks-another-win-g-suite-airbus-grounds-microsoft-office/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.geekwire.com/2018/google-picks-another-win-g-suite-airbus-grounds-microsoft-office/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.geekwire.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/unnamed-2-630x393.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;630&quot; height=&quot;393&quot; class=&quot;size-full-width wp-image-404635&quot; srcset=&quot;https://cdn.geekwire.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/unnamed-2-630x393.png 630w, https://cdn.geekwire.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/unnamed-2-768x479.png 768w, https://cdn.geekwire.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/unnamed-2.png 853w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 630px) 100vw, 630px&quot;/&gt;Google Docs allows multiple members of an organization to easily collaborate on a single document. (Google Image)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With over 130,000 employees, Airbus uses a lot of office productivity software. It recently decided to make a big bet on Google’s G Suite software package after running the company for years on hosted versions of Microsoft Office, according to a report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.co.uk/2018/03/14/airbus_ditches_microsoft_for_google/&quot;&gt;The Register got its hands on&lt;/a&gt; (well, saw on a screen of some sort) an internal memo from Airbus CEO Tom Enders outlining the shift to G Suite as part of the company’s ongoing “digital transformation,” which is the new ubiquitous and fairly meaningless enterprise tech marketing buzzword. We’re really just talking about upgrades from hosted, on-premises software applications to cloud software applications, a transformation that for the most part has already taken place outside big old companies like Airbus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, it’s a nice deal for &lt;a href=&quot;https://gsuite.google.com/&quot;&gt;Google’s G Suite&lt;/a&gt;, the Google-hosted package that includes Docs, Gmail, and several other productivity apps. Google finally decided to share revenue figures for its cloud division, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geekwire.com/2018/google-says-recording-1b-per-quarter-cloud-revenue-including-gsuite/&quot;&gt;telling investors in February&lt;/a&gt; that it is making $1 billion a quarter between Google Cloud Platform and G Suite, and Airbus is a big enough company to move the needle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s also a disappointment for Microsoft, which chose to “politely decline” an opportunity to comment on the Airbus memo to The Register. Companies have been shifting away from on-premises versions of Microsoft Office for years, but Microsoft has done fairly well convincing those companies to use Office 365, as evidenced by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geekwire.com/2018/microsofts-cloud-business-still-growing-strong-fiscal-q2-led-office-365-azure/&quot;&gt;the 41 percent growth in commercial revenue posted by the Office 365 group during its second fiscal quarter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 15:42:23 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kbyatnal</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://cdn.geekwire.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/unnamed-2.png</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Google picks up another win for G Suite as Airbus grounds Microsoft Office</og:title>
<og:description>With over 130,000 employees, Airbus uses a lot of office productivity software. It recently decided to make a big bet on Google’s G Suite software package after running the company for years on hosted…</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.geekwire.com/2018/google-picks-another-win-g-suite-airbus-grounds-microsoft-office/</og:url>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.geekwire.com/2018/google-picks-another-win-g-suite-airbus-grounds-microsoft-office/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Google Cloud Platform’s new interactive CLI</title>
<link>https://cloudplatform.googleblog.com/2018/03/introducing-GCPs-new-interactive-CLI.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://cloudplatform.googleblog.com/2018/03/introducing-GCPs-new-interactive-CLI.html</guid>
<description></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 14:35:47 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>CSDude</dc:creator>
<og:title>Introducing GCP’s new interactive CLI</og:title>
<og:url>https://cloudplatform.googleblog.com/2018/03/introducing-GCPs-new-interactive-CLI.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-X8raHCDc4JA/WqJHiYWXOnI/AAAAAAAAFH4/FMjWQfDOJgkcOzi8angMnEa51aSSYjy2gCLcBGAs/s640/image1.gif</og:image>
<og:description>By Seher Aylin Altiok, Product Manager If you develop applications on Google Cloud Platform (GCP), you probably spend a lot of time in th...</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://cloudplatform.googleblog.com/2018/03/introducing-GCPs-new-interactive-CLI.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>