<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>You can now run Linux apps on Chrome OS</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2018/05/08/you-can-now-run-linux-apps-on-chrome-os/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2018/05/08/you-can-now-run-linux-apps-on-chrome-os/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;For the longest time, developers have taken Chrome OS machines and run tools like &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dnschneid/crouton&quot;&gt;Crouton&lt;/a&gt; to turn them into Linux-based developer machines. That was a bit of a hassle, but it worked. But things are getting easier. Soon, if you want to run Linux apps on your Chrome OS machine, all you’ll have to do is switch a toggle in the Settings menu. That’s because Google is going to start shipping Chrome OS with a custom virtual machine that runs Debian Stretch, the current stable version of the operating system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s worth stressing that we’re not just talking about a shell here, but full support for graphical apps, too. That means you could now, for example, run Microsoft’s Linux version of Visual Studio Code right on your Chrome OS machine. Or build your Android app in Android Studio and test it right on your laptop, thanks to the built-in support for Android apps that came to Chrome OS last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;breakout aligncenter size-full wp-image-1636019&quot; src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/img_20180508_132119.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;768&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first preview of Linux on Chrome OS is now available on the Pixelbook, with support for more devices coming soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/google/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;google&quot;&gt;Google’s&lt;/a&gt; PM director for Chrome OS Kan Liu told me the company was obviously aware that people were using Crouton to do this before. But doing this also meant doing away with all of the security features that come with Google’s operating system. And as more powerful Chrome OS machines hit the market in recent years, the demand for a feature like this also grew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To enable support for graphical apps, the team opted to integrate the Wayland display server; from the user’s perspective, the actual window dressing will look the same as any other Android or web app on Chrome OS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most regular users won’t necessarily benefit from built-in Linux support, but this will make Chrome OS machines even more attractive to developers — especially the more high-end ones like Google’s own Pixelbook. Liu stressed that his team spent quite a bit of work optimizing the virtual machine, too, so there isn’t a lot of overhead when you run Linux apps — meaning that even less powerful machines should be able to handle a code editor without issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, it’s probably only a matter of hours before somebody starts running Windows apps in Chrome OS with the help of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.winehq.org/&quot;&gt;Wine emulator&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/tag/google-i-o-2018&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/google-io-2018-banner.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 20:23:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>willsinclair</dc:creator>
<og:title>You can now run Linux apps on Chrome OS</og:title>
<og:description>For the longest time, developers have taken Chrome OS machines and run tools like Crouton to turn them into Linux-based developer machines. That was a bit of a hassle, but it worked. But things are getting easier. Soon, if you want to run Linux apps on your Chrome OS machine, all you’ll have …</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/chrome-linux-apps.png?w=753</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2018/05/08/you-can-now-run-linux-apps-on-chrome-os/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2018/05/08/you-can-now-run-linux-apps-on-chrome-os/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Android P</title>
<link>https://www.blog.google/products/android/android-p/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.blog.google/products/android/android-p/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Changing how you navigate your phone is a big deal, but small changes can make a big difference too. Android P also brings a redesigned Quick Settings, a better way to take and edit screenshots (say goodbye to the vulcan grip that was required before), simplified volume controls, an easier way to manage notifications and more. You’ll notice small changes like these across the platform, to help make the things you do all the time easier than ever.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Awareness and control of your digital wellbeing&lt;/h2&gt;
Technology should help you with your life, not distract you from it. So we've been working hard to add key capabilities right into Android to help you achieve your desired balance with technology. Our focus is on giving you a greater understanding of how you use your phone, as well as more controls. A new &lt;strong&gt;Dashboard&lt;/strong&gt;, for instance, shows you how you’re spending time on your device, including time spent in apps, how many times you’ve unlocked your phone, and how many notifications you’ve received. &lt;strong&gt;App Timer&lt;/strong&gt; lets you set time limits on apps, and will nudge you when you’re close to your limit and then gray out the icon to remind you of your goal. The new &lt;strong&gt;Do Not Disturb&lt;/strong&gt; mode silences not just the phone calls and notifications, but also all the visual interruptions that pop up on your screen. And to make it even easier to use, we created a new gesture: if you turn your phone over on the table, it automatically enters Do Not Disturb so you can focus on being present.  Finally, &lt;strong&gt;Wind Down&lt;/strong&gt; will switch on Night Light when it gets dark, and it will turn on Do Not Disturb and fade the screen to grayscale at your chosen bedtime to help you remember to get to sleep at the time you want.</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 19:51:31 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>alanfranzoni</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Android P: Packed with smarts and simpler than ever</og:title>
<og:description>We’re unveiling a beta version of Android P, the next release of Android.</og:description>
<og:image>https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/High_Res_YouTube_Thumbnai.1390055722611102.max-2800x2800.png</og:image>
<og:url>https://www.blog.google/products/android/android-p/</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.blog.google/products/android/android-p/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Introducing extended line endings support in Notepad</title>
<link>https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/commandline/2018/05/08/extended-eol-in-notepad/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/commandline/2018/05/08/extended-eol-in-notepad/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;For many years, Windows Notepad only supported text documents containing Windows End of Line (EOL) characters - Carriage Return (CR) &amp;amp; Line Feed (LF). This means that Notepad was unable to correctly display the contents of text files created in Unix, Linux and macOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, here’s a screenshot of Notepad trying to display the contents of a Linux .bashrc text file, which only contains Unix LF EOL characters:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;1081&quot; height=&quot;575&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter&quot; alt=&quot;Before&quot; src=&quot;https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/05/Notepad-before.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, Notepad is incorrectly displaying the file’s contents, making the file look garbled. This has been a major annoyance for developers, IT Pros, administrators, and end users throughout the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Today, we’re excited to announce that we have fixed this issue!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting with the current Windows 10 Insider build, Notepad will support Unix/Linux line endings (LF), Macintosh line endings (CR), and Windows Line endings (CRLF) as usual. New files created within Notepad will use Windows line ending (CRLF) by default, but it will now be possible to view, edit, and print existing files, correctly maintaining the file’s current line ending format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a screenshot of the newly updated Notepad displaying the contents of the same Unix/Linux .bashrc file we saw earlier:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;1081&quot; height=&quot;582&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter&quot; alt=&quot;After&quot; src=&quot;https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/05/Notepad-after.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also note that the status bar indicates the detected EOL format of the currently open file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with any change to a long-established tool, there’s a chance that this new behavior may not work for your scenarios, or you may prefer to disable this new behavior and return to Notepad’s original behavior. To do this, you can change the following registry keys in the following location to tweak how Notepad handles pasting of text, and which EOL character to use when Enter/Return is hit:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[HKEY_CURRENT_USER\Software\Microsoft\Notepad]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;620&quot; height=&quot;280&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter&quot; alt=&quot;Registry&quot; src=&quot;https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/05/Notepad-Registry.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope that you find this change useful and look forward to hearing your feedback&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 18:03:29 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dEnigma</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Introducing extended line endings support in Notepad</og:title>
<og:url>http://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/commandline/2018/05/08/extended-eol-in-notepad/</og:url>
<og:description>For many years, Windows Notepad only supported text documents containing Windows End of Line (EOL) characters - Carriage Return (CR) &amp; Line Feed (LF). This means that Notepad was unable to correctly display the contents of text files created in Unix, Linux and macOS. For example, here’s a screenshot of Notepad trying to display the...</og:description>
<og:image>https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/05/Notepad-before.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/commandline/2018/05/08/extended-eol-in-notepad/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Google Duplex: An AI System for Accomplishing Real World Tasks Over the Phone</title>
<link>https://ai.googleblog.com/2018/05/duplex-ai-system-for-natural-conversation.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://ai.googleblog.com/2018/05/duplex-ai-system-for-natural-conversation.html</guid>
<description></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 17:51:44 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ivank</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Google Duplex: An AI System for Accomplishing Real World Tasks Over the Phone</og:title>
<og:image>http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-qRz-hnwUdY4/WulXSQ6Rv4I/AAAAAAAATvQ/shk7KsphA0c3E3nUMsDVASqYaH0PhLPNwCK4BGAYYCw/s1600/GoogleAI_logo_horizontal_color_rgb.png</og:image>
<og:url>http://ai.googleblog.com/2018/05/duplex-ai-system-for-natural-conversation.html</og:url>
<og:description>Posted by Yaniv Leviathan, Principal Engineer and Yossi Matias, Vice President, Engineering, Google A long-standing goal of human-comput...</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://ai.googleblog.com/2018/05/duplex-ai-system-for-natural-conversation.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Yubico and Microsoft Introduce Passwordless Login</title>
<link>https://www.yubico.com/2018/04/yubico-and-microsoft-introduce-passwordless-login/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.yubico.com/2018/04/yubico-and-microsoft-introduce-passwordless-login/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Ten years ago, at the 2008 RSA Conference, Yubico launched the first YubiKey with the goal of making secure login easy and accessible for everyone.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;The vision was&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;one single security key to work across any number of services, with great user experience, security, and privacy.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;On this anniversary, Yubico has taken another major leap forward toward this vision with the announcement that the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yubico.com/2018/04/new-security-key-fido2/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;recently-launched Security Key by Yubico&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, with FIDO2, will be supported in Windows 10 devices and Microsoft Azure Active Directory (Azure AD). The feature is currently in limited preview for Microsoft Technology Adoption Program (TAP) customers.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;FIDO2 is the passwordless evolution of the FIDO Universal 2nd Factor (U2F) standard, created by Yubico and Google. While U2F included a username and password, FIDO2 supports more use cases, including passwordless authentication. Yubico has worked in close collaboration with Microsoft on developing the FIDO2 technical specifications, and the Security Key by Yubico is the first FIDO2 authentication device on the market.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What Does This Mean?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Organizations will soon have the option to enable employees and customers to sign in to an Azure AD joined device with no password, by simply using a Security Key to get single sign-on to all Azure AD based applications and services. This is just the beginning; Google and Mozilla also announced&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://fidoalliance.org/fido-alliance-and-w3c-achieve-major-standards-milestone-in-global-effort-towards-simpler-stronger-authentication-on-the-web/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Chrome and Firefox support for the Web Authentication API (WebAuthn)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;developed by Yubico and members of the World Wide Web Consortium (W3C) and included in the FIDO2 specification.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;780&quot; height=&quot;428&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wl479T2t6eo&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Is This Important?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Nearly every digital experience today requires passwords, an increasingly frustrating fact of life for businesses and users. For any one person there can be&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;hundreds&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;of sites and devices — both personal and business related — that require memorized passwords. This leads to poor password hygiene: shared and reused passwords. And it is a real cost for businesses managing, storing and resetting passwords for employees and end-users.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Working in conjunction with Windows and Microsoft cloud services, the new Security Key by Yubico offers a secure, seamless and passwordless login experience with one of the world’s largest computer operating systems. Use cases include retail, healthcare, transportation, finance, manufacturing, and more.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How Does It Work?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;FIDO2 is built on the same security and privacy features of FIDO U2F: strong public key cryptography, no drivers or client software and one key for unlimited account access with no shared secrets.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;With FIDO U2F, the user entered a username and password, inserted a  security key in the USB-port, and touched the gold area. F&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;IDO2 adds more options to the login process:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Single Factor:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;span&gt;This only requires possession of the Security Key to log in, allowing for a passwordless tap-and-go experience.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Second-Factor:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;span&gt;In a two-factor authentication scenario, such as the current Google and Facebook FIDO U2F implementations, the Security Key by Yubico is used as a strong second factor along with a username and password.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multi-Factor:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;span&gt;This allows the use of the Security Key by Yubico with an additional factor such as a PIN (instead of a password), to meet the high-assurance requirements of  operations like financial transactions, or submitting a prescription.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who Can Get Involved?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Everyone is encouraged to get involved, and accelerate progress to a secure and passwordless world. As with any open standard, advancement will be a collective industry effort and a process of global adoption. Yubico helped the majority of services in making support for FIDO U2F by providing open source code and support. Together with&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://fidoalliance.org/fido-alliance-and-w3c-achieve-major-standards-milestone-in-global-effort-towards-simpler-stronger-authentication-on-the-web/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;W3C and FIDO Alliance&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;we have made the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;FIDO2 open authentication standard available, and we are helping&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;support its rapid integration into services and applications through our new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;Yubico Developer Program.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enterprises →&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;span&gt;Learn about using FIDO2 with Windows 10 devices and Microsoft Azure Active Directory in your enterprise environment. Explore&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yubico.com/solutions/fido2/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;the benefits of FIDO2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Developers →&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;span&gt;Implement early support for FIDO2 by&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yubico.com/why-yubico/for-developers/developer-program/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;signing up&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;for updates from Yubico’s Developer Program. Members will have first access to resources to implement FIDO2 within their applications and services.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Individuals →&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;span&gt;Are you tired of passwords? If you had a choice to securely and easily login to any device or online service without them, would you? Ask for it! Visit your favorite service or businesses on Twitter and&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://ctt.ec/55eH9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;tell them&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;you want to securely login to your account without a password by using FIDO2 and the Security Key by @Yubico!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Are you interested in learning more about a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://yubico.com/nopasswords&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;life without passwords&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;? Learn more about the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yubico.com/product/security-key-by-yubico/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Security Key by Yubico&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;and benefits of&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yubico.com/solutions/fido2/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;FIDO 2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 17:30:21 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>guitarbill</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Yubico and Microsoft Introduce Passwordless Login | Yubico</og:title>
<og:description>The recently-launched Security Key by Yubico, with FIDO2, will be supported in Windows 10 devices and Microsoft Azure Active Directory (Azure AD).</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.yubico.com/2018/04/yubico-and-microsoft-introduce-passwordless-login/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.yubico.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/fido-smaller-600x300-1.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.yubico.com/2018/04/yubico-and-microsoft-introduce-passwordless-login/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Amazon’s Fake Review Economy</title>
<link>https://www.buzzfeed.com/nicolenguyen/amazon-fake-review-problem</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.buzzfeed.com/nicolenguyen/amazon-fake-review-problem</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;dns-prefetch&quot; href=&quot;https://img.buzzfeed.com/buzzfeed-static/&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;Content-Type&quot; content=&quot;text/html; charset=utf-8&quot;/&gt;&lt;title&gt;Inside Amazon’s Fake Review Economy&lt;/title&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;copyright&quot; content=&quot;Copyright BuzzFeed, Inc. All rights reserved.&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;viewport&quot; content=&quot;width=device-width, initial-scale=1, maximum-scale=1, minimum-scale=1, user-scalable=no&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;referrer&quot; content=&quot;unsafe-url&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;bf:buzzid&quot; content=&quot;4818685&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;bf:userid&quot; content=&quot;2741267&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;description&quot; content=&quot;A vast web of Amazon review fraud lives online, and it's designed to evade the company’s efforts to thwart it.&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;title&quot; content=&quot;Inside Amazon’s Fake Review Economy&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;apple-mobile-web-app-capable&quot; content=&quot;yes&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;apple-mobile-web-app-title&quot; content=&quot;BuzzFeed&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;apple-touch-icon&quot; href=&quot;/static-assets/img/apple-touch-icon.186faa454878ee0d6582ba33b41d2044.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;shortcut icon&quot; crossorigin=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;/static-assets/img/favicon.5a0c77a8815cfcc67c710199054a55c6.ico&quot; type=&quot;image/x-icon&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;theme-color&quot; content=&quot;#ee3322&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;canonical&quot; href=&quot;https://www.buzzfeed.com/nicolenguyen/amazon-fake-review-problem&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;image_src&quot; href=&quot;https://img.buzzfeed.com/buzzfeed-static/static/2018-05/8/16/campaign_images/buzzfeed-prod-web-06/inside-amazons-fake-review-economy-2-31413-1525810418-3_dblbig.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;author&quot; content=&quot;Nicole Nguyen&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;pin:media&quot; content=&quot;https://img.buzzfeed.com/buzzfeed-static/static/2018-05/8/16/campaign_images/buzzfeed-prod-web-06/inside-amazons-fake-review-economy-2-31413-1525810418-3_dblbig.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;pin:description&quot; content=&quot;Inside Amazon’s Fake Review Economy&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;apple-itunes-app&quot; content=&quot;app-id=352969997&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;manifest&quot; href=&quot;/static-assets/data/manifest.0edfa72a42a9e70e5bf211f64eae9384.json&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;fb:smart_publish:robots&quot; content=&quot;noauto&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;fb:app_id&quot; content=&quot;862012947269736&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;article:tag&quot; content=&quot;--primarykeyword-amazon&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;article:tag&quot; content=&quot;amazon&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;article:tag&quot; content=&quot;ecommerce&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;article:tag&quot; content=&quot;fake reviews&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;article:tag&quot; content=&quot;reviews&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;article:section&quot; content=&quot;Tech&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;article:publisher&quot; content=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/BuzzFeed&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:url&quot; content=&quot;https://www.buzzfeed.com/nicolenguyen/amazon-fake-review-problem&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:site_name&quot; content=&quot;BuzzFeed&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:image&quot; content=&quot;https://img.buzzfeed.com/buzzfeed-static/static/2018-05/7/16/enhanced/buzzfeed-prod-web-05/original-21887-1525726656-3.jpg?crop=3071:1608;0,349&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:title&quot; content=&quot;Inside The Ecosystem That Fuels Amazon’s Fake Review Problem&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:description&quot; content=&quot;A vast web of Amazon review fraud lives online, and it's designed to evade the company’s efforts to thwart it.&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:type&quot; content=&quot;article&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:app:id:iphone&quot; content=&quot;352969997&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:app:url:iphone&quot; content=&quot;buzzfeed://buzz/nicolenguyen/amazon-fake-review-problem&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:app:id:ipad&quot; content=&quot;352969997&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:app:url:ipad&quot; content=&quot;buzzfeed://buzz/nicolenguyen/amazon-fake-review-problem&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:site&quot; content=&quot;@fwd&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:creator&quot; content=&quot;@itsnicolenguyen&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:url&quot; content=&quot;https://www.buzzfeed.com/nicolenguyen/amazon-fake-review-problem&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:title&quot; content=&quot;Inside The Ecosystem That Fuels Amazon’s Fake Review Problem&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:description&quot; content=&quot;A vast web of Amazon review fraud lives online, and it's designed to evade the company’s efforts to thwart it.&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:app:id:googleplay&quot; content=&quot;com.buzzfeed.android&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:app:url:googleplay&quot; content=&quot;https://www.buzzfeed.com/nicolenguyen/amazon-fake-review-problem&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:card&quot; content=&quot;summary_large_image&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:image&quot; content=&quot;https://img.buzzfeed.com/buzzfeed-static/static/2018-05/7/16/enhanced/buzzfeed-prod-web-05/original-21887-1525726656-3.jpg?crop=3071:1535;0,349&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;preload&quot; href=&quot;/static-assets/css/enhanced.805b0e733eb4da1ce80c410bcee3396e.css&quot; as=&quot;style&quot; onload=&quot;this.rel='stylesheet'&quot; onerror=&quot;window.bfa('track/website/instrumentation', { data: { target: 'stylesheet', value: 'timeout' } })&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; href=&quot;/static-assets/css/enhanced.805b0e733eb4da1ce80c410bcee3396e.css&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot;/&gt;&lt;title id=&quot;back-to-top__title&quot;&gt;back to top&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;BuzzFeed News Logo&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Reporting To You&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Caret down&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On facebook&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On vk&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On pinterest&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On pinterest&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On lineapp&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On twitter&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On email&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On sms&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On whatsapp&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On more&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On tumblr&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On link&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On copy&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On facebook&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On twitter&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On facebook&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On twitter&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On facebook&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On pinterest&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On pinterest&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On email&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On copy&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On facebook&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On pinterest&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On pinterest&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On facebook&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On pinterest&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On pinterest&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On email&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On copy&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On facebook&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On pinterest&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On pinterest&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On facebook&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On pinterest&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On pinterest&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On email&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On copy&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On facebook&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On pinterest&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On pinterest&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On facebook&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On pinterest&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On pinterest&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On email&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On copy&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On facebook&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On pinterest&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On pinterest&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On facebook&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On pinterest&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On pinterest&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On email&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On copy&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On facebook&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On pinterest&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On pinterest&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On facebook&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On pinterest&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On pinterest&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On email&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On copy&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On facebook&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On pinterest&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On pinterest&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On facebook&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On pinterest&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On pinterest&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On email&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On copy&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On facebook&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On pinterest&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On pinterest&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On facebook&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On twitter&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On facebook&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On twitter&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On facebook&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On pinterest&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On pinterest&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On email&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On copy&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On facebook&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On pinterest&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On pinterest&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On facebook&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On twitter&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On facebook&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On twitter&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On facebook&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On pinterest&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On pinterest&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On email&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On copy&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On facebook&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On pinterest&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On pinterest&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On facebook&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On pinterest&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On pinterest&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On email&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On copy&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On facebook&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On pinterest&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On pinterest&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On facebook&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On pinterest&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On pinterest&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On email&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On copy&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On facebook&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On pinterest&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On pinterest&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On facebook&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On pinterest&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On pinterest&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On email&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On copy&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On facebook&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On pinterest&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On pinterest&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On facebook&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On twitter&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On facebook&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On twitter&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On facebook&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On vk&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On pinterest&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On pinterest&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On lineapp&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On twitter&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On email&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On sms&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On whatsapp&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On more&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On tumblr&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On link&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On copy&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On facebook&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On vk&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On pinterest&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On pinterest&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On lineapp&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On twitter&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On email&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On sms&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On whatsapp&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On more&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On tumblr&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On link&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Share On copy&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Next Quiz&lt;/title&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;4.9344827586207&quot;&gt;




&lt;div class=&quot;js-progressive-image-container xs-relative&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;buzz-feature-image__image xs-block xs-absolute js-progressive-image&quot; src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7&quot; data-src=&quot;https://img.buzzfeed.com/buzzfeed-static/static/2018-05/7/16/enhanced/buzzfeed-prod-web-03/longform-original-6849-1525726622-7.jpg&quot; data-mobile-src=&quot;https://img.buzzfeed.com/buzzfeed-static/static/2018-05/7/16/enhanced/buzzfeed-prod-web-05/mobile-21913-1525726637-5.jpg&quot; data-crop=&quot;68.75&quot; data-mobile-crop=&quot;100.27777777777777&quot; data-force-desktop-width=&quot;1600&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;subbuzz__attribution js-subbuzz__attribution xs-text-6 italic text-gray-lightest xs-mt05 xs-mx2 md-m0&quot;&gt;Edmon de Haro for BuzzFeed News&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://pixiedust.buzzfeed.com/v1.gif?source=buzz_web&amp;amp;platform=bpager&amp;amp;type=instrumentation&amp;amp;target=javascript&amp;amp;value=disabled&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 16:30:16 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jonbaer</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.buzzfeed.com/nicolenguyen/amazon-fake-review-problem</og:url>
<og:image>https://img.buzzfeed.com/buzzfeed-static/static/2018-05/7/16/enhanced/buzzfeed-prod-web-05/original-21887-1525726656-3.jpg?crop=3071:1608;0,349</og:image>
<og:title>Inside The Ecosystem That Fuels Amazon’s Fake Review Problem</og:title>
<og:description>A vast web of Amazon review fraud lives online, and it's designed to evade the company’s efforts to thwart it.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.buzzfeed.com/nicolenguyen/amazon-fake-review-problem</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>iOS 11.4 to Disable USB Port After 7 Days: What It Means for Mobile Forensics</title>
<link>https://blog.elcomsoft.com/2018/05/ios-11-4-to-disable-usb-port-after-7-days-what-it-means-for-mobile-forensics/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.elcomsoft.com/2018/05/ios-11-4-to-disable-usb-port-after-7-days-what-it-means-for-mobile-forensics/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;A new iOS update is about to roll out in the next few weeks or even days. Reading Apple documentation and researching developer betas, we discovered a major new security feature that is about to be released with iOS 11.4. The update will disable the Lightning port after 7 days since the device has been last unlocked. What is the meaning of this security measure, what reasons are behind, and what can be done about it? Let’s have a closer look.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;USB Restricted Mode in iOS 11.4&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the iOS 11.4 Beta, Apple introduced a new called USB Restricted Mode. In fact, the feature made its first appearance in the iOS 11.3 Beta, but was later removed from the final release. This is how it works:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“To improve security, for a locked iOS device to communicate with USB accessories you must connect an accessory via lightning connector to the device while unlocked – or enter your device passcode while connected – at least once a week.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The functionality of USB Restricted Mode is actually very simple. Once the iPhone or iPad is updated to the latest version of iOS supporting the feature, the device will disable the USB data connection over the Lightning port one week after the device has been last unlocked.&lt;span id=&quot;more-4802&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, it is still unclear whether the USB port is blocked if the device has not been unlocked with a passcode for 7 consecutive days; if the device has not been unlocked at all (password or biometrics); or if the device has not been unlocked or connected to a trusted USB device or computer. In our test, we were able to confirm the USB lock after the device has been left idle for 7 days. During this period, we have not tried to unlock the device with Touch ID or connect it to a paired USB device. What we do know, however, is that after the 7 days the Lightning port is only good for charging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Forensic Consequences of USB Restricted Mode&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Restricted USB Mode requires an iPhone running 11.3 to be unlocked at least once every 7 days. Otherwise, the Lightning port will lock down to charge only mode. The iPhone or iPad will still charge, but it will no longer attempt to establish a data connection. Even the “Trust this computer?” prompt will not be displayed once the device is connected to the computer, and any existing lockdown records (iTunes pairing records) will not be honoured until the user unlocks the device with a passcode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, law enforcement will have at most 7 days from the time the device was last unlocked to perform the extraction using any known forensic techniques, be it logical acquisition or passcode recovery via GreyKey or other services . Even the 7 days are not a given, since the exact date and time the device was last unlocked may not be known.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;USB Restricted Mode and Lockdown Records&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before iOS 11, one could use an existing lockdown record to access the iPhone or iPad device for the purpose of creating a new local backup (&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/2016/11/acquisition-of-a-locked-iphone-with-a-lockdown-record/&quot;&gt;logical acquisition&lt;/a&gt;). Essentially, this is exactly how experts perform logical acquisition in the vast majority of cases of iPhone and iPad devices that are &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/2017/01/how-can-i-break-into-a-locked-ios-10-iphone/&quot;&gt;locked with an unknown passcode&lt;/a&gt;. The lockdown record (a small file extracted from the suspect’s computer) allows accessing essential information about the device and initiating the backup sequence &lt;strong&gt;without the passcode&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to iTunes-style backups, the lockdown record &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/2018/04/understanding-logical-acquisition-of-ios-devices/&quot;&gt;could be used&lt;/a&gt; for pulling media files (pictures and videos), list installed apps, and access general information about the device. Once created, the lockdown records would not expire; however, if you &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/2017/11/the-iphone-is-locked-down-dealing-with-cold-boot-situations/&quot;&gt;power-cycle or reboot the iPhone&lt;/a&gt;, even a valid lockdown record will be of little use until you unlock the device with a passcode because of full-disk encryption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;iOS 11 brought limitations to the use of lockdown records. In iOS 11.0 through 11.2.1, lockdown records would expire after a certain unspecified time. Once a lockdown record expired, it could no longer be used to establish communication with the iOS device; the user would need to enter their passcode on the device to establish a new pairing relationship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;iOS 11.3 further limited the lifespan of iTunes pairing records, making the records &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/2018/01/ios-11-3-adds-expiry-date-to-lockdown-pairing-records/&quot;&gt;expire after 7 days&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What Happens After 7 Days?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently, iOS stores information about the date and time the device was last unlocked or had a data connection to a USB port. After the seven days elapse, the Lightning port will be disabled. Once this happens, you will no longer be able to pair the device to a computer or USB accessory, or use an existing lockdown record, without unlocking the device with a passcode. The only thing you’ll be able to do is charging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether or not iPhone unlocking solutions developed by GreyShift and Cellerbrite will work is still an open question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Mitigation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;USB Restricted Mode is aimed squarely at law enforcement, preventing device acquisition after the device has been stored for 7 consecutive days without being unlocked or connected to a (paired) computer or USB accessory. At this time, we suggest two possible mitigations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Extract the device during the first 7 days using a lockdown record (if available).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attempt to unlock the device during the first 7 days. Unlocking solutions (e.g. by GreyShift) will disable USB Restricted Mode if the initial connection is made while the Lightning port is still active.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a lockdown record is available, connecting the device to a paired accessory or computer may extend the time the USB port remains active. However, bear in mind that lockdown records now carry a 7-day expiry date of their own.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition, managed devices may disable USB Restricted Mode for good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The success rate will receive on the condition in which the phone is delivered to the lab. If the phone was seized while it was still powered on, and kept powered on in the meanwhile, than the chance of successfully connecting the phone to a computer for the purpose of making a local backup will depend on whether or not the expert has access to a non-expired lockdown file (pairing record). If, however, the phone is delivered in a powered-off state, and the passcode is not known, the chance of successful extraction is slim at best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why Apple Needed USB Restricted Mode&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually, it was only a matter of time. Companies such as Cellerbrite and the recent newcomer &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2018/03/greykey_iphone_.html&quot;&gt;GreyShift&lt;/a&gt; make their business by unlocking protected iPhones. While Cellerbrite offers this exclusively as an in-house service, and the service is only available to select law enforcement agencies with proper court orders, GreyKey supplies the actual unlocking hardware to North American law enforcement. Both companies keep their lips shut as to the details of their techniques, so the exact method they use to gain access to the devices is not known to Apple. However, their ability to unlock even the latest hardware running the latest version of iOS is worrisome, so Apple is taking action with the USB Restricted Mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In responce to the latest developments, Apple made an attempt to prevent device exploitation. USB Restricted Mode effectively disables the iPhone or iPad Lightning ports after 7 days without an unlock. While this undoubtedly strengthens overall security of iOS devices, effectively disabling logical acquisition through lockdown records after 7 days the device has been in storage, its effect on passcode unlocking techniques developed by Cellerbrite and GreyShift is yet to be seen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What else is Apple baking in iOS 11.4? Without going through the lengthy list of bug fixes and improvements, there is the possibility of iMessage sync with iCloud being finally released in iOS 11.4. iMessage sync showed up in early betas of iOS 11.0, but didn’t make it into the final release. The feature appeared again in iOS 11.3 betas, but was stripped from the final release at the last minute. There are signs the feature might be ready for prime time in iOS 11.4. How will iMessage sync work? How will it be different from Continuity, and what challenges and benefits will it present to the mobile forensic crowd? Stay tuned to find out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;nodash&quot; readability=&quot;13.508771929825&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tags: &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/tag/ios-11-4/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;ios 11.4&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/tag/ipad/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/tag/iphone/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/tag/lightning/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;lightning&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/tag/logical-acquisition/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;logical acquisition&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/tag/passcode-recovery/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;passcode recovery&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/tag/physical-acquisition/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;physical acquisition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;postmetadata alt&quot;&gt;&lt;small&gt;This entry was posted on Tuesday, May 8th, 2018 at 1:25 pm and is filed under &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/category/did-you-know-that/&quot; rel=&quot;category tag&quot;&gt;Did you know that...?&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/category/industry-news/&quot; rel=&quot;category tag&quot;&gt;Industry News&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/category/security/&quot; rel=&quot;category tag&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/a&gt;. You can follow any responses to this entry through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/2018/05/ios-11-4-to-disable-usb-port-after-7-days-what-it-means-for-mobile-forensics/feed/&quot;&gt;RSS 2.0&lt;/a&gt; feed. Both comments and pings are currently closed.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 15:19:47 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Artemis2</dc:creator>
<og:title>iOS 11.4 to Disable USB Port After 7 Days: What It Means for Mobile Forensics</og:title>
<og:url>https://blog.elcomsoft.com/2018/05/ios-11-4-to-disable-usb-port-after-7-days-what-it-means-for-mobile-forensics/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>A new iOS update is about to roll out in the next few weeks or even days. Reading Apple documentation and researching developer betas, we discovered a major new security feature that is about to be released with iOS 11.4. The update will disable the Lightning port after 7 days since the device has b</og:description>
<og:image>https://blog.elcomsoft.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/ios11.4_1200x630.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.elcomsoft.com/2018/05/ios-11-4-to-disable-usb-port-after-7-days-what-it-means-for-mobile-forensics/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How Mapbox Is Winning Over Developers to Challenge Google&amp;#039;s Mapping Dominance</title>
<link>https://www.forbes.com/sites/bizcarson/2018/05/08/mapbox-maps-developers/#79431e78164d</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.forbes.com/sites/bizcarson/2018/05/08/mapbox-maps-developers/#79431e78164d</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/bizcarson/2018/05/08/mapbox-maps-developers/#79431e78164d&quot;&gt;https://www.forbes.com/sites/bizcarson/2018/05/08/mapbox-maps-developers/#79431e78164d&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17021205&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17021205&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Points: 316&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 101&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 14:42:09 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>coloneltcb</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.forbes.com/forbes/welcome/?toURL=https://www.forbes.com/sites/bizcarson/2018/05/08/mapbox-maps-developers/&amp;refURL=http://www.google.co.uk/url?sa=t&amp;source=web&amp;cd=1&amp;referrer=http://www.google.co.uk/url?sa=t&amp;source=web&amp;cd=1</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A Recycled IP Address Caused Me to Pirate Books by Accident</title>
<link>https://nickjanetakis.com/blog/a-recycled-ip-address-caused-me-to-pirate-390000-books-by-accident</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://nickjanetakis.com/blog/a-recycled-ip-address-caused-me-to-pirate-390000-books-by-accident</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;post-meta&quot;&gt;Updated on May 8th, 2018 in &lt;a href=&quot;https://nickjanetakis.com/blog/tag/deployment-tips-tricks-and-tutorials&quot;&gt;#deployment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;https://nickjanetakis.com/assets/blog/cards/a-recycled-ip-address-caused-me-to-pirate-390000-books-by-accident-dab189f3143856dfa269bff43d9d2becc5f64a70b2ef7e2f44e1a66dd54c02cf.jpg&quot; class=&quot;post-card&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;422&quot; alt=&quot;blog/cards/a-recycled-ip-address-caused-me-to-pirate-390000-books-by-accident.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;lead no-letterspacing&quot;&gt;Let me tell you a story on how a subdomain of mine managed to serve 390,000+ PDF books without any of my servers being compromised.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;post-quick-jump&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quick Jump:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://nickjanetakis.com/blog/a-recycled-ip-address-caused-me-to-pirate-390000-books-by-accident#how-did-it-happen&quot;&gt;How Did It Happen?&lt;/a&gt; &lt;small&gt;|&lt;/small&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://nickjanetakis.com/blog/a-recycled-ip-address-caused-me-to-pirate-390000-books-by-accident#fixing-the-problem-in-a-few-seconds&quot;&gt;Fixing the Problem in a Few Seconds&lt;/a&gt; &lt;small&gt;|&lt;/small&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://nickjanetakis.com/blog/a-recycled-ip-address-caused-me-to-pirate-390000-books-by-accident#avoiding-the-problem-in-the-future&quot;&gt;Avoiding the Problem in the Future&lt;/a&gt; &lt;small&gt;|&lt;/small&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://nickjanetakis.com/blog/a-recycled-ip-address-caused-me-to-pirate-390000-books-by-accident#domain-validation-should-be-more-strict&quot;&gt;Domain Validation Should Be More Strict&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When people talk about a site being compromised, usually you would think that your server has been compromised. That would be someone gaining access to your server and then doing whatever they please.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That didn’t happen here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I take security very seriously. I have SSH locked down to only allow SSH key based logins and even root logins are disabled. My site is static too, which means it’s only being hosted through nginx from a non-root user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only way someone is going to gain access to my server is if they manage to gain access to my workstation and steal my SSH key pair. The odds of that are remote because my workstation never leaves my office and I have the reflexes of a highly trained ninja.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how did a subdomain of mine end up help distributing 390,000+ PDF books without my server being compromised? Well, that’s easy…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-did-it-happen&quot;&gt;How Did It Happen?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It boils down to this. About 2 years ago I was recording a video course that dealt with setting up HTTPS on a domain name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In all of my courses, I make sure to “really” do it on video so that you can see the entire process from end to end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back then I used &lt;a href=&quot;https://nickjanetakis.com&quot;&gt;nickjanetakis.com&lt;/a&gt; for all of my courses, so I didn’t have a dedicated domain name for the course I was working on, such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://diveintodocker.com/?utm_source=nj&amp;amp;utm_medium=website&amp;amp;utm_campaign=/blog/a-recycled-ip-address-caused-me-to-pirate-390000-books-by-accident&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;diveintodocker.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also didn’t have a spare domain name that I wanted to publicly share, so I registered a new &lt;a href=&quot;https://m.do.co/c/0a14c0d916b3&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;DigitalOcean&lt;/a&gt; droplet to host an example site on. Then I set up an A record to point ssl.nickjanetakis.com to that droplet’s IP address.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cool, there’s nothing wrong with that. Set up a temporary site for recording the course and then delete it afterwards. Easy peasy, and that’s exactly what I did but I forgot to remove the A record when I was done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So for years, I had ssl.nickjanetakis.com pointing to an IP address that I was no longer in control of. That means the owner of that IP address could host anything and it would automatically be mapped to ssl.nickjanetakis.com without me knowing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;i-ignored-the-first-warning-sign&quot;&gt;I Ignored the First Warning Sign&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/alerts&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Google Alerts&lt;/a&gt; set up so I get emailed when people link to my site. A few months ago I started to receive an absurd amount of notifications, but I ignored them. I chalked it up to “Google is probably on drugs”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stranger things have happened with Google, so I thought maybe something got mixed up. Now I’ve learned my lesson. While bugs roll out into production all the time, Google Alerts being totally busted is super unlikely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;i-didnt-ignore-the-second-warning&quot;&gt;I Didn’t Ignore the Second Warning&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of my morning routine is to check emails with intent to answer any questions about my courses that may have happened during the night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I usually skim the subject lines to see which emails to answer first but one of them caught my eye. It read &lt;em&gt;“Hi, seems your website has been compromised”&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well you don’t see that every day. I figured it was spam that somehow made it to my inbox but I recognized the email because it was someone who signed up for one of my courses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He sent me a screenshot showing a few PDFs being hosted from ssl.nickjanetakis.com, so I immediately went to Google and searched for &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;site:ssl.nickjanetakis.com&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;search-results-for-the-compromised-subdomain&quot;&gt;Search results for the compromised subdomain:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://nickjanetakis.com/assets/blog/dns-mistake-caused-pdfs-to-be-hosted-on-a-subdomain-6d312fde2dd428166b95a2fc252b31e0e18b24a27050f2fc7ebf355330762da6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;619&quot; alt=&quot;blog/dns-mistake-caused-pdfs-to-be-hosted-on-a-subdomain.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was mostly college books but there was a ton of other stuff too. Hopefully by the time you read this most of them have been removed from Google’s index.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;fixing-the-problem-in-a-few-seconds&quot;&gt;Fixing the Problem in a Few Seconds&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since it was linked to a subdomain I instantly knew what was wrong, especially because I remember using that subdomain a few years ago when I made that course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fix was really easy. I just hopped over to my domain registrar’s DNS settings and deleted the entry that mapped the IP address to that subdomain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But before deleting it, I copied the IP address so I could open a support ticket on &lt;a href=&quot;https://m.do.co/c/0a14c0d916b3&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;DigitalOcean&lt;/a&gt;. I figured they would like to know that someone is illegally distributing content on one of their servers. Now that they know the IP address, they can shut it down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;avoiding-the-problem-in-the-future&quot;&gt;Avoiding the Problem in the Future&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Always remove unused records from your DNS settings when you’re done using them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DigitalOcean and many other cloud providers have purchased blocks of IP addresses and they provide these IP addresses to people like you and me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a droplet gets destroyed, the IP address eventually gets put into the public pool of available IP addresses and someone else will get it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is pretty scary because things like the above can happen if you’re not careful, but it also means if an IP address were blacklisted for doing something questionable, you might end up with that IP address in the future (but that’s a totally different problem).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;domain-validation-should-be-more-strict&quot;&gt;Domain Validation Should Be More Strict&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think this brings up an interesting question. Right now you can validate you own a domain by putting an HTML snippet on your page. Services like Google Analytics allow for this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technically the person who took control over ssl.nickjanetakis.com could have proven ownership of that subdomain if they set up a page and hooked it up to Google Analytics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, Let’s Encrypt’s web server based challenge would have passed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know I made a stupid mistake by not removing the A record but this could happen to anyone. I would like to see more services only allow for DNS based authentication by adding TXT records.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I suppose the bigger problem here is having IP addresses being recycled. Hopefully once IPv6 is fully in use we’ll have a big enough pool so that hosting providers can remove previously used addresses from their pool. That won’t be fool proof, but it’s a start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Has this ever happened to you? Let me know in the comments below!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Like you, I'm super protective of my inbox, so don't worry about getting spammed. You can expect a few emails per month (at most), and you can 1-click unsubscribe at any time. &lt;a href=&quot;https://nickjanetakis.com/newsletter&quot;&gt;See what else you'll get&lt;/a&gt; too.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 14:05:57 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>nickjj</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>A Recycled IP Address Caused Me to Pirate 390,000 Books by Accident</og:title>
<og:description>Let me tell you a story on how a subdomain of mine managed to serve 390,000+ PDF books without any of my servers being compromised.</og:description>
<og:url>https://nickjanetakis.com/blog/a-recycled-ip-address-caused-me-to-pirate-390000-books-by-accident</og:url>
<og:image>https://nickjanetakis.com/assets/blog/cards/a-recycled-ip-address-caused-me-to-pirate-390000-books-by-accident-dab189f3143856dfa269bff43d9d2becc5f64a70b2ef7e2f44e1a66dd54c02cf.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://nickjanetakis.com/blog/a-recycled-ip-address-caused-me-to-pirate-390000-books-by-accident</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Amazon Froze My Account and I Still Don’t Know Why</title>
<link>https://bardsandsages.com/juliedawson/2018/05/06/amazon-froze-my-account-and-i-still-dont-know-why/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://bardsandsages.com/juliedawson/2018/05/06/amazon-froze-my-account-and-i-still-dont-know-why/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Where do I begin…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On May 2nd, I got an accusatory email from Amazon, claiming that one of my Society of Misfit Stories ebooks had “misleading metadata” and had been deactivated. Now before I get too far into this story, for those of you that are not tuned in to the soap opera that has become Amazon publishing as of late, metadata abuse is a major problem on Amazon. If you ever came across a book with a title like &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In Love With the Werewolf Billionaire&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(billionaire alpha shifter romance bestseller book three Sexy Werewolf Billionaire Series)&lt;/strong&gt; then you know things like keyword stuffing and bad metadata is a thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the thing is, my metadata is pristine. Because, you know, I’ve been involved in publishing for over a dozen years now and understand professional norms. So, the title and author name in the metadata for EVERY BOOK matches the title and author on the cover, and both match the title and author on the title page. Because, that is what you are supposed to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And while the ebook was in Select, there was no weirdness going on with it. Each ebook in the series is literally: title page, story, one-page author bio. THAT IS IT. No links to competitors. No stuffing of books within other books to increase page reads. No funny coding to trick the system into thinking more pages have been read than were actually read. &lt;strong&gt;Title page, story, author bio.&lt;/strong&gt; That is ALL that is in each entry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was some vague reference to the name of a famous author or personality. No, the email did not NAME the famous personality, and when I used Amazon search to see if there was another author with the same name as my author, nothing came up. So I sent Amazon an email that I didn’t understand what they were talking about. The author name was correct. Please reactivate the story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A short time later, I tried to log into my KDP account to upload the newest Misfit story and…I was frozen out of my account. I couldn’t even access KDP support. I had to go through regular Amazon support to reach a person, who forwarded my complaint to KDP support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus begin the bizarre story of my argument with the Bots of Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most people have suspected for a while now that Amazon was relying way too much on automation. The story you are about to read is evidence of just how ridiculous this has gotten.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following day, I received this email:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During a quality assurance review of your catalog, we found that you have published books with intentionally misleading metadata.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some examples of the books you have submitted:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Society of Misfit Stories Presents…[I have removed the title to avoid embarrassing the affected author]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As stated in our metadata guidelines, we don’t accept content that is meant to advertise, promote, or mislead, because such content may lead to inaccurate or overwhelming search results or impair our readers’ ability to make good buying decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result, we have temporarily suspended your account and we request that you respond to content-review@amazon.com with the following declaration: “I confirm that I have read and will comply with the Content Guidelines [https://kdp.amazon.com/self-publishing/help?topicId=A2TOZW0SV7IR1U] and [https://kdp.amazon.com/self-publishing/help?topicId=A294SHSUYLKTA6], and that I will remove any previously published books that do not meet these guidelines.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until we receive a response from you regarding this issue, your account will remain blocked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you would like to review the KDP Content Guidelines, please visit: https://kdp.amazon.com/self-publishing/help?topicId=A2TOZW0SV7IR1U.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So instead of explaining what they think I did, they send me a notice requiring me to promise not to do again what I have no idea what I have done. So I email them AGAIN asking them to please explain what, exactly, they think I did. Because I am very familiar with the TOS and for the life of me I have no idea what I am being accused of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few hours later, I get the following reply:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For information regarding your account, please reference the message that we sent you on May 3, 2018:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;we request that you respond to content-review@amazon.com with the following declaration: “I confirm that I have read and will comply with the Content Guidelines [https://kdp.amazon.com/self-publishing/help?topicId=A2TOZW0SV7IR1U] and [https://kdp.amazon.com/self-publishing/help?topicId=A294SHSUYLKTA6], and that I will remove any previously published books that do not meet these guidelines.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To reinstate your account please follow the instructions provided in the above email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, I send ANOTHER email asking them what they think I did. I can’t fix something that I don’t know what the problem is. I also forwarded the whole thing to Jeff Bezos’ email address, as sometimes he will get involved or, at least, whomever answers his emails gets involved. Because I NEED TO TALK TO A HUMAN BEING!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On May 4th, I get the following response:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have temporarily suspended your account and we request that you respond to content-review@amazon.com with the following declaration: “I confirm that I have read and will comply with the Content Guidelines and , and that I will remove any previously published books that do not meet these guidelines.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until we receive a response from you regarding this issue, your account will remain blocked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you would like to review the KDP Content Guidelines, please visit: https://kdp.amazon.com/self-publishing/help?topicId=A2TOZW0SV7IR1U.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best Regards,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Camila H&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best Regards,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ian S&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bangs head on table&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A short time later, I DID get an email from someone at KDP Executive Customer Relations, that they were investigating my problem and would get back to me. FINALLY! A human being was involved!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, on the 5th, I got another generic email from Amazon, making the same, identical statement demanding that I promise not to do what I have no idea what they think I did ever again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now at this point, your Sithiness here is ready to Force Choke someone. Because it is so painfully….HILARIOUSLY….obvious that no human being is reading my email queries that I decide to set a trap for the bot. So at 6 PM Saturday night, I sent the following email to their content-review address:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As per the request below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;”I confirm that I have read and will comply with the Content Guidelines [https://kdp.amazon.com/self-publishing/help?topicId=A2TOZW0SV7IR1U] and [https://kdp.amazon.com/self-publishing/help?topicId=A294SHSUYLKTA6], and that I will remove any previously published books that do not meet these guidelines.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I have repeated the requested statement, please unfreeze my account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am repeating this statement at your request. This is not an admission of guilt, as you have not actually informed me of what I an allegedly guilty of. I am complying with an arbitrary request to repeat information in an automated email. Repeating this statement in no way acknowledges the validity of the accusations Implied, since the accusations have never actually be clarified in any way, shape, or form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what do you think are the chances that the bot scanned the response for the required phrase and then unfroze my account without a human being ever reading it? If you answered “Highly likely…YOU WOULD BE CORRECT! Because by Sunday morning, my account was unfrozen, and I got a lovely, accusatory bot response informing me not to do it again or I could lose BOTH my KDP and Createspace accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still have no idea what I did, however. Since the offending story was reinstated with no changes to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started publishing in 2004, before the Kindle was a thing. I started with mobipocket.com and was part of the initial transition into KDP when it launched. I was an early adopter of the Createspace platform. I have been publishing with Amazon for over a decade and have always strived to present professional material. To have a robot accuse me of unethical behavior and demand that I promise not to do it again is insulting and borderline libel. Anyone who has ever worked with me knows I am one of the most open and transparent publishing in the indie community. To have an automated algorithm make an arbitrary decision that I broke some unexplained rule is enough to make me breath fire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what does all this mean?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For starters, it means I will no longer be making any Bards and Sages Publishing titles available exclusively through Select. All current Society of Misfit Stories locked into the 90-day exclusivity will remain available in Select until the 90-day window expires. Future Society of Misfit Stories entries will be published at Smashwords.com. This means they will also be available in epub and PDF formats, as well as mobi format. They will still be removed from sale after the six-month window.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, I’ve already stopped using Createspace for new releases. I’m going to start transitioning all of our older titles off Createspace platform. The books will still be available in print on Amazon, but they will no longer be under Amazon’s bot-tastic thumb where they will be able to lock me out of my own books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, while I will continue to upload ebooks to Amazon for now, I’m going to pursue other affiliate programs and stop driving traffic to Amazon listings entirely. In truth, Amazon has never been my primary market anyway, and if they don’t care enough about their publishers to have actual people make decisions that impact author livelihoods, I don’t know how much more business I want to pursue with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t expect Amazon will even notice or care about these changes. I’m not a seven-figure seller, and therefore I don’t matter to them. That is apparent from the treatment I received this weekend. Unfortunately, the treatment I received this weekend is indicative of how they treat everyone that is not a seven-figure seller. Amazon is not a friend of authors. They see us as interchangeable commodities to be used up, worn out, and replaced: like widgets.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 12:57:54 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ilamont</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://bardsandsages.com/juliedawson/2018/05/06/amazon-froze-my-account-and-i-still-dont-know-why/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>