<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Assembly Language for Beginners [pdf]</title>
<link>https://yurichev.com/writings/AL4B-EN.pdf</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://yurichev.com/writings/AL4B-EN.pdf</guid>
<description>&lt;a href=&quot;https://yurichev.com/writings/AL4B-EN.pdf&quot;&gt;Download PDF&lt;/a&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 11:59:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dennis714</dc:creator>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://yurichev.com/writings/AL4B-EN.pdf</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Linux touchpad like a Macbook: goal worth pursuing?</title>
<link>https://williambharding.com/blog/technology/linux-touchpad-like-a-macbook-goal-worth-pursuing/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://williambharding.com/blog/technology/linux-touchpad-like-a-macbook-goal-worth-pursuing/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Following is my proposal to improve the state of Linux touchpad drivers. It’s a cause I have spent almost a year of my spare time researching in depth. The first section, below, surveys the landscape of today’s available Linux touchpad drivers. The second section (“&lt;a href=&quot;https://williambharding.com/blog/technology/linux-touchpad-like-a-macbook-goal-worth-pursuing/#journey-here&quot;&gt;The Journey Here&lt;/a&gt;“) gets into greater depth describing the current failings of available choices. The third section (“&lt;a href=&quot;https://williambharding.com/blog/technology/linux-touchpad-like-a-macbook-goal-worth-pursuing/#path-forward&quot;&gt;The Path Forward&lt;/a&gt;“) proposes my best ideas for how we might be able to realize a Linux touchpad driver with polish level matching a Macbook Pro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;A survey of today’s Linux touchpad drivers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the last 6 months, I’ve been trying to configure a Dell Precision laptop running Arch to get the same feel as the Macbook Pros I loved until the Touchbar Era. I started with the Arch default, libinput. I gave up on it in about a week, when I determined that something as simple as controlling the two-finger scroll speed was &lt;a href=&quot;https://jlk.fjfi.cvut.cz/arch/manpages/man/libinput.4&quot;&gt;not included in the available options&lt;/a&gt;. The default was about 3x faster than the comfortable speed I’ve grown to love with my Macbooks. Had I not been disuaded by scroll speed, I might’ve still abandoned ship for the lack of scroll gliding (a feature I never knew I’d been using until it was taken away), which apparently I have Strong Opinions about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linux being Linux, I figured that I’d have a universe of touchpad drivers to choose from, each with its own awkward UI that would be confusing and painful to use, but ultimately get the job done. What I discovered instead was all of &lt;em&gt;three&lt;/em&gt; options: one of which I had just eliminated (&lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.archlinux.org/index.php/Libinput&quot;&gt;libinput&lt;/a&gt;), one that has been abandoned by its maintainers in favor of libinput (&lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.archlinux.org/index.php/Touchpad_Synaptics&quot;&gt;synaptics&lt;/a&gt;), and a third that was also abandoned by its maintainers, with zero graphical UI left behind (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BlueDragonX/xf86-input-mtrack&quot;&gt;mtrack&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m writing this blog because I appreciate the nuances of how the Macbook touchpad performs, but the Touchbar Era has taught me that it sucks to have my user experience tied to the whims of a singleminded hardware company. I want to be part of the solution to create a Linux touchpad driver that’s indistinguishable from the Macbook, and has at least a minimal UI to accommodate the most common differences in user preference. I believe this would bring Linux hardware a big step closer to owning the same panache that makes the Macbook experience special. All evidence collected to date suggests that my mission may well prove quixotic. But if other people care about this, it could get done. I &lt;a href=&quot;https://williambharding.com/blog/technology/linux-touchpad-like-a-macbook-goal-worth-pursuing/#path-forward&quot;&gt;posit my ideas on a path forward here&lt;/a&gt;. If you’ve got time and want to learn more about what informs my opinions on the best path forward, read on…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;journey-here&quot; class=&quot;heading&quot;&gt;The Journey Here&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After realizing libinput wasn’t going to work for me, I found &lt;a href=&quot;https://howchoo.com/g/mdy0ngziogm/the-perfect-almost-touchpad-settings-on-linux-2&quot;&gt;this blog post&lt;/a&gt;, whose title seduced me (“The perfect (almost) touchpad settings on Linux”). I went on to write my own &lt;a href=&quot;https://williambharding.com/blog/technology/toward-a-linux-touchpad-as-smooth-as-macbook-pro/&quot;&gt;follow up blog post&lt;/a&gt;, after discovering that the initial blog post left much to be desired compared to the Macbook standard I longed for. When it came to scroll speed and scroll glide, mtrack performed like a champ. Graphical UI be damned, I spent minutes — eventually hours — &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BlueDragonX/xf86-input-mtrack&quot;&gt;parsing the documentation&lt;/a&gt;. Between the 1,001 options available, I was optimistic about my prospects to recreate my Macbook utopia. And I would’ve done it, if not for the wretched nuisance I’d come to call “Cursor Nudge.” In a nutshell, “Cursor Nudge” is the phenomenon by which the center point of your depressed thumb will glide by a few millimeters as a natural effect of transitioning from the “move cursor” position to the “depress” position. None of mtrack’s 1,001 options could conquer Cursor Nudge, and eventually I grew weary of clicking &lt;em&gt;right next&lt;/em&gt; to my target.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Down to my final shot, &lt;a href=&quot;https://williambharding.com/blog/linux-to-macbook/linux-with-a-macbook-touchpad-feel-pt-2/&quot;&gt;I &lt;em&gt;really wanted&lt;/em&gt; synaptics to work&lt;/a&gt;. Yeah, it was abandonware, but it was &lt;a href=&quot;https://who-t.blogspot.com.au/2016/04/why-libinput-doesnt-have-lot-of-config.html&quot;&gt;abandonware that had been forsaken due to its multitude of options&lt;/a&gt;. A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.x.org/archive/X11R7.5/doc/man/man4/synaptics.4.html&quot;&gt;multitude of options&lt;/a&gt; seemed to be what I needed to replicate the Macbook. Initial results were promising: Cursor Nudge was not an issue with Synaptics. In fact, for my first few days using it, I found it pretty bearable. I wouldn’t confuse it with Macbook — not without the smooth acceleration and deceleration. Not with only the slighest twinge of scroll glide. Not with the need to click in the bottom right corner to effect a right click. But it was… &lt;em&gt;probably satisfactory&lt;/em&gt;. If not for the bugs. About once or twice a day, when I put my thumb down to click or start scrolling, my open document would jerk toward the bottom of the scrollable viewing area. I Googled it. I installed the xinput listener, &lt;a href=&quot;https://williambharding.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Selection_091.png&quot;&gt;captured all my tracking input into logs, and tailed the logs to look for patterns that preceded the bug&lt;/a&gt;. And then I wondered, “does Apple still sell the pre-Touchbar Macbook?” Turns out, in what I can only interpret as tacit admission of their wrongdoing, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/shop/buy-mac/macbook-pro?product=MJLQ2LL/A&amp;amp;step=config#&quot;&gt;they do&lt;/a&gt;. It doesn’t have enough RAM, and much of its technology is 10 years old. But its polish level remains eons beyond what I can replicate with Linux, and I refuse to carry around a mouse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a last resort, I emailed the maintainer of libinput (previously maintainer of Synaptics). I asked him what it would take to write a Linux touchpad driver that would approach parity with the Macbook. His take wasn’t optimistic (“unless you raise enough money to hire at least one full-time developer there’s little point”). I have to imagine this is what naturally happens to a developer that has spent large swaths of a career &lt;a href=&quot;https://who-t.blogspot.com.au/2016/04/why-libinput-doesnt-have-lot-of-config.html&quot;&gt;worrying about backwards compatibility and subtle hardware differences&lt;/a&gt;. It sounds like a special type of hell, and I appreciate the heroics that have gone into making a variety of Linux touchpad drivers almost good enough. But, even though I did eventually cave and buy new old Macbook, I’m not resigned to the imperfections of the current Linux touchpad landscape. A friend of mine who doesn’t even work in tech pointed out to me a month ago that he was reading a random post where they linked to &lt;a href=&quot;https://williambharding.com/blog/technology/toward-a-linux-touchpad-as-smooth-as-macbook-pro/&quot;&gt;my first blog post pursuing a Macbook-equivalent Linux driver&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Somebody&lt;/em&gt; besides me cares about this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;path-forward&quot; class=&quot;heading&quot;&gt;The Path Forward&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wherein it becomes apparent that the author doesn’t yet know the best solution.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think a polished driver could only be delivered within a narrow range of parameters. It probably isn’t going to support laptops older than 3-5 years old. It isn’t going to offer 1,001 options. It may or may not be continuously supported. It may use one of the existing drivers as a starting point, even if that starting codebase isn’t “clean” or well-documented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could we build something that works better than existing solutions for 95% of users (= developers) for less than $100k? Probably. Do users (or companies) feel enough pain with the Linux touchpad solutions that they’d donate money (or time) to tackle an esoteric issue? &lt;em&gt;That&lt;/em&gt; is what I need to find out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a sufficiently enthusiastic response to this blog (todo: define sufficient), I would volunteer my own time to spearhead the non-development aspects of a solution [1]. I could create a Kickstarter page, or help PM or QA development efforts on a driver built to mimic Macbook on the widest possible range of modern laptops. I could donate time to whatever better idea you present. But, first I need a hand to determine: does this actually matter?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1] I’d rather be programming this than PMing it, but my programmer brain is currently dedicated to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.staticobject.com&quot;&gt;quantifying developer activity&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.staticobject.com/lines_of_code_garbage_metric&quot;&gt;counting lines of code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 06:49:30 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>macco</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://williambharding.com/blog/technology/linux-touchpad-like-a-macbook-goal-worth-pursuing/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>My adventures getting Disney’s Moana island scene to render well with Pbrt</title>
<link>http://pharr.org/matt/blog/2018/07/16/moana-island-pbrt-all.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://pharr.org/matt/blog/2018/07/16/moana-island-pbrt-all.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Links to all of the articles in my adventures getting Disney’s &lt;em&gt;Moana&lt;/em&gt; island scene to render well with pbrt.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 02:49:03 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dsr12</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://pharr.org/matt/blog/2018/07/16/moana-island-pbrt-all.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>14,400-year-old flatbread remains that predate known agriculture</title>
<link>https://www.atlasobscura.com/articles/worlds-oldest-bread</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.atlasobscura.com/articles/worlds-oldest-bread</guid>
<description>&lt;img class=&quot;article-image with-structured-caption lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.atlasobscura.com/assets/blank-11b9c95a68e295dddd0ea924647536578ce285b2c8469a223c01df1ff3166af1.png&quot; alt=&quot;The Scanning Electron Microscope photograph of bread found at Shubayqa 1.&quot; width=&quot;auto&quot; data-kind=&quot;article-image&quot; id=&quot;article-image-57322&quot; data-src=&quot;https://assets.atlasobscura.com/article_images/57322/image.jpg&quot;/&gt;The Scanning Electron Microscope photograph of bread found at Shubayqa 1. &lt;span class=&quot;caption-credit&quot;&gt;All photos courtesy of Alexis Pantos&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;item-body-text-graf&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;section-start-text&quot;&gt;Bread-making around the world has&lt;/span&gt; evolved from a similar, ancient approach of combining flour, water, and sometimes yeast. But for prehistoric societies with limited tools, making bread wasn’t so simple. Given how laborious it was to make bread thousands of years ago, it’s long been associated with settled Neolithic societies—and only after the advent of agriculture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;item-body-text-graf&quot;&gt;That’s no longer the case. Today, a team of researchers from the University of Copenhagen, the University College London, and the University of Cambridge released a paper in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/07/10/1801071115&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; detailing their discovery of 14,400-year-old crumbs from a flatbread. The archaeological site, known as Shubayqa 1, is located in the Black Desert of northeastern Jordan and was home to Natufian hunter-gatherers. The flatbread remains are not only the oldest instance of bread found to date, but also preeminent examples of how bread-making existed even before agriculture developed some 4,000 years later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;item-body-text-graf&quot;&gt;“Nobody had found any direct evidence for production of bread, so the fact that bread predates agriculture is kind of stunning,” says Tobias Richter, a University of Copenhagen archaeologist who co-authored the paper. “Because making bread is quite labor-intensive, and you don’t necessarily get a huge return for it. So it doesn’t seem like an economical thing to do.” That’s because breadmaking doesn’t just involve baking: Back then, it would have also involved kneading, grinding cereals into fine grains, and dehusking plants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;item-body-text-graf&quot;&gt;Before the find at Shubayqa 1, the closest evidence of bread-like cereal meals had been identified at the Neolithic site Çatalhöyük, in Turkey. “We really didn’t think up until now that in the Natufian [period], people were making bread,” he adds. “We’ve just pushed that 5,000 years earlier.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;item-body-text-graf&quot;&gt;For years, researchers have been excavating Shubayqa 1 to learn more about the Natufians’ diet and lifestyle. “Natufian is a very interesting period in Near Eastern prehistory, because it does mark a real point of departure with some of the preceding periods,” Richter says. “They built some of the world’s earliest stone dwellings, and appear to have been more sedentary than periods before then.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;article-image with-structured-caption lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.atlasobscura.com/assets/blank-11b9c95a68e295dddd0ea924647536578ce285b2c8469a223c01df1ff3166af1.png&quot; alt=&quot;The semi-sunken structure pictured at Shubayqa 1 is made of stone.&quot; width=&quot;auto&quot; data-kind=&quot;article-image&quot; id=&quot;article-image-57321&quot; data-src=&quot;https://assets.atlasobscura.com/article_images/57321/image.jpg&quot;/&gt;The semi-sunken structure pictured at Shubayqa 1 is made of stone.
&lt;p class=&quot;item-body-text-graf&quot;&gt;Richter says that compared to other Natufian sites, Shubayqa 1 is unusual in how well-preserved its plants are, and it reveals intriguing possibilities about the relationship between social change, economic shifts, and climate change. Previous findings &lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.com/books?id=YA-EAgAAQBAJ&amp;amp;pg=PA6&amp;amp;lpg=PA6&amp;amp;dq=natufian+high+carbohydrate+diet&amp;amp;source=bl&amp;amp;ots=4A6Fch1ePF&amp;amp;sig=Q77O4v4a7cVKjyWICfJ12g_OSJM&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=2ahUKEwjr6bX8xaTcAhXIT98KHV2cBVsQ6AEwA3oECAEQXg#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=natufian%20high%20carbohydrate%20diet&amp;amp;f=false&quot;&gt;suggest, for instance,&lt;/a&gt; that the Natufians had high-carbohydrate diets, hunted animals such as gazelles, and, as evidenced by their elaborate burials, had well-established cultural rituals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;item-body-text-graf&quot;&gt;The bread discovery happened by chance, when Amaia Arranz Otaegui, an archaeobotanist at the University of Copenhagen, found unidentifiable charred remains in fireplaces at Shubayqa 1. She took her findings to University College London’s Institute of Archaeology, which has a trove of modern plants that archaeologists can compare their findings to. There, she enlisted the help of Lara González Carretero, an authority on prehistoric bread. Using electronic microscopy, she determined that the charred remains—which Richter describes as “the kind of stuff you might find at the bottom of your toaster”—was likely evidence of unleavened bread.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;item-body-text-graf&quot;&gt;Until recently, food remains weren’t given much attention within archaeological digs. “Mostly up until now archaeobotanists have been interested in seeds, wood fragments, and nuts and so forth,” Richter says. “It’s fairly new that people have started to look at food remains in these sediment samples that we’re excavating from various sites.” Several years ago, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2015-08/bu-wbb082515.php&quot;&gt;a team of researchers&lt;/a&gt; excavating the Natufian site Huzuq Musa (in Israel’s Jordan Valley) processed wild barley and loaves of unleavened bread using 12,500-year-old conical mortars. Some experts have speculated that bread-baking stretches back &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.history.com/news/a-brief-history-of-bread&quot;&gt;even further than 14,400 years ago&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;article-image with-structured-caption lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.atlasobscura.com/assets/blank-11b9c95a68e295dddd0ea924647536578ce285b2c8469a223c01df1ff3166af1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Grinding a club rush plant to experiment with flour-making. &quot; width=&quot;auto&quot; data-kind=&quot;article-image&quot; id=&quot;article-image-57320&quot; data-src=&quot;https://assets.atlasobscura.com/article_images/57320/image.jpg&quot;/&gt;Grinding a club rush plant to experiment with flour-making.
&lt;p class=&quot;item-body-text-graf&quot;&gt;Over the years, fossilized loaves and bread-making grains alike have been unearthed at archaeological sites, such as Italy’s Pompeii and Ohalo II, in what’s now considered Israel, respectively. But the recently discovered flatbread remains at Shubayqa 1 bear similarities to those found at various other sites around Turkey and Europe, too. “So we now know that bread-like products were produced long before the development of farming,” &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ucl.ac.uk/news/news-articles/0718/160718-origins-bread&quot;&gt;said Arranz Otaegui&lt;/a&gt;. “The next step is to evaluate if the production and consumption of bread influenced the emergence of plant cultivation and domestication at all.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;item-body-text-graf item-body-last&quot;&gt;How Natufians made this bread, exactly, remains up for debate. “What’s quite surprising from the work we’ve done so far is that the flour they used is really fine, and you wonder, ‘How the hell did they do that?’” Richter says. “[It’s] really high-quality, so they must have spent a lot of time getting it into a really fine state.” He says the team has been awarded another grant to study food production, so making a very &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.atlasobscura.com/articles/putting-ancient-recipes-plate-classical-recipes-cooking&quot;&gt;old flatbread is on the table&lt;/a&gt;. “One of the things we want to do next is to try and reproduce this bread experimentally,” Richter says. “And see what it tasted like.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gastro Obscura covers the world’s most wondrous food and drink.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.atlasobscura.com/newsletters/gastro-obscura&quot;&gt;Sign up for our email, delivered twice a week&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 00:01:25 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>vinayan3</dc:creator>
<og:title>Found: 14,400-Year-Old Flatbread Remains That Predate Agriculture</og:title>
<og:url>http://www.atlasobscura.com/articles/worlds-oldest-bread</og:url>
<og:image>https://assets.atlasobscura.com/media/W1siZiIsInVwbG9hZHMvYXNzZXRzL2Y2ZTQ0MWY5LWQ5ZmMtNDQ1Yy1iMDdlLWE3MjhhODVlNDkyOThjZjRiNzBhMjUxNTZlZTc2Nl9JbWFnZSAyLmpwZyJdLFsicCIsImNvbnZlcnQiLCItcXVhbGl0eSA4MSAtYXV0by1vcmllbnQiXSxbInAiLCJ0aHVtYiIsIjYwMHg-Il1d/Image%202.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>The burned crumbs shed light on prehistoric hunter-gatherers’ diets.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.atlasobscura.com/articles/worlds-oldest-bread</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Power of Positive People</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/07/10/well/the-power-of-positive-people.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2018/07/10/well/the-power-of-positive-people.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;45.413946587537&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;38.243323442137&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Are you spending time with the right people for your health and happiness?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;While many of us focus primarily on diet and exercise to achieve better health, science suggests that our well-being also is influenced by the company we keep. Researchers have found that certain health behaviors &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0090315&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;appear to be contagious&lt;/a&gt; and that our social networks — in person and online — can influence &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2007/07/25/health/25cnd-fat.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;obesity&lt;/a&gt;, anxiety and overall happiness. A recent report found that a person’s exercise routine &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/04/19/well/move/running-may-be-socially-contagious.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;was strongly influenced&lt;/a&gt; by his or her social network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;I was reminded recently of the power of the crowd during a wellness cruise sponsored by &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/times-journeys/journey-finder/?_ga=2.212729809.4914752.1531196194-1396141597.1525918322&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Times Journeys&lt;/a&gt;. The event attracted a group of like-minded travelers who, despite experiencing various levels of adversity in their lives, including cancer, vision loss and the recent loss of a loved one, were remarkably optimistic and upbeat. The group ranged in age from 17 to 90. One inspiring man, in his 80s, had adopted a vegan lifestyle and a strict exercise routine to control his diabetes. Another new friend, a woman in her 50s who had survived lung cancer, cheered me on and kept me going during a particularly difficult workout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;After the trip, we all promised to keep in touch. Buoyed by the experience, I returned home with a renewed commitment not only to exercise and healthful living, but to simply step up my social life and spend more time hanging out with happy people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Dan Buettner, a National Geographic fellow and author, has studied the health habits of people who live in so-called blue zones — &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bluezones.com/about/history/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;regions&lt;/a&gt; of the world where people live far longer than the average. He noted that positive friendships are a common theme in the blue zones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;37&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;19&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“Friends can exert a measurable and ongoing influence on your health behaviors in a way that a diet never can,” Mr. Buettner said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;In Okinawa, Japan, a place where the average life expectancy for women is around 90, the oldest in the world, people form a kind of social network called a moai — a group of five friends who offer social, logistic, emotional and even financial support for a lifetime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;36.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;18&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“It’s a very powerful idea,” Mr. Buettner said. “Traditionally, their parents put them into moais when they are born, and they take a lifelong journey together.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;In a moai, the group benefits when things go well, such as by sharing a bountiful crop, and the group’s families support one another when a child gets sick or someone dies. They also appear to influence one another’s lifelong health behaviors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;51.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;48&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Buettner is working with federal and state health officials, including the former United States Surgeon General Vivek Murthy, to create moais in two dozen cities around the country. He recently spent time in Fort Worth, Tex., where several residents have formed walking moais — groups of people who meet regularly to walk and socialize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“We’re finding that in some of these cities, you can just put people together who want to change health behaviors and organize them around walking or a plant-based potluck,” he said. “We nudge them into hanging out together for 10 weeks. We have created moais that are now several years old, and they are still exerting a healthy influence on members’ lives.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The key to building a successful moai is to start with people who have similar interests, passions and values. The Blue Zone team tries to group people based on geography and work and family schedules to start. Then they ask them a series of questions to find common interests. Is your perfect vacation a cruise or a backpacking trip? Do you like rock ’n’ roll or classical music? Do you subscribe to The New York Times or The Wall Street Journal?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“You stack the deck in favor of a long-term relationship,” said Mr. Buettner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;One of my fellow travelers, Carol Auerbach of New York City, noted that surrounding herself with positive people has helped her cope with the loss of two husbands over the years. Ms. Auerbach was widowed at 30, when her children were just 2 and 5. With the support of her family and friends, and her own tenacity, she was able to support her family, and she eventually remarried. And then in 1992, her second husband died unexpectedly. To cope the second time, she focused on volunteer work and contributing to her community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Ms. Auerbach said she believes that she learned to have a positive outlook from her mother, a Holocaust survivor who left Germany at the age of 19 and never saw her parents again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;35&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“When I was growing up we were not affluent, and the four of us lived in a one-bedroom apartment, and my parents slept on a pullout sofa,” she said. “My mother never complained. I think she quietly knew that difficult things happen, but you feel very appreciative of the life you do have, and you feel a responsibility to make the most of it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;41.866197183099&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;29.552609776305&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Ms. Auerbach eventually found love again and has been married to her third husband for 15 years. “Life is too short to be around negative people,” she said. “I need people around me who care about me and are appreciative, and see the world as a glass half full, not half empty.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The Blue Zone team &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bluezones.com/live-longer-better/checklists/tribe/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;has created a quiz&lt;/a&gt; to help people assess the positive impact of their own social network. The quiz asks questions about your friends and the state of their health, how much they drink, eat and exercise, as well as their outlook. The goal of the quiz is not to dump your less healthy friends, but to identify the people in your life who score the highest and to spend more time with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“I argue that the most powerful thing you can do to add healthy years is to curate your immediate social network,” said Mr. Buettner, who advises people to focus on three to five real-world friends rather than distant Facebook friends. “In general you want friends with whom you can have a meaningful conversation,” he said. “You can call them on a bad day and they will care. Your group of friends are better than any drug or anti-aging supplement, and will do more for you than just about anything.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;26.060324825986&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;css-ezqtdp e17092zo0&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-8lxt5a e1jq7jgg0&quot; readability=&quot;6.6771653543307&quot;&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;9.1811023622047&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tara Parker-Pope is the founding editor of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/section/well&quot;&gt;Well&lt;/a&gt;, The Times’s award-winning consumer health site. She won an Emmy in 2013 for the video series &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.nytimes.com/www.nytimes.com/interactive/health/life-interrupted.html&quot;&gt;“Life, Interrupted”&lt;/a&gt; and is the author of “For Better: The Science of a Good Marriage.” &lt;span class=&quot;css-4w91ra&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/taraparkerpope&quot; class=&quot;css-1rj8to8&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-0&quot;&gt;@&lt;/span&gt;taraparkerpope&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 19:33:47 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Tomte</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/07/10/well/the-power-of-positive-people.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>The Power of Positive People</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/07/17/autossell/17sci_positive/17sci_positive-facebookJumbo-v3.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Are your friendships giving you a boost or bringing you down?</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/07/10/well/the-power-of-positive-people.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Potential DNA damage from CRISPR has been ‘seriously underestimated’ study finds</title>
<link>https://www.statnews.com/2018/07/16/crispr-potential-dna-damage-underestimated/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.statnews.com/2018/07/16/crispr-potential-dna-damage-underestimated/</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;big-cap-wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;big-cap&quot;&gt;F&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;rom the earliest days of the CRISPR-Cas9 era, scientists have known that the first step in how it &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statnews.com/2018/04/04/how-crispr-works-visualized/&quot;&gt;edits genomes&lt;/a&gt; — snipping DNA — creates an unholy mess: Cellular repairmen frantically try to fix the cuts by throwing random chunks of DNA into the breach and deleting other random bits. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/Nbt.4192&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Research&lt;/a&gt; published on Monday suggests that’s only the tip of a Titanic-sized iceberg: CRISPR-Cas9 can cause significantly greater genetic havoc than experts thought, the study concludes, perhaps enough to threaten the health of patients who would one day receive &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statnews.com/2018/02/21/crispr-sickle-cell-clinical-trials/&quot;&gt;CRISPR-based therapy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results come hard on the heels of two &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statnews.com/2018/06/11/crispr-hurdle-edited-cells-might-cause-cancer/&quot;&gt;studies&lt;/a&gt; that identified a related issue: Some CRISPR’d cells might be missing a key anti-cancer mechanism and therefore be able to initiate tumors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The DNA damage found in the new study included deletions of thousands of DNA bases, including at spots far from the edit. Some of the deletions can silence genes that should be active and activate genes that should be silent, including cancer-causing genes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ad-label&quot;&gt;advertisement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The DNA chaos that CRISPR unleashes has been “seriously underestimated,” said geneticist Allan Bradley of England’s Wellcome Sanger Institute, who led the study. “This should be a wake-up call.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;read-more standard&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Leading CRISPR companies scrambled to play down the latest threat to what they hope will be a multibillion-dollar business &lt;strong&gt;—&lt;/strong&gt; and to their stock prices, but investors reacted with alarm. Within the first 20 minutes of when the study was released, the three publicly traded CRISPR companies lost more than $300 million in value, and it was downhill from there: CRISPR Therapeutics ended down 8.6 percent, Editas Medicine fell 7 percent, and Intellia Therapeutics lost nearly 10 percent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The companies questioned whether the CRISPR-caused DNA damage reported in the new study applied to the kind of cells they’re planning to CRISPR. They emphasized that if genomic scrambling is at all common then it should also be seen in earlier forms of genome-editing such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statnews.com/2017/11/30/crispr-talens-gene-editing/&quot;&gt;zinc fingers and TALENs&lt;/a&gt; (but apparently isn’t). And they insisted they’re on the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We’re not Pollyannaish about this,” said geneticist Tom Barnes, chief innovation officer at Intellia. For its mouse experiments, Intellia analyzes edited genomes for collateral damage both near the editing target and tens of thousands of DNA letters away, he said, but “we have not seen any [cancer-causing] transformation of these cells, even with all the edits we’ve introduced.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a statement, Editas spokeswoman Cristi Barnett said the possibility of genetic chaos from CRISPR is “an interesting topic” that the company “actively examine[s].” The reported DNA havoc, she said, is not “specifically problematic in our work to make CRISPR-based medicines.” CRISPR Therapeutics did not respond to requests for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Academic scientists were less dismissive of the new study, in Nature Biotechnology. One leading CRISPR developer called it “well-done and credible,” “a cautionary note to the [genome-editing] community,” and consistent with other research showing that the DNA cuts that CRISPR makes, called double-stranded breaks, “can induce the types of genomic DNA rearrangements and deletions they report.” He asked not to be identified so as not to jeopardize business relationships with genome-editing companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;read-more statplus&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;read-more-thumbnail-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;read-more-thumbnail&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statnews.com/stat-plus/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/themes/stat/images/icons/stat-plus-white.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;But just as critics of last month’s studies asked why, if CRISPR’d cells can initiate cancer, no CRISPR’d mice had turned up with tumors, so scientists raised similar questions about the new genomic havoc finding: Why don’t scientists see it when they analyze the DNA of CRISPR’d cells?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You find what you look for,” said Bradley. “No one is looking at the impact [of these DNA changes] on downstream genes.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And few studies conduct full-out genome sequencing of CRISPR’d cells. Moreover, scientists typically search for one form of the collateral damage the Sanger study found — deletions of thousands of DNA bases (the double helix’s famous A’s, T’s, C’s, and G’s) — using a standard technique called PCR, which makes millions of DNA copies. But to work, PCR must attach to a “binding site” on DNA; CRISPR sometimes deletes that binding site, said Bradley, whose team used a different technique to analyze the double helix for collateral damage from CRISPR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Sanger scientists didn’t set out to find collateral DNA damage from CRISPR. As they investigated how CRISPR might change gene expression, a “weird thing” showed up, Bradley said: The target DNA was accurately changed, but that set off a chain reaction that engulfed genes far from the target. The scientists therefore changed course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When they aimed CRISPR at different targets in mouse embryonic stem cells, mouse blood-making cells, and human retinal cells, “extensive on-target genomic damage [was] a common outcome,” they wrote in their paper. In one case, genomes in about two-thirds of the CRISPR’d cells showed the expected small-scale inadvertent havoc, but 21 percent had DNA deletions of more than 250 bases and up to 6,000 bases long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since therapeutic uses of CRISPR would edit the genomes of billions of cells in, say, a patient’s liver, even rare DNA damage “makes it likely that one or more edited cells … would be endowed with an important [disease-causing] lesion,” the scientists wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nature Biotechnology took a year to publish the paper, after asking Bradley numerous variations of “are you sure?” and “did you consider this?” and asking him to run additional experiments, Bradley said. The results all held up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one U.S. &lt;a href=&quot;https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT03399448&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;clinical trial&lt;/a&gt; using CRISPR’d cells began recruiting patients this year. It will use CRISPR to make immune cells, removed from patients with any of four types of cancer, attack telltale molecules on the tumor cells’ surface. Asked what genome analysis he plans to do, lead investigator Dr. Edward Stadtmauer of the University of Pennsylvania said, “We are doing extensive testing of the final cellular product as well as the cells within the patient.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The possibility of adverse consequences from CRISPR’d cells has caused some company officials to argue that if, say, their therapy cures a child of a devastating disease, but increases her risk of cancer, that might be an acceptable trade-off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That argument may well prevail. In 2003, however, when a boy in a gene therapy trial in France &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nejm.org/doi/full/10.1056/NEJM200301163480314&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;developed leukemia&lt;/a&gt; because the repair gene landed in the wrong place in his genome and activated a cancer-causing gene, it shut down gene therapy development on both sides of the Atlantic for years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;content-meta&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;author-info&quot; readability=&quot;4.6341463414634&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-avatar&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Circular_Sharon.png&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Circular_Sharon.png 160w, https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Circular_Sharon-80x80.png 80w&quot; width=&quot;80&quot; height=&quot;80&quot; class=&quot;avatar&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-data&quot; readability=&quot;6.1788617886179&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Senior Writer, Science and Discovery&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sharon covers science and discovery.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 19:28:49 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>valeg</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Potential CRISPR damage has been 'seriously underestimated,' study finds</og:title>
<og:description>A new study suggests CRISPR can cause significantly greater genetic havoc than experts thought; leading CRISPR companies scrambled to play down the threat.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.statnews.com/2018/07/16/crispr-potential-dna-damage-underestimated/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.statnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/DNABreak-1024x576.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.statnews.com/2018/07/16/crispr-potential-dna-damage-underestimated/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Prime Down: Amazon’s sale day turns into fail day</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2018/07/16/prime-down-amazons-sale-day-turns-into-fail-day/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2018/07/16/prime-down-amazons-sale-day-turns-into-fail-day/</guid>
<description>&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: Here’s how to get around Amazon’s error. Use smile.amazon.com. TechCrunch confirmed this workaround works.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s not just you. &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/amazon/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;amazon&quot;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; Prime Day started 15 minutes ago, and so far, it’s not going well for Amazon. The landing page for Prime Day does not work. When most links are clicked, visitors are sent to an error page or to a landing page that sends readers back to the main landing page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Direct links to the product pages, either from outside links or the single product placement on the landing page, seem to work fine. I &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B004E4ERIY?th=1&quot;&gt;just bought this tent&lt;/a&gt; two weeks ago for $120. Some users are reporting errors when completing a purchase, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a huge blow to Amazon and its faux holiday Prime Day. The retailer has been pushing this event for weeks and &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/07/13/amazon-prime-days-best-tech-deals/&quot;&gt;there are some great deals to be had&lt;/a&gt;. It’s not a good look for the world’s largest retailer even though the retailer &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.digitalcommerce360.com/2017/07/11/amazon-add-cart-glitch-prime-day/&quot;&gt;saw glitches&lt;/a&gt; last year, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other retailers jumped on Amazon’s bandwagon and are running big sales around Prime Day. As of this post’s publication, both Walmart and Target are not suffering site outages and probably love Amazon’s outage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed breakout&quot; readability=&quot;6.605504587156&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-width=&quot;550&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot; readability=&quot;7.045871559633&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Diane Greene is the only person celebrating Amazon Prime Day so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— megan quinn (@msquinn) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/msquinn/status/1018943659637501952?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;July 16, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Updating…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3:30pm EDT: It’s 30 minutes past the launch of Prime Day and the landing page and deal navigation page is still down.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 19:19:49 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>koolba</dc:creator>
<og:title>Prime Down: Amazon’s sale day turns into fail day</og:title>
<og:description>Update: Here’s how to get around Amazon’s error. Use smile.amazon.com. TechCrunch confirmed this workaround works. It’s not just you. Amazon Prime Day started 15 minutes ago, and so far, it’s not going well for Amazon. The landing page for Prime Day does not work. When most …</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Screen-Shot-2018-07-16-at-3.14.39-PM.png?w=617</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2018/07/16/prime-down-amazons-sale-day-turns-into-fail-day/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2018/07/16/prime-down-amazons-sale-day-turns-into-fail-day/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Jeff Bezos Becomes the Richest Man in Modern History, Topping $150B</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-07-16/happy-prime-day-jeff-amazon-ceo-s-net-worth-tops-150-billion</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-07-16/happy-prime-day-jeff-amazon-ceo-s-net-worth-tops-150-billion</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;title&gt;Terms of Service Violation&lt;/title&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;24&quot;&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;div width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collector-px8fcgygk4.perimeterx.net/api/v1/collector/noScript.gif?appId=PX8FCGYgk4&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;container&quot; readability=&quot;9.4285714285714&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/graphics/assets/img/BB-Logo-2line.svg&quot; width=&quot;310&quot;/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your usage has been flagged as a violation of our &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bloomberg.com/tos&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;terms of service&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For inquiries related to this message please &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bloomberg.com/feedback&quot;&gt;contact support&lt;/a&gt;. For sales inquiries, please visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bloomberg.com/professional/request-demo&quot;&gt;http://www.bloomberg.com/professional/request-demo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;If you believe this to be in error, please confirm below that you are not a robot by clicking &quot;I'm not a robot&quot; below.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Please make sure your browser supports JavaScript and cookies and that you are not blocking them from loading. For more information you can review the Terms of Service and Cookie Policy.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;block_uuid&quot;&gt;Block reference ID:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 17:17:54 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>champagnepapi</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/tosv.html?url=L25ld3MvYXJ0aWNsZXMvMjAxOC0wNy0xNi9oYXBweS1wcmltZS1kYXktamVmZi1hbWF6b24tY2VvLXMtbmV0LXdvcnRoLXRvcHMtMTUwLWJpbGxpb24/&amp;uuid=ab1fe470-89da-11e8-8997-fde7973124a9&amp;vid=</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Instapaper is going independent</title>
<link>http://blog.instapaper.com/post/175953870856</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://blog.instapaper.com/post/175953870856</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;post-meta&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;July 16, 2018&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot; readability=&quot;54.392344497608&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;post-title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.instapaper.com/post/175953870856&quot;&gt;Instapaper is going independent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, we’re announcing that Pinterest has entered into an agreement to transfer ownership of Instapaper to Instant Paper, Inc., a new company owned and operated by the same people who’ve been working on Instapaper since it was &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.umblr.com/redirect?z=https%3A%2F%2Ftechcrunch.com%2F2013%2F04%2F25%2Fbetaworks-instapaper%2F&amp;amp;t=NzY4Yzg4ZjlhOWRmMGVlYjgxMGE5MGNlY2QxYmJmNTUwZDdjNzI0NSxnM0FmdVo5cQ%3D%3D&amp;amp;b=t%3AOZjQZ-Pa6uMEdOyfetS5_g&amp;amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fblog.instapaper.com%2Fpost%2F175953870856&amp;amp;m=1&quot;&gt;sold to betaworks by Marco Arment&lt;/a&gt; in 2013. The ownership transfer will occur after a 21 day waiting period designed to give our users fair notice about the change of control with respect to their personal information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want to emphasize that not much is changing for the Instapaper product outside the new ownership. The product will continue to be built and maintained by the same people who’ve been working on Instapaper for the past five years. We plan to continue offering a robust service that focuses on readers and the reading experience for the foreseeable future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, we want to express our deepest gratitude to Pinterest for being such great stewards of the product over the past two years. With their support, we rebuilt search, introduced an extension for Firefox, made a variety of optimizations for the latest mobile operating systems and more. Our focus is providing a great reading application to our users, we appreciated the opportunity to do that at Pinterest, and are excited to continue our work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, comments or concerns please let us know by sending an email to &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.umblr.com/redirect?z=mailto%3Asupport%40help.instapaper.com&amp;amp;t=NTgzNTU3NDE4YmMxNWI2MmMwZjIxMjUwOGFlMDBmMzExMTc3MjdkNyxnM0FmdVo5cQ%3D%3D&amp;amp;b=t%3AOZjQZ-Pa6uMEdOyfetS5_g&amp;amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fblog.instapaper.com%2Fpost%2F175953870856&amp;amp;m=1&quot;&gt;support@help.instapaper.com&lt;/a&gt; or replying directly to this email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;– Instapaper Team&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 16:27:49 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>uptown</dc:creator>
<og:title>Instapaper is going independent</og:title>
<og:description>Instapaper is going independent Today, we’re announcing that Pinterest has entered into an agreement to transfer ownership of Instapaper to Instant Paper, Inc., a new company owned and operated by the...</og:description>
<og:type>tumblr-feed:tumblelog</og:type>
<og:image>https://staticinstapaper.s3.amazonaws.com/images/insta_logo_med.png</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://blog.instapaper.com/post/175953870856</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Twitch streamers who spend years broadcasting to no one</title>
<link>https://www.theverge.com/2018/7/16/17569520/twitch-streamers-zero-viewers-motivation-community</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theverge.com/2018/7/16/17569520/twitch-streamers-zero-viewers-motivation-community</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;p-dropcap has-dropcap p-large-text&quot; id=&quot;7lOtsG&quot;&gt;When John Hopstead first descended into the virtual world of &lt;em&gt;Dark Souls&lt;/em&gt; in 2013, his mission was to save a decaying world. Famed for its brutal and exacting gameplay, &lt;em&gt;Dark Souls&lt;/em&gt; is a popular game to live stream: if you’re going to die hundreds of times, you might as well perish with some digital company to lighten the mood. What Hopstead didn’t know then was that this would be the start of an even more difficult journey to make connections with other people. Hopstead has been streaming to largely nobody for the last five years, and he’s not alone in this pursuit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;UbBnie&quot;&gt;Twitch, the leading live streaming platform where people play games, make crafts, and showcase their day-to-day lives, attracts over two million broadcasters every month. The number grows each year, thanks in part to how easy it has become to live stream, and platforms like Facebook, Instagram and YouTube also increasingly encourage people to share and watch live stories. With the push of a button on your game console or phone, you can share whatever you’re doing at that exact moment with friends and strangers alike. The rise of popular (and profitable) influencers on platforms like YouTube and Twitch has also made the idea of being an online influencer aspirational. Some parents note that their children &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-07-28/youtube-toy-videos-why-children-love-to-watch/8749188&quot;&gt;pretend to unbox toys to a nonexistent audience&lt;/a&gt;, and teachers report that their students often say they want to pursue YouTubing as a career. But when seemingly everyone wants to record footage or live stream, who ends up watching the content?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;c-float-right c-float-hang&quot;&gt;
&lt;aside id=&quot;HmsHLs&quot;&gt;&lt;q&gt;When seemingly everyone wants to record footage or live stream, who ends up watching the content?&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;jTwQV4&quot;&gt;Starting a career on platforms like Twitch often means spending some time broadcasting to absolutely no one. Discoverability is an issue: when you log into Twitch, the most visible people are those who already have a large following. &lt;a href=&quot;http://lonelystreams.com/&quot;&gt;While there are tools to find lesser-known streamers&lt;/a&gt;, most people starting out without built-in audiences from other platforms or supportive friends and family end up staring at a big, fat zero on their viewership counter. This lonely live stream purgatory can last anywhere from a few days, weeks, months, sometimes even years, depending on your luck. According to people who have gone through it, lacking an audience is one of the most demoralizing things you can experience online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__inner&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__image&quot; data-original=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11687639/Screen_Shot_2018_07_13_at_3.13.13_PM.png&quot;&gt; &lt;img srcset=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/W_M6oie-NT7noES-E-lld5bglxQ=/0x0:1298x681/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:1298x681)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11687639/Screen_Shot_2018_07_13_at_3.13.13_PM.png 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/il9FbpIWzh8katSj3R9WQ8-Djnc=/0x0:1298x681/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:1298x681)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11687639/Screen_Shot_2018_07_13_at_3.13.13_PM.png 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MmTffBOEC2zk2VR33IHn3PznH40=/0x0:1298x681/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:1298x681)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11687639/Screen_Shot_2018_07_13_at_3.13.13_PM.png 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/f0-V0QMP9wp7VbXRS7Umirqls04=/0x0:1298x681/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:1298x681)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11687639/Screen_Shot_2018_07_13_at_3.13.13_PM.png 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gp57wG-o2tRY9I5RoCUlgx0xJ1I=/0x0:1298x681/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:1298x681)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11687639/Screen_Shot_2018_07_13_at_3.13.13_PM.png 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/F7kZfEF620xqminvrb4apB6h2pc=/0x0:1298x681/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:1298x681)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11687639/Screen_Shot_2018_07_13_at_3.13.13_PM.png 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NVoO-yeAM5ztu4aIFaiFrvA2_zM=/0x0:1298x681/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:1298x681)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11687639/Screen_Shot_2018_07_13_at_3.13.13_PM.png 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OFeJIA1eiWVEAmzStF12yiwkJzs=/0x0:1298x681/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:1298x681)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11687639/Screen_Shot_2018_07_13_at_3.13.13_PM.png 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-f1hPtjwwQBrcFCRIycCbuoMyrQ=/0x0:1298x681/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:1298x681)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11687639/Screen_Shot_2018_07_13_at_3.13.13_PM.png 1920w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JBBwSVoJIgaFnVboKj85E9Cr0IY=/0x0:1298x681/1200x0/filters:focal(0x0:1298x681)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11687639/Screen_Shot_2018_07_13_at_3.13.13_PM.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;e-image__meta&quot;&gt;A promotional image for a Twitch post about what makes people come back to the site. &lt;cite&gt;Twitch&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;neDTO9&quot;&gt;“It’s kind of exhausting playing to an empty room day in and day out with no results,” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/Twitch/comments/2r38o1/what_am_i_supposed_to_do_when_nobodys_watching/&quot;&gt;one Redditor wrote on a now-deleted thread on r/Twitch.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;jgTYmO&quot;&gt;“It’s fucking hard to stay positive when doing this 5 days a week when it feels like nobody drops by,” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/Twitch/comments/7z6s58/ive_come_to_a_realization_that_streaming_just/&quot;&gt;another Redditor wrote in a different thread,&lt;/a&gt; after spending months streaming to nobody. “I’ve come to a realization that streaming just isn’t working for me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;fY5R9m&quot;&gt;“Been streaming on and off for 4+ years and everytime I come back I go weeks where the majority of time I’m streaming to no one,” another Redditor wrote. “It’s tough.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;CZDFXF&quot;&gt;Sean Burke, a streamer who spent about a month broadcasting popular games like &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt; without an audience, says that it’s easy to take things personally when nobody turns up to your broadcast. “It was disheartening at times,” says Burke, who nonetheless kept live streaming through it all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;yp8Bcs&quot;&gt;If live streaming is a practice, the person behind the camera is the product. While there are things you can practice and improve, your popularity as a streamer comes down to whether or not people like you or find you interesting. “I [initially] kept internalizing the viewership numbers to mean that I was the problem, that I wasn’t funny enough, that I wasn’t good enough at games.” After a year of hard work, he estimates that he now gets around 10 concurrent viewers per stream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;c-float-right c-float-hang&quot;&gt;
&lt;aside id=&quot;wLoCia&quot;&gt;&lt;q&gt;Lacking an audience is one of the most demoralizing things you can experience online.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;Wn9tdH&quot;&gt;Veteran streamers often have a list of talking points on-hand to help out newbies, one I’ve seen repeated many times across social media platforms. It goes like this: be yourself. Have some fun with it. Set a schedule and stick to it. Make sure you have a good technical setup. Practice your commentary, and vocalize your thinking. Play games that aren’t oversaturated with other streamers already. Trick your live stream out with overlays and plug-ins that make the experience more fun for the viewer, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.twitch.tv/greater-engagement-with-twitch-extensions-porcupines-pixel-hunt-cf1bb5f04a56&quot;&gt;such as mini-games where fans have to keep a virtual pet alive.&lt;/a&gt; Get on social media and tell people about your stream. Network by joining other people’s streams and becoming their friends. But the toughest advice to follow is the idea that an aspiring streamer needs to be performing at all times, even if nobody is watching, just in case someone happens to show up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;KjkpiE&quot;&gt;“Think of it like you’re taping a talk show and you’re the host,” Redditor Neon_Nazgul wrote in a thread offering advice to frustrated streamers. “Sometimes there’s a studio audience, and sometimes you’re shooting something the audience will watch later.” While this is absolutely true, that’s also part of what makes streaming without a significant audience so hard in the first place. It’s a solitary practice where you have to pretend someone is listening, with no idea how long it might be before someone shows up, or if they ever will.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;p-entry-hr&quot; id=&quot;mUBeqe&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;p-dropcap has-dropcap&quot; id=&quot;4woYtC&quot;&gt;Broadcasters can follow all the conventional advice and still not gain much of a fan base, lost in a sea of other hopeful streamers. Some end up turning to schemes that give the appearance of success: you can pay for bots to populate your stream, thereby pushing you higher in the Twitch directory, or join forces with other marginal streamers to boost each other’s subscriber numbers in “follow4follow” groups. Streamers even create broadcasts where &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/Twitch/comments/8nms07/yesterday_i_stumbled_upon_twitchs_dark_underbelly/&quot;&gt;the only purpose is to let hundreds of other people beg each other for a follow in the chat&lt;/a&gt;. More often than not, this method doesn’t work out for anyone involved, as nobody is gaining a real viewer even if the numbers say otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;c-float-right c-float-hang&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__inner&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__image&quot; data-original=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11687653/IRL.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img srcset=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qGDbrnRRR5HIHRCUAEn1MBslLYY=/0x0:1200x675/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:1200x675)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11687653/IRL.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/G_Pn3Bzlu7petzwmLDFkcXC2Xd0=/0x0:1200x675/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:1200x675)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11687653/IRL.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HpVPKJGGSaRjydj6KdfrdJkXecc=/0x0:1200x675/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:1200x675)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11687653/IRL.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/iFoWLvBCJnbMPj8DfMPsJMI4Gi8=/0x0:1200x675/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:1200x675)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11687653/IRL.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/d0sfS2Zkzz3_Ol6XzeQZ5Mb_Ysg=/0x0:1200x675/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:1200x675)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11687653/IRL.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fSB0YYTuKptlLewdHXcZnGCcIXc=/0x0:1200x675/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:1200x675)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11687653/IRL.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OJadv8anZDELf7pycRdEWuRAKlw=/0x0:1200x675/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:1200x675)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11687653/IRL.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BLpdtg6tpXibxEU1dXfJ2UhLy2I=/0x0:1200x675/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:1200x675)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11687653/IRL.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_C3zhBJ4ukAYJNl3ITLZ0OEaF2s=/0x0:1200x675/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:1200x675)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11687653/IRL.jpg 1920w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/eds_9P2vmeEWeiz5ML_Rook7JSo=/0x0:1200x675/1200x0/filters:focal(0x0:1200x675)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11687653/IRL.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;e-image__meta&quot;&gt;Promotional artwork for Twitch’s “IRL” section. &lt;cite&gt;Twitch&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;UnHK5J&quot;&gt;“I tried the follow4follow technique… but no one ever took the next step and watched my channel,” Twitch user Flummoxkid says. “Nothing but a bunch of hollow follows. Even the streamers that cultivated the F4F channels that I watched pulled a 180 and tried to go legit once they made partner and they barely get any viewers. I was naive enough to believe that people would actually return the favor.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;tAXHCp&quot;&gt;Despite the sometimes psychologically taxing nature of trying to get noticed on Twitch, some continue to persevere despite the cold indictment of the zero. Their reasons are varied: some people I spoke to feel that sharing gameplay is so straightforward, that they might as well do it if they’re already playing a game. “It’s better than sitting in a dark room by myself in silence,” wrote Twitch user jostlingjoe on a Reddit discussion about how to deal with having no viewers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;axVNc4&quot;&gt;Many, though, are looking for something more. One streamer I spoke to who spent three months without an audience, MaverickRPDM, says that they kept live streaming games with zero viewers because they saw it as a form of self-improvement. “Streaming has made me more interesting, more quick witted, more outgoing and extroverted,” MaverickRPDM says. “It has helped make me feel more comfortable being myself, and by virtue of that has made me be more myself, more often, even outside of the stream.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;2OY5Tb&quot;&gt;Perhaps the biggest motivator for people who stream for extended periods of time without a viewer is the possibility of meeting like-minded people.“The reason I started streaming was that I was kind of looking for human connections,” said Richárd Szélesy, a streamer who has spent the last few years mostly broadcasting hardcore games to zero viewers. Szélesy says he grew up feeling isolated, largely spending time in front of the glow of a computer. “[I streamed to] escape loneliness and depression,” he said. While he has mostly been streaming without an audience, every so often an errant person will drop by and stick around. Even if this person never comes back — and they often don’t — the small spark is enough to keep Szélesy going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;c-float-left c-float-hang&quot;&gt;
&lt;aside id=&quot;Uz3EVr&quot;&gt;&lt;q&gt;“I was kind of looking for human connections.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;hlw2A0&quot;&gt;“Weirdly as an adult I have an easier time making romantic connections than meeting new friends,” Szélesy says. “I wouldn’t even know where to start! Do I walk up to a random person and go ‘Yo, you like &lt;em&gt;Dark Souls&lt;/em&gt;?’” Twitch also gives a way to eject himself from disagreeable people. “[It’s] way easier to just call out or remove the kind of people who seem cool, but say racist/sexist/homophobic/transphobic/etc shit.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;IM8sAy&quot;&gt;Hopstead, who has spent years streaming mostly to no one, says he is a socialist who cares about the minimum wage, and Twitch gives him an outlet to talk about his beliefs that he doesn’t have in real life. “I’m not a social person so I don’t seek out opportunities to talk about things, like on message boards, especially stuff like politics, I’m comfortable going through a day without talking or interacting with anyone,” Hopstead said. “Twitch certainly helped me attempt to break through my hermit nature, but I think I’m becoming more comfortable with just being alone for the rest of my life.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;iBiFXH&quot;&gt;While wandering through the wasteland of no viewers on Twitch can be discouraging, some who stick with it are happy that they did. Many streamers actually remember the exact moment their view counter went from zero to one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;c88GpF&quot;&gt;“The first viewer felt almost surreal,” Szélesy said. “Twitch is set up to boost those who are already established, so if someone finds you, they were looking and thought you might be the kind of person they wanted to watch. Even though these views or interactions don’t always lead to even follows, let alone deeper connections, it’s always kinda cool, cause hey they found me in my hidden little spot here and decided to hang out.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__inner&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__image&quot; data-original=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11687721/Screen_Shot_2018_07_13_at_3.35.22_PM.png&quot;&gt; &lt;img srcset=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-e0ZdiWHDYZ6mBe7oXDJ3WdCvgQ=/0x0:1384x520/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:1384x520)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11687721/Screen_Shot_2018_07_13_at_3.35.22_PM.png 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LotP8XCmX9kw5vIDg7UEQEUV4os=/0x0:1384x520/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:1384x520)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11687721/Screen_Shot_2018_07_13_at_3.35.22_PM.png 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IRLgBpNgghweohLv1MjxrOJ0qh4=/0x0:1384x520/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:1384x520)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11687721/Screen_Shot_2018_07_13_at_3.35.22_PM.png 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/luzjTe9fOLEu6KM2Dw4iCsUbnpM=/0x0:1384x520/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:1384x520)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11687721/Screen_Shot_2018_07_13_at_3.35.22_PM.png 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/PvlCZd1-l7zMzqlwqxAj721z_Ak=/0x0:1384x520/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:1384x520)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11687721/Screen_Shot_2018_07_13_at_3.35.22_PM.png 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dxZgYFbTXB53L9_aGl-lUWfoF0U=/0x0:1384x520/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:1384x520)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11687721/Screen_Shot_2018_07_13_at_3.35.22_PM.png 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Xc6u6YORpW_tTvUBfPS9dmNjweA=/0x0:1384x520/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:1384x520)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11687721/Screen_Shot_2018_07_13_at_3.35.22_PM.png 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZmO8DRXmjju_fbW8I5ejcxJWr8s=/0x0:1384x520/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:1384x520)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11687721/Screen_Shot_2018_07_13_at_3.35.22_PM.png 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AI7PDpnhz0C73hxbHVvBKPv6DUI=/0x0:1384x520/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:1384x520)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11687721/Screen_Shot_2018_07_13_at_3.35.22_PM.png 1920w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KR4E0DbQ9ERpLMGahiqmI2H4rdc=/0x0:1384x520/1200x0/filters:focal(0x0:1384x520)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11687721/Screen_Shot_2018_07_13_at_3.35.22_PM.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;e-image__meta&quot;&gt;A promotional image for Twitch’s celebration of Pride month. &lt;cite&gt;Twitch&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-dropcap has-dropcap&quot; id=&quot;Y3y0r9&quot;&gt;After months of having no audience, finally getting someone to watch you can be nerve-wracking as well as exciting. You prepare for it, sometimes for dozens of hours&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; and now it’s showtime. Someone is on the other end. They’re here for you. What do you do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;ny85Jd&quot;&gt;“I remember my first viewer and when it happened,” said Reddit user &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/user/TheWhiteLatino69&quot;&gt;TheWhiteLatino69&lt;/a&gt;, a streamer who initially started streaming on Twitch to get through a tough time. At first, TheWhiteLatino broadcasted without an audience to help create the illusion he was hanging out with people. “I was streaming &lt;em&gt;Subnautica&lt;/em&gt; for 0 viewers of course and I glanced over at the chat to see a ‘hey.’ When I saw that it all the sudden hit me, I wasn’t by myself anymore, I had some eyes watching me. I became increasingly nervous as the stream went on and I nervously chatted with them. It’s one thing to pretend you’re talking to someone and another to actually be talking to a human being … [It] did quite the number on me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;Q8xLRP&quot;&gt;Based on conversations I’ve had with dozens of streamers, taking that initial plunge when you’re not sure anyone is going to watch can feel like throwing a message in a bottle into the sea. Maybe someone will find it. Maybe the bottle ends up lost in the abyss. We all gamble in our own ways when we reach out online, whether we’re swiping right on Tinder or using a hashtag to look for people with similar interests. Maybe we end up feeling more alienated than ever before, or maybe we find people who make everything worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;SYQafg&quot;&gt;Lolimdivine, a Redditor who estimates they spent around eight months streaming to no one, says they love the community they’ve built after getting over that initial hump.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__inner&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__image&quot; data-original=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11687751/Screen_Shot_2018_07_13_at_3.40.17_PM.png&quot;&gt; &lt;img srcset=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/im-V3E_dSLpSvCIkj-6oQ1WnrXw=/0x0:1167x665/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:1167x665)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11687751/Screen_Shot_2018_07_13_at_3.40.17_PM.png 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yvYHsd5p5kWU9pKPcmhiYN6y1o8=/0x0:1167x665/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:1167x665)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11687751/Screen_Shot_2018_07_13_at_3.40.17_PM.png 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-hxCqY2AFg5l8OjjCHHdrCUizRM=/0x0:1167x665/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:1167x665)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11687751/Screen_Shot_2018_07_13_at_3.40.17_PM.png 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TVYCMTO3r8EAFfPQTHpToej3wf8=/0x0:1167x665/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:1167x665)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11687751/Screen_Shot_2018_07_13_at_3.40.17_PM.png 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Lq8-C6eQ3vkMI9OkvNqeME80dZc=/0x0:1167x665/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:1167x665)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11687751/Screen_Shot_2018_07_13_at_3.40.17_PM.png 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lK3u2kfpZo8JpH-ONsUEtTU9SgM=/0x0:1167x665/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:1167x665)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11687751/Screen_Shot_2018_07_13_at_3.40.17_PM.png 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5tRgKYMqMW5u9ntkvHaoYo9GgDM=/0x0:1167x665/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:1167x665)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11687751/Screen_Shot_2018_07_13_at_3.40.17_PM.png 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RkbzVbHyGWdhcm9mlr9Tbbxse2Q=/0x0:1167x665/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:1167x665)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11687751/Screen_Shot_2018_07_13_at_3.40.17_PM.png 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/64qm7UQY78Coe3lHBcdGJhEMWgU=/0x0:1167x665/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:1167x665)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11687751/Screen_Shot_2018_07_13_at_3.40.17_PM.png 1920w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/L0cYr5O4u-z7NXiitHQwPvyIttY=/0x0:1167x665/1200x0/filters:focal(0x0:1167x665)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11687751/Screen_Shot_2018_07_13_at_3.40.17_PM.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;e-image__meta&quot;&gt;A scene from Twitch’s 2016 “year in review.” &lt;cite&gt;Twitch&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;UD4ovX&quot;&gt;“My regulars and I always talk about our lives, and we all know stuff about each other,” lolimdivine said. “It’s like we have our own little internet family honestly. I see these people as my friends and not viewers. We welcome people with open arms from all around the world, and we remember things about the people who can only stop by once a month. It’s really an incredible thing that Twitch can do for people’s loneliness or friend groups.” Many streamers I spoke to said that they initially became interested in Twitch after finding a personality that entertained them through a tough time, such as the loss of a loved one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;18Ry9v&quot;&gt;Khryn_Tzu, a Twitch streamer who spent weeks with no viewers, is coming up on their one year anniversary on Twitch. It’s an important date, because without Twitch, Khryn_Tzu wouldn’t have met a particular viewer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;6Mgc0S&quot;&gt;“Lots of days with 0 viewers, just did my thing, learned what works, still am,” Khryn_Tzu said. “Then it happened. There was one viewer. And they stayed. They didn’t say anything for a few streams, but they kept coming back. Then one night I had to go AFK so I put on some Metallica. Out pops a ‘Good choice in music. I like Metallica.’ It was such an exhilarating feeling to have someone completely unknown to me to stick around for MY content. It had been a hard push.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;wsZ30P&quot;&gt;While many dream of having an audience in the thousands, that one person ended up making all the difference in Khryn_Tzu’s life. “We started talking, started chatting, and she made sure to start welcoming people and talking to them too when people would show up,” says Khryn_Tzu. “Soon people started staying… And it became so much more than that too. These viewers that come in? They become your friends. Sometimes more. That first viewer? We are dating now and I couldn’t be happier.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;Q3AyyI&quot;&gt;Most people don’t end up finding a love interest on Twitch, but for plenty of others, that’s not the point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-end-para&quot; id=&quot;XM9HKc&quot;&gt;“Games can be beautiful, clever, goofy and funny and I like to be vocal with my appreciation for them,” Szélesy said. “Even if no one is listening.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 14:39:58 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ss2003</dc:creator>
<og:description>Looking for connections in 2018</og:description>
<og:image>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NgyqY3_OZn7dG4BuN04b0sQHPnc=/0x215:3000x1786/fit-in/1200x630/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11687651/acastro_180713_2730_0001.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>The Twitch streamers who spend years broadcasting to no one</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.theverge.com/2018/7/16/17569520/twitch-streamers-zero-viewers-motivation-community</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theverge.com/2018/7/16/17569520/twitch-streamers-zero-viewers-motivation-community</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>