<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Google Engineers Refused to Build Security Tool to Win Military Contracts</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-06-21/google-engineers-refused-to-build-security-tool-to-win-military-contracts</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-06-21/google-engineers-refused-to-build-security-tool-to-win-military-contracts</guid>
<description>&lt;aside class=&quot;left-column&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;share-article-button&quot; data-variation=&quot;basic-article&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SHARE THIS ARTICLE&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, a group of influential software engineers in Google’s cloud division surprised their superiors by refusing to work on a cutting-edge security feature. Known as “air gap,” the technology would have helped Google win sensitive military contracts. The coders weren’t persuaded their employer should be using its technological might to help the government wage war, according to four current and former employees. After hearing the engineers’ objections, Urs Hölzle, Google’s top technical executive, said the air gap feature would be postponed, one of the people said. Another person familiar with the situation said the group was able to reduce the scope of the feature.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The act of rebellion ricocheted around the company, fueling a growing resistance among employees with a dim view of Google’s yen for multi-million-dollar government contracts. The engineers became known as the “Group of Nine” and were lionized by like-minded staff. The current and former employees say the engineers’ work boycott was a catalyst for larger protests that convulsed the company’s Mountain View, California, campus and ultimately forced executives to let a lucrative Pentagon contract called Project Maven expire without renewal. They declined to name the engineers and requested anonymity to discuss a private matter.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Internal disputes are common at Alphabet  Inc.’s Google, which gives employees ample space to air grievances. But dissent is on the rise (as it is at other tech companies). Last month, in a highly unusual move, a Google employee proposed that executive compensation be tied to efforts to make the company more diverse and inclusive. That proposal was easily voted down by shareholders, but the engineers’ boycott could actually hamper Google’s ability to compete. Big federal contracts often require certification to handle sensitive data—authorizations that rivals Amazon.com Inc. and Microsoft Corp. have, but Google doesn't. Without certain measures including air gap technology, Google may struggle to win portions of the Joint Enterprise Defense Infrastructure, or JEDI, a Pentagon deal worth upwards of $10 billion.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It's unclear if Google has abandoned air gap technology or is still planning to build it over employees’ objections. The feature is not technically very difficult, so Google could easily find other engineers to do the work. While over 4,000 people at the company signed a petition against Project Maven, that’s roughly 5 percent of total full-time staff. A company spokesperson declined to comment. &lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Google cloud chief Diane Greene has expressed continued interest in working with government. Federal agencies are among the largest spenders on corporate computing and starting to gravitate toward cloud services. In March, Greene and her deputies &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blog.google/topics/google-cloud/extending-gcp-security-us-government-customers-through-fedramp-authorization/&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;proudly touted&lt;/a&gt; Google's new approvals under FedRAMP, federal compliance standards for information technology. Google was approved FedRAMP “Moderate,” a designation required for almost 80 percent of government cloud contracts. Google cloud staff said internally that the Project Maven deal was “fast-tracking” higher FedRAMP authorization, according to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://gizmodo.com/google-plans-not-to-renew-its-contract-for-project-mave-1826488620&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Gizmodo report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, Google falls short of rivals. Both Microsoft's Azure and Amazon Web Services (AWS) have “High” certificates that authorize them to hold sensitive or classified data and sell to bodies like the Central Intelligence Agency. To do so, both companies had to set up a separate service called a government cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A critical component of that service is the air gap. Put simply, it physically separates computers from others on a network. So rather than store data from multiple companies on a single server or system, as the commercial cloud providers typically do, a company or agency can place its data and computing processes in isolation on a single piece of hardware. That separation is particularly desirable for agencies in national security, says Michael Carter, vice president of Coalfire, a cybersecurity firm. “Amazon and Azure can literally say, ‘This is your rack,’” he says. “In the government, they want to know where their data is. So if you want to wipe it, go wipe it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In sales pitches, Google touts the security features of its cloud service. In a March press briefing, company executives noted how their artificial intelligence software could spot cybersecurity attacks early. “We think that Google cloud is today the most secure cloud out there,” Hölzle said during the briefing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The entities most likely to require air-gap security systems are government agencies or financial firms. While experts debate the technology’s merits, it does give customers “psychological” comfort, according to Jim Reavis, who runs Cloud Security Alliance, an industry group. “They’re used to having their own computer that they look at, their own blinking light,” he says. “I do question whether or not that’s useful security.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greene and other Google executives will have to persuade employees it’s possible to bid for government contracts without violating Google’s new ethical standards. After pledging not to renew the Project Maven contract, which involves using artificial intelligence to analyze drone footage, the company &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-06-07/google-renounces-ai-for-weapons-but-will-still-sell-to-military&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;issued&lt;/a&gt; a set of AI principles this month that prohibit weapons work. But they don’t rule out selling to the military, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-06-04/google-staff-ai-revolt-puts-pentagon-cloud-deals-in-jeopardy&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Google continues to pursue&lt;/a&gt; other Defense Department cloud contracts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We are still doing everything we can within these guidelines to support our government, the military and our veterans,” Greene wrote in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blog.google/topics/google-cloud/incorporating-googles-ai-principles-google-cloud/&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; on June 7. “For example, we will continue to work with government organizations on cybersecurity, productivity tools, healthcare, and other forms of cloud initiatives.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several Googlers protesting Project Maven have complained about poor communication from senior leaders. Most staff outside the cloud unit were unaware of the contract until February—five months after it was signed—when questions about the deal began circulating more widely on internal message boards. At one point, Greene told staff the deal was worth a meager $9 million. Subsequent reports revealed Google expected the contract to rake in $15 million and grow to as much as $250 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google has yet to address these reports publicly. But on June 8, a day after the company issued its ethical charter, Greene addressed the discrepancy in an internal note. “In speaking about Maven, I did not always have accurate information,” she wrote in an email viewed by Bloomberg News. “For example, I said the contract was $9 [million] when it actually was a different number.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google employees have a history of objecting on ethical grounds. After the Edward Snowden revelations in 2013, several engineers confronted Hölzle about allegations the company had assisted the government in its surveillance program. They threatened to resign, telling Hölzle, “this isn't why we signed up for the company,” according to a former senior executive who attended the meeting. Hölzle voiced his support for the engineers, this person says.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The latest confrontation at Google coincides with growing concern about the entire industry’s relationship with the U.S. government. Civil rights groups have targeted Amazon for selling facial recognition tech to police departments. Microsoft faced similar heat for its work with the U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some Google employees resigned over the Project Maven deal. Tyler Breisacher, a software developer on Google infrastructure who left in April, cited the lack of clear communications about the contract and how Google's software was being used. Management, he says, appeared surprised at the response from employees once they shared more about the program. “It seems like they weren't expecting it to be as controversial as it was,” he says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Breisacher, who joined Google in 2011, says the company has changed. Earlier, if employees felt a decision was bad for Google, its users or the broader world, they had their leaders’ ears. “It felt like you were really listened to,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;inline-newsletter&quot; data-state=&quot;ready&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Greene wrote in the internal email that she wanted to address the “trust issue that has developed” in the past five months. She said she regretted not emailing earlier to correct her misstatement about the size of the Project Maven deal. “In the past, I would have,” Greene wrote, “but in the current climate of leaks, the sense was that it would be a mistake to do because the correction would leak and start another ‘press cycle’ that would not be good for any of us.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;— With assistance by Alistair Barr, and Naomi Nix&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;span itemprop=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Updates with cloud CEO comment in 11th paragraph.&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 04:18:27 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dsr12</dc:creator>
<og:description>A work boycott from the Group of Nine is yet another hurdle to the company’s efforts to compete for sensitive government work.</og:description>
<og:image>https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/i674AyUcypO0/v0/1200x900.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Google Engineers Refused to Build Security Tool to Win Military Contracts</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-06-21/google-engineers-refused-to-build-security-tool-to-win-military-contracts</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-06-21/google-engineers-refused-to-build-security-tool-to-win-military-contracts</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Twitter ‘smytes’ customers</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2018/06/21/twitter-smytes-customers/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2018/06/21/twitter-smytes-customers/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Twitter today &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/06/21/twitter-acquires-anti-abuse-technology-provider-smyte/&quot;&gt;announced it was acquiring&lt;/a&gt; the “trust and safety as a service” startup &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.smyte.com/solutions&quot;&gt;Smyte&lt;/a&gt; to help it better address issues related to online abuse, harassment, spam, and security on its platform. But it also decided to immediately shut down access to Smyte’s API without warning, leaving Smyte’s existing customers no time to transition to a new service provider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The change left Smyte’s current customer base stranded, with production issues related to the safety of their own platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, many were not happy about this situation and took to Twitter to register their complaints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Smyte’s website, its clients included Indiegogo, GoFundMe, npm, Musical.ly, TaskRabbit, Meetup, OLX, ThredUp, YouNow, 99 Designs, Carousell, and Zendesk – big name brands that used Smyte’s feature set in a variety of ways to combat fraud, abuse, harassment, scams, spam, and other security issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Twitter had earlier told TechCrunch that it would be “winding down” Smyte’s business with existing clients, what that apparently meant was that it was going to announce the acquisition, then effectively shut off the lights over at Smyte and leave everyone in the lurch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to reports from those affected, Smyte disabled access to its API with very little warning to clients, and without giving them time to prepare. Customers got a phone call, and then – boom – the service was gone. Clients had multi-year contracts in some cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And again, to reiterate, Smyte is a provider of anti-abuse and anti-fraud protections – not something any business would shut off overnight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In npm’s case, it even led to a production outage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twitter declined to comment, but we understand it was making phone calls to affected Smyte customers today to match them with new service providers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The decision to &lt;del&gt;smite&lt;/del&gt; &lt;em&gt;smyte&lt;/em&gt; an existing customer base the minute the startup joined Twitter isn’t a good look for either company, and is especially ironic in light of Twitter’s promises of “trust and safety” improvements in the months to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trust, huh?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s how it works?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed breakout&quot; readability=&quot;9.1028938906752&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-width=&quot;550&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot; readability=&quot;11.498392282958&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Holy shit Twitter bought Smyte and immediately shut it down. We had a 3 years contract with them and they just disappeared overnight. No communication at all, they just turned their servers off, closed our shared support channel and walked away. What the actual fuck&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Giacomo Gatelli (@arthens) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/arthens/status/1009925187364458496?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 21, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed breakout&quot; readability=&quot;7.3254545454545&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-width=&quot;550&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot; readability=&quot;8.6181818181818&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Wait…so did &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/HelloSmyte?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@HelloSmyte&lt;/a&gt; just shut down it's service entirely today with no warning after &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Twitter?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@Twitter&lt;/a&gt; bought them? What about their customers that rely on them for advanced moderation and the safety of their platforms? &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/smyte?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#smyte&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Michael Ehinger (@MichaelEhinger) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MichaelEhinger/status/1009839657222361088?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 21, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed breakout&quot; readability=&quot;8.5821428571429&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-width=&quot;550&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot; readability=&quot;10.489285714286&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;A vendor notified us of their acquisition at 6am this morning and shut down their APIs 30 minutes later, creating a production outage for npm (package publishes and user registrations). The sheer unprofessionalism of this is blowing my mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Laurie Voss (@seldo) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/seldo/status/1009873821141118976?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 21, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed breakout&quot; readability=&quot;8.0830188679245&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-width=&quot;550&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot; readability=&quot;9.5094339622642&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;It takes weeks to negotiate and sign an acquisition. You didn't find out at 6am. You couldn't give us a week? Even a couple of hours to take your service out of our critical path and avoid an outage? Fucking shocking behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Laurie Voss (@seldo) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/seldo/status/1009874222154305537?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 21, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed breakout&quot; readability=&quot;7.4583333333333&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-width=&quot;550&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot; readability=&quot;8.390625&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Damage is done already anyway. We had the same experience; luckily we were only using them in an async capacity so it didn't take us offline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Jeff Goldschrafe (@jgoldschrafe) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jgoldschrafe/status/1009947081987878912?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 21, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;embed breakout&quot; readability=&quot;7.5377358490566&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-width=&quot;550&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot; readability=&quot;8.8679245283019&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Hey &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/HelloSmyte?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@HelloSmyte&lt;/a&gt; , it's a massive bummer that you couldn't give your customers any notice before turning everything off. Is there anything you can do to help us out?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Dennis Hotson (@dennishotson) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dennishotson/status/1009798866743394305?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 21, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed breakout&quot; readability=&quot;6.7723880597015&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-width=&quot;550&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot; readability=&quot;7.2238805970149&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Thanks for just shutting off service at 615am this morning with 7 minutes notice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Curtis Schofield (@curtisjennings) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/curtisjennings/status/1009846671746916352?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 21, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed breakout&quot; readability=&quot;9.0740740740741&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-width=&quot;550&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot; readability=&quot;11.796296296296&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;This was the worst experience, especially with an acquisition, that we've ever encountered with a partner. We were given less than a half an hour notice before the entire system was shut down, leading to immediate payflow &amp;amp; platform issues with a hefty cost &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/nokok?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#nokok&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/Smyte?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#Smyte&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/fail?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#fail&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Kerry Barker (@kerryjunebug) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kerryjunebug/status/1010015074310688768?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 22, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 03:28:51 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>panarky</dc:creator>
<og:title>Twitter ‘smytes’ customers</og:title>
<og:description>Twitter today announced it was acquiring the “trust and safety as a service” startup Smyte to help it better address issues related to online abuse, harassment, spam, and security on its platform. But it also decided to immediately shut down access to Smyte’s API without warning, …</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/gettyimages-668798001.jpg?w=602</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2018/06/21/twitter-smytes-customers/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2018/06/21/twitter-smytes-customers/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>YouTube (Un)Blocks Blender Videos</title>
<link>https://www.blender.org/media-exposure/youtube-blocks-blender-videos-worldwide/?updated</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.blender.org/media-exposure/youtube-blocks-blender-videos-worldwide/?updated</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday June 21 2018, by Ton Roosendaal&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last night all videos came back (except the one from Andrew Price, which still is blocked in USA).&lt;br/&gt;According to another person in Youtube we now *do* have to sign the other agreement as well. &lt;a href=&quot;http://download.blender.org/institute/Contract%20between%20Google%20and%20Blender%20Foundation.pdf&quot;&gt;You can read it here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure if we should accept this. Will be studied on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday 17h, June 20 2018, by Ton Roosendaal&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None of our videos play still.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday 10.30h, June 20 2018, by Ton Roosendaal&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last night the Youtube Support team contacted Francesco Siddi by phone. As we understand it now it’s a mix of coincidences, bad UIs, wrong error messages, ignorant support desks and our non-standard decision to not monetize a popular Youtube channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The coincidence is that Youtube is rolling out their subscription system in Europe (and Netherlands). This subscription system will allow users to stream music and enjoy Youtube ad-free. They updated terms and conditions for it and need to get monetized channel owners to approve that. Coincidentally our channel was set to allow monetization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.blender.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-20-at-10.34.06-289x512.png?x10773&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignright size-medium wp-image-59931&quot; width=&quot;289&quot; height=&quot;512&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.blender.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-20-at-10.34.06-289x512.png 289w, https://www.blender.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-20-at-10.34.06.png 582w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 289px) 100vw, 289px&quot;/&gt;The bad UI was that the ‘please accept the new terms’ button was only visible if you go the new Youtube “Content Manager” account, which I was not aware of and which is not active when you login to Youtube using the Foundation account to manage videos. The channel was also set to monatization mode which has no option to reset it. To make us even more confused, yesterday the system generated the wrong agreement to be signed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Image: after logging in to the Foundation account, the menu “Switch Accounts” – shows the option to login as “Content Manager”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of not accepting the new terms, the wrong error message was to put all videos on “Not available in your country” mode, which usually signals that there is a copyright issue. Similar happened for Andrew Price’s video last year, which (according to our new contact) was because of a trademark dispute but that was never made explicit to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All support desk people we contacted (since December last year) couldn’t find out what was wrong. They didn’t know that not accepting ‘terms and conditions’ could be causing this. Until yesterday they thought there was a technical error.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After reviewing the new terms and conditions (which basically is to accept the subscription system, I decided to accept that. According to the new Youtube contact our channel then would be back in a few hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just while writing this, the video thumbnails appeared to be back! They don’t play yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday (afternoon) 19 June 2018, by Ton Roosendaal&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are doing a PeerTube test on &lt;a href=&quot;https://video.blender.org/&quot;&gt;video.blender.org&lt;/a&gt;. It is running on one of our own servers, in a European datacenter. Just click around and have some fun. We’re curious to see how it holds!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://video.blender.org&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.blender.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-19-at-16.09.12-1280x591.png?x10773&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-large wp-image-59928 aligncenter&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height=&quot;591&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.blender.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-19-at-16.09.12-1280x591.png 1280w, https://www.blender.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-19-at-16.09.12-512x236.png 512w, https://www.blender.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-19-at-16.09.12-768x355.png 768w, https://www.blender.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-19-at-16.09.12.png 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1280px) 100vw, 1280px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday 19 June 2018, by Ton Roosendaal&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last night we received a contract from Google. &lt;a href=&quot;http://download.blender.org/institute/Contract%20between%20Google%20and%20Blender%20Foundation.pdf&quot;&gt;You can read it here&lt;/a&gt;. It’s six pages of legal talk, but the gist of the agreement appears to be about Blender Foundation accepting to monetize content on its Youtube channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, BF already has an ad-free Youtube account since 2008. We have monetizing disabled, but it looks like Google is going to change this policy. For example, we now see a new section on our channel settings page: “Monetization enabled”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blender.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-19-at-12.25.40.png?x10773&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.blender.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-19-at-12.25.40-512x436.png?x10773&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-59917 aligncenter&quot; width=&quot;512&quot; height=&quot;436&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.blender.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-19-at-12.25.40-512x436.png 512w, https://www.blender.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-19-at-12.25.40-768x654.png 768w, https://www.blender.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-19-at-12.25.40.png 892w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 512px) 100vw, 512px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;However, the actual advertisement option is disabled in the advanced settings:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blender.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-19-at-12.23.43.png?x10773&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.blender.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-19-at-12.23.43-512x98.png?x10773&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-59918 aligncenter&quot; width=&quot;512&quot; height=&quot;98&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.blender.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-19-at-12.23.43-512x98.png 512w, https://www.blender.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-19-at-12.23.43-768x147.png 768w, https://www.blender.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-19-at-12.23.43.png 1012w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 512px) 100vw, 512px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now there’s another issue. Last year we were notified by US Youtube visitors that a very popular Blender Conference talk wasn’t visible for them – the talk Andrew Price gave in 2016; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vM39qhXle4g&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&amp;amp;t=0s&quot;&gt;The 7 Habits of Highly Effective Artists&lt;/a&gt;. It had over a million views already.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With our channel reaching &amp;gt; 100k subscribers, we have special priority support. So we contacted them to ask what was wrong. After a couple of mails back and forth, the reply was as follows (22 dec 2017):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;14.183006535948&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Thanks for your continued support and patience.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I’ve received an update from our experts stating that you need to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/94522?hl=en&quot;&gt;enable ads for your video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. Once you enable, your video will be available in the USA.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;If there’s anything else you’d need help with, please feel free to write back to us anytime as we are available 24/7 to take care of every partner’s concerns.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Appreciate your understanding and thanks for being our valuable partner. Have an amazing day!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which was quite a surprising statement for us. My reply therefore was (22 dec 2017):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m chairman of the Blender Foundation. We choose to use a 100% ad-free channel for our work, this to emphasis our public benefit and non-profit goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to your answer we are being forced to enable advertising now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to know where this new Youtube policy has been published and made official.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then had every other month a reply like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Please allow me some time to work with specialists on your issue. I’ll investigate further and will reach back to you with an update at the earliest possible.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Appreciate your patience and understanding in the interim.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just last week, June 12, I mailed them again to ask for the status of this issue. The reply was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I completely understand your predicament. Apologies for the unusual delay in hearing back from the Policy team. I’ve escalated this issue for further investigation and assistance. Kindly bear with us while we get this fixed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Appreciate your understanding in this regard.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then on June 15th the entire channel went black.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To us it is still unclear what is going on. It could be related to Youtube’s new “subscription” system. It can also be just a human error or a bug; our refusal to monetize videos on a massively popular channel isn’t common.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However – it remains a fair and relevant question to Google: do you allow adfree channels without monetization? Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monday 18 June 2018, by Francesco Siddi&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since a few days all Blender videos on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/BlenderFoundation/featured)&quot;&gt;OFFICIAL BLENDER CHANNEL&lt;/a&gt; have been blocked worldwide without explanation. We are working with YouTube to resolve the issue, but the support has been less than stellar. In the meantime you can find most of the videos on &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.blender.org&quot;&gt;cloud.blender.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/J6ecEv7lOzg&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 23:15:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ycnews</dc:creator>
<og:title> YouTube Blocks Blender Videos Worldwide — blender.org</og:title>
<og:description>Home of the Blender project - Free and Open 3D Creation Software</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.blender.org/media-exposure/youtube-blocks-blender-videos-worldwide/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.blender.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-19-at-13.36.05-500x200.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.blender.org/media-exposure/youtube-blocks-blender-videos-worldwide/?updated</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Announcing Rust 1.27</title>
<link>https://blog.rust-lang.org/2018/06/21/Rust-1.27.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.rust-lang.org/2018/06/21/Rust-1.27.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The Rust team is happy to announce a new version of Rust, 1.27.0. Rust is a systems programming language focused on safety, speed, and concurrency.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you have a previous version of Rust installed via rustup, getting Rust 1.27.0 is as easy as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-bash highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;rustup update stable
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don’t have it already, you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rust-lang.org/install.html&quot;&gt;get &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;rustup&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; from the appropriate page on our website, and check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/blob/master/RELEASES.md#version-1270-2018-06-21&quot;&gt;detailed release notes for 1.27.0&lt;/a&gt; on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, we would like to draw attention to something: just before the release of 1.27.0, we found &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/51686&quot;&gt;a bug&lt;/a&gt; in the ‘default match bindings’ feature introduced in 1.26.0 that can possibly introduce unsoundness. Since it was discovered very late in the release process, and has been present since 1.26.0, we decided to stick to our release train model. We expect to put out a 1.27.1 with that fix applied soon, and if there’s demand, possibly a 1.26.3 as well. More information about the specifics here will come in that release announcement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-in-1270-stable&quot;&gt;What’s in 1.27.0 stable&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This release has two big language features that people have been waiting for. But first, a small comment on documentation: All books in &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.rust-lang.org/&quot;&gt;the Rust Bookshelf&lt;/a&gt; are &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/49623/&quot;&gt;now searchable&lt;/a&gt;! For example, here’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.rust-lang.org/book/second-edition/?search=borrow&quot;&gt;a search of “The Rust Programming Language” for ‘borrow’&lt;/a&gt;. This will hopefully make it much easier to find what you’re looking for. Additionally, there’s one new book: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/49707/&quot;&gt;the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;rustc&lt;/code&gt; Book&lt;/a&gt;. This book explains how to use &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;rustc&lt;/code&gt; directly, as well as some other useful information, like a list of all lints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;simd&quot;&gt;SIMD&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, now for the big news: the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/49664/&quot;&gt;basics of SIMD&lt;/a&gt; are now available! SIMD stands for “single instruction, multiple data.” Consider a function like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-rust highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;8.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;pub&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;fn&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;foo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;u8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;],&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;b&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;u8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;],&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;c&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;mut&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;u8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;])&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;((&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;b&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;c&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;.iter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;.zip&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;b&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;.zip&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;c&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;c&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;b&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, we’re taking two slices, and adding the numbers together, placing the result in a third slice. The simplest possible way to do this would be to do exactly what the code does, and loop through each set of elements, add them together, and store it in the result. However, compilers can often do better. LLVM will often “autovectorize” code like this, which is a fancy term for “use SIMD.” Imagine that &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;a&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;b&lt;/code&gt; were both 16 elements long. Each element is a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;u8&lt;/code&gt;, and so that means that each slice would be 128 bits of data. Using SIMD, we could put &lt;em&gt;both&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;a&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;b&lt;/code&gt; into 128 bit registers, add them together in a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;*single*&lt;/code&gt; instruction, and then copy the resulting 128 bits into &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;c&lt;/code&gt;. That’d be much faster!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While stable Rust has always been able to take advantage of autovectorization, sometimes, the compiler just isn’t smart enough to realize that we can do something like this. Additionally, not every CPU has these features, and so LLVM may not use them so your program can be used on a wide variety of hardware. So, in Rust 1.27, the addtion of &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.rust-lang.org/stable/std/arch/&quot;&gt;the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;std::arch&lt;/code&gt; module&lt;/a&gt; allows us to use these kinds of instructions &lt;em&gt;directly&lt;/em&gt;, which means we don’t need to rely on a smart compiler. Additionally, it includes some features that allow us to choose a particular implementation based on various criteria. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-rust highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;cfg&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;all&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;any&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;target_arch&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;x86&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;target_arch&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;x86_64&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;target_feature&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;avx2&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;))]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;fn&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;foo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nd&quot;&gt;#[cfg(target_arch&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nd&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;x86&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nd&quot;&gt;)]&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;use&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;std&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;arch&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;x86&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;_mm256_add_epi64&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nd&quot;&gt;#[cfg(target_arch&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nd&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;x86_64&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nd&quot;&gt;)]&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;use&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;std&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;arch&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;x86_64&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;_mm256_add_epi64&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;unsafe&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;_mm256_add_epi64&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, we use &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;cfg&lt;/code&gt; flags to choose the correct version based on the machine we’re targetting; on &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;x86&lt;/code&gt; we use that version, and on &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;x86_64&lt;/code&gt; we use its version. We can also choose at runtime:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-rust highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;fn&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;foo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nd&quot;&gt;#[cfg(any(target_arch&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nd&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;x86&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nd&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nd&quot;&gt;target_arch&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nd&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;x86_64&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nd&quot;&gt;))]&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nd&quot;&gt;is_x86_feature_detected!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;avx2&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;unsafe&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;foo_avx2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;};&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;foo_fallback&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, we have two versions of the function: one which uses &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;AVX2&lt;/code&gt;, a specific kind of SIMD feature that lets you do 256-bit operations. The &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;is_x86_feature_detected!&lt;/code&gt; macro will generate code that detects if your CPU supports AVX2, and if so, calls the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;foo_avx2&lt;/code&gt; function. If not, then we fall back to a non-AVX implementation, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;foo_fallback&lt;/code&gt;. This means that our code will run super fast on CPUs that support AVX2, but still work on ones that don’t, albeit slower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If all of this seems a bit low-level and fiddly, well, it is! &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;std::arch&lt;/code&gt; is specifically &lt;em&gt;primitives&lt;/em&gt; for building these kinds of things. We hope to eventually stabilize a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;std::simd&lt;/code&gt; module with higher-level stuff in the future. But landing the basics now lets the ecosystem experiment with higher level libraries starting today. For example, check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AdamNiederer/faster&quot;&gt;faster&lt;/a&gt; crate. Here’s a code snippet with no SIMD:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-rust highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;lots_of_3s&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mf&quot;&gt;123.456f32&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;128&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;][&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;..&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;])&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;.iter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;.map&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;v&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;mf&quot;&gt;9.0&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;v&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;.abs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;.sqrt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;.sqrt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;.recip&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;.ceil&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;.sqrt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mf&quot;&gt;4.0&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mf&quot;&gt;2.0&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;})&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;py&quot;&gt;.collect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;Vec&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;f32&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To use SIMD with this code via &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;faster&lt;/code&gt;, you’d change it to this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-rust highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;lots_of_3s&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mf&quot;&gt;123.456f32&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;128&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;][&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;..&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;])&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;.simd_iter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;.simd_map&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;f32s&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mf&quot;&gt;0.0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;v&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;f32s&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mf&quot;&gt;9.0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;v&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;.abs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;.sqrt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;.rsqrt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;.ceil&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;.sqrt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;f32s&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mf&quot;&gt;4.0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;f32s&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mf&quot;&gt;2.0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;})&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;.scalar_collect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It looks almost the same: &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;simd_iter&lt;/code&gt; instead of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;iter&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;simd_map&lt;/code&gt; instead of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;map&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;f32s(2.0)&lt;/code&gt; instead of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;2.0&lt;/code&gt;. But you get a SIMD-ified version generated for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt;, you may never write any of this yourself, but as always, the libraries you depend on may. For example, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/regex/pull/456&quot;&gt;regex crate has already added support&lt;/a&gt;, and a new release will contain these SIMD speedups without you needing to do anything at all!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;dyn-trait&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;dyn Trait&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rust’s trait object syntax is one that we ultimately regret. If you’ll recall, given a trait &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Foo&lt;/code&gt;, this is a trait object:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Foo&lt;/code&gt; were a struct, it’d just be a normal struct placed inside a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Box&amp;lt;T&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;. When designing the language, we thought that the similarity here was a good thing, but experience has demonstrated that it is confusing. And it’s not just for the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Box&amp;lt;Trait&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; case; &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;impl SomeTrait for SomeOtherTrait&lt;/code&gt; is also technically valid syntax, but you almost always want to write &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;impl&amp;lt;T&amp;gt; SomeTrait for T where T: SomeOtherTrait&lt;/code&gt; instead. Same with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;impl SomeTrait&lt;/code&gt;, which looks like it would add methods or possibly default implementations but in fact adds inherent methods to a trait object. Finally, with the recent addition of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;impl Trait&lt;/code&gt; syntax, it’s &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;impl Trait&lt;/code&gt; vs &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Trait&lt;/code&gt; when explaining things, and so that feels like &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Trait&lt;/code&gt; is what you should use, given that it’s shorter, but in reality, that’s not always true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As such, in Rust 1.27, we have stabilized a new syntax, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rfcs/blob/master/text/2113-dyn-trait-syntax.md&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;dyn Trait&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. A trait object now looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-rust highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;// old =&amp;gt; new&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;Box&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Foo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;Box&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;dyn&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Foo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Foo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;dyn&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Foo&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;mut&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Foo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;mut&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;dyn&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Foo&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And similarly for other pointer types, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Arc&amp;lt;Foo&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; is now &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Arc&amp;lt;dyn Foo&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;, etc. Due to backwards compatibility, we cannot remove the old syntax, but we have included a lint, which is set to allow by default, called &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.rust-lang.org/rustc/lints/listing/allowed-by-default.html#bare-trait-object&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bare-trait-object&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. If you want to lint against the older syntax, you can turn it on. We thought that it would throw far too many warnings to turn on by default at present.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incidentally, we’re working on a tool called &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;rustfix&lt;/code&gt; that can automatically upgrade your code to newer idioms. It uses these sorts of lints to do so. Expect to hear more about &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;rustfix&lt;/code&gt; in a future announcement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;must_use-on-functions&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;#[must_use]&lt;/code&gt; on functions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;#[must_use]&lt;/code&gt; attribute is getting an upgrade: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/48925/&quot;&gt;it can now be used on functions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previously, it only applied to types, like &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Result&amp;lt;T, E&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;. But now, you can do this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-rust highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;must_use&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;fn&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;double&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;i32&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;i32&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;fn&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;main&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;double&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;// warning: unused return value of `double` which must be used&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;_&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;double&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;// (no warning)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve also &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/49533/&quot;&gt;enhanced several bits of the standard library&lt;/a&gt; to make use of this; &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Clone::clone&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Iterator::collect&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ToOwned::to_owned&lt;/code&gt; will all start warning if you don’t use their results, helping you notice expensive operations you may be throwing away by accident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/blob/master/RELEASES.md#version-1270-2018-06-21&quot;&gt;detailed release notes&lt;/a&gt; for more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;library-stabilizations&quot;&gt;Library stabilizations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several new APIs were stabilized this release:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/blob/master/RELEASES.md#version-1270-2018-06-21&quot;&gt;detailed release notes&lt;/a&gt; for more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;cargo-features&quot;&gt;Cargo features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cargo has two small upgrades this release. First, it now &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/cargo/pull/5393/&quot;&gt;takes a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;--target-dir&lt;/code&gt; flag&lt;/a&gt; if you’d like to change the target directory for a given invocation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, a tweak to the way Cargo deals with targets has landed. Cargo will attempt to automatically discover tests, examples, and binaries within your project. However, sometimes explicit configuration is needed. But the initial implementation had a problem: let’s say that you have two examples, and Cargo is discovering them both. You want to tweak one of them, and so you add a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;[[example]]&lt;/code&gt; to your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Cargo.toml&lt;/code&gt; to configure its settings. Cargo currently sees that you’ve set one explicitly, and therefore, doesn’t attempt to do any autodetection for the others. That’s quite surprising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As such, we’ve &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/cargo/pull/5335/&quot;&gt;added several ‘auto’ keys to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Cargo.toml&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; We can’t fix this behavior without possibly breaking projects that may have inadvertently been relying on it, and so, if you’d like to configure some targets, but not others, you can set the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;autoexamples&lt;/code&gt; key to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;true&lt;/code&gt; in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;[package]&lt;/code&gt; section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/blob/master/RELEASES.md#version-1270-2018-06-21&quot;&gt;detailed release notes&lt;/a&gt; for more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;contributors-to-1270&quot;&gt;Contributors to 1.27.0&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people came together to create Rust 1.27. We couldn’t have done it without all of you. &lt;a href=&quot;https://thanks.rust-lang.org/rust/1.27.0&quot;&gt;Thanks!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 20:14:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>steveklabnik</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.rust-lang.org/2018/06/21/Rust-1.27.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Future generations will laugh in horror and derision at the folly of facadism</title>
<link>https://www.architectural-review.com/essays/campaigns/outrage/outrage-future-generations-will-laugh-in-horror-and-derision-at-the-folly-of-facadism/10026645.article</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.architectural-review.com/essays/campaigns/outrage/outrage-future-generations-will-laugh-in-horror-and-derision-at-the-folly-of-facadism/10026645.article</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;As if I were being poked repeatedly in the eye with a blunt stick, I cannot avoid becoming increasingly aware of a painfully cynical trend in architecture that threatens to turn London into the backlot of an abandoned movie studio. If walls could speak, these would tell tales of bad compromises and angry developers who, dissatisfied with the meagre notion of repair and reuse, are driven solely by remorseless greed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, bullied into sacrificing historic buildings of merit, cowed planning authorities must take consolation in the small mercy of retaining a facade. The result is that architects are humiliated into creating passive-aggressive structures – gross hybrids of conflicted intentions that scream ‘Look what you made me do!’ in bitter petulant resentment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At present in Spitalfields, we are presented with a textbook example of such an affront – the London Fruit and Wool Exchange, a high-quality building from 1927 by architect Sydney Perks, enhanced by wooden parquet floors, careful detailing and significant craft elements throughout. In recent decades, it was home to more than a hundred independent businesses employing local people. This redevelopment was forced through by the former Mayor of London, Boris Johnson, against the unanimous wishes of Tower Hamlets’ planning committee, and before construction commenced it was pre-let to a single tenant, Ashurst, an international legal corporation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;inline_image image_size_full&quot; data-attachment=&quot;3095335&quot; data-sequence=&quot;1&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;picture&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;C5gs18lxmauh0mv&quot; src=&quot;https://www.architectural-review.com/pictures/380xany/3/3/5/3095335_c5gs18lxmauh0mv.jpg&quot; width=&quot;660&quot; class=&quot;responsiveImage&quot; data-size-1=&quot;380xany&quot; data-size-1-1=&quot;780xany&quot; data-size-3=&quot;1180xany&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;inline_title&quot;&gt;C5gs18lxmauh0mv&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;inline_caption&quot;&gt;The Duke of Cambridge dating from 1823 with its new shiny crown courtesy of Guy Hollaway Architects&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Axis Architects, working for the developer Exemplar, retained only the frontage of the building with its stone cornice and brick wall. Currently, precast panels of ‘bricks’ and ‘stone’ are being hung on the steel structure that sits behind it. These panels of bricks have an artful irregularity designed into them and an attempt is being made to match the tone of the cast ‘stone’ with the actual stone on the fragment of the earlier building. Yet these panels are already becoming chipped and damaged even as they are being put in place, and no one is fooled by this patronising approach to co-ordinate the old and the new. Indeed, the conflict between these elements manifests the conflict of interests that produced this ungainly chimera.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘A kind of authenticity’ is the language of British Land’s oxymoronic attempt to sell facadism in the publicity for its proposed Norton Folgate office development by Stanton Williams, where it shows an image of the front wall of a 19th-century warehouse pasted onto the lower floors of a towering office block as if it were a Penny Black glued onto a Jiffy bag. This misguided notion assumes there might be 57 varieties of authenticity, when ‘authentic’ is not a relative term – something is either authentic or it is phoney.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;inline_image image_size_full&quot; data-attachment=&quot;3095342&quot; data-sequence=&quot;7&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;picture&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;L1000030&quot; src=&quot;https://www.architectural-review.com/pictures/380xany/3/4/2/3095342_l1000030.jpg&quot; width=&quot;660&quot; class=&quot;responsiveImage&quot; data-size-1=&quot;380xany&quot; data-size-1-1=&quot;780xany&quot; data-size-3=&quot;1180xany&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;inline_title&quot;&gt;L1000030&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;inline_caption&quot;&gt;Alan Sugar’s development of the 13th century The White Hart pub by Rolfe Judd&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I fear Spitalfields is quickly becoming the epicentre of facadism in London, with the recent completion of Alan Sugar’s shameless redevelopment of &lt;em&gt;The White Hart&lt;/em&gt;, dating from 1240, into a cylindrical tower block designed by Rolfe Judd with just the outer wall of one of London’s most historic taverns stuck on the front. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile up the road in Bethnal Green, &lt;em&gt;The Duke of Cambridge&lt;/em&gt;, dating from 1823, has had an aggressively Modernist steel and glass building forcibly inserted into the shell of its dignified brick structure by Guy Hollaway Architects on behalf of Heath Holdings. Such is the conflict between the old and the new, you can almost feel the humiliation and pain of the original building. The ugliness of the outcome is a pertinent slap in the face, reminding us how blatantly any concern for architecture is being sacrificed in this approach. This disastrous hybrid is an unfortunate totem of where we are now, an object lesson for architectural students of what not to do, and we may be assured future generations will laugh in horror and derision at the folly of it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;inline_image image_size_full&quot; data-attachment=&quot;3095341&quot; data-sequence=&quot;6&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;picture&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;L1000009&quot; src=&quot;https://www.architectural-review.com/pictures/380xany/3/4/1/3095341_l1000009.jpg&quot; width=&quot;660&quot; class=&quot;responsiveImage&quot; data-size-1=&quot;380xany&quot; data-size-1-1=&quot;780xany&quot; data-size-3=&quot;1180xany&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;inline_title&quot;&gt;L1000009&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;inline_caption&quot;&gt;The carcass of the London Fruit and Wool Exchange, designed in 1927 by architect Sydney Perks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sticking a new building behind the shell of the former building in this manner is a pitiful way to go about things. It is not worthy of the term architecture. As resources grow ever fewer, the practice of sacrificing good-quality buildings for cheapjack disposable replacements cannot be justified. The default choice must always be to repurpose and reconfigure existing buildings. Some of the greatest of our cathedrals and country houses are the outcome of this approach to architecture, palimpsests in which the history of the building’s evolution can be read by the perceptive viewer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In every case, it is paramount that attention be paid to any structure as an architectural whole, rather than simply sticking a new shed behind an old facade. Taking existing buildings and reworking them sympathetically to serve new purposes requires much more sophisticated thinking from architects and developers than is in evidence in these hideous structures, which manifest the lamentable trend of facadism that blights our age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photographs courtesy of The Gentle Author&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 17:58:08 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>sndean</dc:creator>
<og:title>Outrage: future generations will laugh in horror and derision at the folly of facadism</og:title>
<og:type>Article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.architectural-review.com/essays/campaigns/outrage/outrage-future-generations-will-laugh-in-horror-and-derision-at-the-folly-of-facadism/10026645.article</og:url>
<og:description>We must stand up to the creeping plague of facadism, an infection spreading across the developments of London</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.architectural-review.com/pictures/2000x2000fit/3/3/6/3095336_dsc06359.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.architectural-review.com/essays/campaigns/outrage/outrage-future-generations-will-laugh-in-horror-and-derision-at-the-folly-of-facadism/10026645.article</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>AT&amp;T Successfully Derails California&amp;#039;s Tough New Net Neutrality Law</title>
<link>https://www.techdirt.com/articles/20180620/12174040079/att-successfully-derails-californias-tough-new-net-neutrality-law.shtml</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.techdirt.com/articles/20180620/12174040079/att-successfully-derails-californias-tough-new-net-neutrality-law.shtml</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;This truly is, as they say, why we &lt;em&gt;can't have nice things&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the wake of the FCC's ham-fisted net neutrality repeal, more than half the states in the country are now exploring their own, state-level net neutrality protections. California's proposal, Senator Scott Weiner's &lt;a href=&quot;https://leginfo.legislature.ca.gov/faces/billTextClient.xhtml?bill_id=201720180SB822&quot;&gt;SB 822&lt;/a&gt;, was seen as particularly promising in that it went even farther on some important issues than the 2015 FCC rules it was intended to replace. The EFF went so far as to call California's proposal the &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2018/05/today-tell-californias-senate-defend-net-neutrality-and-pass-sb-822&quot;&gt;gold standard&lt;/a&gt;&quot; for state-level net neutrality laws, noting it did a better job policing many of the problem areas where modern anti-competitive behavior occurs, such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.techdirt.com/articles/20161111/08192636020/too-little-too-late-fcc-finally-realizes-ats-zero-rating-is-anti-competitive.shtml&quot;&gt;zero rating&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.techdirt.com/articles/20150505/09051330890/mere-threat-real-neutrality-rules-appears-to-have-helped-calm-verizon-level-3-cogent-interconnection-feud.shtml&quot;&gt;interconnection&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You probably saw that AT&amp;amp;T just got done spending $86 billion to acquire Time Warner. The company harbors dreams of using its combined dominance over broadband and media content to anti-competitive advantage, something that's undeniable if you've watched AT&amp;amp;T &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.techdirt.com/articles/20160809/05541335192/att-fined-turning-blind-eye-as-drug-dealers-ripped-off-customers.shtml&quot;&gt;do business&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.techdirt.com/articles/20161216/06014836296/att-verizon-laugh-fccs-last-minute-attempt-to-crack-down-zero-rating.shtml&quot;&gt;any particular length of time&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since California's law would have severely hampered AT&amp;amp;T's dreams of dominating the streaming video and ad wars to come, the company got right to work derailing California's legislative push in its usually-underhanded way. The company managed to convince California Assemblyman Miguel Santiago to introduce a series of last-minute secretive Tuesday night amendments that were then voted on &lt;u&gt;without debate&lt;/u&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sfchronicle.com/business/article/California-net-neutrality-bill-eviscerated-13011048.php&quot;&gt;during a Wednesday morning hearing&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&quot;The committee, lead by Assemblyman Miguel Santiago, D-Los Angeles, issued amendments to the bill late Tuesday night. Among its recommendations were to permit a controversial internet service provider practice called “zero rating,” where some websites and apps don’t count against a consumer’s data allotment. Opponents view zero rating as a backdoor way of discriminating against online services that don’t strike free-data deals with broadband and wireless companies.&quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the early days of net neutrality, ISPs like AT&amp;amp;T engaged in more ham-fisted and non-transparent abuse of their broadband monopolies. Like the time AT&amp;amp;T &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2017/12/att-says-it-never-blocked-apps-fails-to-mention-how-it-blocked-facetime/&quot;&gt;blocked Facetime from working&lt;/a&gt; unless users upgraded to more expensive data plans, or the time Comcast throttled all upstream BitTorrent traffic then &lt;a href=&quot;https://torrentfreak.com/comcast-lied-to-fcc-blocks-bittorrent-traffic-247-080515/&quot;&gt;repeatedly lied about it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As people got smarter to what ISPs were up to, ISPs began getting more nefariously clever. Like the time ISPs let their peering and interconnection points &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.techdirt.com/articles/20150505/09051330890/mere-threat-real-neutrality-rules-appears-to-have-helped-calm-verizon-level-3-cogent-interconnection-feud.shtml&quot;&gt;intentionally congest&lt;/a&gt; to kill settlement-free peering and drive up costs for companies like Netflix, slowing down Netflix streams for everyone until the company paid up. Or the way that ISPs now impose &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.techdirt.com/articles/20160105/08100533246/with-fixed-costs-fat-margins-comcasts-broadband-cap-justifications-are-total-bullshit.shtml&quot;&gt;arbitrary and unnecessary usage caps&lt;/a&gt;, then exclude their own streaming services from them while still penalizing competitors (aka zero rating), something it took years for the last FCC to finally realize was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.techdirt.com/articles/20161111/08192636020/too-little-too-late-fcc-finally-realizes-ats-zero-rating-is-anti-competitive.shtml&quot;&gt;just as anti-competitive&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to this week. To convince lawmakers to back off the restrictions on zero rating, AT&amp;amp;T first employed the use of a group dubbed CALinnovates, one of numerous groups AT&amp;amp;T covertly funds to pee in the discourse pool. CALinnovates then circulated an &lt;a href=&quot;https://readsludge.com/2018/06/19/att-tied-to-supposed-startup-group-against-net-neutrality-in-california/&quot;&gt;incredibly misleading study&lt;/a&gt; among lawmakers falsely claiming that AT&amp;amp;T's anti-competitive use of usage caps is a &lt;em&gt;huge boon to the state's minority populations&lt;/em&gt; (err, false). AT&amp;amp;T then got state lawmakers to approve of a list of major amendments Tuesday evening that would cripple the most important parts of the bill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specifically, AT&amp;amp;T convinced Santiago to strip away all rules governing zero rating, all guidance preventing interconnection shenanigans, as well as a rule that would have prevented ISPs from charging other companies &quot;access fees&quot; if they want to reach AT&amp;amp;T customers. Santiago's office refused any and all contact from reporters (myself included) on Tuesday night, then quickly rushed those amendments through the voting process &lt;u&gt;before they could even be debated&lt;/u&gt;. Disgusted by the railroading, Weiner ultimately pulled his bill entirely, arguing that it no longer adequately protected consumers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&quot;It is no longer a net neutrality bill,” a visibly frustrated Wiener said after the vote. In an unusual move, the committee voted on the bill before Wiener was given a chance to testify. “I will state for the record ... I think it was fundamentally unfair,” he said.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Net neutrality activism groups like Fight for the Future were &lt;a href=&quot;http://tumblr.fightforthefuture.org/post/175080347948/breaking-led-by-corrupt-chairman-miguel-santiago&quot;&gt;notably less subtle&lt;/a&gt; in their own statements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&quot;The level of corruption we just witnessed literally makes me sick to my stomach,” said Evan Greer, deputy director of Fight for the Future, a digital rights group with more than 350,000 members in California. &quot;These California democrats will go down in history as among the worst corporate shills that have ever held elected office.Californians should rise up and demand that at their Assembly members represent them. The actions of this committee today are an attack not just on net neutrality, but on our democracy.&quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you've watched AT&amp;amp;T do business, the fact that it was able to scuttle this bill in such a &quot;progressive&quot; state shouldn't be surprising. AT&amp;amp;T's political power over many state legislatures is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.techdirt.com/articles/20160504/10373634345/att-buries-language-missouri-traffic-bill-to-hinder-broadband-competition.shtml&quot;&gt;often downright comical&lt;/a&gt;, to the point where AT&amp;amp;T lawyers are quite literally the ones &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.techdirt.com/articles/20171023/11391838461/michigan-lawmaker-flees-twitter-after-reports-highlight-she-helped-att-push-anti-competition-broadband-law.shtml&quot;&gt;writing terrible state law&lt;/a&gt;. That's particularly true in states like Tennessee, though in ignoring the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.techdirt.com/articles/20180418/10080639655/another-survey-shows-massive-bipartisan-opposition-to-net-neutrality-repeal.shtml&quot;&gt;undeniable will of the public&lt;/a&gt; on this subject, California has proven itself no better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All told it has been a great year and a greater few weeks if your name is AT&amp;amp;T. Net neutrality &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.techdirt.com/articles/20180611/08382240010/net-neutrality-rules-die-today-backlash-is-just-getting-started.shtml&quot;&gt;formally died on June 11&lt;/a&gt;, the company's latest megamerger was approved thanks to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.techdirt.com/articles/20180612/14415140022/att-defeats-doj-merger-fight-opening-door-to-some-major-competitive-headaches.shtml&quot;&gt;comically narrow understanding of the markets&lt;/a&gt; by a Federal Judge, and it managed to scuttle state-level net neutrality in California, purportedly a stronghold for net neutrality activism. This on the heels of successful efforts to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.techdirt.com/articles/20171211/13533738787/no-ftc-wont-save-you-once-net-neutrality-rules-are-killed.shtml&quot;&gt;neuter FCC oversight&lt;/a&gt; of historically unpopular and anti-competitive incumbent ISPs. What could possibly go wrong?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 17:48:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jc_811</dc:creator>
<og:title>AT&amp;T Successfully Derails California's Tough New Net Neutrality Law</og:title>
<og:description>This truly is, as they say, why we can't have nice things. In the wake of the FCC's ham-fisted net neutrality repeal, more than half the states in the country are now exploring their own, state-level net neutrality protections...</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.techdirt.com/articles/20180620/12174040079/att-successfully-derails-californias-tough-new-net-neutrality-law.shtml</og:url>
<og:image>https://ii.techdirt.com/s/t/i/td_icon_300.png</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.techdirt.com/articles/20180620/12174040079/att-successfully-derails-californias-tough-new-net-neutrality-law.shtml</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Nintendo and Microsoft team up to promote cross-play, while Sony remains silent</title>
<link>https://www.theverge.com/2018/6/21/17488530/nintendo-switch-microsoft-xbox-minecraft-cross-play-marketing-sony</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theverge.com/2018/6/21/17488530/nintendo-switch-microsoft-xbox-minecraft-cross-play-marketing-sony</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;Q7Qk7m&quot;&gt;The Nintendo Switch version of &lt;em&gt;Minecraft&lt;/em&gt; is getting a big update today, bringing the Bedrock Engine to Nintendo’s portable console. The update enables cross-play with PC, Xbox One, and smartphones — but notably not the PlayStation 4. Sony is blocking cross-play for &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Rocket League&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Minecraft&lt;/em&gt; so PS4 players can’t play against Xbox One or Nintendo Switch owners. Meanwhile, Nintendo and Microsoft are partnering to utilize cross-play as a marketing weapon today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;Cq7xg1&quot;&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Minecraft&lt;/em&gt; cross-play trailer specifically focuses on the Xbox One and Nintendo Switch being able to play together. It also includes the rare sight of an Xbox One controller in a Switch commercial. If that’s not enough of a partnership, the ad even encourages players to create, explore, and survive together in &lt;em&gt;Minecraft&lt;/em&gt; on Xbox One and Nintendo Switch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__inner&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__image&quot; data-original=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11576687/r4JjEfr.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img srcset=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/W1lBJ4IlyeuMlKjSjzia1xPwk8A=/0x0:848x475/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:848x475)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11576687/r4JjEfr.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/H0euojJbQxSWnYPBxkAx6Tquon4=/0x0:848x475/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:848x475)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11576687/r4JjEfr.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wMLODg9ut0CFgC60RZmJthp8tdo=/0x0:848x475/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:848x475)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11576687/r4JjEfr.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LXiktMfNOYaZGx8N6nCHWozPjHc=/0x0:848x475/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:848x475)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11576687/r4JjEfr.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/PCuRTmoPIGHGLQ0hZa7L4nrKvJ0=/0x0:848x475/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:848x475)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11576687/r4JjEfr.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/khhamBALF_O-tWL2ANwqVEGep2E=/0x0:848x475/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:848x475)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11576687/r4JjEfr.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pXOdJBV9is2xjMDFSAeFgfYhG5I=/0x0:848x475/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:848x475)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11576687/r4JjEfr.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gDL0q65Hp8Dv7dMr2hnd-bUAW2U=/0x0:848x475/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:848x475)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11576687/r4JjEfr.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8mXBOtcRSEU0UCzvyOoofYx5hEo=/0x0:848x475/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:848x475)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11576687/r4JjEfr.jpg 1920w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zovvw6Bab4YLpV__xHtyQW9TZ3w=/0x0:848x475/1200x0/filters:focal(0x0:848x475)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11576687/r4JjEfr.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;FImdHs&quot;&gt;It’s clear that Nintendo and Microsoft have signed a marketing deal to highlight cross-play for &lt;em&gt;Minecraft&lt;/em&gt;, a game that Microsoft publishes itself. It’s unusual to see such a partnership between console rivals, and it once again leaves Sony as the odd one out that’s refusing to enable cross-play between consoles and staying silent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;coUOoB&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2018/6/12/17454606/fortnite-nintendo-switch-ps4-block-accounts-cross-play-e3-2018&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; fans still aren’t happy&lt;/a&gt; that Sony is effectively holding their accounts hostage over its cross-play block, and the company has only &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2018/6/14/17462932/fortnite-nintendo-switch-block-sony-response-comment&quot;&gt;issued a weak response&lt;/a&gt; to the controversy. It’s clear that Microsoft and Nintendo see the advantages of cross-play, and they’re more than happy to use it as marketing leverage.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 16:01:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mikece</dc:creator>
<og:description>Sony is the odd one out for Minecraft and more</og:description>
<og:image>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UEFr00C1pgti_uVk67w4iTrE-Xc=/0x16:849x461/fit-in/1200x630/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11576535/p9FSwxX.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Nintendo and Microsoft team up to promote cross-play, while Sony remains silent</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.theverge.com/2018/6/21/17488530/nintendo-switch-microsoft-xbox-minecraft-cross-play-marketing-sony</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theverge.com/2018/6/21/17488530/nintendo-switch-microsoft-xbox-minecraft-cross-play-marketing-sony</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>States Can Require Internet Tax Collection, Supreme Court Rules</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-06-21/states-can-require-internet-tax-collection-supreme-court-rules-jiomtl5c</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-06-21/states-can-require-internet-tax-collection-supreme-court-rules-jiomtl5c</guid>
<description>&lt;aside class=&quot;left-column&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;text-to-speech&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LISTEN TO ARTICLE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;share-article-button&quot; data-variation=&quot;basic-article&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SHARE THIS ARTICLE&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Supreme Court freed states and local governments to start collecting billions of dollars in new sales taxes from online retailers, overturning a ruling that had made much of the internet a tax-free zone and put traditional retailers at a disadvantage.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;News of the ruling caused shares of Internet retailers including Amazon.com Inc. and Wayfair Inc. to fall.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The court’s 1992 decision involving catalog sales had shielded retailers from tax-collection duties if they didn’t have a physical presence in a state. Writing for the 5-4 court Thursday, Justice Anthony Kennedy said that ruling was obsolete in the e-commerce era.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Broader taxing power will let state and local governments collect an extra $8 billion to $23 billion a year, according to various estimates. All but five states impose sales taxes.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/W:US&quot; title=&quot;Company Overview&quot;&gt;Wayfair&lt;/a&gt; plunged as much as 9.5 percent on the news, and was down 1 percent to $115.13 at 1:25 p.m. in New York trading. &lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/AMZNEUR:EU&quot; title=&quot;Company Overview&quot;&gt;Amazon.com&lt;/a&gt; dropped as much as 1.9 percent; &lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/EBAY:US&quot; title=&quot;Company Overview&quot;&gt;EBay Inc.&lt;/a&gt; dropped as much as 12.6 percent and &lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/ETSY:US&quot; title=&quot;Company Overview&quot;&gt;Etsy Inc.&lt;/a&gt; fell as much as 5.7 percent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;inline-newsletter&quot; data-state=&quot;ready&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ruling will put new pressure on those companies and other internet retailers and marketplaces that don’t always collect taxes -- including &lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/OSTKEUR:EO&quot; title=&quot;Company Overview&quot;&gt;Overstock.com Inc.&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/EGGZ:US&quot; title=&quot;Company Overview&quot;&gt;Newegg Inc.&lt;/a&gt; and thousands of smaller merchants. Overstock.com lost as much as 7.3 percent; while 1-800 &lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/0516075D:US&quot; title=&quot;Company Overview&quot;&gt;Flowers.com Inc.&lt;/a&gt; dropped as much as 1.3 percent and online educational service &lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/CHGG:US&quot; title=&quot;Company Overview&quot;&gt;Chegg Inc.&lt;/a&gt; dropped as much as 7.8 percent. Avalara Inc., which makes tax-processing software, rose 11.9 percent to $50.37 at 1:33 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-tout-type=&quot;story&quot;&gt;&lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-06-21/retailers-have-one-fewer-excuse-as-states-can-tax-online-sales&quot; title=&quot;Click for full story&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Retailers Have One Less Excuse as States Can Tax Online Sales&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon, the biggest online retailer, wasn’t involved in the case. Amazon charges consumers in states that impose a sales tax, but only when selling products from its own inventory. About half its sales involve goods owned by millions of third-party merchants, many of which don’t collect tax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A key question for Amazon will be how states will go about collecting taxes from those sellers. An Amazon spokeswoman declined to comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ruling is a victory for South Dakota, whose law requires retailers with more than $100,000 in sales or 200 transactions annually in the state to pay a 4.5 percent tax on purchases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the court left open the possibility that other arguments could be pressed against the South Dakota law, Kennedy’s majority opinion strongly suggested the measure was constitutional, in part because it has the $100,000 threshold and doesn’t try to impose retroactive taxation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;South Dakota’s tax system includes several features that appear designed to prevent discrimination against or undue burdens upon interstate commerce,&quot; Kennedy wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;President Donald Trump told governors meeting at the White House Thursday that the ruling is “a big, big victory” for them and that it was a “good decision.” The Trump administration backed South Dakota in the case, urging that the 1992 ruling be overturned or at least limited to catalog sales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Not a ‘Green Light’&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andy Pincus, a Washington lawyer who filed a brief on behalf of EBay and a group of small businesses, said the ruling wasn’t a &quot;green light&quot; for other states. &quot;They’re going to have to meet some additional constitutional tests,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About 16 states already have laws similar to South Dakota’s that could let them require tax collection by internet retailers in the coming months, and more could follow quickly. Other states would have to revise their tax laws.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traditional retailers declared victory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Retailers have been waiting for this day for more than two decades,” said Matthew Shay, chief executive officer of the National Retail Federation. “This ruling clears the way for a fair and level playing field where all retailers compete under the same sales tax rules whether they sell merchandise online, in-store or both.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marketplaces such as EBay, which depend on millions of small merchants selling goods on their platforms, are now pushing for federal legislation providing exemptions for small businesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Today’s ruling is limited to large online retailers and confirms that small businesses are clearly viewed differently by the court,&quot; EBay said in an email. &quot;Now is the time for Congress to provide clear tax rules with a strong small business exemption.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Retroactive Taxes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Internet retailers say they are especially worried that tax collectors will try to impose years of retroactive liability, which the laws of many states allow. South Dakota and its allies say those concerns are overblown for practical and legal reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kennedy didn’t directly decide whether states could try to collect taxes retroactively, but he said that issue wasn’t a reason to keep the physical-presence rule. He said the court had other legal tools to ensure that sales taxes don’t become an &quot;undue burden&quot; on small businesses and startups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Justices Clarence Thomas, Neil Gorsuch, Ruth Bader Ginsburg and Samuel Alito joined Kennedy in a majority that cut across ideological lines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In dissent, Chief Justice John Roberts said the court should have left it to Congress to change the physical-presence rule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;‘Critical Segment’ of Economy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Any alteration to those rules with the potential to disrupt the development of such a critical segment of the economy should be undertaken by Congress,&quot; the chief justice wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The South Dakota measure was opposed by Wayfair, Overstock and Newegg. They said small sellers would be hit with heavy costs of complying with rules for thousands of products in thousands of taxing jurisdictions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congress could still intervene. Amazon and Overstock are among the companies that say they support a nationwide law that would relieve retailers from dealing with a patchwork of state tax laws.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 1992 ruling, Quill v. North Dakota, turned on the so-called dormant commerce clause, a judge-created legal doctrine that says states can’t unduly burden interstate commerce unless authorized by Congress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kennedy wrote that &quot;each year, the physical presence rule becomes further removed from economic reality and results in significant revenue losses to the states.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;‘Tax Shelter’&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He added: &quot;Quill has come to serve as a judicially created tax shelter for businesses that decide to limit their physical presence and still sell their goods and services to a state’s consumer.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;South Dakota urged the court to let sales taxes be imposed on companies with an &quot;economic presence&quot; in a state -- a test South Dakota said its law would pass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grover Norquist, president of the anti-tax group Americans for Tax Reform, said in a statement, &quot;Today the Supreme Court said yes -- you can be taxed by politicians you do not elect and who act knowing you are powerless to object.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is South Dakota v. Wayfair, 17-494.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;— With assistance by Alexa N Green, Molly Schuetz, and Spencer Soper&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;disclaimer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;news-rsf-automation-disclaimer&quot;&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;disclaimer&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Securities and Exchange Commission filing is accessible at: &lt;a href=&quot;custom:bloomberg:W%20US%20Equity%20CF&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot;&gt;W US Equity CF&lt;/a&gt; (for the company's Edgar filings) or &lt;a href=&quot;custom:bloomberg:W%20US%20Equity%20CN&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot;&gt;W US Equity CN&lt;/a&gt; (for all company news)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 14:22:43 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>uptown</dc:creator>
<og:description>The U.S. Supreme Court freed states and local governments to start collecting billions of dollars in new sales taxes from online retailers, overturning a ruling that had made much of the internet a tax-free zone and put traditional retailers at a disadvantage.</og:description>
<og:image>https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iwtxAps.ZgdE/v0/1200x800.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Online Retailers Can Be Forced to Collect Tax, High Court Rules</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-06-21/states-can-require-internet-tax-collection-supreme-court-rules-jiomtl5c</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-06-21/states-can-require-internet-tax-collection-supreme-court-rules-jiomtl5c</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: Why Do I Procrastinate? –  Web MD for Procrastination</title>
<link>https://whydoiprocrastinate.com/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://whydoiprocrastinate.com/</guid>
<description>&lt;h2 class=&quot;muted bold&quot;&gt;Okay, tell me more&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Expectancy&quot; is your belief in the outcome of the task you're avoiding. Expectancy can be either too high (overconfidence) or too low.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It looks like you have low expectancy for this task. Maybe you’re discouraged because it didn’t go well in the past. Low expectancy is especially pernicious in areas where rejections are inevitable in the beginning. Think sales jobs, or job hunting. Once you’ve had a few rejections, it’s easy to start believing that the goal isn’t achievable. Every rejection, every unanswered email after that only reinforces this belief.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And because you expect the task to fail, you postpone sending out more applications, or calling more prospects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This goes hand in hand with learned helplessness, which occurs when prior experiences convince you that you have no power to change a situation. To give an example, that’s how elephants are trained. When a elephant is a baby, the trainer ties it to a pole with a rope. The baby elephant strains to break loose, but it’s not strong enough to break the rope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it eventually gives up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it grows up, into its full strength as an adult elephant, it's still tied up with the same rope. If the elephant tries to break free at this point, the rope, or several such ropes, would not suffice to contain it. But the elephant doesn’t try to break free. In its head, it believes that the rope cannot be broken. &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Learned_helplessness&quot;&gt;More reading on learned helplessness&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humans behave very much like the elephant. It’s frighteningly easy to sink into this state of mind, especially after a few disappointments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to increase your motivation to do this task, we’re going to have to increase your expectancy, that is, your belief that you can successfully complete the task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;muted bold&quot;&gt;How do I fix this?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each card below has a strategy. You can’t apply them all, but choose a few that you can try immediately. And get back to work and see if it works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;modal&quot; id=&quot;successSpirals2&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot; role=&quot;dialog&quot; aria-labelledby=&quot;exampleModalLabel&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;modal-dialog modal-lg&quot; role=&quot;document&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;modal-content&quot; readability=&quot;50.5&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;modal-body&quot; readability=&quot;71&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Success begets more success. With every successful outcome, your belief in yourself is boosted. Most of the time, that belief is enough to carry you past the finish line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, incorporating success spirals into your life builds up your confidence in your ability to get things done. The more you complete things successfully, the more likely you are to continue doing so. In the long term, you can build up success spirals into your life by using the power of streaks. Commit to something, even if it’s small, and do it every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 class=&quot;modal-title do-this-now&quot;&gt;Do this now&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6 col-md-6 col-sm-12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;time-estimate&quot;&gt;Takes 20 mins&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start a success spiral for the task you’re working on. Take the task and break it into a list of the tiniest pieces of discrete units that you can. For example, if you’re struggling with writing a report, it could be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Click on word processor icon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click on File &amp;gt;&amp;gt; New.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write title of the report.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write down 5 main points to make in the report.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write 2 sub points for each point.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write down 1 major point to make in the introduction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;And so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It might take 10-20 minutes to just finish this list. And you might feel a little silly doing it. It doesn’t matter. You’d have spent that time on Youtube anyway. Just make the list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then start working on each of them. They’re so tiny, you’ll be done in seconds, or at maximum, minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And when you do each, check it off with a huge marker. You’re also allowed to execute a war dance if you like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each time you finish a tiny task, and startle your long-suffering and hapless neighbours with your yodel of victory, that’s a win. And if you can do the first task, you can do the second. So move to the next one. And see how quickly you get to the final step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;modal&quot; id=&quot;vicariousVictory2&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot; role=&quot;dialog&quot; aria-labelledby=&quot;exampleModalLabel&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;modal-dialog modal-lg modal-lg&quot; role=&quot;document&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;modal-content&quot; readability=&quot;39.5&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;modal-body&quot; readability=&quot;49&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a simple idea – see other people succeed, and you realize that it’s not impossible. It's even more motivating if you hear of their struggles before they attain their success -- you understand that they probably had a rocky road to achieve their goals, and success did not just happen to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The long term way to incorporate this into your life is to hang out with people you admire, those you can learn from. They say you’re the average of the five people you spend time with most. Spend time with people who are productive, and help others get things done as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 class=&quot;modal-title do-this-now&quot;&gt;Do this now&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6 col-md-6 col-sm-12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;time-estimate&quot;&gt;Takes 5-10 mins&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For an instant jolt of vicarious victory, pick a video from the suggestions here and watch it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Caveat: Don’t get drawn into the rabbit hole of Youtube videos! It’s better to watch one on loop till you’re feeling pumped. Please pick only one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;video-responsive&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;420&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/6xisazZX9bA&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; class=&quot;youtube&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/WYP9AGtLvRg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;modal&quot; id=&quot;wishFulfilment2&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot; role=&quot;dialog&quot; aria-labelledby=&quot;exampleModalLabel&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;modal-dialog modal-lg modal-lg&quot; role=&quot;document&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;modal-content&quot; readability=&quot;44.22477440525&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;modal-body&quot; readability=&quot;58.966365873667&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two steps to this tactic, and the second is the most important, so don’t skip it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wish fulfilment is visualizing the results of your work. Vividly imagining the completion of the task increases expectancy, by increasing your belief in its successful outcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 class=&quot;modal-title do-this-now&quot;&gt;Do this now&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6 col-md-6 col-sm-12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;time-estimate&quot;&gt;Takes 5-10 mins&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sit somewhere quiet. Put on headphones and listen to &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://rainymood.com/&quot;&gt;calming ambient music&lt;/a&gt; for 1 minute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think of the task you want to finish. Imagine how it will feel when you've finally completed it. Imagine yourself hitting save for the last time, hitting send on the email, walking back from the gym. Imagine the feeling of warm success in the pit of your stomach. Imagine yourself at the end of the day, going to do something fun. Decide what you’ll do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now contrast that with where you are right now. Sitting in front of a blank page, dithering and spending “just 5 more minutes” on Youtube. Feeling stressed out instead of feeling like you accomplished something. Contrast this to the first visualization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gap between the future and present should close, as you contrast these two situations, and you should find yourself motivated to work on the task, to sooner be able to get to that point where you imagined it done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;card-deck&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;card mb-4 box-card text-center hvr-icon-wobble-horizontal solution-card&quot; readability=&quot;26.897058823529&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;card-body d-flex flex-column&quot; readability=&quot;27.764705882353&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;card-title&quot;&gt;Success Spirals&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;card-text&quot;&gt;Success begets more success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;card-text&quot;&gt;Takes 20 mins&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;divLink&quot; data-toggle=&quot;modal&quot; data-target=&quot;#successSpirals2&quot;&gt;Read More&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;card mb-4 box-card text-center hvr-icon-wobble-horizontal solution-card&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;card-body d-flex flex-column&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;card-title&quot;&gt;Vicarious Victory&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;card-text&quot;&gt;See others succeed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;card-text&quot;&gt;Takes 10-15 mins&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;divLink&quot; data-toggle=&quot;modal&quot; data-target=&quot;#vicariousVictory2&quot;&gt;Read More&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;card mb-4 box-card text-center hvr-icon-wobble-horizontal solution-card&quot; readability=&quot;27.717647058824&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;card-body d-flex flex-column&quot; readability=&quot;28.611764705882&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;card-title&quot;&gt;Wish Fulfillment&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;card-text&quot;&gt;Imagine successful completion of the task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;card-text&quot;&gt;Takes 5-10 mins&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;divLink&quot; data-toggle=&quot;modal&quot; data-target=&quot;#wishFulfilment2&quot;&gt;Read More&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 14:01:17 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ppterodactyl</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://whydoiprocrastinate.com</og:url>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:title>Why do I procrastinate | And How to Stop Right Away</og:title>
<og:description>This quick quiz, based on the Procrastination Equation, helps you understand why you're procrastinating, and suggests ways to overcome it.</og:description>
<og:image>https://i.imgur.com/InNZFNk.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://whydoiprocrastinate.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Intel CEO resigns after relationship with employee</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/06/21/technology/intel-ceo-resigns-consensual-relationship.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2018/06/21/technology/intel-ceo-resigns-consensual-relationship.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;42.516612641815&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;32.484602917342&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;SAN FRANCISCO — For decades, Intel was one of the most predictable players in the technology industry. On Thursday, the semiconductor maker blindsided Silicon Valley with the abrupt resignation of its chief executive over a relationship with a subordinate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The chip company said it was recently informed that Brian Krzanich had a &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.intc.com/investor-relations/investor-education-and-news/investor-news/press-release-details/2018/Intel-CEO-Brian-Krzanich-Resigns-Board-Appoints-Bob-Swan-as-Interim-CEO/default.aspx&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;“past consensual relationship”&lt;/a&gt; with an Intel employee. An investigation by internal and external counsel then found that Mr. Krzanich, 58, had violated a non-fraternization policy that applies to managers, the company said. So Intel’s board accepted his resignation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The disclosure about Mr. Krzanich, a soft-spoken chip manufacturing specialist who joined Intel in 1982 and has &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2013/05/03/technology/intel-names-brian-krzanich-as-chief-executive.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;run it for five years&lt;/a&gt;, left many questions unanswered. The company declined to identify the employee involved, when the relationship took place or any additional details. It characterized its internal investigation as “ongoing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Krzanich’s relationship with the subordinate was not recent, said one person briefed on the situation, who declined to be identified because the company discussions over the matter were confidential. Intel found out about the relationship only a few days ago, this person added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;44.112704918033&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;37.147540983607&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Robert Swan, Intel’s chief financial officer, was appointed interim chief executive while the company conducts a search for a permanent new leader. Mr. Krzanich could not be reached for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“We appreciate Brian’s many contributions to Intel,” Andy Bryant, Intel’s chairman, said in a prepared statement. He added that he knew the company would continue to perform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Krzanich’s resignation is the latest turmoil in executive suites since the &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/series/metoo-moment&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;#MeToo movement&lt;/a&gt; emerged in the wake of allegations against &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/10/05/us/harvey-weinstein-harassment-allegations.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;producer Harvey Weinstein&lt;/a&gt;. The heightened scrutiny of workplace behavior has led &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/04/28/business/nike-women.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;executives at Nike&lt;/a&gt;, Lululemon Athletica, &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/09/12/technology/sofi-chief-executive-toxic-workplace.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Social Finance&lt;/a&gt; and many other companies to leave their jobs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Over the years, other chief executives have also been felled after violating workplace behavior standards, either because of affairs or through other incidents, including at &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2005/03/07/business/boeing-board-ousts-chief-citing-relationship-with-executive.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Boeing&lt;/a&gt;, Hewlett-Packard and &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2016-04-28/priceline-ceo-huston-resigns-after-relationship-with-employee&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Priceline&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Intel, which recently yielded the title of the world’s largest chip maker to Samsung, is approaching its 50th birthday. The company, known for microprocessor chips that carry out calculations in most personal computers and server systems, has prided itself as a standard-setter in corporate governance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;50.534351145038&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;47.618907809748&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;An Intel spokesman said the company’s most recent version of its strict non-fraternization policy, which prohibits managers from sexual or romantic relationships with employees who report directly or indirectly to them, has been in place since 2011.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Even so, Intel, like many companies, has not been impervious to romance. Mr. Krzanich, who rose through the ranks at Intel, married a woman who once worked in the company’s manufacturing operations. They have two daughters. The wife of Mr. Krzanich’s predecessor, Paul Otellini, &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/10/03/obituaries/paul-s-otellini-who-led-intel-and-saw-it-grow-even-more-dies-at-66.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;who died last year&lt;/a&gt;, also once worked at Intel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;As chief executive, Mr. Krzanich has been changing Intel’s corporate culture. The company has undergone an exodus of longtime managers — such as Renee James, &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/02/05/technology/renee-james-intel-ampere-startup.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;who was Mr. Krzanich’s No. 2&lt;/a&gt; but later faded in prominence and left the company — and the arrival of senior executives from other companies such as Qualcomm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Krzanich argued that Intel needed an infusion of fresh thinking to achieve his goal of reducing the company’s dependence on the sluggish P.C. market. He also publicly committed the company to increasing the number of employees from groups underrepresented in some technical specialties, including minorities and women.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“Intel is a different place, and we’ve done this while growing the business,” Mr. Krzanich said at the company’s annual shareholder meeting in May.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;But five former Intel employees, who declined to be identified for fear of retaliation, said Mr. Krzanich at times exhibited an arrogant personal style and handled staff changes in ways that created enemies. Some of these people said the #MeToo movement most likely influenced how Intel’s board handled the matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;50.812772133527&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;49.871794871795&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Krzanich also raised eyebrows by &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/01/07/technology/intel-chip-security.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;selling about $39 million in Intel shares&lt;/a&gt; last November, after the company learned of potential security flaws in its chips and before the issue was disclosed this year. The company said the sale was unrelated to the flaws, adding that Mr. Krzanich continued to hold shares in line with Intel guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Krzanich sought to broaden Intel’s business, taking the company into fields such as drones and wearable devices. He also presided over major acquisitions such as &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/03/13/business/dealbook/intel-mobileye-autonomous-cars-israel.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Intel’s $15.3 billion acquisition of Mobileye&lt;/a&gt;, an Israeli company that makes chips and software used in driver-assistance systems and self-driving cars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Yet Intel has lately &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2016/05/05/technology/moores-law-running-out-of-room-tech-looks-for-a-successor.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;struggled to sustain Moore’s Law&lt;/a&gt;, the pace of chip miniaturization named for the company’s co-founder, Gordon Moore, which expands the capabilities of its chips. It has announced repeated delays in perfecting its latest production process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;During Mr. Krzanich’s tenure, Intel’s market capitalization rose to above $240 billion, with a share price that is up 50 percent since the beginning of 2017. On Thursday, while the company’s shares declined 2 percent on the announcement of the leadership change, Intel said it expected to report second-quarter results that exceed Wall Street estimates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Pierre Ferragu, an analyst with New Street Research, said the projection points to a “monster” quarter for the company. “The resignation itself is in our view a completely idiosyncratic event, with no impact to the company,” he wrote in a research note.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Swan is a relative newcomer to Intel, joining the company as chief financial officer from General Atlantic in 2016. His past experience includes a stint at private equity firm General Atlantic and nine years as chief financial officer at eBay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Krzanich’s total compensation last year was $21.5 million, according to the executive compensation firm Equilar. That put him at 60th place in an annual ranking of highest-paid chief executives in the United States that Equilar conducted for The New York Times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;30.448888888889&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-a7wxe6&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-acwcvw&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;css-1vg6q84&quot;&gt;Correction:&lt;/strong&gt; 
&lt;p class=&quot;css-yosoyf e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;An earlier version of this article misstated Intel’s position in the semiconductor market. It is one of the largest makers of semiconductors, not the largest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-k8fkhk&quot; readability=&quot;8.0898876404494&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Follow Don Clark on Twitter: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/donal888&quot;&gt;@donal888&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adam Satariano contributed reporting from London.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 13:31:41 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>trequartista</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/06/21/technology/intel-ceo-resigns-consensual-relationship.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Intel C.E.O. Brian Krzanich Resigns After Relationship With Employee</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/06/22/business/22intel1/22intel1-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Mr. Krzanich, who resigned after violating Intel’s “non-fraternization policy,” will be replaced on an interim basis by the company’s chief financial officer.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/06/21/technology/intel-ceo-resigns-consensual-relationship.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>