<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Browserling goes viral with cheap phone users trying to use WhatsApp</title>
<link>http://www.catonmat.net/blog/incredible-events-at-browserling/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.catonmat.net/blog/incredible-events-at-browserling/</guid>
<description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.browserling.com?from=catonmat&quot; title=&quot;Cross-browser testing&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.catonmat.net/images/browserling-effortless-cross-browser-testing.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most random and amazing things happened at my company &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.browserling.com&quot;&gt;Browserling&lt;/a&gt; in the last few weeks. Someone in India discovered that they can use WhatsApp on very cheap $20 phones (Jio Phones) via Browserling. These cheap phones can't run WhatsApp but if you go to Browserling, you can use it via web.whatsapp.com. He made a video (first video below), the video went viral, got reposted everywhere, and more people started making videos about it (some more links below). I started getting crazy traffic, thousands, then tens of thousands of visitors and it just kept increasing from India, all trying to use Browserling as a WhatsApp proxy tool. Indian blogs picked it up, started reposting it, too. Traffic was going insane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/3wovEFNjPvs&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3wovEFNjPvs&quot;&gt;Use Whatsapp on Jio Phone with 100% working method&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More examples:&lt;br/&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uI-PjW3868k&lt;br/&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lEKCvUUp_Lw&lt;br/&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=U_SuM7JDSPU&lt;br/&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kJBGFOY0Jy0&lt;br/&gt;https://jiophone4g.com/jiophone/how-to-use-whatsapp-on-jio-phone#r&lt;br/&gt;http://www.rkhack.com/trick-use-whatsapp-jiophone/&lt;br/&gt;etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.catonmat.net/images/incredible-browserling-events/jiophone-browserling-video.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I couldn't handle tens of thousands of free sessions and it just kept increasing. I couldn't understand what was happening. Why was everyone trying to go to WhatsApp inside Browserling? I didn't know there was a viral video. I thought it was a DDOS attack. I noticed everyone had this weird user agent that said it was a JIO phone. I throught these attackers were fools. A classic newbie mistake not to randomize the user agent. So I quickly banned this JIO user agent with &quot;fatal error&quot; message. But instead of a victory, my web servers started getting DDOSed even more, these users were hitting refresh like crazy. I spent half a day identifying the attackers, found that it was all Indian IPs and blocked half of country at firewall level. All was well. I could go to sleep. But then suddenly someone messaged me and said why don't I let him use WhatsApp. Then 100 users started messaging me. Then 1000s. My Facebook was blowing up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.catonmat.net/images/incredible-browserling-events/whatsapp-fb-messages.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was now thinking I was under the most sophisticated attack ever on a personal level. I had no clue what was going on. I started blocking all these people but I was getting messages faster than I could block them one by one. I was freaking out. I decided to delete my Facebook for my own safety. While I was looking for the delete link, I accidentally noticed a link to YouTube in one of the messages. I opened it and I instantly got it. This was no attack! I was going viral! But I still didn't know what to do and kept &quot;fatal error&quot; message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Days went by and users started making videos about how to get around the &quot;fatal error&quot;, like this one:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/GjiSfy6dW4w&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GjiSfy6dW4w&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Jio phone me what'sapp &quot;fatal error solved&quot; without Browserling.com 100% Working&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They started linking to my competitors as an alternative solution. I was thinking, hah, great, let them crash competitor websites. A few more days went by and and then it suddenly struck me! Why am I blocking these users?! This is the biggest opportunity ever! I can capture tens of millions of users. Everyone in India who uses this phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had no idea how much these phones cost or how much money Indian users spent on online services. I quickly put a $1/day link for 1 day of Browserling to see if I could easily monetize it, but no one bought this subscription. Then I decreased the price to $0.50 and still no one was buying. I put a $0.10 cents sessions and still no buyers. I couldn't provide a free service to all of India, so I decided at least to do something with this traffic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So instead of banning the entire country via firewall or a &quot;fatal error&quot; message I created this message and asked users to follow @browserling and tweet messages about it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.catonmat.net/images/incredible-browserling-events/tweet-message-in-place-of-fatal-error.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And they did! All these users started following Browserling and tweeting about it. But they still couldn't use Browserling or Whatsapp, it was just a new message in place of &quot;fatal error&quot;. I started getting thousands of new followers and tens of thousands of tweets about Browserling:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/search?f=tweets&amp;amp;q=browserling&amp;amp;src=typd&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/search?f=tweets&amp;amp;q=browserling&amp;amp;src=typd&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It looked like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.catonmat.net/images/incredible-browserling-events/tweets-about-browserling.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I got curious. Would these users tweet anything that I asked them? So I decided to troll my competitors a little bit, and asked users to tweet a popular meme &lt;a href=&quot;http://knowyourmeme.com/memes/taiwan-1&quot;&gt;Taiwan number one&lt;/a&gt; to them. And it worked! Suddenly Twitter was full with my troll tweets:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.catonmat.net/images/incredible-browserling-events/trolling-competitors-taiwan-number-one.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was super hilarious. I was literally rolling on the floor laughing. TAIWAN NUMBER ONE! COMPETITORS NUMBER NINE!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then something weird happened with these tweets. Some kind of weird spam protection triggered at Twitter and they started blocking tweets about Browserling. No one could tweet with a @browserling mention anymore. So I changed message to one with just a shout out to browserling and without at-handle:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.catonmat.net/images/incredible-browserling-events/tweets-about-browserling-without-mention.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then instead of just tweeting and trolling, I asked users to start following Browserling on Facebook so I could reconnect with them and let them know when the software was up and running again. I started getting thousands of new followers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.catonmat.net/images/incredible-browserling-events/total-fb-followers.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turns out Jio Phone users would tweet, follow, like, and do anything I tell them to get access to Browserling. Very interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After having had fun with this I remembered I had many loyal blog readers from India. I messaged some of my blog followers from India and we talked about this. It turns out users in India can't easily make online USD purchases with credit or debit cards as it requires a special bank permission. That's why no one was signing up for a subscription for a $1 or 50c or 10c. I kept chatting with my friends and it turns out in India they have their own localized payment system that they use. It's hard to access from the outside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I teamed up with my friends Sunit and Wrishiraj from Assam, India. They've built a Linux distribution for India called &lt;a href=&quot;https://superxos.com/&quot;&gt;SuperX&lt;/a&gt; and have a company called Libresoft also based in Assam that can easily accept Indian payments such as UPI, prepaid wallets, and local debit and credit cards that work only inside India.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got to work and over last two weeks I built a &quot;WhatsApp over Browserling for India in an old browser on a $20 Jio Phone&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First I launched a simple user registration page. I just threw together quickest possible signup page. Simple HTML+CSS+jQuery. Does the job, works well and gets things done, just the way I like it. Here's how it looks on Jio Phones that have 240x320 resolution:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.catonmat.net/images/incredible-browserling-events/browserling-on-jio-phone-landing.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As soon as I launched it, I started getting thousands of new signups:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.catonmat.net/images/incredible-browserling-events/jio-user-signups.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The software wasn't ready yet so I just left a message that asked users to keep tweeting to keep the momentum going:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.catonmat.net/images/incredible-browserling-events/browserling-on-jio-phone-need-support.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I worked around the clock for over a week, 20 hours a day to create a new version of Browserling that can handle hundreds of thousands of users and can run thousands of Chromes in kiosk mode on servers with terabytes of ram. I put it to the test and it worked flawlessly:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.catonmat.net/images/incredible-browserling-events/whatsapp-in-browserling.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But now I was no longer getting any tweets, likes or shares, and I was losing momentum. Everyone was just using it for free. I had to do something to keep it up. So after chatting with my friends I learned people in India love lotteries. So I created a Browserling Lottery:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.catonmat.net/images/incredible-browserling-events/browserling-lottery-jio-phone.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lottery had a countdown timer and gave a 50% chance of winning. To speed up the lottery countdown timer and increase chances of winning, users had to tweet about Browserling and follow Browserling:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.catonmat.net/images/incredible-browserling-events/browserling-lottery-timer.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone loved it and wrote me hundreds of messages that they are winning the lottery and thanked me for making Browserling. The momentum was back up! I worked for a couple more days and just launched payments yesterday:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.catonmat.net/images/incredible-browserling-events/browserling-on-jio-phone.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently I'm running a multivariate test on various plans and prices to find which ones are the most popular. I randomly display an option to buy a daily plan, a weekly plan, or a monthly plan with a different price. Here are all the possibilities. (Only one plan is displayed to one user, so for example, someone will see 19/week, someone else 29/week, someone else 12/week, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.catonmat.net/images/incredible-browserling-events/browserling-payment-passes.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The price is in rupees. 9 rupees is 14 cents, 19 rupees is 30 cents, 29 rupees is 45 cents, 39 rupees is 60 cents. I'm using the local Indian payment processor called Instamojo, which is Stripe for India and integrates together all possible Indian payment methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I was working on Indian version, the word spread to Cameroon and Nigeria where people also use cheap phones that can't run Whatsapp or other software. I'm now setting up a few servers for Africa and targeting African countries next. If anyone wants to help spread the word in those countries, please reach out to me at peter@catonmat.net. (Update: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.catonmat.net/blog/browserling-cameroon/&quot;&gt;Browserling for Cameroon is up!&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is well aligned with Browserling's vision, which is &quot;run any application on any platform in any browser.&quot; In this case I've a web version of Whatsapp running in a Chrome on Linux, used in a cheap $20 phone's browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will keep you posted about what happens. Do I take over India?! Does this go further and it's a success in Africa, too?! Or does this go nowhere? Find out in the next episode of incredible events at Browserling! See you next time!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 03:04:29 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>amasad</dc:creator>
<og:image>http://www.catonmat.net/images/incredible-browserling-events/jiophone-browserling-video-fb.png</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.catonmat.net/blog/incredible-events-at-browserling/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Intel CEO’s Stock Sales May Warrant SEC Examination</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-01-08/intel-ceo-krzanich-s-stock-sales-seen-warranting-sec-examination</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-01-08/intel-ceo-krzanich-s-stock-sales-seen-warranting-sec-examination</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/INTC:US&quot; title=&quot;Company Overview&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Intel Corp.&lt;/a&gt; Chief Executive Officer Brian Krzanich’s sale of a chunk of company stock in the fourth quarter of last year has prompted questions about the transaction’s timing because it happened after the discovery that modern processors are vulnerable to hackers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Intel says Krzanich’s sales were part of a pre-arranged stock plan with an automated schedule, but some securities lawyers say the larger-than-usual transaction will probably be examined by the U.S. Securities &amp;amp; Exchange Commission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;lazy-img-231855652&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/i9FcHK9WAteg/v3/60x-1.jpg&quot; data-native-src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/i9FcHK9WAteg/v3/-1x-1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img__image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;news-figure-caption-text caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brian Krzanich&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photographer: Simon Dawson/Bloomberg&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The size of the transaction makes it inevitable that the SEC will take a look at this,” said Stephen Crimmins, a former SEC enforcement lawyer who now works for Murphy &amp;amp; McGonigle. “But I have to believe that the executive would have been exceptionally well advised by a good securities lawyer and everything would have been cleared. People who are CEOs of companies like Intel don’t make mistakes like this.”&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Under the SEC’s 10b5-1 rule -- designed to help avoid accusations of insider trading -- executives can set up plans to sell a pre-determined number of shares at pre-determined times. Krzanich has been doing so since at least 2015. But his latest sale coincided with revelations that all modern processors can be attacked, potentially exposing crucial data, such as passwords and encryption keys. The &lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-01-03/amd-soars-after-rival-intel-said-to-reveal-processor-flaw&quot; title=&quot;Intel Confronts Potential ‘PR Nightmare’ With Reported Flaw (1)&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;news&lt;/a&gt; sent Intel shares tumbling last week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two other things also attracted attention. Krzanich changed the timing of his trading instructions. In 2015, 2016 and 2017, his sales instructions were issued in June, April and February, respectively; however, this past October he issued a new set of instructions. Plus, he sold thousands more shares last year than in previous years, though the sale coincided with the biggest payout of performance-based shares he’s gotten since at least 2012. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Brian’s sale is unrelated,” a company spokesman said last week. “It was made pursuant to a pre-arranged stock sale plan with an automated sale schedule. He continues to hold shares in line with corporate guidelines.” Intel had no further comment on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;inline-newsletter&quot; data-state=&quot;ready&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to filings, on Nov. 29, Krzanich exercised and sold 644,135 options and sold an additional 245,743 shares that he already owned. That sale decreased his overall holdings by about 50 percent, bringing his ownership level nearer to what he held at the end of 2013 and at the minimum number of shares he must hold under Intel’s ownership requirements, according to the recent proxy filing. Each of those share transactions were made according to the pre-arranged trading plan, with the sale instructions determined at the end of October. The first mention of these planned trade decisions was in June 2015. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;lazy-img-322291719&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iIB.Cp8y72Go/v4/60x-1.png&quot; data-native-src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iIB.Cp8y72Go/v4/-1x-1.png&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img__image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the plan was set up, Krzanich has had a common trading pattern. In February, he gets his equity payout under Intel’s performance-based incentive plan and makes incremental sales during the year under his pre-arranged trading plan. In 2017, he set up pre-arranged sales of 28,000 shares, which were executed in March, July and October. Then in November, he sold a large stake, cutting his holdings by half.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technology companies, including Microsoft Corp., Apple Inc., Google and Amazon.com Inc. are rushing out fixes for PCs, smartphones and the servers that power the internet, and some have warned that their solutions may dent performance in some cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intel shares fell 0.2 percent to $44.64 at 11:46 a.m. in New York.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;— With assistance by Jenn Zhao, and Ian King&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 01:21:37 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>CPAhem</dc:creator>
<og:description>Intel Corp. Chief Executive Officer Brian Krzanich’s sale of a chunk of company stock in the fourth quarter of last year has prompted questions about the transaction’s timing because it happened after the discovery that modern processors are vulnerable to hackers.</og:description>
<og:image>https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iczyiBVLctwY/v0/1200x800.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Intel CEO’s Stock Sales May Warrant SEC Examination</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-01-08/intel-ceo-krzanich-s-stock-sales-seen-warranting-sec-examination</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-01-08/intel-ceo-krzanich-s-stock-sales-seen-warranting-sec-examination</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>What Spectre and Meltdown Mean for WebKit</title>
<link>https://webkit.org/blog/8048/what-spectre-and-meltdown-mean-for-webkit/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://webkit.org/blog/8048/what-spectre-and-meltdown-mean-for-webkit/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://googleprojectzero.blogspot.com/2018/01/reading-privileged-memory-with-side.html&quot;&gt;Security researchers have recently uncovered&lt;/a&gt; security issues known as &lt;a href=&quot;https://meltdownattack.com&quot;&gt;Meltdown&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://spectreattack.com&quot;&gt;Spectre&lt;/a&gt;. These issues apply to all modern processors and allow attackers to gain read access to parts of memory that were meant to be secret. To initiate a Spectre- or Meltdown-based attack, the attacker must be able to run code on the victim’s processor. WebKit is affected because in order to render modern web sites, any web JavaScript engine must allow untrusted JavaScript code to run on the user’s processor. Spectre impacts WebKit directly. Meltdown impacts WebKit because WebKit’s security properties must first be bypassed (via Spectre) before WebKit can be used to mount a Meltdown attack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;1.5&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;WebKit relies on &lt;em&gt;branch instructions&lt;/em&gt; to enforce what untrusted JavaScript and WebAssembly code can do. Spectre means that an attacker can control branches, so branches alone are no longer adequate for enforcing security properties.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meltdown means that userland code, such as JavaScript running in a web browser, can read kernel memory. Not all CPUs are affected by Meltdown and Meltdown is being mitigated by operating system changes. Mounting a Meltdown attack via JavaScript running in WebKit requires first bypassing branch-based security checks, like in the case of a Spectre attack. Therefore, Spectre mitigations that fix the branch problem also prevent an attacker from using WebKit as the starting point for Meltdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;This document explains how Spectre and Meltdown affect existing WebKit security mechanisms and what short-term and long-term fixes WebKit is deploying to provide protection against this new class of attacks. The first of these mitigations shipped on Jan 8, 2018:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT208401&quot;&gt;iOS 11.2.2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT208397&quot;&gt;High Sierra 10.13.2 Supplemental Update&lt;/a&gt;. This reuses the 10.13.2 version number. You can check if your Safari and WebKit are patched by verifying the full version number in About Safari. The version number should be either 13604.4.7.1.6 or 13604.4.7.10.6.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT208403&quot;&gt;Safari 11.0.2&lt;/a&gt; for El Capitan and Sierra. This reuses the 11.0.2 version number. Patched versions are 11604.4.7.1.6 (El Capitan) and 12604.4.7.1.6 (Sierra).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Spectre and Security Checks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spectre means that branches are no longer sufficient for enforcing the security properties of read operations in WebKit. The most impacted subsystem is JavaScriptCore (WebKit’s JavaScript engine). Almost all bounds checks can be bypassed to read arbitrarily out-of-bounds. This could allow an attacker to read arbitrary memory. All type checks are also vulnerable. For example, if some type contains an integer at offset 8 while another type contains a pointer at offset 8, then an attacker could use Spectre to bypass the type check that is supposed to ensure that you can’t use the integer to craft an arbitrary pointer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JavaScriptCore is meant to be a secure language virtual machine. It should be possible to load untrusted JavaScript or WebAssembly code into your process without the risk of your process’s memory being leaked to the JavaScript code except in cases where you explicitly export data to JavaScript via our C or Objective-C binding API. Spectre breaks this property of JavaScriptCore because untrusted JavaScript or WebAssembly now has a theoretical path to reading all of the host process’s address space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DOM APIs and system APIs called by DOM APIs also use branches to enforce their security properties, and those are callable from JavaScript. Hence, Spectre is not just an attack on JavaScriptCore itself but also everything that is callable from JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Reasoning About Spectre&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To understand how Spectre works, it’s useful to think about how security-sensitive programming language operations (like any property access in JavaScript) get executed in JavaScriptCore on a modern processor. Most discussions about Spectre have involved bounds checks, so this section considers that case as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;var tmp = intArray[index];
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this example, let’s assume that &lt;code&gt;intArray&lt;/code&gt; is known to our JavaScript engine to be a reference to a &lt;code&gt;Int32Array&lt;/code&gt; instance, but that we have not proved that &lt;code&gt;index&lt;/code&gt; is in bounds of &lt;code&gt;intArray.length&lt;/code&gt;. The compiler will have to emit a bounds check when it translates this high-level JavaScript operation into a lower-level form:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;if (((unsigned) index) &amp;gt;= ((unsigned) intArray-&amp;gt;length))
    fail;
int tmp = intArray-&amp;gt;vector[index];
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compiling this on x86 CPUs results in the following instructions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;mov 0x10(%rsi), %rdx     ; %rsi has intArray. This loads
                         ; intArray-&amp;gt;vector.
cmp 0x18(%rsi), %ecx     ; %ecx has the index. This compares
                         ; the index to intArray-&amp;gt;length.
jae Lfail                ; Branch to Lfail if
                         ; index &amp;gt;= intArray-&amp;gt;length according
                         ; to unsigned comparison.
mov (%rdx,%rcx,4), %ecx  ; Load intArray-&amp;gt;vector[index].
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modern CPUs are able to execute the bounds check branch (&lt;code&gt;jae&lt;/code&gt;) and the subsequent load (&lt;code&gt;mov (%rdx,%rcx,4), %ecx&lt;/code&gt;) in parallel. This is possible because:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Modern CPUs profile branches. In this case, they will observe that the branch always falls through. This is called &lt;em&gt;branch prediction&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Modern CPUs can roll back execution. The load after the branch can execute before the CPU verifies that the branch actually did fall through. If the branch turns out to be taken instead, the CPU can undo everything that happened between when the branch was encountered and when it finally got verified. This is called &lt;em&gt;speculative execution&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Spectre is an attack that exploits information leaks from speculative execution. Consider this code:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;var tmp = intArray[index];
otherArray[(tmp &amp;amp; 1) * 128];
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CPU has the ability to initiate loads from main memory into L1 (the CPU’s level 1 memory cache, which is the fastest and smallest) while executing speculatively. As a performance optimization, the CPU does not undo fetches into L1 when rolling back speculative execution. This leads to a timing-based information leak: in this code, whether the CPU loads &lt;code&gt;otherArray[0]&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;otherArray[128]&lt;/code&gt; depends on &lt;code&gt;tmp &amp;amp; 1&lt;/code&gt;, and it’s possible to later determine which the CPU loaded speculatively by timing the speed of access to &lt;code&gt;otherArray[0]&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;otherArray[128]&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The example so far involved controlling a bounds checking branch. This is a particularly effective Spectre attack because &lt;code&gt;index&lt;/code&gt; behaves like a pointer that can be used to read ~16GB of memory above &lt;code&gt;intArray-&amp;gt;vector&lt;/code&gt;. But Spectre could theoretically involve any branch that enforces security properties, like the branches used for type checks in JavaScriptCore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To summarize:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Spectre requires high fidelity timing so that the difference between L1 latency and main memory latency can be observed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spectre lets attackers control branches. Speculative execution executes branches according to past history, and the attacker can control this history. Therefore, the attacker controls what branches do during speculative execution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spectre is a race between the branch verifier and the initiation of the information-leaking load (what we wrote as &lt;code&gt;otherArray[(tmp &amp;amp; 1) * 128]&lt;/code&gt; above). The attacker knows if they won the race (one of the two &lt;code&gt;otherArray&lt;/code&gt; cache lines will be in L1), so the attack works so long as the attacker’s chance of winning is not zero.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Mitigating Spectre&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WebKit’s response to Spectre is a two-tiered defense:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;WebKit has disabled &lt;code&gt;SharedArrayBuffer&lt;/code&gt; and reduced timer precision.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WebKit is transitioning to using branchless security checking in addition to branch-based security checking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some of these changes shipped in the Jan 8 updates and more such changes are continuing to land in WebKit. The remainder of this document covers our mitigations in detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Reducing Timer Precision&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are reducing timer precision in WebKit. These changes have landed in trunk as of &lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.webkit.org/changeset/226495/webkit&quot;&gt;r226495&lt;/a&gt; and they shipped in the Jan 8 updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Timer precision from &lt;code&gt;performance.now&lt;/code&gt; and other sources is reduced to 1ms (&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.webkit.org/changeset/226495/webkit&quot;&gt;r226495&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We have disabled &lt;code&gt;SharedArrayBuffer&lt;/code&gt;, since it can be used to create a high-resolution timer (&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.webkit.org/changeset/226386/webkit&quot;&gt;r226386&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our long-term plan is to make Spectre impossible even in the presence of high fidelity timing; further work is needed to re-enable this path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Branchless Security Checks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since learning about Spectre, we have been researching how to do security checks without relying on branches. We have begun making the transition to this new style of security checks and we shipped the first branchless checks in the Jan 8 updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Index Masking&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The simplest example of a branchless security check is masking the index of an array access:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;int tmp = intArray-&amp;gt;vector[index &amp;amp; intArray-&amp;gt;mask];
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modern CPUs do not speculate on bit masking. If the mask is picked to fit the array length, this mitigation ensures that even with Spectre, an attacker cannot read out-of-bounds of the array.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have implemented index masking for:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Typed arrays (&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.webkit.org/changeset/226461/webkit&quot;&gt;r226461&lt;/a&gt;),&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WebAssembly memories (&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.webkit.org/changeset/226461/webkit&quot;&gt;r226461&lt;/a&gt;, mostly via shared code with typed arrays),&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strings (&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.webkit.org/changeset/226068/webkit&quot;&gt;r226068&lt;/a&gt;),&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;WTF::Vector&lt;/code&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.webkit.org/changeset/226068/webkit&quot;&gt;r226068&lt;/a&gt;), and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plain JavaScript arrays (&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.webkit.org/changeset/225913/webkit&quot;&gt;r225913&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Changes (1-4) shipped in the Jan 8 updates. (5) landed in WebKit but has not yet shipped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Index masking is not yet a complete fix for out-of-bounds access. Our current index masking mitigations use a mask that is computed by rounding up the length to the next power of two (and subtracting one). This still allows out-of-bounds reads, just not to arbitrary memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our current testing indicates that index masking has no measurable impact on the Speedometer and ARES-6 tests and an impact of less than 2.5% on the JetStream benchmark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Pointer Poisoning&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Index masking is easy to apply for array accesses, but many security check branches have to do with object type, not array bounds. Pointer poisoning is a technique that can be used to make any type check secure under Spectre by changing the shape of the object subject to the check.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poisoning a pointer just means performing some reversible math on it that will make access attempts fail unless the pointer is unpoisoned. In WebKit, poisoning involves xoring a value that is sure to have at least one bit set in high positions so that accesses that do not unpoison are very likely to hit unmapped memory. WebKit picks poison values using a compile-time random number generator with lots of subtle rules, but to understand the approach, just consider &lt;code&gt;1 &amp;lt;&amp;lt; 40&lt;/code&gt; as a poison value. Adding one terabyte to a valid pointer is sure to result in an unmapped pointer in WebKit’s memory layout on macOS and iOS, and probably on other operating systems, too. Many possible poison values exist that would have this effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poisoning becomes most powerful when each static declaration of a pointer field has a unique poison value, and the poison values differ in the high bits so that unpoisoning with the wrong value results in an unmapped pointer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an example of how to apply pointer poisoning as a branchless type check, consider some class &lt;code&gt;Foo&lt;/code&gt; that belongs to a hierarchy of classes that participate in dynamic downcasts based on some checks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;class Foo : public Base {
public:
    ...
private:
    int m_x;
    Bar* m_y;
};
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to make this class’s type checks sound under Spectre, we can simply move Foo’s fields out into a data struct pointed to by a uniquely poisoned pointer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;class Foo : public Base {
public:
    ....
private:
    struct Data {
        int x;
        Bar* y;
    };
    ConstExprPoisoned&amp;lt;FooDataKey, Data&amp;gt; m_data;
};
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where &lt;code&gt;FooDataKey&lt;/code&gt; is a key unique to &lt;code&gt;Foo&lt;/code&gt;, based on which &lt;code&gt;ConstExprPoisoned&amp;lt;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; will compute a random poison value at compile time. If all classes in this hierarchy use a pointer poisoned indirection to protect their fields then this suffices as a branchless type check for all accesses to these types. In addition to being a great Spectre mitigation, this is also a useful remote code execution mitigation, since it makes it harder to do any kind of type confusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pointer poisoning sometimes does not require any extra indirections. JavaScriptCore has tons of data structures that roughly fit this pattern:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;struct Thingy {
    Type type;
    void* data; // The shape of this depends on `type`.
};
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any such data structure’s type checks can be made branchless by poisoning the &lt;code&gt;data&lt;/code&gt; pointer according to a poison value that depends on &lt;code&gt;type&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have begun converting WebKit’s object models to use pointer poisoning (&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.webkit.org/changeset/225363/webkit&quot;&gt;r225363&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.webkit.org/changeset/225437/webkit&quot;&gt;rr225437&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.webkit.org/changeset/225620/webkit&quot;&gt;r225632&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.webkit.org/changeset/225659/webkit&quot;&gt;r225659&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.webkit.org/changeset/225697/webkit&quot;&gt;r225697&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.webkit.org/changeset/225857/webkit&quot;&gt;r225857&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.webkit.org/changeset/226015/webkit&quot;&gt;r226015&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.webkit.org/changeset/226247/webkit&quot;&gt;r226247&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.webkit.org/changeset/226344/webkit&quot;&gt;r226344&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.webkit.org/changeset/226485/webkit&quot;&gt;r226485&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.webkit.org/changeset/226530/webkit&quot;&gt;r226530&lt;/a&gt;), and some of the initial pointer poisoning work is shipping in the Jan 8 updates (specifically, &lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.webkit.org/changeset/225363/webkit&quot;&gt;r225363&lt;/a&gt;–&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.webkit.org/changeset/225857/webkit&quot;&gt;r225857&lt;/a&gt;). So far, we have not observed any performance regressions from using pointer poisoning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Mitigating Meltdown&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meltdown allows userland code to read kernel memory. WebKit is indirectly affected by Meltdown because a Meltdown attack could be initiated using any kind of code execution, including JavaScript. However, the memory accesses used to perform Meltdown would be a violation of WebKit’s security model. Therefore, JavaScript-based Meltdown attacks must first use Spectre to get around WebKit’s security checks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT208394&quot;&gt;Meltdown has already&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kernel_page-table_isolation&quot;&gt;been mitigated by&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/4073119/protect-against-speculative-execution-side-channel-vulnerabilities-in&quot;&gt;operating system changes&lt;/a&gt;, so even if WebKit lacked any Spectre mitigations, it should no longer be possible to mount a Meltdown attack via WebKit. Any future Spectre mitigations will make it even less likely that WebKit could be used for a Meltdown attack, since the Spectre stage of that attack will be harder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Recommendations For App Developers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spectre means that secrets in the same address space as untrusted JavaScript are more vulnerable than ever before. Based on this, we recommend:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Switch to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/videos/play/wwdc2014/206/&quot;&gt;Modern WebKit API&lt;/a&gt; if you have not done so already. This protects your app by running untrusted JavaScript in another process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid exposing sources of high-precision timing to untrusted JavaScript or WebAssembly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spectre and Meltdown are a new class of security issues that apply to modern processors and the software that runs on them. WebKit is affected by both issues because WebKit allows untrusted code to run on users’ processors. In response to these new issues, we have implemented mitigations to defend against Spectre (and Meltdown by proxy, since you need Spectre to do Meltdown via the browser). The first of these mitigations have shipped in the Jan 8 updates (iOS 11.2.2, High Sierra 10.13.2 supplemental update, and Safari 11.0.2 reissue). Stay tuned for more WebKit Spectre fixes!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 00:50:58 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pizlonator</dc:creator>
<og:title>What Spectre and Meltdown Mean For WebKit</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://webkit.org/blog/8048/what-spectre-and-meltdown-mean-for-webkit/</og:url>
<og:image>https://webkit.org/wp-content/themes/webkit/images/ogimage.png</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://webkit.org/blog/8048/what-spectre-and-meltdown-mean-for-webkit/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Net Neutrality to Get U.S. Senate Vote as Democrats Force Issue</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-01-08/net-neutrality-to-get-u-s-senate-vote-as-democrats-force-issue</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-01-08/net-neutrality-to-get-u-s-senate-vote-as-democrats-force-issue</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The U.S. Senate will hold a vote on net neutrality — albeit a symbolic one. Less than a month after the Federal Communications Commission reversed Obama-era rules that prohibited internet providers from blocking or slowing down certain websites, or accepting payment for faster service, Democratic senators have collected enough support to force a vote to block the changes from taking effect. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Democrats, led by Massachusetts Senator Ed Markey, are using a vehicle known as a Congressional Review Act, or CRA, which is essentially an official form of disapproval of the FCC’s action. If passed, it would block the commission’s new rules. If 30 senators call for a CRA, they can make the entire Senate vote on it. Claire McCaskill became the 30th senator to get behind Markey’s move. None of them are Republicans.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;To take effect, the CRA would need majority votes in both houses, in addition to sign-off from the president. Given that Republicans have almost unanimously supported the FCC’s new rules, the prospects for the CRA are dim. But in this case having a vote is the entire point. Democrats are eager to make net neutrality a political issue, and they want Republicans on-record taking a stance they’re convinced will be unpopular. The pro-net neutrality group Fight for the Future said last week it plans to rally opposition to any lawmaker who votes against the act. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The timing of a vote is still up in the air. The FCC’s rules first have to be published in the Federal Register, giving Markey 60 legislative days to call for a vote on the CRA. In the meantime, net neutrality supporters are also pursuing litigation and state laws.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 22:45:28 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rayuela</dc:creator>
<og:description>Republicans are being asked to acknowledge they support the FCC’s reversal of Obama-era rules</og:description>
<og:image>https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/i2I4QdMU181c/v1/1200x1801.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Net Neutrality to Get U.S. Senate Vote as Democrats Force Issue</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-01-08/net-neutrality-to-get-u-s-senate-vote-as-democrats-force-issue</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-01-08/net-neutrality-to-get-u-s-senate-vote-as-democrats-force-issue</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>CEO of porn cryptocurrency disappears with investor money</title>
<link>https://nypost.com/2018/01/08/ceo-of-porn-cryptocurrency-disappears-with-investor-money/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://nypost.com/2018/01/08/ceo-of-porn-cryptocurrency-disappears-with-investor-money/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;A cryptocurrency built for watching live-streaming porn is turning out to be a buzzkill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Four investors in the digital currency, called Fantasy Market, claimed last week that its shadowy CEO disappeared with their money — and has not refunded all their investment despite repeated requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The alleged inability of investors to trade out of the Fantasy Market tokens, or FMtokens, could stand as a warning to all investors in the red-hot cryptocoin market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jonathan Lucas, the brains behind FMtokens, was aiming to raise as much as $25 million last year, according to Lucas’ white paper — the investment plan circulated among investors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FMtokens would be used to pay for viewing live-streaming porn, the paper said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cryptocurrencies like bitcoin, ethereum and ripple, with their values soaring, are among the buzziest investments on Wall Street.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FMtokens, like other initial coin offerings, or ICOs, usually have limited use — unlike cryptocurrencies — and often use the technology supporting ethereum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cryptotokens are also wildly popular investment assets. They are thinly regulated and are subject to wild swings in valuation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of their volatility and lack of regulation, Securities and Exchange Commission Chairman Jay Clayton in December voiced his concern about Main Street investors jumping into ICOs with dreams of making a fortune.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clayton’s statement came too late for the irate FMtoken investors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The venture flamed out in November after The Post questioned Lucas for about an hour on how his ICO would work and about statements he made in the white paper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Jonathan Lucas (most likely an alias) has scammed us and run off with the cryptocurrency,” one irate investor fumed to The Post, more than two months after investing in Fantasy Market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s unclear how close Lucas got to his $25 million fundraising goal. He told a reporter in November he had raised less than $2 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But he boasted in September in private chats seen by The Post to being just 13 percent away from raising $5 million — which translates to about $4.4 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lucas, who has not been charged with any wrongdoing, didn’t return a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The company, on its site on Sunday, appeared to be trying to get money back to investors — asking out-of-pocket investors to contact them “in the next 90 days.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One investor who got a refund is still unhappy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“[Recently] I wrote threatening to file police and FBI reports,” a second aggrieved investor told The Post. “Within hours they refunded me ethereum with a dollar amount equal to what I had contributed in early September, but since the coin has more than tripled in value since then, they kept the rest of my contribution, essentially stealing quite a lot of money from me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investors had to buy FMtokens with ethereum, whose value has risen 160 percent in the last month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A third investor claimed that Lucas appears to be actively trading on cryptocurrency exchanges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I’m not in the business of scamming people, or again, I wouldn’t have used my real name for the project,” Lucas wrote in a Nov. 14 chat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;jp-post-flair&quot; class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-like-enabled sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;robots-nocontent sd-block sd-social sd-social-icon-text sd-sharing&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Share this:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 22:20:52 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>prostoalex</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>CEO of porn cryptocurrency disappears with investor money</og:title>
<og:url>https://nypost.com/2018/01/08/ceo-of-porn-cryptocurrency-disappears-with-investor-money/</og:url>
<og:description>A cryptocurrency built for watching live-streaming porn is turning out to be a buzzkill. Four investors in the digital currency, called Fantasy Market, claimed last week that its shadowy CEO disapp…</og:description>
<og:image>https://thenypost.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/crypto1.jpg?quality=90&amp;strip=all&amp;w=1200</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://nypost.com/2018/01/08/ceo-of-porn-cryptocurrency-disappears-with-investor-money/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ibuprofen alters human testicular physiology</title>
<link>http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;contributors&quot;&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;contributor-list&quot; id=&quot;contrib-group-1&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;contributor&quot; id=&quot;contrib-1&quot; itemprop=&quot;author&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Person&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;name&quot; itemprop=&quot;name&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;name-search&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/search?author1=David+Møbjerg+Kristensen&amp;amp;sortspec=date&amp;amp;submit=Submit&quot;&gt;David Møbjerg Kristensen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-aff-1-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-aff&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#aff-1&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;a&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;xref-sep&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-aff-2-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-aff&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#aff-2&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;b&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;xref-sep&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-fn-3-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-fn&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#fn-3&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;xref-sep&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-corresp-1-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-corresp&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#corresp-1&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;contributor&quot; id=&quot;contrib-2&quot; itemprop=&quot;author&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Person&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;name&quot; itemprop=&quot;name&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;name-search&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/search?author1=Christèle+Desdoits-Lethimonier&amp;amp;sortspec=date&amp;amp;submit=Submit&quot;&gt;Christèle Desdoits-Lethimonier&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-aff-2-2&quot; class=&quot;xref-aff&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#aff-2&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;b&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;xref-sep&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-fn-3-2&quot; class=&quot;xref-fn&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#fn-3&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;contributor&quot; id=&quot;contrib-3&quot; itemprop=&quot;author&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Person&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;name&quot; itemprop=&quot;name&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;name-search&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/search?author1=Abigail+L.+Mackey&amp;amp;sortspec=date&amp;amp;submit=Submit&quot;&gt;Abigail L. Mackey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-aff-3-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-aff&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#aff-3&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;c&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;xref-sep&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-aff-4-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-aff&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#aff-4&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;d&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;contributor&quot; id=&quot;contrib-4&quot; itemprop=&quot;author&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Person&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;name&quot; itemprop=&quot;name&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;name-search&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/search?author1=Marlene+Danner+Dalgaard&amp;amp;sortspec=date&amp;amp;submit=Submit&quot;&gt;Marlene Danner Dalgaard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-aff-5-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-aff&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#aff-5&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;e&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;contributor&quot; id=&quot;contrib-5&quot; itemprop=&quot;author&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Person&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;name&quot; itemprop=&quot;name&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;name-search&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/search?author1=Federico+De+Masi&amp;amp;sortspec=date&amp;amp;submit=Submit&quot;&gt;Federico De Masi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-aff-5-2&quot; class=&quot;xref-aff&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#aff-5&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;e&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;contributor&quot; id=&quot;contrib-6&quot; itemprop=&quot;author&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Person&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;name&quot; itemprop=&quot;name&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;name-search&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/search?author1=Cecilie+Hurup+Munkbøl&amp;amp;sortspec=date&amp;amp;submit=Submit&quot;&gt;Cecilie Hurup Munkbøl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-aff-6-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-aff&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#aff-6&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;f&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;contributor&quot; id=&quot;contrib-7&quot; itemprop=&quot;author&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Person&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;name&quot; itemprop=&quot;name&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;name-search&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/search?author1=Bjarne+Styrishave&amp;amp;sortspec=date&amp;amp;submit=Submit&quot;&gt;Bjarne Styrishave&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-aff-6-2&quot; class=&quot;xref-aff&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#aff-6&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;f&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;contributor&quot; id=&quot;contrib-8&quot; itemprop=&quot;author&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Person&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;name&quot; itemprop=&quot;name&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;name-search&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/search?author1=Jean-Philippe+Antignac&amp;amp;sortspec=date&amp;amp;submit=Submit&quot;&gt;Jean-Philippe Antignac&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-aff-7-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-aff&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#aff-7&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;g&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;contributor&quot; id=&quot;contrib-9&quot; itemprop=&quot;author&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Person&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;name&quot; itemprop=&quot;name&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;name-search&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/search?author1=Bruno+Le+Bizec&amp;amp;sortspec=date&amp;amp;submit=Submit&quot;&gt;Bruno Le Bizec&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-aff-7-2&quot; class=&quot;xref-aff&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#aff-7&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;g&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;contributor&quot; id=&quot;contrib-10&quot; itemprop=&quot;author&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Person&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;name&quot; itemprop=&quot;name&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;name-search&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/search?author1=Christian+Platel&amp;amp;sortspec=date&amp;amp;submit=Submit&quot;&gt;Christian Platel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-aff-8-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-aff&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#aff-8&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;h&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;contributor&quot; id=&quot;contrib-11&quot; itemprop=&quot;author&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Person&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;name&quot; itemprop=&quot;name&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;name-search&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/search?author1=Anders+Hay-Schmidt&amp;amp;sortspec=date&amp;amp;submit=Submit&quot;&gt;Anders Hay-Schmidt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-aff-9-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-aff&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#aff-9&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;i&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;contributor&quot; id=&quot;contrib-12&quot; itemprop=&quot;author&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Person&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;name&quot; itemprop=&quot;name&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;name-search&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/search?author1=Tina+Kold+Jensen&amp;amp;sortspec=date&amp;amp;submit=Submit&quot;&gt;Tina Kold Jensen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-aff-10-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-aff&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#aff-10&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;j&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;contributor&quot; id=&quot;contrib-13&quot; itemprop=&quot;author&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Person&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;name&quot; itemprop=&quot;name&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;name-search&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/search?author1=Laurianne+Lesné&amp;amp;sortspec=date&amp;amp;submit=Submit&quot;&gt;Laurianne Lesné&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-aff-2-3&quot; class=&quot;xref-aff&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#aff-2&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;b&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;contributor&quot; id=&quot;contrib-14&quot; itemprop=&quot;author&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Person&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;name&quot; itemprop=&quot;name&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;name-search&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/search?author1=Séverine+Mazaud-Guittot&amp;amp;sortspec=date&amp;amp;submit=Submit&quot;&gt;Séverine Mazaud-Guittot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-aff-2-4&quot; class=&quot;xref-aff&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#aff-2&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;b&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;contributor&quot; id=&quot;contrib-15&quot; itemprop=&quot;author&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Person&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;name&quot; itemprop=&quot;name&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;name-search&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/search?author1=Karsten+Kristiansen&amp;amp;sortspec=date&amp;amp;submit=Submit&quot;&gt;Karsten Kristiansen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-aff-11-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-aff&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#aff-11&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;k&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;xref-sep&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-aff-12-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-aff&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#aff-12&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;l&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;contributor&quot; id=&quot;contrib-16&quot; itemprop=&quot;author&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Person&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;name&quot; itemprop=&quot;name&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;name-search&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/search?author1=Søren+Brunak&amp;amp;sortspec=date&amp;amp;submit=Submit&quot;&gt;Søren Brunak&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-aff-1-2&quot; class=&quot;xref-aff&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#aff-1&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;a&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;contributor&quot; id=&quot;contrib-17&quot; itemprop=&quot;author&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Person&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;name&quot; itemprop=&quot;name&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;name-search&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/search?author1=Michael+Kjaer&amp;amp;sortspec=date&amp;amp;submit=Submit&quot;&gt;Michael Kjaer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-aff-3-2&quot; class=&quot;xref-aff&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#aff-3&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;c&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;xref-sep&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-aff-4-2&quot; class=&quot;xref-aff&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#aff-4&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;d&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;contributor&quot; id=&quot;contrib-18&quot; itemprop=&quot;author&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Person&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;name&quot; itemprop=&quot;name&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;name-search&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/search?author1=Anders+Juul&amp;amp;sortspec=date&amp;amp;submit=Submit&quot;&gt;Anders Juul&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-aff-9-2&quot; class=&quot;xref-aff&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#aff-9&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;i&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;last&quot; id=&quot;contrib-19&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;name&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;name-search&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/search?author1=Bernard+Jégou&amp;amp;sortspec=date&amp;amp;submit=Submit&quot;&gt;Bernard Jégou&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-aff-2-5&quot; class=&quot;xref-aff&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#aff-2&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;b&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;xref-sep&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-corresp-1-2&quot; class=&quot;xref-corresp&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#corresp-1&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;ol class=&quot;affiliation-list&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;aff&quot;&gt;
&lt;address&gt;&lt;sup&gt;a&lt;/sup&gt;Danish Headache Center, Department of Neurology, Rigshospitalet, &lt;span class=&quot;institution&quot;&gt;University of Copenhagen&lt;/span&gt;, 1165 Copenhagen, Denmark;&lt;/address&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;aff&quot;&gt;
&lt;address&gt;&lt;sup&gt;b&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;institution&quot;&gt;Université de Rennes I&lt;/span&gt;, Inserm, EHESP-School of Public Health, Irset (Institut de Recherche en Santé, Environnement et Travail) - UMR_S 1085, F-35000 Rennes, France;&lt;/address&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;aff&quot;&gt;
&lt;address&gt;&lt;sup&gt;c&lt;/sup&gt;Institute of Sports Medicine, Department of Orthopaedic Surgery M, &lt;span class=&quot;institution&quot;&gt;Bispebjerg Hospital&lt;/span&gt;, 2400 Copenhagen NV, Denmark;&lt;/address&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;aff&quot;&gt;
&lt;address&gt;&lt;sup&gt;d&lt;/sup&gt;Center for Healthy Aging, Department of Biomedical Sciences, Faculty of Health and Medical Sciences, &lt;span class=&quot;institution&quot;&gt;University of Copenhagen&lt;/span&gt;, 1165 Copenhagen, Denmark;&lt;/address&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;aff&quot;&gt;
&lt;address&gt;&lt;sup&gt;e&lt;/sup&gt;DTU Bio and Health Informatics, &lt;span class=&quot;institution&quot;&gt;Technical University of Denmark&lt;/span&gt;, 2800 Kongens Lyngby, Denmark;&lt;/address&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;aff&quot;&gt;
&lt;address&gt;&lt;sup&gt;f&lt;/sup&gt;Department of Pharmacy, Faculty of Health and Medical Sciences, &lt;span class=&quot;institution&quot;&gt;University of Copenhagen&lt;/span&gt;, 1165 Copenhagen, Denmark;&lt;/address&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;aff&quot;&gt;
&lt;address&gt;&lt;sup&gt;g&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;institution&quot;&gt;L'Université Nantes Angers Le Mans&lt;/span&gt; (LUNAM), Oniris, UMR 1329 INRA Laboratoire d'Etude des Résidus et Contaminants dans les Aliments (LABERCA), F-44307 Nantes, France;&lt;/address&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;aff&quot;&gt;
&lt;address&gt;&lt;sup&gt;h&lt;/sup&gt;Unité de coordination hospitalière des prélèvements d’organes et de tissus, Centre Hospitalier Universitaire de Rennes, 35000 Rennes, France;&lt;/address&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;aff&quot;&gt;
&lt;address&gt;&lt;sup&gt;i&lt;/sup&gt;Department of Odontology, Faculty of Health and Medical Sciences, &lt;span class=&quot;institution&quot;&gt;University of Copenhagen&lt;/span&gt;, 1165 Copenhagen, Denmark;&lt;/address&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;aff&quot;&gt;
&lt;address&gt;&lt;sup&gt;j&lt;/sup&gt;Department of Environmental Medicine, &lt;span class=&quot;institution&quot;&gt;University of Southern Denmark&lt;/span&gt;, 5000 Odense, Denmark;&lt;/address&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;aff&quot;&gt;
&lt;address&gt;&lt;sup&gt;k&lt;/sup&gt;Department of Biology, Faculty of Science, &lt;span class=&quot;institution&quot;&gt;University of Copenhagen&lt;/span&gt;, 2100 Copenhagen, Denmark;&lt;/address&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;aff&quot;&gt;
&lt;address&gt;&lt;sup&gt;l&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;institution&quot;&gt;Institute of Metagenomics&lt;/span&gt;, BGI-Shenzhen, Shenzhen 518083, China&lt;/address&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;ol class=&quot;fn-track&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;fn-edited-by&quot; id=&quot;fn-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-1&quot;&gt;Edited by David W. Russell, University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center, Dallas, TX, and approved December 1, 2017 (received for review August 31, 2017)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;executive-summary&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Significance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-5&quot;&gt;Concern has been raised over declining male reproductive health in humans. Our study addresses this issue by extending data showing antiandrogen effects of analgesics and suggests that such compounds may be involved in adult male reproductive problems. Using a unique combination of a randomized, controlled clinical trial and ex vivo and in vitro approaches, we report a univocal depression of important aspects of testicular function, including testosterone production, after use of over-the-counter ibuprofen. The study shows that ibuprofen use results in selective transcriptional repression of endocrine cells in the human testis. This repression results in the elevation of the stimulatory pituitary hormones, resulting in a state of compensated hypogonadism, a disorder associated with adverse reproductive and physical health disorders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section abstract&quot; id=&quot;abstract-2&quot;&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-6&quot;&gt;Concern has been raised over increased male reproductive disorders in the Western world, and the disruption of male endocrinology has been suggested to play a central role. Several studies have shown that mild analgesics exposure during fetal life is associated with antiandrogenic effects and congenital malformations, but the effects on the adult man remain largely unknown. Through a clinical trial with young men exposed to ibuprofen, we show that the analgesic resulted in the clinical condition named “compensated hypogonadism,&quot; a condition prevalent among elderly men and associated with reproductive and physical disorders. In the men, luteinizing hormone (LH) and ibuprofen plasma levels were positively correlated, and the testosterone/LH ratio decreased. Using adult testis explants exposed or not exposed to ibuprofen, we demonstrate that the endocrine capabilities from testicular Leydig and Sertoli cells, including testosterone production, were suppressed through transcriptional repression. This effect was also observed in a human steroidogenic cell line. Our data demonstrate that ibuprofen alters the endocrine system via selective transcriptional repression in the human testes, thereby inducing compensated hypogonadism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-7&quot; class=&quot;flushleft&quot;&gt;Much concern has been raised over declining male reproductive health, and the disruption of male endocrinology has been suggested to play a central role (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-1-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-1&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-2-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-2&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;). Male reproduction and general health rely on androgens, as well as on other hormones, which are mainly produced by testicular Leydig and Sertoli cells. In addition to the testis, the androgens act in many somatic organs, e.g., producing anabolic effects on muscle mass and influencing cognitive functions (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-3-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-3&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;). Luteinizing hormone (LH) produced by the pituitary is the primary stimulator of testosterone production, and the testosterone/LH ratio is routinely used as a clinical marker of Leydig cell function. When Leydig cell function is compromised, normal or nearly normal testosterone levels can often be sustained by augmented LH levels, as observed in the clinical entity termed “compensated hypogonadism” (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-4-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-4&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;). The essential importance of the pituitary–gonadal axis is emphasized by the recent association of hypogonadism with a wide range of risk factors and all-cause mortality in men (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-4-2&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-4&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-5-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-5&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-8&quot;&gt;The so-called “over-the-counter” mild analgesics (hereafter simply called “analgesics”), such as acetaminophen/paracetamol, acetylsalicylic acid/aspirin, and ibuprofen, are among the most commonly used pharmaceutical compounds worldwide (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-6-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-6&quot;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-7-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-7&quot;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;). Increasing evidence from recent years shows that exposure to analgesics can generate negative endocrine and reproductive effects during fetal life (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-6-2&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-6&quot;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;). Nonetheless, no in-depth studies have analyzed the effect of mild analgesics on the human pituitary–gonadal axis. In this context, ibuprofen is especially interesting because of its increasing use in the general population and in particular by elite athletes (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-8-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-8&quot;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-9-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-down-link&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-9&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;⇓&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-10-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-down-link&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-10&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;⇓&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-11-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-down-link&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-11&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;⇓&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;–&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-12-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-12&quot;&gt;12&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-9&quot;&gt;Therefore in this study we focused on how ibuprofen, used in the general population for aches, pains, fever, and arthritis and heavily used by athletes (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-13-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-13&quot;&gt;13&lt;/a&gt;), affects the pituitary–testis axis. Because of the intrinsic great challenge in identifying endocrine-disrupting effects of chemicals in the adult human, we performed a unique combination of three interconnected approaches: (&lt;em&gt;i&lt;/em&gt;) a randomized, controlled clinical trial; (&lt;em&gt;ii&lt;/em&gt;) an ex vivo organ model using adult human testis explants; and (&lt;em&gt;iii&lt;/em&gt;) a standardized in vitro model system based on a steroidogenic cell line of human origin to complement the ex vivo approach. The complementary results revealed that ibuprofen induces a state of compensated hypogonadism by modifying hormonal profiles through selective repression of gene expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section results&quot; id=&quot;sec-1&quot;&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;sec-2&quot; class=&quot;subsection&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Ibuprofen Affects the Hormonal Balance in Adult Men.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;h-lead h3-h-lead&quot; id=&quot;p-10&quot;&gt;We conducted a randomized, controlled clinical trial of ibuprofen administration to identify its possible effects on pituitary–gonadal feedback in young men. During administration, ibuprofen levels in plasma ranged on average from 25 to 35 µg/mL (∼1.2–1.7 × 10&lt;sup&gt;−4&lt;/sup&gt; M); the highest level measured was 100 µg/mL (4.85 × 10&lt;sup&gt;−4&lt;/sup&gt; M). The mean of this ibuprofen concentration was in the range measured after administration of 600 mg of ibuprofen to healthy volunteers (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-14-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-14&quot;&gt;14&lt;/a&gt;). Samples drawn before administration showed that there were no initial differences between the placebo and ibuprofen groups for hormones or sex hormone-binding globulin (SHBG), a liver protein that specifically binds a substantial part of circulating testosterone (&lt;a class=&quot;in-nw&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/lookup/suppl/doi:10.1073/pnas.1715035115/-/DCSupplemental/pnas.201715035SI.pdf?targetid=nameddest=SF1&quot;&gt;Fig. S1&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-11&quot;&gt;We investigated the levels of total testosterone and its direct downstream metabolic product, 17β-estradiol. Administration of ibuprofen did not result in any significant changes in the levels of these two steroid hormones after 14 d or at the last day of administration at 44 d (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-fig-1-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-fig&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#F1&quot;&gt;Fig. 1 &lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;C&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). The levels of free testosterone were subsequently analyzed by using the SHBG levels. Neither free testosterone nor SHBG levels were affected by ibuprofen during the administration (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-fig-1-2&quot; class=&quot;xref-fig&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#F1&quot;&gt;Fig. 1 &lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;C&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;F1&quot; class=&quot;fig pos-float type-featured odd&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fig-inline&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115/F1.expansion.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Fig. 1.&quot; src=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115/F1.small.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;callout&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;View larger version:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fig-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;fig-label&quot;&gt;Fig. 1.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-12&quot; class=&quot;first-child&quot;&gt;Ibuprofen increases gonadotropins and decreases AMH in adult men. (&lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt;–&lt;em&gt;D&lt;/em&gt;) Fold change in the Leydig cell–pituitary axis (&lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;C&lt;/em&gt;) and the Sertoli cell–pituitary axis (&lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;D&lt;/em&gt;) compared with baseline after 14 d (&lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt;) and at the end of the intervention after 44 d (&lt;em&gt;C&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;D&lt;/em&gt;). Values are means ± SEM, and differences were analyzed with an unpaired Student’s &lt;em&gt;t&lt;/em&gt; test. (&lt;em&gt;E&lt;/em&gt;) Correlation between absolute ibuprofen levels in plasma (&lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt; axis) and fold change in LH levels compared with baseline levels (&lt;em&gt;y&lt;/em&gt; axis) 14 d after intervention. The slope and &lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; value were calculated with a Pearson product-moment coefficient correlation. AMH, anti-Müllerian hormone; Free T, free testosterone; Inh B, inhibin B; SHBG, sex hormone-binding protein; Total T, total testosterone. *&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; ≤ 0.05, **&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; ≤ 0.01.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-13&quot;&gt;The pituitary gonadotropin hormones LH and FSH regulate the production of testosterone and peptide hormones by acting on Leydig and Sertoli cells, respectively. The levels of LH in the ibuprofen group had increased by 23% after 14 d of administration (&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; = 0.05) (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-fig-1-3&quot; class=&quot;xref-fig&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#F1&quot;&gt;Fig. 1&lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). This increase was even more pronounced at 44 d, at 33% (&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; = 0.01) (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-fig-1-4&quot; class=&quot;xref-fig&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#F1&quot;&gt;Fig. 1&lt;em&gt;C&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). While a slight, nonsignificant increase in the average FSH concentration was observed at 14 d (+5%) (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-fig-1-5&quot; class=&quot;xref-fig&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#F1&quot;&gt;Fig. 1&lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;), no difference in the average value of this hormone was seen at 44 d (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-fig-1-6&quot; class=&quot;xref-fig&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#F1&quot;&gt;Fig. 1&lt;em&gt;D&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). These data suggested a link between pituitary LH levels and ibuprofen exposure. This assumption was confirmed when we investigated ibuprofen and LH levels in plasma and found they were significantly and positively correlated at 14 d (&lt;em&gt;r&lt;/em&gt; = 0.73; &lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; = 0.003) (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-fig-1-7&quot; class=&quot;xref-fig&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#F1&quot;&gt;Fig. 1&lt;em&gt;E&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). We next calculated the free testosterone/LH ratio in the men. We found an 18% decrease (&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; = 0.056) in the ibuprofen group compared with the placebo group after 14 d (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-fig-1-8&quot; class=&quot;xref-fig&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#F1&quot;&gt;Fig. 1&lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) and a 23% decrease (&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; = 0.02) after 44 d (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-fig-1-9&quot; class=&quot;xref-fig&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#F1&quot;&gt;Fig. 1&lt;em&gt;C&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). Taken together, these in vivo data suggest that ibuprofen induced a state of compensated hypogonadism during the trial, which occurred as early as 14 d and was maintained until the end of the trial at 44 d.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-14&quot;&gt;Inhibin B and anti-Müllerian hormone (AMH) are peptide hormones secreted to the blood from the Sertoli cells. The administration of ibuprofen did not change mean inhibin B levels (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-fig-1-10&quot; class=&quot;xref-fig&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#F1&quot;&gt;Fig. 1 &lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;D&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). To examine the stimulatory action of FSH on the Sertoli cells, we next examined the inhibin B/FSH ratio and found that it decreased by 4% after 14 d (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-fig-1-11&quot; class=&quot;xref-fig&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#F1&quot;&gt;Fig. 1&lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) and by 12% at the end administration at 44 d (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-fig-1-12&quot; class=&quot;xref-fig&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#F1&quot;&gt;Fig. 1&lt;em&gt;D&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). Importantly, further investigation of Sertoli cell activity showed that AMH levels decreased significantly with ibuprofen administration, by 9% (&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; = 0.02) after 14 d (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-fig-1-13&quot; class=&quot;xref-fig&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#F1&quot;&gt;Fig. 1&lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) and by 7% (&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; = 0.05) after 44 d compared with the placebo group (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-fig-1-14&quot; class=&quot;xref-fig&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#F1&quot;&gt;Fig. 1&lt;em&gt;D&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). The AMH data show that the hypogonadism affected not only Leydig cells but also Sertoli cells and also occurred as early as 14 d of administration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;sec-3&quot; class=&quot;subsection&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Ibuprofen Inhibits Steroidogenesis ex Vivo and in Vitro.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;h-lead h3-h-lead&quot; id=&quot;p-15&quot;&gt;To determine the direct effect of ibuprofen on the testis, we next exposed adult testis explants from donors to doses of 10&lt;sup&gt;−9&lt;/sup&gt;–10&lt;sup&gt;−4&lt;/sup&gt; M, which corresponded to the oral doses producing mean plasma levels of 1.2–1.7 × 10&lt;sup&gt;−4&lt;/sup&gt; M used among the men in the trial (see above). We first investigated testosterone production after 24 and 48 h of ibuprofen exposure to assess its effects on Leydig cell steroidogenesis. Inhibition of testosterone levels was significant and dose-dependent (β = −0.405, &lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; = 0.01 at 24 h and β = −0.664, &lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.0001 at 48 h) (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-fig-2-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-fig&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#F2&quot;&gt;Fig. 2&lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) and was augmented over time (10&lt;sup&gt;−4&lt;/sup&gt; M at 24 h and 10&lt;sup&gt;−5&lt;/sup&gt;–10&lt;sup&gt;−4&lt;/sup&gt; M at 48 h, −40%) (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-fig-2-2&quot; class=&quot;xref-fig&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#F2&quot;&gt;Fig. 2&lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). Examination of the effect of ibuprofen exposure on both the ∆4 and ∆5 steroid pathways (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-fig-2-3&quot; class=&quot;xref-fig&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#F2&quot;&gt;Fig. 2&lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) showed that it generally inhibited all steroids from pregnenolone down to testosterone and 17β-estradiol; the production of each steroid measured decreased at doses of 10&lt;sup&gt;−5&lt;/sup&gt;–10&lt;sup&gt;−4&lt;/sup&gt; M. Under control conditions, production of androstenediol and dehydroepiandrosterone (DHEA) was below the limit of detection except in one experiment with DHEA (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-fig-2-4&quot; class=&quot;xref-fig&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#F2&quot;&gt;Fig. 2&lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;F2&quot; class=&quot;fig pos-float type-figure odd&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fig-inline&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115/F2.expansion.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Fig. 2.&quot; src=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115/F2.small.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;callout&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;View larger version:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fig-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;fig-label&quot;&gt;Fig. 2.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-16&quot; class=&quot;first-child&quot;&gt;Ibuprofen inhibits Leydig cell hormone production in human testicular explants. (&lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt;) Dose effect of ibuprofen for 24 and 48 h on testosterone production by the adult human testis. Values are means ± SEM of five independent experiments from different donors. Dose responses were analyzed for significance with the Mann–Whitney &lt;em&gt;U&lt;/em&gt; test. The slopes and &lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; values of these results were calculated with Spearman correlation. (&lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt;) Effect of 10&lt;sup&gt;−5&lt;/sup&gt; and 10&lt;sup&gt;−4&lt;/sup&gt; M ibuprofen on the Δ4 and Δ5 steroidogenic pathways. Steroid precursors were measured by GC-MS/MS. Values are means ± SEM of three independent experiments from different donors. Dose effects were analyzed for significance with the Mann–Whitney &lt;em&gt;U&lt;/em&gt; test. DHEA, dehydroepiandrosterone. (&lt;em&gt;C&lt;/em&gt;) Effect of 10&lt;sup&gt;−5&lt;/sup&gt; and 10&lt;sup&gt;−4&lt;/sup&gt; M ibuprofen on the gene expression of steroidogenic enzymes after 48-h exposure. Values are means ± SEM of five independent experiments from different donors. Each bar represents the mean ± SEM of the fold change in target gene expression relative to the reference genes &lt;em&gt;BZW1&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;GUSB&lt;/em&gt;. Dose responses were analyzed for significance with the Mann–Whitney &lt;em&gt;U&lt;/em&gt; test. (&lt;em&gt;D&lt;/em&gt;) Dose effect of ibuprofen for 24 and 48 h on INSL3 production by the adult human testis. Values are means ± SEM of three independent experiments from different donors. Dose responses were analyzed for significance with the Mann–Whitney &lt;em&gt;U&lt;/em&gt; test. (&lt;em&gt;E&lt;/em&gt;) Specific Leydig cell hormone gene expression. Values are means ± SEM of five independent experiments from different donors. Each bar represents the mean ± SEM of the fold change in target gene expression relative to the reference genes &lt;em&gt;BZW1&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;GUSB&lt;/em&gt;. Dose responses were analyzed for significance with the Mann–Whitney &lt;em&gt;U&lt;/em&gt; test. BZW1, basic leucine zipper and W2 domains 1; CYP11A1, cytochrome P450 family 11 subfamily A member 1; CYP17A1, cytochrome P450 family 17 subfamily A member 1; CYP19A1, cytochrome P450 family 19 subfamily A member 1; GUSB, β-glucuronidase; INSL3, insulin-like factor 3; HSD17B3, hydroxysteroid 17-β dehydrogenase 3; HSD3B2, hydroxy-δ-5-steroid dehydrogenase 3 β- and steroid δ-isomerase 2; LHCGR, luteinizing hormone/choriogonadotropin receptor; StAR, steroidogenic acute regulatory protein; TSPO: translocation protein. *&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; ≤ 0.05, **&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; ≤ 0.01.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-17&quot;&gt;We next examined the gene expression involved in testicular steroidogenesis ex vivo and found that levels of expression of every gene that we studied except &lt;em&gt;CYP19A1&lt;/em&gt; decreased after exposure for 48 h compared with controls (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-fig-2-5&quot; class=&quot;xref-fig&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#F2&quot;&gt;Fig. 2&lt;em&gt;C&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). Suppression of gene expression concerned the initial conversion of cholesterol to the final testosterone synthesis. Hence, expression of genes involved in cholesterol transport to the Leydig cell mitochondria was impaired: Compared with controls, &lt;em&gt;TSPO/BZRP&lt;/em&gt; fell significantly after exposure to 10&lt;sup&gt;−4&lt;/sup&gt; M; &lt;em&gt;StAR&lt;/em&gt; expression was suppressed at both doses of 10&lt;sup&gt;−5&lt;/sup&gt; and 10&lt;sup&gt;−4&lt;/sup&gt; M (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-fig-2-6&quot; class=&quot;xref-fig&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#F2&quot;&gt;Fig. 2&lt;em&gt;C&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;); &lt;em&gt;CYP11A1&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;CYP17A1&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;HSD17B3&lt;/em&gt; were suppressed by 40–50% at doses of 10&lt;sup&gt;−5&lt;/sup&gt;–10&lt;sup&gt;−4&lt;/sup&gt; M; and &lt;em&gt;HSD3B2&lt;/em&gt; was reduced by about 90%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-18&quot;&gt;The data from the ex vivo testis model showed inhibition of both the ∆4 and ∆5 steroid pathways. A previous study reported androsterone levels decreased by 63% among men receiving 400 mg of ibuprofen every 6 h for 4 wk (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-15-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-15&quot;&gt;15&lt;/a&gt;), suggesting a possible inhibitory effect on CYP17A1. We therefore exposed the NCI-H295R cells of human origin [which, although derived from the adrenal gland (instead of testis) and from a cancer originating in the cortex, are considered the best in vitro model of human steroidogenesis according to the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD) (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-16-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-16&quot;&gt;16&lt;/a&gt;)] to ibuprofen and, as a positive control, to the CYP17A1 antagonist abiraterone. The latter compound is clinically used as an androgen biosynthesis inhibitor (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-17-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-17&quot;&gt;17&lt;/a&gt;). Before testing ibuprofen’s action on steroidogenesis, we verified that none of the doses used had a toxic effect on the NCI-H295R cell line (&lt;a class=&quot;in-nw&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/lookup/suppl/doi:10.1073/pnas.1715035115/-/DCSupplemental/pnas.201715035SI.pdf?targetid=nameddest=SF2&quot;&gt;Fig. S2 &lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). This in vitro work confirmed the global antagonistic effect of abiraterone on CYP17A1 (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-fig-3-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-fig&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#F3&quot;&gt;Fig. 3&lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). In contrast, ibuprofen significantly decreased androstenedione and other sex steroid levels downstream from the CYP17A1 lyase activity, including testosterone (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-fig-3-2&quot; class=&quot;xref-fig&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#F3&quot;&gt;Fig. 3&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&quot;in-nw&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/lookup/suppl/doi:10.1073/pnas.1715035115/-/DCSupplemental/pnas.201715035SI.pdf?targetid=nameddest=ST1&quot;&gt;Table S1&lt;/a&gt;), complementing the results in the ex vivo testis model. These data therefore reveal that ibuprofen, unlike abiraterone, is not a general CYP17A1 antagonist. It is noteworthy that the NCI-295R cell line was less sensitive to ibuprofen than were the ex vivo cells in the organ model, likely due to its different origin (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-6-3&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-6&quot;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-18-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-18&quot;&gt;18&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;F3&quot; class=&quot;fig pos-float type-figure odd&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fig-inline&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115/F3.expansion.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Fig. 3.&quot; src=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115/F3.small.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;callout&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;View larger version:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fig-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;fig-label&quot;&gt;Fig. 3.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-19&quot; class=&quot;first-child&quot;&gt;The steroid screen identifies ibuprofen as an inhibitor of steroidogenesis in the human NCI-H295R cell line. (&lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt;) Effects of ibuprofen (red trace; &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; = 9–18) and abiraterone (blue trace; &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; = 6&lt;em&gt;–&lt;/em&gt;15) exposure on the relative steroidogenic hormone production in the dose ranges of 10&lt;sup&gt;−6&lt;/sup&gt;–10&lt;sup&gt;−3&lt;/sup&gt; M and 3.15 × 10&lt;sup&gt;−11&lt;/sup&gt;–3.15 × 10&lt;sup&gt;−6&lt;/sup&gt; M (&lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt; axis), respectively, in the human NCI-H295R cell line, according to OECD standards. The position of each graph corresponds to the position of that particular steroid hormone in steroidogenesis. Steroid concentrations (&lt;em&gt;y&lt;/em&gt; axis; % of control) are depicted as mean ± SEM with key enzymes shown in blue boxes. For statistics see &lt;a class=&quot;in-nw&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/lookup/suppl/doi:10.1073/pnas.1715035115/-/DCSupplemental/pnas.201715035SI.pdf?targetid=nameddest=ST1&quot;&gt;Table S1&lt;/a&gt;. (&lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt;–&lt;em&gt;D&lt;/em&gt;) Quantitative RT-PCR screen of steroidogenic gene expression in NCI-H295R cells after 48 h of culture with 10&lt;sup&gt;−7&lt;/sup&gt;–10&lt;sup&gt;−3&lt;/sup&gt; M ibuprofen. Values are means ± SEM of three independent experiments analyzed with one-way ANOVA followed by a post hoc Dunnett’s test. CYP11A1, cytochrome P450 family 11 subfamily A member 1; CYP17A1, cytochrome P450 family 17 subfamily A member 1; CYP19A1, cytochrome P450 family 19 subfamily A member 1; HSD17B3, hydroxysteroid 17-β dehydrogenase 3; HSD3B2, hydroxy-δ-5-steroid dehydrogenase 3 β- and steroid δ-isomerase 2; StAR, steroidogenic acute regulatory protein; TSPO, translocation protein. *&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; ≤ 0.05, **&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; ≤ 0.01, ***&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; ≤ 0.001.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-20&quot;&gt;Measuring the mRNA expression of genes involved in steroidogenesis in vitro showed that ibuprofen had a profound inhibitory effect on the expression of these genes (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-fig-3-3&quot; class=&quot;xref-fig&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#F3&quot;&gt;Fig. 3 &lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt;–&lt;em&gt;D&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;), consistent with that seen above in our ex vivo organ model. Taken together, these data examining effects on the endocrine cells confirm that ibuprofen-induced changes in the transcriptional machinery were the likely reason for the inhibition of steroidogenesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;sec-4&quot; class=&quot;subsection&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;h-p-wrap&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Ibuprofen Inhibits Leydig Cell Insulin-like Factor 3 in the Adult Human Testis ex Vivo.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;h-lead h3-h-lead&quot; id=&quot;p-21&quot;&gt;In addition to steroids, Leydig cells also produce insulin-like factor 3 (INSL3) (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-19-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-19&quot;&gt;19&lt;/a&gt;). Its production increased at 24 h at the 10&lt;sup&gt;−9&lt;/sup&gt; M dose and subsequently decreased at the 10&lt;sup&gt;−7&lt;/sup&gt; M dose (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-fig-2-7&quot; class=&quot;xref-fig&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#F2&quot;&gt;Fig. 2&lt;em&gt;D&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). These variations were transient, with no significant effect of ibuprofen observed after 48 h. &lt;em&gt;INSL3&lt;/em&gt; expression decreased by 50% at a dose of 10&lt;sup&gt;−4&lt;/sup&gt; M, but expression of the LH receptor, luteinizing hormone/choriogonadotropin receptor (&lt;em&gt;LHCGR&lt;/em&gt;), which is also Leydig cell specific, was not repressed (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-fig-2-8&quot; class=&quot;xref-fig&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#F2&quot;&gt;Fig. 2&lt;em&gt;E&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). Nonetheless, overall the changes in gene expression indicate that the transcriptional machinery behind the endocrine action of Leydig cells was most likely impaired by ibuprofen exposure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;sec-5&quot; class=&quot;subsection&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Ibuprofen Impairs Sertoli Cell Function in the Adult Human Testis ex Vivo.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;h-lead h3-h-lead&quot; id=&quot;p-22&quot;&gt;Data from the trial showed that ibuprofen affected Sertoli cells, inhibiting AMH and decreasing the inhibin B/FSH ratio. Ex vivo, increasing doses of ibuprofen resulted in an inverse correlation with inhibin B after 24 h (β = −0.467; &lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; = 0.01), although none of the individual ibuprofen concentrations significantly inhibited this hormone (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-fig-4-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-fig&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#F4&quot;&gt;Fig. 4&lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). After 48 h of exposure, however, ibuprofen doses of 10&lt;sup&gt;−7&lt;/sup&gt;–10&lt;sup&gt;−4&lt;/sup&gt; M significantly decreased inhibin B production, resulting in a further significant negative association between ibuprofen concentrations and inhibin B (β = −0.739, &lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.0001). AMH production was also negatively correlated with increasing ibuprofen concentration (β = −0.451; &lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; = 0.01) (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-fig-4-2&quot; class=&quot;xref-fig&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#F4&quot;&gt;Fig. 4&lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). Accordingly, a dose of 10&lt;sup&gt;−4&lt;/sup&gt; M repressed gene expression of &lt;em&gt;AMH&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;INHBB&lt;/em&gt; by ∼35% (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-fig-4-3&quot; class=&quot;xref-fig&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#F4&quot;&gt;Fig. 4&lt;em&gt;C&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). Together, these data show that ibuprofen also directly impairs Sertoli cell function ex vivo by inhibiting transcription. Of note, no significant changes were found in the gene expression of the Sertoli cell-specific FSH receptor (&lt;em&gt;FSH-R&lt;/em&gt;) or of &lt;em&gt;LAMA5&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-fig-4-4&quot; class=&quot;xref-fig&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#F4&quot;&gt;Fig. 4&lt;em&gt;C&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;F4&quot; class=&quot;fig pos-float type-figure odd&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fig-inline&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115/F4.expansion.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Fig. 4.&quot; src=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115/F4.small.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;callout&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;View larger version:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fig-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;fig-label&quot;&gt;Fig. 4.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-23&quot; class=&quot;first-child&quot;&gt;Ibuprofen affects Sertoli cell activity in human testicular explants. (&lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt;) Dose effect of ibuprofen on the production of inhibin B after 24 and 48 h (&lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt;) and anti-Müllerian hormone (AMH) after 48 h (&lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt;) by the adult human testis. Values are means ± SEM of three independent experiments from different donors. Slopes and &lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; values of Spearman correlation are indicated. (&lt;em&gt;C&lt;/em&gt;) Quantitative RT-PCR performed after 48 h of culture treated with 10&lt;sup&gt;−5&lt;/sup&gt; and 10&lt;sup&gt;−4&lt;/sup&gt; M ibuprofen for specific Sertoli cell gene expression. Values are means ± SEM of five independent experiments from different donors. Each bar represents the mean ± SEM of the fold change in target gene expression relative to the reference genes &lt;em&gt;BZW1&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;GUSB&lt;/em&gt;. Dose responses were analyzed for significance with the Mann–Whitney &lt;em&gt;U&lt;/em&gt; test. AMH, anti-Müllerian hormone; BZW1, basic leucine zipper and W2 domains 1; FSHR, follicle-stimulating hormone receptor; GUSB, β-glucuronidase; INHBB, inhibin B subunit B; LAMA5, laminin subunit α5. *&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; ≤ 0.05, **&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; ≤ 0.01.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;sec-6&quot; class=&quot;subsection&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Ibuprofen Selectively Affects Peritubular Cells’ Gene Expression in the Adult Human Testis ex Vivo.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;h-lead h3-h-lead&quot; id=&quot;p-24&quot;&gt;Peritubular cells lining the seminiferous wall play an important role in sustaining seminiferous tubule function (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-20-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-20&quot;&gt;20&lt;/a&gt;). The peritubular cells are not broadly characterized in terms of specific markers. Nevertheless, we investigated the expression of a few genes that are assigned to these cells. We found that ibuprofen selectively repressed &lt;em&gt;ACTA2&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;MYH-11&lt;/em&gt; by 50%, but two other peritubular cell markers, &lt;em&gt;THY1&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;KCNIP4&lt;/em&gt;, did not change significantly (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-fig-5-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-fig&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#F5&quot;&gt;Fig. 5&lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;F5&quot; class=&quot;fig pos-float type-figure odd&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fig-inline&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115/F5.expansion.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Fig. 5.&quot; src=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115/F5.small.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;callout&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;View larger version:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fig-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;fig-label&quot;&gt;Fig. 5.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-25&quot; class=&quot;first-child&quot;&gt;Ibuprofen decreases gene expression in peritubular cells but does not affect germ cells or morphology in human testicular explants. (&lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt;) Quantitative RT-PCR performed after 48 h of culture treated with 10&lt;sup&gt;−5&lt;/sup&gt; and 10&lt;sup&gt;−4&lt;/sup&gt; M ibuprofen for gene expression in peritubular cells (&lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt;) and germ cells (&lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt;). Each bar represents the mean ± SEM of the fold change in target gene expression relative to the reference genes &lt;em&gt;BZW1&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;GUSB&lt;/em&gt;. Values are means ± SEM of five independent experiments from different donors. A Mann–Whitney &lt;em&gt;U&lt;/em&gt; test was performed. (&lt;em&gt;C&lt;/em&gt;) Number of apoptotic germ cells. Values are means ± SEM of caspase&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; cells in three independent experiments from different donors. (&lt;em&gt;D&lt;/em&gt;) Immunostaining of apoptotic germ cells in testis explants cultured for 48 h in the presence of DMSO (control) or 10&lt;sup&gt;−5&lt;/sup&gt; or 10&lt;sup&gt;−4&lt;/sup&gt; M ibuprofen. Each micrograph shows representative areas of ibuprofen-induced morphology compared with corresponding area. (Scale bars: 50 µm.) ACTA2, actin α2 smooth muscle aorta; ALPP, alkaline phosphatase, placental; BZW1, basic leucine zipper and W2 domains 1; GUSB, β-glucuronidase; KCNIP4, potassium voltage-gated channel interacting protein 4; MYH11, myosin heavy polypeptide 11, smooth muscle; PGK2, phosphoglycerate kinase 2; PRM2, protamine 2; THY1, Thy-1 cell-surface antigen. **&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; ≤ 0.01.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;sec-7&quot; class=&quot;subsection&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;h-p-wrap&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Ibuprofen Spares the Spermatogenic Cells in the Adult Human Testis ex Vivo.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;h-lead h3-h-lead&quot; id=&quot;p-26&quot;&gt;Turning our attention to germ cells in the explants, we found no significant changes in the expression of genes involved specifically with spermatogenesis (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-fig-5-2&quot; class=&quot;xref-fig&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#F5&quot;&gt;Fig. 5&lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). The absence of a change in the germ cell complement by ibuprofen was confirmed by staining for caspase 3 after 48 h of exposure: Apoptosis did not increase significantly in the testis after exposure (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-fig-5-3&quot; class=&quot;xref-fig&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#F5&quot;&gt;Fig. 5 &lt;em&gt;C&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;D&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;), and the histopathology of the testis at the highest doses did not differ from that of controls (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-fig-5-4&quot; class=&quot;xref-fig&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#F5&quot;&gt;Fig. 5&lt;em&gt;D&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;sec-8&quot; class=&quot;subsection&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Ibuprofen Suppresses Prostaglandin Production in the Adult Human Testis ex Vivo and in Vitro.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;h-lead h3-h-lead&quot; id=&quot;p-27&quot;&gt;As ibuprofen acts specifically on COX sites of prostaglandin H2 synthase (prostaglandin endoperoxide synthase or prostaglandin G/H synthase and cyclooxygenase, PTGS), and because prostaglandin receptors and synthesizing enzymes are widely distributed within the testis (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-21-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-21&quot;&gt;21&lt;/a&gt;), we investigated prostaglandin D2 (PGD2) and E2 (PGE2) in our culture system. Ibuprofen produced a significant dose-dependent reduction of PGD2 (β = −0.781; &lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.0001 at 24 h and β = −0.797; &lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.0001 at 48 h) (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-fig-6-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-fig&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#F6&quot;&gt;Fig. 6&lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) and of PGE2 (β = −0.707; &lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.0001 and β = −0.627; &lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.0001, respectively) (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-fig-6-2&quot; class=&quot;xref-fig&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#F6&quot;&gt;Fig. 6&lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;em&gt;PTGS1&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;PTGS2&lt;/em&gt; gene expression decreased similarly: &lt;em&gt;PTGS1&lt;/em&gt; mRNA levels fell significantly by 24 and 48 h (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-fig-6-3&quot; class=&quot;xref-fig&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#F6&quot;&gt;Fig. 6&lt;em&gt;C&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;), and &lt;em&gt;PTGS2&lt;/em&gt; mRNA was significantly repressed after 48 h of exposure. These ex vivo data show that ibuprofen suppressed both PTGS enzyme activity and &lt;em&gt;PTGS&lt;/em&gt; gene expression in the adult testis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;F6&quot; class=&quot;fig pos-float type-figure odd&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fig-inline&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115/F6.expansion.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Fig. 6.&quot; src=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115/F6.small.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;callout&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;View larger version:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fig-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;fig-label&quot;&gt;Fig. 6.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-28&quot; class=&quot;first-child&quot;&gt;Ibuprofen decreases PGE2 and PGD2 production and PTGS gene expression in human testicular explants. (&lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt;) Dose effect of ibuprofen exposure after 24 and 48 h on PGD2 (&lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt;) and PGE2 (&lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt;) production by adult human testicular explants. Values are means ± SEM of five independent experiments from different donors. Dose responses were analyzed for significance with the Mann–Whitney &lt;em&gt;U&lt;/em&gt; test. Slopes and &lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; values of Spearman correlation are indicated. (&lt;em&gt;C&lt;/em&gt;) Quantitative RT-PCR was performed after 48 h of culture treated with 10&lt;sup&gt;−5&lt;/sup&gt; and 10&lt;sup&gt;−4&lt;/sup&gt; M ibuprofen. Each bar represents the mean ± SEM of the fold change in target gene expression relative to the reference genes &lt;em&gt;BZW1&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;GUSB&lt;/em&gt;. Values are means ± SEM of five independent experiments from different donors. Differences in gene expression were analyzed with a Mann–Whitney &lt;em&gt;U&lt;/em&gt; test. BZW1, basic leucine zipper and W2 domains 1; GUSB, β-glucuronidase; PTGS, prostaglandin-endoperoxide synthase. *&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; ≤ 0.05, **&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; ≤ 0.01.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-29&quot;&gt;To complement our ex vivo model system, we next screened the human NCI-H295R cell line for prostaglandin production. This screen showed that the NCI-H295R cells produced detectable levels of prostaglandins, which were decreased dose dependently with ibuprofen (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-fig-7-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-fig&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#F7&quot;&gt;Fig. 7&lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). As also shown in the experiments presented above, ibuprofen decreased the expression of PTGS1 and PTGS2 in the NCI-H295R cell line (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-fig-7-2&quot; class=&quot;xref-fig&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#F7&quot;&gt;Fig. 7&lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;F7&quot; class=&quot;fig pos-float type-figure odd&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fig-inline&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115/F7.expansion.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Fig. 7.&quot; src=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115/F7.small.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;callout&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;View larger version:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fig-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;fig-label&quot;&gt;Fig. 7.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-30&quot; class=&quot;first-child&quot;&gt;Ibuprofen dose-dependently reduces prostaglandin levels and mRNA expression in human endocrine NCI-H295R cells. (&lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt;) Effects of ibuprofen on general prostaglandin production from NCI-H295R cells after 24 h. Values are means ± SEM of three independent experiments analyzed with one-way ANOVA followed by a post hoc Dunnett’s test. (&lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt;) Quantitative RT-PCR screen of steroidogenic and &lt;em&gt;PTGS&lt;/em&gt; gene expression in NCI-H295R cells after 48 h of culture with 10&lt;sup&gt;−7&lt;/sup&gt;–10&lt;sup&gt;−3&lt;/sup&gt; M ibuprofen. Values are means ± SEM of three independent experiments analyzed with one-way ANOVA followed by a post hoc Dunnett’s test. PTGS, prostaglandin-endoperoxide synthase. *&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; ≤ 0.05, **&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; ≤ 0.01.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section discussion&quot; id=&quot;sec-9&quot;&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Discussion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-31&quot; class=&quot;flushleft&quot;&gt;The pituitary–gonadal axis plays key roles in growth, sex development, metabolism, musculoskeletal build-up, strength, mood, energy, immune system, libido, and reproduction (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-22-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-22&quot;&gt;22&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-23-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-down-link&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-23&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;⇓&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;–&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-24-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-24&quot;&gt;24&lt;/a&gt;). Fluctuations in or impaired fine-tuning of the axis can result in a wide range of endocrine disorders that may be local but severe, e.g., infertility (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-25-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-25&quot;&gt;25&lt;/a&gt;), or affect the entire body, as seen with adverse outcomes involving this axis such as sexual symptoms (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-4-3&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-4&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;), depression (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-26-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-26&quot;&gt;26&lt;/a&gt;), coronary heart disease/heart attack (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-27-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-27&quot;&gt;27&lt;/a&gt;), autoimmune diseases such as arthritis (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-28-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-28&quot;&gt;28&lt;/a&gt;), and diabetes (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-29-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-29&quot;&gt;29&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-30-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-30&quot;&gt;30&lt;/a&gt;). Testosterone forms a negative feedback loop that inhibits the production of both LH and gonadotropin-releasing hormone (GnRH) in the hypothalamus (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-31-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-31&quot;&gt;31&lt;/a&gt;). While testosterone plays multiple roles outside the testes, the extratesticular actions of inhibin B are more subtle, working primarily to decrease FSH (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-32-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-32&quot;&gt;32&lt;/a&gt;). Nonetheless, inhibin B is a key clinical marker of reproductive health (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-32-2&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-32&quot;&gt;32&lt;/a&gt;). The function of AMH, also secreted by Sertoli cells, and its regulation through FSH remain unclear in men (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-33-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-33&quot;&gt;33&lt;/a&gt;). It has, however, been shown that the AMH concentrations are lower in seminal plasma from patients with azoospermia than from men with normal sperm levels (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-32-3&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-32&quot;&gt;32&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-32&quot;&gt;Our trial showed that ibuprofen use in men led to (&lt;em&gt;i&lt;/em&gt;) elevation of LH; (&lt;em&gt;ii&lt;/em&gt;) a decreased testosterone/LH ratio and, to a lesser degree, a decreased inhibin B/FSH ratio; and (&lt;em&gt;iii&lt;/em&gt;) a reduction in the levels of the Sertoli cell hormone AMH. The decrease in the free testosterone/LH ratio resulted primarily from the increased LH levels, revealing that testicular responsiveness to gonadotropins likely declined during the ibuprofen exposure. Our data from the ex vivo experiments support this notion, indicating that the observed elevation in LH resulted from ibuprofen’s direct antiandrogenic action. Accordingly, in the trial the average inhibin B levels did not differ significantly in the ibuprofen-treated men and the control group. This is consistent with a previous report that men who volunteered to take another nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drug (NSAID), acetylsalicylic acid, coadministered with human chorionic gonadotropin (hCG), which mimics LH, had lower levels of steroidal hormones than controls exposed to hCG but not to the analgesic (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-34-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-34&quot;&gt;34&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-33&quot;&gt;AMH levels were consistently suppressed by ibuprofen both in vivo and ex vivo, indicating that this hormone is uncoupled from gonadotropins in adult men. The ibuprofen suppression of AMH further demonstrated that the analgesic targeted not only the Leydig cells but also the Sertoli cells, a feature encountered not only in the human adult testis but also in the fetal testis (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-35-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-35&quot;&gt;35&lt;/a&gt;). It is noteworthy that ibuprofen repressed the expression of both &lt;em&gt;AMH&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;INHBB&lt;/em&gt; as well as genes encoding essential proteins and enzymes involved in both cholesterol transport and steroidogenesis. Thus, ibuprofen displayed broad transcription-repression abilities involving steroidogenesis, peptide hormones, and prostaglandin synthesis. However, these repressive abilities were selective, as a number of gene-expression patterns were spared by ibuprofen, namely prostaglandin inhibition in Leydig cells (&lt;em&gt;CYP19A1&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;LHCGR&lt;/em&gt;), Sertoli cells (&lt;em&gt;LAMA5&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;FSHR&lt;/em&gt;), peritubular cells (&lt;em&gt;KCNIP4&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;THY1&lt;/em&gt;), and all those investigated in germ cells. Of note, the absence of an effect of ibuprofen on the expression levels of gonadotropin receptor genes (&lt;em&gt;LHCGR&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;FSHR&lt;/em&gt;) indicates that the responsiveness of Leydig cells and Sertoli cells to the action of LH and FSH is likely not affected by ibuprofen. However, more investigation is required at this level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-34&quot;&gt;Several compounds have been found to have unintentional antiandrogenic effects, and these are normally investigated in connection with fetal male development using rodent models (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-36-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-36&quot;&gt;36&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-37-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-37&quot;&gt;37&lt;/a&gt;). Our approach, using ibuprofen as an example, demonstrates how a chemical compound, through its effects on the signaling compounds, can result in changes in the testis at gene level, resulting in perturbations at higher physiological levels in the adult human. The analgesics acetaminophen/paracetamol and ibuprofen have previously been shown to inhibit the postexercise response in muscles by repressing transcription (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-38-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-38&quot;&gt;38&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-39-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-down-link&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-39&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;⇓&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;–&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-40-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-40&quot;&gt;40&lt;/a&gt;). However, the striking dual effect of ibuprofen observed here on both Leydig and Sertoli cells makes this NSAID the chemical compound, of all the chemical classes considered, with the broadest endocrine-disturbing properties identified so far in men. Previous ex vivo studies on adult testis have indeed pointed to an antiandrogenicity, only on Leydig cells, of phthalates (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-41-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-41&quot;&gt;41&lt;/a&gt;), aspirin, indomethacin (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-42-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-42&quot;&gt;42&lt;/a&gt;), and bisphenol A (BPA) and its analogs (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-43-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-43&quot;&gt;43&lt;/a&gt;). However, ibuprofen’s effects were not restricted to Leydig and Sertoli cells, as data showed that the expression of genes in peritubular cells was also affected. Previous studies have shown that long-term fetal exposure to acetaminophen and acetylsalicylic acid in mice and rats targets primordial germ cell proliferation by blocking RNA synthesis and thus leads to reduced follicle reservoir and subsequent decreased fertility in adulthood (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-44-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-44&quot;&gt;44&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-45-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-down-link&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-45&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;⇓&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;–&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-46-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-46&quot;&gt;46&lt;/a&gt;). By contrast, in the present study using human testes, germ cells were the only cell category not altered by this analgesic in our ex vivo culture conditions. However, it must be noted that our ex vivo model systems can be used only for short-term exposure. Therefore, determining the effect on men that sustained exposure to ibuprofen would generate in terms of sperm production and fertility would require designing specific and challenging experiment(s). It is noteworthy that exposure to analgesics in men has been associated with increased time to pregnancy (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-47-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-47&quot;&gt;47&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-35&quot;&gt;An important question is the exact relationship between the prostaglandin-inhibitory actions of ibuprofen and its effects on testosterone and gene expression. This has been investigated previously in studies on rodent and human testicular development, which showed no correlation between the endocrine-disruptive effects of analgesics and their prostaglandin-inhibitory actions (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-6-4&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-6&quot;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-48-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-48&quot;&gt;48&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-49-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-49&quot;&gt;49&lt;/a&gt;). However, in the present study using testes from adult men, the suppression of androgens and prostaglandins occurred in parallel, and, because for several decades prostaglandins have been known to be involved in male reproduction (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-50-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-50&quot;&gt;50&lt;/a&gt;), a link between the endocrine-disruptive properties of ibuprofen and the prostaglandin-inhibitory action of NSAIDs in the adult testis cannot be excluded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-36&quot;&gt;In the clinical setting, compromised Leydig cell function resulting in increased insensitivity to LH is defined as compensated hypogonadism (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-4-4&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-4&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;), an entity associated with all-cause mortality (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-5-2&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-5&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;). Therefore, investigating ibuprofen-induced compensatory hypogonadism is crucial, as this clinical state is generally associated with smoking and aging (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-4-5&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-4&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-51-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-51&quot;&gt;51&lt;/a&gt;). Moreover, compensated hypogonadic men present with an increased likelihood of reproductive, cognitive, and physical symptoms (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-4-6&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-4&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-52-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-52&quot;&gt;52&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-53-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-down-link&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-53&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;⇓&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;–&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-54-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-54&quot;&gt;54&lt;/a&gt;). Further characterizations of the state of compensated hypogonadism induced by ibuprofen, which was already established after 14 d of ibuprofen administration, are therefore important in determining the potential effects on healthy young men. Several reports have stressed the high level of long-term analgesic use among both amateur (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-55-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-55&quot;&gt;55&lt;/a&gt;) and professional athletes; ibuprofen has been favored in this use and abuse (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-56-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-56&quot;&gt;56&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-57-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-down-link&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-57&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;⇓&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-58-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-down-link&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-58&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;⇓&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;–&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-59-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-59&quot;&gt;59&lt;/a&gt;). Of note, an inverse relationship was recently reported between endurance exercise training and male sexual libido, but the possibility that medication uptake might interfere in this observation could not be totally excluded (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-22-2&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-22&quot;&gt;22&lt;/a&gt;). Moreover, ibuprofen appears to be the preferred pharmaceutical analgesic for long-term chronic pain and arthritis (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-60-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-60&quot;&gt;60&lt;/a&gt;). Therefore it is also of concern that men with compensated hypogonadism may eventually progress to overt primary hypogonadism, which is characterized by low circulating testosterone and prevalent symptoms including reduced libido, reduced muscle mass and strength, and depressed mood and fatigue (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-4-7&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-4&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-60-2&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-60&quot;&gt;60&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-61-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-61&quot;&gt;61&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section materials-methods&quot; id=&quot;sec-10&quot;&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Materials and Methods&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;sec-11&quot; class=&quot;subsection&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;In Vivo Intervention Trial.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;sec-12&quot; class=&quot;subsection&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Design and participants.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;h-lead h4-h-lead&quot; id=&quot;p-37&quot;&gt;The in vivo study was designed as a double-blinded, placebo-controlled, randomized intervention trial in which ibuprofen or placebo was administered to subjects for 2 wk before and 30 d after a single exercise session. Staff not involved in the project prepared and distributed the medication in boxes weekly. Study personnel and participants were blinded to treatment, and all later analyses were performed blinded to the treatment type, participant, and time point. The study was part of a broader investigation also focusing on muscle biopsies, collected on days 0, 2, 7, and 30 postexercise, a subset of which is described elsewhere (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-62-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-62&quot;&gt;62&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-38&quot;&gt;The study protocol was in compliance with the Helsinki Declaration, was approved by the Regional Scientific Ethical Committees of Copenhagen in Denmark (Ref: HD-2008-074), and was registered at &lt;a href=&quot;http://ClinicalTrials.gov&quot; class=&quot;in-nw&quot;&gt;ClinicalTrials.gov&lt;/a&gt; (no. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/external-ref?link_type=CLINTRIALGOV&amp;amp;access_num=NCT00832663&quot;&gt;NCT00832663&lt;/a&gt;). The study recruited 31 healthy white men, age 18–35 y. Subjects were included after an interview, a questionnaire assessing physical activity status, and the results of a screening blood sample. Exclusion criteria included body mass index above 30, knee injuries, peptic ulcers, signs of liver or kidney dysfunction, and participation in regular physical activity (especially strength training) apart from cycling as a means of transport. All individuals provided written informed consent to participate in the study. Subsequently, the subjects were assigned to either a placebo (17 subjects) or ibuprofen (14 subjects) group; the groups were matched for age, height, and weight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;sec-13&quot; class=&quot;subsection&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;h-p-wrap&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Supplementation.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;h-lead h4-h-lead&quot; id=&quot;p-39&quot;&gt;One group of subjects received ibuprofen, 2 × 600 mg/d, (Ibumetin; Nycomed Denmark Aps) for a period of 6 wk, from 14 d before to 4 wk after the electrical stimulation exercise. Ibuprofen was detected only in participants to whom ibuprofen was distributed and only after administration began. The second group received placebo pills (which were visually indistinguishable from the ibuprofen pills) over the same period. Subjects received the medication in Medidos No. 1 boxes (KiBodan A/S), which were refilled every week. To verify compliance, ibuprofen levels in the blood were determined by HPLC at every blood-sampling time point (see below). Additionally, to monitor liver and kidney function, blood samples were analyzed for creatine, C-reactive protein, alkaline phosphates, and total cholesterol during the study. No subjects reported any adverse signs of taking the medication, nor did any blood parameters indicate or suggest adverse effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;sec-14&quot; class=&quot;subsection&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;h-p-wrap&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Blood samples and hormonal analysis.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;h-lead h4-h-lead&quot; id=&quot;p-40&quot;&gt;A 40-mL blood sample was collected from the antecubital vein of the nondominant arm when subjects arrived at the laboratory for screening. Samples were also taken at 3 and 2 wk before exercise (days −21 and −14), on the day of exercise before the exercise (day 0), after exercise (+2 h; day 0.1), and subsequently at 2, 4, 7, and 30 d after exercise. Hence, ibuprofen and placebo administration was ongoing for samples drawn on day 0, 0+2 h, 2, 4, 7, and 30. In the present study, we focused on samples drawn on day 0 after 14 d of supplementation. Plasma samples were stored at −80 °C until being assayed. The samples were analyzed for LH, FSH, testosterone, 17β-estradiol, AMH, inhibin B, and SHBG, as previously described in Aksglaede et al. (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-63-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-63&quot;&gt;63&lt;/a&gt;), and ibuprofen as previously described in Farrar et al. (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-64-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-64&quot;&gt;64&lt;/a&gt;). Of note, the LH measurements of one subject in the placebo group were aberrant and were discarded, thus decreasing the &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; value from 17 to 16.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;sec-15&quot; class=&quot;subsection&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Ex Vivo Organ Model: Testis Explant Assay.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;h-lead h3-h-lead&quot; id=&quot;p-41&quot;&gt;To determine the direct effect of ibuprofen on adult human testis physiology, we used a validated organ model assay (Testis Explant Assay) (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-65-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-65&quot;&gt;65&lt;/a&gt;). Testes were obtained from prostate cancer patients who had not undergone any antihormonal treatment or from multiorgan donors (average age 46.9 ± 4.4 y). The protocol was approved by the local ethics committee (Agence de la Biomédine; authorization no. PFS09-015), and informed consent was obtained from all donors or their next of kin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-42&quot;&gt;After collection of each testis, the organ was placed at 4 °C and rapidly processed for experimentation. Observation by transillumination allowed us to discard the rare testes not displaying spermatogenesis. Four 3-mm&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; testis explants were placed onto a polyethylene terephthalate insert (Falcon Labware) at the interface of air in 1 mL of DMEM (Sigma-Aldrich) in a well of a 12-well plate. The medium for exposure experiments contained 0.1% DMSO as a control and ibuprofen at different concentrations (purity &amp;gt;99%) (Sigma-Aldrich) in 0.1% DMSO. Four wells were analyzed for each condition. Exposures lasted 24 or 48 h, with a total medium change at 24 h, in a humidified atmosphere containing 5% CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; at 34 °C. The culture medium was then collected and stored at −80 °C. On the day of collection, three testis explants for each culture condition were randomly selected and fixed in neutral buffer, 4% formaldehyde, or Bouin’s fixative for 2 h at 4 °C, embedded in paraffin, sliced into 5.0-µm-thick sections, and stored at 4 °C until immunostaining.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-43&quot;&gt;Hormone levels were assayed in duplicate in the culture medium. Testosterone levels were assayed with a specific RIA (Beckman Coulter). The intra- and interassay coefficients of variation were ≤8.6 and 11.9%, respectively. Control testis explants produced an average of 10.26 ± 2.50 ng testosterone per milliliter of explant after 24 h of culture and 8.47 ± 2.16 ng testosterone per milliliter of explant after 48 h of culture. INSL3 production was assayed with a commercial RIA (Phoenix France). Each sample was diluted twofold in RIA buffer before RIA. The intra- and interassay coefficients of variation were ≤15 and 7%, respectively, and the lower limit of detection was 20.17 pg/mL. Control testis explants produced an average of 0.29 ± 0.25 ng INSL3 per milliliter of explant after 24 h of culture and 0.20 ± 0.21 ng INSL3 per milliliter of explant after 48 h of culture. Inhibin B was assayed with a commercial ELISA kit (Beckman Coulter) according to the manufacturer’s instructions. Each sample was diluted twofold in sample diluent solution before reactions. The intra- and interassay coefficients of variation for serum samples were ≤5.6 and 7.6%, respectively. Control testis explants produced an average of 570.43 ± 78.50 ng inhibin B per milliliter of explant after 24 h of culture and 529.44 ± 79.17 ng inhibin B per milliliter of explant after 48 h of culture. PGD2 and prostaglandin E2 (PGE2) were assayed by an ELISA method (Cayman Chemical Company), as was AMH (Immunotech).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-44&quot;&gt;RNA was extracted from testes with the NucleoSpin RNA II kit (Macherey-Nagel) according to the manufacturer’s instructions and then was precipitated. Each total RNA sample (250 ng) was reverse transcribed with the Iscript cDNA Synthesis Kit (Bio-Rad). Quantitative PCR was performed according to the manufacturer’s instructions with iTaq Universal SYBR Green Supermix (Bio-Rad) and a 2.5-µL cDNA template in a CFX384 Touch Real-Time PCR Detection System (Bio-Rad). The amplification program was as follows: an initial denaturation of 3 min at 95 °C; 40 cycles of 10-s denaturation at 95 °C; and 30 s at 62 °C for annealing and extension. Dissociation curves were produced with the thermal melting profile performed after the last PCR cycle. To avoid amplification of contaminating genomic DNA, primer pairs were selected on two different exons. Bzw1 and GusB mRNA were used as internal controls for normalization. Results were calculated by the ΔΔCT method as &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt;-fold differences in target gene expression with respect to the reference gene and the calibration sample.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-45&quot;&gt;To analyze steroidogenesis in the explants, we performed solid-phase extraction (SPE) with C18 cartridges, reagents, and solvents from Solvent Documentation Synthesis. Standard reference steroids were from Sigma. Deuterated internal standards were from Steraloids. Quantification was performed by isotopic dilution. Samples were spiked with 400 pg of internal standards (etiocholanolone-d5, 17a-testosterone-d3, dihydrotestosterone-d3, 19-androstenedione-d3, progesterone-d9, 17a-methyltestosterone-d3, and 17b-estradiol-d3). Samples were applied to a C18 SPE column (2 g stationary phase) previously conditioned with 10 mL methanol and 10 mL water. The column was washed with water (5 mL) and then with cyclohexane (5 mL), and the steroids were eluted with methanol (10 mL). The extracts were dried (N2, 458C), and 400 pg of external standard (norgestrel) was added. Derivatization procedures and measurements in GC-MS/MS in electronization mode were performed as previously described (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-66-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-66&quot;&gt;66&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-67-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-67&quot;&gt;67&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-46&quot;&gt;Cells were labeled with the primary rabbit antibody directed against cleaved caspase-3 (1/100; Cell Signaling) (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-41-2&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-41&quot;&gt;41&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-42-2&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-42&quot;&gt;42&lt;/a&gt;) to enable detection of cells undergoing apoptosis in the explants. Slides were then scanned with a NanoZoomer slide scanner (Hamamatsu Photonics). Caspase-3&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; cells were counted by ImageJ software, and the results were expressed as percentages of the control values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;sec-16&quot; class=&quot;subsection&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;In Vitro: NCI-H295R Cell Line.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;h-lead h3-h-lead&quot; id=&quot;p-47&quot;&gt;The NCI-H295R human adrenocortical carcinoma cell line was obtained from ATCC (CRL-2128), and experiments aiming at completing the ex vivo experiments using human adult testis explants were conducted in accordance with OECD guidelines (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-16-2&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-16&quot;&gt;16&lt;/a&gt;). Steroids were analyzed after exposure to ibuprofen, abiraterone, and PGD2 (Sigma-Aldrich). Toxicity was evaluated with the Alamar Blue assay (Sigma-Aldrich). Deuterated steroid analogs were obtained for analysis from CDN Isotopes and Toronto Research Chemicals, and derivatization quality-control standards (7b-17β-estradiol-17-acetate), instrument control standards (estrone-3-methyl ether), and derivatization reagents (&lt;em&gt;N&lt;/em&gt;-trimethylsilylimidazole, &lt;em&gt;N&lt;/em&gt;-methyl-&lt;em&gt;N&lt;/em&gt;-trimethylsilyl-trifluoroacetamide, and 1,4-dithioerythritol) were obtained from Sigma-Aldrich. Steroid extraction and the subsequent quantification of steroid hormones were performed according to Holm et al. (&lt;a id=&quot;xref-ref-68-1&quot; class=&quot;xref-bibr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full#ref-68&quot;&gt;68&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-48&quot;&gt;For prostaglandin secretion analysis, the NIC-H295R cells were plated in 12-well plates and were exposed overnight; the global prostaglandin synthesis was evaluated immediately afterward with a Prostaglandin Screening ELISA Kit (Cayman Chemical Company).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-49&quot;&gt;For transcriptional analysis with RT-qPCR, RNA was isolated from cells with the All Prep DNA/RNA kit (Qiagen). RNA integrity was measured on a NanoDrop ND-1000 spectrophotometer (Thermo Scientific), and only 260/280 and 260/230 ratios &amp;gt;2.0 were accepted for further processing. Quantitative PCR was performed as previously described.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;sec-17&quot; class=&quot;subsection&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;h-p-wrap&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Statistical Analysis.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;h-lead h3-h-lead&quot; id=&quot;p-50&quot;&gt;For the trial, each individual’s samples were normalized by division by the mean of the baseline samples drawn before the intervention. Hence, samples from each volunteer were normalized with the individual’s own baseline values before the administration. Unpaired Student &lt;em&gt;t&lt;/em&gt; tests were used to compare the placebo and ibuprofen groups after 14 and 44 d of administration. For the ex vivo experiments, data were compared using the Mann–Whitney &lt;em&gt;U&lt;/em&gt; test and slopes with &lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; values and Spearman correlation when indicated. For in vitro cell experiments, analysis was performed with one-way ANOVA followed by a post hoc Dunnett’s multiple comparison test. All data are expressed as mean ± SEM, and differences were considered statistically significant when &lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; ≤ 0.05.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section ack&quot; id=&quot;ack-1&quot;&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Acknowledgments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-51&quot;&gt;We thank the staff at the Pontchaillou Hospital (Rennes, France) for help with organ donation and the men who participated in the intervention trial (Copenhagen). Funding for this study was provided by a Nordea Foundation Healthy Ageing Grant, The Lundbeck Foundation, The Danish Council for Independent Research (Medical Sciences), INSERM, University of Rennes 1, the School of Public Health, and Agence Nationale de Sécurité du Médicament et des Produits de Santé Grant AAP-2012-037. No funding bodies had any role in study design, data collection and analysis, decision to publish, or preparation of the manuscript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section fn-group&quot; id=&quot;fn-group-1&quot;&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;fn-other&quot; id=&quot;fn-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-2&quot;&gt;Author contributions: D.M.K., C.D.-L., A.L.M., M.D.D., S.M.-G., M.K., A.J., and B.J. designed research; D.M.K., C.D.-L., A.L.M., M.D.D., C.H.H., B.S., J.-P.A., B.L.B., C.P., L.L., S.M.-G., M.K., and A.J. performed research; D.M.K., S.B., and B.J. contributed new reagents/analytic tools; D.M.K., C.D.-L., F.D.M., C.H.H., B.S., J.-P.A., B.L.B., C.P., A.H.-S., T.K.J., L.L., S.M.-G., K.K., S.B., M.K., A.J., and B.J. analyzed data; and D.M.K., C.D.-L., and B.J. wrote the paper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;fn-conflict&quot; id=&quot;fn-4&quot;&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-52&quot;&gt;The authors declare no conflict of interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;fn-other&quot; id=&quot;fn-5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-53&quot;&gt;This article is a PNAS Direct Submission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;fn-supplementary-material&quot; id=&quot;fn-6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;p-54&quot;&gt;This article contains supporting information online at &lt;a class=&quot;in-nw&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/lookup/suppl/doi:10.1073/pnas.1715035115/-/DCSupplemental&quot;&gt;www.pnas.org/lookup/suppl/doi:10.1073/pnas.1715035115/-/DCSupplemental&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;copyright-statement&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;fn&quot; id=&quot;copyright-statement-1&quot;&gt;Copyright © 2018 the Author(s). Published by PNAS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 21:58:56 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tokai</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/01/03/1715035115.full</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Useful Mental Models (2016)</title>
<link>http://www.defmacro.org/2016/12/22/models.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.defmacro.org/2016/12/22/models.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;These are some mental models I find useful. They’re rooted in decades of experience of thousands of experts – a modern equivalent of folk wisdom. Mental models are useful to quickly and correctly reason about seemingly intractable problems. They require quite a bit of intuition to properly internalize, but once you’ve internalized them they’re relatively easy to apply. They’re also easy to forget in the moment – use this post as a checklist when thinking about complex problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a living document. Instead of creating an exhaustive list on day one, I will add models as they arise (and as I discover new ones).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The small-improvements method&lt;/strong&gt; – the observation that psychologically frequently making small incremental improvements is a better approach than attempting to fix big looming problems once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.joelonsoftware.com/2002/01/06/fire-and-motion/&quot;&gt;The just-get-started method&lt;/a&gt; – Joel Spolsky’s observation that just starting to work on a small, concrete, finishable problem puts your consciousness in a productive state.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Corollary:&lt;/strong&gt; Just do something concrete. Anything. Do your laundry, or dust the counters, or add a single unit test. Just do something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cs.virginia.edu/~robins/YouAndYourResearch.html&quot;&gt;The top-five-problems method&lt;/a&gt; – Richard Hamming’s algorithm for doing important work. Periodically ask yourself: “what are the top five most important problems in my field (and life), and why am I not working on them?”&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Corollary:&lt;/strong&gt; What are the top five most important problems in your field (and life), and why aren’t you working on them?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The LRU prioritization method&lt;/strong&gt; – since you can only work on one problem at a time, it’s usually sufficient to pick the most important problem, work on that, and ignore everything else. This method also works with organizing most things (from email to physical possessions).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pitt.edu/~druzdzel/feynman.html&quot;&gt;The teaching method&lt;/a&gt; – Richard Feynman’s observation that teaching the basics is an excellent method for generating profound new ideas, and for putting consciousness in a productive state.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Corollary:&lt;/strong&gt; If you’re stuck, put yourself in a position where you have to teach someone the basics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Planning_fallacy&quot;&gt;Planning fallacy&lt;/a&gt; – the observation that humans are overly optimistic when predicting success of their undertakings. Empirically, the average case turns out to be worse than the worst case human estimate.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Corollary:&lt;/strong&gt; Be &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; pessimistic when estimating. Assume the average case will be slightly worse than the hypothetical worst case.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Corollary:&lt;/strong&gt; When estimating time, upgrade the units and double the estimate (e.g. convert “one week” to “two months”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Behavior-shaping_constraint&quot;&gt;Forcing function&lt;/a&gt; – an external, usually social, constraint that increases the probability of accomplishing a set of tasks.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example:&lt;/strong&gt; Pair programming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Efficient-market_hypothesis&quot;&gt;Efficient market hypothesis&lt;/a&gt; – the state of any given issue in the world is &lt;em&gt;roughly&lt;/em&gt; as close to optimal as is currently possible.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Corollary:&lt;/strong&gt; It’s unlikely that the status quo can be easily improved without significant resources.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example:&lt;/strong&gt; Cucumber juice probably doesn’t cure cancer.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example:&lt;/strong&gt; The iPhone app you wrote in a weekend probably doesn’t double the phone’s battery life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_mechanics&quot;&gt;Statistical mechanics&lt;/a&gt; – probabalistic systems that follow certain laws in the long run can have perturbations that diverge from these laws in the short run.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Corollary:&lt;/strong&gt; Occasionally the status quo &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; be easily improved without significant resources (but it is unlikely that &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; found such an occassion).&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Idiom:&lt;/strong&gt; In the short run the market is a voting machine, but in the long run it is a weighing machine.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Idiom:&lt;/strong&gt; If an economist saw a $100 bill on a sidewalk they wouldn’t pick it up (because if it were real, it would have been picked up already).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Base_rate&quot;&gt;Base rates&lt;/a&gt; – you can approximate the likelihood of a specific event occurring by examining the wider probability distribution of similar events.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example:&lt;/strong&gt; You’re evaluating the probability of success of a given startup. Ask yourself, if you saw ten similar startups a year, how many of them are likely to succeed?&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example:&lt;/strong&gt; You caught an employee stealing, but they claim they need money to buy medication and it’s the first time they’ve ever stolen anything. Ask yourself, if you saw ten employee thefts a year, how many of them are likely to be first offences?&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; This method is especially useful to combat &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Optimism_bias&quot;&gt;optimism&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Overconfidence_effect&quot;&gt;overconfidence&lt;/a&gt; biases, or when evaluating outcomes of events you’re emotionally close to.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;See also:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://lesswrong.com/lw/3m6/techniques_for_probability_estimates/&quot;&gt;Techniques for probability estimates&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reference_class_forecasting&quot;&gt;reference class forecasting&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Prior_probability&quot;&gt;prior probability&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emic_and_etic&quot;&gt;Emic vs etic&lt;/a&gt; (aka inside vs outside view) – two perspectives you can choose when evaluating persuasive arguments. The inside view is time consuming and requires you to engage with the arguments on their merits. The outside view only requires you ask “what kind of person does sincerely believing this stuff turn you into?”&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Corollary:&lt;/strong&gt; You can &lt;em&gt;usually&lt;/em&gt; predict correctness of arguments by evaluating superficial attributes of the people making them.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example:&lt;/strong&gt; If someone is wearing funny clothes, purports to know the one true way, and keeps talking about the glorious leader, you can usually dismiss their arguments without deeper examination.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warning:&lt;/strong&gt; This method usually works because most kooky people aren’t innovators, but will misfire in important situations because many innovators initially seem kooky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inversion&lt;/strong&gt; – the observation that many hard problems are best solved when they’re addressed backward. In other words figure out what you don’t want, avoid it, and you’ll get what you do want.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Corollary:&lt;/strong&gt; Find out how people commonly fail doing what you do, and avoid failing like them.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example:&lt;/strong&gt; If you want to help India, ask “what is doing the worst damage in India and how can we avoid it?”&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;See also:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Failure_mode_and_effects_analysis&quot;&gt;Failure mode&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bias for action&lt;/strong&gt; – in daily life many important decisions are easily reversible. It’s not enough to have information – it’s crucial to move quickly and recover if you were wrong, than to deliberate indefinitely.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Idiom:&lt;/strong&gt; One test is worth a thousand expert opinions.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Idiom:&lt;/strong&gt; The best thing you can do is the right thing, the next best thing is the wrong thing, and the worst thing you can do is nothing.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; The best people do this naturally, without brooding, and with a light touch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Expected_value&quot;&gt;Expected value&lt;/a&gt; – a simple model for evaluating uncertain events (multiply the probability of the event by its value).&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Corollary:&lt;/strong&gt; Sometimes you’ll have to estimate probabilities when it feels really hard to do.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example:&lt;/strong&gt; Chance of winning NY lotto is 1 in 292,201,338 per game. Let’s say the grand prize is $150M and ticket price is $1. Then the expected value is roughly $0.5. Since $0.5 &amp;lt; $1, the model tells us the game isn’t worth playing.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warning:&lt;/strong&gt; Looking at expected value often isn’t enough. You need to consider utility to make good decisions.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;See also:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://lesswrong.com/lw/3m6/techniques_for_probability_estimates/&quot;&gt;Techniques for probability estimates&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.lesswrong.com/wiki/Shut_up_and_multiply&quot;&gt;shut up and multiply&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://lesswrong.com/lw/hw/scope_insensitivity/&quot;&gt;scope insensitivity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marginal_utility&quot;&gt;Marginal utility&lt;/a&gt; – the change in utility from the change in consumption of a good. Marginal utility usually diminishes with increase in consumption.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example:&lt;/strong&gt; The first car in your garage improves your life significantly more than the second one.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example:&lt;/strong&gt; Because utility loss from losing a dollar is negligible relative to utility gain from winning NY Lotto at ridiculously low odds, it might be worth buying a ticket even at negative expected value (but seriously, don’t).&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Corollary:&lt;/strong&gt; Think through your utility function carefully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Strategy&quot;&gt;Strategy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tactic_(method)&quot;&gt;tactics&lt;/a&gt; – empirically decisions tend to fall into one of two categories. Strategic decisions have long-term, gradual, and subtle effects (they’re a gift that keeps on giving). Tactical decisions are encapsulated into outcomes that have relatively quick binary resolutions (success or failure).&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example:&lt;/strong&gt; Picking a programming language is a strategic decision.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example:&lt;/strong&gt; Picking a line of reasoning when trying to close a sale is a tactical decision.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Corollary:&lt;/strong&gt; Most people misuse these terms (e.g. “we need a strategy for this meeting”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Intelligence_quotient&quot;&gt;IQ&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.research-and-analytics.csfb.com/docView?language=ENG&amp;amp;format=PDF&amp;amp;source_id=csplusresearchcp&amp;amp;document_id=1048541371&amp;amp;serialid=mofPYk1Y4WanTeErbeMtPx6ur0SCIcSlaZ7sKGPdQQU%3D&quot;&gt;RQ&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emotional_intelligence&quot;&gt;EQ&lt;/a&gt; – respectively, intelligence quotient (assessment of the mind’s raw horse power), rationality quotient (assessment of how well the mind’s models map to the real world; a measure of efficiency of the IQ’s application to real problems), and emotional quotient (ability to recognize and label emotions).&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Corollary:&lt;/strong&gt; brilliant people can be jerks and kooks, empathic people can have wacky ideas about reality, and effective people can have average intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Structure_and_agency&quot;&gt;Structure and agency&lt;/a&gt; – the observation that human behavior derives from a balance of internalized cultural patterns and capacity to act independently. The interaction of these two properties influences and limits individual behavior.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Corollary:&lt;/strong&gt; Pay attention to the need for structure and independence in each individual.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Corollary:&lt;/strong&gt; Put a structure in front of even the most independent-minded people, and they’ll internalize it.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Corollary:&lt;/strong&gt; People often behave the way they believe their &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Presentation_of_Self_in_Everyday_Life&quot;&gt;role&lt;/a&gt; requires them to (as opposed to the actual requirements of the role).&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Corollary:&lt;/strong&gt; Pay attention to how people perceive their own roles, and break their expectations with caution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_status&quot;&gt;Social status&lt;/a&gt; – the observation (particularly in improv) that social status is so important to humans, that modeling status alone results in extremely realistic performances.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Corollary:&lt;/strong&gt; Pay attention to how people perceive their own status, and break their expectations with caution.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;See also:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Self-serving_bias&quot;&gt;Self-serving bias&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Controlled vulnerability:&lt;/strong&gt; – the observation that humans are attracted to confidently expressed vulnerability in others but are scared to be vulnerable themselves.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Corollary:&lt;/strong&gt; Humans feel strong attraction towards others who confidently display vulnerability.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Corollary:&lt;/strong&gt; Humans feel a strong desire to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reciprocity_(social_psychology)&quot;&gt;reciprocate&lt;/a&gt; vulnerability. Vulnerability expression by others gives them a sense of safety to express themselves, followed by a feeling of relief and a strong bond with the counterpary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mere-exposure_effect&quot;&gt;Mere-exposure effect&lt;/a&gt; – an observation that humans tend to develop a preference for things, people, and processes merely because they are familiar with them. This effect is much stronger than it initially seems.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Corollary:&lt;/strong&gt; Merely putting people in a room together repeatedly, giving them a shared direction, symbology, and competition will create a group with very strong bonds.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;See also:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/In-group_favoritism&quot;&gt;In-group favoritism&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.defmacro.org/2015/02/25/startup-ideas.html&quot;&gt;Story arc&lt;/a&gt; – human beings are wired to respond to storytelling. A story arc is a way to structure ideas to tap into this response, typically by describing a change in the world.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example:&lt;/strong&gt; Once upon a time there was ___. Every day, ___. One day ___. Because of that, ___. Because of that, ___. Until finally ___.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.defmacro.org/2016/12/22/writing-well.html&quot;&gt;Writing well&lt;/a&gt; – use arresting imagery and tabulate your thoughts precisely. Never use a long word where a short one will do. If it’s possible to cut a word out, always cut it out. Don’t hedge – decide what you want to say and say it as vigorously as possible. Of all the places to go next, choose the most interesting.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Principle_of_charity&quot;&gt;Charitable interpretation&lt;/a&gt; – interpreting a speaker’s statements to be rational and, in the case of any argument, considering its best, strongest possible interpretation. Charitable interpretation makes conversations (and relationships) go better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nonviolent_Communication&quot;&gt;Nonviolent Communication&lt;/a&gt; (aka NVC) – a communication framework that allows expressing grievances and resolving conflicts in a non-confrontational way. Structuring difficult conversations as described in NVC makes the process dramatically less painful. NVC contains four components: (1) expressing facts, (2) expressing feelings, (3) expressing needs, and (4) making a request.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example:&lt;/strong&gt; You didn’t turn in the project yesterday. When that happened I felt betrayed. I need to be able to rely on you to have a productive relationship. In the future, could you notify me in advance if something like that happens?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Utilitarianism&quot;&gt;Global utility maximization&lt;/a&gt; – our innate sense of fairness is often unsatisfiable, and attemping to satisfy it can occasionally cause much grief in exchange for little gain. It’s much better to optimize for the needs of the many, not for an idealistic notion of fairness.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Corollary:&lt;/strong&gt; There are times when it makes sense to be unfair to the individual in the interest of the common good.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example:&lt;/strong&gt; It makes sense to fire an underperforming employee who has valid excuses for their poor performance.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Idiom:&lt;/strong&gt; It is the greatest happiness of the greatest number that is the measure of right and wrong.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;See also:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Preference_utilitarianism&quot;&gt;Preference utilitarianism&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tragedy_of_the_commons&quot;&gt;Tragedy of the commons&lt;/a&gt; – a set of circumstances where individuals acting independently in a reasonable manner behave contrary to the common good.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example:&lt;/strong&gt; Tourists taking small artifacts from popular attractions.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Corollary:&lt;/strong&gt; Governance is necessary to preserve the common good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Front page test&lt;/strong&gt; – an ethical standard for behavior that evaluates each action through the lens of the media/outside world.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example:&lt;/strong&gt; What would happen if HN found out we’re mining our users’s IMs?&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warning:&lt;/strong&gt; Incentivizes extreme risk aversion, often without appropriate consideration for potential gain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cs.cmu.edu/~weigand/staff/&quot;&gt;Reasonable person principle&lt;/a&gt; – a rule of thumb for group communication originated in CMU. It holds that reasonable people strike a suitable balance between their own immediate desires and the good of the community at large.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Corollary:&lt;/strong&gt; Fire people that are offensive or easily offended. (It usually turns out that people who possess one of these qualities, possess both.)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; unreasonable persons can be extremely valuable in greater society (e.g. journalists, comedians, whistleblowers, etc.), but usually not in small organizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Overton_window&quot;&gt;Overton window&lt;/a&gt; – the range of ideas a particular group of people will accept. Ideas range in degree of acceptance from policy, to popular, sensible, acceptable, radical, and unthinkable.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Corollary:&lt;/strong&gt; you need to be sensitive to the overton window when presenting the group with cultural changes.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Political_capital&quot;&gt;Political capital&lt;/a&gt; – the trust and influence a leader wields with other people. Political capital increases when you make other people successful and decreases when you make unpopular decisions.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Corollary:&lt;/strong&gt; Spend political capital carefully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.defmacro.org/2016/11/23/talking-to-users.html&quot;&gt;Target market&lt;/a&gt; – a predicate that partitions new leads into opportunities and distractions. A good target market function is terse, has a discoverable domain, and has a well defined probability of close in a specific time bound.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example:&lt;/strong&gt; Anyone who has a Cisco password has a 50% probability of close within 30 days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quora.com/Amazon-company-What-is-Amazons-approach-to-product-development-and-product-management/answer/Ian-McAllister?srid=3TH&quot;&gt;Internal press release&lt;/a&gt; – you &lt;em&gt;start&lt;/em&gt; developing a product by writing an internal press release &lt;em&gt;first&lt;/em&gt;, explaining to target customers why the product is useful and how it blows away the competition. You then test it against potential users (it’s much easier to iterate on the press release than the product).&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Corollary:&lt;/strong&gt; If the press release is hard to write, then the product is probably going to suck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=542768&quot;&gt;Quantum of utility&lt;/a&gt; – a rule of thumb for launching the product. A product possesses a quantum of utility when there is at least some set of users who would be excited to hear about it, because they can now do something they couldn’t do before.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; “Launch” can be defined as a private beta, or even giving the product to a friend. The point is to get it into the hands of &lt;em&gt;someone&lt;/em&gt; who’s not in the building as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dreamsongs.com/RiseOfWorseIsBetter.html&quot;&gt;Worse is better&lt;/a&gt; – a design philosophy which states that solving the customer’s problem and leaving unpolished rough edges empirically outperforms “beautiful” products.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example:&lt;/strong&gt; Lisp Machines vs C/Unix.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;See also:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.artima.com/weblogs/viewpost.jsp?thread=24807&quot;&gt;Worse is worse&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kano_model&quot;&gt;Kano model&lt;/a&gt; – a model for categorizing possible features to optimize resource allocation. Essentially partitions the product into gamechangers, showstoppers, and distractions.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;See also:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.defmacro.org/2013/09/26/products.html&quot;&gt;How to build great products&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Porter's_five_forces_analysis&quot;&gt;Five forces&lt;/a&gt; – a model for analyzing the competitive intensity and therefore attractiveness of an industry. The five forces are: threat of new entrants, threat of substitutes, bargaining power of buyers, bargaining power of suppliers, and industry rivalry.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; this is essentially a &lt;em&gt;base rate&lt;/em&gt; estimation model for companies in an industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Familiarity_heuristic&quot;&gt;Power of defaults&lt;/a&gt; – the observation that people favor the familiar over novel places, people, things, and processes.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Corollary:&lt;/strong&gt; Overcoming the familiarity heuristic at scale requires enormous &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Activation_energy&quot;&gt;activation energy&lt;/a&gt; unavailable to startups.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Corollary:&lt;/strong&gt; It is dramatically easier to capture mindshare before people’s minds are made up, than to change their mind later.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;See also:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Default_effect_(psychology)&quot;&gt;Default effect&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Path_of_least_resistance&quot;&gt;path of least resistance&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brand_equity&quot;&gt;brand equity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Economies_of_scale&quot;&gt;Economies of scale&lt;/a&gt; – the advantages due to size or scale of operation, where cost per unit decreases with increasing scale.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;See also:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Network_effect&quot;&gt;Network effects&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brand_equity&quot;&gt;brand equity&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/First-mover_advantage&quot;&gt;first mover advantage&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Price%E2%80%93performance_ratio&quot;&gt;Price/performance curve&lt;/a&gt; – the observation that the price of important technology drops and performance improves over time.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Moore%27s_law&quot;&gt;Moore’s Law&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 21:43:18 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Mougatine</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.defmacro.org/2016/12/22/models.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The growing body of evidence that digital distraction is damaging our minds</title>
<link>https://www.theglobeandmail.com/technology/your-smartphone-is-making-you-stupid/article37511900/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theglobeandmail.com/technology/your-smartphone-is-making-you-stupid/article37511900/</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;article-dropcap&quot;&gt;I&lt;/span&gt;n the winter of 1906, the year San Francisco was destroyed by an earthquake and SOS became the international distress signal, Britain's Punch magazine published a dark joke about the future of technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;Under the headline, &quot;Forecasts for 1907,&quot; a black and white cartoon showed a well-dressed Edwardian couple sitting in a London park. The man and woman are turned away from each other, antennae protruding from their hats. In their laps are little black boxes, spitting out ticker tape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;A caption reads: &quot;These two figures are not communicating with one another. The lady is receiving an amatory message, and the gentleman some racing results.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;u-wrapper pb-feature pb-layout-item pb-f-commercial-dfp-ads&quot; id=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;c-ad--flex-gpt-1&quot; class=&quot;c-ad c-ad--inline c-ad--flex&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;c-ad__wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-ad__message&quot;&gt;Story continues below advertisement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;element element-rawhtml&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article-media-photo article-media-photo--ratiooriginal&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article-media-photo__content&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;article-media-photo__content__img&quot; data-id=&quot;37511448&quot; itemprop=&quot;url&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 960px) calc(960px - 320px), (min-width: 768px) calc(100vw - 60px), calc(100vw - 20px)&quot; src=&quot;https://www.theglobeandmail.com/ece-images/db5/news/national/article37511448.ece/BINARY/w620/punch-cartoon.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.theglobeandmail.com/ece-images/4e6/news/national/article37511448.ece/BINARY/w1100/punch-cartoon.jpg 1100w, https://www.theglobeandmail.com/ece-images/498/news/national/article37511448.ece/BINARY/w940/punch-cartoon.jpg 940w, https://www.theglobeandmail.com/ece-images/db5/news/national/article37511448.ece/BINARY/w620/punch-cartoon.jpg 620w, https://www.theglobeandmail.com/ece-images/1fb/news/national/article37511448.ece/BINARY/w780/punch-cartoon.jpg 780w, https://www.theglobeandmail.com/ece-images/f63/news/national/article37511448.ece/BINARY/w460/punch-cartoon.jpg 460w&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;The cartoonist was going for broad humour, but today the image looks prophetic. A century after it was published, Steve Jobs unveiled the first iPhone. Today, thanks to him, we can sit in parks and not only receive amatory messages and racing results, but summon all the world's knowledge with a few taps of our thumbs, listen to virtually every song ever recorded and communicate instantaneously with everyone we know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;More than two billion people around the world, including three-quarters of Canadians, now have this magic at their fingertips – and it's changing the way we do countless things, from taking photos to summoning taxis. But smartphones have also changed us – changed our natures in elemental ways, reshaping the way we think and interact. For all their many conveniences, it is here, in the way they have changed not just industries or habits but people themselves, that the joke of the cartoon has started to show its dark side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;The evidence for this goes beyond the carping of Luddites. It's there, cold and hard, in a growing body of research by psychiatrists, neuroscientists, marketers and public health experts. What these people say – and what their research shows – is that smartphones are causing real damage to our minds and relationships, measurable in seconds shaved off the average attention span, reduced brain power, declines in work-life balance and hours less of family time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;They have impaired our ability to remember. They make it more difficult to daydream and think creatively. They make us more vulnerable to anxiety. They make parents ignore their children. And they are addictive, if not in the contested clinical sense then for all intents and purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;Consider this: In the first five years of the smartphone era, the proportion of Americans who said internet use interfered with their family time nearly tripled, from 11 per cent to 28 per cent. And this: Smartphone use takes about the same cognitive toll as losing a full night's sleep. In other words, they are making us worse at being alone and worse at being together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;Ten years into the smartphone experiment, we may be reaching a tipping point. Buoyed by mounting evidence and a growing chorus of tech-world jeremiahs, smartphone users are beginning to recognize the downside of the convenient little mini-computer we keep pressed against our thigh or cradled in our palm, not to mention buzzing on our bedside table while we sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;Nowhere is the dawning awareness of the problem with smartphones more acute than in the California idylls that created them. Last year, ex-employees of Google, Apple and Facebook, including former top executives, began raising the alarm about smartphones and social media apps, warning especially of their effects on children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;u-wrapper pb-feature pb-layout-item pb-f-commercial-dfp-ads&quot; id=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;c-ad--flex-gpt-2&quot; class=&quot;c-ad c-ad--inline c-ad--flex&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;c-ad__wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-ad__message&quot;&gt;Story continues below advertisement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;Chris Marcellino, who helped develop the iPhone's push notifications at Apple, told The Guardian last fall that smartphones hook people using the same neural pathways as gambling and drugs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;Sean Parker, ex-president of Facebook, recently admitted that the world-bestriding social media platform was designed to hook users with spurts of dopamine, a complicated neurotransmitter released when the brain expects a reward or accrues fresh knowledge. &quot;You're exploiting a vulnerability in human psychology,&quot; he said. &quot;[The inventors] understood this, consciously, and we did it anyway.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;Peddling this addiction made Mr. Parker and his tech-world colleagues absurdly rich. Facebook is now valued at a little more than half a trillion dollars. Global revenue from smartphone sales reached $435-billion (U.S.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;Now, some of the early executives of these tech firms look on their success as tainted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;&quot;I feel tremendous guilt,&quot; said Chamath Palihapitiya, former vice-president of user growth at Facebook, in a public talk in November. &quot;I think we all knew in the back of our minds… something bad could happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;&quot;The short-term, dopamine-driven feedback loops that we have created are destroying how society works,&quot; he went on gravely, before a hushed audience at Stanford business school. &quot;It is eroding the core foundations of how people behave.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;u-wrapper pb-feature pb-layout-item pb-f-commercial-dfp-ads&quot; id=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;c-ad--flex-gpt-3&quot; class=&quot;c-ad c-ad--inline c-ad--flex&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;c-ad__wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-ad__message&quot;&gt;Story continues below advertisement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;None of the Bay Area whistle-blowers have been louder than Tristan Harris, a former star product manager at Google. He has spent the past several years of his life telling people to use less of the technologies he helped create through a non-profit called Time Well Spent, which aims to raise awareness among consumers about the dangers of the attention economy, and pressure the tech world to design its products more ethically. Judging by the momentum his movement is suddenly building – he receives hundreds of requests for speaking engagements a month – his message is being heard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;Policy makers and government leaders are among those listening. Prime Minister Justin Trudeau met with Mr. Harris at the Global Progress Summit in Montreal last September. The PM's office wouldn't provide details of the session, but if the federal government is considering restrictions on cellphone use, it wouldn't be alone. This fall, France plans to ban mobile phones from primary and secondary schools, including between classes and during lunch breaks. &quot;We must come up with a way of protecting pupils from loss of concentration via screens and phones,&quot; said French education minister Jean-Michel Blanquer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;Business leaders are grappling with the issue, too. In a recent blog post, Bank of England analyst Dan Nixon argues that the distraction wrought by smartphones may be hurting productivity. It takes office workers an average of 25 minutes to get back on task after an interruption, he notes, while workers who are habitually interrupted by e-mail become likelier to &quot;self-interrupt&quot; with little procrastination breaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;The TD Centre in downtown Toronto was channelling that business case against smartphones when it placed a coaxing poster in its lobby recently. &quot;Disconnect to reconnect,&quot; the poster read. &quot;Put your phone down and be present.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;Yes, people are always put off by the strange power of new technologies. Socrates thought writing would melt the brains of Athenian youths by undermining their ability to memorize. Erasmus cursed the &quot;swarm of new books&quot; plaguing post-Gutenberg Europe. In its infancy, TV was derided as a &quot;vast wasteland.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;But while previous generations may have cried wolf about new media, &quot;it's different this time,&quot; Mr. Harris says. Unlike TVs and desktop computers, which are typically relegated to a den or home office, smartphones go with us everywhere. And they know us. The stories that pop up in your iPhone newsfeed and your social media apps are selected by algorithms to grab your eye.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;Smartphones are &quot;literally using the power of billion-dollar computers to figure out what to feed you,&quot; Mr. Harris said. That's why you can't look away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;Socrates was wrong about writing and Erasmus was wrong about books. But after all, the boy who cried wolf was eaten in the end. And in smartphones, our brains may have finally met their match.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;&quot;It's &lt;em&gt;Homo sapiens&lt;/em&gt; minds against the most powerful supercomputers and billions of dollars …. It's like bringing a knife to a space laser fight,&quot; Mr. Harris said. &quot;We're going to look back and say, 'Why on earth did we do this?'&quot;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;article-dropcap&quot;&gt;I&lt;/span&gt;f we have lost control over our relationship with smartphones, it is by design. In fact, the business model of the devices demands it. Because most popular websites and apps don't charge for access, the internet is financially sustained by eyeballs. That is, the longer and more often you spend staring at Facebook or Google, the more money they can charge advertisers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;To ensure that our eyes remain firmly glued to our screens, our smartphones – and the digital worlds they connect us to – internet giants have become little virtuosos of persuasion, cajoling us into checking them again and again – and for longer than we intend. Average users look at their phones about 150 times a day, according to some estimates, and about twice as often as they think they do, according to a 2015 study by British psychologists. &lt;span class=&quot;underline&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;Add it all up and North American users spend somewhere between three and five hours a day looking at their smartphones. As the New York University marketing professor Adam Alter points out, that means over the course of an average lifetime, most of us will spend about seven years immersed in our portable computers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;These companies have persuaded us to give over so much of our lives by exploiting a handful of human frailties. One of them is called novelty bias. It means our brains are suckers for the new. As the McGill neuroscientist Daniel Levitin explains, we're wired this way to survive. In the infancy of our species, novelty bias kept us alert to dubious red berries and the growls of sabre-toothed tigers. But now it makes us twig helplessly to Facebook notifications and the buzz of incoming e-mail. That's why social media apps nag you to turn notifications on. They know that once the icons start flashing onto your lock screen, you won't be able to ignore them. It's also why Facebook switched the colour of its notifications from a mild blue to attention-grabbing red.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;App designers know that nagging works. In &lt;em&gt;Persuasive Technology&lt;/em&gt;, one of the most quietly influential books to come out of Silicon Valley in the past two decades, the Stanford psychologist B.J. Fogg predicted that computers could and would take massive advantage of our susceptibility to prodding. &quot;People get tired of saying no; everyone has a moment of weakness when it's easier to comply than to resist,&quot; he wrote. Published in 2002, Prof. Fogg's book now seems eerily prescient&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;The makers of smartphone apps rightly believe that part of the reason we're so curious about those notifications is that people are desperately insecure and crave positive feedback with a kneejerk desperation. Matt Mayberry, who works at a California startup called Dopamine Labs, says it's common knowledge in the industry that Instagram exploits this craving by strategically withholding &quot;likes&quot; from certain users. If the photo-sharing app decides you need to use the service more often, it'll show only a fraction of the likes you've received on a given post at first, hoping you'll be disappointed with your haul and check back again in a minute or two. &quot;They're tying in to your greatest insecurities,&quot; Mr. Mayberry said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;Some of the mental quirks smartphones exploit are obvious, others counterintuitive. The principle of &quot;variable rewards&quot; falls into the second camp. Discovered by the psychologist B.F. Skinner and his acolytes in a series of experiments on rats and pigeons, it predicts that creatures are likelier to seek out a reward if they aren't sure how often it will be doled out. Pigeons, for example, were found to peck a button for food more frequently if the food was dispensed inconsistently rather than reliably each time, the Columbia University law professor Tim Wu recounts in his recent book &lt;em&gt;The Attention Merchants&lt;/em&gt;. So it is with social media apps: Though four out of five Facebook posts may be inane, the &quot;bottomless,&quot; automatically refreshing feed always promises a good quip or bit of telling gossip just below the threshold of the screen, accessible with the rhythmic flick of thumb on glass. Likewise the hungry need to check email with every inbox buzz.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;Apple has made a point of presenting the dopamine dispensers of the mobile internet in the most alluring possible package, one that people would want to and be able to use non-stop – even behind the wheel of a car. Weeks before the iPhone's launch, Apple gave out devices for senior staff to test in the real world. One engineer took the prototype on a test run to make sure it wasn't overly difficult to text and drive with, according to tech journalist Brian Merchant, who wrote a history of the iPhone &lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;The phone's most seductive quality was its screen. Throughout the iPhone's development, Mr. Jobs fought to proceed without a keyboard, making the screen larger and more immersive. As the product was about to ship &lt;strong&gt;,&lt;/strong&gt; he slammed on the brakes and demanded the case recede infinitesimally so the screen could be made larger still. This was a jarring innovation. Time magazine's technology writer Lev Grossman was one of the first people outside Apple to see the iPhone, when he was sent to Cupertino, Calif., for a preview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;The screen's unique power to absorb attention quickly became clear, though. In his first piece about the iPhone after its launch, Mr. Grossman observed, &quot;There's a powerful illusion that you're physically handling data with your fingers.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;Though Mr. Grossman gave the iPhone some of its earliest rave reviews, that power to absorb that once seemed so dazzling, has come to trouble him. He now says the device has done more harm than good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;&quot;We still haven't understood or accepted how completely smartphones have distorted our daily lives and our social lives, and just our relationships with ourselves and with the reality around us,&quot; he said. &quot;We are divorced from ourselves and from the world – those relationships are now routed through our phones.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;article-dropcap&quot;&gt;O&lt;/span&gt;n some level, we know that smartphones are designed to be addictive. The way we talk about them is steeped in the language of dependence, albeit playfully: the CrackBerry, the Instagram fix, the Angry Bird binge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;But the best minds who have studied these devices are saying it's not really a joke. Consider the effect smartphones have on our ability to focus. In 2015, Microsoft Canada published a report indicating that the average human attention span had shrunk from 12 to eight seconds between 2000 and 2013. The finding was widely reported at the time and elicited some shock – for about eight seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;But John Ratey, an associate professor of psychiatry at Harvard Medical School and an expert on attention-deficit disorder, said the problem is actually getting worse. &quot;We're not developing the attention muscles in our brain nearly as much as we used to,&quot; he said. In fact, Prof. Ratey has noticed a convergence between his ADD patients and the rest of the world. The symptoms of people with ADD and people with smartphones are &quot;absolutely the same,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;A recent study of Chinese middle schoolers found something similar. Among more than 7,000 students, mobile phone ownership was found to be &quot;significantly associated&quot; with levels of inattention seen in people with attention-deficit disorder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;Maybe studies like these have gotten so little attention because we already know, vaguely, that smartphones dent concentration – how could a buzzing, flashing computer in our pocket have any other effect? But people tend to treat attention span like some discrete mental faculty, such as skill at arithmetic, that is nice to have but that plenty of folks manage fine without.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;Valuable as it is, attention is also easy to squander. When taking in information, our minds are terrible at discerning between the significant and the trivial. So if we're trying to work out a dense mental problem in our heads and our phone pings, we will pay attention to the ping automatically and stop focusing on the mental problem. That weak attentional filter is a bigger shortcoming in the smartphone era than ever before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;The average American in 2007 was absorbing the equivalent of 174 newspapers a day, via sources as wide-ranging as TV, texting and the internet – five times the amount of information they took in about two decades earlier &lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;In the smartphone era, that figure can only have grown. Our brains just aren't built for the geysers of information our devices train at them. Inevitably, we end up paying attention to all kinds of things that aren't valuable or interesting, just because they flash up on our iPhone screens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;&quot;Our attentional systems evolved over tens of thousands of years when the world was much slower,&quot; Dr. Levitin explained in an interview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;All that distraction adds up to a loss of raw brain power. Workers at a British company who multitasked on electronic media – a decent proxy for frequent smartphone use – were found in a 2014 study to lose about the same quantity of IQ as people who had smoked cannabis or lost a night's sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;Even people who are disciplined about their smartphone use feel the effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;The devices exert such a magnetic pull on our minds that just the effort of resisting the temptation to look at them seems to take a toll on our mental performance. That's what Adrian Ward and his colleagues at the University of Texas business school found in an experiment last year. They had three groups of people take a test that required their full concentration. One group had their phones face down on the table, one had them in their bags or pockets and the last group left them in another room. None of the test-takers were allowed to check their devices during the test. But even so, the closer at hand the phones were, the worse the groups performed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;&quot;It's [one] of these things that's pretty crazy and yet comports pretty well with how life feels,&quot; Prof. Ward said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;Some people might be willing to trade 10 IQ points for the pleasures of their smartphone – especially the social pleasures. We've never been so capable of constant communication with others and for extroverts, that should be a blessing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;But 10 years into this age of connectedness, we have learned something troubling: Being connected to everyone all the time makes us less attentive to the people we care about most. Nowhere is the alienating power of smartphones more troubling than in the relationship between parents and children. Put simply, smartphones are making mothers and fathers pay less attention to their kids and it could be causing emotional harm. Lactation consultants in Canada and the United States have begun noticing the prevalence of women texting and scrolling through their phones while they breastfeed, breaking valuable eye contact with their baby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;&quot;It is a whole new phenomenon,&quot; said Attie Sandink, a breastfeeding educator based in Burlington, Ont. &quot;It has on occasion become quite problematic.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;Researchers at Cambridge University showed recently that eye contact synchronizes the brainwaves of infant and parent, which helps with communication and learning. Meeting each other's gaze, Ms. Sandink says, amounts to &quot;a silent language between the baby and the mom.&quot; That doesn't mean breastfeeding mothers need to lock eyes with their children 24 hours a day. But while Ms. Sandink emphasizes that she isn't trying to shame women, she worries that texting moms may be missing out on vital bonding time with their babies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;&quot;While texting or communicating on their cellphones, do mothers possibly miss some of their [infants'] feeding cues or behavioural cues? Is the mother losing the hormonal interaction or interplay that baby signals to her?&quot; Ms. Sandink said in an e-mail. &quot;These are important questions to ask.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;Maybe it's best for children to learn young that their parents frequently find their phone more absorbing than them, because they will learn sooner or later. Catherine Steiner-Adair, a clinical psychologist and research associate in psychiatry at Harvard Medical School, interviewed 1,000 kids between the ages of 4 and 18 for her 2013 book &lt;em&gt;The Big Disconnect&lt;/em&gt;. Many of them said they no longer run to the door to greet their parents because the adults are so often on their phones when they get home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;And it gets worse once they're through the door. One of the smartphone's terrible, mysterious powers, from a child's perspective, is its ability &quot;to pull you away instantly, anywhere, anytime,&quot; Dr. Steiner-Adair writes. Because what's happening on the smartphone screen is inscrutable to others, parents often seem to have simply gotten sucked into another dimension, leaving their kid behind. &quot;To children, the feeling is often one of endless frustration, fatigue and loss.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;The digital drift affecting families shows up in national statistics. The Center for the Digital Future, an American think tank, found that between 2006 and 2011, the average number of hours American families spent together per month dropped by nearly a third, from 26 to about 18.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;Distracted parents may even be putting their children at risk of physical harm, Dr. Steiner-Adair says. The U.S. Centers for Disease Control found a 12-per-cent spike in injuries to children under 5 between 2007 and 2010, after a long decline. The years coincide with the crash of the American economy, but also with the infancy of the iPhone &lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;If there's a silver lining to all of this grim evidence, it's that the wages of smartphone addiction are beginning to take hold in people's minds. When Dr. Steiner-Adair gives public talks, as she did in Maryland recently, parents often commiserate with her afterward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;&quot;They all say roughly, 'That was terrific and terrifying. We're changing our family's MO as of today,'&quot; she said. &quot;Just about everyone knows there's something terribly wrong.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;She's not the only person to notice the beginning of a turning point in the way people relate to their mobile computers. Just recently, Prof. Wu was thinking of taking out a smartphone in his daughter's preschool class to play a song when he realized it would be taboo, given growing concerns about kids' screen time – like &quot;taking out a toy gun.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;&quot;So it spreads,&quot; he said. &quot;It's like a norm.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;Prof. Wu's right: The belief that smartphones can be socially and mentally harmful – and that their overuse should be stigmatized – is spreading into the culture in little ways. A recent Dilbert cartoon showed a doctor looking wide-eyed at a medical chart and telling his patient, &quot;The MRI shows that your brain has been hijacked by dopamine pirates.&quot; (When the patient asks, &quot;Are you writing me a prescription,&quot; the doctor replies, &quot;No, I'm buying stock in those companies.&quot;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;Even comedian Will Ferrell has joined the struggle. In a series of videos produced by Common Sense Media for the U.S. nonprofit's #DeviceFreeDinner campaign this fall, the actor plays a smartphone-addled father whose family tries to lure him away from his screen. In one clip, Mr. Ferrell's wife and kids persuade him to place his phone in a basket on the dinner table, but the father finds a loophole: &quot;As long as it's in the basket, though, I can technically still touch it, right?&quot; he says, his finger creeping toward the screen of his imprisoned device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;element element-rawhtml&quot;&gt;
&lt;div itemprop=&quot;associatedMedia video&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;https://schema.org/VideoObject&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article-media-video js-article-media-video&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe frameborder=&quot;0&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ayp_Bq25sQ4&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;A culture shift is happening in Silicon Valley too. An ex-Google product manager, Ben Tauber, recently became executive director of the rejuvenated Esalen Institute, a former hippie hotel in California where techies have taken to visiting for unplugged weekends of soul searching about the plugged-in world they've created.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;Still, for all the hints of change in the air, Mr. Harris remains on high alert. Billions of people continue to be distracted and turned away from loved ones thanks to their smartphones. And untold billions of dollars, wielded by some of the world's biggest companies, are devoted to keeping it that way. In fact, every financial incentive spurring the flanks of these firms is telling them to make smartphones more compulsively usable and therefore more damaging, not less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;Mr. Harris and other smartphone skeptics are starting to hatch ideas, some more plausible than others, about how the devices might be made less toxic. Imagine, Mr. Harris said, if Facebook's app delivered all your notifications at once, at a given time of day, like the mail. Prof. Wu, meanwhile, has suggested that tech companies should develop a phone designed to protect users' attention and time. He would pay double, he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;The trouble with reforming these products, of course, is that the versions we have now are kind of amazing – fun to use and wildly convenient. That's why they're so addictive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;The lesson we're slowly beginning to learn, though, is that they're not a harmless vice. Used the way we currently use them, smartphones keep us from being our best selves. The world is starting to make up its mind about whether it's worth it and whether the sugary hits of digital pleasure justify being worse, both alone and together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;We need to make up our minds soon, Mr. Harris said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;&quot;I worry that we're not going to get this fast enough.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;c-article-body__text&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DIGITAL DISTRACTIONS: MORE FROM THE GLOBE AND MAIL&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 18:47:26 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mmayberry</dc:creator>
<og:title>Your smartphone is making you stupid, antisocial and unhealthy. So why can’t you put it down?</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.theglobeandmail.com/technology/your-smartphone-is-making-you-stupid/article37511900/</og:url>
<og:description>A decade ago, smart devices promised to change the way we think and interact, and they have – but not by making us smarter. Eric Andrew-Gee explores the growing body of scientific evidence that digital distraction is damaging our minds</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://www.theglobeandmail.com/resizer/RaJT6OasaX2VWtasqapk5Q8hQvA=/1200x0/filters:quality(80)/arc-anglerfish-tgam-prod-tgam.s3.amazonaws.com/public/DPECPYDEJNBPNBBCIWB3ZDCTVU.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-CA</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theglobeandmail.com/technology/your-smartphone-is-making-you-stupid/article37511900/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>James Damore has filed a class action lawsuit against Google</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2018/01/08/james-damore-just-filed-a-class-action-lawsuit-against-google-saying-it-discriminates-against-white-male-conservatives/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2018/01/08/james-damore-just-filed-a-class-action-lawsuit-against-google-saying-it-discriminates-against-white-male-conservatives/</guid>
<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/screen-shot-2018-01-08-at-10-16-45-am.png?w=738&quot; class=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot;&gt;James Damore, a former Google engineer who was fired in August after posting a memo to an internal Google message board arguing that women may not be equally represented in tech because they are biologically less capable of engineering, has filed a class action lawsuit against the company in Santa Clara Superior Court in Northern California.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;His claims: that Google unfairly discriminates against white men whose political views are unpopular with its executives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Damore is joined in the 161-page suit by another former Google engineer named David Gudeman, who spent three years with Google working on a query engine. According to Gudeman’s LinkedIn profile, he left the company in December 2016 and has been self-employed since.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lawsuit, filed by Dhillon Law Group, says it aims to represent all employees of Google who’ve been discriminated against due to their “perceived conservative political views by Google,” due to “their male gender by Google” and “due to their Caucasian race by Google.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More specifically, it accuses Google of singling out, mistreating and systematically punishing and terminating employees who “expressed views deviating from the majority view at Google on political subjects raised in the workplace and relevant to Google’s employment policies and its business, such as ‘diversity’ hiring policies, ‘bias sensitivity’ or ‘social justice’…”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Damore isn’t holding back any punches here. According to his filing, Google employs “illegal hiring quotas to fill its desired percentages of women and favored minority candidates, and openly shames managers of business units who fail to meet their  quotas—in the process, openly denigrating male and Caucasian employees as less favored than others.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The suit also claims that the “numerical presence of women celebrated at Google” was based “solely due to their gender” while the “presence of Caucasians and males was mocked with ‘boos’ during companywide weekly meetings.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somewhat redundantly, it adds that Damore, Gudeman and “other class members” were “ostracized, belittled, and punished for their heterodox political views, and for the added sin of their birth circumstances of being Caucasians and/or males.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lawsuit is seeking monetary, non-monetary and punitive remedies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Damore’s firing last summer became the talk of the nation, with many in Silicon Valley outraged that Google didn’t act even more swiftly to terminate him. Elsewhere, many wondered whether the firing would have a chilling effect on employees’ ability to openly discuss their viewpoints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google said it fired Damore for violating its code of conduct and advancing “harmful gender stereotypes in our workplace.” Damore meanwhile began a kind of press tour, denouncing the company for being close-minded and worse. In an interview with CNBC, for example, he compared being a conservative at Google to “&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2017/08/18/james-damore-being-conservative-at-google-like-being-gay-in-the-1950s.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;being gay in the 1950s&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a press conference this afternoon, Damore’s attorney, Harmeet Dhillon, a &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://gop.com/leaders/national-committeewoman-harmeet-dhillon-ca&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;California representative&lt;/a&gt; for the Republican National Committee, elaborated more on the very lengthy complaint and argued that her current clients are far from alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, she said she spoke with “dozens” of employees at Google to formulate the lawsuit and that she expects there will be “future lawsuits” to explore, as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To underscore her point that Google’s policies need to be amended, she cited so-called TGIF meetings at Google, telling reporters that during Damore’s tenure, “managers were called out and shamed and mocked if they didn’t have 50/50 gender parity in [their respective] units.” She called the goal “fair” but asked, rhetorically: “How do you get there? Job fairs. Making yourself more attractive. Not by saying, ‘White guy, you can’t have that job because that’s reserved for a woman or [other] minority.'”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asked separately who is financing the suit, Dhillon told us in an email earlier today that “nobody but my law firm is financing the lawsuit at this time. We may choose to seek funding in the future, but neither Peter Thiel (I have been asked by others) or anyone else is involved besides my clients and my firm.” (Thiel, the billionaire investor, &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2016/05/26/business/dealbook/peter-thiel-tech-billionaire-reveals-secret-war-with-gawker.html?_r=0&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;famously financed&lt;/a&gt; multiple lawsuits against Gawker Media.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new suit isn’t the only one Google is having to defend itself against. In September, three female former Google employees &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.usatoday.com/story/tech/2017/09/14/google-hit-gender-pay-gap-lawsuit-seeking-class-action-status/666944001/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;filed a lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; against the company, saying it discriminates against women. To wit, says the suit, Google pays women at all levels of the company less than men, as well as assigns them lower job tiers with less opportunity for upward mobility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last month, a &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/01/03/google-faces-revised-gender-pay-lawsuit/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;fourth complainant&lt;/a&gt; joined their suit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Labor Department is separately investigating systemic pay discrimination at Google. The company says it hasn’t found a pay gap in its own analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read the lawsuit filed by Damore and Gudeman here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a&gt;James Damore vs. Google: Class Action Lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/a&gt; on Scribd&lt;/p&gt;

 &lt;small&gt;Featured Image: James Damore/Twitter&lt;/small&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 18:28:56 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>willwill100</dc:creator>
<og:title>James Damore just filed a class action lawsuit against Google, saying it discriminates against white male conservatives</og:title>
<og:description>James Damore, a former Google engineer who was fired in August after posting a memo to an internal Google message board arguing that women may not be equally..</og:description>
<og:image>https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/screen-shot-2018-01-08-at-10-16-45-am.png</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2018/01/08/james-damore-just-filed-a-class-action-lawsuit-against-google-saying-it-discriminates-against-white-male-conservatives/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2018/01/08/james-damore-just-filed-a-class-action-lawsuit-against-google-saying-it-discriminates-against-white-male-conservatives/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Stanford paper says rent control is driving up cost of housing in San Francisco</title>
<link>https://sf.curbed.com/2017/11/3/16603900/rent-control-san-francisco-stanford-study-gentrification</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://sf.curbed.com/2017/11/3/16603900/rent-control-san-francisco-stanford-study-gentrification</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;2Yr8tE&quot;&gt;Just as &lt;a href=&quot;https://sf.curbed.com/2017/10/25/16545952/ballot-rent-control-costa-hawkins-california&quot;&gt;California voters might overturn&lt;/a&gt; the state’s heavy-handed restrictions on new rent-control units, Stanford economists Rebecca Diamond and Tim McQuade &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mercurynews.com/2017/11/02/rent-control-policy-likely-fueled-the-gentrification-of-san-francisco-study-finds/&quot;&gt;presented a paper&lt;/a&gt; in October making the provocative argument that San Francisco rent control ultimately drove rents up citywide since 1995.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;WG0J2X&quot;&gt;But the conclusion from their findings is not necessarily that rent control is bad. Instead, the findings are a bit more complex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;Yex74W&quot;&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;http://conference.nber.org/confer//2017/PEf17/Diamond_McQuade_Qian.pdf&quot;&gt;the paper, snappily titled&lt;/a&gt; “The Effects of Rent Control Expansion on Tenants, Landlords, and Inequality: Evidence from San Francisco,” Diamond and McQuade used public and private data to look at how often people moved out of rent-control units, how often landlords converted those units to new types of housing not covered under rent control, and how median rents changed since the 1990s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;7Z181H&quot;&gt;The pair singled out SF specifically to “exploit a unique rent control expansion in San Francisco in 1994 that suddenly provided rent control protections for small multifamily housing built prior to 1980” so that renters in post-1980 homes form a natural control group with which to compare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;90M7R2&quot;&gt;Here are some of their conclusions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id=&quot;CryJy9&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rent controlled tenants are of course more likely to stay in their current homes.&lt;/strong&gt; “Rent control increased the probability a renter stayed at their address by close to 20 percent,” note Diamond and McQuade, with younger renters more likely to leave the roost anyway than older ones.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;H8GJcF&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And that in turn prevents flight from San Francisco itself.&lt;/strong&gt; “We find that absent rent control essentially all of those incentivized to stay in their apartments would have otherwise moved out of San Francisco,” note the economists. Yikes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__inner&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__image&quot; data-original=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/6587251/san-francisco-neighborhood-1459695606m8F.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;c-dynamic-image&quot; src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAUEBAAAACwAAAAAAQABAAACAkQBADs&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-chorus-optimize-field=&quot;main_image&quot; data-cid=&quot;site/dynamic_size_image-1515509092_9331_98605&quot; data-cdata=&quot;{&amp;quot;asset_id&amp;quot;:6587251,&amp;quot;ratio&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;*&amp;quot;}&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/6587251/san-francisco-neighborhood-1459695606m8F.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;e-image__meta&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.publicdomainpictures.net/view-image.php?image=157809&amp;amp;picture=san-francisco-neighborhood&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id=&quot;Nv8fFJ&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;However, in some the priciest neighborhoods, tenant turnover in rent&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;-&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;controlled apartments was actually&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;higher.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;“&lt;/strong&gt;This evidence suggests that landlords actively try to remove their tenants in those areas where the reward for resetting to market rents is greatest,” either by gamely buying out long term tenants or just evicting them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;xNLOjl&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;L&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;andlords of rent&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;-c&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ontrolled homes were more likely to convert them to the types of buildings not covered by the provisions.&lt;/strong&gt; “Landlords whose properties were exogenously covered by rent control reduced their supply of available rental housing by 15 percent.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;KuZp5A&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Particularly via the old TIC trick.&lt;/strong&gt; “Rent-controlled buildings were almost 10 percent more likely to convert to a condo or a Tenancy in Common (TIC) than buildings in the control group, representing a substantial reduction in the supply of rental housing.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;LylYUS&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Even so, rent control is definitely good for the tenants who get it, even with the added risk of landlord shenanigans.&lt;/strong&gt; “Rent control offered large benefits to impacted tenants during the 1995-2012 period, averaging between $2,300 and $6,600 per person each year, with aggregate benefits totaling over $390 million annually.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;7Ny5yW&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But the loss of housing might drive up rents elsewhere.&lt;/strong&gt; “We find that six percent decrease in housing supply led to seven percent increase in rental prices. These caused an aggregate welfare loss to renters of $5 Billion. This is almost as large as the benefits accrued by the lucky beneficiaries of rent control.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p id=&quot;7cp7nM&quot;&gt;What does it all mean? First, bear in mind that just because two economists say so doesn’t make it true. But even if we take Diamond and McQuade’s findings as fact, different parties will draw different conclusions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__inner&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__image&quot; data-original=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/9603919/470565858.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;c-dynamic-image&quot; src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAUEBAAAACwAAAAAAQABAAACAkQBADs&quot; alt=&quot;San Francisco Area Leads Nation In High Rents&quot; data-chorus-optimize-field=&quot;main_image&quot; data-cid=&quot;site/dynamic_size_image-1515509092_8423_98606&quot; data-cdata=&quot;{&amp;quot;asset_id&amp;quot;:9603919,&amp;quot;ratio&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;*&amp;quot;}&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/9603919/470565858.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;San Francisco Area Leads Nation In High Rents&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;e-image__meta&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Photo by Justin Sullivan/Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;gS2Nzj&quot;&gt;For example, the paper says that the cost to general renters was “almost” as high as the benefit to those in rent-controlled homes, but not quite. Is that trade off worth it? That may boil down to a judgment call.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;1ehfh4&quot;&gt;Some also may respond to the findings by simply suggesting further regulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;BQFRpz&quot;&gt;Jennifer Fieber, director of the San Francisco Tenants Union, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mercurynews.com/2017/11/02/rent-control-policy-likely-fueled-the-gentrification-of-san-francisco-study-finds/&quot;&gt;told the &lt;em&gt;San Jose Mercury News&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that the city or state should just make it harder for landlords to shimmy out of rent-control arrangements via TIC conversion, for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;8vUirQ&quot;&gt;On the other hand, those who have griped about rent-control laws all along will point to this research as vindication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;A7BHsX&quot;&gt;According to the urban design think tank SPUR, &lt;a href=&quot;https://sf.curbed.com/2017/10/25/16545952/ballot-rent-control-costa-hawkins-california&quot;&gt;about 45 percent&lt;/a&gt; of SF’s housing stock—roughly 172,000 units in 2014—are presently rent controlled, although the city itself keeps no official tally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id=&quot;yCLuLV&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 17:47:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>nwsm</dc:creator>
<og:description>Economists Rebecca Diamond and Tim McQuade’s study makes the provocative argument that San Francisco rent control drove rents up citywide since 1995.</og:description>
<og:image>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sSTxTkO0iXIVyQGTh3ZY1gszufo=/0x0:793x415/fit-in/1200x630/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/6824319/Houses_in_San_Francisco.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Stanford paper says rent control is driving up cost of housing in San Francisco</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://sf.curbed.com/2017/11/3/16603900/rent-control-san-francisco-stanford-study-gentrification</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://sf.curbed.com/2017/11/3/16603900/rent-control-san-francisco-stanford-study-gentrification</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>