<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Speaking to yourself in the third person makes you wiser</title>
<link>https://aeon.co/ideas/why-speaking-to-yourself-in-the-third-person-makes-you-wiser</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://aeon.co/ideas/why-speaking-to-yourself-in-the-third-person-makes-you-wiser</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;We credit Socrates with the insight that ‘the unexamined life is not worth living’ and that to ‘know thyself’ is the path to true wisdom. But is there a right and a wrong way to go about such self-reflection? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simple rumination – the process of churning your concerns around in your head – isn’t the answer. It’s likely to cause you to become stuck in the rut of your own thoughts and immersed in the emotions that might be leading you astray. Certainly, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1469029215000308&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;research&lt;/a&gt; has shown that people who are prone to rumination also often suffer from impaired decision making under pressure, and are at a substantially increased risk of depression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, the scientific research suggests that you should adopt an ancient rhetorical method favoured by the likes of Julius Caesar and known as ‘illeism’ – or speaking about yourself in the third person (the term was coined in 1809 by the poet Samuel Taylor Coleridge from the Latin &lt;em&gt;ille&lt;/em&gt; meaning ‘he, that’). If I was considering an argument that I’d had with a friend, for instance, I might start by silently thinking to myself: ‘David felt frustrated that…’ The idea is that this small change in perspective can clear your emotional fog, allowing you to see past your biases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A bulk of research has already shown that this kind of third-person thinking can temporarily improve decision making. Now a &lt;a href=&quot;https://psyarxiv.com/a5fgu&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;preprint&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;em&gt;PsyArxiv&lt;/em&gt; finds that it can also bring long-term benefits to thinking and emotional regulation. The researchers said this was ‘the first evidence that wisdom-related cognitive and affective processes can be trained in daily life, and of how to do so’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The findings are the brainchild of the psychologist Igor Grossmann at the University of Waterloo in Canada, whose work on the psychology of wisdom was one of the inspirations for my recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hodder.co.uk/titles/david-robson/the-intelligence-trap/9781473669833/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; on intelligence and how we can make wiser decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grossmann’s aim is to build a strong experimental footing for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://evidencebasedwisdom.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;study of wisdom&lt;/a&gt;, which had long been considered too nebulous for scientific enquiry. In one of his earlier experiments, he established that it’s possible to measure wise reasoning and that, as with IQ, people’s scores matter. He did this by asking participants to discuss out-loud a personal or political dilemma, which he then scored on various elements of thinking long-considered crucial to wisdom, including: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/17439760.2019.1579359&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;intellectual humility&lt;/a&gt;; taking the perspective of others; recognising uncertainty; and having the capacity to search for a compromise. Grossmann &lt;a href=&quot;https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1745691616672066&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;found&lt;/a&gt; that these wise-reasoning scores were far better than intelligence tests at predicting emotional wellbeing, and relationship satisfaction – supporting the idea that wisdom, as defined by these qualities, constitutes a unique construct that determines how we navigate life challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working with Ethan Kross at the University of Michigan in the United States, Grossmann has also looked for ways to improve these scores – with some striking experiments demonstrating the power of illeism. In a series of laboratory &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/24916084&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;experiments&lt;/a&gt;, they found that people tend to be humbler, and readier to consider other perspectives, when they are asked to describe problems in the third person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine, for instance, that you are arguing with your partner. Adopting a third-person perspective might help you to recognise their point of view or to accept the limits of your understanding of the problem at hand. Or imagine you are considering moving jobs. Taking the distanced perspective could help you to weigh up the benefits and the risks of the move more dispassionately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ld-dropcap&quot;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;his earlier research involved only short-term interventions, however – meaning it was far from clear whether wiser reasoning would become a long-term habit with regular practice at illeism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To find out, Grossmann’s latest research team asked nearly 300 participants to describe a challenging social situation, while two independent psychologists scored them on the different aspects of wise reasoning (intellectual humility, etc). The participants then had to keep a diary for four weeks. Each day, they had to describe a situation they’d just experienced, such as a disagreement with a colleague or some bad news. Half were prompted to do so in the first-person, while the others were encouraged to describe their trials from a third-person perspective. At the end of the study, all participants repeated the wise-reasoning test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grossmann’s results were exactly as he’d hoped. While the control participants showed no overall change in their wise-reasoning scores, those using illeism improved in their intellectual humility, perspective-taking and capacity to find a compromise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A further stage of the study suggested that this newfound wisdom also translated into greater emotional regulation and stability. After they had finished the four-week diary intervention, participants had to predict how their feelings of trust, frustration or anger about a close family member or friend might change over the next month – then, after that month was up, they reported back on how things had actually gone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In line with other work on ‘affective forecasting’, the people in the control condition overestimated their positive emotions and underestimated the intensity of their negative emotions over the course of the month. In contrast, those who’d kept a third-person diary were more accurate. A closer look revealed that their negative feelings, as a whole, were more muted, and that’s why their rosy predictions were more accurate. It seems their wiser reasoning had allowed them to find better ways to cope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find these emotion and relationship effects particularly fascinating, considering the fact that illeism is often considered to be infantile. Just think of Elmo in the children’s TV show &lt;em&gt;Sesame Street&lt;/em&gt;, or the intensely irritating Jimmy in the sitcom &lt;em&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/em&gt; – hardly models of sophisticated thinking. Alternatively, it can be taken to be the sign of a narcissistic personality – the very opposite of personal wisdom. After all, Coleridge believed that it was a ruse to cover up one’s own egotism: just think of the US president’s critics who point out that Donald Trump often refers to himself in the third person. Clearly, politicians might use illeism for purely rhetorical purposes but, when applied to genuine reflection, it appears to be a powerful tool for wiser reasoning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the researchers point out, it would be exciting to see whether the benefits apply to other forms of decision making besides the more personal dilemmas examined in Grossmann’s study. There’s reason to think that they might. Previous &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10899-012-9311-3&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;experiments&lt;/a&gt; have shown, for instance, that rumination leads to worse choices in poker (hence why expert players strive for a detached, emotionally distanced attitude), and that greater emotional awareness and regulation can &lt;a href=&quot;https://journals.aom.org/doi/abs/10.5465/amj.2007.26279217&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;improve&lt;/a&gt; performance on the stock market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, Grossmann’s work continues to prove that the subject of wisdom is worthy of rigorous experimental study – with potential benefits for all of us. It is notoriously difficult to increase general intelligence through brain-training, but these results suggest that wiser reasoning and better decision making are within everyone’s power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is an adaptation of an&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2019/05/24/a-new-trial-of-an-ancient-rhetorical-trick-finds-it-can-make-you-wiser/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;article&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;originally published by The British Psychological Society’s Research Digest.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2019 17:15:06 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>prostoalex</dc:creator>
<og:title>Why speaking to yourself in the third person makes you wiser – David Robson | Aeon Ideas</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://nu.aeon.co/images/80e97cbb-9cc5-4278-8338-49ea75b6c05d/idea_sized-the_mirror_by_william_merritt_chase_cincinnati_art_museum.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Wisdom and good decision making are within your power: just as soon as you start speaking of yourself in the third person</og:description>
<og:url>https://aeon.co/ideas/why-speaking-to-yourself-in-the-third-person-makes-you-wiser</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://aeon.co/ideas/why-speaking-to-yourself-in-the-third-person-makes-you-wiser</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>US Navy will replace touchscreen with mechanical controls on its destroyers</title>
<link>https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/11/20800111/us-navy-uss-john-s-mccain-crash-ntsb-report-touchscreen-mechanical-controls</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/11/20800111/us-navy-uss-john-s-mccain-crash-ntsb-report-touchscreen-mechanical-controls</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;bzC0Mw&quot;&gt;The US Navy will replace the touchscreen throttle and helm controls currently installed in its destroyers with mechanical ones starting in 2020, &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.usni.org/2019/08/09/navy-reverting-ddgs-back-to-physical-throttles-after-fleet-rejects-touchscreen-controls&quot;&gt;says &lt;em&gt;USNI News&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The move comes after the National Transportation Safety Board released an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ntsb.gov/investigations/AccidentReports/Reports/MAR1901.pdf&quot;&gt;accident report&lt;/a&gt; from a 2017 collision, which cites the design of the ship’s controls as a factor in the accident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;orAnZG&quot;&gt;On August 21st, 2017, the USS John S. McCain collided with the Alnic MC, a Liberian oil tanker, off the coast of Singapore. The report provides a detailed overview of the actions that led to the collision: when crew members tried to split throttle and steering control between consoles, they lost control of the ship, putting it into the path of the tanker. The crash killed 10 sailors and injured 48 aboard the McCain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;jSCHbc&quot;&gt;The report says that while fatigue and lack of training played a role in the accident, the design of the ship’s control console were also contributing factors. Located in the middle of the McCain’s bridge, the Ship’s Control Console (SCC) features a pair of touch-screens on both the Helm and Lee Helm stations, through which the crew could steer and propel the ship. Investigators found that the crew had placed it in “backup manual mode,” which removed computer-assisted help, because it allowed for “more direct form of communication between steering and the SSC.” That setting meant that any crew member at another station could take over steering operations, and when the crew tried to regain control of the ship from multiple stations, control “shifted from the lee helm, to aft steering, to the helm, and back to aft steering.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;c-float-right&quot;&gt;
&lt;aside id=&quot;pNNLs7&quot;&gt;&lt;q&gt;The ship’s touchscreen controls and procedures were overly complicated&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;x6oAhS&quot;&gt;The NTSB report calls out the configuration of the bridge’s systems, pointing out that the decision to transfer controls while in the strait helped lead to the accident, and that the procedures for transferring the controls from one station to another were complicated, further contributing to the confusion. Specifically, the board points to the touchscreens on the bridge, noting that mechanical throttles are generally preferred because “they provide both immediate and tactile feedback to the operator.” The report notes that had mechanical controls been present, the helmsmen would have likely been alerted that there was an issue early on, and recommends that the Navy better adhere to better design standards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;mYiKd8&quot;&gt;Following the incident, the Navy conducted fleet-wide surveys, and according to Rear Admiral Bill Galinis, the Program Executive Officer for Ships, personnel indicated that they would prefer mechanical controls. Speaking before a recent Navy symposium, he described the controls as falling under the “‘just because you can doesn’t mean you should’ category,” and that ship systems were simply too complicated. He also noted that they’re looking into the design of other ships to see if they can bring some system commonalities between different ship classes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;c-float-left&quot;&gt;
&lt;aside id=&quot;mWXxtt&quot;&gt;&lt;q&gt;The Navy will begin to replace the controls in the summer of 2020&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;uKCXno&quot;&gt;Admiral Galinis tells &lt;em&gt;USNI News&lt;/em&gt; that plans are currently underway to switch out the systems. “We’re already in the contracting process, and it’s going to come on almost as a kit that’s relatively easy to install.” According to the Naval Sea Systems Command, all &lt;em&gt;Arleigh Burke&lt;/em&gt; class destroyers with the Integrated Bridge and Navigation System will get physical throttles, beginning in the summer of 2020 with the USS &lt;em&gt;Ramage.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;g9Vcwm&quot;&gt;Touchscreens weren’t the only issue in the collision: the report calls out that several crew members on the bridge at the time weren’t familiar with the systems that they were overseeing and were inexperienced in their roles, and that many were fatigued, with an average of 4.9 hours of sleep between the 14 crew members present. The report recommended that the Navy conduct better training for the bridge systems, update the controls and associated documentation, and ensure that Navy personnel aren’t tired when they’re on the job.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2019 15:31:21 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Grazester</dc:creator>
<og:description>After a deadly 2017 crash between a destroyer and an oil tanker</og:description>
<og:image>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IpVPgBI6GUbCg0_gATxXv26z9Ss=/0x216:2100x1315/fit-in/1200x630/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/18959435/5751712103_a924c2cab4_o.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>The US Navy will replace its touchscreen controls with mechanical ones on its destroyers</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/11/20800111/us-navy-uss-john-s-mccain-crash-ntsb-report-touchscreen-mechanical-controls</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/11/20800111/us-navy-uss-john-s-mccain-crash-ntsb-report-touchscreen-mechanical-controls</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Insect &amp;#039;apocalypse&amp;#039; in U.S. driven by 50x increase in toxic pesticides: study</title>
<link>https://www.nationalgeographic.com/environment/2019/08/insect-apocalypse-under-way-toxic-pesticides-agriculture/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nationalgeographic.com/environment/2019/08/insect-apocalypse-under-way-toxic-pesticides-agriculture/</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nationalgeographic.com/environment/2019/08/insect-apocalypse-under-way-toxic-pesticides-agriculture/&quot;&gt;https://www.nationalgeographic.com/environment/2019/08/insect-apocalypse-under-way-toxic-pesticides-agriculture/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20667031&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20667031&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 682&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 277&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2019 08:16:25 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>whatami</dc:creator>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nationalgeographic.com/environment/2019/08/insect-apocalypse-under-way-toxic-pesticides-agriculture/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Black Hat Talk About ‘Time AI’ Causes Uproar, Is Deleted by Conference</title>
<link>https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/8xw9kp/black-hat-talk-about-time-ai-causes-uproar-is-deleted-by-conference</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/8xw9kp/black-hat-talk-about-time-ai-causes-uproar-is-deleted-by-conference</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Attendees at the Black Hat security conference in Las Vegas ridiculed a sponsored talk where the speaker made questionable claims about a new and innovative encryption method on Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robert Grant, of a company called Crown Sterling, gave a talk titled: &quot;The 2019 Discovery of Quasi-Prime Numbers: What Does This Mean For Encryption?&quot; in which he explained a mysterious technology called “Time AI.” After attendees criticized it, the conference took it down from its website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/veorq/status/1159559785068429312?s=12&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;People in attendance&lt;/a&gt;, as well as &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ncweaver/status/1160225585051783170&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;security researchers&lt;/a&gt; who were following it on Twitter, made fun of the talk and criticized the conference for letting Grant speak. Dan Guido, the CEO of cyber security consulting firm Trail of Bits even got up and challenged the speaker, accusing him of potentially putting people in danger by pitching an unproven encryption technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They’re scamming people. They’re here to use Black Hat to trick people into giving them money. It’s fraud,” Guido said in an interview after the talk. “Other people in the audience tried to reason with them, that the math isn’t right etc, but they don’t care about that. It’s offensive, and they shouldn’t get the benefit of using our names and our event to commit fraud.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Motherboard was not in attendance at the talk. Guido and others tweeted about it as it was happening, describing claims that are similar to those Crown Sterling makes in the video below, which features a collection of math and cryptography buzzwords—such as “infinite wave conjugations,” and “quasi prime numbers.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They look like scam artists,” Steve Weis, a cryptographer who used to work at Facebook said ahead of the talk, after reviewing material posted by the company online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The uproar caused by the attendees forced the organizers of Black Hat to respond, taking down the talk’s materials from its site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We are aware of the situation with the Crown Sterling talk and have removed it from our website,” a Black Hat spokesperson said in an email. “Content discussed in Black Hat sponsored sessions are determined by the individual sponsor, however, we are working to implement a stronger vetting process moving forward to avoid this happening in the future.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;article__blockquote&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have a tip about a data breach or a security incident? You can contact Lorenzo Franceschi-Bicchierai securely on Signal at +1 917 257 1382, OTR chat at lorenzofb@jabber.ccc.de, or email lorenzofb@vice.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usually, talks submitted to Black Hat go through a thorough approval process managed by a review board of industry experts. But, as in this case, companies can also pay to play and get these sponsored talks, which are not vetted for quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On its part, Crown Sterling is denying any wrongdoing, and defending its technology and talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We stand by the accuracy of the talk and will continue to do so,” a Crown Sterling spokesperson said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The speaker, Grant, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Robert_E_Grant_&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;is also defending his talk on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Subscribe to our new cybersecurity podcast,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/gb/podcast/cyber/id1441708044?mt=2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;CYBER&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2019 03:34:16 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>lnguyen</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Black Hat Talk About ‘Time AI’ Causes Uproar, Is Deleted By Conference</og:title>
<og:image>https://video-images.vice.com/articles/5d4f2e1c4324cc000aed1473/lede/1565470630768-image.png?crop=0.864339065485496xw:1xh;center,center&amp;resize=1200:*</og:image>
<og:url>https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/8xw9kp/black-hat-talk-about-time-ai-causes-uproar-is-deleted-by-conference</og:url>
<og:description>A controversial sponsored talk at the Black Hat security conference caused an uproar among security professionals and prompted the conference to delete the talk from the internet.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/8xw9kp/black-hat-talk-about-time-ai-causes-uproar-is-deleted-by-conference</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Uber, losing billions, freezes engineering hires</title>
<link>https://arstechnica.com/cars/2019/08/uber-freezes-engineering-hires-amid-mounting-losses/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://arstechnica.com/cars/2019/08/uber-freezes-engineering-hires-amid-mounting-losses/</guid>
<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/GettyImages-182636183-800x533.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A man in an open-collared suit smirks.&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/GettyImages-182636183.jpg&quot; class=&quot;enlarge-link&quot; data-height=&quot;2667&quot; data-width=&quot;4000&quot;&gt;Enlarge&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;sep&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; Dara Khosrowshahi, shown here in 2013, is CEO of Uber.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;aside id=&quot;social-left&quot; aria-label=&quot;Read the comments or share this article&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;comment-count-before&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;135 posters participating&quot; class=&quot;comment-count icon-comment-bubble-down&quot; href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/cars/2019/08/uber-freezes-engineering-hires-amid-mounting-losses/?comments=1&quot;&gt;reader comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;a title=&quot;135 posters participating&quot; class=&quot;comment-count icon-comment-bubble-down&quot; href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/cars/2019/08/uber-freezes-engineering-hires-amid-mounting-losses/?comments=1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;comment-count-number&quot;&gt;193&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;with 135 posters participating&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;share-links&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Share this story&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Uber is freezing hiring for software engineers and product managers across its US and Canadian workforce, the company &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-08-09/uber-freezes-hiring-of-u-s-tech-staff-as-it-seeks-to-cut-costs&quot;&gt;acknowledged to Bloomberg&lt;/a&gt; on Friday. The shift was &lt;a href=&quot;https://finance.yahoo.com/news/uber-imposes-engineer-hiring-freeze-as-losses-mount-exclusive-202234064.html&quot;&gt;reported by Yahoo&lt;/a&gt; earlier in the day. The freeze does not apply to Uber's autonomous vehicle and freight-shipping divisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The news comes a day after Uber reported &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/cars/2019/08/uber-loses-5-billion-in-q2-2019-despite-big-uptick-in-trips/&quot;&gt;second-quarter operating losses of $5.4 billion&lt;/a&gt;—a new record for the company. That figure exaggerates Uber's quarterly burn rate because it includes more than $4 billion in one-time charges related to Uber's initial public offering. Still, excluding IPO-related charges still leaves around $1.2 billion in operating losses, worse than the &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/cars/2019/05/uber-lost-another-1-billion-last-quarter/&quot;&gt;$1 billion the firm lost&lt;/a&gt; in the first quarter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uber recently &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/07/29/technology/uber-job-cuts.html&quot;&gt;laid off 400 marketing workers&lt;/a&gt;. According to Yahoo, Uber employees are worried that this could be a prelude to broader cuts as the company struggles to stem its losses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;During a recent all-hands meeting, a question about potential layoffs in the engineering department was also raised, but executives didn't provide any timelines,&quot; Yahoo's Krystal Hu reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uber is in no immediate financial danger. Despite years of losses, Uber had $13.7 billion in the bank at the end of the second quarter—a figure boosted by $8 billion in Uber's IPO. With that much cash in the bank, Uber can continue at its current burn rate for more than two years. But CEO Dara Khosrowshahi will face pressure from Wall Street to stem Uber's losses much sooner than that.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2019 00:27:52 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>0xffff2</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://arstechnica.com/cars/2019/08/uber-freezes-engineering-hires-amid-mounting-losses/</og:url>
<og:title>Uber, losing billions, freezes engineering hires</og:title>
<og:image>https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/GettyImages-182636183-760x380.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Uber has been burning cash at more than $1 billion per quarter.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://arstechnica.com/cars/2019/08/uber-freezes-engineering-hires-amid-mounting-losses/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Get your work recognized: write a brag document</title>
<link>https://jvns.ca/blog/brag-documents/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://jvns.ca/blog/brag-documents/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;There’s this idea that, if you do great work at your job, people will (or should!) automatically recognize that work and reward you for it with promotions / increased pay. In practice, it’s often more complicated than that – some kinds of important work are more visible/memorable than others. It’s frustrating to have done something really important and later realize that you didn’t get rewarded for it just because the people making the decision didn’t understand or remember what you did. So I want to talk about a tactic that I and lots of people I work with have used!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This blog post isn’t just about being promoted or getting raises though. The ideas here have actually been more useful to me to help me reflect on themes in my work, what’s important to me, what I’m learning, and what I’d like to be doing differently. But they’ve definitely helped with promotions!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also &lt;a href=&quot;https://jvns.ca/blog/brag-documents/#template&quot;&gt;skip to the brag document template at the end&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;you-don-t-remember-everything-you-did&quot;&gt;you don’t remember everything you did&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I’m always struck by when it comes to performance review time is a feeling of “wait, what &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; I do in the last 6 months?“. This is a kind of demoralizing feeling and it’s usually not based in reality, more in “I forgot what cool stuff I actually did”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I invariably end up having to spend a bunch of time looking through my pull requests, tickets, launch emails, design documents, and more. I always end up finding small (and sometimes not-so-small) things that I completely forgot I did, like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;mentored an intern 5 months ago&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;did a small-but-important security project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;spent a few weeks helping get an important migration over the line&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;helped X put together this design doc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;etcetera!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;your-manager-doesn-t-remember-everything-you-did&quot;&gt;your manager doesn’t remember everything you did&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you don’t remember everything important you did, your manager (no matter how great they are!) probably doesn’t either. And they need to explain to other people why you should be promoted or given an evaluation like “exceeds expectations” (“X’s work is so awesome!!!!” doesn’t fly).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if your manager is going to effectively advocate for you, they need help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;here-s-the-tactic-write-a-document-listing-your-accomplishments&quot;&gt;here’s the tactic: write a document listing your accomplishments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tactic is pretty simple! Instead of trying to remember everything you did with your brain, maintain a “brag document” that lists everything so you can refer to it when you get to performance review season! This is a pretty common tactic – when I started doing this I mentioned it to more experienced people and they were like “oh yeah, I’ve been doing that for a long time, it really helps”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where I work we call this a “brag document” but I’ve heard other names for the same concept like “hype document” or “list of stuff I did” :).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a basic template for a brag document at the end of this post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;share-your-brag-document-with-your-manager&quot;&gt;share your brag document with your manager&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first wrote a brag document I was kind of nervous about sharing it with my manager. It felt weird to be like “hey, uh, look at all the awesome stuff I did this year, I wrote a long document listing everything”. But my manager was really thankful for it – I think his perspective was “this makes my job way easier, now I can look at the document when writing your perf review instead of trying to remember what happened”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Giving them a document that explains your accomplishments will really help your manager advocate for you in discussions about your performance and come to any meetings they need to have prepared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brag documents also &lt;strong&gt;really&lt;/strong&gt; help with manager transitions – if you get a new manager 3 months before an important performance review that you want to do well on, giving them a brag document outlining your most important work &amp;amp; its impact will help them understand what you’ve been doing even though they may not have been aware of any of your work before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;share-it-with-your-peer-reviewers&quot;&gt;share it with your peer reviewers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, if your company does peer feedback as part of the promotion/perf process – share your brag document with your peer reviewers!! Every time someone shares their doc with me I find it SO HELPFUL with writing their review for much the same reasons it’s helpful to share it with your manager – it reminds me of all the amazing things they did, and when they list their goals in their brag document it also helps me see what areas they might be most interested in feedback on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On some teams at work it’s a team norm to share a brag document with peer reviewers to make it easier for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;explain-the-big-picture&quot;&gt;explain the big picture&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to just listing accomplishments, in your brag document you can write the narrative explaining the big picture of your work. Have you been really focused on security? On building your product skills &amp;amp; having really good relationships with your users? On building a strong culture of code review on the team?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my brag document, I like to do this by making a section for areas that I’ve been focused on (like “security”) and listing all the work I’ve done in that area there. This is especially good if you’re working on something fuzzy like “building a stronger culture of code review” where all the individual actions you do towards that might be relatively small and there isn’t a big shiny ship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;use-your-brag-document-to-notice-patterns&quot;&gt;use your brag document to notice patterns&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past I’ve found the brag document useful not just to hype my accomplishments, but also to reflect on the work I’ve done. Some questions it’s helped me with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;What work do I feel most proud of?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are there themes in these projects I should be thinking about? What’s the big picture of what I’m working on? (am I working a lot on security? localization?).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What do I wish I was doing more / less of?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which of my projects had the effect I wanted, and which didn’t? Why might that have been?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What could have gone better with project X? What might I want to do differently next time?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;you-can-write-it-all-at-once-or-update-it-every-2-weeks&quot;&gt;you can write it all at once or update it every 2 weeks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people have told me that it works best for them if they take a few minutes to update their brag document every 2 weeks ago. For me it actually works better to do a single marathon session every 6 months or every year where I look through everything I did and reflect on it all at once. Try out different approaches and see what works for you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;don-t-forget-to-include-the-fuzzy-work&quot;&gt;don’t forget to include the fuzzy work&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of us work on fuzzy projects that can feel hard to quantify, like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;improving code quality on the team / making code reviews a little more in depth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;making on call easier&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;building a more fair interview process / performance review system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;refactoring / driving down technical debt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;A lot of people will leave this kind of work out because they don’t know how to explain why it’s important. But I think this kind of work is especially important to put into your brag document because it’s the most likely to fall under the radar! One way to approach this is to, for each goal:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;explain your goal for the work (why do you think it’s important to refactor X piece of code?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;list some things you’ve done towards that goal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;list any effects you’ve seen of the work, even if they’re a little indirect&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you tell your coworkers this kind of work is important to you and tell them what you’ve been doing, maybe they can also give you ideas about how to do it more effectively or make the effects of that work more obvious!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;encourage-each-other-to-celebrate-accomplishments&quot;&gt;encourage each other to celebrate accomplishments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One nice side effect of having a shared idea that it’s normal/good to maintain a brag document at work is that I sometimes see people encouraging each other to record &amp;amp; celebrate their accomplishments (“hey, you should put that in your brag doc, that was really good!”). It can be hard to see the value of your work sometimes, especially when you’re working on something hard, and an outside perspective from a friend or colleague can really help you see why what you’re doing is important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brag documents are good when you use them on your own to advocate for yourself, but I think they’re better as a collaborative effort to recognize where people are excelling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, I want to talk about a couple of structures that we’ve used to help people recognize their accomplishments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-brag-workshop-help-people-list-their-accomplishments&quot;&gt;the brag workshop: help people list their accomplishments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way this “brag document” practice started in the first place is that my coworker &lt;a href=&quot;https://karla.io/&quot;&gt;Karla&lt;/a&gt; and I wanted to help other women in engineering advocate for themselves more in the performance review process. The idea is that some people undersell their accomplishments more than they should, so we wanted to encourage those people to “brag” a little bit and write down what they did that was important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We did this by running a “brag workshop” just before performance review season. The format of the workshop is like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Part 1: write the document: 1-2 hours&lt;/strong&gt;. Everybody sits down with their laptop, starts looking through their pull requests, tickets they resolved, design docs, etc, and puts together a list of important things they did in the last 6 months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Part 2: pair up and make the impact of your work clearer: 1 hour&lt;/strong&gt;. The goal of this part is to pair up, review each other’s documents, and identify places where people haven’t bragged “enough” – maybe they worked on an extremely critical project to the company but didn’t highlight how important it was, maybe they improved test performance but didn’t say that they made the tests 3 times faster and that it improved everyone’s developer experience. It’s easy to accidentally write “I shipped $feature” and miss the follow up (“… which caused $thing to happen”). Another person reading through your document can help you catch the places where you need to clarify the impact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;biweekly-brag-document-writing-session&quot;&gt;biweekly brag document writing session&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another approach to helping people remember their accomplishments: my friend Dave gets some friends together every couple of weeks or so for everyone to update their brag documents. It’s a nice way for people to talk about work that they’re happy about &amp;amp; celebrate it a little bit, and updating your brag document as you go can be easier than trying to remember everything you did all at once at the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These don’t have to be people in the same company or even in the same city – that group meets over video chat and has people from many different companies doing this together from Portland, Toronto, New York, and Montreal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, especially if you’re someone who really cares about your work, I think it’s really positive to share your goals &amp;amp; accomplishments (and the things that haven’t gone so well too!) with your friends and coworkers. It makes it feel less like you’re working alone and more like everyone is supporting each other in helping them accomplish what they want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;thanks&quot;&gt;thanks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Karla Burnett who I worked with on spreading this idea at work, to Dave Vasilevsky for running brag doc writing sessions, to Will Larson who encouraged me to start one &lt;a href=&quot;https://lethain.com/career-narratives/&quot;&gt;of these&lt;/a&gt; in the first place, to my manager Jay Shirley for always being encouraging &amp;amp; showing me that this is a useful way to work with a manager, and to Allie, Dan, Laura, Julian, Kamal, Stanley, and Vaibhav for reading a draft of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d also recommend the blog post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.aashni.me/2019/01/hype-yourself-youre-worth-it/&quot;&gt;Hype Yourself! You’re Worth It!&lt;/a&gt; by Aashni Shah which talks about a similar approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a template for a brag document! Usually I make one brag document per year. (“Julia’s 2017 brag document”). I think it’s okay to make it quite long / comprehensive – 5-10 pages or more for a year of work doesn’t seem like too much to me, especially if you’re including some graphs/charts / screenshots to show the effects of what you did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I want to emphasize, for people who don’t like to brag, is – &lt;strong&gt;you don’t have to try to make your work sound better than it is&lt;/strong&gt;. Just make it sound &lt;strong&gt;exactly as good as it is&lt;/strong&gt;! For example “was the primary contributor to X new feature that’s now used by 60% of our customers and has gotten Y positive feedback”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;goals-for-this-year&quot;&gt;Goals for this year:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;List your major goals here! Sharing your goals with your manager &amp;amp; coworkers is really nice because it helps them see how they can support you in accomplishing those goals!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;goals-for-next-year&quot;&gt;Goals for next year&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;If it’s getting towards the end of the year, maybe start writing down what you think your goals for next year might be.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;projects&quot;&gt;Projects&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For each one, go through:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;What your contributions were (did you come up with the design? Which components did you build? Was there some useful insight like “wait, we can cut scope and do what we want by doing way less work” that you came up with?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The impact of the project – who was it for? Are there numbers you can attach to it? (saved X dollars? shipped new feature that has helped sell Y big deals? Improved performance by X%? Used by X internal users every day?). Did it support some important non-numeric company goal (required to pass an audit? helped retain an important user?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Remember: don’t forget to explain what the results of you work actually were! It’s often important to go back a few months later and fill in what actually happened after you launched the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;collaboration-mentorship&quot;&gt;Collaboration &amp;amp; mentorship&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples of things in this category:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Helping others in an area you’re an expert in (like “other engineers regularly ask me for one-off help solving weird bugs in their CSS” or “quoting from the C standard at just the right moment”)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mentoring interns / helping new team members get started&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Writing really clear emails/meeting notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Foundational code that other people built on top of&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improving monitoring / dashboards / on call&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any code review that you spent a particularly long time on / that you think was especially important&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Important questions you answered (“helped Risha from OTHER_TEAM with a lot of questions related to Y”)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mentoring someone on a project (“gave Ben advice from time to time on leading his first big project”)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Giving an internal talk or workshop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;design-documentation&quot;&gt;Design &amp;amp; documentation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;List design docs &amp;amp; documentation that you worked on&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Design docs: I usually just say “wrote design for X” or “reviewed design for X”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation: maybe briefly explain the goal behind this documentation (for example “we were getting a lot of questions about X, so I documented it and now we can answer the questions more quickly”)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;company-building&quot;&gt;Company building&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a category we have at work – it basically means “things you did to help the company overall, not just your project / team”. Some things that go in here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Going above &amp;amp; beyond with interviewing or recruiting (doing campus recruiting, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improving important processes, like the interview process or writing better onboarding materials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-you-learned&quot;&gt;What you learned&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My friend Julian suggested this section and I think it’s a great idea – try listing important things you learned or skills you’ve acquired recently! Some examples of skills you might be learning or improving:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;how to do performance analysis &amp;amp; make code run faster&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;internals of an important piece of software (like the JVM or Postgres or Linux)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how to use a library (like React)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how to use an important tool (like the command line or Firefox dev tools)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;about a specific area of programming (like localization or timezones)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an area like product management / UX design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how to write a clear design doc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a new programming language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s really easy to lose track of what skills you’re learning, and usually when I reflect on this I realize I learned a lot more than I thought and also notice things that I’m &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; learning that I wish I was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;outside-of-work&quot;&gt;Outside of work&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s also often useful to track accomplishments outside of work, like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;blog posts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;talks/panels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;open source work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Industry recognition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think this can be a nice way to highlight how you’re thinking about your career outside of strictly what you’re doing at work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This can also include other non-career-related things you’re proud of, if that feels good to you! Some people like to keep a combined personal + work brag document.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;general-prompts&quot;&gt;General prompts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re feeling stuck for things to mention, try:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;If you were trying to convince a friend to come join your company/team, what would you tell them about your work?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did anybody tell you you did something well recently?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 23:41:13 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>yesenadam</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://jvns.ca/blog/brag-documents/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Companies Use Borrowed Billions to Buy Back Stock, Not to Invest</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-08-08/companies-use-borrowed-billions-to-buy-back-stock-not-to-invest</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-08-08/companies-use-borrowed-billions-to-buy-back-stock-not-to-invest</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-08-08/companies-use-borrowed-billions-to-buy-back-stock-not-to-invest&quot;&gt;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-08-08/companies-use-borrowed-billions-to-buy-back-stock-not-to-invest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20664553&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20664553&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 312&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 316&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 21:14:32 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>JumpCrisscross</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/tosv2.html?vid=&amp;uuid=cb767950-bc9c-11e9-acc3-e7e916f48f04&amp;url=L25ld3MvYXJ0aWNsZXMvMjAxOS0wOC0wOC9jb21wYW5pZXMtdXNlLWJvcnJvd2VkLWJpbGxpb25zLXRvLWJ1eS1iYWNrLXN0b2NrLW5vdC10by1pbnZlc3Q=</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Problem at Yale Is Not Free Speech</title>
<link>https://palladiummag.com/2019/08/05/the-real-problem-at-yale-is-not-free-speech</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://palladiummag.com/2019/08/05/the-real-problem-at-yale-is-not-free-speech</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;When I saw him, he was outside Payne Whitney. Nothing about the tall, gray façade suggests it is the university gym, unless there is a new trend of contractors housing athletics departments in Gothic cathedrals. You wouldn’t guess by looking at the frosted glass panes and arches that the third floor hosts the world’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yalebulldogs.com/information/facilities/payne_whitney_gym/pools&quot;&gt;largest suspended indoor swimming pool&lt;/a&gt;. It is a work of art, like the rest of Yale’s buildings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marcus was smoking by a bench, his face jaundiced from three packs that day. This is atypical for Yale students—most abstain from smoking. There was no reason for him to smoke so much, just as there was no reason for me to ride around campus on a blue Razor scooter. But Yale students tend to have such quirks. His suit-jacket was dusty and smelled of sweat—he didn’t mind lifting weights in a dress shirt and trousers if that meant more time to read Nietzsche alone at the bar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I hugged him, he felt skeletal. I asked if he had eaten today. He assured me that his earthly requirements were limited—no need for anything other than alcohol and cigarettes. “I can buy you a sandwich.” He refused. I insisted. A nice one. Bacon and egg. Or steak and cheese. I was testy now. “GHeav is right there. I’ll be back in six minutes.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He turned his face towards me, warm with friendliness—and with one sentence, he changed our relationship forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You know I’m rich, right?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You know I have a trust fund, right? I can buy my own sandwich if I wanted it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the moment when after three years of friendship, Marcus sat down and told me his life story. His cottages in Norway. Sneaking into the family study. Learning about the cost of hardwoods and hearing his boorish, critical father sulk in 5-star hotel rooms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marcus did not act this way out of anxiety, grief, stress, or because he had nobody to tell him his habits will kill him. He lived as a starving writer not out of necessity, but for the aesthetic. Out of some desire to imitate the Bohemian 19th century writers. Out of artistry. Style. Intentional choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of income at Yale, I was in the bottom 2%. And the people to whom I extended my generosity did not need it, whatsoever. This is mildly entertaining, but not the point. This is not a story about me, or about Marcus, or about our amusing adventures at Yale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a story about an institution and an elite that have lost themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;***&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The top universities can’t keep out of national news. Just in the past few months, there have been several high-profile stories about Yale and Harvard. Harvard is being sued for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/04/04/us/harvard-asian-admission.html&quot;&gt;discrimination&lt;/a&gt; against Asians. Yale is being &lt;a href=&quot;https://yaledailynews.com/blog/2019/02/13/female-students-sue-yale-frats/&quot;&gt;sued&lt;/a&gt; for not admitting women into its fraternities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These scandals have been framed as a consequence of the culture wars. Left versus right. Political correctness versus free speech. Empathy and inclusion versus economic realities. Students fighting for social and racial justice against morally bankrupt faculty and administrators. But after attending Yale for some of the larger scandals in recent years, these dichotomies ring hollow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past decade, elite colleges have been staging grounds for what Matthew Yglesias has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/2019/3/22/18259865/great-awokening-white-liberals-race-polling-trump-2020&quot;&gt;termed the Great Awokening&lt;/a&gt;. Dozens of scandals have illustrated a stifling new ideological orthodoxy that is trickling down into the rest of society through HR departments, corporations, churches, foundations, and activist organizations. The nation is becoming polarized and its parts disconnected. The right is evil, and the left is stupid. Or is it the other way around?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The campus “free speech” debate is just a side-effect. So are debates about “diversity” and “inclusion.” The real problems run much deeper. The real problems start with Marcus and me, and the masks we wear for each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;***&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story of how I ended up at Yale is not typical. Yale’s tuition costs $50,000 per year, but if a student’s parents earn less than $60,000, they can attend virtually for free. This means that for the poorer subset of American society, Yale is not just cheaper than the state school, but cheaper than community college. Through the magic of the universe, I figured this out, and I wanted to go. I wanted to leave my small town, and I had the SAT score to try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/projects/college-mobility/yale-university&quot;&gt;statistics&lt;/a&gt; from the class of 2013, approximately 2% of students hailed from the lowest income quintile, while 69% came from the top 20%. How did those poor students fare after graduation? Around 2% of students at Yale move from the bottom to the top quintile. In other words, nearly all of them. You show up poor, and you leave rich. Going to an Ivy League school may be the fastest way to join the upper class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But this low number of 2% surprised me because when I was at Yale, everybody kept talking about how broke they were.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Want to go out for brunch?” “I can’t—I’m so broke.” This was a common line. Sometimes the conversations had a more accusatory tone. “Wow, you took a taxi to the airport? I always take the subway.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poor people—actually poor people—don’t talk this way. They tend to stay under the radar because they don’t know the rules of the game. But I bought it—at least when I was a freshman. If they were constantly announcing how broke they were, my assumption was that they must have even less money than I do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This turned out to be wrong. The reality was that they were invariably from the upper-middle and upper classes. I know this because they eventually told me, like Marcus did. But there were tells. These students didn’t act the way my friends and I did growing up. They didn’t know how much pens or flights or cars were supposed to cost. They couldn’t tell when a restaurant was a good deal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pretending to be poor is a lot easier than pretending to be rich—just because there are so many different ways to be poor. But there are still small quirks you have to get right. Social class doesn’t just influence how you walk and talk; it influences how you interact with others. The stereotype is that poor people are improper—but sometimes it is the opposite. They try to do things as they think they are meant to be done. Spending a hundred hours building bat wings for a Halloween costume. Renting a limo for their child’s prom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But lying about anything is tricky—you risk being found out—so what were these people trying to accomplish by acting broke? And this raises the broader question: why pretend to be of a social class you are not?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Benefits Of Being Poor&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The usual answer is that rich people need safety. A Saudi billionaire wants to avoid being kidnapped, so he keeps a low profile. But that same Saudi billionaire still needs to demonstrate his status somehow to make friends and business contacts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were bodyguards at Yale who lived in nice, off-campus apartments next to their assigned student’s off-campus penthouse. These students were briefed by their parents about what to discuss publicly, and what to keep private. The point was to disguise their status-signals, so they would appear to be smaller targets. These are the hyper-rich.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What about the regular rich? Not the children of billionaires, but the children of millionaires. The common impulse is to emulate the people one or two levels above you—so they might also act poorer than they are. But whereas the super-rich learned purposeful discretion from their parents at weekly dinner table meetings, the regular rich did not. They learned it through mimicry—and with varying degrees of success. The less sophisticated copycats end up brazenly proclaiming that they are “broke” and “upper-middle class.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For some people, this isn’t an act; they actually believe this. After all, they do seem poor when compared to the hyper-rich. They can’t afford spontaneous Spring Break trips to private Bali islands. They see their prep-school classmates’ Facebook photos and realize that they are one, or maybe two, pegs down from that, and so they use the term “upper-middle class” without really knowing what this term refers to. They have no idea how the actual upper-middle class, the middle class, or the poor really live. Those students never went to their prep school, so for all intents and purposes, they do not exist. Like Krasnoyarsk, Siberia—we know it exists. We can find it on a map. But we don’t need to concern ourselves with it. Often, this is what the real poor are to rich people—they are a theoretical construct that exists somewhere else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;***&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poor people pretend to be rich to look cool. Go visit the Russians on Brighton Beach in their tank tops and gold chains. Rich people pretend to be poor to fit in. Go to San Francisco and play a round of “Homeless or tech billionaire.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But bizarre effects emerge when signals are mixed up. In particular, I have seen bizarre effects from mixed-up wealth signaling structures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most noticeable one was that nobody believed me whenever I said I was broke. I usually kept this to myself during my time in college, but sometimes, in strange circumstances, it would come up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once, I was shamed in front of a crowd for not donating to a society—even when I had donated a different gift just a day ago—and I confided my feelings to a close friend. His response: “What, so you’re upper-middle-class?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In another instance, I was privately discussing with a professor the pros and cons of a Food Stamp reform proposal. After some analysis, I commented on my own experience with the program. His response was complete shock. “You don’t really mean you were on welfare. You just mean you were supported by your parents, right?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a world of masks and façades, it is hard to convey the truth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this is how I ended up offering a sandwich to a man with hundreds of millions in a foreign bank account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But are the bizarre effects of distorted wealth signaling all that bad? Society is complicated, and there is miscommunication in every interaction. Being vague about your social class, and assuming other people are also being vague, can be useful—just as white lies, and sometimes actual lies, can be useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the surface, there is nothing wrong with haphazard and sometimes warped class signaling. But if you put on a façade for long enough, you end up forgetting that it is a façade. The rich and powerful actually start believing that they are neither of those things. They actually start believing that there is not much difference in status and resources between themselves and the upper-middle class, the middle class—and eventually, between themselves and the actual poor. They forget that they have certain privileges and duties that others do not. They forget that the inside joke was just a joke all along.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When do the rich lose sight of their status? For most people, it starts well before Yale. One incident stands out from my high school years. I had attended a summer program at the Center for Talented Youth at Princeton and befriended a well-spoken boy of 17 from Hartford. The other students mocked him—not for being poor, but for being &lt;em&gt;too rich&lt;/em&gt;. They would elevate their voices into a high-pitched taunt to mock his prestigious prep-school. I was angry, but didn’t know what to say at the time. I had no idea that these students were themselves from Harvard-Westlake, a prestigious and prohibitively expensive private school in Beverly Hills. I had no idea that these kids were even richer than the boy they were mocking. The only difference was that my friend showed the tells of his class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When these kids grow up, they end up &lt;a href=&quot;https://palladiummag.com/2019/02/02/a-trip-behind-the-spectacle-at-davos/&quot;&gt;at conferences&lt;/a&gt; where everybody lifts their champagne glasses to speeches about how we all need to “tear down the Man!” How we need to usurp conventional power structures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You hear about these events. They sound good. It’s important to think about how to improve the world. But when you look around at the men and women in their suits and dresses, with their happy, hopeful expressions, you notice that these are the exact same people with the power—they are the Man supposedly causing all those problems that they are giving feel-good speeches about. They are the kids from Harvard-Westlake who never realized they were themselves the elite. They are the people with power who fail to comprehend the meaning of that power. They are abdicating responsibility, and they don’t even know it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Normal class dynamics shouldn’t trouble anyone. It doesn’t do much damage to society for the rich to sometimes hide their status to stay safe, or for the poor to pretend that they are richer than they are to fit in with their idols.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But something else is going on—something more systemic. We mock each other over wealth and mannerisms, to the point that we forget how and why wealth is built in the first place. We forget the extent of our own power and start blaming an ephemeral elite beyond ourselves for the ills of society. And when something does need to be challenged in elite thought, not in the fake, recuperated way that Greta Thunberg ritually challenges an already-supportive crowd at Davos, but in the real way that carries personal risk—we bail. When we see an unfashionable truth that may risk criticism or ostracism, we forget our own position of strength and assume we cannot bear those risks. We give up the fight before it even starts—as if somebody else can or will fight it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is what can lead to societal dysfunction. But it is also a symptom of that dysfunction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bad Times Make Bad Elites&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is another reason why people might pretend to be poor. This reason is much more serious than fitting in or avoiding hitmen. The rich and powerful are expected to take responsibility for things, and blamed when they go wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Check your privilege.” Just about every college student has heard this phrase since 2013. What it means is evasive. But like most memes that strike a chord with people—there is some point to it. The rich have privileges. They therefore also have responsibilities. The responsibilities are not always so fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine you are in a prehistoric village and you are 25% bigger than everybody else. To compensate, you need to eat 50% more food. Food is hunted collectively and then divided up. How would everybody feel about this arrangement?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might suspect that this is great—it is better for you to be bigger and stronger. But there is a cost. Something more would be expected from you than from everybody else. Perhaps you would be on call longer. Or perhaps you would be sent to negotiate with hostile neighbors. With greater consumption and ability comes greater responsibility. You don’t need any grand theory of legitimacy to see how this works—this responsibility simply emerges from the rules of interpersonal politics. From the rules of cause and effect. If you do not pull your weight, if you do not prove that your greater consumption is serving some purpose—that with your higher consumption and ability you are doing some good, you better watch your back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happens when you have power, but you do not take responsibility? You would be in trouble. Resentment would grow. Why do you get to eat so much of our hard-won food? What makes you so special?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You do more work not just because of the possibility of jealous retaliation and the threat of being usurped, but also because if you fully understand your role, you should want to. The greater capacity for violence and power gives you more control over, and more stake in, the fate of your tribe. You do the work of leadership because that is your unique niche in the social order. If you don’t pull your weight and lead, your investments within the tribe would start to lose their value. The things you care about would cease to exist—first gradually, then all at once when your people face threat by nature and rivals. Your weak leadership would be seen by others in your tribe who want power—or by outsiders who want to invade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would you want to be the strongest man in the village right at the moment when you failed to use that strength properly and the village is dying and rivals are out for blood? Or would you rather be the average person, eating the normal amount of food, without being hated?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that was just a thought experiment. Those are people in crises—in a hunter-gatherer village at war. We live in America. Certainly things are different during a stable, prosperous period, in a technologically advanced society. Would you want to be exceptional then?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not necessarily. The elite are faced with certain hard burdens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The elite are expected—by everyone else, and by each other—to use their power to make sure society works properly. That is, they are expected to rule benevolently. The reason they are expected to do this is that if they don’t, nobody else can or will. The middle class and the poor do not have the powers and privileges that the rich and elite do, and cannot afford the necessary personal risks. But without active correction towards health and order, society fails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every society exists in a fragile balance. The Holocaust and Communism had their peak in the 1940s. Genocides in Yugoslavia and Cambodia were as recent as the 1990s. The Rwandan Genocide only ended in 1995. Syria was a flourishing nation just a decade ago, but has now descended into total war. Venezuela &lt;a href=&quot;https://palladiummag.com/2019/03/06/venezuela-an-up-close-look-at-a-nation-in-free-fall/&quot;&gt;was stable&lt;/a&gt; just six years ago. Society without benevolent and competent leadership becomes vulnerable to takeover by insane factions, or to collapse into chaos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elites thus have an incredible weight of responsibility hanging over their heads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In times of political uncertainty, when things are not going well, elites face more scrutiny, and more internal pressure to find people to blame—whether rightly, or as scapegoats. It becomes a bigger liability to be openly elite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further, such times are themselves caused by political dysfunction among the elite, when elite institutions forget how to listen to reason (or have decided not to) and forget how to coordinate towards benevolent rule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At elite conferences, they &lt;a href=&quot;https://thefifthwave.wordpress.com/2019/07/23/notes-from-a-nameless-conference/&quot;&gt;wonder how to regain trust&lt;/a&gt;, or otherwise deal with the rising atmosphere of populist discontent. They acknowledge that something is deeply wrong. But they dare not lay the blame at their own feet, caused by their own overreaches and dysfunction. Anyone who did would immediately be under suspicion. No longer one of us, but one of them. So, those who might otherwise lead the difficult but necessary elite self-critique instead keep their mouths shut, or they say the wrong thing without ideological, psychological, and social preparation for the consequences and get cast out. Only the true believers incapable of self-critique, the incompetent, and the cynics, remain as voices in the public forum. They talk in circles, never quite able to correct course and come to any new conclusions, except the need to double down on current ideological practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The younger generations, who don’t necessarily see the full shape of elite dysfunction, can still tell that now is not a comfortable time to be a rich and powerful elite. Too much expectation, and no good examples to be seen of what to do with that expectation. Better to present themselves as just another member of the “upper middle class,” or even an underdog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But this just tightens our feedback loop. Something is wrong in elite circles, preventing clear examination and correction of ideological errors. This creates an atmosphere of impotence and guilt that contributes to rich young people pretending to be broke to escape that responsibility. But this just contributes back to the decay of elite functionality that could have allowed course correction in the first place. When they misunderstand both the nature of power and their own power, how can they be expected to coordinate to use that power to rule well? How can they be expected not to abuse it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Secret Of Yale’s Demons&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They say that the recent scandals at Yale had to do with racial and social justice. I don’t think that’s what it was really about. When looking at one or two scandals, it’s easy to buy the story that it is just students organizing and using their rights of free speech and assembly to protest what they see as injustices perpetrated by the university. But when looking at all of the scandals together, another narrative starts to emerge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that narrative is much closer to this: members of the ruling class are not sure what to do with themselves—and they are not even sure they want to rule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;***&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yale is different from other Ivy League schools in that its history is rooted in public service. It started in 1701, when a few ministers were disappointed by Harvard and left to start a more pure, more good, more proper university. There is a reason why Harvard’s motto is “Veritas”—truth, whereas Yale’s motto is “Lux et veritas”—light and truth. Truth without light is pointless. Knowledge without an aim is at best not useful—and at worst, destructive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When people think of universities, they think of their local state school, or else Harvard, Princeton, and Yale. And when they think about Yale, it is often when they are reading about a president, a Supreme Court justice, or an editor of &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;. That’s because Yale graduates play no small part in running the world. It is the school the elite want to send their kids to. It is the school the lower classes assume their kids will never go to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;No matter how far I have traveled, something from Yale has always followed with me.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;–President Gerald Ford&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Great things have happened and luck came my way, and I want to say that whatever credit is due of a personal character in the honor that came to me, I believe is due to Yale.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;–President William Howard Taft&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happens when a school with this position is embarrassed about its role as an international trendsetter? What if instead of doing the hard work to set the tone for responsible rule, it abdicates that responsibility?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;***&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Yale, I encountered the unique institution of the Master. The Master is the person who memorizes student’s names, meets with parents, and is a welcoming presence. There were twelve of them—one for each residential college (Yale’s name for an all-inclusive dormitory, a self-sustaining community with its own dining hall, library, gym, and administrators). The dean of each residential college handled administrative and academic concerns, whereas the Master was involved in cultural matters. The Master throws Master’s teas, where they curate and welcome special guests. The etymology of the word stems from “magister” of the Oxford system. Such a title does not exist at any other U.S. school, and neither does the role. Its presence speaks to an institution which wants to create a culture. A welcoming spirit, a sense of refinement. I found this attention-to-detail admirable, and this was one of the reasons I chose Yale over Harvard and Princeton. At Harvard, this sense of culture was nonexistent. A welcoming party with the president? Wine? Forget about it. We picked up our welcome packet and were sent on our way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How would a university with vision act when such cultural institutions come under attack? In Yale’s case, several students began to agitate that the term “Master” had problematic racial connotations. In other words, “Master” was also what African-American slaves called their owners. In the case of authentic individual tensions—if a student had a difficult background where they had been forced to use the term—perhaps the university would find a reasonable resolution to make the student comfortable. But in the case of broader misunderstanding, perhaps it would be better to educate the students about their academic heritage. The administration could have explained that this term has nothing to do with slavery in America and actually derives from a rich history that makes Yale unique.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What actually happened? After some debate, the title was quickly changed to “head of college.” The suspicion is that this was done to appease the student body as a compromise for not changing the name of a dormitory. In the end, the compromise was rejected, a large number of students took to the streets, and both were changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the appearance of bottom-up protest politics is always a bit of a false narrative.  It would be one thing if the students were polled and a majority said they wanted the name changed, or some other process was used. At least the university could say that it was making decisions based on some objective democratic process, and wasn’t just being pushed around. But this is not what happened. No polls were taken. There was no authoritative process. The school said no for a few months, then caved. If the school were actually confident in its position to resist, it could have easily pushed back on the protests. Instead, it folded on demands from a small number of students willing to make noise. Either the university administrators are spectacularly spineless, or the protests just provided a convenient impetus and excuse to do something they already wanted. We can look at several more incidents and notice a similar trend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Halloween Costumes incident also made national headlines. It was another test for Yale. The Intercultural Affairs Council wrote &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thefire.org/email-from-intercultural-affairs/&quot;&gt;an authoritative email&lt;/a&gt; to the entire student body before Halloween, instructing students to be mindful about offensive costumes. A few students approached Erika Christakis, a professor, child psychologist, and wife of Yale Master Nicholas Christakis, and told her that they found it strange that the Council could just email the entire student body and tell it what to do. Erika took note and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thefire.org/email-from-erika-christakis-dressing-yourselves-email-to-silliman-college-yale-students-on-halloween-costumes/&quot;&gt;wrote her own email&lt;/a&gt;, proposing that Halloween costumes should be policed not from the top down with institutions instructing people on their behavior, but from the bottom up, with students having conversations with each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happened next? If this were 2005, nothing would have happened. Erika’s letter was benign and non-confrontational, centering on her experience and research with children, and invoking notions of self-regulation and free expression. But this was 2015, so all hell broke loose. Students called for her to be fired. When her husband stood by her, he became a target, too. Both professors, with ambivalent and ambiguous support from the university, stopped teaching. It did not matter that Erika’s classes were so desirable that she had despairingly long waitlists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Calhoun incident, people took to the streets because the name of a dormitory was offensive to them. The reason? It was named after Vice President John C. Calhoun, who, even for his era, was vocally pro-slavery. After months of student protest, it was changed to Grace Hopper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there were the Yelp reviews. The student newspaper &lt;a href=&quot;https://yaledailynews.com/blog/2017/06/20/pierson-dean-june-chu-leaves-position-after-yelp-scandal/&quot;&gt;parsed hundreds&lt;/a&gt; of Dean June Chu’s Yelp reviews, found all of the worst ones, collated them into a PDF, and published it in the student newspaper. What would a university president with vision have done? What should he have done when national newspapers reprinted the piece? Maybe the student newspaper would be placed on suspension, or receive a guidance order. Maybe he would add a faculty advisor. The point is that collating the ‘worst’ of a dean’s activity online and publishing it as a single document—unless there is something criminal or truly heinous—has less in common with journalism than with a revenge plot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did leadership respond in real life? Chu was supported at first, but then, when it was found out that there were seven offensive reviews and not just two as she initially claimed, she was let go, and no student was punished. This case made national headlines, but the actual administrative proceedings that determined her leave are still a black box. Perhaps she was already in hot water, and this was the last straw. Perhaps she was paid off to leave and keep quiet. Nobody knows. The public story is that her leaving was solely because of the Yelp reviews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some conflicts were public explosions, and some were completely private. The change from “Freshman” to “First-year” &lt;a href=&quot;https://yaledailynews.com/blog/2017/09/15/yale-formalizes-freshman-to-first-year-change/&quot;&gt;happened&lt;/a&gt; when an administrator requested that all instances of “Freshman” be changed to “First-year” in all of the materials and pamphlets for the 2018–2019 school year. But women were not asked if they were actually offended by the word. Students were not asked what they thought. This was a change that came completely from the top.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do all of these events have in common? Some had student support. Some did not. Some started as public outrage taken to the street. Some were completely internal. What they had in common was an administration and student body coordinated around an ideology that continually mutated to ensure moral entrepreneurship and a continued supply of purges, as new forms of human behavior or commonplace descriptors became off-limits. Some of this energy was genuine, some cynical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These were not kids protesting the Vietnam war, or graduate students mobilizing for better pay and medical care. Nobody would have had a gun shoved into their arms and sent across the world if Yale had not fired the professors. Nobody would have lost money if they did not change “Master.” In fact—Yale lost money on these changes in the form of alumni donations and administrative time. Meetings, committees, redone paperwork, and brand new “head of college” plaques. These changes were neither meant to save lives, nor to save money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; the point of it all?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s Really Behind The Campus Wars &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The news stories portrayed the Halloween Costumes debacle as either an obvious issue of professors’ rights, or an obvious issue of minority rights. But they missed all the messy emotions on the ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You must understand—a woman—&lt;em&gt;one&lt;/em&gt; professor—wrote an email, and the entire campus went insane. For an entire year, nobody knew what was going to happen. Will the professors really be fired? Can you be fired over an email like that? A cloud of tension drenched the campus. Those opposed to the “politically correct” view whispered among themselves about if, and how, they should mobilize. Those who wanted the firings waited anxiously for the administrative response. On the national scale, this was a minor news story updated every few months, but on the campus these were not minor debates. They changed the entire dynamic. These issues were debated in dining halls. They split apart friends. They formed a mist over everything else—&lt;em&gt;for an entire year&lt;/em&gt;. The people who wanted the professors to stay? Either because they disagreed with the scandal, or they liked their classes? They were not just wrong—they must also be cruel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thousands of hours of human effort and labor. And for what? What was it for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you ask supporters, they will tell you the cost does not matter so much, because this is about creating an ideal world. Of course the professor should be fired—how dare she stand against the minority student organizations? Of course it’s okay that the Yelp reviews were published—she should never have written them. Of course names should be changed if they hint at or honor the wrong ideology. What does preserving history matter if history is racist? The university is handling things according to its proper ideals of empathy and inclusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, their point was that this was all to help poor people. Immigrants. People whose parents are from distant, impoverished lands. People of color. Changing “Master,” firing the dean, and firing professors was all for this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except this did so little to actually help any of these people that this could not possibly have been the main motivation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None of this was actually to their benefit, except for the few activists willing to invest time and energy into the game. It is not easy to stay up-to-date with the new, ever-more-complex rules about what you are allowed to say to qualify as the bare minimum of sociable and sane. It is cognitively and socially demanding. I had to not just study psychology and computer science, but I had to stay up-to-date with the latest PhD-level critical theory just to have conversations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had to debate with people why it is not racist that my Russian parents actually liked the word “Master.” That they liked that Yale was drawing from a rich, centuries-long tradition. “Master” connotes mastery of a subject. It connotes responsibilities and a cultural aesthetic far beyond what “head of college” connotes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If words like “Master” are deemed offensive based on questionable linguistic or historical standards, then this means other words and phrases can become offensive at a moment’s notice. Under these rules, only people in the upper ranks who receive constant updates can learn what is acceptable. Everybody else will be left behind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The people best positioned for this are professors at elite universities. They are ingrained in the culture that makes up these social rules. They get weekly or even daily updates, but even they cannot keep up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Erika and Nicholas Christakis were on-the-record liberals who had fought for minority issues at Harvard. That didn’t matter; they didn’t get with the program, so they had to go. June Chu had penned an article saying that deans need to be mindful of their students’ backgrounds and diverse challenges. If even competent, qualified, liberal, well-meaning, tenured professors at Ivy League universities are in danger of losing their livelihood for arbitrary reasons just because they said something subtly wrong to the wrong student organization, then what hope do the rest of us have?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nicholas Christakis was ousted as if he were a bad guy. His on-campus family was bullied. His entire life was cast aside over one email, as if the email were the one standard by which he should be judged. Jonathan Holloway, the African-American then-Dean of Yale College, was shouted at by students for not doing enough for black students. Whether June Chu was a good dean or not—and maybe she wasn’t—does not matter. What mattered was what she wrote on Yelp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A cynical observer might conclude that this is all just revolution as usual—a small clique of agitators seizing more and more power, and purging their enemies by virtue of their superior internal solidarity, a bold and demanding ideology, lukewarm popular moral support, and no real organized opposition. In some ways, that is what’s going on. They have the bold ideology, the ambient support, and no real opposition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But importantly, they don’t have internal coordination by any means other than adherence to the ideology itself. Even members of the clique are never really safe. Anyone who contradicts the latest consensus version of the constantly mutating ideology, even if they have worked to its benefit or are otherwise obviously on side, gets purged. If you don’t keep up, you get purged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t matter that the ideology is abusive to its own constituents and allies, or that it doesn’t really even serve its formal beneficiaries. All that matters is this: for everyone who gets purged for a slight infraction, there are dozens who learn from this example never to stand up to the ideology, dozens who learn that they can attack with impunity if they use the ideology to do it, and dozens who are vaguely convinced by its rhetoric to be supportive of the next purge. So, on it goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the nature of coordination via ideology. If you’re organizing out of some common interest, you can have lively debates about what to do, how things work, who’s right and wrong, and even core aspects of your intellectual paradigm. But if your only standard for membership in your power coalition is detailed adherence to your ideology, as is increasingly true for membership in elite circles, then it becomes very hard to correct mistakes, or switch to a different paradigm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this helps explain much of the quagmire American elites are stuck in: being unable to speak outside of the current ideology, the only choice is to double down on a failing paradigm. These failures lead to lower elite morale, resulting in the class identity crisis which afflicts so many at Yale. Ironically, the result is an expression of that ideology which is increasingly rigid on ever more minute points of belief and conduct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abandoning The Ship Of State&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is some truth in virtually every ideology. But ideas don’t win, and get the backing of elite power, because they are the most true or important. Nor are they ultimately about that truth. Many of the most important truths that the critical theory PhDs deal in—truths about the structure of power, how power manifests through language, how even “objective” social institutions are tools of hidden power—are hobbled from their full and proper expression by being confined to a small set of acceptable uses within progressive ideology. The ideology, once picked up and recuperated by existing powers, becomes a containment system for those truths, a way to reliably transmute dissent into loyalty. Ideologies win because they serve some purpose to the powers that invest in them, and they become about that purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the point of this new ideology? This ideology is filled with inconsistencies and contradictions, because it is not really about ideological rigor. Among other things, it is an elaborate containment system for the theoretical and practical discontent generated by the failures of the system, an absolution from guilt, and a new form of class signaling. Before, to signal you were in the fashionable and powerful crowd, you would show off your country-club membership, refined manners, or Gucci handbags. Now, you show how woke you are. To reinforce their new form of structural power, people dismiss the idea that they even have the older, more legible forms of status. They find any reverse-privilege points they can, and if they are cis-white-men, they pose as allies. On an institutional level, the old ways of legitimizing power are gone, and the new motto is this: diversity is legitimacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a deep comedy to this sort of signaling. Only around 2% of the student body was in the bottom 20% of American society, and yet extremely wealthy Singaporean students who had spent just a few years in America marched in the street and referred to themselves as “people of color.” People’s experiences were ignored when they volunteered information that countered the main narrative, because the surface-level debate wasn’t the point. The point was to signal that you were with the program. Only a select and secret group of student “leaders”—who were already savvy enough to engage comfortably with hierarchy—were invited in to chat with administrators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shouting from the rooftops that “They aren’t doing enough!” is much easier than following any traditional system of elite social norms and duties, let alone carefully re-engineering that system to reestablish order in a time of growing crisis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Western elites are not comfortable with their place in society and the responsibilities that come with it, and realize that there are deep structural problems with the old systems of coordination. But lacking the capacity for an orderly restructuring, or even a diagnosis of problems and needs, we dive deeper into a chaotic ideological mode of coordination that sweeps away the old structures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you live with this mindset, what you end up with is not an establishment where a woke upper class rallies and advocates for the rights of minorities, the poor, and underprivileged groups. What you have is a blind and self-righteous upper class that becomes structurally unable to take coordinated responsibility. You get stuck in an ideological mode of coordination, where no one can speak the truth to correct collective mistakes and overreaches without losing position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This ideology is promulgated and advertised by universities, but it doesn’t start or stop at universities. All the fundraisers. All the corporate events. The Oscars. Let’s take down the Man. They say this in front of their PowerPoints. They clink champagne glasses. Let’s take down the Man! But there is no real spirit of revolution in these words. It is all in the language they understand—polite and clean, because it isn’t really real. It is a performative spectacle about their own morale and guilt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you were the ruler while everything was burning around you, and you didn’t know what to do, what would you do? You would deny that you are in charge. And you would recuperate the growing discontented masses into your own power base, so that things stay comfortable for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yale students, if they weren’t powerful when they came in (and most of them were), they gain power by being bestowed a Yale degree. What would you do with this power? You don’t want to abuse it; you’re not outright evil. No, you want something different. You want to be absolved of your power. You are ashamed of your power. Why should you have it, and not somebody else—maybe somebody more deserving? You never really signed up for this. You would rather be somebody normal. But not, “normal,” normal. More like normal with options and vacations and money “normal.” Normal but still powerful. Or you want to be something even better than normal. You want to be the underdog. There is always a certain strange sense of pleasure in being an underdog. Expectations are lower. Whenever you accomplish anything at all—it is an accomplishment. You would rather have a narrative story of “coming up from the bottom.” Someone who not only does not have the responsibility of power, but someone who has a right to feel resentful of those who do. And better yet—someone who can use this resentment as a tool for self-interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do Yale students give up their power? They do this in one of two ways. One way is termed “selling out.” This usually means taking a high-paying job at an institution that is at worst blatantly unethical, and at best not intentionally idealistic. A consulting job, a meaningless tech job, or a position at an investment bank. This is generally seen as the selfish route.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there is more to selling out that nobody talks about. These jobs are the dream jobs of the middle class. They’re not supposed to be jobs for the sons and daughters of millionaires and billionaires—these kids don’t &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; need the money. They want independence from their parents and proof that they can make it on their own—and prestigious work experience—but they have wealth acquired through generations that they can always fall back on. These people are generally as harmless as the middle class—which is to say completely harmless. They keep to themselves. They quietly grow their bank accounts and their 401ks. And just like the real middle class, they don’t want to risk their next promotion through being too outspoken. They have virtually no political power. This mindset is best encapsulated by: “I’ll go with the program. Please leave me alone to be comfortable and quietly make money.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They effectively become middle class, because there is no longer any socially esteemed notion of upper class. They have a base of power, of f-you money, that they could use to become something greater than just another office worker or businessperson. But there is no script for that, no institutional or ideological support. What would it even mean to be an esteemed, blue-blooded aristocrat in 2019? So they take the easy and safe way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How else do Yale students give up their responsibility?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They go in the other direction. These are the people who call themselves idealists and say they want to save the world. They feel the weight of responsibility from their social status—but they don’t know how to process and integrate this responsibility into their lives properly. Traditionally, structurally well-organized elite institutions would absorb and direct this benevolent impulse to useful purpose. But our traditional institutions have decayed and lost their credibility, so these idealists start looking for alternatives, and start signaling dissociation from those now-disreputable class markers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The capacity to really think through what an alternative should look like, and create one, is so rare as to be effectively nonexistent. Instead, idealists are forced to take the easy way of just going along with dominant ideological narratives of what it means to do good. They feel guilty about their wealth and privileges, and feel that they won’t be doing their part unless they do something very altruistic, and the idealistic ideologies reinforce these feelings. So they go overboard, and rush headlong into whatever they are supposed to do. They purport to speak for and be allied with underprivileged groups. They get their professors fired for minor infractions. They frantically tear down whatever vestiges of the old institutions and hierarchies that they can, and conspicuously feel guilty about the rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are the people who buy clothes from Salvation Army and decline your Sunday brunch invitation because it’s too expensive, sometimes with the implication that they are saving their money to donate to more effective causes, if they aren’t pretending not to have it. They are the people who might attack or cut off their friends for ideological reasons. They discharge their personal responsibility by sacrificing everything outside of their distant mission, including friendships and social fabric.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s an understandable impulse. After all, given the state of legacy institutions, what else are you going to do with the energy of idealism? But ultimately, by going along with the narratives of an ideology that can efficiently capture these impulses, but has no structural ability to deliver on its promises, it just diverts more energy from what a normal benevolent elite should be doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These people might sometimes say that they are “tired of fighting”—but this is not the full truth. Fighting is fun. It is always fun to be a warrior—to have something you believe in that guides you. To be part of a tribe, working for the good of mankind. To be revered and respected for being on the bleeding edge of the paradigm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Especially when you’re winning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who Is In Charge?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who is winning? This question is an important one. Yale administrators had lofty goals. In an attempt to placate their own biases, the administrators and faculty forgot that they are the ones who are supposed to be teaching. Instead of expelling or suspending the small number of people actively undermining the student body and university as a whole, the university does nothing, or actively accelerates the process. The professors are the ones who leave. The radical clique feels emboldened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we can begin to understand the real problem at Yale. It is not free speech—and it is not non-inclusivity. The standards of reality, and the standards of morality not based solely on being woke, are ousted. That’s because the conventional standards of elite morality, based on responsible use of power—actually responsible, not just a convenient feeling of doing good—are much harder, and based on the very self-consciousness that everyone is trying to avoid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The faculty get pushed around by a small number of students, and administrators actively fire up conflict on their behalf. If an administrator wins favor among them, that administrator gains power. If administrators come to understand that they can gain power via this vector, it makes sense why they would chip away at existing holders of power: the people on the board, the donors, the alumni, and the traditions of the institution itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In effect, a large fraction of the administrators form a revolutionary class within the rest of the university structure. They use both their existing power and new ideological mandates to expand their own domain at the expense of other players. The purpose of the administrators is to shape, tear down, and rebuild the university on the institutional level, which lets them act on ideological goals in a way students and faculty generally cannot. The people filling these expanded roles often come from the student body itself, having served in student government or activist student organizations before transitioning into their bureaucratic roles after graduation. This is the human institutional structure behind the ideological phenomenon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result is an institution increasingly unable to carry out its own mission, as tuition rises to pay for more administrators, and ideological drama makes it harder and harder to actually teach. And now we are back at the original question. What was the point of Yale? What was the point of going to Yale? What is the point of elite institutions?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is the point of Yale to promote the humanities and knowledge of the West that is hard to learn anywhere else? This is not the full mission. Donald Kagan and Lee Bass’s year-long history of the West program was cut, due to faculty protesting that it was not multicultural enough, despite having large interest and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/1995/03/15/us/yale-returns-20-million-to-an-unhappy-patron.html&quot;&gt;$20 million in funding&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is Yale’s vision a futuristic, technocratic university? Is the university divesting from the liberal arts for the purpose of committing to the technology of the future? This isn’t the case, either. Computer science enrollment has increased significantly in the past decade, but Yale’s computer science department is &lt;a href=&quot;https://yaledailynews.com/blog/2018/11/06/computer-science-expands-still-lacks-resources/&quot;&gt;lagging behind&lt;/a&gt; other schools. The university has taken steps towards improving the department, but in general shows no signs of a visionary commitment to expanding tech or significantly expanding professorships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yale is having an existential crisis. Students are taught to break the system, but Yale doesn’t even want to teach them what the original system is, what it was for, or how to productively replace it. The university is so lacking in vision that it doesn’t even know what the ideal student looks like, or what it wants to teach them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe the university has lost every purpose other than giving students a social environment in which to party. If the students aren’t educated or visionary, at least they’re networking and hedonically satisfied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except they’re not. It would be one thing if they were happy—but even this is not true. They don’t know what is expected of them, or what they should aspire to be. The lack of expectations creates nihilistic tendencies and existential crises. In 2018, around &lt;a href=&quot;https://yaledailynews.com/blog/2018/04/05/students-criticize-mental-health-services/&quot;&gt;one quarter&lt;/a&gt; of Yale undergraduates said they sought mental health counseling. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/01/26/nyregion/at-yale-class-on-happiness-draws-huge-crowd-laurie-santos.html&quot;&gt;One quarter&lt;/a&gt; of Yale students took the “Happiness and the Good Life” course in 2018 in an attempt to find answers. Students are demanding more mental health resources. A new wellness space was created with bean-bag chairs and colored walls. But the real sources of unhappiness are more systemic. They are rooted in uncertainty about the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If Yale students are uncertain about the future and their role in it, what does that say about the rest of society?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What will happen after Yale? Its high level of prestige established over centuries is important and entrenched. Yale will not be replaced any time soon. Its worldwide brand recognition is worth trillions. And Yale’s role as an institution older than the Republic is important. It is the preserver of cultural knowledge. While Stanford can produce entrepreneurs, it still falls to Yale to produce the bulk of Supreme Court justices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Current Yale administrators have a sense of self-preservation for themselves and their corporation, but not for what made them great in the first place. They are quick to appease students, when they go along with the new zeitgeist, as if students and the latest wokeness were the preservers of cultural knowledge. This is the key to understanding why beloved faculty members can end up purged, against all public sentiment. Whether out of ideological commitment or hard-nosed realpolitik, these apparatchik administrators, bolstered by a minority of students, have effectively outmaneuvered their rivals. In doing so, they have also accelerated the tearing down of Yale’s institutional legacy and undermined its historical mission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If they were confronting a university and student body with a powerful commitment to that mission, things might be different. But they aren’t. As we’ve seen, the classes represented at Yale have themselves opened up a massive ideological vacuum. Shrinking back from their position and opportunities, they have lost the ability to coordinate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So What If Yale Dies?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what if Yale, and Yale students, are abdicating responsibility? We can all just send our kids to Harvard, or MIT, or move to California and go to a state school. I heard UC Berkeley is pretty good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the problems present at Yale are present at every other university, and schools outside of the United States look to elite American universities as role models. If things are broken at elite universities, things are broken, period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most important fact is this: Yale is a school that sets the standards for other universities. When and where Yale goes, everything else goes, too. Its curricula and administrative policies have a disproportionate effect on the standards for excellence not just for universities, but for industry. Yale psychology undergraduates become Princeton psychology professors, join the American Psychological Association, and determine which conditions get covered by insurance policies. Art students go on to join the National Endowment for the Arts and decide which projects deserve funding. A single idea from a single professor at Yale Law can determine how a future justice chooses to vote when she joins the Supreme Court.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Why is Yale in the news so much?” “Why do people care about Yale’s tiny controversies?” “Why do alumni care about what happens? They’re gone. It’s not their Yale anymore.” These are questions that people ask me often. These questions show a misunderstanding of what Yale is and its role in society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every once in a while, the staff and editors of the Yale Daily News ask these questions. “Why are people so critical of us? If you don’t like what we print, you have every chance to join the News Team and write for us yourself.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They forget one thing. The Yale Daily News is reprinted by national newspapers. The Yale Daily News has a history of getting students suspended, and even faculty fired. But the Yale Daily News is not accountable to anybody. There are no faculty advisors. They are completely independent, and yet have disproportionate power—not just for a student organization, but for any organization at all. That it is a student organization just makes it even more incredible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lack of self-consciousness brings us back to the phenomenon I first saw among so many “broke” rich kids. The same vacuum of awareness crops up again and again, influencing both people and institutions, until they are unable to even grasp the potential of their position. Without doing that, rebuilding a shared set of goals around which to coordinate on a large scale will remain impossible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yale is supposed to be using its power and reputation to set standards for excellence, but instead it is abandoning its responsibilities and getting embroiled in controversy after controversy. Yale is not special in this regard—other colleges are also often embroiled in controversies. But the controversies of top colleges matter most because they determine what is acceptable for everybody else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what’s happening at Yale reflects a crisis in America’s broader governing class. Unable to effectively respond to the challenges facing them, they instead try to bail out of their own class. The result is an ideology which acts as an escape raft, allowing some of the most privileged young people in the country to present themselves as devoid of power. Institutions like Yale, once meant to direct people in how to use their position for the greater good, are systematically undermined—a vicious cycle which ultimately erodes the country as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Segments of this class engage in risk-averse managerialism, while others take advantage of the glut to disrupt things and expand personal power. The broader population becomes caught up in these conflicts as these actors attempt to build power bases and mobilize against each other. And like Yale, it seems a safe bet that things will continue and even accelerate until some new vision and stable, non-ideological set of coordination mechanisms are able to establish hegemony and become a new ground for real cooperation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As much as Yale is watching the world, the world is watching Yale. As it should be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hope &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people tell me to forget about all this. I graduated. None of this matters anymore. Except it still seems to follow me around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even on the very day in 2016 that I walked up in cap and gown, these scandals were still ever-present: Yale President Peter Salovey used his graduation speech that day to talk about the merits of free speech. Imagine the Yale University president standing up at the podium and unexpectedly talking about the need for a marketplace of ideas. This was a point he could have made all year; instead, he made it on the day when it all was over. He could have called an assembly. He could have sent a mass email. But he was not thumotic enough, and now, on graduation day, everyone was listening to a not-so-covert jab at all the scandals that occurred in the past year. At least now we knew what the president really thought. Except later, we would watch the students who helped lead the race riots be honored with prizes for improving race relations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do I still care about any of this? For one thing, pre-frosh kids still send me messages asking me what the hell happened over there. I give them general mentorship advice, and then they ask me what the Halloween thing was. They don’t understand it, because they haven’t yet spent time in the echo-chamber where the ideas stack up just gently enough to somewhat make sense. I have to explain it to them, and watch them grow more and more confused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They ask me if I had a good time at Yale. I tell them that I did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, I saw a hopeful article about Nicholas Christakis, the professor who was so unsupported during the Halloween Scandal, and was harassed at his house. He stopped teaching for some time, and now the schizophrenic university awarded him the &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.yale.edu/2018/07/23/dr-nicholas-christakis-named-sterling-professor&quot;&gt;highest honor—the Sterling Professorship.&lt;/a&gt; It cannot undo past damage, but it can set precedent for what it wants from the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marcus, the trust-fund kid, is still a dear friend of mine. I visit him whenever I can. Most of my life-long friends and my acquaintances are either a direct or indirect result of my attendance at Yale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still visit the campus sometimes. Some of my friends are younger and haven’t yet graduated. Besides, the campus is especially beautiful in the fall and spring, where the scent of the leaves and pollen create a transcendent intellectual and spiritual halo around the campus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once, I was walking with an English professor among the trees. The conversation was leisurely. He smoked, not out of addiction, but as if a Davidoff was the natural pairing for a stroll through the cherry blossoms, just as you would eat a scone with English breakfast tea. After some time, he asked me what I thought about campus politics. We talked in abstractions, and then he stopped to ask, “Why do you care so much about what happens to the university?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My answer surprised him, which in turn surprised me, because it was one of the few truths that I know is truly incontestable. I told him, “Yale was the most important thing that happened to me. I didn’t have anything before. And now I have everything.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 19:20:14 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jseliger</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://palladiummag.com/2019/08/05/the-real-problem-at-yale-is-not-free-speech/</og:url>
<og:title>The Real Problem At Yale Is Not Free Speech</og:title>
<og:description>Yale, and other elite colleges, have been rocked by controversies and protests. The problem is an elite that has forgotten itself, neglected its institutions, and fallen into ideological frenzy.</og:description>
<og:image>https://palladiummag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/tim-bish-MOLPxhKRVlI-unsplash-e1565043693389-600x315.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://palladiummag.com/2019/08/05/the-real-problem-at-yale-is-not-free-speech/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Creeping normality</title>
<link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality</guid>
<description>&lt;a class=&quot;mw-jump-link&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality#mw-head&quot;&gt;Jump to navigation&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;a class=&quot;mw-jump-link&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality#p-search&quot;&gt;Jump to search&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;div id=&quot;mw-content-text&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; class=&quot;mw-content-ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;mw-parser-output&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Creeping normality&lt;/b&gt; is a term that describes the way a major change can be accepted as a normal situation if it happens slowly, through unnoticeable increments of change. The change could otherwise be regarded as objectionable if it took place in a single step or short period.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The phrase was coined by an American scientist, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jared_Diamond&quot; title=&quot;Jared Diamond&quot;&gt;Jared Diamond&lt;/a&gt;, in his 2005 book, &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Collapse:_How_Societies_Choose_to_Fail_or_Succeed&quot; title=&quot;Collapse: How Societies Choose to Fail or Succeed&quot;&gt;Collapse: How Societies Choose to Fail or Succeed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;.  He had previously alluded to this theory while attempting to explain why in the course of long-term &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Environmental_degradation&quot; title=&quot;Environmental degradation&quot;&gt;environmental degradation&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Easter_Island&quot; title=&quot;Easter Island&quot;&gt;Easter Island&lt;/a&gt; natives would, seemingly irrationally, chop down the last tree:&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-Diamond_1-0&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality#cite_note-Diamond-1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style data-mw-deduplicate=&quot;TemplateStyles:r886047036&quot;&gt;&lt;![CDATA[.mw-parser-output .templatequote{overflow:hidden;margin:1em 0;padding:0 40px}.mw-parser-output .templatequote .templatequotecite{line-height:1.5em;text-align:left;padding-left:1.6em;margin-top:0}]]&gt;&lt;/style&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;templatequote&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;I suspect, though, that the disaster happened &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Hollow_Men&quot; title=&quot;The Hollow Men&quot;&gt;not with a bang but with a whimper&lt;/a&gt;. After all, there are those hundreds of abandoned statues to consider. The forest the islanders depended on for rollers and rope didn't simply disappear one day—it vanished slowly, over decades.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his book, Diamond also refers to creeping normality as &quot;landscape amnesia&quot;.&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-2&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality#cite_note-2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Other_uses&quot;&gt;Other uses&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creeping normality and landscape amnesia have been used to explain a number of different phenomena, including the examples listed below:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Gun_violence_in_the_United_States&quot;&gt;Gun violence in the United States&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andrew Hammond, a writer for the &lt;i&gt;Gulf News&lt;/i&gt;, used the term in his February 2018 article &quot;Mass shootings have started to look, sound and feel the same—and that's a problem&quot;.&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-:1_3-0&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality#cite_note-:1-3&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; He wrote that &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mass_shooting&quot; title=&quot;Mass shooting&quot;&gt;mass shootings&lt;/a&gt; feature the same coverage of sobbing pairs of people, contemplative witnesses, night-time vigils, and prayer circles, and that there is a familiarity to all of it, a &quot;creeping normality.&quot;&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-:1_3-1&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality#cite_note-:1-3&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Hammond argues that, with the increasing number of major active shooter incidents occurring annually in the United States, the ubiquity of the events has begun producing its own distinctive aesthetic.&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-:1_3-2&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality#cite_note-:1-3&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Family_businesses&quot;&gt;Family businesses&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Antheaume and Barbelivien described the creeping normality that destroys businesses, causing them to not see the subtle, negative shifts in the community around them. The authors state that owners of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Family_business&quot; title=&quot;Family business&quot;&gt;family businesses&lt;/a&gt; are more likely to notice the small changes than a large &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Corporation&quot; title=&quot;Corporation&quot;&gt;corporation&lt;/a&gt;, although &quot;detecting a problem is no guarantee of the ability to solve it&quot;.&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-4&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality#cite_note-4&quot;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Cybercrime&quot;&gt;Cybercrime&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his thesis, Chon states that the increase in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cybercrime&quot; title=&quot;Cybercrime&quot;&gt;cybercrime&lt;/a&gt; fits the pattern for creeping normality. The number of websites involved in &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Security_hacker&quot; title=&quot;Security hacker&quot;&gt;hacking&lt;/a&gt; and cybercrime activities&quot;&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-:5_5-0&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality#cite_note-:5-5&quot;&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; has increased at a slow and steady pace, mostly below society's awareness.&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-:5_5-1&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality#cite_note-:5-5&quot;&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Flooding_in_Singapore&quot;&gt;Flooding in Singapore&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peter_Ho&quot; title=&quot;Peter Ho&quot;&gt;Peter Ho&lt;/a&gt; referred to creeping normality in his four-part &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Institute_of_Policy_Studies_(Singapore)&quot; title=&quot;Institute of Policy Studies (Singapore)&quot;&gt;IPS&lt;/a&gt;-Nathan lecture series in spring of 2017. In regard to several issues &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Singapore&quot; title=&quot;Singapore&quot;&gt;Singapore&lt;/a&gt; is facing, he claimed that &quot;things get just a little bit worse each year than the year before, but not bad enough for anyone to notice&quot;.&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-:6_6-0&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality#cite_note-:6-6&quot;&gt;[6]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; As an example, he used the increase in flooding in Singapore. He stated that the country did not realize the problem was caused by rising temperatures due to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Climate_change&quot; title=&quot;Climate change&quot;&gt;catastrophic climate change&lt;/a&gt; and not poor drainage as first suspected.&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-:6_6-1&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality#cite_note-:6-6&quot;&gt;[6]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Media_in_education&quot;&gt;Media in education&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researchers at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/University_of_Central_Florida&quot; title=&quot;University of Central Florida&quot;&gt;University of Central Florida&lt;/a&gt; looked into the evolving media landscape on the University's campuses and argued that there has been a gradual shift to offer more &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Online_classes&quot; class=&quot;mw-redirect&quot; title=&quot;Online classes&quot;&gt;online classes&lt;/a&gt;, resources, and a technology and media-rich environment.&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-:2_7-0&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality#cite_note-:2-7&quot;&gt;[7]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; The article, &quot;Assessing Online Learning: What One University Learned about Student Success, Persistence, and Satisfaction,&quot; cited Jared Diamond's&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-Diamond_1-1&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality#cite_note-Diamond-1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; use of the term &quot;landscape amnesia&quot; to describe the &quot;ubiquitous presence of media and technology&quot; on campuses.&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-:2_7-1&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality#cite_note-:2-7&quot;&gt;[7]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Famine&quot;&gt;Famine&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alex_de_Waal&quot; title=&quot;Alex de Waal&quot;&gt;Alex de Waal&lt;/a&gt; has discussed the timescale over which disasters like &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Famine&quot; title=&quot;Famine&quot;&gt;famine&lt;/a&gt; occur.&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-:3_8-0&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality#cite_note-:3-8&quot;&gt;[8]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; De Waal makes the point that governments and media outlets have a responsibility to recognise the underlying causes of famine and natural disaster, as opposed to focusing on the visibility of the crisis alone.&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-:3_8-1&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality#cite_note-:3-8&quot;&gt;[8]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; He uses &quot;landscape amnesia&quot; to explain how a person or society may be shocked to realize the gradual changes that lead to disaster.&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-:3_8-2&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality#cite_note-:3-8&quot;&gt;[8]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Obese_and_overweight_maternity_patients&quot;&gt;Obese and overweight maternity patients&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The term has also been used several times in conjunction with the increase of maternity patients who are &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Obesity&quot; title=&quot;Obesity&quot;&gt;obese&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Overweight&quot; title=&quot;Overweight&quot;&gt;overweight&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-:0_9-0&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality#cite_note-:0-9&quot;&gt;[9]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; In their research article, authors Wilkinson, Poad, and Stapleton suggest that as the number of clinically obese or overweight pregnant women increase, the negative stigmatisation with being overweight decreases.&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-:0_9-1&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality#cite_note-:0-9&quot;&gt;[9]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Schmeid, et al., states that as health care providers see more women with an unhealthy weight, they are less likely to advise healthy weight gain goals during &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pregnancy&quot; title=&quot;Pregnancy&quot;&gt;pregnancy&lt;/a&gt;, out of fear of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_stigma_of_obesity&quot; title=&quot;Social stigma of obesity&quot;&gt;fat-shaming&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-10&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality#cite_note-10&quot;&gt;[10]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-11&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality#cite_note-11&quot;&gt;[11]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Physicians may not be aware that they are not addressing the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gestational_age&quot; title=&quot;Gestational age&quot;&gt;gestational&lt;/a&gt; weight gain as soon as necessary.&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-12&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality#cite_note-12&quot;&gt;[12]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; A survey conducted from January to April of 2010 of obstetrics and gynecology residents found that of those surveyed, only &quot;7.6% selected correct BMI ranges for each category, and only 5.8% selected correct gestational weight gain ranges&quot;.&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-13&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality#cite_note-13&quot;&gt;[13]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;More recently, in an Australian study published in 2013, researchers surveyed maternity health care providers in Queensland and discovered a lack of knowledge of body mass index (BMI) and body weight guidelines for pregnant women.&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-:4_14-0&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality#cite_note-:4-14&quot;&gt;[14]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; The lack of guideline knowledge was identified as a barrier to effective care, while the researchers also addressed the social stigma associated communicating guidelines and recommendations for overweight and obese pregnant patients.&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-:4_14-1&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality#cite_note-:4-14&quot;&gt;[14]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; The study acknowledged that the stigmatisation traditionally associated with excessive weight is increasingly challenged by the ‘creeping normality’ and broader acceptance of overweight and obese people worldwide.&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-:4_14-2&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality#cite_note-:4-14&quot;&gt;[14]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; As of 2013, people considered to be of a healthy weight were only 39.40% of the world's population.&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-:4_14-3&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality#cite_note-:4-14&quot;&gt;[14]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;See_also&quot;&gt;See also&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a number of metaphors related to creeping normality, including:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boiling_frog&quot; title=&quot;Boiling frog&quot;&gt;Boiling frog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Camel%27s_nose&quot; title=&quot;Camel's nose&quot;&gt;Camel's nose&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gaslighting&quot; title=&quot;Gaslighting&quot;&gt;Gaslighting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Defeat_in_detail&quot; title=&quot;Defeat in detail&quot;&gt;Defeat in detail&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/First_they_came_...&quot; title=&quot;First they came ...&quot;&gt;First they came ...&lt;/a&gt;&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Foot-in-the-door_technique&quot; title=&quot;Foot-in-the-door technique&quot;&gt;Foot-in-the-door technique&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Moving_the_goalposts&quot; title=&quot;Moving the goalposts&quot;&gt;Moving the goalposts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Normalisation_of_deviance&quot; class=&quot;mw-redirect&quot; title=&quot;Normalisation of deviance&quot;&gt;Normalisation of deviance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Overton_window&quot; title=&quot;Overton window&quot;&gt;Overton window&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Principiis_obsta&quot; class=&quot;mw-redirect&quot; title=&quot;Principiis obsta&quot;&gt;Principiis obsta&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Salami_tactics&quot; title=&quot;Salami tactics&quot;&gt;Salami tactics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shifting_baseline&quot; title=&quot;Shifting baseline&quot;&gt;Shifting baseline&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Slippery_slope&quot; title=&quot;Slippery slope&quot;&gt;Slippery slope&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Technological_change#Technological_change_as_a_social_process&quot; title=&quot;Technological change&quot;&gt;Technological change as a social process&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tyranny_of_small_decisions&quot; title=&quot;Tyranny of small decisions&quot;&gt;Tyranny of small decisions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Change_blindness&quot; title=&quot;Change blindness&quot;&gt;Change blindness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;References&quot;&gt;References&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;reflist&quot; style=&quot;list-style-type: decimal;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;mw-references-wrap mw-references-columns&quot;&gt;&lt;ol class=&quot;references&quot;&gt;&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-Diamond-1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;^ &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality#cite_ref-Diamond_1-0&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;a&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality#cite_ref-Diamond_1-1&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;b&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;&lt;cite class=&quot;citation web&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jared_Diamond&quot; title=&quot;Jared Diamond&quot;&gt;Diamond, Jared&lt;/a&gt; (1995-08-01). &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;http://discovermagazine.com/1995/aug/eastersend543&quot;&gt;&quot;Easter's End&quot;&lt;/a&gt;. Discover magazine&lt;span class=&quot;reference-accessdate&quot;&gt;. Retrieved &lt;span class=&quot;nowrap&quot;&gt;2014-08-03&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;span title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Abook&amp;amp;rft.genre=unknown&amp;amp;rft.btitle=Easter%27s+End&amp;amp;rft.pub=Discover+magazine&amp;amp;rft.date=1995-08-01&amp;amp;rft.aulast=Diamond&amp;amp;rft.aufirst=Jared&amp;amp;rft_id=http%3A%2F%2Fdiscovermagazine.com%2F1995%2Faug%2Feastersend543&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fen.wikipedia.org%3ACreeping+normality&quot; class=&quot;Z3988&quot;/&gt;&lt;style data-mw-deduplicate=&quot;TemplateStyles:r886058088&quot;&gt;&lt;![CDATA[.mw-parser-output cite.citation{font-style:inherit}.mw-parser-output .citation q{quotes:&quot;\&quot;&quot;&quot;\&quot;&quot;&quot;'&quot;&quot;'&quot;}.mw-parser-output .citation .cs1-lock-free a{background:url(&quot;//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/6/65/Lock-green.svg/9px-Lock-green.svg.png&quot;)no-repeat;background-position:right .1em center}.mw-parser-output .citation .cs1-lock-limited a,.mw-parser-output .citation .cs1-lock-registration a{background:url(&quot;//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/d/d6/Lock-gray-alt-2.svg/9px-Lock-gray-alt-2.svg.png&quot;)no-repeat;background-position:right .1em center}.mw-parser-output .citation .cs1-lock-subscription a{background:url(&quot;//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/a/aa/Lock-red-alt-2.svg/9px-Lock-red-alt-2.svg.png&quot;)no-repeat;background-position:right .1em center}.mw-parser-output .cs1-subscription,.mw-parser-output .cs1-registration{color:#555}.mw-parser-output .cs1-subscription span,.mw-parser-output .cs1-registration span{border-bottom:1px dotted;cursor:help}.mw-parser-output .cs1-ws-icon a{background:url(&quot;//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/4/4c/Wikisource-logo.svg/12px-Wikisource-logo.svg.png&quot;)no-repeat;background-position:right .1em center}.mw-parser-output code.cs1-code{color:inherit;background:inherit;border:inherit;padding:inherit}.mw-parser-output .cs1-hidden-error{display:none;font-size:100%}.mw-parser-output .cs1-visible-error{font-size:100%}.mw-parser-output .cs1-maint{display:none;color:#33aa33;margin-left:0.3em}.mw-parser-output .cs1-subscription,.mw-parser-output .cs1-registration,.mw-parser-output .cs1-format{font-size:95%}.mw-parser-output .cs1-kern-left,.mw-parser-output .cs1-kern-wl-left{padding-left:0.2em}.mw-parser-output .cs1-kern-right,.mw-parser-output .cs1-kern-wl-right{padding-right:0.2em}]]&gt;&lt;/style&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality#cite_ref-2&quot;&gt;^&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;&lt;cite class=&quot;citation journal&quot;&gt;Fogg GE, LaBolle EM (14 March 2006). &quot;Motivation of synthesis, with an example on groundwater quality sustainability&quot;. &lt;i&gt;Water Resources Research&lt;/i&gt;. &lt;b&gt;42&lt;/b&gt;: W03S05. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_object_identifier&quot; title=&quot;Digital object identifier&quot;&gt;doi&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1029%2F2005WR004372&quot;&gt;10.1029/2005WR004372&lt;/a&gt;  – via Google Scholar.&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;span title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Ajournal&amp;amp;rft.genre=article&amp;amp;rft.jtitle=Water+Resources+Research&amp;amp;rft.atitle=Motivation+of+synthesis%2C+with+an+example+on+groundwater+quality+sustainability&amp;amp;rft.volume=42&amp;amp;rft.pages=W03S05&amp;amp;rft.date=2006-03-14&amp;amp;rft_id=info%3Adoi%2F10.1029%2F2005WR004372&amp;amp;rft.aulast=Fogg&amp;amp;rft.aufirst=Graham+E.&amp;amp;rft.au=LaBolle%2C+Eric+M.&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fen.wikipedia.org%3ACreeping+normality&quot; class=&quot;Z3988&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;mw-deduplicated-inline-style&quot; href=&quot;mw-data:TemplateStyles:r886058088&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-:1-3&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;^ &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality#cite_ref-:1_3-0&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;a&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality#cite_ref-:1_3-1&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;b&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality#cite_ref-:1_3-2&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;c&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;Mass shootings have started to look, sound and feel the same — and that’s a problem. (2018). &lt;i&gt;Gulf News&lt;/i&gt;, p. Gulf News, Feb 18, 2018.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-4&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality#cite_ref-4&quot;&gt;^&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;&lt;cite class=&quot;citation web&quot;&gt;Antheaume N, Barbelivien D. &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://www.researchgate.net/publication/283300199_Why_do_family_businesses_die_An_investigation_through_the_work_of_an_ethnologist_and_geographer_on_the_collapse_of_human_societies&quot;&gt;&quot;Why do family businesses die? An investigation through the work of an ethnologist and geographer on the collapse of human societies&quot;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;Research Gate&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;span title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Ajournal&amp;amp;rft.genre=unknown&amp;amp;rft.jtitle=Research+Gate&amp;amp;rft.atitle=Why+do+family+businesses+die%3F+An+investigation+through+the+work+of+an+ethnologist+and+geographer+on+the+collapse+of+human+societies&amp;amp;rft.aulast=Antheaume&amp;amp;rft.aufirst=N&amp;amp;rft.au=Barbelivien%2C+D&amp;amp;rft_id=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.researchgate.net%2Fpublication%2F283300199_Why_do_family_businesses_die_An_investigation_through_the_work_of_an_ethnologist_and_geographer_on_the_collapse_of_human_societies&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fen.wikipedia.org%3ACreeping+normality&quot; class=&quot;Z3988&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;mw-deduplicated-inline-style&quot; href=&quot;mw-data:TemplateStyles:r886058088&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-:5-5&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;^ &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality#cite_ref-:5_5-0&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;a&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality#cite_ref-:5_5-1&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;b&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;&lt;cite class=&quot;citation journal&quot;&gt;Chon K (June 2016). &quot;Cybercrime precursors: Towards a model of offender resources&quot;. &lt;i&gt;Australian National University&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;span title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Ajournal&amp;amp;rft.genre=article&amp;amp;rft.jtitle=Australian+National+University&amp;amp;rft.atitle=Cybercrime+precursors%3A+Towards+a+model+of+offender+resources&amp;amp;rft.date=2016-06&amp;amp;rft.aulast=Chon&amp;amp;rft.aufirst=K&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fen.wikipedia.org%3ACreeping+normality&quot; class=&quot;Z3988&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;mw-deduplicated-inline-style&quot; href=&quot;mw-data:TemplateStyles:r886058088&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-:6-6&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;^ &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality#cite_ref-:6_6-0&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;a&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality#cite_ref-:6_6-1&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;b&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;&lt;cite class=&quot;citation book&quot;&gt;Tan A, Ho P (2017). &lt;i&gt;The Challenges of Governance in a Complex World&lt;/i&gt;. World Scientific Publishing Company Pte Limited. p. 11.&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;span title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Abook&amp;amp;rft.genre=book&amp;amp;rft.btitle=The+Challenges+of+Governance+in+a+Complex+World&amp;amp;rft.pages=11&amp;amp;rft.pub=World+Scientific+Publishing+Company+Pte+Limited&amp;amp;rft.date=2017&amp;amp;rft.aulast=Tan&amp;amp;rft.aufirst=Ariel&amp;amp;rft.au=Ho%2C+Peter&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fen.wikipedia.org%3ACreeping+normality&quot; class=&quot;Z3988&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;mw-deduplicated-inline-style&quot; href=&quot;mw-data:TemplateStyles:r886058088&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-:2-7&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;^ &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality#cite_ref-:2_7-0&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;a&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality#cite_ref-:2_7-1&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;b&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;&lt;cite class=&quot;citation journal&quot;&gt;Moskal, Patsy, Dziuban, Charles, Upchurch, Randall, Hartman, Joel, Truman, Barbara (Fall 2006). &quot;Assessing Online Learning: What One University Learned about Student Success, Persistence, and Satisfaction&quot;. &lt;i&gt;Association of American Colleges and Universities&lt;/i&gt;. &lt;b&gt;8&lt;/b&gt;: 26–29  – via ProQuest.&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;span title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Ajournal&amp;amp;rft.genre=article&amp;amp;rft.jtitle=Association+of+American+Colleges+and+Universities&amp;amp;rft.atitle=Assessing+Online+Learning%3A+What+One+University+Learned+about+Student+Success%2C+Persistence%2C+and+Satisfaction&amp;amp;rft.ssn=fall&amp;amp;rft.volume=8&amp;amp;rft.pages=26-29&amp;amp;rft.date=2006&amp;amp;rft.au=Moskal%2C+Patsy%2C+Dziuban%2C+Charles%2C+Upchurch%2C+Randall%2C+Hartman%2C+Joel%2C+Truman%2C+Barbara&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fen.wikipedia.org%3ACreeping+normality&quot; class=&quot;Z3988&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;cs1-maint citation-comment&quot;&gt;CS1 maint: Multiple names: authors list (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Category:CS1_maint:_Multiple_names:_authors_list&quot; title=&quot;Category:CS1 maint: Multiple names: authors list&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;mw-deduplicated-inline-style&quot; href=&quot;mw-data:TemplateStyles:r886058088&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-:3-8&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;^ &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality#cite_ref-:3_8-0&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;a&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality#cite_ref-:3_8-1&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;b&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality#cite_ref-:3_8-2&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;c&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;De Waal, Alex. (2006). TOWARDS A COMPARATIVE POLITICAL ETHNOGRAPHY OF DISASTER PREVENTION. Journal of International Affairs, 59(2), 129-XIV.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-:0-9&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;^ &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality#cite_ref-:0_9-0&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;a&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality#cite_ref-:0_9-1&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;b&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;&lt;cite class=&quot;citation journal&quot;&gt;Wilkinson SA, Poad D, Stapleton H (May 2013). &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3664593&quot;&gt;&quot;Maternal overweight and obesity: a survey of clinicians' characteristics and attitudes, and their responses to their pregnant clients&quot;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;BMC Pregnancy and Childbirth&lt;/i&gt;. &lt;b&gt;13&lt;/b&gt;: 117. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_object_identifier&quot; title=&quot;Digital object identifier&quot;&gt;doi&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1186%2F1471-2393-13-117&quot;&gt;10.1186/1471-2393-13-117&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PubMed_Central&quot; title=&quot;PubMed Central&quot;&gt;PMC&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;cs1-lock-free&quot; title=&quot;Freely accessible&quot;&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3664593&quot;&gt;3664593&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PubMed_Identifier&quot; class=&quot;mw-redirect&quot; title=&quot;PubMed Identifier&quot;&gt;PMID&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/23692981&quot;&gt;23692981&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;span title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Ajournal&amp;amp;rft.genre=article&amp;amp;rft.jtitle=BMC+Pregnancy+and+Childbirth&amp;amp;rft.atitle=Maternal+overweight+and+obesity%3A+a+survey+of+clinicians%27+characteristics+and+attitudes%2C+and+their+responses+to+their+pregnant+clients&amp;amp;rft.volume=13&amp;amp;rft.pages=117&amp;amp;rft.date=2013-05&amp;amp;rft_id=%2F%2Fwww.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov%2Fpmc%2Farticles%2FPMC3664593&amp;amp;rft_id=info%3Apmid%2F23692981&amp;amp;rft_id=info%3Adoi%2F10.1186%2F1471-2393-13-117&amp;amp;rft.aulast=Wilkinson&amp;amp;rft.aufirst=SA&amp;amp;rft.au=Poad%2C+D&amp;amp;rft.au=Stapleton%2C+H&amp;amp;rft_id=%2F%2Fwww.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov%2Fpmc%2Farticles%2FPMC3664593&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fen.wikipedia.org%3ACreeping+normality&quot; class=&quot;Z3988&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;mw-deduplicated-inline-style&quot; href=&quot;mw-data:TemplateStyles:r886058088&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-10&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality#cite_ref-10&quot;&gt;^&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;&lt;cite class=&quot;citation journal&quot;&gt;Schmied VA, Duff M, Dahlen HG, Mills AE, Kolt GS (August 2011). &quot;&lt;span class=&quot;cs1-kern-left&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;Not waving but drowning': a study of the experiences and concerns of midwives and other health professionals caring for obese childbearing women&quot;. &lt;i&gt;Midwifery&lt;/i&gt;. &lt;b&gt;27&lt;/b&gt; (4): 424–30. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_object_identifier&quot; title=&quot;Digital object identifier&quot;&gt;doi&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1016%2Fj.midw.2010.02.010&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.midw.2010.02.010&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PubMed_Identifier&quot; class=&quot;mw-redirect&quot; title=&quot;PubMed Identifier&quot;&gt;PMID&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/20381222&quot;&gt;20381222&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;span title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Ajournal&amp;amp;rft.genre=article&amp;amp;rft.jtitle=Midwifery&amp;amp;rft.atitle=%27Not+waving+but+drowning%27%3A+a+study+of+the+experiences+and+concerns+of+midwives+and+other+health+professionals+caring+for+obese+childbearing+women&amp;amp;rft.volume=27&amp;amp;rft.issue=4&amp;amp;rft.pages=424-30&amp;amp;rft.date=2011-08&amp;amp;rft_id=info%3Adoi%2F10.1016%2Fj.midw.2010.02.010&amp;amp;rft_id=info%3Apmid%2F20381222&amp;amp;rft.aulast=Schmied&amp;amp;rft.aufirst=VA&amp;amp;rft.au=Duff%2C+M&amp;amp;rft.au=Dahlen%2C+HG&amp;amp;rft.au=Mills%2C+AE&amp;amp;rft.au=Kolt%2C+GS&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fen.wikipedia.org%3ACreeping+normality&quot; class=&quot;Z3988&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;mw-deduplicated-inline-style&quot; href=&quot;mw-data:TemplateStyles:r886058088&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-11&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality#cite_ref-11&quot;&gt;^&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;&lt;cite class=&quot;citation journal&quot;&gt;Mills A, Schmied VA, Dahlen HG (July 2013). &quot;&lt;span class=&quot;cs1-kern-left&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;Get alongside us', women's experiences of being overweight and pregnant in Sydney, Australia&quot;. &lt;i&gt;Maternal &amp;amp; Child Nutrition&lt;/i&gt;. &lt;b&gt;9&lt;/b&gt; (3): 309–21. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_object_identifier&quot; title=&quot;Digital object identifier&quot;&gt;doi&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1111%2Fj.1740-8709.2011.00386.x&quot;&gt;10.1111/j.1740-8709.2011.00386.x&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PubMed_Identifier&quot; class=&quot;mw-redirect&quot; title=&quot;PubMed Identifier&quot;&gt;PMID&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/22168548&quot;&gt;22168548&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;span title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Ajournal&amp;amp;rft.genre=article&amp;amp;rft.jtitle=Maternal+%26+Child+Nutrition&amp;amp;rft.atitle=%27Get+alongside+us%27%2C+women%27s+experiences+of+being+overweight+and+pregnant+in+Sydney%2C+Australia&amp;amp;rft.volume=9&amp;amp;rft.issue=3&amp;amp;rft.pages=309-21&amp;amp;rft.date=2013-07&amp;amp;rft_id=info%3Adoi%2F10.1111%2Fj.1740-8709.2011.00386.x&amp;amp;rft_id=info%3Apmid%2F22168548&amp;amp;rft.aulast=Mills&amp;amp;rft.aufirst=A&amp;amp;rft.au=Schmied%2C+VA&amp;amp;rft.au=Dahlen%2C+HG&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fen.wikipedia.org%3ACreeping+normality&quot; class=&quot;Z3988&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;mw-deduplicated-inline-style&quot; href=&quot;mw-data:TemplateStyles:r886058088&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-12&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality#cite_ref-12&quot;&gt;^&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;&lt;cite class=&quot;citation journal&quot;&gt;Miller M, Hearn L, van der Pligt P, Wilcox J, Campbell KJ (2014-06-06). &quot;Preventing maternal and early childhood obesity: the fetal flaw in Australian perinatal care&quot;. &lt;i&gt;Australian Journal of Primary Health&lt;/i&gt;. &lt;b&gt;20&lt;/b&gt; (2): 123–7. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_object_identifier&quot; title=&quot;Digital object identifier&quot;&gt;doi&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1071%2FPY13080&quot;&gt;10.1071/PY13080&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PubMed_Identifier&quot; class=&quot;mw-redirect&quot; title=&quot;PubMed Identifier&quot;&gt;PMID&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/24176286&quot;&gt;24176286&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;span title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Ajournal&amp;amp;rft.genre=article&amp;amp;rft.jtitle=Australian+Journal+of+Primary+Health&amp;amp;rft.atitle=Preventing+maternal+and+early+childhood+obesity%3A+the+fetal+flaw+in+Australian+perinatal+care&amp;amp;rft.volume=20&amp;amp;rft.issue=2&amp;amp;rft.pages=123-7&amp;amp;rft.date=2014-06-06&amp;amp;rft_id=info%3Adoi%2F10.1071%2FPY13080&amp;amp;rft_id=info%3Apmid%2F24176286&amp;amp;rft.aulast=Miller&amp;amp;rft.aufirst=M&amp;amp;rft.au=Hearn%2C+L&amp;amp;rft.au=van+der+Pligt%2C+P&amp;amp;rft.au=Wilcox%2C+J&amp;amp;rft.au=Campbell%2C+KJ&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fen.wikipedia.org%3ACreeping+normality&quot; class=&quot;Z3988&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;mw-deduplicated-inline-style&quot; href=&quot;mw-data:TemplateStyles:r886058088&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-13&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality#cite_ref-13&quot;&gt;^&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;&lt;cite class=&quot;citation journal&quot;&gt;Moore Simas TA, Waring ME, Sullivan GM, Liao X, Rosal MC, Hardy JR, Berry RE (December 2013). &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3974574&quot;&gt;&quot;Institute of medicine 2009 gestational weight gain guideline knowledge: survey of obstetrics/gynecology and family medicine residents of the United States&quot;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;Birth&lt;/i&gt;. &lt;b&gt;40&lt;/b&gt; (4): 237–46. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_object_identifier&quot; title=&quot;Digital object identifier&quot;&gt;doi&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1111%2Fbirt.12061&quot;&gt;10.1111/birt.12061&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PubMed_Central&quot; title=&quot;PubMed Central&quot;&gt;PMC&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;cs1-lock-free&quot; title=&quot;Freely accessible&quot;&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3974574&quot;&gt;3974574&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PubMed_Identifier&quot; class=&quot;mw-redirect&quot; title=&quot;PubMed Identifier&quot;&gt;PMID&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/24344704&quot;&gt;24344704&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;span title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Ajournal&amp;amp;rft.genre=article&amp;amp;rft.jtitle=Birth&amp;amp;rft.atitle=Institute+of+medicine+2009+gestational+weight+gain+guideline+knowledge%3A+survey+of+obstetrics%2Fgynecology+and+family+medicine+residents+of+the+United+States&amp;amp;rft.volume=40&amp;amp;rft.issue=4&amp;amp;rft.pages=237-46&amp;amp;rft.date=2013-12&amp;amp;rft_id=%2F%2Fwww.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov%2Fpmc%2Farticles%2FPMC3974574&amp;amp;rft_id=info%3Apmid%2F24344704&amp;amp;rft_id=info%3Adoi%2F10.1111%2Fbirt.12061&amp;amp;rft.aulast=Moore+Simas&amp;amp;rft.aufirst=TA&amp;amp;rft.au=Waring%2C+ME&amp;amp;rft.au=Sullivan%2C+GM&amp;amp;rft.au=Liao%2C+X&amp;amp;rft.au=Rosal%2C+MC&amp;amp;rft.au=Hardy%2C+JR&amp;amp;rft.au=Berry%2C+RE&amp;amp;rft_id=%2F%2Fwww.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov%2Fpmc%2Farticles%2FPMC3974574&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fen.wikipedia.org%3ACreeping+normality&quot; class=&quot;Z3988&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;mw-deduplicated-inline-style&quot; href=&quot;mw-data:TemplateStyles:r886058088&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-:4-14&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;^ &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality#cite_ref-:4_14-0&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;a&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality#cite_ref-:4_14-1&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;b&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality#cite_ref-:4_14-2&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;c&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality#cite_ref-:4_14-3&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;d&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;Wilkinson, S. A., Poad, D., &amp;amp; Stapleton, H. (2013). Maternal overweight and obesity: A survey of clinicians' characteristics and attitudes, and their responses to their pregnant clients. BMC Pregnancy and Childbirth, 13, 117. doi:http://dx.doi.org/10.1186/1471-2393-13-117&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;!-- 
NewPP limit report
Parsed by mw1251
Cached time: 20190811035705
Cache expiry: 2592000
Dynamic content: false
Complications: [vary&amp;#8208;revision&amp;#8208;sha1]
CPU time usage: 0.300 seconds
Real time usage: 0.358 seconds
Preprocessor visited node count: 720/1000000
Preprocessor generated node count: 0/1500000
Post&amp;#8208;expand include size: 23329/2097152 bytes
Template argument size: 678/2097152 bytes
Highest expansion depth: 7/40
Expensive parser function count: 2/500
Unstrip recursion depth: 1/20
Unstrip post&amp;#8208;expand size: 38957/5000000 bytes
Number of Wikibase entities loaded: 2/400
Lua time usage: 0.167/10.000 seconds
Lua memory usage: 3.46 MB/50 MB
--&gt;
&lt;!--
Transclusion expansion time report (%,ms,calls,template)
100.00%  293.840      1 -total
 84.27%  247.629      1 Template:Reflist
 42.63%  125.250      8 Template:Cite_journal
 26.44%   77.688      2 Template:Cite_web
 10.34%   30.374      1 Template:Quote
  5.52%   16.214      1 Template:Trim_quotes
  3.09%    9.071      1 Template:Cite_book
  1.12%    3.304      1 Template:Main_other
--&gt;

&lt;!-- Saved in parser cache with key enwiki:pcache:idhash:1957465-0!canonical and timestamp 20190811035705 and revision id 910305064
 --&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Special:CentralAutoLogin/start?type=1x1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;border: none; position: absolute;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
		
		&lt;div class=&quot;printfooter&quot;&gt;Retrieved from &quot;&lt;a dir=&quot;ltr&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Creeping_normality&amp;amp;oldid=910305064&quot;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Creeping_normality&amp;amp;oldid=910305064&lt;/a&gt;&quot;&lt;/div&gt;
		
		
		&lt;div class=&quot;visualClear&quot;/&gt;
		
	</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 19:18:40 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Ismair</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creeping_normality</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>What Does a Coder Do If They Can&amp;#039;t Type?</title>
<link>http://nsaphra.github.io/post/hands/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://nsaphra.github.io/post/hands/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;In August of 2015, my hands stopped working. I could still control them, but every movement accumulated more pain, so every motion came with a cost: getting dressed in the morning, sending a text, lifting a glass. I was interning at Google that summer about to begin a PhD in Scotland, but coding all day would have left me in agony. In relating this story, I often mention that for months before I learned to work without my hands, I had nothing to do but go to a bar and order a shot of vodka with a straw in it. This is a very funny joke.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been in pain for four years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;talon&quot;&gt;Talon&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to this disability, I cannot type or write by hand. Many people have asked me about the stack that enables me to be productive in spite of this limitation. I hope this information is helpful both for people with more severe limitations, and for programmers with mild repetitive stress injuries who can benefit from reducing their keyboard use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The star of the show is &lt;a href=&quot;https://talonvoice.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Talon&lt;/a&gt;, a system which makes it easy to write customized grammars and scripts that work with speech recognition systems to enable programming. Commands range from simple aliases for common symbols to complex meta-commands which repeat a previous utterance or change dictation modes. For example, just in the case of parentheses, I have separate commands for &lt;code&gt;(&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;)&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;()&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;()⬅️&lt;/code&gt; (which leaves the cursor between parentheses so my next utterance is bracketed).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each Talon user has a number of personal scripts. The most precious script that I’ve written is probably my indexed clipboard:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-python&quot; data-lang=&quot;python&quot;&gt; &lt;span&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; talon.voice &lt;span&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; Key, press, Str, Context
 &lt;span&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; talon &lt;span&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; clip
 &lt;span&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; .talon_community.utils &lt;span&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;

 ctx &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; Context(&lt;span&gt;'clipboard'&lt;/span&gt;)

 &lt;span&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;copy_selection&lt;/span&gt;(m):
     &lt;span&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; clip&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;capture() &lt;span&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; sel:
         press(&lt;span&gt;'cmd-c'&lt;/span&gt;)
     &lt;span&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; len(m&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;_words) &lt;span&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;:
         key &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;' '&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;join(parse_words(m))
         value &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; sel&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;get()
         keymap[&lt;span&gt;'paste &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;%s&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;'&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;%&lt;/span&gt; key] &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; value
         ctx&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;keymap(keymap)
         ctx&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;reload()
     &lt;span&gt;else&lt;/span&gt;:
         clip&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;set(sel&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;get())

 keymap &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; {
     &lt;span&gt;'paste'&lt;/span&gt;: Key(&lt;span&gt;'cmd-v'&lt;/span&gt;),
     &lt;span&gt;'clip [&amp;lt;dgndictation&amp;gt;]'&lt;/span&gt;: copy_selection,
 }

 ctx&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;keymap(keymap)&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The use is simple. After selecting a particular phrase using my cursor control commands, I say “clip [foo]“, and every time I want to enter the same phrase after, I say “paste [foo]“. I therefore only have to dictate a particularly obnoxious variable name once. However, it does introduce a new challenge: every variable has two names, its written name and its spoken name. This unfortunate side effect exacerbates the difficulty of naming variables, which has been called “the hardest problem in computer science”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are a vim or Emacs power user, this may all feel familiar to you. I have commands for searching, moving a cursor, selection, and manipulating the clipboard. Learning to dictate code is a lot like learning a new text editor very thoroughly, down to the challenge of customizing for your particular languages and needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dwiel/talon_community&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Talon community&lt;/a&gt; has specialized commands that take effect depending on application or programming language. For a Perl user, for example, a good starting point might be to borrow settings from Emily Shea:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/Mz3JeYfBTcY&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;YouTube Video&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Talon setup relies on Dragon for the speech recognition side. Unfortunately, Nuance has discontinued OSX Dragon editions that make scripting possible. The coder behind Talon, &lt;a href=&quot;http://ryanhileman.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ryan Hileman&lt;/a&gt;, is working on a suitable replacement but at time of writing, it is not yet ready.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;interlude&quot;&gt;Interlude&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People often ask for my diagnosis, but it officially depends on the country I’m in. After an initial assumption that carpal tunnel was to blame, a rheumatologist gave me my first American diagnosis: &lt;em&gt;fibromyalgia&lt;/em&gt;, a word which is Doctorspeak for “go away”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did not go away. A neurologist performed a skin biopsy that led to my official American diagnosis of “idiopathic small fiber neuropathy”, meaning that I am missing crucial nerve fibers that transmit heat and pain but nobody knows why. &lt;em&gt;Idiopathic&lt;/em&gt; is also Doctorspeak for “go away”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went away to the UK. I brought my medical records from America, but my British neurologist did not read my records or perform examinations. After a brief conversation, he gave me my British diagnosis by submitting a note that he had no evidence of any physical cause, and he “suspected significant functional overlay”, which is how they teach you to call someone delusional in medical school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My GP read the note and informed me: He would not prescribe me painkillers. He would not send me for a second opinion from a neurologist, or treatment from any other specialist. The only referral he would write would be to a psychologist to help me “resolve the underlying issues behind my pain”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He then kicked me out of his office for using the word “fucking”. “We do not tolerate cursing”, said a sign in the lobby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;equipment&quot;&gt;Equipment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For dictating, I use two different microphones. In the office, I use a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en-uk.sennheiser.com/me-3-ii&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sennheiser ME-3&lt;/a&gt;, while for travel I use a Bluetooth headset, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en-uk.sennheiser.com/mb-pro-1-uc-ml-and-mb-pro-2-uc-ml&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sennheiser MB Pro 2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another essential piece of equipment for me is my foot pedal, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pageflip.com/products/firefly&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PageFlip Firefly&lt;/a&gt;. It is programmable, so I have modified the settings to include one that is useful for reading papers in &lt;a href=&quot;https://skim-app.sourceforge.io/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Skim&lt;/a&gt;, with the left pedal corresponding to a click and the right pedal corresponding to down arrow. I can use my feet to scroll, and to click for annotations. Another pedal setting I have added maps the pedals to click and shift+enter. This setting is useful for Jupyter notebooks and writing my research notes and mathematical scratch work in &lt;a href=&quot;https://happenapps.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Quiver&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When my hands are unusually aggravated, I cannot nudge my mouse around anymore and I fall back on &lt;a href=&quot;https://shortcatapp.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;shortcat&lt;/a&gt;, which allows me to press buttons by dictating keyboard strokes instead of using a mouse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My final essential piece of equipment is a pair of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.futuro-usa.com/3M/en_US/futuro-us/products/~/FUTURO-Night-Wrist-Support/?N=4318+3294508029+3294529207&amp;amp;rt=rud&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;large wrist braces&lt;/a&gt;. The primary purpose of my braces is to discourage me from habitual hand use. I always wear them at conferences, because wearing them is easier than constantly repeating, “I cannot shake hands due to a disability”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;interlude-1&quot;&gt;Interlude&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I struggle with sleep. I dream that my thumbs fall off. I dream that every bone in my hands breaks. I dream that my arms break out in open bleeding sores. I wake up and the pain remains like an invisible nightmare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;limitations&quot;&gt;Limitations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe ironically, the largest concern if you begin to dictate code is that you do not develop a repetitive stress injury in your vocal tract. Speaking quietly can actually cause more damage, hydration is important, and better posture will prevent damage in your voice as well as the rest of your body. I strongly recommend finding a vocal coach who teaches actors and singers how to protect their voices. It is important to take breaks, and you may find talking tiring outside of work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speech recognition technology is not perfect, and the error rate is even higher if you have an unusual accent. Furthermore, it may force you to take time off from programming every time you develop a cold or sore throat. I live in fear of even minor colds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having a private space to dictate in is essential. I was unable to be productive working from home, but as soon as I had a private office I developed momentum on several research projects. I know that this is a huge limitation for a lot of people because of the productivity-destroying, soul-sucking trend towards open offices for all programming work. If your workplace has fallen prey to this trend, you may still have options. In many countries, large companies will be obligated to provide a space to work in if you are disabled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;addendum&quot;&gt;Addendum&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life with my disability is not easy, but thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hedonic_treadmill&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;hedonic adaptation&lt;/a&gt; as well as satisfying &lt;a href=&quot;http://nsaphra.github.io/publication/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;work&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://auldreekierollerderby.com/2019/08/10/the-one-gift-i-received-along-with-my-disability/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;hobbies&lt;/a&gt;, I am actually very happy. If you have recently developed a disability or chronic pain condition, it may feel like you could never adjust to the lifestyle required. That is why I have tried to give you a lens into my challenges as well as my successes. It is easy to respond to anyone who has overcome adversity with one of two reactions: “It can’t be that hard,” or “I could never do that”. Move past both reactions. It is that hard. You can do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are currently able-bodied, please support your disabled colleagues, coworkers, and anyone you have power over in their quest to do valuable and fulfilling work. I encourage other disabled scientists and programmers to reach out to me with any questions they have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thank you for comments on early drafts: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cs.jhu.edu/~vandurme/Carrell.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Annabelle Carrell&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.craiginnes.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Craig Innes&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/uscm_&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Matthew Summers&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dinalevitan.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Dina Lev&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ims.uni-stuttgart.de/institut/mitarbeiter/schlecdk/index.en.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Dominik Schlechtweg&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://americanstudies.yale.edu/people/yuhe-faye-wang&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Yuhe Faye Wang&lt;/a&gt; (who is in The Humanities!). Thank you to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.recurse.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Recurse Center&lt;/a&gt; for providing a private space for me to learn to dictate code. Thank you to my PhD advisor, &lt;a href=&quot;https://alopez.github.io/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Adam Lopez&lt;/a&gt;, who has unfailingly supported me and made all of this possible.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 14:28:22 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>panic</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://nsaphra.github.io/post/hands/</og:url>
<og:title>What Does a Coder Do If They Can't Type? | Objective Funk</og:title>
<og:description>In August of 2015, my hands stopped working. I could still control them, but every movement accumulated more pain, so every motion came with a cost: getting dressed in the morning, sending a text, lifting a glass. I was interning at Google that summer about to begin a PhD in Scotland, but coding all day would have left me in agony. In relating this story, I often mention that for months before I learned to work without my hands, I had nothing to do but go to a bar and order a shot of vodka with a straw in it.</og:description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://nsaphra.github.io/post/hands/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>