<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Show HN: GradientMagic</title>
<link>https://www.gradientmagic.com/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.gradientmagic.com/</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gradientmagic.com/&quot;&gt;https://www.gradientmagic.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24177804&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24177804&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 231&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 31&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 13:57:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jordanmarshall</dc:creator>
<og:title>Gradient Magic - Fantastic and Unique CSS Gradients</og:title>
<og:description>A Free Gallery of Fantastic and Unique CSS Gradients.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.gradientmagic.com</og:url>
<og:image>./img/GM_Social.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.gradientmagic.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Web by Google (TM)</title>
<link>https://landshark.io/2020/08/16/web-by-google.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://landshark.io/2020/08/16/web-by-google.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Looking at Mozilla’s finances, it’s reasonable to conclude that Google is keeping them on life support to keep the anti-trust hounds at bay. Mozilla’s deal with Google will account for at least 70% of their revenues going forward. That’s over $400 million to be the default search provider in 4% of browsers. For 1 year. I’ll bet my next paycheck that Google reupped this rather generous agreement to avoid a repeat of Microsoft’s troubles over an Internet Explorer monopoly. My guess is that Google will decide it’s in their interest to pull the plug right around the time this latest wave of anti-trust talk blows over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the troubles at Mozilla, Google is one step closer to replicating the WeChat and Facebook walled-garden model on the Web. A quick survey a the field of play shows just how far Google has come in capturing the once open Web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;browser-war-is-over&quot;&gt;(Browser) War is over&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chrome’s ability to dictate web standards will only get stronger over time. Safari and Firefox have been able to apply some shame to Chrome on things like disabling third-party cookies, but soon it’ll just be Apple left with a voice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Google doesn’t even need Chrome to dictate standards since it controls the Web’s front door. AMP, a technology no one asked for, is now on over 70% of all marketing websites for no other reason than Google said so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And let’s not forget that most people now access the web via mobile devices, 75% of which run Google’s Android.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;original-sins&quot;&gt;Original Sins&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two deficiencies have determined the course the Web has taken: lack of native search and lack of native payments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lacking native distributed search allowed Google to grab a monopoly position as the entry point to the web. The Web’s orignal architects were off base on hyperlinks; it turns out people just want to skip right to the answer they’re looking for. There was once the beginnings of an alternative in public bookmarking sites, but social networks came and sucked all the air out of that space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lack of a safe and easy way of exchanging funds was a big factor in advertising becoming the dominant business model on the Web. No-charge services became the norm because, for a long time, there was no reasonable way to pay for them. Enter advertising to fill the void. I think it’s safe to say that Google’s AdWords is the dominant advertising platform on the open Web, which means it holds a commanding position in the Web’s finances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m also going to throw in an honorable mention to poor native video support (it is hyper_text_ after all). It’s beating a dead horse to point out that Google also serves up the vast majority of videos streamed on the Web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-then&quot;&gt;So then…&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So Google controls the Web’s search and video infrastructure. It can and does dictate standards and media formats. It also controls a huge chunk of the revenues available when publishing and selling on the Web. It even controls the operating system and browser through which most people interact with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google’s capture of the Web is a &lt;em&gt;fait accompli&lt;/em&gt;. Only legislation will keep the World Wide Web from finally becoming Web by Google (TM).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 11:23:48 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>alangibson</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://landshark.io/2020/08/16/web-by-google.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Visual Game Editor for Pixi.js</title>
<link>https://ctjs.rocks/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://ctjs.rocks/</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://ctjs.rocks/&quot;&gt;https://ctjs.rocks/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24176655&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24176655&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 233&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 22&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 10:20:37 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>erlend_sh</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://ctjs.rocks/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>SQLite 3.33</title>
<link>https://www.sqlite.org/releaselog/3_33_0.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.sqlite.org/releaselog/3_33_0.html</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;viewport&quot; content=&quot;width=device-width, initial-scale=1.0&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;content-type&quot; content=&quot;text/html; charset=utf-8&quot; /&gt;&lt;link href=&quot;../sqlite.css&quot; rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot; /&gt;&lt;title&gt;SQLite Release 3.33.0 On 2020-08-14&lt;/title&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;24.791707798618&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;nosearch&quot; readability=&quot;3.2307692307692&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sqlite.org/index.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;logo&quot; src=&quot;https://www.sqlite.org/images/sqlite370_banner.gif&quot; alt=&quot;SQLite&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Small. Fast. Reliable.&lt;br /&gt;Choose any three.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;SQLite Release 3.33.0 On 2020-08-14&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;lessindent&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Support for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sqlite.org/lang_update.html#upfrom&quot;&gt;UPDATE FROM&lt;/a&gt; following the PostgreSQL syntax.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increase the maximum size of database files to 281 TB.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extended the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sqlite.org/pragma.html#pragma_integrity_check&quot;&gt;PRAGMA integrity_check&lt;/a&gt; statement so that it can optionally be limited to verifying just a single table and its indexes, rather than the entire database file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sqlite.org/floatingpoint.html#decext&quot;&gt;decimal extension&lt;/a&gt; for doing arbitrary-precision decimal arithmetic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhancements to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sqlite.org/floatingpoint.html#ieee754ext&quot;&gt;ieee754 extension&lt;/a&gt; for working with IEEE 754 binary64 numbers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sqlite.org/cli.html&quot;&gt;CLI&lt;/a&gt; enhancements:
&lt;ol type=&quot;a&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Added four new &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sqlite.org/cli.html#dotmode&quot;&gt;output modes&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;box&quot;, &quot;json&quot;, &quot;markdown&quot;, and &quot;table&quot;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &quot;column&quot; output mode automatically expands columns to contain the longest output row and automatically turns &quot;.header&quot; on if it has not been previously set.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &quot;quote&quot; output mode honors &quot;.separator&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sqlite.org/floatingpoint.html#decext&quot;&gt;decimal extension&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sqlite.org/floatingpoint.html#ieee754ext&quot;&gt;ieee754 extension&lt;/a&gt; are built-in to the CLI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Query planner improvements:
&lt;ol type=&quot;a&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Add the ability to find a full-index-scan query plan for queries using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sqlite.org/lang_indexedby.html&quot;&gt;INDEXED BY&lt;/a&gt; which previously would fail with &quot;no query solution&quot;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do a better job of detecting missing, incomplete, and/or dodgy &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sqlite.org/fileformat2.html#stat1tab&quot;&gt;sqlite_stat1&lt;/a&gt; data and generates good query plans in spite of the misinformation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved performance of queries like &quot;SELECT min(x) FROM t WHERE y IN (?,?,?)&quot; assuming an index on t(x,y).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sqlite.org/wal.html&quot;&gt;WAL mode&lt;/a&gt;, if a writer crashes and leaves the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sqlite.org/walformat.html#shm&quot;&gt;shm file&lt;/a&gt; in an inconsistent state, subsequent transactions are now able to recover the shm file even if there are active read transactions. Before this enhancement, shm file recovery that scenario would result in an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sqlite.org/rescode.html#protocol&quot;&gt;SQLITE_PROTOCOL&lt;/a&gt; error.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hashes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SQLITE_SOURCE_ID: 2020-08-14 13:23:32 fca8dc8b578f215a969cd899336378966156154710873e68b3d9ac5881b0ff3f&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SHA3-256 for sqlite3.c: d00b7fffa6d33af2303430eaf394321da2960604d25a4471c7af566344f2abf9&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sqlite.org/changes.html&quot;&gt;complete list of SQLite releases&lt;/a&gt; in a single page and a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sqlite.org/chronology.html&quot;&gt;chronology&lt;/a&gt; are both also available. A detailed history of every check-in is available at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sqlite.org/src/timeline&quot;&gt;SQLite version control site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 10:10:47 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>chmaynard</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.sqlite.org/releaselog/3_33_0.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>USPS Files Patent for a Blockchain-Based Voting System</title>
<link>https://heraldsheets.com/us-postal-service-usps-files-patent-for-blockchain-based-voting-system/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://heraldsheets.com/us-postal-service-usps-files-patent-for-blockchain-based-voting-system/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;tdb-block-inner td-fix-index&quot; readability=&quot;48.746642793196&quot;&gt;
&lt;center/&gt;
The United States Postal Service (USPS) has reportedly filed a patent for a blockchain-based mail-in voting system.
&lt;p&gt;Following President Donald Trump’s conclusion that mail-in voting would represent ballots all over the place and fraudulent ballots would be named after dogs and dead people, the patent that was filed back in February 2020 was made public on Thursday 13th August.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The public patent application that contains 47 pages is majorly occupied with diagrams showing various components of the proposed mail-in voting system, coupled with each stage of the electronic process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The patent filed by the postal service &lt;a href=&quot;https://pdfaiw.uspto.gov/.aiw?PageNum=0&amp;amp;docid=20200258338&amp;amp;IDKey=7A4F4EA40D1F&amp;amp;HomeUrl=http%3A%2F%2Fappft.uspto.gov%2Fnetacgi%2Fnph-Parser%3FSect1%3DPTO1%2526Sect2%3DHITOFF%2526d%3DPG01%2526p%3D1%2526u%3D%2Fnetahtml%2FPTO%2Fsrchnum.html%2526r%3D1%2526f%3DG%2526l%3D50%2526s1%3D20200258338.PGNR.%2526OS%3D%2526RS%3D&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;reads in part&lt;/a&gt; as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“A voting system can use the security of blockchain and the mail to provide a reliable voting system. A registered voter receives a computer-readable code in the mail and confirms identity and confirms correct ballot information in an election. The system separates voter identification and votes to ensure vote anonymity, and stores votes on a distributed ledger in a blockchain.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Often a voter is not able to or does not desire to go to a polling place to cast a vote. An election official in a jurisdiction may wish to send secure ballots via mail. Or, a jurisdiction may opt to utilize electronic resources for voting. In such cases, a secure voting system is desired.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The security of a voting system can be increased by using the dependability and security of the United States Postal Service or similar entity, and this can be incorporated with a secure computer system using a blockchain or distributed ledger to ensure vote security and to prevent tampering or modification of electronic voting results.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, &lt;a href=&quot;https://heraldsheets.com/tag/coronavirus/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;coronavirus pandemic&lt;/a&gt; is causing a twist in virtually everything across the world, including the process of the coming US presidential election.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There has been a political debate over the system that would be adopted to restrain the spread of the virus during the election. It has now been concluded that mail-in voting system would be adopted, but some people are still of the opinion that the system would encourage fraudulence during the election, hence the need for blockchain technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join us on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Herald_Sheets&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join us on &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.me/HeraldSheets&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Telegram&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join us on &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.facebook.com/HeraldSheets/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 08:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>seigando</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://heraldsheets.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/BLOCKCHAIN.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>United States Postal Service (USPS) Files Patent for a Blockchain-Based Voting System - Herald Sheets</og:title>
<og:description>The United States Postal Service (USPS) has reportedly filed a patent for a blockchain-based mail-in voting system. Following President Donald Trump’s conclusion that mail-in voting would represent ballots all over the place and fraudulent ballots would be named after dogs and dead people, the patent that was filed back in February 2020 was made public …</og:description>
<og:url>https://heraldsheets.com/us-postal-service-usps-files-patent-for-blockchain-based-voting-system/</og:url>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://heraldsheets.com/us-postal-service-usps-files-patent-for-blockchain-based-voting-system/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Amazon Liable for Defective Third-Party Products Rules CA Appellate Court</title>
<link>https://californiaglobe.com/section-2/amazon-liable-for-defective-third-party-products-rules-ca-appelate-court/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://californiaglobe.com/section-2/amazon-liable-for-defective-third-party-products-rules-ca-appelate-court/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, California’s 4th District Court of Appeal in Santa Ana found that Amazon.com can now be held liable for injury for selling defective products from third party sellers in it’s online marketplace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Amazon now liable for damages from any product sold in their online marketplace&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ruling has moved Amazon in with other retailers who face the same liability risk when selling online, as per state product liability law. Thursday’s decision also overturned the previous state Superior Court ruling in San Diego, who had been found to have been a “service provider” instead of a “retailer” and therefore not being responsible for liability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plaintiff of the case, Angela Bolger, had bought a laptop battery off of Amazon from a seller called “E-Life”, the working name for Hong Kong battery seller Lenoge Technology. Bolger said that the battery had burst into flames when used, burning her arms, legs, and feet, as well as damaging her laptop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon argued that it wasn’t liable because it did not distribute, manufacture, or sell that product, and that it was only available on their website from a third party seller order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Appellate Court didn’t agree with Amazon’s stance, noting that the product had been listed on Amazon, was stored in an Amazon warehouse, had facilitated payment, and shipped it out in Amazon packaging, proving it to have a hand in getting it to Bolger and thus being liable under California law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;gnt_ar_b_p&quot;&gt;“Amazon placed itself between Lenoge and Bolger in the chain of distribution of the product at issue here,” explained the court in their ruling. “Amazon accepted possession of the product from Lenoge, stored it in an Amazon warehouse, attracted Bolger to the Amazon website, provided her with a product listing for Lenoge’s product, received her payment for the product, and shipped the product in Amazon packaging to her. Whatever term we use to describe Amazon’s role, be it “retailer,” “distributor,” or merely “facilitator,” it was pivotal in bringing the product here to the consumer.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The court also found a federal statue in favor of the plaintiff, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mtsu.edu/first-amendment/article/1070/communications-decency-act-of-1996&quot;&gt;Communications Decency Act of 1996&lt;/a&gt;, noting that “It does not apply here because Bolger’s strict liability claims depend on Amazon’s own activities, not its status as a speaker or publisher of content provided by Lenoge for its product listing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;“It is impossible to overstate the magnitude of this ruling.”&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Legal experts have been slightly surprised by the ruling, as Amazon had been avoiding cases like Bolger’s for years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Amazon has successfully avoided being liable for other sellers selling through their website for years,” noted Maryland-based product liability lawyer Jim Dunham in an interview with the Globe. “Most courts have said they’re not a seller at all which makes California’s case interesting. They’re pretty much saying that, in California, if it’s on the website for sale, they’re selling it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If it continues to hold up, Amazon is going to have to take a step back now and reconfigure how they sell all of these products others want to sell with the liability risk. That means company verification of these products, and with thousands upon thousands of sellers, multiplied by many more products, that is a huge commitment. A very expensive commitment. It’s that big. They’re now liable for pretty much anything on there now. That’s a lot of potential lawsuits and enough to potentially put a dent in their earnings. And that’s just California. It’s that big.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“But, remember, Amazon has proven to have a lot of fight in them, so they’ll bring this up further.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bolger’s lawyer, Jeremy Robinson, also said a more succinct statement after the ruling on Thursday, noting that “It is impossible to overstate the magnitude of this ruling. Consumers across the nation will feel the impact of this.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;California’s ruling may effect other ruling’s nationwide, including suits in Ohio, Texas, and Pennsylvania.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon is expected to bring the case to a higher court in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;abh_box abh_box_down abh_box_business&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;abh_tab_content&quot;&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;vcard author abh_about_tab abh_tab&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemprop=&quot;author&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Person&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;abh_image&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://californiaglobe.com/author/evan-symon/&quot; class=&quot;url&quot; title=&quot;Evan Symon&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://6f45g2d4rjnipqbg27qcdg1a-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/gravatar/sym.jpg&quot; class=&quot;photo&quot; width=&quot;250&quot; alt=&quot;Evan Symon&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;abh_text&quot;&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;description note abh_description&quot; itemprop=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Evan V. Symon is the Senior Editor for the California Globe. Prior to the Globe, he reported for the Pasadena Independent, the Cleveland Plain Dealer, and was head of the Personal Experiences section at Cracked. He can be reached at evan@californiaglobe.com.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;abh_posts_tab abh_tab&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;abh_image&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://californiaglobe.com/author/evan-symon/&quot; class=&quot;url&quot; title=&quot;Evan Symon&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://6f45g2d4rjnipqbg27qcdg1a-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/gravatar/sym.jpg&quot; class=&quot;photo&quot; width=&quot;250&quot; alt=&quot;Evan Symon&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;abh_text&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;abh_name&quot;&gt;Latest posts by Evan Symon &lt;span class=&quot;abh_allposts&quot;&gt;(&lt;a href=&quot;https://californiaglobe.com/author/evan-symon/&quot;&gt;see all&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;heateor_sss_sharing_container heateor_sss_horizontal_sharing&quot; heateor-sss-data-href=&quot;https://californiaglobe.com/section-2/amazon-liable-for-defective-third-party-products-rules-ca-appelate-court/&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;heateor_sss_sharing_title&quot;&gt;Spread the news:&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 02:14:30 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>hirundo</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Amazon Liable For Defective Third-Party Products Rules CA Appellate Court - California Globe</og:title>
<og:description>On Thursday, California's 4th District Court of Appeal in Santa Ana found that Amazon.com can now be held liable for injury for selling defective products</og:description>
<og:url>https://californiaglobe.com/section-2/amazon-liable-for-defective-third-party-products-rules-ca-appelate-court/</og:url>
<og:image>https://californiaglobe.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/amaz-1.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://californiaglobe.com/section-2/amazon-liable-for-defective-third-party-products-rules-ca-appelate-court/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Trump says he is considering pardon for Edward Snowden</title>
<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-politics-snowden/trump-says-hes-considering-pardon-for-leaker-edward-snowden-idUSKCN25B10Z</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-politics-snowden/trump-says-hes-considering-pardon-for-leaker-edward-snowden-idUSKCN25B10Z</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;WASHINGTON (Reuters) - U.S. President Donald Trump said on Saturday he is considering a pardon for Edward Snowden, the former U.S. National Security Agency contractor - now living in Russia - whose spectacular leaks shook the U.S. intelligence community in 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;PrimaryAsset_container&quot; readability=&quot;7.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Image_container&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;LazyImage_container LazyImage_dark&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s1.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;amp;d=20200815&amp;amp;t=2&amp;amp;i=1529771239&amp;amp;r=LYNXNPEG7E0M1&amp;amp;w=20&quot; aria-label=&quot;FILE PHOTO: Edward Snowden speaks via video link during a news conference in New York City, U.S. September 14, 2016. REUTERS/Brendan McDermid&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;FILE PHOTO: Edward Snowden speaks via video link during a news conference in New York City, U.S. September 14, 2016. REUTERS/Brendan McDermid&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Republican president's comments followed an interview &lt;a href=&quot;https://nypost.com/2020/08/13/trump-a-lot-of-people-think-edward-snowden-not-being-treated-fairly&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; Trump gave to the New York Post this week in which he said of Snowden that &quot;there are a lot of people that think that he is not being treated fairly&quot; by U.S. law enforcement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I’m going to start looking at it,” Trump told reporters about a possible pardon, speaking at a news conference at his Bedminster, New Jersey golf club.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;U.S. authorities for years have wanted Snowden returned to the United States to face a criminal trial on espionage charges brought in 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Snowden fled the United States and was given asylum in Russia after he leaked a trove of secret files in 2013 to news organizations that revealed vast domestic and international surveillance operations carried out by the NSA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Snowden’s Russian lawyer, Anatoly Kucherena, told RIA news agency the United States should not simply pardon him, but should drop all possible prosecutions against Snowden as he had not commited any crimes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“He was acting not only in the interest of the American citizens, but in the interest of all the humankind,” Kucherena said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trump’s softening stance toward Snowden represents a sharp reversal. Shortly after the leaks, Trump expressed hostility toward Snowden, calling him “a spy who should be executed.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trump said on Saturday he thinks Americans on both the political left and the right are divided on Snowden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It seems to be a split decision,” Trump told reporters. “Many people think he should be somehow treated differently. And other people think he did very bad things.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;DOMESTIC SPYING&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some civil libertarians have praised Snowden for revealing the extraordinary scope of America’s digital espionage operations including domestic spying programs that senior U.S. officials had publicly insisted did not exist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But such a move would horrify many in the U.S. intelligence community, some of whose most important secrets were exposed. Trump has harshly criticized past leaders of the U.S. intelligence community and FBI, and on Thursday took aim at the bureau’s current director Christopher Wray, his own appointee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Justice Department filed a lawsuit last September against Snowden, arguing that the memoir he published last year, “Permanent Record,” violated non-disclosure agreements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Justice Department said Snowden published the book without submitting it to intelligence agencies for review, adding that speeches given by Snowden also violated nondisclosure agreements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trump’s use of his executive clemency powers including pardons has often benefited allies and well-connected political figures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last month he commuted the sentence of his longtime friend and adviser Roger Stone, sparing him from prison after he was convicted of lying under oath to lawmakers investigating Russian interference in the 2016 U.S. election to boost Trump’s candidacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Attribution_container&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Attribution_attribution&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Attribution_content&quot;&gt;Reporting by Raphael Satter; Additional reporting by Vladimir Soldatkin in Moscow; Editing by Daniel Wallis, Will Dunham and Frances Kerry&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;StandardArticleBody_trustBadgeContainer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;StandardArticleBody_trustBadgeTitle&quot;&gt;Our Standards:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;trustBadgeUrl&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thomsonreuters.com/en/about-us/trust-principles.html&quot;&gt;The Thomson Reuters Trust Principles.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 02:12:25 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>elliekelly</dc:creator>
<og:title>Trump says he is considering pardon for leaker Edward Snowden</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-politics-snowden-idUSKCN25B10Z</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>U.S. President Donald Trump said on Saturday he is considering a pardon for Edward Snowden, the former U.S. National Security Agency contractor - now living in Russia - whose spectacular leaks shook the U.S. intelligence community in 2013.</og:description>
<og:image>https://s1.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;d=20200815&amp;t=2&amp;i=1529771239&amp;w=1200&amp;r=LYNXNPEG7E0M1</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-politics-snowden/trump-says-hes-considering-pardon-for-leaker-edward-snowden-idUSKCN25B10Z</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Mutt email client 25 years old</title>
<link>http://mutt.org</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://mutt.org</guid>
<description>&lt;h2&gt;Latest News&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Git&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent Commits: &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/muttmua/mutt/commits/master&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/muttmua/mutt/commits/master?format=atom&quot;&gt;RSS Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Stable&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mutt 1.14.6 was released on July 11, 2020. This is a bug-fix release, fixing an error resetting access-time for relative path mailboxes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mutt 1.14.5 was released on June 23, 2020. This fixes a regression when using $tunnel to connect to a preauthenticated IMAP connection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mutt 1.14.4 was released on June 18, 2020. This is an important bug-fix release. It fixes a possible machine-in-the-middle response injection attack when using STARTTLS with IMAP, POP3, and SMTP (CVE-2020-14954).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mutt 1.14.3 was released on June 14, 2020. This is an important bug-fix release. It fixes a possible IMAP fcc/postpone machine-in-the-middle attack (CVE-2020-14093). It also fixes some GnuTLS certificate prompt issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mutt 1.14.2 was released on May 25, 2020. This is a bug-fix release, fixing a few prompt buffer-size issues and adding a potential DoS mitigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mutt 1.14.1 was released on May 16, 2020. This is a bug-fix release, fixing a documentation build issue and a few other small bugs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mutt 1.14.0 was released on May 2, 2020. This release has new features and bug fixes. See the &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/muttmua/mutt/raw/stable/UPDATING&quot;&gt;UPDATING&lt;/a&gt; file, or for more details see the &lt;a href=&quot;http://mutt.org/relnotes/1.14/&quot;&gt;release notes&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mutt 1.13.5 was released on March 28, 2020. This is a bug-fix release, fixing a use-after-free bug, and a couple format string processing bugs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mutt 1.13.4 was released on February 15, 2020. This is a bug-fix release, fixing a possible memory corruption bug when sync'ing imap mailboxes, improving large-threaded mailbox opening speed, and reverting $ssl_force_tls to default unset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mutt 1.13.3 was released on January 12, 2020. This is a bug-fix release, fixing exit screen handling and a possible segfault on imap-logout-all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mutt 1.13.2 was released on December 18, 2019. This is a bug-fix release, reverting an incorrect cleanup change to mutt_dotlock made in 1.13.0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mutt 1.13.1 was released on December 14, 2019. This is a bug-fix release, fixing two crash bugs involving IMAP and the postpone menu. It also reverts by default the 1.13.0 sidebar display changes. See the &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/muttmua/mutt/raw/stable/UPDATING&quot;&gt;UPDATING&lt;/a&gt; file for more details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mutt 1.13.0 was released on November 30, 2019. This release has new features and bug fixes. See the &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/muttmua/mutt/raw/stable/UPDATING&quot;&gt;UPDATING&lt;/a&gt; file, or for more details see the &lt;a href=&quot;http://mutt.org/relnotes/1.13/&quot;&gt;release notes&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mutt 1.12.2 was released on September 21, 2019. This is a bug-fix release, fixing file monitor compilation on older systems, and application/pgp-encrypted attachment handling for sent emails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mutt 1.12.1 was released on June 15, 2019. This is a bug-fix release, fixing issues with $forward_attachments, IMAP new mail detection, IMAP fcc'ing, and a build issue on OpenBSD. Additionally $fcc_before_send was added. See the &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/muttmua/mutt/raw/stable/UPDATING&quot;&gt;UPDATING&lt;/a&gt; file for more details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mutt 1.12.0 was released on May 25, 2019. This release has new features and bug fixes. See the &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/muttmua/mutt/raw/stable/UPDATING&quot;&gt;UPDATING&lt;/a&gt; file, or for more details see the &lt;a href=&quot;http://mutt.org/relnotes/1.12/&quot;&gt;release notes&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mutt 1.11.4 was released on March 13, 2019. This is a bug-fix release, fixing a Gmail $trash bug that could end up deleting incorrect messages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mutt 1.11.3 was released on February 1, 2019. This is a bug-fix release, fixing compilation with LibreSSL and various other bug fixes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mutt 1.11.2 was released on January 7, 2019. This is a bug-fix release, fixing compilation with the latest OpenSSL version and various other bug fixes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mutt 1.11.1 was released on December 1, 2018 (the &quot;A Chorus Line&quot; release). This is a bug-fix release, fixing a crash in the new $imap_qresync code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mutt 1.11.0 was released on November 25, 2018. This release has new features and bug fixes. See the &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/muttmua/mutt/raw/stable/UPDATING&quot;&gt;UPDATING&lt;/a&gt; file, or for more details see the &lt;a href=&quot;http://mutt.org/relnotes/1.11/&quot;&gt;release notes&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mutt 1.10.1 was released on July 16, 2018. This is an important bug-fix release, fixing a code injection and a couple path traversal vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mutt 1.10.0 was released on May 19, 2018. This release has new features and bug fixes. See the &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/muttmua/mutt/raw/stable/UPDATING&quot;&gt;UPDATING&lt;/a&gt; file, or for more details see the &lt;a href=&quot;http://mutt.org/relnotes/1.10/&quot;&gt;release notes&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mutt.org/news.html&quot;&gt;more news&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 00:24:25 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>job</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://mutt.org/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Arm co-founder: Sale to Nvidia would be a disaster</title>
<link>https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-53637463</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-53637463</guid>
<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape has-caption full-width lead&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                &lt;img class=&quot;js-image-replace&quot; alt=&quot;ARM logo on phone&quot; src=&quot;https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/320/cpsprodpb/8F83/production/_113793763_arm.jpg&quot; width=&quot;976&quot; height=&quot;549&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    The smartphone industry is built on the foundations of ARM's technology
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body__introduction&quot;&gt;The co-founder of the company described as the jewel in the crown of British tech has said it would be disastrous for it to be sold to a US computing firm that is reportedly negotiating a takeover.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's the second time in four years that the future of Cambridge-based chip-designer ARM Holdings has been uncertain.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2016, Softbank ended up buying it. But the Japanese firm is now reportedly in advanced talks to sell it to Nvidia.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hermann Hauser told the BBC he thought the UK government should intervene.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The tech entrepreneur - who spun off ARM from Acorn Computers in 1990 - says ministers should help make it an independent UK business again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;'Unsuitable owner'&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;ARM creates computer chip designs that others then customise to their own ends. It also develops instruction sets, which define how software controls processors.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just about every modern mobile phone and smart home gadget is powered by a chip that relies on one or both of these innovations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When Softbank bought the firm for £24bn soon after the referendum to leave the EU in 2016, it was hailed by the government as a vote of confidence in a post-Brexit Britain.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But Dr Hauser said at the time it was a sad day for him and for UK technology.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape has-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    Dr Hauser was given an honorary knighthood in 2016 for his services to UK industry and engineering
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Four years on, after a number of big bets went wrong for the Japanese firm - notably its investment in the shared office space business WeWork - SoftBank wants to dispose of ARM, either returning it to the stock market through a share sale or letting another organisation buy it outright.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In recent days, there have been a number of reports that Nvidia - which recently overtook Intel to become the world's most valuable chip-maker - is keen to buy it. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The last weekend in July, I contacted Dr Hauser who spends the UK's winters in New Zealand and remained there because of the coronavirus pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He told me that a sale of ARM to Nvidia would be a disaster, but thought it very unlikely to happen. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This past weekend he got back in touch to say the reports now looked very credible and his concern had deepened.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He explained that ARM's business model - in which all the big chip-makers license its technologies - made Nvidia an unsuitable owner.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;It's one of the fundamental assumptions of the ARM business model that it can sell to everybody,&quot; he explained.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;The one saving grace about Softbank was that it wasn't a chip company, and retained ARM's neutrality. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;If it becomes part of Nvidia, most of the licensees are competitors of Nvidia, and will of course then look for an alternative to ARM.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While Dr Hauser voted against the Softbank deal in 2016, he says the Japanese firm kept its promises to retain Cambridge as the main focus of ARM's research and to boost employment there. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He has little faith in that remaining the case if Nvidia takes over.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape has-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
                 &lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;Reuters&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    Acquiring ARM would be a major coup for Nvidia's chief executive Jensen Huang
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;It will become one of the Nvidia divisions, and all the decisions will be made in America, no longer in Cambridge.&quot; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But the Austrian-born venture capitalist hopes that can still be avoided.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;The great opportunity that the cash needs of Softbank presents is to bring ARM back home and take it public, with the support of the British government,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;'Not about the money'&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dr Hauser added that he would like to see it listed on both the London and New York Stock Exchanges.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He acknowledged that an already financially stretched government could not be expected to provide cash for the deal, but could still encourage it to happen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;It's not about the money, it's the industrial strategy statements that the government can make,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dr Hauser thinks the government's recent move to invest $500m (£378m) in the satellite firm OneWeb may be a sign that it is prepared to intervene when the UK's technology future is at stake. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And he thinks the UK's wider microprocessor sector should be championed, pointing to the success of Bristol-based Graphcore in designing AI chips.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;[OneWeb was] a strong statement that the government is actually serious about industrial strategy,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;And if ever there was a big strategic prize to be had, it would be to take the crown away from Intel as the number one microprocessor company in the world and make it part of the UK&quot;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Both Softbank and Nvidia declined to comment.&lt;/p&gt;
            </description>
<pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 23:59:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mepian</dc:creator>
<og:title>ARM founder says sale to US would be a disaster</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Hermann Hauser wants the UK government to intervene to stop Nvidia buying the chip designer.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-53637463</og:url>
<og:image>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/8F83/production/_113793763_arm.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-53637463</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Oh Shit, Git?</title>
<link>https://ohshitgit.com/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://ohshitgit.com/</guid>
<description>&lt;header class=&quot;spaced&quot;&gt;
&lt;/header&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;intro&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;&lt;aside class=&quot;ads&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Git is hard: screwing up is easy, and figuring out how to fix your mistakes is fucking impossible. Git documentation has this chicken and egg problem where you can't search for how to get yourself out of a mess, &lt;em&gt;unless you already know the name of the thing you need to know about&lt;/em&gt; in order to fix your problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here are some bad situations I've gotten myself into, and how I eventually got myself out of them &lt;em&gt;in plain english&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;spaced&quot; readability=&quot;11.148936170213&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-git&quot;&gt;git reflog
# you will see a list of every thing you've 
# done in git, across all branches!
# each one has an index HEAD@{index}
# find the one before you broke everything
git reset HEAD@{index}
# magic time machine
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use this to get back stuff you accidentally deleted, or just to remove some stuff you tried that broke the repo, or to recover after a bad merge, or just to go back to a time when things actually worked. I use &lt;code&gt;reflog&lt;/code&gt; A LOT. Mega hat tip to the many many many many many people who suggested adding it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;spaced&quot; readability=&quot;11.534682080925&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-git&quot;&gt;# make your change
git add . # or add individual files
git commit --amend --no-edit
# now your last commit contains that change!
# WARNING: never amend public commits
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This usually happens to me if I commit, then run tests/linters... and FML, I didn't put a space after an equals sign. You could also make the change as a new commit and then do &lt;code&gt;rebase -i&lt;/code&gt; in order to squash them both together, but this is about a million times faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Warning: You should never amend commits that have been pushed up to a public/shared branch! Only amend commits that only exist in your local copy or you're gonna have a bad time.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;spaced&quot; readability=&quot;2.6666666666667&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-git&quot;&gt;git commit --amend
# follow prompts to change the commit message
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stupid commit message formatting requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;spaced&quot; readability=&quot;10.234234234234&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-git&quot;&gt;# create a new branch from the current state of master
git branch some-new-branch-name
# remove the last commit from the master branch
git reset HEAD~ --hard
git checkout some-new-branch-name
# your commit lives in this branch now :)
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: this doesn't work if you've already pushed the commit to a public/shared branch, and if you tried other things first, you might need to &lt;code&gt;git reset HEAD@{number-of-commits-back}&lt;/code&gt; instead of &lt;code&gt;HEAD~&lt;/code&gt;. Infinite sadness. Also, many many many people suggested an awesome way to make this shorter that I didn't know myself. Thank you all!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;spaced&quot; readability=&quot;10.989079563183&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-git&quot;&gt;# undo the last commit, but leave the changes available
git reset HEAD~ --soft
git stash
# move to the correct branch
git checkout name-of-the-correct-branch
git stash pop
git add . # or add individual files
git commit -m &quot;your message here&quot;;
# now your changes are on the correct branch
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of people have suggested using &lt;code&gt;cherry-pick&lt;/code&gt; for this situation too, so take your pick on whatever one makes the most sense to you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-git&quot;&gt;git checkout name-of-the-correct-branch
# grab the last commit to master
git cherry-pick master
# delete it from master
git checkout master
git reset HEAD~ --hard
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;spaced&quot; readability=&quot;9.3669467787115&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you know that you made changes to files, but &lt;code&gt;diff&lt;/code&gt; is empty, you probably &lt;code&gt;add&lt;/code&gt;-ed your files to staging and you need to use a special flag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-git&quot;&gt;git diff --staged
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;File under ¯\_(ツ)_/¯ (yes, I know this is a feature, not a bug, but it's fucking baffling and non-obvious the first time it happens to you!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;spaced&quot; readability=&quot;12.861626248217&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-git&quot;&gt;# find the commit you need to undo
git log
# use the arrow keys to scroll up and down in history
# once you've found your commit, save the hash
git revert [saved hash]
# git will create a new commit that undoes that commit
# follow prompts to edit the commit message 
# or just save and commit
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turns out you don't have to track down and copy-paste the old file contents into the existing file in order to undo changes! If you committed a bug, you can undo the commit all in one go with &lt;code&gt;revert&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also revert a single file instead of a full commit! But of course, in true git fashion, it's a completely different set of fucking commands...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;spaced&quot; readability=&quot;10.112903225806&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-git&quot;&gt;# find a hash for a commit before the file was changed
git log
# use the arrow keys to scroll up and down in history
# once you've found your commit, save the hash
git checkout [saved hash] -- path/to/file
# the old version of the file will be in your index
git commit -m &quot;Wow, you don't have to copy-paste to undo&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I finally figured this out it was HUGE. HUGE. H-U-G-E. But seriously though, on what fucking planet does &lt;code&gt;checkout --&lt;/code&gt; make sense as the best way to undo a file? :shakes-fist-at-linus-torvalds:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;spaced&quot; readability=&quot;16.337662337662&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-git&quot;&gt;cd ..
sudo rm -r fucking-git-repo-dir
git clone https://some.github.url/fucking-git-repo-dir.git
cd fucking-git-repo-dir
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Eric V. for this one. All complaints about the use of &lt;code&gt;sudo&lt;/code&gt; in this joke can be directed to him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For real though, if your branch is sooo borked that you need to reset the state of your repo to be the same as the remote repo in a &quot;git-approved&quot; way, try this, but beware these are destructive and unrecoverable actions!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-git&quot;&gt;# get the lastest state of origin
git fetch origin
git checkout master
git reset --hard origin/master
# delete untracked files and directories
git clean -d --force
# repeat checkout/reset/clean for each borked branch
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;spaced&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;*Disclaimer: This site is not intended to be an exhaustive reference. And yes, there are other ways to do these same things with more theoretical purity or whatever, but I've come to these steps through trial and error and lots of swearing and table flipping, and I had this crazy idea to share them with a healthy dose of levity and profanity. Take it or leave it as you will!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;spaced top-lined&quot; readability=&quot;4.6415094339623&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many thanks to everyone who has volunteered to translate the site into new languages, you rock! &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pReya&quot;&gt;Moritz Stückler&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://ohshitgit.com/de&quot;&gt;de&lt;/a&gt;) · &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dadyarri&quot;&gt;Daniil Golubev&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://ohshitgit.com/ru&quot;&gt;ru&lt;/a&gt;) · &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lwojcik&quot;&gt;Łukasz Wójcik&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://ohshitgit.com/pl&quot;&gt;pl&lt;/a&gt;) · &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/fedemcmac&quot;&gt;fedemcmac&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://ohshitgit.com/it&quot;&gt;it&lt;/a&gt;) · &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/michelc&quot;&gt;Michel&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://ohshitgit.com/fr&quot;&gt;fr&lt;/a&gt;) · &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/LastGenius-edu&quot;&gt;Andriy Sultanov&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://ohshitgit.com/ua&quot;&gt;ua&lt;/a&gt;) · &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/meih&quot;&gt;Meiko Hori&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://ohshitgit.com/ja&quot;&gt;ja&lt;/a&gt;) · &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Tzal3x&quot;&gt;Alex Tzimas&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://ohshitgit.com/gr&quot;&gt;gr&lt;/a&gt;) · &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/MartijntenHeuvel&quot;&gt;Martijn ten Heuvel&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://ohshitgit.com/nl&quot;&gt;nl&lt;/a&gt;) · &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/eladleev&quot;&gt;Elad Leev&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://ohshitgit.com/he&quot;&gt;he&lt;/a&gt;) · &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/francofantini&quot;&gt;Franco Fantini&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://ohshitgit.com/es&quot;&gt;es&lt;/a&gt;) · &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/catalinafox&quot;&gt;Catalina Focsa&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://ohshitgit.com/ro&quot;&gt;ro&lt;/a&gt;) · &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/davialexandre&quot;&gt;Davi Alexandre&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://ohshitgit.com/pt_BR&quot;&gt;pt_BR&lt;/a&gt;) · &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/GoodbyePlanet&quot;&gt;Nemanja Vasić&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://ohshitgit.com/sr&quot;&gt;sr&lt;/a&gt;) · &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/taojy123&quot;&gt;Tao Jiayuan&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://ohshitgit.com/zh&quot;&gt;zh&lt;/a&gt;) · &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/edee111&quot;&gt;Eduard Tomek&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://ohshitgit.com/cs&quot;&gt;cs&lt;/a&gt;) · &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/quellcrist-falconer&quot;&gt;Ricky Gultom&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://ohshitgit.com/id&quot;&gt;id&lt;/a&gt;) . With additional help from &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/imurray&quot;&gt;Iain Murray&lt;/a&gt; · &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/DirtyF&quot;&gt;Frank Taillandier&lt;/a&gt; · &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/davidfyffe&quot;&gt;David Fyffe&lt;/a&gt; · &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/LucasLarson&quot;&gt;Lucas Larson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you'd like to help add a translation into your language, submit a PR on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ksylor/ohshitgit&quot; class=&quot;no-wrap&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 23:11:50 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>auraham</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://ohshitgit.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>