<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Tesla Roadster</title>
<link>https://www.tesla.com/roadster/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.tesla.com/roadster/</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tesla.com/roadster/&quot;&gt;https://www.tesla.com/roadster/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=15719262&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=15719262&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Points: 274&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 171&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 05:38:52 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>franl</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.tesla.com/</og:url>
<og:title>Roadster | Tesla</og:title>
<og:image>https://www.tesla.com/sites/default/files/images/software_update.jpg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.tesla.com/roadster/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Tesla Semi</title>
<link>https://www.tesla.com/semi/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.tesla.com/semi/</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tesla.com/semi/&quot;&gt;https://www.tesla.com/semi/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=15718686&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=15718686&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Points: 223&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 202&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 03:35:16 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>runesoerensen</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.tesla.com/</og:url>
<og:title>Semi | Tesla</og:title>
<og:image>https://www.tesla.com/sites/default/files/images/software_update.jpg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.tesla.com/semi/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Introduction to Computer Organization: ARM Assembly Language on the Raspberry Pi</title>
<link>http://bob.cs.sonoma.edu/IntroCompOrg-RPi/intro-co-rpi.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://bob.cs.sonoma.edu/IntroCompOrg-RPi/intro-co-rpi.html</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;Content-Type&quot; content=&quot;text/html; charset=utf-8&quot;/&gt;&lt;title&gt;Introduction to Computer Organization&lt;/title&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;Keywords&quot; content=&quot;Authored in PreTeXt&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;viewport&quot; content=&quot;width=device-width, initial-scale=1.0, user-scalable=0, minimum-scale=1.0, maximum-scale=1.0&quot;/&gt;&lt;link href=&quot;https://aimath.org/knowlstyle.css&quot; rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot;/&gt;&lt;link href=&quot;https://fonts.googleapis.com/css?family=Open+Sans:400,400italic,600,600italic&quot; rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot;/&gt;&lt;link href=&quot;https://fonts.googleapis.com/css?family=Inconsolata:400,700&amp;amp;subset=latin,latin-ext&quot; rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot;/&gt;&lt;link href=&quot;https://aimath.org/mathbook/stylesheets/mathbook-3.css&quot; rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot;/&gt;&lt;link href=&quot;https://aimath.org/mathbook/mathbook-add-on.css&quot; rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot;/&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body class=&quot;mathbook-book has-toc has-sidebar-left&quot; id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;1.1796116504854&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;assistive&quot; href=&quot;http://bob.cs.sonoma.edu/IntroCompOrg-RPi/intro-co-rpi.html#content&quot;&gt;Skip to main content&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(\newcommand{\doubler}[1]{2#1} \newcommand{\binary}{\mathtt} \newcommand{\hex}{\mathtt} \newcommand{\octal}{\mathtt} \newcommand{\prog}{\mathtt} \newcommand{\lt}{&amp;lt;} \newcommand{\gt}{&amp;gt;} \newcommand{\amp}{&amp;amp;} \)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;header id=&quot;masthead&quot; class=&quot;smallbuttons&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;banner&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;container&quot;&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;logo-link&quot; href=&quot;http://bob.cs.sonoma.edu&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://bob.cs.sonoma.edu/IntroCompOrg-RPi/images/me_at_it.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Logo image for document&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;title-container&quot;&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;byline&quot;&gt;Robert G. Plantz&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;nav id=&quot;primary-navbar&quot; class=&quot;navbar&quot;&gt;
&lt;/nav&gt;&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 21:49:31 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ingve</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://bob.cs.sonoma.edu/IntroCompOrg-RPi/intro-co-rpi.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The FCC has repealed a 42-year-old rule blocking broadcast media mergers</title>
<link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/the-switch/wp/2017/11/16/the-fcc-just-repealed-decades-old-rules-blocking-broadcast-media-mergers/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/the-switch/wp/2017/11/16/the-fcc-just-repealed-decades-old-rules-blocking-broadcast-media-mergers/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;inline-content inline-photo inline-photo-normal&quot;&gt; &lt;img class=&quot;unprocessed placeholder&quot; data-hi-res-src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php?src=https://img.washingtonpost.com/blogs/the-switch/files/2017/01/215206582.jpg&amp;amp;w=1484&quot; data-low-res-src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php?src=https://img.washingtonpost.com/blogs/the-switch/files/2017/01/215206582.jpg&amp;amp;w=480&quot; data-raw-src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/blogs/the-switch/files/2017/01/215206582.jpg&quot; src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php?src=https://img.washingtonpost.com/blogs/the-switch/files/2017/01/215206582.jpg&amp;amp;w=60&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pb-caption&quot;&gt;Federal Communications Commission Chairman Ajit Pai. (Andrew Harrer/Bloomberg News)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Federal regulators rolled back decades-old rules on Thursday, making it far easier for media outlets to be bought and sold — potentially leading to more newspapers, radio stations and television broadcasters being owned by a handful of companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The regulations, eliminated in a 3-to-2 vote by the Federal Communications Commission, were first put in place in the 1970s to ensure that a diversity of voices and opinions could be heard on the air or in print. But now &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fcc.gov/consumers/guides/fccs-review-broadcast-ownership-rules&quot;&gt;those rules&lt;/a&gt; represent a threat to small outlets that are struggling to survive in a vastly different media world, according to FCC Chairman Ajit Pai. With the rise of blogs, websites and podcasts, Pai said, traditional media outlets now face more competition than ever — and rules that once enforced a diversity of viewpoints are no longer needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Few of the FCC's rules are staler than our broadcast ownership regulations,” Pai said. By eliminating them, he said, “this agency finally drags its broadcast ownership rules to the digital age.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One long-standing rule repealed Thursday prevented one company in a given media market from owning both a daily newspaper and a TV station. Another rule blocked TV stations in the same market from merging with each other if the combination would leave fewer than eight independently owned stations. The agency also took aim at rules restricting the number of TV and radio stations that any media company could simultaneously own in a single market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A major beneficiary of the deregulatory moves, analysts say, is Sinclair, a conservative broadcasting company that is seeking to buy up Tribune Media for $3.9 billion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This has a huge impact,” said Andrew Schwartzman, an expert on media law at Georgetown University. He added that the decisions will “reduce or eliminate” the need for Sinclair to sell off many stations to receive regulatory approval for the deal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The FCC vote is the latest to ease regulations for the broadcast industry. It came the same day that the agency was expected to approve the deployment of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/the-switch/wp/2017/11/14/tv-stations-are-about-to-track-you-and-sell-targeted-ads-just-like-google-and-facebook/&quot;&gt;Next Gen TV&lt;/a&gt;, a new broadcast standard that is ultimately expected to lead to improved audio and video quality on over-the-air television, as well as targeted advertising. And it came one month after &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/the-switch/wp/2017/10/24/the-fcc-just-ended-a-decades-old-rule-designed-to-keep-tv-and-radio-under-local-control/?tid=a_inl&amp;amp;utm_term=.a69e81375ba3&quot;&gt;the FCC voted&lt;/a&gt; to no longer require broadcasters to operate a physical studio in the markets where they are licensed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The National Association of Broadcasters welcomed Thursday's vote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“These rules are not only irrational in today’s media environment, but they have also weakened the newspaper industry, cost journalism jobs and forced local broadcast stations onto unequal footing with our national pay-TV and radio competitors,” the trade group said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Critics of the FCC repeal effort say that the decision will lead to the concentration of power in the hands of a dwindling number of media titans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Instead of engaging in thoughtful reform,” said Democratic FCC Commissioner Jessica Rosenworcel, “this agency sets its most basic values on fire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“As a result of this decision, wherever you live, the FCC is giving the green light for a single company to own the newspaper and multiple television and radio stations in your community. I am hard pressed to see any commitment to diversity, localism, or competition in that result.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senate Democrats this week called on the FCC's inspector general to launch a probe of the agency, over concerns that its impartiality with respect to Sinclair had been “tainted.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This merger would never have been possible without a series of actions to overturn decades-long, settled legal precedent by Chairman Pai,” Sen. Maria Cantwell (D-Wash.) and 14 other lawmakers wrote &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cantwell.senate.gov/imo/media/doc/11152017%20Letter%20to%20Inspector%20General.pdf&quot;&gt;in a letter&lt;/a&gt;. The letter added that Pai has “signaled his clear receptiveness to approving the Sinclair-Tribune transaction and in fact paved the way for its consummation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The FCC didn't immediately respond to a request for comment. Sinclair declined to comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his remarks Thursday, Pai said it was “utter nonsense” that his agency's decisions on media ownership would lead to a company dominating local media markets by buying up newspapers and radio stations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It will open the door to pro-competitive combinations that will strengthen local voices,” he said, and “better serve local communities.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;inline-content inline-video&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;inline-video-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pb-caption&quot;&gt;President Trump has suggested that negative stories could result in a TV network's broadcast license being taken away. He's not the first president to do this. (Victoria Walker/The Washington Post)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 21:16:28 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>uptown</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/the-switch/wp/2017/11/16/the-fcc-just-repealed-decades-old-rules-blocking-broadcast-media-mergers/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.washingtonpost.com/rf/image_1484w/2010-2019/Wires/Images/2017-05-05/Getty/679316088.jpg?t=20170517</og:image>
<og:title>The FCC just repealed a 42-year-old rule blocking broadcast media mergers</og:title>
<og:description>The move paves the way for greater consolidation in the TV and radio industries.</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/the-switch/wp/2017/11/16/the-fcc-just-repealed-decades-old-rules-blocking-broadcast-media-mergers/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Security alerts on GitHub</title>
<link>https://github.com/blog/2470-introducing-security-alerts-on-github</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/blog/2470-introducing-security-alerts-on-github</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Last month, we made it easier for you to keep track of the projects your code depends on with the dependency graph, currently supported in Javascript and Ruby. Today, for the over 75 percent of GitHub projects that have dependencies, we’re helping you do more than see those important projects. With your dependency graph enabled, we’ll now notify you when we detect a vulnerability in one of your dependencies and suggest known fixes from the GitHub community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/594029/32851987-76c36e4a-c9eb-11e7-98fc-feb39fddaadb.gif&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/594029/32851987-76c36e4a-c9eb-11e7-98fc-feb39fddaadb.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Security Alerts &amp;amp; Suggested Fix&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How to start using security alerts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether your projects are private or public, security alerts get vital vulnerability information to the right people on your team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enable your dependency graph&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Public repositories will automatically have your dependency graph and security alerts enabled. For private repositories, you’ll need to opt in to security alerts in your repository settings or by allowing access in the Dependency graph section of your repository’s Insights tab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Set notification preferences&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When your dependency graph is enabled, admins will receive security alerts by default. Admins can also add teams or individuals as recipients for security alerts in the dependency graph settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Respond to alerts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we notify you about a potential vulnerability, we’ll highlight any dependencies that we recommend updating. If a known safe version exists, we’ll select one using machine learning and publicly available data, and include it in our suggestion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Vulnerability coverage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vulnerabilities that have &lt;a href=&quot;https://cve.mitre.org/&quot;&gt;CVE IDs&lt;/a&gt; (publicly disclosed vulnerabilities from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://nvd.nist.gov/&quot;&gt;National Vulnerability Database&lt;/a&gt;) will be included in security alerts. However, not all vulnerabilities have CVE IDs—even many publicly disclosed vulnerabilities don't have them. We'll continue to get better at identifying vulnerabilities as our security data grows. For more help managing security issues, check out our &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/marketplace/category/security&quot;&gt;security partners in the GitHub Marketplace&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the next step in using the world’s largest collection of open source data to help you keep code safer and do your best work. The dependency graph and security alerts currently support Javascript and Ruby—with Python support coming in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://help.github.com/articles/about-security-alerts-for-vulnerable-dependencies/&quot;&gt;Learn more about security alerts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 18:05:45 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>stablemap</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/24463350/32863389-32ab14d6-ca10-11e7-9bea-e5035cd8a06e.png</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Introducing security alerts on GitHub</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/blog/2470-introducing-security-alerts-on-github</og:url>
<og:description>Last month, we made it easier for you to keep track of the projects your code depends on with the dependency graph, currently supported in Javascript and Ruby. Today, for the over 75 percent of Git...</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/blog/2470-introducing-security-alerts-on-github</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Startup Ideas</title>
<link>http://blog.ycombinator.com/13-startup-ideas/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://blog.ycombinator.com/13-startup-ideas/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Hey, my name is Kyle Corbitt and I’m a software developer at Y Combinator. I spend most of my time creating software to support our founders as they build their businesses. Before joining YC I ran my own startup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was in high school, I sometimes got the frustrating feeling that all of the good startup ideas had been taken before I had a chance to work on them myself. As I’ve gotten a bit older and gained more experience, I’ve found that valuable startup ideas aren’t actually a scarce resource. In fact, they’re only becoming more abundant — as the world moves faster and more new businesses are created, more novel niches appear for profitable, productive companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that in mind, we asked YC alumni and staff for startup ideas that they wish existed but aren’t currently working on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interested in pursuing one of these ideas? Please get in touch at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:kyle@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;kyle@ycombinator.com&lt;/a&gt; — I’d love to chat about your plans, and I may be able to put you in touch with the idea’s author or other good resources. Also, if you have your own great idea that you’d like to see in a future version of this list, let me know! If we see community interest we’re thinking about creating a larger repository for ideas like these.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AI for Communicating with Dogs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Use the immense amount of video footage captures of interactions with dogs to predict what behaviors will happen based on what the dog is doing i.e. predict that your dog is in pain, or hungry or thirsty etc. (Note: this might sound a little crazy but this has been done already for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencemag.org/news/2017/06/artificial-intelligence-learns-spot-pain-sheep&quot;&gt;identifying pain in sheep&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Elizabeth Iorns, Science Exchange S11&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smart Bathroom&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Healthcare in the U.S. is a $3.2 trillion industry. Individuals take care of most of their health needs in the bathroom (bms, urine, teeth, hygiene, et cetera). All this data is literally flushed down the drain. Big opportunity to install a virtual doctor’s office in everyone’s bathroom, collecting data and providing feedback to help people reduce cost on health and wellness while achieving much better outcomes. New types of sensors and great data analysis and UX is needed to make the smart bathrooms a reality.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Breck Yunits, NudgePad S09&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accounts Receivables as a Service&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;It can be a huge pain to get enterprises to pay their vendors, even after contracts are signed. It’s one of those business inefficiencies that they’re not inclined to fix because there’s little downside to them paying late. Handing it off to a “collections agency” seems aggressive and most startups won’t do it, but I think something like an outsourced AR service that appears to be from the company but is actually a third party could be great. Potentially a mix of $/mo+% of revenue or $/mo depending at different tiers depending on how many transactions.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yuri Sagalov, AeroFS S10/Y Combinator&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Baby Bidet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;A semi-automatic baby bidet where you could sit them over the sink and clean out the yuck simply and without having to touch it. Could work well as a kickstarter.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jeffrey Engler, Wright Electric W17&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Securitized Assets on the Blockchain&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I would be working on making it easier to securitize and create a market for unique assets on the blockchain. There are many types of new securities and types of assets being created, not only tokens but anything else that can be bought or sold. In theory you could sell those on the blockchain currently, but you’d have to spin up and create your own blockchain in its entirety. It seems like that’s something you should be able to do as a service; I have some asset and I’d like a blockchain for it, and I’ll pay a monthly fee. I’d build that if I had time.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Austen Allred, Lambda School S17&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Renewable Energy from Engineered Microbes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Microbes are outstandingly powerful and have the potential to be engineered to do almost anything. If I had more time, I would love to look more into the idea of engineering a bacteria that could efficiently convert a renewable resource into a usable fuel. Obviously, many microbes already exist that can do this, and so I would like to do more research into why this is not an option in common practice yet, and what strategies could be developed to make it possible here and now. Is the problem that the fuels they are making are incompatible with our current infrastructure (e.g. the microbes make ethanol, and most cars run on gas)? Or is the problem that bugs that can make usable fuel do so inefficiently, and thus need to be engineered to produce sufficient quantities in a cost-effective manner and/or on a reasonable time scale? In short, what problem(s) need to be solved to utilize microbes as fuel sources?&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Zack Abbott, Z-Biotics Fellowship&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adwords for Outdoor and Transit Advertising&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Billboards are still sold manually by sales teams. You literally cannot buy a billboard online. If people could buy them as easily as you buy an Adwords ad, maybe many more small companies would.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jared Friedman, Scribd S06/Y Combinator&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Design on Demand&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Upload a photo of furniture of a piece of home decor, and select between “find” or “match” options. The “find” option would bring up very similar options and let you sort by price point and delivery time, so you could find the Crate and Barrel knock off of that designer table you saw in a magazine. The “match” option would recommends items that go well stylistically with that item. All of that instantly delivered through an app or website.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kathryn Minshew, The Muse W12&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Low-Friction Lending Library&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Most people end up accumulating dozens or hundreds of items that they only need a few times a year. In my case these are things like camping equipment, a soldering iron, an electric drill, paper cutter, etc. — but everybody has their own unique list. I’d much rather not have to keep track of all this infrequently-used inventory and instead rent it on demand, especially since I have limited storage space. Lending libraries for this type of stuff exist but are too high-friction to be popular today — it’s substantially easier to just buy something on Amazon than rent it from a local depot. I think with automated inventory management and (potentially) sidewalk delivery bots the cost and friction can be brought low enough to turn this into a popular and defensible subscription business.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kyle Corbitt, Y Combinator&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make Technology Relatable and Accessible&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Technology is advancing at a rapid pace and it can be overwhelming and scary for people that don’t understand the underlying principles or have a safe place to ask questions and be taught. Think about how frustrated you get trying to explain to your grandfather why Facebook isn’t working when the Wi-Fi isn’t connected and what wi-fi is or browsers are. This is most pronounced with seniors but applies also to lots of people that don’t work in tech. It is only getting worse with topics like AI and cryptocurrency. Build a service that makes technology accessible and not scary for older or non tech savvy people. We need a text/call and software based solution with really great people on the other end who don’t judge, but explain concepts simply — someone who will help and doesn’t make anyone feel dumb. Ultimately the goal would be to make people of all types more technologically conversant while build ing a membership and/or e-commerce business model.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Avni Patel Thompson, Poppy W16&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buyer’s Remorse Insurance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Money back guarantee for art buyers: Buying fine art has a steep learning curve. Firstly, galleries are very uninviting. Then, when you get inside, the sales process is super unclear. A final barrier is that art is very arbitrarily priced, and as a new buyer it’s hard to know if you will get buyer’s remorse and feel like you overpaid for something. To overcome this, offer insurance that galleries can offer to buy art back from the purchaser if the purchaser is unsatisfied. Lowered risk for buyers =&amp;gt; Increased spend, and you take some of that increased revenue.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Justin Kan, Justin.TV/Twitch W07&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Social Network for Children&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This is a super tough nut to crack. You have to be cool and offer a safe and private environment for kids to communicate with each other while enabling trusted adults to peer in/interact, etc… The company that can build something that is used and useful for all parties can build something of great value throughout a person’s entire life.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Holly Liu, Kabam/Y Combinator&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Modern Firefighting&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Climate change is already having real consequences on our society, and this year has been one of the worst years for wildfire in history, leaving entire neighborhoods flattened. Fire fighting and the tools we use to fight fires haven’t changed much in 100 years. Sprinklers were a big innovation for homes, but forest fires are often spotted and fought in the same way we did many decades ago. With the arrival of autonomous drones, industrial drones, better sensors and better prediction we should be able do a better job saving our forests, cities and firefighters.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gustaf Alstromer, Y Combinator&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 17:03:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kcorbitt</dc:creator>
<og:image>http://blog.ycombinator.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/13-Startup-Ideas.png</og:image>
<og:title>13 Startup Ideas</og:title>
<og:url>http://blog.ycombinator.com/13-startup-ideas/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Startup ideas aren’t actually a scarce resource. In fact, they’re only becoming more abundant -- as the world moves faster and more new businesses are created, more novel niches appear for profitable, productive companies. With that in mind, we asked YC alumni and staff for startup ideas that they w</og:description>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://blog.ycombinator.com/13-startup-ideas/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Apology after Japanese train departs 20 seconds early</title>
<link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/amp/world-asia-42009839</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/amp/world-asia-42009839</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;gel-layout__item gel-1/1&quot; readability=&quot;40.782847718527&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;article-image__copyright&quot;&gt;AFP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;Japan has one of the world's most reliable railways&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;amp-o-paragraph--bold&quot;&gt;A rail company in Japan has apologised after one of its trains departed 20 seconds early.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;amp-o-paragraph&quot;&gt;Management on the Tsukuba Express line between Tokyo and the city of Tsukuba say they &quot;sincerely apologise for the inconvenience&quot; caused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;amp-o-paragraph&quot;&gt;In a statement, &lt;a class=&quot;amp-o-link&quot; href=&quot;http://www.mir.co.jp/company/release/2017/post_109.html&quot;&gt;the company said the train had been scheduled to leave at 9:44:40 local time but left at 9:44:20.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;amp-o-paragraph&quot;&gt;Many social media users reacted to the company's apology with surprise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;amp-o-social-embed&quot;&gt;
&lt;div fallback=&quot;&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;amp-o-social-embed--unavailable&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;amp-o-social-embed--unavailable-message&quot;&gt;Sorry, this Twitter post is currently unavailable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;amp-o-social-embed&quot;&gt;
&lt;div fallback=&quot;&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;amp-o-social-embed--unavailable&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;amp-o-social-embed--unavailable-message&quot;&gt;Sorry, this Twitter post is currently unavailable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;amp-o-paragraph&quot;&gt;The mistake happened because staff had not checked the timetable, the company statement said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;amp-o-paragraph&quot;&gt;&quot;The crew did not sufficiently check the departure time and performed the departure operation,&quot; it said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;amp-o-paragraph&quot;&gt;It added that no customers had complained about the early departure from Minami Nagareyama Station, which is just north of Tokyo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;amp-o-paragraph&quot;&gt;The Tsukuba Express line takes passengers from Akihabara in eastern Tokyo to Tsukuba in about 45 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;amp-o-paragraph&quot;&gt;It is rare for trains in Japan, which has one of the world's most reliable railways, to depart at a different time to the one scheduled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;amp-o-paragraph&quot;&gt;The country's Tokaido line, which runs from Tokyo to the city of Kobe, is by far the world's busiest and carries nearly 150 million passengers a year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;amp-o-paragraph&quot;&gt;Impressed railway users worldwide tweeted the story to their local train operators - particularly in Britain, where rail services are often delayed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;amp-o-social-embed&quot;&gt;
&lt;div fallback=&quot;&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;amp-o-social-embed--unavailable&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;amp-o-social-embed--unavailable-message&quot;&gt;Sorry, this Twitter post is currently unavailable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;amp-o-social-embed&quot;&gt;
&lt;div fallback=&quot;&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;amp-o-social-embed--unavailable&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;amp-o-social-embed--unavailable-message&quot;&gt;Sorry, this Twitter post is currently unavailable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;amp-o-social-embed&quot;&gt;
&lt;div fallback=&quot;&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;amp-o-social-embed--unavailable&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;amp-o-social-embed--unavailable-message&quot;&gt;Sorry, this Twitter post is currently unavailable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;related-articles&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;related-articles__title&quot;&gt;More on this story&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;related-articles__article&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gel-layout&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gel-layout__item gel-6/10&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;related-articles__article-title&quot;&gt;India launches first bullet train project&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;related-articles__article-timestamp&quot;&gt;14 September 2017&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;related-articles__article&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gel-layout&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gel-layout__item gel-6/10&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;related-articles__article-title&quot;&gt;Japan etiquette video discourages applying make-up on trains&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;related-articles__article-timestamp&quot;&gt;28 October 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;amp-o-hr&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 16:11:59 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>gridscomputing</dc:creator>
<og:title>Apology after Japanese train departs 20 seconds early</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-42009839</og:url>
<og:description>Management on the Tsukuba Express line &quot;sincerely apologised for the inconvenience&quot; caused.</og:description>
<og:image>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/cpsprodpb/3F95/production/_98777261_gettyimages-475245508.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-gb</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/amp/world-asia-42009839</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Bootstrapping My Side Project to $6k/Month</title>
<link>https://www.indiehackers.com/@EO/how-i-bootstrapped-my-side-project-to-6k-mo-hating-everything-it-stood-for-43c35faa25</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.indiehackers.com/@EO/how-i-bootstrapped-my-side-project-to-6k-mo-hating-everything-it-stood-for-43c35faa25</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;medium-insert-images medium-insert-images-overhang&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://storage.googleapis.com/indie-hackers.appspot.com/articles/aW72cKGwcWWLmE9O6mNZUNh4Lug1/@EO%7C43c35faa25/sept-earnings.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;medium-insert-image-active&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Every story that starts with “How I bootstrapped…”, is a happy story. Nobody ever bootstrapped a product to profitability and felt bad about it.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;da89&quot; id=&quot;da89&quot;&gt;This is different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;8cc0&quot; id=&quot;8cc0&quot;&gt;This is the long story of how I built and grew &lt;a href=&quot;https://appygen.net?utm_source=indiehackers_story&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;AppyGEN&lt;/a&gt;’s revenue to 6k+/month. And why I started hating it while still working full time on it, and how you can avoid going through the same thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;432b&quot; id=&quot;432b&quot;&gt;AppyGEN is a native Android app builder, designed for internet marketers, or more specifically: non-developers looking to make money online. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;432b&quot; id=&quot;432b&quot;&gt;It was launched in 2014, and since that time, I’ve done my best to keep it under the radar and basically never talk about it to anyone who was not a potential customer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How it all started&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;2fc7&quot; id=&quot;2fc7&quot;&gt;I’ve always loved building stuff. I made my first $1000 at 14, selling remote administration tools to wannabe hackers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;45c4&quot; id=&quot;45c4&quot;&gt;So in 2012, while pursuing my college degree (in France) and struggling to pay my rent, I started taking remote freelance dev jobs whenever I could. I was making a substantial amount of money for a broke 22 year old, doing what I loved. I even started investing some of it in online poker, heck, I even built a bot to play for me (didn’t work out though).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;cc0c&quot; id=&quot;cc0c&quot;&gt;After saving enough to pay my debts and some more to sustain my lifestyle, I decided that I could do this for a long time. So I dropped out, and went back to my home country (Morocco) where the cost of living was about 5 times cheaper than France.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;8403&quot; id=&quot;8403&quot;&gt;Fast forward to a few months later, I had amassed enough money to live comfortably for the next two years. But with all my friends working on their 9 to 5 jobs all day, I got bored pretty fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;0a52&quot; id=&quot;0a52&quot;&gt;So, I decided to start a company (with a friend) and bring the startup mindset to traditional small businesses. I remember thinking: I’ll be the first to do this so I’ll definitely have an edge in the long run. (Spoiler alert: Didn’t work).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;fa2a&quot; id=&quot;fa2a&quot;&gt;We had the bright idea to sell a customer &amp;amp; appointment management software to doctors who were still using pen and paper at the time (Nope, not even excel). We sold a few copies, but it quickly became obvious that most of them didn’t need our tool, there was no market for our product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;dc36&quot; id=&quot;dc36&quot;&gt;After that, we tried making a cool b2c app startup. We had no experience in mobile dev but it was fun learning everything from scratch. A few months later, we had 10.000+ users on our app, but not enough revenue. Ad revenue was too low to keep us afloat and eventually, we ran out of money to pay the office rent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;41c2&quot; id=&quot;41c2&quot;&gt;With no money and no vision for the future, we were back to square one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;medium-insert-images medium-insert-images-inline&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://storage.googleapis.com/indie-hackers.appspot.com/articles/aW72cKGwcWWLmE9O6mNZUNh4Lug1/@EO%7C43c35faa25/startup-failure-hyphon-music-group.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The inception of AppyGEN&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;65ba&quot; id=&quot;65ba&quot;&gt;One night, in an effort to sharpen his Android dev skills, my partner built a simple app with a list of videos, targeting a specific trending niche.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;afbc&quot; id=&quot;afbc&quot;&gt;In a matter of days, we were up to thousands of downloads from all around the world. The RPM (Revenue per 1000 impressions) was high, and almost overnight we started making a good amount of money just from the ads in that single app. So we thought, let’s make more of those apps!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;6405&quot; id=&quot;6405&quot;&gt;There was no need for us to spend months building an original startupy app, we could just make similarly simple apps and make a ton of money!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;b07c&quot; id=&quot;b07c&quot;&gt;And it worked, a month later we had enough money to pay our rent for the rest of the year. I loved automating stuff, especially if it could make me money and save me time at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;9170&quot; id=&quot;9170&quot;&gt;So we turned our apps into templates and I made a tool where we could just input the app name, icon and content, click a button, and get a native &amp;amp; profitable app, ready to be published. We used the tool to make dozens of those apps until we ran out of niches to target. Since we had enough money coming in, there was no real motivation to keep doing this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;04f9&quot; id=&quot;04f9&quot;&gt;As an experiment, we’ve decided to turn our tool into a product and sell it to people looking to make money online, and I knew just the place: &lt;a href=&quot;https://warriorforum.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;The Warrior Forum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;2333&quot; id=&quot;2333&quot;&gt;We wrote a PDF to teach the process of finding niches to target, monetizing and publishing the apps on the play store. And started selling v1 for a whopping $49 lifetime payment, including updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;71b5&quot; id=&quot;71b5&quot;&gt;Here’s an old video of one of the early versions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;medium-insert-embeds&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;medium-insert-embed&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;420&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/d8DfNbJHY_U&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;e75f&quot; id=&quot;e75f&quot;&gt;Embarrassing right? Not to the members of the warrior forum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;e75f&quot; id=&quot;e75f&quot;&gt;They were so used to overpriced bullshit courses that they couldn’t believe this simple, cheap software was helping them make a consistent and recurring revenue in a matter of days!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;da32&quot; id=&quot;da32&quot;&gt;They loved it and sales skyrocketed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;743f&quot; id=&quot;743f&quot;&gt;We’ve updated the tool a few more times and raised the price to $97 per license. I loved reading the reviews and getting emails from our customers saying we’ve changed their lives. I wanted to do this forever, and quickly stopped pursuing the original vision of the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;fdad&quot; id=&quot;fdad&quot;&gt;On the other hand, my partner who didn’t get to work on AppyGEN or enjoy it as much as I did started losing interest. So I bought his shares, and he went off to do his own thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Where’s my recurring revenue ?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;450f&quot; id=&quot;450f&quot;&gt;A few months later after me and my partner parted ways, sales started dwindling and I had to take another freelance gig to make some extra money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;b448&quot; id=&quot;b448&quot;&gt;One day, I was having a conversation with one of AppyGEN’s customers and he shared with me his ad revenue on Skype. This guy had made hundreds of apps in less than two months, and was making 10 times what I was making from the software sales!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;f774&quot; id=&quot;f774&quot;&gt;I was blown away, and to be honest, I also felt entitled to some of it. And that’s when it dawned on me. Why was I giving away lifetime licenses to a tool that helps you make money every month ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;deac&quot; id=&quot;deac&quot;&gt;The answer was simple: I had no real experience in entrepreneurship, pricing, marketing or growth. All I knew how to do was build stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;b2c8&quot; id=&quot;b2c8&quot;&gt;So I dropped my freelance gig, and embarked on a 6 month journey to learn everything about startups &amp;amp; entrepreneurship, as well as sharpen my web development and sysadmin skills. By the end of the learning phase I had a solid plan:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li name=&quot;4ac9&quot; id=&quot;4ac9&quot;&gt;To turn the software into a SaaS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;46f2&quot; id=&quot;46f2&quot;&gt;To have a free plan where users could make and monetize apps in exchange for a cut from their ad revenue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;ee81&quot; id=&quot;ee81&quot;&gt;To have a paid plan for users who want to keep 100% of their ad inventory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;medium-insert-images medium-insert-images-inline&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://storage.googleapis.com/indie-hackers.appspot.com/articles/aW72cKGwcWWLmE9O6mNZUNh4Lug1/@EO%7C43c35faa25/5-best-books-for-startups-and-growth-hackers.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;It wasn’t easy. I had to figure out a way to compile native Android apps on the cloud (emphasis on native), and handle the ton of traffic pouring in from the apps, in real time.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;2123&quot; id=&quot;2123&quot;&gt;I also had to keep my promise to the hundreds of early adopters who purchased the lifetime plan when the software didn’t have any server costs, and basically just give them premium features and 100% of their revenue for life (including the thousands apps guy).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;e9d7&quot; id=&quot;e9d7&quot;&gt;I stopped selling the desktop software and spent another six months building the web platform. It was an extremely fulfilling experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;SaaS is hard, making money from free users is even harder&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;024b&quot; id=&quot;024b&quot;&gt;The web platform was ready mid 2015, I silently launched a beta to the existing (lifetime) customers and they helped me eliminate the bugs I had missed. At that point, I thought it was a done deal. All I had to do was drive some traffic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;afa7&quot; id=&quot;afa7&quot;&gt;Since users could sign up for free, I wouldn’t even have to invest time in converting them to paid users or optimizing the funnel. I’d be sharing their ad revenue and making money wether they upgrade to a paid account or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;a430&quot; id=&quot;a430&quot;&gt;But still, I wasn’t very confident about my ability to manage tons of API calls from every app made through the software. So I decided to soft launch to a small audience of 200 people who had signed up to the waiting list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;d4b0&quot; id=&quot;d4b0&quot;&gt;This part was only supposed to take a few weeks. Just enough time for the new users to build and publish some apps and make sure that the platform does not break down under heavy load. It ended up taking months before I could get those users to publish any apps at all. There were so many things I didn’t account for, more specifically:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li name=&quot;38fd&quot; id=&quot;38fd&quot;&gt;Cumbersome Onboarding: Getting someone who had no development or app experience from “I want to make money online” to “I just published my first app on the play store” to “I just made my first dollar” was extremely hard to do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p name=&quot;4cb7&quot; id=&quot;4cb7&quot;&gt;I had to figure out a way to teach users how to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li name=&quot;dc6d&quot; id=&quot;dc6d&quot;&gt;Research for profitable niches find or create copyright-free content for their apps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;7ca7&quot; id=&quot;7ca7&quot;&gt;Create a developer account on Google Play Store (And convincing them to pay the $25 fee before they made a cent)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;1cf7&quot; id=&quot;1cf7&quot;&gt;Publish apps and do app store optimization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p name=&quot;6d54&quot; id=&quot;6d54&quot;&gt;Also, free users lack motivation. I never had that issue with the early adopters, most likely because they paid a price to use the tool. No matter how small that price was, they weren’t going to just drop everything whenever they stumble along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;f9d8&quot; id=&quot;f9d8&quot;&gt;The new users, not so much. At the slightest whim, like “Create an icon for your app”, or “Pay the $25 google play developer fee”, they’d just close everything and disappear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;medium-insert-images medium-insert-images-inline&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://storage.googleapis.com/indie-hackers.appspot.com/articles/aW72cKGwcWWLmE9O6mNZUNh4Lug1/@EO%7C43c35faa25/churn-header.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;e13c&quot; id=&quot;e13c&quot; class=&quot;&quot;&gt;So I was back at square one again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;497a&quot; id=&quot;497a&quot;&gt;After spending almost a year working my ass off, I still had no recurring revenue, new server costs, and a shitload of subtle obstacles I didn’t account for and had no idea how to deal with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Self-doubt and not changing the world like everyone else&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;e796&quot; id=&quot;e796&quot;&gt;AppyGEN was taking a toll on my personal life. I had previously disabled all my social networks to focus on it, and more than a year had gone by with nothing to show for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;d329&quot; id=&quot;d329&quot;&gt;Reading the successes of other simpler products made me angry at myself, why did I have to go after such a complicated project ? Couldn’t I have just made a to-do list app ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;3a31&quot; id=&quot;3a31&quot;&gt;I also came to the conclusion that AppyGEN didn’t really help make the world a better place like every other startup I read about. It seemed to me like it was just making the play store a worse place, helping non-developers publish hundreds of unoriginal apps that only took away from the visibility and chances of more ambitious apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;e711&quot; id=&quot;e711&quot;&gt;I was myself an app developer once and I could clearly see how my product ultimately harmed other developers. I started hating everything AppyGEN stands for, no matter how much money it continued to make for my existing customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;medium-insert-images medium-insert-images-inline&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://storage.googleapis.com/indie-hackers.appspot.com/articles/aW72cKGwcWWLmE9O6mNZUNh4Lug1/@EO%7C43c35faa25/20170802205551-GettyImages-691046381.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;ad43&quot; id=&quot;ad43&quot; class=&quot;&quot;&gt;But what else could I do ? I had already invested so much of my time into it, and I knew for a fact that it could eventually become a profitable business, plus I needed the money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;a399&quot; id=&quot;a399&quot;&gt;I had learned so much in the process of building the platform, and for that I was grateful. There was still a lot to learn too, and I was confident it would serve me well in my future ventures. So I decided to secretly keep working on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;5909&quot; id=&quot;5909&quot;&gt;Whenever someone would ask me what I’m working on, I’d say I’m freelancing. Whenever I’d get a freelancing offer, I’d turn it down saying I had too much on my plate right now. Gone were the days where I would proudly say that I’m building an awesome SaaS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Onboarding and motivating free users&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;efa2&quot; id=&quot;efa2&quot;&gt;I did my best to optimize the onboarding process as much as I could. Which was not enough considering the fact that users still had to do some work in order to be able to generate unique apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;ac1a&quot; id=&quot;ac1a&quot;&gt;I didn’t want every app made through the software to look the same, and I knew there was no way they would be able to make an income just copying existing or demo apps. They had to invest some time in reading the tutorials, doing research, creating icons and assets, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;532f&quot; id=&quot;532f&quot;&gt;So I tried a bunch of things like drip campaigns, a concierge service for paid users, a forum, and a bunch of other hacks I had read about in case studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;a0bc&quot; id=&quot;a0bc&quot;&gt;Although these things did help decrease churn a little bit, it wasn’t enough. Only about 5% of new users would get to the point where they got value from the software to invest more of their time in building apps and growing their revenue (and mine).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;a73e&quot; id=&quot;a73e&quot;&gt;You’d think that if you promised someone they’d make a consistent, growing and recurring income, without requiring any upfront investment, they’d be all over it day and night. It wasn’t an onboarding or engagement problem, it was a motivation problem. And it took me some time to figure this out since none of the churned users would answer my emails when I reached out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;b204&quot; id=&quot;b204&quot;&gt;Completely burned out and disenchanted, I decided I’d try one last thing before giving up: &lt;strong&gt;Gamification&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;1e0b&quot; id=&quot;1e0b&quot;&gt;The idea was to turn the whole thing into a game, where you learn a bunch of stuff about making profitable apps, build your app portfolio, and grow your ad revenue. All at the same time, while having fun and competing with other members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;8816&quot; id=&quot;8816&quot;&gt;It felt like the perfect (and only) answer to all my problems, so I scrapped about 50% of the existing code and re-wrote it in a way that made gamification an essential and required part of the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;53d8&quot; id=&quot;53d8&quot;&gt;New users would automatically be assigned a “rank” and two or three “missions” they needed to complete in order to move to the next level, every mission had a step by step tutorial on how to complete it and every time a user gets to a higher level, they’d get rewarded with a new rank and a shiny badge icon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;167b&quot; id=&quot;167b&quot;&gt;Users could see their progress in real time and compete for the top 10 spots on the leaderboard, automatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;3c67&quot; id=&quot;3c67&quot;&gt;It worked great and everyone loved it! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;3c67&quot; id=&quot;3c67&quot;&gt;Here's a screenshot of the new gamified dashboard:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;medium-insert-images medium-insert-images-inline&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://storage.googleapis.com/indie-hackers.appspot.com/articles/aW72cKGwcWWLmE9O6mNZUNh4Lug1/@EO%7C43c35faa25/Screen%20Shot%202017-11-04%20at%202.41.51%20PM.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;medium-insert-images-inline&quot;&gt;Dividing the onboarding process in terms of “levels” also helped me figure out (thanks to mixpanel’s analytics) that anyone who got to level 3 in the first week, would most likely keep coming back, making more apps, and eventually making his first dollar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;68b3&quot; id=&quot;68b3&quot; class=&quot;medium-insert-images-inline&quot;&gt;It was one of those amazing Aha moments that got me into entrepreneurship in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;adf7&quot; id=&quot;adf7&quot; class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Before I knew it, the conversion rate from new user to active user (level 3+) skyrocketed from 5% to 45%. I could finally start driving traffic to the site and working on other things like acquisition and retention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Growing slowly, quietly and automatically&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;fd94&quot; id=&quot;fd94&quot;&gt;By the end of 2016, we had 1000+ active users and monthly revenue had reached a consistent $3k+/Month for the past 6 months. 70% of it from sharing the ad revenue of free users, and 30% from paid subscriptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;febb&quot; id=&quot;febb&quot;&gt;I couldn’t understand why users who were making a thousand dollars in ad revenue each month, didn’t upgrade their accounts, after all it only costs $25. Turns out, a lot of these users were living in countries where they couldn’t have a Visa card or PayPal account, and just couldn’t pay me even if they wanted to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;29ae&quot; id=&quot;29ae&quot;&gt;In terms of revenue, this worked out fine for me, I’d probably be making a lot less money without the rev-share plan and I wouldn’t have been able to offer the service for free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;a570&quot; id=&quot;a570&quot;&gt;Remember earlier when I said I hated what AppyGEN stands for ?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The recurring revenue didn’t fix that, I still felt too self conscious about the whole thing, and I would constantly think about it whenever I was working on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;54a0&quot; id=&quot;54a0&quot;&gt;It’s hard growing a business you hate, no matter how much money it made or could make. But I couldn’t just ignore it and be contented with the current revenue, hoping it will never drop. It happened once. One of my biggest earners had lost his play store account due to policy violations and overnight the revenue dropped to 2K until the same guy decided to get back at it. So I had to keep a continuous flow of new users at all times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;f6d7&quot; id=&quot;f6d7&quot;&gt;I sucked at SEO and paid advertising. Press, social and content marketing were out of the question since it would put me and the software in front of all kinds of readers, and I wasn’t ready for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;5705&quot; id=&quot;5705&quot;&gt;In retrospect, a bunch of my worries were exclusively in my head, but that’s what you get when you spend years keeping your work to yourself, convinced that what you’re doing is bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;4bdc&quot; id=&quot;4bdc&quot;&gt;Although I still enjoyed adding new features, I still felt bad about sharing it with the world, and acquisition is all about sharing nowadays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;9425&quot; id=&quot;9425&quot;&gt;So I came up with the idea to get my users to share it, so that I didn’t have to. To do so, I set up a very enticing referral program:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;a58b&quot; id=&quot;a58b&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users could share their referral link and get a 10% cut of the ad revenue from every app the referred user makes, forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;b4f6&quot; id=&quot;b4f6&quot;&gt;For example, if user A brings in user B, and user B makes an app that brings in $10/day, user A would get $1 every day without lifting a finger.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If user B decides to upgrade to a premium account, user A would get a commission every time user B pays his subscription.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;c89c&quot; id=&quot;c89c&quot;&gt;And it worked, some users even stopped making apps and focused solely on referring new users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;149b&quot; id=&quot;149b&quot;&gt;A few months later, AppyGEN’s revenue doubled to reach $6k+/Month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Lessons learned&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;28b1&quot; id=&quot;28b1&quot;&gt;Today, I am actually grateful that AppyGEN is bringing in enough money for me to work on whatever I want. But more importantly, I am so grateful about the hard lessons I learned along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;169c&quot; id=&quot;169c&quot;&gt;Hopefully, you were able to extract some of those lessons through this post. If not, here are the most important rules you should keep in mind for your next project:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li name=&quot;ea4d&quot; id=&quot;ea4d&quot;&gt;Making money should never be your main motivation when working on something new.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;ef90&quot; id=&quot;ef90&quot;&gt;Never, ever, keep your work to yourself. Share as much as you can, as soon as you can.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;68a5&quot; id=&quot;68a5&quot;&gt;Build something you’d be proud of 5 years from now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p name=&quot;cfd0&quot; id=&quot;cfd0&quot;&gt;If you have questions or want to get in touch or want to work with me on something, I’d love to chat. Email me (eothmane.io[at]gmail.com), follow me on Twitter (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/get_eo&quot; data-href=&quot;https://twitter.com/get_eo&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@get_eo&lt;/a&gt;) &amp;amp; Medium (&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@e_othmane&quot; data-href=&quot;https://medium.com/@e_othmane&quot; data-anchor-type=&quot;2&quot; data-user-id=&quot;2ba9d4a65efd&quot; data-action-value=&quot;2ba9d4a65efd&quot; data-action=&quot;show-user-card&quot; data-action-type=&quot;hover&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Othmane E.&lt;/a&gt;), or leave a comment below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;0d49&quot; id=&quot;0d49&quot;&gt;Thank you for reading!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 15:39:36 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ChanningAllen</dc:creator>
<og:description>Every story that starts with “How I bootstrapped…”, is a happy story. Nobody ever bootstrapped a product to profitability and felt bad about it. This is d…</og:description>
<og:image>https://storage.googleapis.com/indie-hackers.appspot.com/articles/aW72cKGwcWWLmE9O6mNZUNh4Lug1/@EO%7C43c35faa25/20170802205551-GettyImages-691046381.jpeg</og:image>
<og:title>How I Bootstrapped My Side Project to $6k/Month While Hating Everything It Stands For – Indie Hackers</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.indiehackers.com/@EO/how-i-bootstrapped-my-side-project-to-6k-mo-hating-everything-it-stood-for-43c35faa25</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.indiehackers.com/@EO/how-i-bootstrapped-my-side-project-to-6k-mo-hating-everything-it-stood-for-43c35faa25</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Learn just enough Linux to get things done</title>
<link>http://alexpetralia.com/posts/2017/6/26/learning-linux-bash-to-get-things-done</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://alexpetralia.com/posts/2017/6/26/learning-linux-bash-to-get-things-done</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-layout sqs-grid-12 columns-12&quot; data-layout-label=&quot;Post Body&quot; data-type=&quot;item&quot; data-updated-on=&quot;1494691404127&quot; id=&quot;item-59172e359de4bb3c0182fac9&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row sqs-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col sqs-col-12 span-12&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html&quot; data-block-type=&quot;2&quot; id=&quot;block-cbd47cbc293bece8fd30&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Different operating systems have long catered to different audiences: Windows for the business professional, Mac for the creative professional and Linux for the software developer. For OS providers, this sort of market segmentation greatly simplified product vision, technical requirements, user experience and marketing direction. However, it also reinforced workplace norms which bucket individuals into narrow, non-overlapping domains: business people can offer no insight into the creative process, and developers no insight into business problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In reality, knowledge and skill are fluid, spanning multiple disciplines and fields. The notion that &quot;you can only be good at one thing&quot; is not a roadmap to mastery but rather a prescription for premature optimization. You can only know what you're good at once you've sampled a lot of things - &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://tim.blog/2007/09/14/the-top-5-reasons-to-be-a-jack-of-all-trades/&quot;&gt;and you may just find that you're good at a lot of them&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://alexpetralia.com/posts/2017/6/8/hard-skills-for-modern-business-analyst&quot;&gt;modern business analysts&lt;/a&gt;, bridging the gap between business and software development is especially important. Business analysts must be &quot;dual platform,&quot; able to leverage command-line tools available only on Linux (or OS X) yet still benefit from the power of Microsoft Office on Windows. Understandably, the world of Linux is intimidating for those with a business degree. Fortunately, as with most things, you only need to learn 20% of the information to accomplish 80% of the work. Here is my 20%.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why modern business analysts should know Linux&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to its open source roots, Linux benefited from the contributions of thousands of developers over time. They built programs and utilities not only to make their jobs easier, but also the jobs of programmers who followed them. As a result, open source development created a network effect: the more developers built utilities on the platform, the more other developers could leverage those utilities to write their programs right away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What resulted was an expansive suite of programs and utilities (collectively, software) that were written in Linux, for Linux - much of which was never ported to Windows. One example of this is the popular version control system (VCS) called &lt;em&gt;git&lt;/em&gt;. Developers &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; have written this software to work on Windows, but they didn't. They wrote it to work on the command line for Linux because it was the ecosystem which already had all the tools they needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Concretely, development on Windows runs into two main problems:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Basic tasks, like file parsing, job scheduling, and text search are more involved than running a command-line utility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Programming languages (eg. Python, C++) and their associated code libraries will throw errors because they are expecting certain Linux parameters or file system locations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Together, this means more time spent rewriting basic tools already available in Linux and troubleshooting OS compatibility errors. This is not a surprise - the Windows ecosystem simply wasn't designed with software development in mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the case made for Linux development, let's begin with the basics.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The fundamental unit of Linux: the &quot;shell&quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;shell&lt;/strong&gt; (also known as the terminal, console or command line) is a text-based user interface through which commands are sent to the machine. On Linux, the shell's default language is called &lt;strong&gt;bash&lt;/strong&gt;. Unlike Windows users who primarily point-and-click inside of windows, Linux developers stick to their keyboard and type commands into the shell. While this transition is at first unnatural for those without a programming background, the benefits of developing in Linux easily outweigh the initial learning investment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row sqs-row&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;col sqs-col-8 span-8&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block image-block sqs-block-image&quot; data-block-type=&quot;5&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_5_1496920204975_5480&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-outer-wrapper layout-caption-below design-layout-inline&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;intrinsic&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-wrapper has-aspect-ratio&quot; data-description=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/5564802ee4b01df36d2c2984/t/5950843db6ac5081d708b0ab/1498448962396/&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;thumb-image&quot; data-src=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/5564802ee4b01df36d2c2984/t/5950843db6ac5081d708b0ab/1498448962396/&quot; data-image=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/5564802ee4b01df36d2c2984/t/5950843db6ac5081d708b0ab/1498448962396/&quot; data-image-dimensions=&quot;782x480&quot; data-image-focal-point=&quot;0.5,0.5&quot; data-load=&quot;false&quot; data-image-id=&quot;5950843db6ac5081d708b0ab&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html&quot; data-block-type=&quot;2&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_5_1496920204975_5758&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning the few important concepts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compared to a full-fledged programming language, bash only has a few major concepts that need to be learned. Once these are covered, the rest of bash is just memorization. I'll restate for clarity: &lt;strong&gt;being good at bash is simply memorizing about 20-30 commands and their most common arguments&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linux seems impenetrable to non-developers because of the way that developers seem to effortlessly regurgitate esoteric terminal commands at will. The reality is that they committed only a few dozen commands to memory - for anything more complicated, they too (like all mere mortals) consult Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that out of the way, here are the main concepts in bash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Command syntax&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Commands follow the syntax of: {command} {arguments..}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, in 'grep -inr', &lt;em&gt;grep&lt;/em&gt; is the command (to search for a string of text) and &lt;em&gt;-inr&lt;/em&gt; are flags/arguments which change what grep does by default. The only way to learn what these mean is to look them up through Google or by typing 'man grep'. I recommend learning the commands and their most common arguments together; it's too burdensome otherwise to remember what each and every flag does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Directory aliases&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The present directory (ie. where am I?): .&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The parent directory of the present directory: ..&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The user's home directory: ~&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The file system root (or the parent of all parents): /&lt;br/&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;For example, to change from the current directory to the parent directory, one would type: &quot;cd ..&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, to copy a file located at &quot;/path/to/file.txt&quot; into the present directory, one would enter &quot;cp /path/to/file.txt .&quot; (note the period at the end of the command). Since these are no more than aliases, the actual path name could be used in their place instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;STDIN / STDOUT&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anything you type into the window and submit (via ENTER) is called &lt;strong&gt;standard input&lt;/strong&gt; (STDIN).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anything that a program prints back out to the terminal (eg. text from within a file) is called &lt;strong&gt;standard output&lt;/strong&gt; (STDOUT).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Piping&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;|&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A pipe takes the STDOUT of the command to the left of the pipe and makes it the STDIN to the command on the right of the pipe.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;example:&lt;/strong&gt; echo 'test text' | wc -l&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A greater-than sign takes the STDOUT of the command on the left and &lt;strong&gt;writes/overwrites&lt;/strong&gt; to a new &lt;strong&gt;file&lt;/strong&gt; on the right&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;example&lt;/strong&gt;: ls &amp;gt; tmp.txt&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two greater-than signs takes the STDOUT of the command on the left and &lt;strong&gt;appends&lt;/strong&gt; to a new or existing &lt;strong&gt;file&lt;/strong&gt; on the right.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;example&lt;/strong&gt;: date &amp;gt;&amp;gt; tmp.txt&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Wildcards&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can think of this like SQL's % symbol - for example, you might write &quot;WHERE first_name LIKE 'John%'&quot; to catch any first name starting with John.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In bash, you would write &quot;John&lt;strong&gt;*&lt;/strong&gt;&quot;. If you want to list all of the files ending with &quot;.json&quot; in a folder, you would write: &quot;ls *.json&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Tab completion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bash will often finish off commands intelligently for you if you start typing a command and hit your TAB key.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That being said, you should really use something like &lt;strong&gt;zsh&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;fish&lt;/strong&gt; for autocomplete since it is hard to remember the commands and all their parameters - rather, these tools will autocomplete your commands based on your command history!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Quitting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometime's you'll get stuck in some program and you can't get out. This is a &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; frequent occurrence for beginners in Linux and it is extremely demotivating. Often, quitting has something to do with &lt;strong&gt;q&lt;/strong&gt;. It's good to memorize the following and try them all when you're trapped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bash
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;CTRL+c&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;q&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;exit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python: quit()&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nano: CTRL+x&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vim: &amp;lt;Esc&amp;gt; :q!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My memorized list of bash commands&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the commands I use most frequently in Linux (sorted from most to least frequently used). As I mentioned before, knowing just a handful of commands will accomplish the vast majority of programmable tasks you need to perform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;cd {directory}
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;change directory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ls -lha
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;list directory (verbose)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vim &lt;em&gt;or&lt;/em&gt; nano
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;command line editor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;touch {file}
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;create a new empty file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cp -R {original_name} {new_name}
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;copy a file or directory (and all of its contents)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mv {original_name} {new_name}
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;move or rename a file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rm {file}
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;delete a file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rm -rf {file/folder}
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;permanently delete a file or folder [use with caution!]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pwd
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;print the present working directory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cat &lt;em&gt;or&lt;/em&gt; less &lt;em&gt;or&lt;/em&gt; tail &lt;em&gt;or&lt;/em&gt; head -n10 {file}
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;STDOUT contents of a file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mkdir {directory}
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;make an empty directory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;grep -inr {string}
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;find a string in any files in this directory or child directories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tabview &amp;lt;delimited_file&amp;gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;display a delimited file in columnar format&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ssh {username}@{hostname}
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;connect to a remote machine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tree -LhaC 3
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;show directory structure 3 levels down (with file sizes and including hidden directories)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;htop
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;task manager&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pip install --user {pip_package}
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Python package manager to install  packages to ~/.local/bin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pushd . ; popd ; dirs; cd -
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;push/pop/view directories onto the stack + change back to last directory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sed -i &quot;s/{find}/{replace}/g&quot; {file}
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;replace a string in a file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;find . -type f -name '*.txt' -exec sed -i &quot;s/{find}/{replace}/g&quot; {} \;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;replace a string for each file in this and child folders with a name like *.txt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tmux new -s session, tmux attach -t session
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;create another terminal session without creating a new window [advanced]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;wget {link}
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;download a webpage or web resource&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;curl -X POST -d &quot;{key: value}&quot; http://www.google.com
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;send an HTTP request to a web server&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;find &amp;lt;directory&amp;gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;list all directory contents and their children, recursively&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advanced and infrequently commands&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find it's good to keep a list of commands that are useful in certain situations (eg. which process is blocking a certain network port), even though those situations don't happen very often. These are some uncommon commands I keep nearby:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;lsof -i :8080
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;list open file descriptors (-i flag for network interfaces)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;netstat | head -n20
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;list currently open Internet/UNIX sockets and related information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dstat -a
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;stream current disk, network, CPU activity &amp;amp; more&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;nslookup &amp;lt;IP address&amp;gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;find hostname for a remote IP address&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;strace -f -e &amp;lt;syscall&amp;gt; &amp;lt;cmd&amp;gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;trace system calls of a program (-e flag to filter for certain system calls)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ps aux | head -n20
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;print currently active processes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;file &amp;lt;file&amp;gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;check what a file type is (eg. executable, binary, ASCII-text file)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;uname -a
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;kernel information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lsb_release -a
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;OS information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hostname
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;check the hostname of your machine (ie. the name so other computers can reach you)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pstree
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;visualize process forks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;time &amp;lt;cmd&amp;gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;execute a command and report statistics about how long it took&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CTRL + z ; bg; jobs; fg
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;send a process in current tty into background and back to foreground&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cat file.txt | xargs -n1 | sort | uniq -c
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;count unique words in a file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;wc -l &amp;lt;file&amp;gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;line count in a file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;du -ha
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;show size on disk for directories and their contents&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;zcat &amp;lt;file.gz&amp;gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;display contents of a zipped text file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;scp &amp;lt;user@remote_host&amp;gt; &amp;lt;local_path&amp;gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;copy a file from remote to local server, or vice versa&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;man {command}
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;show manual (ie. documentation) for a command, but you're probably better off using Google&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 14:12:02 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>shrikant</dc:creator>
<og:title>Learn just enough Linux to get things done</og:title>
<og:url>http://alexpetralia.com/posts/2017/6/26/learning-linux-bash-to-get-things-done</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Different operating systems have long catered to different audiences: Windows for the business professional, Mac for the creative professional and Linux for the software developer. For OS providers, this sort of market segmentation greatly simplified product vision, technical requirements, user expe</og:description>
<og:image>http://static1.squarespace.com/static/5564802ee4b01df36d2c2984/5758be42e32140048007459a/59172e359de4bb3c0182fac9/1500409563367/Selection_031.png?format=1000w</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://alexpetralia.com/posts/2017/6/26/learning-linux-bash-to-get-things-done</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Magic: The Gathering Is Turing Complete (2012)</title>
<link>http://www.toothycat.net/~hologram/Turing/index.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.toothycat.net/~hologram/Turing/index.html</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;Content-Type&quot; content=&quot;text/html; charset=UTF-8&quot; /&gt;&lt;title&gt;Magic: the Gathering is Turing Complete&lt;/title&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; href=&quot;turing.css&quot; media=&quot;screen&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot; /&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;84.317042208823&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We always knew &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wizards.com/Magic/TCG/&quot;&gt;Magic: the Gathering&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; was a complex game. But now it's proven: you could assemble a computer out of Magic cards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Magic Turing Machine v6: Wild Evocation / Rotlung Reanimator&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What does &quot;Turing complete&quot; mean?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's an idea called &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Turing_completeness&quot;&gt;Turing completeness&lt;/a&gt;&quot;, which is used to indicate that a system has a particular degree of complexity. Any Turing-complete system is theoretically able to emulate any other. One way to show that a system is Turing complete is to make a &quot;Turing machine&quot; in it. This isn't the only way of demonstrating Turing completeness, but it is one of the more understandable. In the discussion on this site I assemble a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Universal_Turing_machine&quot;&gt;Universal Turing Machine&lt;/a&gt; from Magic: the Gathering cards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;But doesn't Magic involve the players making lots of choices?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Normally, yes, it does. But occasionally in normal gameplay you get a sequence of three or four events in a row that are forced to happen by the cards and the rules of the game. The machine below just extends this idea to millions of forced choices in a row.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea of my Magic Turing machine is that the players do &lt;strong&gt;nothing at all&lt;/strong&gt;, except when the game offers them a choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the in-game &quot;machine&quot; has started, processing continues without requiring any choices from the players, with one category of exceptions: Some of the cards in the machine say &quot;You may [do X]. If you do, [Y happens].&quot; In these cases, the machine arranges that the players will be able to do X, in precisely one way. It just requires the players to always choose to take the game up on any options they're offered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(For discussion of the possibility of removing the &quot;may&quot; cards, see the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.toothycat.net/~hologram/Turing/Future.html#Future&quot;&gt;Future Directions&lt;/a&gt; page.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How does it work?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm glad you asked! On this website you can see the full list of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.toothycat.net/~hologram/Turing/Cards.html&quot;&gt;all cards required in the machine&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.toothycat.net/~hologram/Turing/HowItWorks.html&quot;&gt;an explanation of how it works in detail&lt;/a&gt;. You can also find out &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.toothycat.net/~hologram/Turing/About.html&quot;&gt;more about the person who created this monstrosity&lt;/a&gt;. Have fun!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;News&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6th November 2017: Translation into Japanese&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keisuke Kishimoto has translated this site into Japanese! So if you'd find it easier to follow reading in Japanese than English, head over to &lt;a href=&quot;http://d.hatena.ne.jp/kkishi/20171104/&quot;&gt;http://d.hatena.ne.jp/kkishi/20171104/&lt;/a&gt; and enjoy. Many thanks, Keisuke!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20th September 2012: Version 5 Has Arrived&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;With all the recent attention from the Internet, it's been brought to my attention again how the (2, 3) universal Turing machine used in versions 1-4 is only a proper universal Turing machine in very specific circumstances, involving an infinitely long nonrepeating section of tape, which the combo failed to deliver. This spurred on my efforts to fix this by making a version instead of the (2, 18) universal Turing machine, and today, the results have gone online. Enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;16th September 2012: Hello, Internet!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It seems the Magic Turing machine has been getting a sudden burst of online attention. So if you like to read other people's thoughts, you could go and read about it on: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/magicTCG/comments/zoojk/magic_is_apparently_turing_complete/&quot;&gt;Reddit&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/compsci/comments/zp7c1/magic_the_gathering_is_turing_complete/&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/programming/comments/zqt4d/magic_the_gathering_is_turing_complete/&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;), &lt;a href=&quot;http://boingboing.net/2012/09/12/magic-the-gathering.html&quot;&gt;BoingBoing&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://kotaku.com/5942472/dark-wizards-turn-magic-card-game-into-basic-computer?post=52599392&quot;&gt;Kotaku&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.metafilter.com/119840/Magic-the-Gathering-is-Turing-complete&quot;&gt;Metafilter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://games.slashdot.org/story/12/09/12/0059200/magic-the-gathering-is-turing-complete&quot;&gt;Slashdot&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://markrosewater.tumblr.com/post/31451269236/did-you-see-the-post-that-demonstrated-that-magic-is&quot;&gt;Mark Rosewater's blog&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;http://community.wizards.com/go/thread/view/75842/29377357/Magic_is_Turing_Complete_(the_Turing_Machine_combo)&quot;&gt;the Wizards of the Coast forums&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 13:15:13 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>reimertz</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.toothycat.net/~hologram/Turing/index.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>