<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>The Right to Repair could help address a critical shortage in school computers</title>
<link>https://uspirg.org/blogs/blog/usp/right-repair-could-help-address-critical-shortage-school-computers#new_tab</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://uspirg.org/blogs/blog/usp/right-repair-could-help-address-critical-shortage-school-computers#new_tab</guid>
<description>&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;In many places across the United States, school has begun, with much of that schooling actually remote learning. We’ve found out we have a big problem: There are not enough computers for every student stuck at home because of the COVID-19 pandemic. According to an AP investigation, America is some &lt;a href=&quot;https://apnews.com/01e9302796d749b6aadc35ddc8f4c946&quot;&gt;5 million laptops short&lt;/a&gt; of what we need. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Whether or not you or your child can access a computer and the internet could mean the difference between getting an education this fall, or not. The stakes have perhaps never been higher for equitable computer access in the U.S. But thanks to disruptions in the supply chain, even though schools and businesses have ordered new computers, they aren’t showing up. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;California is short &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sacbee.com/news/politics-government/capitol-alert/article244418057.html&quot;&gt;1 million computers&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.denverpost.com/2020/08/20/denver-public-schools-computer-shortage-covid/&quot;&gt;Denver&lt;/a&gt;’s public schools are lacking thousands of computers, while waiting for orders to be fulfilled. Delays are threatening remote learning for school districts in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kolotv.com/2020/08/21/laptop-shortage-an-issue-for-wcsd-in-turning-to-distance-learning/&quot;&gt;Nevada&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dailyworld.com/story/news/local/2020/08/01/st-landry-parish-board-members-question-virtual-reopening-schools/5549317002/&quot;&gt;Louisiana&lt;/a&gt;. All across the country, schools are scrambling, from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.savannahnow.com/news/20200817/savannah-public-schools-will-be-thousands-short-of-its-order-of-computer-dhttps://www.savannahnow.com/news/20200817/savannah-public-schools-will-be-thousands-short-of-its-order-of-computer-devices-when-classes-startevices-when-classes-start&quot;&gt;Savannah&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kvue.com/article/news/education/schools/austin-isd-chromebooks-ipads-delay-2020-fall/269-c0016959-618c-43ce-ad70-968e1d8dbf15&quot;&gt;Austin&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sample of results from an exclusive Associated Press report on school computer shortages&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&quot;Sales have been up 20 percent to 40 percent every single week,&quot; Stephen Baker, a consumer tech analyst with The NPD Group, told &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.axios.com/coronavirus-education-laptop-shortage-f5990485-6277-4f4e-a37c-ec7f77d68241.html&quot;&gt;Axios&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Refurbished computers meet critical need&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;We likely already have all the computers we need to meet this shortfall. While new computers are hard to find, there is another solution: collecting, refurbishing and distributing computers that no one is using. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Given that Americans bought 48 million &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statista.com/statistics/722361/united-states-mobile-pc-unit-shipments/&quot;&gt;laptops&lt;/a&gt; and 17 million &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statista.com/statistics/722354/united-states-desktop-pc-unit-shipments/&quot;&gt;desktops&lt;/a&gt; in 2019, and that globally, the combined production of laptops, desktops and tablets has been fairly steady for the last &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statista.com/statistics/272595/global-shipments-forecast-for-tablets-laptops-and-desktop-pcs/&quot;&gt;10 years&lt;/a&gt;, there are more than enough devices, especially if you add in tablets. &lt;/p&gt;


&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple refurbisher John Bumstead believes restoring activtation locked tablets could address the shortfall. &lt;/em&gt;

&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;“We have a majority of what we need,” said TechDump CEO Amanda LaGrange, citing that businesses and households often retire “outdated” computers to the back of their closets when they can easily be fixed and updated. In any case, if a PC or laptop is unredeemable, refurbishers can extract the parts they need for other repairs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Our problem is that while the production and shipment of new computers is, under normal circumstances, streamlined, the same can’t be said for how we treat reuse and refurbishing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;According to goTRG CEO Sender Shamiss, refurbishing is critical, but the lack of trust between manufacturers and refurbishers makes it difficult to establish a line of communication. More often than not, manufacturers malign independent refurbishers as inferior even though the independent evaluators have determined that the quality of their repair is comparable to that of authorized refurbishers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;“Almost everything is refurbished by third parties,” said Shamiss. “There is no difference between an authorized refurbisher and a non-authorized refurbisher.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Robin Ingenthron, founder of Good Point Recycling says that manufacturers create obstacles with the devices themselves to dissuade the reuse of  tech products. “Technology may auto-lock (“brick”) devices sold to second-hand and third-hand consumers,” explained Ingenthron at an event about reusing products, hosted by the Massachusetts Department of Environmental Protection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Reuse helps meet shortfalls&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;All across the country, refurbishers are stepping in to fill the gaps. In &lt;a href=&quot;https://delawarebusinesstimes.com/news/remote-learning-needs-computers/&quot;&gt;Delaware&lt;/a&gt;, a local non-profit called NERDit NOW is providing low-cost computers to students in partnership with local schools, and has ramped up its local operation. In &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fox5atlanta.com/news/nonprofit-works-to-supply-students-with-refurbished-laptops&quot;&gt;Atlanta&lt;/a&gt;, New Life Tech Group, which normally refurbishes and donates 50 computers each year, ramped up its workflow and gave away more than 2,000. Both non-profits note that it costs about $50 to refurbish one laptop. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Necessity is the mother of invention.Two &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pwcs.edu/news/2019-20_news/p_w_c_s_students_distribute_refurbished_computers&quot;&gt;high school students&lt;/a&gt; started their own refurbishing program in Virginia, and as did an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newsherald.com/story/news/2020/08/10/panama-city-man-refurbishes-laptops-bay-county-students-need/3317716001/&quot;&gt;engineer in Florida&lt;/a&gt; to address the needs in their respective communities. In Cuyahoga County, Ohio, a local television station is running a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wkyc.com/article/news/local/outreach/3cares/computers-for-kids-drive-rolls-into-its-second-week/95-132c9dad-fc08-49c7-abeb-4da6c06b781a&quot;&gt;used computer drive&lt;/a&gt; to collect and refurbish devices for students. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Most of these community-refurbished computers are going directly to families, and not through the school system, explained Erez Pikar, the CEO of Toxell-CDI, one of the larger computer refurbishers. “Schools don’t have enough IT staff,” explained Pikar to U.S. PIRG, and therefore can’t support too many dissimilar devices. The best products for schools to use are refurbished business computers which tend to come in lot sizes big enough to give each student the same computer. Unfortunately, according to Pikar, businesses have been reluctant to send computers to refurbishers over the last few months.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Right to Repair reforms would lower barriers for critical computer refurbishing&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Even as refurbished computers are more and more mission critical, many barriers remain to getting them into the hands of students. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Many usable computers are sitting in corporate overstock or empty offices, and perhaps even in your basement. But even when refurbishers get those computers, they can’t always get them working because manufacturers restrict access to spare parts or manuals. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;LaGrange and other refurbishers describe bins of activation-locked devices in their facilities -- devices that work fine, but are locked down because the original owner forgot to unlock her account when she donated or sold it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;We’d have a lot more computers available if the industry as a whole valued reuse and the secondary life of electronics. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;According to LaGrange, manufacturers should use this as an opportunity to evaluate their positions regarding the right to repair and how lower barriers to repair could help address the digital divide. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;“This would all be a lot easier if we had right to repair,” said LaGrange.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://uspirg.org/feature/usp/rebuilt-school&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;For tips on how to purchase a refurbished computer, check out our guide.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alex DeBellis contributed to the article. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 16:18:08 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>elorant</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://uspirg.org/blogs/blog/usp/right-repair-could-help-address-critical-shortage-school-computers</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Hard to discover tips and apps for macOS</title>
<link>https://thume.ca/2020/09/04/macos-tips/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://thume.ca/2020/09/04/macos-tips/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Inspired by a few different conversations with friends who’ve switched to macOS where I give them a whole bunch of tips and recommendations I’ve learned about over many years which are super important to how I use my computer, but often quite hard to find out about, I decided to write them all down:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;hidden-macos-tips&quot;&gt;Hidden macOS tips&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Dragging a file or folder onto a file open dialog selects it in the dialog. Similarly dragging onto a “Choose file” button.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dragging onto a terminal window pastes the full path of that file/folder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can drag the little file/folder icons at the top of many windows, useful in combo with previous tips.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you hold down &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;option&lt;/code&gt; while clicking the “Scaled” radio button in the Display preferences it’ll give you many more resolution options on external displays. If you want native resolution with no scaling on the built in display you’ll still need an external tool like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.madrau.com/&quot;&gt;SwitchResX&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thnkdev.com/QuickRes/&quot;&gt;QuickRes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In Finder, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;return&lt;/code&gt; is the shortcut for rename, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;option&lt;/code&gt;+drag copies, and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;space&lt;/code&gt; is quicklook preview&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In Preview if you open the Sidebar in a PDF you can drag pages around including between documents, hold option to copy, delete pages with backspace. This plus the edit toolbar solves 90% of my PDF munging needs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can select multiple images in Finder and drag them onto the Preview dock icon to open them in one window with a Sidebar where you can quickly flip between them with arrow keys.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the Dock preferences there’s a “Prefer tabs when opening documents” setting which automatically groups your windows with window tabs. I find this especially useful for Sublime Text.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;cmd+backtick&lt;/code&gt; is like &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;cmd+tab&lt;/code&gt; but between windows of the same app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drag your most frequently used folders into the Finder sidebar for easy access including in file select dialogs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the Finder preferences you can add your computer and drives to the sidebar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;cmd+shift+4&lt;/code&gt; pops up a crosshair to take a screenshot of a region.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.defaults-write.com/disable-press-and-hold-option-in-mac-os-x-10-7/&quot;&gt;disable the popup for accented characters when you hold a key&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://apple.stackexchange.com/questions/10467/how-to-increase-keyboard-key-repeat-rate-on-os-x&quot;&gt;increase key repeat rate beyond the normal maximum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;open&lt;/code&gt; command lets you use the normal macOS file opening mechanism from the command line, I most frequently use &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;open .&lt;/code&gt; to navigate to my current directory in my file browser.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Display “scales” other than 1x or 2x the physical resolution work by rendering at 2x the resolution then down-scaling. This causes apps to need to render a bunch of pixels that are mostly scaled away, consuming power and sometimes causing lag. It can also lead to weird aliasing issues in some contexts like shimmering of thin fonts when scrolling, as well as rendering in general not being pixel-perfect. I recommend trying to stick to either 1x or 2x scaling if you don’t lose much from it, then just adjusting your default web page scale and font sizes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Text fields &lt;a href=&quot;https://jblevins.org/log/kbd&quot;&gt;support a bunch of powerful movement and editing shortcuts based on Emacs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;option+2&lt;/code&gt; types the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;™&lt;/code&gt; symbol, for use with sarcasm™. I probably use this more than the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;^&lt;/code&gt; symbol. You can open the keyboard viewer (you may have to enable “Show keyboard and emoji viewers in menu bar” in Keyboard Preferences) and hold down option to see all the other symbols you can type like this. The “Emoji &amp;amp; Symbols” pallete is also a great UI for finding handy Unicode characters, especially if you use the gear menu to add more symbol category pages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;apps&quot;&gt;Apps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A big part of why I prefer macOS is this list of macOS-only native apps which often don’t have adequate substitutes on Linux:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://kapeli.com/dash&quot;&gt;Dash&lt;/a&gt;: An amazing fast offline documentation search app. Cuts down a ton on the amount I Google for docs. It’s very quick to use especially when summoned with a keyboard shortcut and has tons of documentation sets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hammerspoon.org/&quot;&gt;Hammerspoon&lt;/a&gt;: My favorite app for getting the benefits of a Linux tiling window manager. I have home row shortcuts on my left hand bound to switch directly to my most frequently used apps, and my right hand to maximize windows, move them between screens and tile them to the left and right halves of the screen. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/trishume/dotfiles/blob/d12f869062b2fa2d4b3f72eeed2f0e05df5a8657/hammerspoon/hammerspoon.symlink/init.lua&quot;&gt;Here’s my config.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thnkdev.com/Screenie/&quot;&gt;Screenie&lt;/a&gt;: I only use this for the feature where dragging from the menu bar icon lets you put your most recent screenshot in say messaging apps. It also offers search and things. &lt;a href=&quot;https://cleanshot.com/&quot;&gt;CleanShot X&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://zapier.com/zappy&quot;&gt;Zappy&lt;/a&gt; also look like good screenshot apps but I haven’t tried them yet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://karabiner-elements.pqrs.org/&quot;&gt;Karabiner Elements&lt;/a&gt;: A powerful keyboard remapping tool. I use it to bind right command to control and caps lock to &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ctrl+cmd+option+shift&lt;/code&gt; for use with Hammerspoon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.alfredapp.com/&quot;&gt;Alfred&lt;/a&gt;: A mildly better spotlight alternative, but for me the main benefit over spotlight is &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/deanishe/alfred-repos&quot;&gt;this workflow for indexing git repos&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cocoatech.com/#/&quot;&gt;Path Finder&lt;/a&gt;: A fancier version of Finder with multiple panes and various other advanced features. Other third party file managers you may want to try include &lt;a href=&quot;https://binarynights.com/&quot;&gt;Forklift&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://mac.eltima.com/file-manager.html&quot;&gt;Commander One&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://magnumbytes.com/&quot;&gt;Nimble Commander&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://marta.yanex.org/&quot;&gt;Marta&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://fman.io/&quot;&gt;fman&lt;/a&gt;. I use Path Finder because it’s the only one with a good columns view and that’s my favorite view for browsing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sparkmailapp.com/&quot;&gt;Spark&lt;/a&gt;: A nice email app with categorized inbox functionality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bjango.com/mac/istatmenus/&quot;&gt;iStat Menus&lt;/a&gt;: All sorts of system monitoring in a menu bar. I really like the weather, and I also have a combined menu which shows my current power draw in watts and GPU selection in the icon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tapbots.com/tweetbot/mac/&quot;&gt;Tweetbot&lt;/a&gt;: A native Twitter client that syncs with a similar IOS client. I really like how it just keeps your position in an infinite scroll where new tweets get added to the top, so I can easily read every new tweet from people I follow without seeing any likes, algorithmic suggestions or ads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ridiculousfish/HexFiend/&quot;&gt;Hex Fiend&lt;/a&gt;: A really good hex editor/viewer. I like their “Templates” feature where you can describe a binary format with a script and it will overlay the parse tree on the hex view.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iterm2.com/&quot;&gt;iTerm2&lt;/a&gt;: An alternative Terminal with just &lt;em&gt;so many features&lt;/em&gt;. I particularly like the ability to split windows into panes, which Apple’s Terminal does not have.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brettterpstra.com/projects/nvalt/&quot;&gt;nvAlt&lt;/a&gt;: A note taking app that I like, although it’s kinda bare-bones and has some bugs. It’s currently unmaintained because the author is working on &lt;a href=&quot;https://nvultra.com/&quot;&gt;nvUltra&lt;/a&gt; which isn’t released yet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://imageoptim.com/mac&quot;&gt;ImageOptim&lt;/a&gt;: Easy app where you drag image files onto it and it reduces their size.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vmware.com/products/fusion.html&quot;&gt;VMWare Fusion&lt;/a&gt;: Great for running Linux and Windows VMs. The reason I chose it over &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.parallels.com/products/desktop/pro/&quot;&gt;Parallels&lt;/a&gt; is that I knew it had virtualized PMC support, which enables using &lt;a href=&quot;https://rr-project.org/&quot;&gt;rr&lt;/a&gt; in VMs. But apparently Parallels also has this in the Pro version, and it might be nicer in other ways, not sure which is better.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://calca.io/&quot;&gt;Calca&lt;/a&gt;: A weird live math calculator notebook thing with units. The editing can be kind of glitchy but the basic functionality is really cool. &lt;a href=&quot;https://soulver.app/&quot;&gt;Soulver&lt;/a&gt; is a similar but more expensive app with a nicer UI but less powerful underlying calculator language.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/download/more/&quot;&gt;Quartz Debug&lt;/a&gt;: There are some apps that reduce your battery life in an insidious way where it doesn’t show as CPU usage for their process but as increased &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;WindowServer&lt;/code&gt; CPU usage. If your &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;WindowServer&lt;/code&gt; process CPU usage is above maybe 6-10% when you’re not doing anything, some app in the background is probably spamming 60fps animation updates. As far as I know you can only figure out which app is at fault by getting the Quartz Debug app from &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/download/more/&quot;&gt;Apple’s additional developer tools&lt;/a&gt;, enabling flash screen updates (and no delay after flash), then going to the overview mode (four finger swipe up) and looking for flashing. This same problem can also occur on Linux and Windows but I don’t know how much power it saps there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sublimetext.com/&quot;&gt;Sublime Text&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sublimemerge.com/&quot;&gt;Merge&lt;/a&gt;: These aren’t exactly macOS-only apps but they’re some of my favorite apps and they integrate excellently with macOS so I’m putting them here anyways.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;bonus-browsers&quot;&gt;Bonus: Browsers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Middle click opens links in a new tab and middle clicking on a tab closes it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There’s lots of lesser-known handy shortcuts: cmd/ctrl+l focuses the search filed, cmd/ctrl+w closes a tab&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://vimium.github.io/&quot;&gt;Vimium&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.octotree.io/&quot;&gt;OctoTree&lt;/a&gt; are my favorite browser extensions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I believe YouTube in Chrome and Firefox default to VP8/9 video codecs which can’t be hardware-decoded so use lots of CPU and thus battery power especially at 2x speed or high resolutions. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/alextrv/enhanced-h264ify&quot;&gt;h264ify&lt;/a&gt; family of extensions can force usage of GPU-supported h264 codecs. This can close some of the battery life gap with Safari.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you use Safari, Chrome and Firefox have much better sounding audio resampling for watching videos on 1.5x or 2x speed. This is the only reason I don’t use Safari.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;bonus-ios&quot;&gt;Bonus: IOS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IOS also has a bunch of hidden UI features, especially if you have a medium-old model of iPhone that still has force touch sensors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Swiping left and right on the home bar at the bottom of the screen on phones since the iPhone X quickly switches between recent apps. This is absolutely essential to how I use my phone and such a huge boost to multitasking fluidity I feel bad for all the people who don’t know about it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Force or long pressing on the keyboard (maybe just the spacebar on some phones), brings up a moveable cursor in text fields.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you have force touch try it on everything, tons of widgets in the pull down settings have force touch features, notifications do, links do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I’ve tried a lot of calculator apps and Kalkyl is my favorite for launch time and UI design for quick simple calculations. I also recommend Unread for RSS, and Apollo as possibly the best Reddit experience on any platform.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://isitsnappy.com/&quot;&gt;Is It Snappy&lt;/a&gt; lets you use an IOS device’s high speed camera to measure full-system interaction latency and find out that you have a slow keyboard, mouse or monitor. I have not found a similar app for Android.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not exactly a software tip, but a non-obvious purchasing option: I contend buying an iPhone X on Ebay offers outstanding price/quality ratio even in 2020. It has basically the same screen/form factor/build quality as an iPhone 11 Pro, and I find it plenty fast and the camera sufficiently good, and those are basically the only things that improved. You even get force touch, which I really like as having lower latency than the more press-and-hold “3D Touch”. Meanwhile it’s less than half the price. I got mine discounted after the iPhone XS replaced it, and if mine broke I’d probably just buy another one now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;bonus-the-chromium-catapult-trace-viewer&quot;&gt;Bonus: The Chromium Catapult Trace Viewer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The motivation to write this post was caused by a conversation with a friend about macOS, which was in turn kicked off by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/trishume/status/1302069073640120320?s=20&quot;&gt;a tweet&lt;/a&gt; about the &lt;a href=&quot;https://aras-p.info/blog/2017/01/23/Chrome-Tracing-as-Profiler-Frontend/&quot;&gt;The Chromium Trace Viewer (AKA Catapult)&lt;/a&gt;. Catapult is super easy to get started with for visualizing trace data and I know lots of different people and projects who use it. Almost none of them know about this incredibly helpful first tip until I tell it to them, so they’re stuck with having to switch to the zoom tool in the toolbar:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Use &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;alt+scroll&lt;/code&gt; to zoom. This really ought to be in noticeable text on their UI not buried in a shortcuts pane you have to press &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;?&lt;/code&gt; to see.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The search bar in the top left searches not only names but also arguments values, which you can use to search for IDs or add special tags like &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;top100&lt;/code&gt; for the 100 slowest events. Press &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;f&lt;/code&gt; to zoom to a span once you’ve selected it with the search arrow buttons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The JSON event format also supports “flow” arrows, which lets you draw arrows between your boxes to visualize dependencies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://perfetto.dev/&quot;&gt;Perfetto&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/wolfpld/tracy&quot;&gt;Tracy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.speedscope.app/&quot;&gt;Speedscope&lt;/a&gt; can all visualize the same JSON format with different UIs and potentially without a trace size cap.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 15:15:08 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>trishume</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://thume.ca/2020/09/04/macos-tips/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Hong Kong mourns the end of its way of life</title>
<link>https://www.nationalgeographic.com/history/2020/09/hong-kong-mourns-way-life-china-cracks-down-dissent/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nationalgeographic.com/history/2020/09/hong-kong-mourns-way-life-china-cracks-down-dissent/</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nationalgeographic.com/history/2020/09/hong-kong-mourns-way-life-china-cracks-down-dissent/&quot;&gt;https://www.nationalgeographic.com/history/2020/09/hong-kong-mourns-way-life-china-cracks-down-dissent/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24391716&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24391716&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 293&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 226&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 14:51:01 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>frrp</dc:creator>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nationalgeographic.com/history/2020/09/hong-kong-mourns-way-life-china-cracks-down-dissent/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Attention is your scarcest resource</title>
<link>https://www.benkuhn.net/attention/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.benkuhn.net/attention/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Like many people, I have most of my best ideas in the shower.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is sometimes annoying: I could use more than one shower’s worth of good ideas a day, but I’d rather not end up as a shrivelled yet insightful prune. Mostly, though, shower ideas are the incentive that keeps me smelling okay, so I grudgingly accept the constraint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The time when it was most constraining was the first time I became a manager. I only had a few reports, so managing them wasn’t a full-time job. But I was very bad at it, and so it &lt;em&gt;should have&lt;/em&gt; been what I spent all my shower insights on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I was spending my non-management time on programming. And even if I tried to use my showers to think about my thorny and awkward people issues, my mind somehow always wandered off to tackle those nice, juicy software design problems instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Management Attempt #1 didn’t go very well; being distracted by programming, I made lots of embarrassing mistakes that made my reports’ lives harder, which in turn made me feel stressed and guilty. I ended up bouncing back to being an individual contributor after a few months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That experience of mine resonates strongly with Byrne Hobart’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://diff.substack.com/p/the-future-of-remote-work-is-not&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;observation about focus in knowledge work&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The output of knowledge workers is extremely skewed based on focus. The productivity tiers seem to be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol readability=&quot;1.5&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;10% focused on the job at hand: meaningful risk of getting fired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10-50% focus: “meets expectations,” gets regular raises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;50%+ focus: superstar, 10x engineer, destined for greatness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“50%+ focus” is roughly when something becomes &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.paulgraham.com/top.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the top idea in your mind&lt;/a&gt;. It’s when you start caring enough to think about it in the shower. It’s when you start habitually asking “how could this go faster?” It’s when you get &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.paulgraham.com/relres.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;relentlessly resourceful&lt;/a&gt;. It’s around when you start &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.benkuhn.net/impatient/&quot;&gt;annoying your coworkers and/or significant other&lt;/a&gt;, although that part is avoidable with practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most importantly, you can only be 50%+-focused on one thing at a time—or zero, in bad cases. That makes it critical to conserve your attention, so that you can spend it on what matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve found a few different strategies that help me with this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;care-viscerally&quot;&gt;Care viscerally&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to recruit 50%+ of your brain to work on something just because you feel like you “should” do it. Your superego might listen to this newfangled “logic” and “reason” stuff, but the monkey-era parts of your brain can’t be fooled so easily. To be reliably able to focus on something, you need to be intuitively, emotionally invested in the outcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, that’s not automatic—for instance, even though &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.benkuhn.net/work/&quot;&gt;I’m incredibly excited about what Wave is doing&lt;/a&gt;, my day-to-day motivation gets worse if I work remotely for too long without visiting our operations in Senegal. Unless I can periodically see for myself that people are using the things we’re building, it starts feeling a little bit fake, like the so-called “real world” is a simulation that I can only communicate with via Slack channels and &lt;code&gt;git push&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;monotask&quot;&gt;Monotask&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a programmer, I tried to make sure that I was only ever working on one thing at a time. Even if I got stuck on that one thing—say I was blocked on waiting for a tech partner to give me API documentation—I’d let myself stay stuck instead of sliding off to work on something else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the short term, this made me less efficient, because I’d spend less time programming and more time staring vacantly at the ceiling. But if I stared vacantly for long enough, I’d eventually get mad enough to, e.g., reverse-engineer the partner’s API in a fit of rage. This resulted in me shipping my most important projects faster, hence getting &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.benkuhn.net/impatient/#startups&quot;&gt;faster compounding growth&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;evade-obligations&quot;&gt;Evade obligations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a manager, it became impossible to “only work on one thing:” there were too many small tasks and too many projects going on in parallel. But I have a similar principle: I can only have one &lt;em&gt;obligation to other people&lt;/em&gt;. “Give advice on this project?” Whenever you want! “Review my 1,000-line change?” Only if review isn’t blocking you from shipping it. “Check in every so often to make sure this doesn’t go off the rails?” Sorry, I have to, uh, powder my nose. “Figure out what the process should be?” I’ll get back to you in a couple years. (The best process is no process, right?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During Management Attempt #1, my programming project distracted me so much because other people cared a lot that I finished it—if I ever had to de-prioritize it, I would make those people sad. This made it take up my attention (by worrying about letting people down) even when I wasn’t working on it. Unfortunately, since management work comes in urgent bursts, I’d often end up in a situation where I had to delay either the programming or the management—i.e., choose between making two different sets of people sad—and in those cases it was very hard for me to control my focus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I’ve noticed this, I allow myself to contribute to multiple things in parallel, as long as they don’t tax my object permanence skills—if I totally forgot about this project today, would anything bad happen? As long as the answer is no (usually because someone else is the one taking initiative to move things forward), I can be pretty sure that project won’t try to colonize my brain in the shower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;timebox-bullshit&quot;&gt;Timebox bullshit&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if I have only one major project that other people depend on, I somehow always end up with a bunch of minor chores to do—responding to emails, deflecting secondary obligations, buying household necessities, powdering my nose, filing expense reports, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For these, I employ a “bullshit timebox”—a one-hour period a few times a week when I do &lt;a href=&quot;http://paulgraham.com/vb.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;all the things life is too short for&lt;/a&gt;. During the remaining 165 hours per week, I do my resolute best not to think about any of the bullshit, no matter how much people bug me about whether a &lt;a href=&quot;https://thume.ca/2019/03/03/my-tungsten-cube/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;1.5” tungsten cube&lt;/a&gt; is really a legitimate work expense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order for bullshit not to distract me for the rest of the week, I try to minimize my number of “open loops”—projects or processes that I’ve started but not completed. Much like how I single-task on programming until it’s done, I’ll make phone calls instead of email threads, or, God forbid, texts or instant messaging. It took a while for me to train my friends not to instant message me, but by now they remember my rants about how distracting it is, practically word-for-word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Management Attempt #2 didn’t go great for me either. But I finally did an okay job at Management Attempt #3. Part of this was because I avoided repeating the particular mistakes of Attempts #1 and #2. But part of it was that on Attempt #3, our engineering team grew quickly enough that I went from “no managing” straight to “full-time managing” with no transitional period in which to be distracted, screw up and be miserable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I was full-time managing, I had no shiny distractions and was able to spend my showers focusing on how to be a better manager. And once I was 50%+ focused, well, I haven’t become a “superstar 10x manager” yet, but I quickly stopped being 0.1x.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 14:46:18 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>adambyrtek</dc:creator>
<og:title>Attention is your scarcest resource</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.benkuhn.net/attention/</og:url>
<og:description>how to ration your shower thoughts • care viscerally • monotask • evade obligations • timebox bullshit</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.benkuhn.net/attention/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Common color mistakes and how to avoid them</title>
<link>https://blog.datawrapper.de/beautifulcolors/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.datawrapper.de/beautifulcolors/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;wide&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==&quot; alt=&quot;header image&quot; class=&quot;b-lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/img/full-200805_goodcolors34.png&quot; data-src-thumb=&quot;/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors34.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choosing good colors for your charts is hard. This article tries to make it easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want you to feel more confident in your color choices. And if you have no sense for colors at all, here’s my attempt to help you find good ones anyway. We’ll talk about common color mistakes I see out there in the wild, and how to avoid them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not the right article for you if you’re trying to find good gradients or shades. But if you need to find beautiful, distinctive colors for different &lt;strong&gt;categories (e.g. continents, industries, bird species)&lt;/strong&gt; for your line charts, pie charts, stacked bar charts, etc., read on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==&quot; alt=&quot;different data visualizations&quot; class=&quot;b-lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/img/full-200805_goodcolors-f.png&quot; data-src-thumb=&quot;/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors-f.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Visualized categories by &lt;a href=&quot;https://fivethirtyeight.com/features/the-56-best-and-weirdest-charts-we-made-in-2019/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;FiveThirtyEight&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://whydocatsanddogs.com/cats&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Nadieh Bremer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://congress.pudding.cool/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;The Pudding&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2019/10/14/us/politics/democrats-political-facebook-ads.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;New York Times&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://infographics.economist.com/2019/AChristmasGiftForYou/AYearInGraphicDetail.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;The Economist&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/accurat-studio/beautiful-reasons-c1c6926ab7d7&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Akkurat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;Index&quot;&gt;Index&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.datawrapper.de/beautifulcolors/#0&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;00&lt;/strong&gt; Before we start…&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.datawrapper.de/beautifulcolors/#1&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01&lt;/strong&gt; Broaden your understanding of colors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.datawrapper.de/beautifulcolors/#2&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t dance all over the color wheel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.datawrapper.de/beautifulcolors/#3&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03&lt;/strong&gt; Use saturation and lightness to make your hues work&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.datawrapper.de/beautifulcolors/#4&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04&lt;/strong&gt; Use warm colors &amp;amp; blue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.datawrapper.de/beautifulcolors/#5&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05&lt;/strong&gt; When using green, make it a yellow or blue one&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.datawrapper.de/beautifulcolors/#6&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06&lt;/strong&gt; Avoid pure colors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.datawrapper.de/beautifulcolors/#7&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07&lt;/strong&gt; Avoid bright, saturated colors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.datawrapper.de/beautifulcolors/#8&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08&lt;/strong&gt; Combine colors with different lightness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.datawrapper.de/beautifulcolors/#9&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09&lt;/strong&gt; Make your colors similarly “colorful”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.datawrapper.de/beautifulcolors/#10&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10&lt;/strong&gt; Avoid too little contrast to the background&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.datawrapper.de/beautifulcolors/#11&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11&lt;/strong&gt; Avoid too much contrast to the background&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.datawrapper.de/beautifulcolors/#12&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12&lt;/strong&gt; Choose a background that’s desaturated enough&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.datawrapper.de/beautifulcolors/#13&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;13&lt;/strong&gt; Copy colors, or understand them&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;Before-we-start…&quot;&gt;Before we start…&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will mention saturation, brightness and hue a lot. The HSB (&lt;strong&gt;H&lt;/strong&gt;ue, &lt;strong&gt;S&lt;/strong&gt;aturation, &lt;strong&gt;B&lt;/strong&gt;rightness) or HSV (&lt;strong&gt;H&lt;/strong&gt;ue, &lt;strong&gt;S&lt;/strong&gt;aturation, &lt;strong&gt;V&lt;/strong&gt;alue) color spaces work fairly well to check them:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hue&lt;/strong&gt; ranges from 0° to 360°…that’s your typical color wheel: &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Saturation&lt;/strong&gt; ranges from 0% (grey) to 100% (super duper colorful!!): &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brightness/Value&lt;/strong&gt; ranges from 0% (black) to 100% (the actual color): &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;To convert your colors from HEX (e.g. &lt;code&gt;#cc0000&lt;/code&gt;) or RGB (e.g. &lt;code&gt;rgb(207, 176, 58)&lt;/code&gt;) to HSB/HSV, use a tool like &lt;a href=&quot;http://colorizer.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;colorizer.org&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A relative of HSB/HSV is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HCL_color_space&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;HCL&lt;/a&gt; color space. It uses the same parameters (&lt;strong&gt;H&lt;/strong&gt;ue, &lt;strong&gt;C&lt;/strong&gt;hroma = saturation, &lt;strong&gt;L&lt;/strong&gt;ightness), but is closer to “how we really see colors”. &lt;a href=&quot;https://academy.datawrapper.de/article/255-how-to-pick-colors-in-datawrapper&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Datawrapper&lt;/strong&gt; uses the HCL color space&lt;/a&gt; for its color picker:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==&quot; alt=&quot;HCL color picker in Datawrapper&quot; class=&quot;b-lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/img/full-200805_goodcolors31.png&quot; data-src-thumb=&quot;/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors31.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But since you won’t find HCL in Adobe Photoshop or &lt;a href=&quot;http://colorizer.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;colorizer.org&lt;/a&gt;, every time I mention degrees (like 0°) or percentages, I’ll be talking about the HSB/HSV color space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alright, let’s do this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;Broaden-your-understanding-of-colors&quot;&gt;Broaden your understanding of colors&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;b-lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/img/full-200805_goodcolors30.png&quot; data-src-thumb=&quot;/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors30.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might think like this: “I need five colors for my chart. So I use green and yellow and blue and red. And …um…maybe orange? Or purple!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t thought much about colors since you were a kid coloring out your coloring book, this thought makes sense. So today I’m here to tell you: They are more colors than that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look at this graphic and compare them with the basic colors &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;b-lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/img/full-200805_goodcolors13.png&quot; data-src-thumb=&quot;/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors13.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://whydocatsanddogs.com/cats&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Why do Cats and Dogs?&lt;/a&gt; by Nadieh Bremer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They’re different. The red that Nadieh uses &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt; is different from your typical red &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;. The green &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt; is…can you even call it a green &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So before we impose rules that limit us, let me freak you out a bit: There are thousands of colors you can use. There is yellow-ish red &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt; and blue-ish red &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt; and everything in between. There is grey &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;, but there is also cold grey &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt; and there is warm grey &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;. And then there is blue. So much blue! Like this &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;, this &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;, this &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;, this &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt; and this &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;. And we haven’t even talked about orange and yellow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have &lt;em&gt;lots&lt;/em&gt; of options. Which means you can stay in a small area of the color wheel and still have many options. Which means:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;Don’t-dance-all-over-the-color-wheel&quot;&gt;Don’t dance all over the color wheel&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;b-lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/img/full-200805_goodcolors28.png&quot; data-src-thumb=&quot;/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors28.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s no need to rely on hues from all around the color wheel like &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt; for your visualizations. It will look more professional – and therefore more trustworthy – when it only uses a few hues and their neighbors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s where it becomes a good idea to actually look at a color wheel. You can use &lt;a href=&quot;https://color.adobe.com/create/color-wheel&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Adobe Color&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sessions.edu/color-calculator/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Color Calculator&lt;/a&gt; to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;b-lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/img/full-200805_goodcolors21.png&quot; data-src-thumb=&quot;/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors21.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sessions.edu/color-calculator/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Color Calculator&lt;/a&gt; harmonies&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lots of these tools let you choose different harmonies. One of them is called “square” or “tetradic”. &lt;strong&gt;Don’t use it.&lt;/strong&gt; It will result in too many hues – and we’re on a mission to avoid that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the video above, I used the color tool &lt;a href=&quot;https://paletton.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Paletton&lt;/a&gt; to start with a tetradic harmony and then decrease the distance. Note how more beautiful the color combinations become.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the distance becomes small enough, you’re basically using &lt;strong&gt;complementary&lt;/strong&gt; colors. And that’s a great choice! Lots of complementary color pairs work awesome together. &lt;strong&gt;If in doubt, use complementary colors and their neighbors.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let’s do this – this time with Adobe Color:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;b-lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/img/full-200805_goodcolors22.png&quot; data-src-thumb=&quot;/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors22.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Our complementary colors in &lt;a href=&quot;https://color.adobe.com/create/color-wheel&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Adobe Color&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our colors are opposite each other on the color wheel, so they’re clearly complementary. Yay! But they’re also unusable: The two oranges are way too similar. And everything looks so…bright.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s where we need to change the saturation and lightness:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;Use-saturation-and-lightness-to-make-your-hues-work&quot;&gt;Use saturation and lightness to make your hues work&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;b-lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/img/full-200805_goodcolors27.png&quot; data-src-thumb=&quot;/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors27.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saturation and brightness are as important as hue. In fact, you can create new colors when you just change the saturation and brightness. Here are two color pairs with the same hue, just different saturation and lightness: &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt; / &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;. (If you change the hue just a tiny bit, you’ll achieve even better results: &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt; / &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s come back to our color combination: &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;. After playing around with the saturation and darkness, it becomes this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;b-lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/img/full-200805_goodcolors23.png&quot; data-src-thumb=&quot;/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors23.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Our better (!) complementary colors in &lt;a href=&quot;https://color.adobe.com/create/color-wheel&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Adobe Color&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I desaturated the light blue &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt; and the lighter orange &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt; and made every color darker except the lighter orange. Heck yeah, we can work with that!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if your color combination doesn’t look awesome yet, don’t immediately add another hue. &lt;strong&gt;Change the saturation and lightness first and see if that’s better.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s what I did to all of these color palettes: &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;. They’re all roughly complementary, and they all come with different saturations and lightness. That’s what makes them work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;Use-warm-colors-blue&quot;&gt;Use warm colors &amp;amp; blue&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;b-lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/img/full-200805_goodcolors29.png&quot; data-src-thumb=&quot;/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors29.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a complementary color combination that is especially loved by data visualization designers: &lt;strong&gt;yellow/orange/red and blue&lt;/strong&gt;. Scroll through graphics portfolios like the one from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://multimedia.scmp.com/culture/article/SCMP-printed-graphics-memory/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;South China Morning Post&lt;/a&gt; or this one by &lt;a href=&quot;https://infographics.economist.com/2019/AChristmasGiftForYou/AYearInGraphicDetail.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;The Economist (PDF)&lt;/a&gt; and you’ll notice that they use these colors far more often than colors like purple or green.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;b-lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/img/full-200805_goodcolors19.png&quot; data-src-thumb=&quot;/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors19.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://multimedia.scmp.com/culture/article/SCMP-printed-graphics-memory/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Three pages by The South China Morning Post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s because these warm colors and blue are super versatile for categories. Yellow and orange and red look very pleasing together, but people will still perceive them as different colors: &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt; – which is exactly what we want for categorical colors. And blue is more flexible than any other hue: Lots of blues, no matter if dark &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt; or light &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt; or saturated &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt; or not saturated &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;, look pleasing, calming and professional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And they are accessible: colorblind people can easily distinguish blue and orange/red from each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if in doubt, use an orange/red with blue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;When-using-green-make-it-a-yellow-or-blue-one&quot;&gt;When using green, make it a yellow or blue one&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;b-lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/img/full-200805_goodcolors26.png&quot; data-src-thumb=&quot;/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors26.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forest green covers a full sixth on the color wheel, from approximately 90° &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt; to 150° &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;, with 120° as its peak &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;. However, you will find few well-designed visualizations that use it. Why is that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, forest green is just very dark. And lightening up the forest green means going into an awkward neon &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;. So you need to lighten up &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; desaturate green enormously – more than other colors – to get to a nice one. That’s exactly what the Washington Post does with their green &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt; here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;b-lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/img/full-200805_goodcolors17.png&quot; data-src-thumb=&quot;/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors17.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/graphics/politics/trump-rolling-back-obama-rules/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;How Trump is rolling back Obama’s legacy&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a 142° green, but only 14% saturated. Here’s what the same hue with the same brightness would look like 100% saturated: &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;. Yikes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And remember our colorblind friends: A pure green in combination with red, orange or brown is hard for them to distinguish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So when using green, make it a bit yellow or a bit blue. You can see this in the examples at the top of this article: All of the greens except FiveThirtyEight’s one &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt; have a hue greater than 160° (=bluer) &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt; or lower than 60° (=more yellow) &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;. Nadieh uses both yellow green and blue green in this project we’ve already seen:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;b-lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/img/full-200805_goodcolors13.png&quot; data-src-thumb=&quot;/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors13.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://whydocatsanddogs.com/cats&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Why do Cats and Dogs?&lt;/a&gt; by Nadieh Bremer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looks like you can use them in your visualization as two different colors as Nadieh does: Win-win!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;Avoid-pure-colors&quot;&gt;Avoid pure colors&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;b-lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/img/full-200805_goodcolors5.png&quot; data-src-thumb=&quot;/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors5.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Pure” hues are the ones that are located at exactly 60°, 120°, 180°, 240°, 300° or 360°/0° in the color wheel:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;b-lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/img/full-200805_goodcolors7.png&quot; data-src-thumb=&quot;/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors7.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s an example: In HSV/HSB, the &lt;strong&gt;H&lt;/strong&gt;ue value of this bright blue &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt; is 180°, the &lt;strong&gt;S&lt;/strong&gt;aturation value is 67% and the &lt;strong&gt;L&lt;/strong&gt;ightness value is 91%. You can also check the RGB values of your color: If at least two of the values are the same, they’re “pure”. For example, our &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt; is a &lt;code&gt;rgb(77, 232, 232)&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make your colors look more natural and pleasing to the eyes of your readers, you can either tune down the saturation of pure colors or make them darker. &lt;strong&gt;If you want to have bright, saturated colors, rely on mixed colors&lt;/strong&gt; that are at least 5-10° away from the pure colors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the image above, the red and orange, the blues and the greens have the same saturation and lightness. The only difference is the hue: The red &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt; (0°), blue &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt; (240°) and green &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt; (120°) look more colorful than the orange &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt; (40°), medium blue &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt; (211°) and blue-ish green &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt; (170°).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;Avoid-bright-saturated-colors&quot;&gt;Avoid bright, saturated colors&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;b-lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/img/full-200805_goodcolors4.png&quot; data-src-thumb=&quot;/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors4.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neon colors will definitely attract the attention of readers. But these readers won’t thank you. Most of us get a bit stressed out when we see them: “Highly saturated, light colors will NOT be appropriate [to communicate] Serious or Trust, or Calm,” as Bartram, Patra &amp;amp; Stone explain in their paper “Affective Color in Visualization” from 2017 (&lt;a href=&quot;https://research.tableau.com/sites/default/files/Affective%20Color%20CHI%202017.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your colors come close to 100% saturation &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; 100% brightness, it’s likely your colors are too colorful. That’s definitely the case for pure colors like &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“But I’ve seen such crazy colors before, and they look good,” you might say, and refer to projects like these ones:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you compare the colors from these examples with colors like &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;, you see how they former ones are all less saturated or darker. A 100% saturated and 100% bright green &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt; becomes less saturated in the New York Times &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;, and less saturated &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; darker in both the Bloomberg article &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt; and the Pudding article &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They have the same fun, attention-grabbing effect as neon colors have, while being easier on the eye.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This works more or less because the people at The Pudding, The New York Times and Bloomberg are great designers. &lt;strong&gt;If in doubt, avoid 100% saturation combined with 100% lightness.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;Combine-colors-with-different-lightness&quot;&gt;Combine colors with different lightness&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;b-lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/img/full-200805_goodcolors11.png&quot; data-src-thumb=&quot;/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors11.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I sometimes see charts – especially area charts – where neighboring elements have the same lightness. You can easily check this: Just convert your colors in black &amp;amp; white (e.g. with an external colorblind simulator or with our &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Datawrapper/status/1298293123584536578&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Datawrapper colorblind check&lt;/a&gt;). If they all have the same grey, they’re the same lightness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, the &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt; from the far left chart look like &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt; in greyscale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To avoid that dull and eye-hurting experience, you have two options:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;“Get it right in black &amp;amp; white”: change the darkness of each area, making some brighter and some darker, like so: &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;. They look like this in greyscale: &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Separate the areas, e.g. with a white border&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;I highly recommend the first option (you can still put a white border around it if you like the style): The colors will look more dynamic, and colorblind people will thank you. Actually, everyone will thank you, regardless of their color-seeing abilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, a valid way to pick colors for categorical data is to pick colors from gradients like these ones:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==&quot; alt=&quot;viridis gradients&quot; class=&quot;b-lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/img/full-200630_colorblind3.png&quot; data-src-thumb=&quot;/img/thumb-200630_colorblind3.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bids.github.io/colormap/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Viridis&lt;/a&gt; color schemes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All these gradients move smoothly from light to dark, so colors you pick from there will all have a different lightness: &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt; or &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;. Try this &lt;a href=&quot;https://learnui.design/tools/data-color-picker.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Color Palette Generator&lt;/a&gt; if you’re a fan of this approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;Make-your-colors-similarly-“colorful”&quot;&gt;Make your colors similarly “colorful”&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;b-lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/img/full-200805_goodcolors32.png&quot; data-src-thumb=&quot;/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors32.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your visualizations, you often want colors to stand out. There are different ways to achieve that. Colors stand out:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;because they’re way darker &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;because they’re way lighter &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;because they’re more saturated &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;because they’re more “pure” &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;But you usually just want one or two colors to stand out. Most of your colors are supposed to be &lt;strong&gt;more or less equally attention-grabbing&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re using colors with different lightness (“Get it right in black &amp;amp; white”), you’ll need to balance them out. &lt;strong&gt;Try to desaturate bright colors. Put more saturation in dark colors.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or choose a less pure hue: in the image above, the green &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt; and blue &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt; are very pure, so I darkened them (that’s how they look like with 100% brightness: &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then wanted to bring a red in…but the bright red would have been too intense as a pure hue (with 0°) &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;. So I had two options:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;simply darken it: &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;move the hue (and just the hue) to 30° to make it more orange &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;I chose the second option to make it look a bit more friendly. But both options work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;Avoid-too-little-contrast-to-the-background&quot;&gt;Avoid too little contrast to the background&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;b-lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/img/full-200805_goodcolors8.png&quot; data-src-thumb=&quot;/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors8.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A surprising number of charts on bright backgrounds use very pastel-ish colors. They’re often not very saturated, and awfully light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That comes with problems: If you work with small areas like lines and dots, light and desaturated colors can be hard to distinguish for your readers. But even if legibility is not an issue – e.g. for bigger areas – , your visualizations should have enough visual contrast to the background to confidently communicate: “Hey, I’m here, and I have something to say”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s what to do when your colors are too desaturated &amp;amp; light &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Increase the saturation: &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make them darker: &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Or do both for the best result: &lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;⬤&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of course, that’s also a matter of taste. But if you’re not sure if your colors are too pastel-ish, simply try to make them more saturated and darker. Just see how it feels. And if it feels good, keep it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;Avoid-too-much-contrast-to-the-background&quot;&gt;Avoid too much contrast to the background&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;b-lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/img/full-200805_goodcolors9.png&quot; data-src-thumb=&quot;/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors9.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The opposite is true, too: Don’t make your colors too dark and saturated when you’re using a bright background. If in doubt, try it out. Make your colors lighter, pull some saturation out of them and see how it feels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;Choose-a-background-that’s-desaturated-enough&quot;&gt;Choose a background that’s desaturated enough&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;b-lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/img/full-200805_goodcolors10.png&quot; data-src-thumb=&quot;/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors10.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you become more confident with colors, colorful backgrounds can seem like a good idea. But they come with two big drawbacks: First, they easily distract from your data. Second, they’re extremely limiting your potential color palette and are therefore hard to work with. In fact, the more saturated your background, the harder it gets – so desaturated colors are your best bet. Here are some rules of thumbs for the HSB/HSV color space:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;If you want a light background, stay away from colors below 95% lightness and above 7% saturation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you want a dark background, stay below 20% saturation. Also, &lt;a href=&quot;https://ianstormtaylor.com/design-tip-never-use-black/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;don’t go full black&lt;/a&gt; – keep your lightness between 10% and 25%.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;Copy-colors-or-understand-them&quot;&gt;Copy colors or understand them&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Picking good colors is hard. It’s totally ok to be bad with colors, to keep being bad with colors and to just copy colors. Seriously, there’s no shame in stealing. &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.datawrapper.de/colorguide/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I wrote a whole article&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; about where to get inspiration for colors: From movies, artists, color palettes others have created, etc. (And may I add: Other data visualizations are an excellent source.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to build a better intuitive understanding of which colors fit well together, try this: Analyze them. Some ways to do that include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==&quot; alt=&quot;Photo of a tree&quot; class=&quot;b-lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/img/full-200805_goodcolors24.jpg&quot; data-src-thumb=&quot;/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors24.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@niko_photos&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;niko photos&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/s/photos/tree&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Select a picture with colors you consider beautiful, like an art piece or photo of nature. Then pick colors out of them with the eyedropper tool, e.g. with Photoshop or &lt;a href=&quot;https://image-color.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;image-color.com&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Try to use them in your next chart.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.adobe.com/products/capture.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adobe Capture&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which is the same idea but for “live images”: It lets you capture colors from your environment. (It’s fascinating to see how desaturated many colors are around us!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Play “manual color picker”: &lt;strong&gt;Look up your screen. Which colors do you see?&lt;/strong&gt; How dark and how saturated are there? Which hues are closeby; which one are opposite the color wheel?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pick colors from beautiful data visualizations. &lt;strong&gt;Change a few colors.&lt;/strong&gt; Do they still work well together?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also, the next time you’re creating a data visualization and you’re not happy with your colors, &lt;strong&gt;analyze them in the HSV/HSB color space&lt;/strong&gt;, e.g. with &lt;a href=&quot;http://colorizer.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;colorizer.org&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;How &lt;strong&gt;saturated&lt;/strong&gt; are they – and do they look better if you increase or decrease the saturation by a few (or a lot of) percentage points?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which &lt;strong&gt;hue&lt;/strong&gt; value do they have? What happens if you change the hue by just a few degrees?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are your colors differently &lt;strong&gt;bright&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;With time, your understanding will move from “that’s beautiful, but I don’t know why” to “that’s beautiful, because …”. And you’ll find that you can break more and more of these rules I explained here – and still create great color combinations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I hope this article was helpful! If you want to continue reading: There are quite some articles on this blog about color, e.g. about &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.datawrapper.de/gendercolor/&quot;&gt;colors for gender&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.datawrapper.de/partycolors/&quot;&gt;colors for political parties&lt;/a&gt;, colorblindness (&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.datawrapper.de/colorblindness-part1/&quot;&gt;part 1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.datawrapper.de/colorblindness-part2/&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.datawrapper.de/colorblindness-part3/&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;), and &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.datawrapper.de/colors/&quot;&gt;what to consider in general when using colors&lt;/a&gt; in your visualizations. If there’s a great trick this article is missing, let me know at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:lisa@datawrapper.de&quot;&gt;lisa@datawrapper.de&lt;/a&gt; or in the comments below.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 13:05:26 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>hunvreus</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>How to pick more beautiful colors for your data visualizations</og:title>
<og:url>https://blog.datawrapper.de/beautifulcolors/index.html</og:url>
<og:description>Choosing good colors for your charts is hard. This article tries to make it easier.</og:description>
<og:image>https://blog.datawrapper.de/img/200805_goodcolors34.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.datawrapper.de/beautifulcolors/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>&amp;#039;You&amp;#039;re Not Allowed to Film&amp;#039;: The Fight to Control Who Reports from Portland</title>
<link>https://reason.com/2020/09/04/youre-not-allowed-to-film-the-fight-for-control-over-who-reports-from-portland/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://reason.com/2020/09/04/youre-not-allowed-to-film-the-fight-for-control-over-who-reports-from-portland/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;YOU'RE NOT ALLOWED TO FILM!&quot; is a cry you hear incessantly at protests in Portland, Oregon, always shouted at close range to your face by after-dark demonstrators. You can assert that, yes, you&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;can&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;film; you can point out that they themselves are filming incessantly; you can push their hands away from covering your phone; you can have your phone record them stealing your phone—all of these things have happened to me—and none will have any impact on their contention that &quot;YOU'RE NOT ALLOWED TO FILM&quot; and its occasional variation, &quot;PHOTOGRAPHY EQUALS DEATH!&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I cannot say who came up with these anti-camera battle cries. But it's easy to understand why protesters use them: to shape the narrative the country sees about the protests. And that narrative, in my estimation after many weeks covering street clashes in a city where I lived for 15 years, is 90 percent bullshit.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I wondered, the first time I attended the protests at the federal building back in July, who all these young people with PRESS emblazoned on their jackets or helmets were. I asked one such guy who he worked for.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;Independent Press Corps,&quot; he told me. As it turned out, dozens of other young PRESS people happened to work for the same outfit, which I at first assumed was a fancy way of saying &quot;I want to report stuff and stream it on my Instagram.&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;This turned out to be naive. The IPC is an organized group in league with the activists, and it is usually their footage you see streamed online and recycled on the news: mostly innocent protestors being harassed and beaten by police.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The police indeed have tear-gassed and beaten people; there has been brutality. It is equally true, but featured less prominently in the news coverage, that activists spend hours every night menacing and setting fires to police stations and other institutions: City Hall, Immigration and Customs Enforcement headquarters, and last week Mayor Ted Wheeler's apartment building (until he agreed to move out). With the PRESS crew recording part of the story and the &quot;YOU'RE NOT ALLOWED TO FILM!&quot; crew harassing other journalists, the result can be a misleading view of the protests. It's a revolution via the cellphone video they allow you to see.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The IPC and other documentarians who are deemed sympathetic to the activists' cause agree on certain principles. You do not show activists' faces. You only show activists in a defensive position: responding to, rather than inciting, violence. You enhance what can appear to be police brutality, e.g., activists defending themselves with homemade shields, often bearing the anarchist circle-A, against police. The shields are largely ineffective for personal defense, but extremely effective for optics, and that's precisely the point. If a member of the IPC is arrested, he or she&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/PDocumentarians/status/1278458060130775040?s=20&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;will be protected&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Reporters seen as&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;not&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;sufficiently sympathetic to the cause—which is defined by the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tenforjustice.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Ten Demands for Justice&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, and includes most notably the abolition of the police—will be followed, be harassed, have their notes photographed and their phones blocked or stolen. (All these things have happened to me in the last month. A photographer friend has been repeatedly doxxed and placed on a list of &quot;enemies.&quot;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;If you forget any of these rules, you can just refer to the handy&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/e/2PACX-1vSus2TGVTY9xek0ySPzLEiSUbPc8Z7vvWA5w6mInVgMfrTCrWmncvzAqScbc-39KZm8wVUVtNjhS5vR/pubhtml&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Google spreadsheet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;of approved journalists and suggested behavior. The spreadsheet contains names, Twitter handles, and ways to financially support the journos who make the cut.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Note who the people on this activist-approved list are writing for. Sergio Olmos, who made IPC's list of approved journalists,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/07/19/us/portland-protests.html&quot;&gt;freelancing&lt;/a&gt; as a man on the ground for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;The New York Times&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;.* Freelancer&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;Robert Evans, whose early tick-tock of events on the ground I have admired,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/iwriteok/status/1284793130114445317?lang=en&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;tweeted&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;on July 19 that the burning of the Portland Police Association was &quot;the single biggest win so far.&quot; When questioned why, he replied that protesters have been &quot;tear-gassed and beaten&quot; for weeks. Unmentioned in his tweets: Protesters have been setting fire to the building for hours on many&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://reason.com/2020/08/17/a-quiet-night-in-portland/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;nights throughout the summer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;before&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;a police response materializes.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/iwriteok/status/1284793130114445317&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone wp-image-8083204 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://d2eehagpk5cl65.cloudfront.net/img/q60/uploads/2020/09/image1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;344&quot; height=&quot;444&quot; data-credit=&quot;Nancy Rommelmann&quot; srcset=&quot;https://d2eehagpk5cl65.cloudfront.net/img/q60/uploads/2020/09/image1.png 344w, https://d2eehagpk5cl65.cloudfront.net/img/q60/uploads/2020/09/image1-232x300.png 232w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 344px) 100vw, 344px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;These protester-approved journalists are producing much of the news you see about the protests, with an assist from the national press. Kate Shepherd isn't on the list, but she was previously a sympathetic reporter for local Portland media, and she is now filing such stories for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;The&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Washington Post&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;, with headlines like &quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/nation/2020/08/10/portland-demetria-hester-arrest/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Portland police arrest a hate crime survivor and Wall of Moms organizer in crackdown&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Meanwhile, Portland has become a political football, with Donald Trump essentially running his presidential campaign against Democratic mayors like Wheeler,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/realdonaldtrump/status/1300170578134003713?lang=en&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;tweeting&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;that &quot;Portland will never recover with a fool for a Mayor. He tried mixing with the Agitators and Anarchists and they mocked him. He would like to blame me and the Federal Government for going in, but he hasn't seen anything yet. We have only been there with a small group to defend our U.S. Courthouse, because he couldn't do it.&quot; Both sides are getting their information through purposely bottlenecked media reports, and the results are predictably distorted and dangerous.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;It will not be quiet in Portland this weekend. Last night self-professed antifa supporter Michael Reinoehl was shot to death as the authorities tried to arrest him for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://reason.com/2020/09/01/when-a-killing-becomes-a-rorschach-test-dispatch-from-portland/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;killing Patriot Prayer member Aaron Danielson&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. (Reinoehl claimed in an&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/v7g8vb/man-linked-to-killing-at-a-portland-protest-says-he-acted-in-self-defense&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;interview&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Vice&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;that it was self-defense.) It's going to be 100 degrees in the city. As we move into what is shaping to be the hottest weekend thus far in Portland, it's important to understand how the coverage you are getting is being shaped, and by whom.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;*CLARIFICATION: This article has been edited to clarify that Sergio Olmos is a freelancer. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 12:31:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Bostonian</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://reason.com/2020/09/04/youre-not-allowed-to-film-the-fight-for-control-over-who-reports-from-portland/</og:url>
<og:title>'You're Not Allowed To Film': The Fight To Control Who Reports From Portland</og:title>
<og:description>Both sides are getting their information through purposely bottlenecked media reports, and the results are predictably distorted and dangerous.</og:description>
<og:image>https://reason.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Portland-protest-3-1161x630.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://reason.com/2020/09/04/youre-not-allowed-to-film-the-fight-for-control-over-who-reports-from-portland/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>C++20 has been approved</title>
<link>https://twitter.com/PatriceRoy1/status/1302055575140945921</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://twitter.com/PatriceRoy1/status/1302055575140945921</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/PatriceRoy1/status/1302055575140945921&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/PatriceRoy1/status/1302055575140945921&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24389549&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24389549&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 229&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 261&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 06:59:06 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dgellow</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mobile.twitter.com/PatriceRoy1/status/1302055575140945921</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Data Broker Opt-Out List</title>
<link>https://github.com/yaelwrites/Big-Ass-Data-Broker-Opt-Out-List</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/yaelwrites/Big-Ass-Data-Broker-Opt-Out-List</guid>
<description>&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;Symbols&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Meanings&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;☠&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;high priority&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;🎫&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;requires driver’s license (cross out your ID #!)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;📞&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;must pick up a (gasp!) phone&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;📠&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;must go back in time and find a fax machine&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;📫&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;must use snail mail&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;💰&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;site charges money for access or removal (whaaaat?)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;*last updated 7/21/20: updated link for Addresses.com 6/17/20: Added SmartBackground Checks 6/14 update: Added BeenVerified property search, SearchPeopleFree address search, added ID True, NeighborReport, Persopo, TruePeopleSearch, US Phone Book, VoterRecords, Xlek, removed Veromi and VerifyThem, which appear to no longer exist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please send corrections or updates to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:yael.grauer@gmail.com&quot;&gt;yael.grauer@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disclaimers: Some of these opt-outs take a long time to go through. Sometimes, information is pulled from other sources and you’ll need to opt out multiple times for the same site. Data brokers come and go (and are bought out by others), and they also often change their opt-out pages. I try to update this ~every six months, but it’s not always current. Finally, even opting out of these sites doesn’t mean that your address is secure. In many states, real estate data and voter registration information is public (or easy to obtain). And, of course, location data can be found by physical means (e.g., following you home) and through other people who know it (i.e., social engineering). That said, removing your home address from data broker sites can significantly lower your attack surface and make it harder for people to find it. 💕&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;People Search Sites&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;411.com&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See Whitepages.com below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Acxiom&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is hard to find your own info for free, but you can opt out here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://isapps.acxiom.com/optout/optout.aspx#section8&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://isapps.acxiom.com/optout/optout.aspx#section8&lt;/a&gt; (U.S.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://isapps.acxiom.com/optout/optout.aspx#section7&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://isapps.acxiom.com/optout/optout.aspx#section7&lt;/a&gt; (non-U.S.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://isapps.acxiom.com/optout/optout.aspx&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://isapps.acxiom.com/optout/optout.aspx&lt;/a&gt; (info)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don’t have an email address, call (877) 774-2094 and follow the prompts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Addresses&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find your information here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.addresses.com/white-pages&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://www.addresses.com/white-pages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opt out via Intelius here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www1.intelius.com/optout&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www1.intelius.com/optout&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;AddressSearch:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look up your address here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.addresssearch.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://www.addresssearch.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opt out via Intelius here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www1.intelius.com/opt-out/submit&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www1.intelius.com/opt-out/submit/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Advanced Background Checks:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remove your data here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.advancedbackgroundchecks.com/removal&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.advancedbackgroundchecks.com/removal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;AnyWho&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find your information here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anywho.com/people/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.anywho.com/people/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opt out here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anywho.com/help/privacy&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.anywho.com/help/privacy&lt;/a&gt; or here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www1.intelius.com/optout&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www1.intelius.com/optout&lt;/a&gt; (it’ll redirect you there).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Archives&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To find your information, you must sign up for a free trial here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.archives.com/search/ancestor/checkout&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.archives.com/search/ancestor/checkout&lt;/a&gt;(and then cancel)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opt out here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.archives.com/?_act=Optout&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://www.archives.com/?_act=Optout&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;☠ BeenVerified&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find your information and opt out here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.beenverified.com/app/optout/search&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.beenverified.com/app/optout/search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opt out of property search here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.beenverified.com/app/optout/address-search&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.beenverified.com/app/optout/address-search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;CheckThem.com&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find your information and opt out here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.checkthem.com/optout/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.checkthem.com/optout/&lt;/a&gt;. You will receive a link via email you’ll need to click on to complete the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Classmates.com&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opt out or control information that’s posted here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.classmates.com/siteui/account/privacy&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.classmates.com/siteui/account/privacy&lt;/a&gt;, owned by Intelius.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also cancel your membership entirely here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://secure.classmates.com/auth/removemember&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://secure.classmates.com/auth/removemember&lt;/a&gt; (for free versions).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See instructions for paid versions here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://help.classmates.com/hc/en-us/articles/115002224171-How-can-I-cancel-my-membership-&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://help.classmates.com/hc/en-us/articles/115002224171-How-can-I-cancel-my-membership-&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;DOBSearch&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find your information here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dobsearch.com/people-finder/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.dobsearch.com/people-finder/&lt;/a&gt;. Then hit &quot;manage my records&quot; and opt out. You will need to supply your number and email address and provide text or email confirmation. Info here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dobsearch.com/people-finder/pf_manage_help.php&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.dobsearch.com/people-finder/pf_manage_help.php&lt;/a&gt; You can also find instructions here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dobsearch.com/contact.php?nature=remove&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.dobsearch.com/contact.php?nature=remove&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;FamilyTreeNow&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Search for yourself and remove your information here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.familytreenow.com/optout&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.familytreenow.com/optout&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;FastPeopleSearch&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look for and remove your information here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fastpeoplesearch.com/removal&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.fastpeoplesearch.com/removal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;IDTrue&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find your information and out here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.idtrue.com/optout/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.idtrue.com/optout/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;🎫 📠 📫 InfoTracer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find your information here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infotracer.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.infotracer.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will need to opt out by mail or fax by filling out this form: &lt;a href=&quot;https://members.infotracer.com/tspec/shared/assets/data_opt_out_form.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://members.infotracer.com/tspec/shared/assets/data_opt_out_form.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;☠ InstantCheckmate&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find and remove your information here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instantcheckmate.com/opt-out/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.instantcheckmate.com/opt-out/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;💰 InstantPeopleFinder&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find your information here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://instantpeoplefinder.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://instantpeoplefinder.com&lt;/a&gt;, remove listings from the sites it’s aggregating the data from, and try to opt out here, though you can’t provide requested URLs without paying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instantpeoplefinder.com/optout.php&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.instantpeoplefinder.com/optout.php.&lt;/a&gt; You can also email &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:optout@instantpeoplefinder.com&quot;&gt;optout@instantpeoplefinder.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;☠ Intelius&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find your information here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.intelius.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.intelius.com&lt;/a&gt;. Opt out here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.intelius.com/optout&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.intelius.com/optout&lt;/a&gt;. (Intelius owns Classmates, DateCheck, iSearch, LookUpAnyone, Peopleconnect.us, PeopleLookup, Phonesbook, Publicrecords, Spock, USSearch, Zabasearch).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;☠ 📞 MyLife&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find your information here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mylife.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.mylife.com&lt;/a&gt;. (You don’t need to sign up and pay for anything). Opt out by calling (888) 704-1900, press 2, ask to be removed from MyLife (and Wink.com, just in case). You’ll need to provide your name, age, date of birth, email address, current mailing address, and a previous mailing address. Another option to try is to email a link to your profile to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:removalrequests@mylife.com&quot;&gt;removalrequests@mylife.com&lt;/a&gt;. (It also appears that you can sign up for a free membership to remove your reputation profile, though not your personal information such as your home address.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;NeighborReport&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look for your name or search under your address at &lt;a href=&quot;https://neighbor.report/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://neighbor.report/&lt;/a&gt;. Try to get information removed at &lt;a href=&quot;https://neighbor.report/remove&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://neighbor.report/remove&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Nuwber&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find your information here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://nuwber.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://nuwber.com/&lt;/a&gt;. Enter the URL of the profile page you found and your email address here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://nuwber.com/removal/link&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://nuwber.com/removal/link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;☠ PeekYou&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find your information here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.peekyou.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.peekyou.com/&lt;/a&gt; , opt out here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.peekyou.com/about/contact/optout&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.peekyou.com/about/contact/optout&lt;/a&gt;. You will need the letters at the end of your profile’s URL in the &quot;unique ID&quot; field. Make sure to check &quot;remove my entire listing.&quot; You can also remove your information from the sites that it says it has aggregated information from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;💰 PeopleByName&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Type your phone number here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.peoplebyname.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://www.peoplebyname.com/&lt;/a&gt;. It may not give you information without you paying, but it will tell you whether there is data associated with your number. Opt out for each number here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.peoplebyname.com/remove.php&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://www.peoplebyname.com/remove.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;PeopleFinder&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find your information here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.peoplefinder.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://www.peoplefinder.com/&lt;/a&gt;, opt out at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.peoplefinder.com/optout.php&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://www.peoplefinder.com/optout.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;☠ PeopleFinders&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;: Find your information and opt out here:&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.peoplefinders.com/opt-out&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.peoplefinders.com/opt-out&lt;/a&gt; (includes PublicRecordsNow)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;PeopleLooker&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PeopleLooker’s opt-out process is now managed by BeenVerified. The reports available on the PeopleLooker site require a paid trial. Instead, opt out here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.beenverified.com/app/optout/search&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.beenverified.com/app/optout/search&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;🎫 📠 📫 PeopleLookUp&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find your information here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://peoplelookup.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://peoplelookup.com/&lt;/a&gt;, follow opt-out instructions here, which include sending your name, address, date of birth, a notarized identity form and a copy of a government-issued ID to P.O. Box 4145, Bellevue, WA 98009-4145, or faxed to 425.974.6194. &lt;a href=&quot;https://peoplelookup.com/privacy-policy#updating-or-removing-your-information&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://peoplelookup.com/privacy-policy#updating-or-removing-your-information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;PeopleSearchNow&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find your information and opt out here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.peoplesearchnow.com/opt-out&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.peoplesearchnow.com/opt-out&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;PeopleSmart&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now owned by BeenVerified (see their opt-out instructions). Look for your info here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.peoplesmart.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.peoplesmart.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Persopo&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Search for your information here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://persopo.com/search&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://persopo.com/search&lt;/a&gt;. Cut and paste the text of it (which is hard to do because of the 1990s site format, but is required by the site) and email it along with your opt-out request to&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:support@persopo.com&quot;&gt;support@persopo.com&lt;/a&gt;. You can also mail your request to Persopo.com, Attention: Opt Out Dept., 848 N. Rainbow Blvd., Suite 20, Las Vegas, NV 89107. (Opt-out instructions are posted here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://info.persopo.com/opt-out.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://info.persopo.com/opt-out.html&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Phone Detective&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now owned by BeenVerified (see their opt-out instructions). Do a search on your number here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.phonedetective.com/PD.aspx&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.phonedetective.com/PD.aspx&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;☠ Pipl&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go to &lt;a href=&quot;https://pipl.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://pipl.com&lt;/a&gt; to find your data. Opt out from Pipl at &lt;a href=&quot;https://pipl.com/personal-information-removal-request&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://pipl.com/personal-information-removal-request&lt;/a&gt;. Then, remove your information from any sites it’s aggregated from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Private Eye&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look for your info here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.privateeye.com/static/view/optout/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.privateeye.com/&lt;/a&gt; Opt out here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.privateeye.com/static/view/optout/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.privateeye.com/static/view/optout/&lt;/a&gt;. You can also skip the first part and head to the second. This site will also take you to PeopleFinders, so you can opt out of that, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;☠ 📫 📠 PublicRecords&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Owned by Intelius. Find your information here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.publicrecords.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.publicrecords.com/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To opt out, you need to mail or fax a &lt;em&gt;notarized form&lt;/em&gt; (available here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.intelius.com/docs/notaryverificationform.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.intelius.com/docs/notaryverificationform.pdf&lt;/a&gt;) along with your driver’s license or state-issued ID card, your full name, any nicknames or variations you want removed, address, and date of birth to the address and fax number listed under &quot;How to Remove your Information from PublicRecords.com Public Records Databases&quot; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://secure.publicrecords.com/privacy.php&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://secure.publicrecords.com/privacy.php&lt;/a&gt;. Unfortunately, that site appears to be down. The most recent contact information we have is a fax number, which is (425) 974-6194, and two mailing addresses: P.O. Box 4145, Bellevue, WA 98009-4145, and PublicRecords.com, Attn: Removal, 4607 Lakeview Canyon Rd. Suite 127, Westlake Village, CA 91361.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;PublicRecordsNow&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Appears to have merged with Truthfinder. Find your information here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.publicrecordsnow.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.publicrecordsnow.com/&lt;/a&gt;. Click &quot;opt out&quot; on this form &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.publicrecordsnow.com/static/view/contact/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.publicrecordsnow.com/static/view/contact/&lt;/a&gt; (or go to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.publicrecordsnow.com/static/view/contact/#&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.publicrecordsnow.com/static/view/contact/#&lt;/a&gt;), fill out the form, complete the captcha and send it in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;☠ 🎫 PublicRecords360&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find your information and opt out here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.publicrecords360.com/optout.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.publicrecords360.com/optout.html&lt;/a&gt;, or go directly to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www1.intelius.com/optout&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www1.intelius.com/optout&lt;/a&gt; (processed by Intelius). You will also need to send identification (a driver’s license, U.S. passport, US military ID card, state ID card or employee ID card from a state agency) or a &lt;a href=&quot;https://p_pr360.commondatastorage.googleapis.com/images/notaryverificationform.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;notarized ID verification form&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:custserv@publicrecords360.com&quot;&gt;custserv@publicrecords360.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Radaris&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find your information here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://radaris.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://radaris.com&lt;/a&gt;. Click on &quot;control information&quot; and &quot;remove information&quot; by clicking on the X next to it or by removing specific listings. You can also privatize your account. You unfortunately need to register to remove information, and are limited to removing six items at a time. (I recommend removing items even if you privatize your account because these settings don’t always stick.) Details are here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://radaris.com/page/how-to-remove&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://radaris.com/page/how-to-remove&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;ReversePhone Lookup&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look up your number on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reversephonelookup.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.reversephonelookup.com&lt;/a&gt; &lt;del&gt;and opt out at&lt;/del&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reversephonelookup.com/remove.php&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;https://www.reversephonelookup.com/remove.php&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Unfortunately, the site’s opt-out page is broken and contact form is not accepting messages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;💰 SearchBug&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, you have to pay to search for your information at&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.searchbug.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.searchbug.com&lt;/a&gt;, but you can email &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:support@searchbug.com&quot;&gt;support@searchbug.com&lt;/a&gt; to ask them to block the display of your personal information from being listed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;SearchPeopleFree&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FInd your information here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.searchpeoplefree.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.searchpeoplefree.com/&lt;/a&gt;, making sure to search by name, phone number, address and email address: Opt out here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.searchpeoplefree.com/opt-out&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.searchpeoplefree.com/opt-out&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;SmartBackground Checks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find your information here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.smartbackgroundchecks.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.smartbackgroundchecks.com/&lt;/a&gt;. Opt out here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.smartbackgroundchecks.com/optout&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.smartbackgroundchecks.com/optout&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Spoke&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find your information here:&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.spoke.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://www.spoke.com/&lt;/a&gt;. Suppress it by clicking on the &quot;Request Removal&quot; link at the bottom of the page, enter the URL in the contact form it takes you to, and provide your email address. You can also email your removal request to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:feedback@readwritelabs.com&quot;&gt;feedback@readwritelabs.com&lt;/a&gt;. Unfortunately, Spoke’s opt-out page may not be working—its link from the FAQ page is dead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;☠ Spokeo&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find your information here &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.spokeo.com/search&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.spokeo.com/search&lt;/a&gt; and remove your information by entering the URL of the profile you want removed and your email address here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.spokeo.com/optout&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.spokeo.com/optout&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;TruePeopleSearch&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opt out here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.truepeoplesearch.com/removal&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.truepeoplesearch.com/removal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;That’s Them&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find your information here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://thatsthem.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://thatsthem.com/&lt;/a&gt;, if it shows up, try to opt out here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://thatsthem.com/optout&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://thatsthem.com/optout&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;TruthFinder&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find and remove your information at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.truthfinder.com/opt-out/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.truthfinder.com/opt-out/&lt;/a&gt;. Search for your name, click &quot;remove this record,&quot; and fill out the information (your name and email address). You can also send your removal request in the mail to TruthFinder, attn: OptOut, 2534 State St., Suite 473, San Diego, CA 92101. If you find your information after you have opted out, contact Truthfinder at (800) 699-8081 or &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:help@truthfinder.com&quot;&gt;help@truthfinder.com&lt;/a&gt;. (More contact information here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.truthfinder.com/about/#contact&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.truthfinder.com/about/#contact&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;USA People Search&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find and remove your information at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usa-people-search.com/manage&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.usa-people-search.com/manage&lt;/a&gt;. The site asks you to wait four hours between opt-out requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;USPhoneBook&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opt out here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usphonebook.com/opt-out/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.usphonebook.com/opt-out/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;VoterRecords&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go to &lt;a href=&quot;https://voterrecords.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;VoterRecords.com&lt;/a&gt;, find your information, scroll to the bottom of the page and click on the &quot;record opt-out&quot; link. This will lead to an opt-out form, which you’ll need to submit. You may receive a verification link you’ll need to click on to verify your opt-out request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;☠ 📞 White Pages&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find your information here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whitepages.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.whitepages.com/&lt;/a&gt;, and then opt out here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whitepages.com/suppression_requests&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.whitepages.com/suppression_requests&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will need to provide a phone number and enter an opt-out code when you receive the phone call. Opt-out information is available here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.whitepages.com/hc/en-us/articles/115010106908-How-do-I-edit-or-remove-a-personal-listing&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://support.whitepages.com/hc/en-us/articles/115010106908-How-do-I-edit-or-remove-a-personal-listing&lt;/a&gt;-. You can also send a request here &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.whitepages.com/hc/en-us/requests/new&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://support.whitepages.com/hc/en-us/requests/new&lt;/a&gt;. (Including multiple options because these sites have a tendency to disappear.) Sometimes, information is removed from White Pages but not White Pages Premium, so make sure to double-check for your listing. Also, White Pages also owns &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.411.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;411.com&lt;/a&gt;, so check for your information there. The opt-out is the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Xlek&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(formerly Cubib?) Look up your information at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.xlek.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.xlek.com/&lt;/a&gt;. Opt out at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.xlek.com/optout.php&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.xlek.com/optout.php&lt;/a&gt;. You’ll need to submit a separate opt-out request for each item you’d like removed&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;☠ ZabaSearch&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(now owned by Intelius): Find your information here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://zabasearch.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://zabasearch.com&lt;/a&gt;. Opt out on Intelius: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.intelius.com/optout&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.intelius.com/optout&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;☠ 🎫 ZoomInfo&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check to see if your information is on ZoomInfo by filling out this form:&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zoominfo.com/lookupEmail&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://www.zoominfo.com/lookupEmail&lt;/a&gt;. Opt out if it has an email on record—they will email you a code. ZoomInfo appears to have moved towards focusing primarily on business rather than individuals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Special Circumstances&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re a victim of violent crime or identity theft, it’s often possible to opt out of information that others can’t opt out of. You may, however, need to provide court orders or other information. It may be worth checking more complete data broker lists which include those: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.privacyrights.org/data-brokers&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.privacyrights.org/data-brokers&lt;/a&gt; See this resource: &lt;a href=&quot;https://nnedv.org/mdocs-posts/people-searches-data-brokers/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://nnedv.org/mdocs-posts/people-searches-data-brokers/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Preventing Identity Theft &amp;amp; Opting Out of Marketing Sites&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;📞 Consider freezing your credit&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;, which prevents creditors from accessing your credit report. (It also prevents credit, loans, and services from being approved in your name, but you will receive a pin to unfreeze your credit, if needed.) You will need to provide personal information such as your name, address, date of birth, and social security number to freeze your credit. While you can sometimes initiate this online, it’s better to do it by phone. Fees for freezing your credit &lt;a href=&quot;http://consumersunion.org/research/consumers-unions-guide-to-security-freeze-protection-2/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;vary by state&lt;/a&gt;. To freeze your credit, contact:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Explore any privacy options&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;offered by your state’s motor vehicle department.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Contact your home and mobile phone companies&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;to see if they offer privacy options, such as not listing your number on caller ID or allowing you to opt out of sales of phone numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Consider opting out of direct marketing and telemarketing.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This list, compiled by Griffin Boyce, has a lot of information on doing so: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/glamrock/data-brokers/blob/master/data-brokers.md&quot;&gt;https://github.com/glamrock/data-brokers/blob/master/data-brokers.md&lt;/a&gt;. A good place to start is to opt out at the Direct Marketing Association. &lt;a href=&quot;https://dmachoice.thedma.org/register.php&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://dmachoice.thedma.org/register.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Opt out of prescreened credit offers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow the instructions at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.optoutprescreen.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.optoutprescreen.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Get on the Do Not Call Registry&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.donotcall.gov/register/reg.aspx&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.donotcall.gov/register/reg.aspx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Paid options&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DeleteMe, PrivacyDuck, OneRep, Reputation Defender and Reputation.com all offer different opt-out services. However, these are not comprehensive, as some data brokers do not allow third parties to remove listings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Further reading&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fastcompany.com/90310803/here-are-the-data-brokers-quietly-buying-and-selling-your-personal-information&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Here are the data brokers quietly buying and selling your personal information&lt;/a&gt; (Fast Company)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://inteltechniques.com/data/workbook.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Personal Data Removal Workbook and Credit Freeze Guide&lt;/a&gt; (Michael Bazzell)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/cr-digital-lab/preliminary-results-are-in-ccpa-testers-provide-important-insights-into-the-landmark-privacy-law-c299f733de09&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Preliminary results are in! CCPA testers provide important insights into the landmark privacy law&lt;/a&gt; (Medium/Consumer Reports)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 03:44:21 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>JoshTriplett</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars3.githubusercontent.com/u/3827521?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>yaelwrites/Big-Ass-Data-Broker-Opt-Out-List</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/yaelwrites/Big-Ass-Data-Broker-Opt-Out-List</og:url>
<og:description>Contribute to yaelwrites/Big-Ass-Data-Broker-Opt-Out-List development by creating an account on GitHub.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/yaelwrites/Big-Ass-Data-Broker-Opt-Out-List</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Traffic Prediction with Advanced Graph Neural Networks</title>
<link>https://deepmind.com/blog/article/traffic-prediction-with-advanced-graph-neural-networks</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://deepmind.com/blog/article/traffic-prediction-with-advanced-graph-neural-networks</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;56.696312364425&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;By partnering with Google, DeepMind is able to bring the benefits of AI to billions of people all over the world.  From reuniting a speech-impaired user with his&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://deepmind.com/blog/article/Using-WaveNet-technology-to-reunite-speech-impaired-users-with-their-original-voices&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;original voice&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;, to helping users discover&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://deepmind.com/blog/article/Advanced-machine-learning-helps-Play-Store-users-discover-personalised-apps&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;personalised apps&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;, we can apply breakthrough research to immediate real-world problems at a Google scale. Today we’re delighted to share the results of our latest partnership, delivering a truly global impact for the more than one billion people that use Google Maps. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our collaboration with Google Maps&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;People rely on Google Maps for accurate traffic predictions and estimated times of arrival (ETAs). These are critical tools that are especially useful when you need to be routed around a traffic jam, if you need to notify friends and family that you’re running late, or if you need to leave in time to attend an important meeting. These features are also useful for businesses such as rideshare companies, which use Google Maps Platform to power their services with information about pickup and dropoff times, along with estimated prices based on trip duration. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://deepmind.com/about/deepmind-for-google&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Researchers at DeepMind&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;have partnered with the Google Maps team to improve the accuracy of real time ETAs by up to 50% in places like Berlin, Jakarta, São Paulo, Sydney, Tokyo, and Washington D.C. by using advanced machine learning techniques including Graph Neural Networks, as the graphic below shows:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;58&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How Google Maps Predicts ETAs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;To calculate ETAs, Google Maps analyses live traffic data for road segments around the world. While this data gives Google Maps an accurate picture of&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;current&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;traffic, it doesn’t account for the traffic a driver can expect to see 10, 20, or even 50 minutes into their drive. To accurately predict&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;future&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;traffic, Google Maps uses machine learning to combine live traffic conditions with historical traffic patterns for roads worldwide. This process is complex for a number of reasons. For example - even though rush-hour inevitably happens every morning and evening, the exact time of rush hour can vary significantly from day to day and month to month. Additional factors like road quality, speed limits, accidents, and closures can also add to the complexity of the prediction model. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;DeepMind partnered with Google Maps to help improve the accuracy of their ETAs around the world. While Google Maps’ predictive ETAs have been consistently accurate for over 97% of trips, we worked with the team to minimise the remaining inaccuracies even further - sometimes by more than 50% in cities like Taichung. To do this at a global scale, we used a generalised machine learning architecture called Graph Neural Networks that allows us to conduct spatiotemporal reasoning by incorporating relational learning biases to model the connectivity structure of real-world road networks. Here’s how it works: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dividing the world’s roads into Supersegments&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We divided road networks into “Supersegments” consisting of multiple adjacent segments of road that share significant traffic volume. Currently, the Google Maps traffic prediction system consists of the following components: (1) a route analyser that processes terabytes of traffic information to construct Supersegments and (2) a novel Graph Neural Network model, which is optimised with multiple objectives and predicts the travel time for each Supersegment.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt; The model architecture for determining optimal routes and their travel time. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;61&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On the road to novel machine learning architectures for traffic prediction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The biggest challenge to solve when creating a machine learning system to estimate travel times using Supersegments is an architectural one. How do we represent dynamically sized examples of connected segments with arbitrary accuracy in such a way that a single model can achieve success?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Our initial proof of concept began with a straight-forward approach that used the existing traffic system as much as possible, specifically the existing segmentation of road-networks and the associated real-time data pipeline. This meant that a Supersegment covered a set of road segments, where each segment has a specific length and corresponding speed features. At first we trained a single fully connected neural network model for every Supersegment. These initial results were promising, and demonstrated the potential in using neural networks for predicting travel time. However, given the dynamic sizes of the Supersegments, we required a separately trained neural network model for each one. To deploy this at scale, we would have to train millions of these models, which would have posed a considerable infrastructure challenge. This led us to look into models that could handle variable length sequences, such as Recurrent Neural Networks (RNNs). However, incorporating further structure from the road network proved difficult. Instead, we decided to use Graph Neural Networks. In modeling traffic, we’re interested in how cars flow through a network of roads, and Graph Neural Networks can model network dynamics and information propagation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Our model treats the local road network as a graph, where each route segment corresponds to a node and edges exist between segments that are consecutive on the same road or connected through an intersection. In a Graph Neural Network, a message passing algorithm is executed where the messages and their effect on edge and node states are learned by neural networks. From this viewpoint, our Supersegments are road subgraphs, which were sampled at random in proportion to traffic density. A single model can therefore be trained using these sampled subgraphs, and can be deployed at scale.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;123.64511784512&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Graph Neural Networks extend the learning bias imposed by Convolutional Neural Networks and Recurrent Neural Networks by generalising the concept of “proximity”, allowing us to have arbitrarily complex connections to handle not only traffic ahead or behind us, but also along adjacent and intersecting roads. In a Graph Neural Network, adjacent nodes pass messages to each other. By keeping this structure, we impose a locality bias where nodes will find it easier to rely on adjacent nodes (this only requires one message passing step). These mechanisms allow Graph Neural Networks to capitalise on the connectivity structure of the road network more effectively. Our experiments have demonstrated gains in predictive power from expanding to include adjacent roads that are not part of the main road. For example, think of how a jam on a side street can spill over to affect traffic on a larger road. By spanning multiple intersections, the model gains the ability to natively predict delays at turns, delays due to merging, and the overall traversal time in stop-and-go traffic. This ability of Graph Neural Networks to generalise over combinatorial spaces is what grants our modeling technique its power. Each Supersegment, which can be of varying length and of varying complexity - from simple two-segment routes to longer routes containing hundreds of nodes - can nonetheless be processed by the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;strong&gt;same&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;span&gt;Graph Neural Network model. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From basic research to production-ready machine learning models&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;A big challenge for a production machine learning system that is often overlooked in the academic setting involves the large variability that can exist across multiple training runs of the same model. While small differences in quality can simply be discarded as poor initialisations in more academic settings, these small inconsistencies can have a large impact when added together across millions of users. As such, making our Graph Neural Network robust to this variability in training took center stage as we pushed the model into production. We discovered that Graph Neural Networks are particularly sensitive to changes in the training curriculum - the primary cause of this instability being the large variability in graph structures used during training. A single batch of graphs could contain anywhere from small two-node graphs to large 100+ nodes graphs.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;After much trial and error, however, we developed an approach to solve this problem by adapting a novel reinforcement learning technique for use in a supervised setting.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In training a machine learning system, the learning rate of a system specifies how ‘plastic’ – or changeable to new information – it is. Researchers often reduce the learning rate of their models over time, as there is a tradeoff between learning new things, and forgetting important features already learned–not unlike the progression from childhood to adulthood. We initially made use of an exponentially decaying learning rate schedule to stabilise our parameters after a pre-defined period of training. We also explored and analysed model ensembling techniques which have proven effective in previous work to see if we could reduce model variance between training runs.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In the end, the most successful approach to this problem was using&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1805.09801&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;MetaGradients&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;to dynamically adapt the learning rate during training - effectively letting the system learn its own optimal learning rate schedule. By automatically adapting the learning rate while training, our model not only achieved higher quality than before, it also learned to decrease the learning rate automatically. This led to more stable results, enabling us to use our novel architecture in production. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Making models generalise through customised loss functions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;While the ultimate goal of our modeling system is to reduce errors in travel estimates, we found that making use of a linear combination of multiple loss functions (weighted appropriately) greatly increased the ability of the model to generalise. Specifically, we formulated a multi-loss objective making use of a regularising factor on the model weights, L_2 and L_1 losses on the global traversal times, as well as individual Huber and negative-log likelihood (NLL) losses for each node in the graph. By combining these losses we were able to guide our model and avoid overfitting on the training dataset. While our measurements of quality in training did not change, improvements seen during training translated more directly to held-out tests sets and to our end-to-end experiments.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Currently we are exploring whether the MetaGradient technique can also be used to vary the composition of the multi-component loss-function during training, using the reduction in travel estimate errors as a guiding metric. This work is inspired by the MetaGradient efforts that have found success in reinforcement learning, and early experiments show promising results.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Collaboration&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Thanks to our close and fruitful collaboration with the Google Maps team, we were able to apply these novel and newly developed techniques at scale. Together, we were able to overcome both research challenges as well as production and scalability problems. In the end, the final model and techniques led to a successful launch, improving the accuracy of ETAs on Google Maps and Google Maps Platform APIs around the world.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Working at Google scale with cutting-edge research represents a unique set of challenges. If you’re interested in applying cutting edge techniques such as Graph Neural Networks to address real-world problems, learn more about the team working on these problems&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://deepmind.com/about/deepmind-for-google&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;here&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;In collaboration with: Marc Nunkesser, Seongjae Lee, Xueying Guo, Austin Derrow-Pinion, David Wong, Peter Battaglia, Todd Hester, Petar Veličković‎, Vishal Gupta, Ang Li, Zhongwen Xu, Geoff Hulten, Jeffrey Hightower, Luis C. Cobo, Praveen Srinivasan &amp;amp; Harish Chandran.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Figures by Paulo Estriga &amp;amp; Adam Cain.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 20:23:27 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>beefman</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:title>Traffic prediction with advanced Graph Neural Networks</og:title>
<og:description>Working with our partners at Google Maps, we used advanced machine learning techniques including Graph Neural Networks, to improve the accuracy of real time ETAs by up to 50%.</og:description>
<og:image>https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/_0l569a7inOy7JzU1-ZvhKqYL6pCL6q_yEMTOPtZx-IeFPzN2yvLIRC8vZe922Q1JL4WB2JziEXj0CurKHeD5vSt3ILJtHgX5d36Fg</og:image>
<og:url>/blog/article/traffic-prediction-with-advanced-graph-neural-networks</og:url>
<dc:language>ALL</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://deepmind.com/blog/article/traffic-prediction-with-advanced-graph-neural-networks</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Mathematicians should stop naming things after each other</title>
<link>http://nautil.us/issue/89/the-dark-side/why-mathematicians-should-stop-naming-things-after-each-other</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://nautil.us/issue/89/the-dark-side/why-mathematicians-should-stop-naming-things-after-each-other</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;A&lt;/span&gt;ny student of modern math must know what it feels like to drown in a well of telescoping terminology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a high-profile example, let’s take the Calabi-Yau manifold, made famous by string theory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Calabi-Yau manifold is a compact, complex Kähler manifold with a trivial first Chern class.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you could even guess what that definition might mean, you would need to find another source to define a Kähler manifold:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Kähler manifold is a Hermitian manifold for which the Hermitian form is closed.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After which you would need a third source to define a Hermitian manifold:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Hermitian manifold is the complex analogue of the Riemannian manifold …&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And you’re down the rabbit hole. When everything is named for its discoverer, it can be impossible even to track the outline of a debate without months of rote memorization. The discoverer’s name doesn’t tell you anything about what the landscape is like, any more than the “Ackerman” in Ackerman’s Island helps to convey a sandbar in downtown Wichita. Except in a few one-hit-wonder situations where a famous mathematician had extremely narrow tastes (like an Ackerman who, as everyone knew, could only live on sandy substrates, and never left the state of Kansas), their name gives no mnemonic boost whatsoever. Whatever faint associations it might once have held fade away, especially when the discover was neither famous nor narrow, and the reader is several generations removed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;pull-quote&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some very nice names have sprung up with no clear first use, like “pair of pants” and the Hairy Ball Theorem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This nesting of proper nouns helps to make higher math impenetrable not just to outsiders, but also to working mathematicians trying to read their way from one subfield into another. The venerable Bill Thurston was known to complain about the perversity which, by the end of his career, had produced Thurston’s theorem, which says that Thurston maps are Thurston-equivalent to polynomials, unless they have Thurston obstructions. Every field has terms of art, but when those terms are descriptive, they are easier to memorize. Imagine how much steeper the learning curve would be in medicine or law if they used the same naming conventions, with the same number of layers to peel back:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Thurston tumor is a benign Thurston growth in the bones of patients with type-1 Thurstonism.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Thurston homicide requires a finding of Thurston recklessness and is a Thurston-class felony.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ancient Greeks were better about this. Euclid’s &lt;em&gt;Elements&lt;/em&gt; is full of common, descriptive names, even though he was drawing on discoveries made by many different people. If he needs a term for something like a triangle with two sides of the same length, he calls it “isosceles,” literally “equal-legged” in Greek. A triangle with sides of all different lengths is “scalene,” or “unequal.” Euclid doesn’t even name &lt;a href=&quot;https://mathcs.clarku.edu/~djoyce/java/elements/bookI/propI47.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the Pythagorean Theorem&lt;/a&gt; we all learn in school after Pythagoras, preferring just to state it plainly. In ancient Greece, it was polite for students to attribute their work to their teachers rather than themselves, if attribution was needed at all, so in the same way that &lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.com/books?id=Oo9xDwAAQBAJ&amp;amp;pg=PA41&amp;amp;lpg=PA41&amp;amp;dq=plato+gives+socrates+credit+for+his+ideas&amp;amp;source=bl&amp;amp;ots=qt0Sp_oel9&amp;amp;sig=ACfU3U3s_AHmF50G8u9SaMipNYUC72Bj4Q&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=2ahUKEwjfnM7O567pAhVnITQIHRQdC4gQ6AEwD3oECBoQAQ#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=plato%20gives%20socrates%20credit%20for%20his%20ideas&amp;amp;f=false&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Plato credited his own insights to Socrates&lt;/a&gt;, the eight or more objects now named after Pythagoras on Wolfram MathWorld might well be due to his students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things seem to have gotten out of hand after the Renaissance. Pierre Fermat’s name is on not just his Last Theorem and his Little Theorem, but on points, primes, pseudoprimes, polynomials, conics, spirals, a principle in optics, and a method for factoring odd numbers. Henri Poincaré, working at the end of the 19th century, has &lt;a href=&quot;https://mathworld.wolfram.com/search/?query=poincare&amp;amp;x=0&amp;amp;y=0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;at least 21&lt;/a&gt; mathematical entities named after him. It looks to me as though Bernhard Riemann might have as many as 82.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.researchgate.net/publication/297723759_Researchers'_Individual_Publication_Rate_Has_Not_Increased_in_a_Century&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;average number of coauthors&lt;/a&gt; on math papers has gone up since 1900. So has &lt;a href=&quot;http://math.univ-lille1.fr/~tumpach/Site/Files/Bourguignon.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the number of working mathematicians&lt;/a&gt; in the world, which raises the odds of independent rediscoveries, separated in time or space. These two trends have opened the door to triple and even quadruple hyphen situations, as in the Albert-Brauer-Hasse-Noether Theorem and the Grothendieck-Hirzebruch-Riemann-Roch Theorem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;pull-quote&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine how much steeper the learning curve would be in medicine if it used the same naming conventions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Names may get even longer if &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ias.edu/news/2017/vladimir-voevodsky-obituary&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Vladimir Voevodsky&lt;/a&gt; carries the day and modern math becomes dependent on computer-verified proofs. Papers published through big collaborations on shared technologies in other fields now have &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/news/physics-paper-sets-record-with-more-than-5-000-authors-1.17567&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;thousands of authors&lt;/a&gt;, but a theorem cannot have a thousand hyphens. We could pack in more people if we used initials, as with HOMFLY polynomials, named for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ams.org/journals/bull/1985-12-02/S0273-0979-1985-15361-3/S0273-0979-1985-15361-3.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;their six co-discovers&lt;/a&gt; (Hoste, Ocneanu, Millet, Freyd, Lickorish, and Yetter) and sometimes even called HOMFLYPT polynomials, to mete out credit to &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1610.06679.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Przytycki and Traczyk&lt;/a&gt; as well.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That, or mathematicians could take a pass on immortality and introduce their new objects with sensible, semantically parsable names instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For role models in the modern age, we look first to John Horton Conway, lately lost to COVID-19, whose many amazing names include &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-0-387-30389-5_9&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the Monster&lt;/a&gt; for the largest sporadic simple group (with over a thousand octillion elements) as well as &lt;a href=&quot;http://citeseerx.ist.psu.edu/viewdoc/download?doi=10.1.1.103.3704&amp;amp;rep=rep1&amp;amp;type=pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Monstrous Moonshine&lt;/a&gt; for that group’s totally unexpected connection with modular functions. More recently in topology, I have enjoyed Josh Greene’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1010.6257.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;changemaker vectors&lt;/a&gt;, whose components can sum to any integer less than their total value, as if making exact change with cash. David Wolpert and Bill Macready proved the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ti.arc.nasa.gov/m/profile/dhw/papers/78.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;No Free Lunch Theorems&lt;/a&gt; often cited in machine learning, which hold that every improvement in an optimization algorithm in one domain must come at the expense of worse performance in another, although &lt;a href=&quot;http://citeseerx.ist.psu.edu/viewdoc/download?doi=10.1.1.390.9412&amp;amp;rep=rep1&amp;amp;type=pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Wolpert attributes their name choice to David Haussler&lt;/a&gt;. Surely we can agree it is a much better name than “Wolpert-Macready-Haussler Theorems” would have been.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, some credit or blame must lie with the collective response to a new result, not just the individual who presents it. Poor Riemann did not name Riemannian manifolds after himself. Names like that emerge in the wave of secondary scholarship reacting to a new idea, and emergent names aren’t always bad. Some very nice names have sprung up though diffuse consensus with no clear first use, like the term “pair of pants” for a sphere with three holes in it (which I can’t trace further than &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.numdam.org/article/SB_1978-1979__21__66_0.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a Bourbaki Seminar&lt;/a&gt; in 1978) and the Hairy Ball Theorem, which says that every vector field on a sphere with even dimensions must have a zero point, so any hairy billiard ball must have a cowlick (whose trail runs cold with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.researchgate.net/publication/268035774_Differential_Topology&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Morris Hirsch’s &lt;em&gt;Differential Topology&lt;/em&gt; textbook&lt;/a&gt; in 1976). But in general, mathematicians seem to feel a Scout’s Honor to name new things after their creators, unless those creators act like Conway and make concerted, repeated efforts to give descriptive names to their own objects instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;reco&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;issue-article&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nautil.us/issue/49/The%20Absurd/the-impossible-mathematics-of-the-real-world&quot; class=&quot;obnd_lnk&quot; data-trval=&quot;the-impossible-mathematics-of-the-real-world&quot; data-trlbl=&quot;foc_rec&quot; data-tract=&quot;internal_art&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://static.nautil.us/12492_c9772667ba6122896327f5856ff8224f.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sapolsky_TH-F1&quot; width=&quot;314&quot; height=&quot;177&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;article-tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;article-tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;article-tag-focus&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nautil.us/term/f/Math&quot;&gt;Also in Math&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;article-title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nautil.us/issue/49/The%20Absurd/the-impossible-mathematics-of-the-real-world&quot; class=&quot;obnd_lnk&quot; data-trval=&quot;the-impossible-mathematics-of-the-real-world&quot; data-trlbl=&quot;foc_rec&quot; data-tract=&quot;internal_art&quot;&gt;The Impossible Mathematics of the Real World&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article-author&quot;&gt;By Evelyn Lamb&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using stiff paper and transparent tape, Craig Kaplan assembles a beautiful roundish shape that looks like a Buckminster Fuller creation or a fancy new kind of soccer ball. It consists of four regular dodecagons (12-sided polygons with all angles and...&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nautil.us/issue/49/The%20Absurd/the-impossible-mathematics-of-the-real-world&quot; class=&quot;obnd_lnk&quot; data-trval=&quot;the-impossible-mathematics-of-the-real-world&quot; data-trlbl=&quot;foc_rec&quot; data-tract=&quot;internal_art&quot;&gt;READ MORE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the last decade, the field of algebraic geometry was set on fire by “perfectoid spaces” rather than “Scholze spaces” because Peter Scholze &lt;a href=&quot;https://video.ias.edu/graf/2011/03/22/scholze&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;kept&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ihes.fr/~abbes/CAGA/scholze.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;on&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1111.4914&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;calling&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.math.uni-bonn.de/people/scholze/CDM.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;them&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.math.uni-bonn.de/people/scholze/ICM.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;that&lt;/a&gt; in his talks and papers. Like Conway and Wolpert, he put his descriptive name into the titles of his work, not just the body. That seems to help. By contrast, Shing-Tung Yau says in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Shape-Life-Mathematicians-Universes-Geometry/dp/0300235909&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;his autobiography&lt;/a&gt; that the Calabi-Yau manifold was given its name by other people eight years after he proved its existence, which Eugenio Calabi had conjectured some 20 years before that. Calabi and Yau would have had more right than anyone to interject and suggest something else, but as Yau tells it, they were both proud and happy to watch their names spread together through scholarly publications and through popular culture. What we have now is a system which gives naming rights to the discoverers in an implicit way, where your contributions will bear your names by default, unless you decide to agitate for something else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do mathematicians continue to proffer and accept this courtesy, when it increases their own mental load and makes their own work more opaque?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The worst answer I can imagine is &lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.com/books?id=PtdKAwAAQBAJ&amp;amp;pg=PA23&amp;amp;lpg=PA23&amp;amp;dq=gregory+vii+latin+slavonic&amp;amp;source=bl&amp;amp;ots=HYFjFybJ7K&amp;amp;sig=ACfU3U3VfMffhCl8T71RWNO_mqzlsi7_hw&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=2ahUKEwiexpC_wKfpAhXVPn0KHUs-ABcQ6AEwCXoECA0QAQ#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=gregory%20vii%20latin%20slavonic&amp;amp;f=false&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the one Pope Gregory VII gave&lt;/a&gt; for refusing to let the Holy Scripture be translated out of Latin: “... [I]f it were plainly apparent to all men, perchance it would be little esteemed and be subject to disrespect; or it might be falsely understood by those of mediocre learning, and lead to error.” The memory-intensive naming schemes in modern math may have the result of boxing out the laymen, but we must hope the priests of the academy are not doing it on purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A more sympathetic answer would be that mathematicians want the glory of seeing their names outlive themselves as a reward for the long, solitary hours they labor to produce their results. In law or in medicine, research has a practical object, often with money attached. Can we count on the pleasure of finding things out to sustain work in pure math, if we eliminate this appeal to the ego?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hold out the hope that research culture would be better off without it. One of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/worldnews/europe/russia/7866230/Mathematician-rejected-1-million-prize-because-it-is-unfair.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the most compelling reasons&lt;/a&gt; Grisha Perelman gave for refusing his Fields Medal and his Millennium Prize was the unfairness of singling out one person as the progenitor of a 100-page proof, which necessarily represents a stitching together of many people’s breakthroughs, made over many decades of work. Changing the name scheme of modern math might imply a change in motive force, but if that change discouraged some people, it might welcome others in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Laura Ball is a journalist-in-residence at the Kavli Institute for Theoretical Physics, a Thiel Fellow, and an alumna of the Math Prize for Girls program. She spent the last two years researching computational morality at Mila, the Quebec AI Institute.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lead image: Ollyy / Shutterstock&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;leaderboard-ad-belt&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;leaderboard-ad-belt-inner adarticle&quot;&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;div-gpt-ad-1380044019755-0&quot; class=&quot;leaderboard-ad&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 17:40:33 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>abnry</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>http://nautil.us/issue/89/the-dark-side/why-mathematicians-should-stop-naming-things-after-each-other</og:url>
<og:title>Why Mathematicians Should Stop Naming Things After Each Other - Issue 89: The Dark Side - Nautilus</og:title>
<og:description>Any student of modern math must know what it feels like to drown in a well of telescoping terminology.For a high-profile example,&amp;#8230;</og:description>
<og:image>http://static.nautil.us/17633_ef58947dc33e8fc85af0f246352112f7.png</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://nautil.us/issue/89/the-dark-side/why-mathematicians-should-stop-naming-things-after-each-other</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>