<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Aaron, 5 years later</title>
<link>https://www.bensw.com/blog/Aaron-5-Years-Later/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bensw.com/blog/Aaron-5-Years-Later/</guid>
<description>&lt;h3&gt;Aaron, 5 years later&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember with astonishing clarity the moment I received the phone call.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was in the back left seat of a minivan driving from New York City to Atlantic City. We were a little ways down the NJ turnpike. I was playing Zoo Keeper Battle on my newly gifted tablet. My stomach was filled with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/UXGBlelnP7/&quot;&gt;a pastrami sandwich&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My phone started buzzing in my pocket. I pulled it out and looked at it. The call was coming from my parents' home line. Immediately, I was confused. It was Friday night--the Sabbath--my parents never made phone calls on the Sabbath.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I unlocked my phone to pick up the call I honestly didn't know what to expect. My dad spoke. My brain lifted out of my body as the words came out of his mouth. I didn't believe them. I didn't want to believe them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hung up. I was shocked. I doubted that I heard what I heard. My friends in the car asked me what was up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;My brother is dead. I need to go back to New York City.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's been 5 years since Aaron killed himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot has changed in those 5 years. The world has changed; technology has changed; I have changed. At first, I fell into a deep dark depression. I didn't respond to messages from my friends. I didn't want to go back to work. I tried to find the few things in my life that actually brought me joy. I wasn't sure if there was a way out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As time went on, things started to get better. I was incredibly scared when that started happening. I had this outrageous fear that if things were getting better it meant I was forgetting about Aaron. I fought against things getting better for so long for precisely this reason. I felt that I needed to feel bad in order to honor him. I felt that I needed to cry every night in order to prove to the universe that I missed my brother.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That sounds and is crazy. But even now, as I type these words into my computer, crying, I think that the times I've been carefree and happy over the past year have been my fault.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know this isn't sane. I know that this isn't fair to myself. I just keep thinking to myself that I've wasted the last 5 years of my life. I haven't done anything that would've made Aaron be proud of me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This too I know isn't true. The last time I ever saw Aaron face to face was Thanksgiving 2012. He wasn't upset that I was working at Google, he was upset that I wasn't using my power as a Google employee to effect change. As we talked over the phone after Thanksgiving it was clear that he was proud of me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shortly after he died, I attempted to do everything that might have made him proud. I convinced Google to allow me to give their USENET archives to the Internet Archive. I made sure to give money to Givewell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing ever seemed like enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every year, on the anniversary of his death, I spend the day reflecting on Aaron. I reread old blog posts, watch old videos, and read articles. One video I always watch is his Freedom To Connect Speech &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Fgh2dFngFsg&quot;&gt;&quot;How we stopped SOPA&quot;&lt;/a&gt;. One especially powerful quote from it is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It wasn't a dream or a nightmare, it was all very real. And it will happen again. Sure, it will have yet another name and maybe a different excuse and probably do its damage in a different way. But make no mistake the enemies of the freedom to connect have not disappeared...If we let them persuade us we didn't actually make a difference. If we start seeing it as someone else's responsibility to do this work and it's our job just to go home and pop some popcorn and curl up on the couch to watch Transformers, well then next time, they might just win.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2017, I had the privilege to respond to this quote exactly. I worked to make sure that Twitch had a response for the Net Neutrality Day of Action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working on the project was exhilarating yet exhausting. I felt amazing writing code that I knew would make the world a better place. I felt good when I finally convinced people that we needed to do this. But every time I ran into bureaucratic problems, I felt crushed. Every time I ran into a bug, I felt hopeless. I felt the weight of the entire internet on my shoulders--I felt that if I failed, I would be flattened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can only start to imagine how Aaron felt every day fighting for the things he fought for. Hopefully, by giving back even a tiny amount, I've made a difference that he would have been proud of.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2018 19:57:36 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>bensw</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bensw.com/blog/Aaron-5-Years-Later/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Alert About Missile Bound for Hawaii Was Sent in Error, Officials Say</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/01/13/us/hawaii-missile.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2018/01/13/us/hawaii-missile.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;114&quot; data-total-count=&quot;1454&quot; id=&quot;story-continues-3&quot;&gt;At no time, officials said, was there any indication that a nuclear attack had been launched on the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;146&quot; data-total-count=&quot;1600&quot;&gt;The Federal Communications Commission announced Saturday afternoon it had begun “a full investigation into the FALSE missile alert in Hawaii.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;258&quot; data-total-count=&quot;1858&quot;&gt;The alert went out at about 8:10 a.m., lighting up phones of people still in bed, having coffee by the beach at a Waikiki resort, or up for an early surf. “BALLISTIC MISSILE THREAT INBOUND TO HAWAII. SEEK IMMEDIATE SHELTER. THIS IS NOT A DRILL,” it read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;378&quot; data-total-count=&quot;2236&quot;&gt;Hawaii has been on high emotional alert — it began staging monthly air-raid drills, complete with sirens, in December — since President Trump and Kim Jong-un, the leader of North Korea, began exchanging nuclear threats. Hawaii is about 4,600 miles from Pyongyang, the North Korean capital. Estimates vary, but the flight time for a missile would likely be around 37 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;271&quot; data-total-count=&quot;2507&quot;&gt;Within moments of the alert, people flocked to shelters, crowding highways in scenes of terror and helplessness. “I was running through all the scenarios in my head, but there was nowhere to go, nowhere to pull over to,” said Mike Staskow, a retired military captain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;172&quot; data-total-count=&quot;2679&quot;&gt;Ray Gerst was vacationing on Oahu with his wife to celebrate their 28th wedding anniversary. Just as they pulled up for their tour of Kualoa Ranch, they received the alert.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;171&quot; data-total-count=&quot;2850&quot;&gt;“All the buses stopped, and people came running out of the ranch and said, ‘Just sit still for a minute, nobody get off the bus, nobody get off the bus,’” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;story-ad-2&quot; class=&quot;story-ad ad ad-placeholder nocontent robots-nocontent&quot;&gt;

&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/01/13/us/hawaii-missile.html#story-continues-4&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;187&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3037&quot; id=&quot;story-continues-4&quot;&gt;They were taken into the mountains, Mr. Gerst said, and dropped off at a concrete bunker. They sheltered in place for about 15 minutes, he said, during which time they had no cell signal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;69&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3106&quot;&gt;“It was scary,” Mr. Gerst said. “I mean, there was no intel.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;296&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3402&quot;&gt;At Konawaena High School on the Island of Hawaii, where a high school wrestling championship was taking place, school officials, more accustomed to responding to alerts of high surf or tsunamis, moved people to the center of the gym as they tried to figure out how to take shelter from a missile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;322&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3724&quot;&gt;“Everyone cooperated,” said Kellye Krug, the athletic director at the school. “Once they were gathered, we let them use cellphones to reach loved ones. There were a couple kids who were emotional, the coaches were right there to console kids. After the retraction was issued, we gave kids time to reach out again.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;175&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3899&quot;&gt;Matt LoPresti, a state representative, told CNN that he and his family headed for a bathroom. “I was sitting in the bathtub with my children, saying our prayers,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;261&quot; data-total-count=&quot;4160&quot;&gt;In Washington, Lindsay Walters, a deputy press secretary, said that President Trump had been informed of the events. “The president has been briefed on the state of Hawaii’s emergency management exercise,” she said. “This was purely a state exercise.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;193&quot; data-total-count=&quot;4353&quot;&gt;“What happened today is totally inexcusable,” Senator Brian Schatz of Hawaii said. “The whole state was terrified. There needs to be tough and quick accountability and a fixed process.”&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;183&quot; data-total-count=&quot;4536&quot;&gt;The false alert was a stark reminder of what happens when the old realities of the nuclear age collide with the speed — and the potential for error — inherent in the internet age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;623&quot; data-total-count=&quot;5159&quot;&gt;The alert came at one of the worst possible moments: when tension with North Korea has been at one of the highest points in decades, and when the government of Kim Jong-un, North Korea’s leader, has promised more missile tests and threatened the possibility of an atmospheric nuclear test. But the cellphone alerting system was in the hands of state authorities; the detection of missile launches is the responsibility of the United States Strategic Command and Northern Command. It was the military — not Hawaiian officials — who were the first to come out and declare that there was no evidence of a missile launch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;500&quot; data-total-count=&quot;5659&quot;&gt;During the Cold War there were many false alarms. William J. Perry, the defense secretary during the Clinton administration, recalled in his memoir “My Journey at the Nuclear Brink” a moment in 1979 when, as an undersecretary of defense, he was awakened by a watch officer who reported that his computer system was showing 200 intercontinental ballistic missiles headed to the United States. “For one heart-stopping second I thought my worst nuclear nightmare had come true,” Mr. Perry wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;story-ad-3&quot; class=&quot;story-ad ad ad-placeholder nocontent robots-nocontent&quot;&gt;

&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/01/13/us/hawaii-missile.html#story-continues-5&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;273&quot; data-total-count=&quot;5932&quot; id=&quot;story-continues-5&quot;&gt;It turned out that a training tape had been mistakenly inserted in an early-warning system computer. No one woke up the president. But Mr. Perry went on to speculate what might have happened if such a warning had come “during the Cuban Missile Crisis or a Mideast war?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;263&quot; data-total-count=&quot;6195&quot;&gt;The United States faces an especially difficult problem today, not just because of tense relations with North Korea but also because of growing fears inside the military about the cyber vulnerability of both the nuclear warning system and nuclear control systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;285&quot; data-total-count=&quot;6480&quot;&gt;Because of its location, Hawaii — more than any other part of the United States — has been threatened by escalating tensions and the risks of war. Preparations had already begun, including an air-raid siren alert on Dec. 1, the start of what officials said would be monthly drills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;240&quot; data-total-count=&quot;6720&quot;&gt;On Friday, the day before the erroneous alert, several hundred people attended an event in Honolulu sponsored by the Chamber of Commerce in which military commanders, politicians and others discussed the threat to the islands’ population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;250&quot; data-total-count=&quot;6970&quot;&gt;“The U.S. is the designated recipient — and that’s because we are public enemy No. 1 to North Korea,” Dan Leak, a retired Air Force lieutenant general and Pacific Command deputy commander, was quoted as saying in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.staradvertiser.com/2018/01/13/hawaii-news/isle-military-brass-weigh-n-korean-threats/?HSA=ec9b0bad59102b42e8b49c9f38c01026a97b13f1&quot;&gt;Honolulu Star Advertiser.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;261&quot; data-total-count=&quot;7231&quot;&gt;In a keynote speech to the group, Admiral Harry B. Harris Jr., commander of the United States Pacific Command, was quoted as saying: “While the possibility of a nuclear strike is slim, we now live in a world where we must be prepared for every contingency.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;392&quot; data-total-count=&quot;7623&quot;&gt;The Hawaii Emergency Management Agency has been holding &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/hawaiiema?src=hash&quot;&gt;“are you ready” drills&lt;/a&gt;. As a chain of islands, Hawaii is subject to all kinds of threats — hurricanes, volcanoes, earthquakes and tsunamis — but officials have made clear that none is more urgent now than the threat of an attack by North Korea, given how little time there would be between an alert and the detonation of a bomb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;200&quot; data-total-count=&quot;7823&quot;&gt;The fifth page of an &lt;a href=&quot;https://dod.hawaii.gov/hiema/files/2017/09/20170921-Preparedness-brief-SEPT-2017.pdf&quot;&gt;emergency preparation pamphlet&lt;/a&gt; issued by the Hawaii Emergency Management Agency features a picture of a rocket lifting off. “Nuclear Threat — Unlikely But Cannot Ignore It.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;story-ad-4&quot; class=&quot;story-ad ad ad-placeholder nocontent robots-nocontent&quot;&gt;

&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/01/13/us/hawaii-missile.html#story-continues-6&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;162&quot; data-total-count=&quot;7985&quot; id=&quot;story-continues-6&quot;&gt;Mr. Rapoza, the agency spokesman, said that the shift-change drill was intended to make sure that incoming staff members were up to date with computer operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;236&quot; data-total-count=&quot;8221&quot;&gt;Mr. Rapoza said he did not know if anyone would be disciplined for the mistake. “At this point, our major concern is make sure we do what we need to do to reassure the public,” he said. “This is not a time for pointing fingers.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;360&quot; data-total-count=&quot;8581&quot;&gt;The panic the followed the alert — if relatively short-lived — gripped the island. There were &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.civilbeat.org/2018/01/false-missile-threat-mistakenly-triggered-as-part-of-internal-drill/&quot;&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt; of cars seeking shelter by parking inside a highway tunnel that cuts through a mountain. People in Hawaii tend to know what to do to protect themselves to threats of a tsunami or a hurricane. The prospect of nuclear annihilation was entirely new terrain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;223&quot; data-total-count=&quot;8804&quot;&gt;“So this was the most terrifying few minutes of my LIFE!” Paul Wilson, a professor at Brigham Young University in Hawaii, said on Twitter. “I just want to know why it took 38 minutes to announce it was a mistake?!?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;100&quot; data-total-count=&quot;8904&quot;&gt;Chris Tacker, a veteran who lives in Kealakekua, said the mistake had left her angry and frustrated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;155&quot; data-total-count=&quot;9059&quot;&gt;“I didn’t know where to go,” she said. “Anyone try to dig a hole in lava? Good luck trying to build a shelter. I’m stocking my liquor cabinet.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;90&quot; data-total-count=&quot;9149&quot;&gt;Still, she added, “If we don’t have our sense of humor about this, it’s all over.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;addenda&quot; class=&quot;addenda&quot; readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;story-addendum story-content theme-correction&quot; readability=&quot;38&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Correction: January 13, 2018&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;p&gt;An earlier version of this story misstated the distance between Pyongyang, North Korea, and Hawaii. It is about 4,600 miles, not 5,700 miles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;story-addendum story-content theme-correction&quot; readability=&quot;38&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Correction: January 13, 2018&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;p&gt;An earlier version of this story misstated the distance between Pyongyang, North Korea, and Hawaii. It is about 4,600 miles, not 5,700 miles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/01/13/us/hawaii-missile.html#whats-next&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2018 19:06:11 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>brandonhall</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/01/13/us/hawaii-missile.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Hawaii Panics After Alert About Incoming Missile Is Sent in Error</og:title>
<og:description>The alert appeared on cellphones warning people to “seek immediate shelter,” and said, “This is not a drill.” The authorities said it was a false alarm.</og:description>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/01/14/us/14xp-hawaii-sub2/14xp-hawaii-sub2-facebookJumbo-v3.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/01/13/us/hawaii-missile.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>iOS 11 Security</title>
<link>https://www.apple.com/business/docs/iOS_Security_Guide.pdf?</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.apple.com/business/docs/iOS_Security_Guide.pdf?</guid>
<description>&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/business/docs/iOS_Security_Guide.pdf?&quot;&gt;Download PDF&lt;/a&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2018 17:54:52 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Artemis2</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/01/13/us/hawaii-missile.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Hawaii Panics After Alert About Incoming Missile Is Sent in Error</og:title>
<og:description>The alert appeared on cellphones warning people to “seek immediate shelter,” and said, “This is not a drill.” The authorities said it was a false alarm.</og:description>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/01/14/us/14xp-hawaii-sub2/14xp-hawaii-sub2-facebookJumbo-v3.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.apple.com/business/docs/iOS_Security_Guide.pdf?</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>India has a hole where its middle class should be</title>
<link>https://www.economist.com/news/leaders/21734454-should-worry-both-government-and-companies-india-has-hole-where-its-middle-class-should-be</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.economist.com/news/leaders/21734454-should-worry-both-government-and-companies-india-has-hole-where-its-middle-class-should-be</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;AFTER China, where next? Over the past two decades, the world’s most populous country has become the market &lt;em class=&quot;Italic&quot;&gt;qua non&lt;/em&gt; of just about every global company seeking growth. As its economy slows, businesses are looking for the next set of consumers to keep the tills ringing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To many, India feels like the heir apparent. Its population will soon overtake its Asian rival’s. It occasionally grows at the kind of pace that propelled China to the status of economic superpower. And its middle class is thought by many to be in the early stages of the journey to prosperity that created hundreds of millions of Chinese consumers. Exuberant management consultants speak of a 300m-400m horde of potential frapuccino-sippers, Fiesta-drivers and globe-trotters. Rare is the chief executive who, upon visiting India, does not proclaim it as central to his or her plans. Some of that may be a diplomatic dose of flattery; much of it, from firms such as IKEA, SoftBank, Amazon and Starbucks, is sincerely meant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;newsletter-form&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;newsletter-form__message&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;newsletter-form__message-title&quot;&gt;Upgrade your inbox&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;newsletter-form__message-subtitle&quot;&gt;Receive our Daily Dispatch and Editors' Picks newsletters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;latest-updates-panel__container latest-updates-panel__container--blog-post&quot;&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;latest-updates-panel__body&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;latest-updates-panel__article-link&quot; readability=&quot;27&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__title&quot;&gt;Donald Trump gives the Iran nuclear deal a “last chance”&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;-1.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;latest-updates-panel__article-link&quot; readability=&quot;28&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__title&quot;&gt;In Germany, online hate speech has real-world consequences&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;latest-updates-panel__article-link&quot; readability=&quot;27&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__title&quot;&gt;Germany moves one step closer to a new government&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;latest-updates-panel__article-link&quot; readability=&quot;27&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__title&quot;&gt;How to run a bank in Afghanistan&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;-1.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;latest-updates-panel__article-link&quot; readability=&quot;28&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__title&quot;&gt;Trust me, I’m a journalist&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;latest-updates-panel__article-link&quot; readability=&quot;27&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__title&quot;&gt;Turkish Airlines bounces back to growth&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hold your elephants. The Indian middle class conjured up by the marketers and consultants scarcely exists. Firms peddling anything much beyond soap, matches and phone-credit are targeting a minuscule slice of the population (see &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.economist.com/news/briefing/21734382-multinational-businesses-relying-indian-consumers-face-disappointment-indias-missing-middle&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt;). The top 1% of Indian adults, a rich enclave of 8m inhabitants making at least $20,000 a year, equates to roughly Hong Kong in terms of population and average income. The next 9% is akin to central Europe, in the middle of the global wealth pack. The next 40% of India’s population neatly mirrors its combined South Asian poor neighbours, Bangladesh and Pakistan. The remaining half-billion or so are on a par with the most destitute bits of Africa. To be sure, global companies take the markets of central Europe seriously. Plenty of fortunes have been made there. But they are no China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;xhead&quot;&gt;Centre parting&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worse, the chances of India developing a middle class to match the Middle Kingdom’s are being throttled by growing inequality. The top 1% of earners pocketed nearly a third of all the extra income generated by economic growth between 1980 and 2014, according to new research from economists including Thomas Piketty. The well-off are ten times richer now than in 1980; those at the median have not even doubled their income. India has done a good job at getting those earning below $2 a day (at purchasing-power parity) to $3, but it has not matched other countries’ records in getting those on $3 a day to earning $5, those at $5 a day to $10, and so on. Middle earners in countries at India’s stage of development usually take more of the gains from growth. Eight in ten Indians cite inequality as a big problem, on a par with corruption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reasons for this failure are not mysterious. Decades of statist intervention meant that when a measure of liberalisation came in the early 1990s, only a few were able to benefit. The workforce is woefully unproductive—no surprise given the abysmal state of India’s education system, which churns out millions of adults equipped only for menial work. Its graduates go on to toil in small or micro-enterprises, operating informally; these “employ” 93% of all Indians. The great swell of middle-class jobs that China created as it became the workshop to the world is not to be found in India, because turning small businesses into productive large ones is made nigh-on impossible by bureaucracy. The fact that barely a quarter of women work—a share that has seen a precipitous decline in the past decade—only makes matters worse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good policy can do an enormous amount to improve prospects. However, hope should be tempered by realism. India is blessed with a deeply entrenched democratic system, but that is no shield against poor decisions. The sudden and brutal “demonetisation” of the economy in 2016 was meant to target fat cats, but ended up hurting everybody. And the path to prosperity walked by China, where manufacturing produced the jobs that pushed up incomes, is narrowing as automation limits opportunities for factory work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of which means that companies need to deal with the India that exists today rather than the one they wish to emerge. A strategy of waiting for Indians to develop a taste for products that the global middle class indulges in—cars as income per head crosses one threshold, foreign holidays when it crosses the next—may lead to decades of frustration. Only 3% of Indians have ever been on an aeroplane; only one in 45 owns a car or lorry. If nearly 300m Indians count as “middle class”, as HSBC has proclaimed, some of them make around $3 a day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;xhead&quot;&gt;Big market, smaller opportunities&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Companies would do better to “Indianise” their business by, for example, peddling wares using regional languages preferred by hundreds of millions of Indians. Pricing matters. Services proffered at the same price in India as Indiana will appeal to mere millions, not a billion. Even for someone in the top 10% of Indian earners, an annual Netflix subscription can cost over a week’s income; the equivalent in America would be around $3,000. Apple ads may plaster Mumbai, Delhi and Bangalore, but for only one in ten Indians would the latest iPhone represent less than half a year’s salary. The biggest consumer hits in India have been goods and services that offer stonking value: scooters and mobile telephony have grown fast, but only after prices tumbled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sharpest businesses work out which “enablers” will allow Indians to gain access to new goods. Electrification drives demand for fridges. Cheap mobile data (India is in the midst of a data-price war that has hugely benefited consumers) are a boon to streaming services. Logistics networks put together by e-commerce giants are for the first time making it possible for a consumer in a third-tier city to buy global fashion brands. A surge in consumer financing has put desirable baubles within reach of more Indians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Insofar as it is the job of politicians to create a consumer class, successive Indian governments have largely failed. Businesses hoping the Indian middle class will provide their next spurt of growth should be under no illusion. Companies will have to work very hard to turn potential into profits.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2018 11:11:27 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pbhowmic</dc:creator>
<og:description>That should worry both government and companies</og:description>
<og:image>https://cdn.static-economist.com/sites/default/files/images/print-edition/20180113_LDD002_0.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.economist.com/news/leaders/21734454-should-worry-both-government-and-companies-india-has-hole-where-its-middle-class-should-be</og:url>
<og:title>India has a hole where its middle class should be</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.economist.com/news/leaders/21734454-should-worry-both-government-and-companies-india-has-hole-where-its-middle-class-should-be</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Meltdown patch reduces mkfile(8) throughput to less than 1/3 on OS X</title>
<link>http://blog.metaobject.com/2018/01/meltdown-patch-reduces-mkfile8.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://blog.metaobject.com/2018/01/meltdown-patch-reduces-mkfile8.html</guid>
<description>In a &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.metaobject.com/2017/02/mkfile8-is-severely-syscall-limited-on.html&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;, I noted that &lt;code&gt;mkfile&lt;/code&gt; was severely syscall limited on OSX due to too small transaction sizes, managing only around 250MB/s on the built-in SSD hardware that could achieve 2GB/s with larger buffer size.
&lt;p&gt;I just retested the stock &lt;code&gt;mkfile&lt;/code&gt; after the meltdown patch, and I/O rates are now down to a measly 61.5MB/s, measured both by wall-clock (well, &lt;code&gt;time&lt;/code&gt;) and &lt;code&gt;iostat&lt;/code&gt;. That's actually 1/4 the throughtput measured before, but the new timing is also with APFS enabled. Using large buffers to minimize the number of sys calls and presumably effectively eliminates the meltdown penalty shows the maximum throughput with APFS to be reduced by about 20% compared to before, to 1.6GBs. Just to put that graphically, here's disk throughput pre-APFS/Meltdown and post, using either very large block sizes (1MB) or the 512 byte block sizes used by &lt;code&gt;mkfile&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://software-performance.com/downloads/meltdown-mkfile.png&quot; title=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;538&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So more than ever: use (really) large batches for I/O!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2018 09:43:34 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mpweiher</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://blog.metaobject.com/2018/01/meltdown-patch-reduces-mkfile8.html</og:url>
<og:title>Meltdown patch reduces mkfile(8) throughput to less than 1/3 on macOS</og:title>
<og:description>In a previous post , I noted that mkfile was severely syscall limited on OSX due to too small transaction sizes, managing only around 250MB...</og:description>
<og:image>https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/proxy/AhEqzpQLRZ55rruiokAYLnu7zI89KCvFHBAj5Y7ODM7WdQwvS26bZMbZ8XTZZ6siLGVVAScYJslUL24OzQyGiahjYZCr5K2sT0n23IUgs-PbnQ=w1200-h630-p-k-no-nu</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://blog.metaobject.com/2018/01/meltdown-patch-reduces-mkfile8.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>What Really Happened with Vista: An Insider&amp;#039;s Retrospective</title>
<link>https://blog.usejournal.com/what-really-happened-with-vista-an-insiders-retrospective-f713ee77c239</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.usejournal.com/what-really-happened-with-vista-an-insiders-retrospective-f713ee77c239</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*7tQ4kI9hVJxGDzo1Ejy42Q.jpeg&quot; data-width=&quot;1600&quot; data-height=&quot;1066&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*7tQ4kI9hVJxGDzo1Ejy42Q.jpeg&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*7tQ4kI9hVJxGDzo1Ejy42Q.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
It was a tradition for Windows team members to sign a poster (in this case an image of the DVD) upon release of a version of Windows. By the time the release party was over, there would be hundreds or thousands of signatures on the poster.
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;aef2&quot; id=&quot;aef2&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--figure&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Experience is something you don’t get until just after you need it.” — Steven Wright.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;9f36&quot; id=&quot;9f36&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--blockquote&quot;&gt;[Author’s Note: Originally published &lt;a href=&quot;http://benbobsworld.blogspot.com/2017/06/what-really-happened-with-vista.html&quot; data-href=&quot;http://benbobsworld.blogspot.com/2017/06/what-really-happened-with-vista.html&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, this blog has recently been getting a lot of hits as it was referenced in &lt;a href=&quot;https://read.acloud.guru/the-gospel-of-dogfooding-can-i-hear-an-amen-brother-1af4d82cf221&quot; data-href=&quot;https://read.acloud.guru/the-gospel-of-dogfooding-can-i-hear-an-amen-brother-1af4d82cf221&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;my recent blog on dogfooding&lt;/a&gt; so I decided to republish it on Medium in slightly different format and with a few updates.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;710e&quot; id=&quot;710e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I enjoyed reading Terry Crowley’s thoughtful blog (&lt;a href=&quot;https://hackernoon.com/what-really-happened-with-vista-4ca7ffb5a1a&quot; data-href=&quot;https://hackernoon.com/what-really-happened-with-vista-4ca7ffb5a1a&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;What Really Happened with Vista&lt;/a&gt;). Terry worked in the Office organization and did a fantastic job covering the complex machinations that went into Windows Vista and the related but doomed Longhorn project — from an outsider’s point of view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;ac5c&quot; id=&quot;ac5c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;He correctly identified many of the problems that dogged the project and I don’t mean to rehash any of them here. I figured it was only fair to try to offer an insider’s view of the same events. I can’t hope to be as eloquent or thorough as Terry but hope to shed some light on what went wrong. Ten years have gone by since the original release date of Windows Vista but the lessons seem more relevant now than ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;9a37&quot; id=&quot;9a37&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Windows is a beast. Thousands of developers, testers, program managers, security experts, UI designers, architects, you name it. And that’s before the supporting cast of HR people, recruiters, marketing folks, salespeople, lawyers, and of course many managers, directors, and vice presidents for each of the disciplines mentioned above. The entire ensemble cast is supported by many thousands of others at partner teams (within Microsoft as well as outside) that deliver everything from hardware underneath to device drivers and applications on top of the platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;0*wv_nOUEL0QQyfG7c.jpg&quot; data-width=&quot;400&quot; data-height=&quot;134&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/0*wv_nOUEL0QQyfG7c.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Aerial photo of the Windows team taken on the soccer field at Microsoft
&lt;p name=&quot;0a55&quot; id=&quot;0a55&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;Organizationally, at the time, Windows was really three teams: Core, Server, and Client. The core team delivered the “plumbing”, all the core components of the operating system (the kernel itself, storage, security, networking, device drivers, the installation and upgrade model, Win32, etc) shared by all versions of Windows. The server team, in turn, concentrated on technologies needed for the server market (terminal services, clustering and high availability, enterprise management tools, etc) while the client team was responsible for technologies related to the desktop and consumer releases (web browser, media player, graphics, shell, etc).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;9d54&quot; id=&quot;9d54&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;There were, of course, many reorgs but that basic structure was kept in place even as Windows grew in popularity and the teams grew in size. It would also be fair to say, culturally and organizationally speaking, that the core team was closer to the server team than it was to the client team — at least until after Vista shipped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;ab36&quot; id=&quot;ab36&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;By the time I arrived at Microsoft, in early 1998, Windows meant Windows NT — architecturally, organizationally, and product wise. The Windows 95 code base had largely been abandoned and Windows NT had been adopted for every personality of Windows — from the laptop to the clustered Server. Two years later, the Windows 95/98 code base would be resurrected for one last release — the much maligned Windows ME — but that project was executed by a small team while the vast majority worked on the NT code base. I was lucky enough to spend a dozen years in the belly of the beast, joining during the heyday of Windows 2000 development and staying through to the completion of Windows 7.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;9252&quot; id=&quot;9252&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I spent the first seven years of my tenure managing the teams responsible for storage, file systems, high availability/clustering, file level network protocols, distributed file systems, and related technologies. Later, I spent a year or two managing security for Microsoft. This included everything from security technologies in Windows to antivirus products as add-on solutions to security marketing and emergency response such as security patches. This was towards the tail end of Vista when viruses and worms were bringing Windows to its knees and when Microsoft’s reputation for building secure software had taken a massive beating in the marketplace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;cc15&quot; id=&quot;cc15&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;For the last three or four years, for the duration of the Windows 7 release, I managed all core development in Windows. That meant dev ownership of pretty much all technologies running “under the hood” and used by both the client and server teams. After Vista shipped, the Windows team was organized by disciplines and a “triad” (Dev, Test, PM) was put in charge at every level of the org so I ended up with two partners in crime. I managed the development teams while they managed, respectively, the test and program management teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;f776&quot; id=&quot;f776&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The Windows team had a history of attempting massive and ambitious projects that were often abandoned or repurposed after a few years. An earlier example was the ambitious Cairo project which was eventually gutted, with some pieces salvaged and shipped as part of Windows 2000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;ebc1&quot; id=&quot;ebc1&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;By far the biggest problem with Windows releases, in my humble opinion, was the duration of each release. On average, a release took about three years from inception to completion but only about six to nine months of that time was spent developing “new” code. The rest of the time was spent in integration, testing, alpha and beta periods — each lasting a few months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;0b91&quot; id=&quot;0b91&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Some projects needed more than six months of core development so they proceeded in parallel and merged with the main code base when ready. This meant that the main tree was almost always in a semi-broken state as large pieces of functionality were being integrated or replaced. Much tighter controls were put in place during the Windows 7 release to ensure a constantly healthy and functioning code base but earlier releases were plagued with daily instability for months at a time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;7c54&quot; id=&quot;7c54&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The chaotic nature of development often resulted in teams playing schedule chicken, convincing themselves and others that their code was in better shape than other projects, that they could “polish” the few remaining pieces of work just in time, so they would be allowed to checkin their component in a half-finished state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;57fe&quot; id=&quot;57fe&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The three year release cycle meant we rarely knew what the competitive landscape and external ecosystem would look like when we started a release. Missing a release meant cancellation (as the feature rarely made sense six years later) or, worse, banishment to Siberia — continued development on a component that was mostly ignored by the rest of the organization and doomed to eventual failure or irrelevance, but one that the team or the execs simply couldn’t bring themselves to abandon. I was personally responsible for a few such projects. Hindsight is 20/20.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;9e78&quot; id=&quot;9e78&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Given that each team was busy pushing their own agenda and features into the release, they often skimped on integration with other components, user interface, end to end testing, and ugly and tedious issues such as upgrade, leaving these thorny issues for the endgame. That, in turn, meant some teams quickly became bottlenecks as everyone jockeyed for their help in finishing their UI or upgrade testing at the last minute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;3792&quot; id=&quot;3792&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;At any given point in time, there were multiple major releases in progress as well as multiple side projects. Different teams were responsible for code bases in various states of health resulting in a model where “the rich got richer and the poor got poorer” over time — teams that fell behind, for one reason or another, more often than not stayed behind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;4ddf&quot; id=&quot;4ddf&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;As a project neared completion, program managers would start looking at requirements for the next release and developers in “healthy” (rich) teams would start implementing new code but vast parts of the organization (the poor) were still stuck on the current release. In particular, test teams rarely freed up from a release until it shipped so new code wasn’t thoroughly tested in the beginning of a project and “unhealthy” teams always lagged behind, putting the finishing touches on the current release and falling further and further behind. These teams were also often the ones with the lowest morale and highest attrition meaning that the engineers inherited fragile code they hadn’t written and hence didn’t understand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;5680&quot; id=&quot;5680&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;For most of the duration of Vista/Longhorn, I was responsible for the storage and file systems technologies. That meant I was involved with the WinFS effort although it was driven primarily by the SQL database team, a sister organization to the Windows team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;2224&quot; id=&quot;2224&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Bill Gates was personally involved at a very detailed level and was even jokingly referred to as “the WinFS PM”: the program manager responsible for the project. Hundreds, if not thousands, of man years of engineering went into an idea whose time had simply passed: what if we combine the query capabilities of the database with the streaming capabilities and unstructured data functionality of the file system and expose it as a programming paradigm for the creation of unique new “rich” applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;0fc6&quot; id=&quot;0fc6&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;In hindsight, it’s obvious that Google handily solved this problem, providing a seamless and fast indexing experience for unstructured data. And they did so for the entire internet, not just for your local disk. And you didn’t even need to rewrite your applications to take advantage of it. Even if WinFS had been successful, it would have taken years for applications to be rewritten to take advantage of its features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;15de&quot; id=&quot;15de&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;When Longhorn was cancelled and Vista was hastily put together from its smoldering embers, WinFS was kicked out of the OS release. It was pursued by the SQL team for a few more years as a standalone project. By this time, Windows had a built-in indexing engine and integrated search experience — implemented purely on the side with no application changes needed. So the relevance of WinFS became even murkier but the project still carried on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;9169&quot; id=&quot;9169&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The massive security related architectural changes in Longhorn were kept as part of the Windows Vista project. We had learned a lot about security in the rapidly expanding internet universe and wanted to apply those learnings at an architectural level in the OS to improve overall security for all customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;edec&quot; id=&quot;edec&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;We had no choice. Windows XP had shown that we were victims of our own success. A system that was designed for usability fell far short in terms of security when confronted with the realities of the internet age. Addressing these security problems meant the creation of a parallel project, Windows XP Service Pack 2, which (despite its name) was a huge undertaking sucking resources away from Longhorn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;faa5&quot; id=&quot;faa5&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;We couldn’t exactly go backwards in terms of security in our next major OS release. So it was that Vista became massively more secure than any earlier OS shipped by Microsoft, but in the process also managed to break application and device driver compatibility in an unprecedented manner for the ecosystem. Customers hated it because their apps broke and ecosystem partners hated it because they felt they didn’t have enough time to update and certify their drivers and applications as Vista was rushed out the door to compete with a resurgent Apple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;1d50&quot; id=&quot;1d50&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;In many cases, these security changes meant deep architectural changes were required to third party solutions. And most ecosystem vendors were not incented to invest heavily in their legacy apps. Some of these solutions took the unorthodox approach of modifying data structures and even instructions in the kernel in order to implement their functionality, bypassing APIs and multiprocessor locks that often caused havoc. Antivirus vendors were notorious for using this approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;d55f&quot; id=&quot;d55f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;In my role as the head of Microsoft security, I personally spent many years explaining to antivirus vendors why we would no longer allow them to “patch” kernel instructions and data structures in memory, why this was a security risk, and why they needed to use approved APIs going forward, that we would no longer support their legacy apps with deep hooks in the Windows kernel — the same ones that hackers were using to attack consumer systems. Our “friends”, the antivirus vendors, turned around and sued us, claiming we were blocking their livelihood and abusing our monopoly power! With friends like that, who needs enemies? They just wanted their old solutions to keep working even if that meant reducing the security of our mutual customer — the very thing they were supposed to be improving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;84a8&quot; id=&quot;84a8&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;There were so many seismic shifts happening in the computing industry during those years — the advent of the internet, the rise of the mobile phone, the emergence of cloud computing, the creation of new ad-supported business models, the viral growth of social media, the relentless march of Moore’s law, and the popularity of open source are just a few factors that assaulted Windows from all directions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;8ccc&quot; id=&quot;8ccc&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The response, not surprisingly for a wildly successful platform, was to dig its heels in and keep incrementally improving the existing system — innovator’s dilemma in a nutshell. The more code we added, the more complexity we created, the larger the team got, the bigger the ecosystem, the harder it became to leapfrog the competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;883a&quot; id=&quot;883a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;As if the competitive forces weren’t enough, this was also the time when armies of engineers and program managers spent countless hours, days, weeks, and months with representatives from the DOJ and corporate lawyers, documenting existing APIs from previous releases in order to comply with the government’s antitrust rulings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;8f9d&quot; id=&quot;8f9d&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The stark reality is that, at this point in its lifecycle, it took roughly three years to get a major release of Windows out the door and that was simply too slow for the fast moving market. WinFS, Security, and Managed Code were just a few of the massive projects on the agenda for Longhorn. There were also hundreds of smaller bets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;cc5c&quot; id=&quot;cc5c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;When you have a multi-thousand person organization and literally billions of customers, everyone gets a say. The same OS release that is supposed to work on the forthcoming tablet and smartphone footprint is also supposed to work on your laptop, in servers running in the data center, and in embedded devices such as NAS boxes “Powered by Windows” — not to mention on top of a hypervisor (HyperV) in the cloud. The requirements pulled the team in opposite directions as we tried to make forward progress on all segments of the market simultaneously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;0*iKcXepF1iH7PKzdR.&quot; data-width=&quot;400&quot; data-height=&quot;163&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/0*iKcXepF1iH7PKzdR.&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;e12b&quot; id=&quot;e12b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;It’s impossible to look at Longhorn and Vista in isolation. They make sense only when viewed in conjunction with the releases right before and right after them — Windows 2000 and XP on the one hand, Windows Server 2008 and Windows 7 on the other — and with full knowledge of the broader industry in retrospect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;7a0e&quot; id=&quot;7a0e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Windows was a victim of its own success. It had penetrated many markets successfully and each of those businesses now exerted some influence on the design of the operating system pulling it in different, and often conflicting, directions. Trying to deliver on all of those disparate requirements meant not satisfying any one of them completely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;3da8&quot; id=&quot;3da8&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;An architecture that had been massively successful during the nineties became bogged down a decade later because the world around us was changing ever more rapidly while the organization struggled to keep up with it. To be clear, we saw all these trends and we worked hard to respond to them but, if I may mix my metaphors, it was hard to turn an aircraft carrier on a dime when you’re two years pregnant with a three year release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;6b86&quot; id=&quot;6b86&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;In short, what we thought we knew three or four years ago when we planned a given OS release was laughably outdated and sometimes flat out wrong when the product finally shipped. The best thing we could have done was to enable incremental and friction-free delivery of new cloud based services to an ever-simplifying device. Instead, we kept adding features to an existing client-based monolithic system that required many months of testing before each release, slowing us down just when we needed to speed up. And, of course, we didn’t dare remove old pieces of functionality which were needed in the name of compatibility by applications already running on previous releases of Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;9243&quot; id=&quot;9243&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Now imagine supporting that same OS for a dozen years or more for a population of billions of customers, millions of companies, thousands of partners, hundreds of scenarios, and dozens of form factors — and you’ll begin to have an inkling of the support and compatibility nightmare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;1428&quot; id=&quot;1428&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;In hindsight, Linux has been more successful in this respect. The open source community and approach to software development is undoubtedly part of the solution. The modular and pluggable architecture of Unix/Linux is also a big architectural improvement in this respect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;31a1&quot; id=&quot;31a1&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;An organization, sooner or later, ships its org chart as its product; the Windows organization was no different. Open source doesn’t have that problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;0*jFv5Uf-5-tpur6cf.&quot; data-width=&quot;320&quot; data-height=&quot;240&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/0*jFv5Uf-5-tpur6cf.&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
The Windows “War room”, later renamed the “Ship room”.
&lt;p name=&quot;d7fe&quot; id=&quot;d7fe&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;Add to this, if you will, internal organizational dynamics and personalities. We all had our own favorite features, our own ecosystem partners pushing us to adopt new standards, to help them certify their solutions on the platform, to add APIs for their particular scenarios. We all had ambitions for proving that our technology, our idea would win the battle… if we could just get it into the next release of Windows and instantly pick up millions of customers. We believed it enough to fight for it in planning meetings and war rooms. We also all had managers who wanted to get promoted and increase their sphere of influence or their team size, as a proxy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;7e52&quot; id=&quot;7e52&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Dev and test teams were often at odds, the former pushing hard to get code checked in while the latter was rewarded for finding ever more complex and esoteric test cases that had no earthly resemblance to customer environments. The internal dynamics were complex, to say the least. As if that weren’t enough, at least once a year we had a massive reorg and new organizational dynamics to deal with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;35c8&quot; id=&quot;35c8&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;None of this, by the way, should be taken as excuses or apologies. It is not intended in that sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;a3c2&quot; id=&quot;a3c2&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Did we make mistakes? Yup, aplenty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;b9af&quot; id=&quot;b9af&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Did we &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;intentionally&lt;/em&gt; make bad decisions? Nope, not that I can ever recall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;937b&quot; id=&quot;937b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Was it an incredibly complex product with an amazingly huge ecosystem (the largest in the world at that time)? Yup, that it was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;17ce&quot; id=&quot;17ce&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Could we have done better? Yup, you bet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;9659&quot; id=&quot;9659&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Would we make different decisions today? Yup. Hindsight is 20/20. We didn’t know then what we know now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;f64b&quot; id=&quot;f64b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p graf--trailing&quot;&gt;Should we look back in dismay or regret? No, I prefer looking at it as lessons learned. I’m pretty sure none of us went on to make the same set of mistakes on later projects. We learned from the experience — which means we made a whole &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;different&lt;/em&gt; set of mistakes the next time. To err is human.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2018 08:08:06 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ductionist</dc:creator>
<og:title>What Really Happened with Vista: An Insider’s Retrospective</og:title>
<og:url>https://blog.usejournal.com/what-really-happened-with-vista-an-insiders-retrospective-f713ee77c239</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*7tQ4kI9hVJxGDzo1Ejy42Q.jpeg</og:image>
<og:description>“Experience is something you don’t get until just after you need it.” — Steven Wright.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.usejournal.com/what-really-happened-with-vista-an-insiders-retrospective-f713ee77c239?gi=f05b65fec911</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ask HN: Best introductory video courses on ML and Deep Learning?</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16138353</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16138353</guid>
<description>&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.55737704918033&quot;&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=&quot;#FF6600&quot;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.5947611710324&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;fatitem&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.9460708782743&quot;&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing&quot; id=&quot;16138353&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;title&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16138353&quot; class=&quot;storylink&quot;&gt;Ask HN: Best introductory video courses on ML and Deep Learning?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.75&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;subtext&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;score&quot; id=&quot;score_16138353&quot;&gt;279 points&lt;/span&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/user?id=rayalez&quot; class=&quot;hnuser&quot;&gt;rayalez&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;age&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16138353&quot;&gt;18 hours ago&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span id=&quot;unv_16138353&quot;/&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/hide?id=16138353&amp;amp;goto=item%3Fid%3D16138353&quot;&gt;hide&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://hn.algolia.com/?query=Ask%20HN%3A%20Best%20introductory%20video%20courses%20on%20ML%20and%20Deep%20Learning%3F&amp;amp;sort=byDate&amp;amp;dateRange=all&amp;amp;type=story&amp;amp;storyText=false&amp;amp;prefix&amp;amp;page=0&quot; class=&quot;hnpast&quot;&gt;past&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=Ask%20HN%3A%20Best%20introductory%20video%20courses%20on%20ML%20and%20Deep%20Learning%3F&quot;&gt;web&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/fave?id=16138353&amp;amp;auth=19d94d7688ec06d4ab36f833e61a13d993b06bbb&quot;&gt;favorite&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16138353&quot;&gt;34 comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;15.5&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;18&quot;&gt;Hi there! I'm looking for an easy way to get started with AI/ML/DL.
&lt;p&gt;I don't necessarily need to go super deep into details, I'm more interested in a practical high-level overview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know about Andrew Ng course [1], 3blue1brown videos [2], and Berkeley AI course [3]. What else would you recommend?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] https://www.coursera.org/learn/machine-learning&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[2] https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLZHQObOWTQDNU6R1_67000Dx_ZCJB-3pi&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[3] https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLIeooNSdhQE5kRrB71yu5yP9BRCJCSbMt&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;1.0096153846154&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;yclinks&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsguidelines.html&quot;&gt;Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsfaq.html&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Support&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/HackerNews/API&quot;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/security.html&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/lists&quot;&gt;Lists&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/bookmarklet.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Bookmarklet&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/dmca.html&quot;&gt;DMCA&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Apply to YC&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Contact&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2018 05:09:32 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rayalez</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16138353</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Cloud companies consider Intel rivals after security flaws found</title>
<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-cyber-microchips-cloud/cloud-companies-consider-intel-rivals-after-security-flaws-found-idUSKBN1EZ1A4</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.reuters.com/article/us-cyber-microchips-cloud/cloud-companies-consider-intel-rivals-after-security-flaws-found-idUSKBN1EZ1A4</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;SAN FRANCISCO (Reuters) - Some of Intel Corp’s (&lt;span id=&quot;“symbol_INTC.O_0”&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/finance/stocks/overview?symbol=INTC.O&quot;&gt;INTC.O&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;) data center customers, whose thousands of computers run cloud networks, are exploring using microchips from the market leader’s rivals to build new infrastructure after the discovery of security flaws affecting most chips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether Intel sees a slew of defectors or is forced to offer discounts, the company could take a hit to one of its fastest growing business units. Intel chips back 98 percent of data center operations, according to industry consultancy IDC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Security researchers last week disclosed flaws, dubbed Meltdown and Spectre, that could allow hackers to steal passwords or encryption keys on most types of computers, phones and cloud-based servers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft Corp (&lt;span id=&quot;“symbol_MSFT.O_1”&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/finance/stocks/overview?symbol=MSFT.O&quot;&gt;MSFT.O&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;) said on Tuesday the patches necessary to secure the threats could have a significant performance impact on servers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intel will help customers find the best approach in terms of security, performance and compatibility, it said in a statement on Tuesday. “For many customers, the performance element is foremost, and we are sharply focused on doing all we can to ensure that we meet their expectations.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alternatives include Advanced Micro Devices (&lt;span id=&quot;“symbol_AMD.O_2”&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/finance/stocks/overview?symbol=AMD.O&quot;&gt;AMD.O&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;), which shares with Intel a chip architecture called x86, or chips based on technology from ARM Holdings or graphics processing chips, which were developed for different tasks than Intel and AMD’s central processing units, or CPUs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Gleb Budman’s company, San Mateo-based online storage firm Backblaze, building with ARM chips would not be difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If ARM provides enough computing power at lower cost or lower power than x86, it would be a strong incentive for us to switch,” said Budman. “If the fix for x86 results in a dramatically decreased level of performance, that might increasingly push in favor of switching to ARM.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Infinitely Virtual, a Los Angeles-based cloud computing vendor, is counting on Intel to replace equipment or offer a rebate to make up for the loss in computing power, Chief Executive Adam Stern said in an interview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Image_container_1tVQo&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;Image_caption_KoNH1&quot;&gt;FILE PHOTO: A Microsoft logo is seen on an office building in New York City in this July 28, 2015 file photo. REUTERS/Mike Segar/File Photo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If Intel doesn’t step up and do something to make this right then we’re going to have to punish them in the marketplace by not purchasing their products,” said Stern, whose company relies exclusively on Intel processors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cloud providers said swapping out previously installed Intel chips for rivals’ would be too complex, but moving forward they could expand their networks using alternatives. Moving from Intel to AMD is easiest since AMD and Intel chips share a common core technology called the x86 instruction set, they said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ARM-based chips lag the speed of Intel’s x86 based chips for tasks such as searches, and software would have to be rewritten.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nvidia Corp’s (&lt;span id=&quot;“symbol_NVDA.O_3”&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/finance/stocks/overview?symbol=NVDA.O&quot;&gt;NVDA.O&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;) so-called graphical processing units, or GPUs, are not a direct replacement for Intel’s CPUs, but they are taking over the CPU’s role for new types of work like image recognition and speech recognition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Major technology companies had been experimenting with Intel alternatives even before the security flaws were revealed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last March, Microsoft committed to using ARM processors for its Azure cloud service, and in December, Microsoft Azure deployed Advanced Micro Devices processors in its data centers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alphabet Inc’s (&lt;span id=&quot;“symbol_GOOGL.O_4”&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/finance/stocks/overview?symbol=GOOGL.O&quot;&gt;GOOGL.O&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;) Google said in 2016 that it was designing a server based on International Business Machines Corp’s (&lt;span id=&quot;“symbol_IBM.N_5”&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/finance/stocks/overview?symbol=IBM.N&quot;&gt;IBM.N&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;) Power9 processor. And Amazon.com Inc’s (&lt;span id=&quot;“symbol_AMZN.O_6”&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/finance/stocks/overview?symbol=AMZN.O&quot;&gt;AMZN.O&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;) Amazon Web Services chose AMD graphics processing units for a graphics design service announced in September.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both Qualcomm Inc (&lt;span id=&quot;“symbol_QCOM.O_7”&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/finance/stocks/overview?symbol=QCOM.O&quot;&gt;QCOM.O&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;) and Cavium Inc (&lt;span id=&quot;“symbol_CAVM.O_8”&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/finance/stocks/overview?symbol=CAVM.O&quot;&gt;CAVM.O&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;) are developing ARM chips aimed at data centers. Cavium said it aimed to rival the performance of Intel chips for applications like databases and the content-delivery networks that help speed things like how fast online videos load.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cavium is working with Microsoft and “several other cloud” vendors, said Gopal Hegde, vice president of the data center processor group. Cavium and ARM rival Qualcomm work together to reduce the amount of software that has to be rewritten for ARM chips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cloudflare, a San Francisco cloud network company, has been evaluating ARM chips. The new security patches have not slowed its performance, but it will use the security issues as an opportunity to re-evaluate its use of Intel products, said Chief Technology Officer John Graham Cumming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Attribution_attribution_o4ojT&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Attribution_content_27_rw&quot;&gt;Reporting by Salvador Rodriguez and Stephen Nellis; Editing by Peter Henderson and Richard Chang&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;StandardArticleBody_trustBadgeContainer_1gqgJ&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;StandardArticleBody_trustBadgeTitle_7sKLj&quot;&gt;Our Standards:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;trustBadgeUrl&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thomsonreuters.com/en/about-us/trust-principles.html&quot;&gt;The Thomson Reuters Trust Principles.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2018 01:17:07 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jonbaer</dc:creator>
<og:title>Cloud companies consider Intel rivals after security flaws found</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-cyber-microchips-cloud/cloud-companies-consider-intel-rivals-after-security-flaws-found-idUSKBN1EZ1A4</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Some of Intel Corp's data center customers, whose thousands of computers run cloud networks, are exploring using microchips from the market leader's rivals to build new infrastructure after the discovery of security flaws affecting most chips.</og:description>
<og:image>https://s2.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;d=20180110&amp;t=2&amp;i=1220810356&amp;w=1200&amp;r=LYNXMPEE090O4</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-cyber-microchips-cloud/cloud-companies-consider-intel-rivals-after-security-flaws-found-idUSKBN1EZ1A4</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Half of the US government&amp;#039;s financial assets are student loans</title>
<link>https://community.finimize.com/t/graphic-of-the-week/1044/25?u=anders_finimize</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://community.finimize.com/t/graphic-of-the-week/1044/25?u=anders_finimize</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regards the chart- excellent idea! One add, and realize this add could be difficult to decide - a bit more detail to explain the chart - again realize that simplicity has great value - a good, clean graphic perfectly exemplified “one good picture is worth a thousand words”. Keep up the great job!! And concur on maps, same idea, same reasoning. Thanks!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m a datavizophile so love the concept. This week’s overseas cash chart is well done but would love to see more of the “so what?” I’m thinking how you could tie it to the US tax reform bill that would make it easier for companies to repatriate their overseas cash and maybe an insight about what the tech community is saying about that. Great job and please keep the CotW coming!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like it! Somehow make it sharable with a link that gives me credit for new subscribers when I share it &lt;img src=&quot;https://community.finimize.com/images/emoji/apple/slight_smile.png?v=5&quot; title=&quot;:slight_smile:&quot; class=&quot;emoji&quot; alt=&quot;:slight_smile:&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great idea! We want to try and do this when you share articles as well in the future&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;love the idea! new, interesting charts are usually the first thing I share with colleagues&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s amazing! We want to make the charts easily shareable - stay tuned! &lt;img src=&quot;https://community.finimize.com/images/emoji/apple/raised_hands.png?v=5&quot; title=&quot;:raised_hands:&quot; class=&quot;emoji&quot; alt=&quot;:raised_hands:&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The graphics are very simple to interpret, which further follows Finimize’s core goal to simplify. I like it a lot and I hope to see it continue! It will be useful if Finimize also had a historical fact section. Since Fake News is a hot topic, it is even more important to not only mention Finimize’s news in my conversations, but actual interesting facts that are relevant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://community.finimize.com/images/emoji/apple/tada.png?v=5&quot; title=&quot;:tada:&quot; class=&quot;emoji&quot; alt=&quot;:tada:&quot;/&gt; Happy new year Finimizers!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are your thoughts on this week’s chart?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;lightbox-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;a data-download-href=&quot;//community.finimize.com/uploads/default/bdcf80fd3acf7ae353dd7764ecbe9c9981df245c&quot; href=&quot;https://community.finimize.com/uploads/default/original/1X/bdcf80fd3acf7ae353dd7764ecbe9c9981df245c.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lightbox&quot; title=&quot;0105_Chart.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://community.finimize.com/uploads/default/optimized/1X/bdcf80fd3acf7ae353dd7764ecbe9c9981df245c_1_690x474.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;0105_Chart&quot; width=&quot;690&quot; height=&quot;474&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Really interesting to see how investors don’t tend to have a good January in comparison to November and December. Might provide an interesting debate around when you should enter the market. Love the idea of the GotW.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you have a spreadsheet version of this, I’d like to run some analysis on it and post back here!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wow super interesting. The consistency of last year vs previous is pretty weird - returns on a per month basis are much more modest than the peaks in other years, but no losses. Would be interested to hear some theories as to why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Global synchronous economic growth across US, Europe, Japan, EM as spurred by/in combination with accommodative monetary policy has greatly reduced volatility in the past few years. When stocks’ performance can be traced to a monetary policy implemented by the Fed, that rising tide is likely to lift all boats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this case, that tide has risen slowly. I think this is partly because investors have been reluctant to really jump behind this expansionary cycle/market rally after being BURNED twice in 10 years (2001, 2008). This lack of enthusiasm and low expectations for earnings and economic growth establish a low bar to clear. When the numbers turn up positive, it has slowly helped build momentum. If the numbers were “meh” or negative, investors were unsurprised and any punishment to stocks was less drastic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Volatility tends to come back towards the end of the cycle as monetary policy becomes less accommodative and sentiment has improved. Stock performance becomes driven more by individual company earnings and you start to see more distinct winners and losers. Heading into 2018, everyone is feeling pretty good about the markets (tax reform, bitcoin, positive earnings, new highs) which makes disappointment more likely. Disappointment can contribute to brining some of the volatility back to the market. Would not be surprised to see some of these more drastic market moves in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very interesting graph. I’m curious of what the monthly returns were during the ~1996-1999 years to see if what we’re seeing now is similar to the period leading up to the dot com bubble/crash or if there isn’t a correlation between the two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may find this interesting, Tom (covering 1926-2012). Historically, the worst month is September and the most volatile is April …&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;lightbox-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;a data-download-href=&quot;//community.finimize.com/uploads/default/7dc8dae5e65bc3e765e695a219ae9d798ed95753&quot; href=&quot;https://community.finimize.com/uploads/default/original/1X/7dc8dae5e65bc3e765e695a219ae9d798ed95753.png&quot; class=&quot;lightbox&quot; title=&quot;image.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://community.finimize.com/uploads/default/optimized/1X/7dc8dae5e65bc3e765e695a219ae9d798ed95753_1_446x500.png&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; width=&quot;446&quot; height=&quot;500&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here you are, Annie:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;lightbox-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;a data-download-href=&quot;//community.finimize.com/uploads/default/45419013aebc5900a490c4ce9906c5d3dfef7907&quot; href=&quot;https://community.finimize.com/uploads/default/original/1X/45419013aebc5900a490c4ce9906c5d3dfef7907.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lightbox&quot; title=&quot;image.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://community.finimize.com/uploads/default/optimized/1X/45419013aebc5900a490c4ce9906c5d3dfef7907_1_623x500.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; width=&quot;623&quot; height=&quot;500&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey &lt;a class=&quot;mention&quot; href=&quot;https://community.finimize.com/u/wes&quot;&gt;@wes&lt;/a&gt; ,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Managed to throw one together for you &lt;img src=&quot;https://community.finimize.com/images/emoji/apple/slight_smile.png?v=5&quot; title=&quot;:slight_smile:&quot; class=&quot;emoji&quot; alt=&quot;:slight_smile:&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;onebox googledocs&quot;&gt;&lt;header class=&quot;source&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1EeM9J0Ht7vOlRfpvXA2P0EDIiCks6R01H-iUqcHb7wc/edit?usp=sharing&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;docs.google.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/header&gt;&lt;article class=&quot;onebox-body&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1EeM9J0Ht7vOlRfpvXA2P0EDIiCks6R01H-iUqcHb7wc/edit?usp=sharing&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;A millennium in the markets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sheet1 S&amp;amp; P 500 Monthly Total Returns, www. finimize. com Year, Jan, Feb, Mar, Apr, May, Jun, Jul, Aug, Sep, Oct, Nov, Dec 2017, 1. 90%, 4. 00%, 0. 10%, 1. 00%, 1. 40%, 0. 60%, 2. 10%, 0. 30%, 2. 10%, 2. 30%, 3. 10%, 1. 10% 2016,- 5. 00%,- 0. 10%, 6. 80%, 0. 40%, 1. 80%, 0. 30%, 3. 70%, 0. 1...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;

&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Will be cool to see what you come up with!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks! Let’s see what stats I can remember from university and apply to this &lt;img src=&quot;https://community.finimize.com/images/emoji/apple/slight_smile.png?v=5&quot; title=&quot;:slight_smile:&quot; class=&quot;emoji&quot; alt=&quot;:slight_smile:&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://community.finimize.com/images/emoji/apple/thinking.png?v=5&quot; title=&quot;:thinking:&quot; class=&quot;emoji&quot; alt=&quot;:thinking:&quot;/&gt; What are your thoughts on today’s chart? Drop them below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;==&amp;gt; And for those coming in from HN, you can understand financial news in 3 minutes a day for free&lt;br/&gt;at &lt;a href=&quot;http://Finimize.com&quot;&gt;Finimize.com&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;https://community.finimize.com/images/emoji/apple/wink.png?v=5&quot; title=&quot;:wink:&quot; class=&quot;emoji&quot; alt=&quot;:wink:&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;lightbox-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;a data-download-href=&quot;//community.finimize.com/uploads/default/f3089a9bec11747dd71f96da6bdde9c5f0ff0f7f&quot; href=&quot;https://community.finimize.com/uploads/default/original/1X/f3089a9bec11747dd71f96da6bdde9c5f0ff0f7f.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lightbox&quot; title=&quot;0112_Chart.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://community.finimize.com/uploads/default/optimized/1X/f3089a9bec11747dd71f96da6bdde9c5f0ff0f7f_1_690x474.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;0112_Chart&quot; width=&quot;690&quot; height=&quot;474&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doesn’t seem sustainable to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congratulations Anders! You’ve made it to the top of HN &lt;img src=&quot;https://community.finimize.com/images/emoji/apple/sparkles.png?v=5&quot; title=&quot;:sparkles:&quot; class=&quot;emoji&quot; alt=&quot;:sparkles:&quot;/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://community.finimize.com/images/emoji/apple/sparkles.png?v=5&quot; title=&quot;:sparkles:&quot; class=&quot;emoji&quot; alt=&quot;:sparkles:&quot;/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://community.finimize.com/images/emoji/apple/sparkles.png?v=5&quot; title=&quot;:sparkles:&quot; class=&quot;emoji&quot; alt=&quot;:sparkles:&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;lightbox-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;a data-download-href=&quot;//community.finimize.com/uploads/default/d1fcdf82db71689695b015d1ac89846d1cebcb13&quot; href=&quot;https://community.finimize.com/uploads/default/original/1X/d1fcdf82db71689695b015d1ac89846d1cebcb13.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lightbox&quot; title=&quot;image.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://community.finimize.com/uploads/default/optimized/1X/d1fcdf82db71689695b015d1ac89846d1cebcb13_1_690x387.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; width=&quot;690&quot; height=&quot;387&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16136330&quot; class=&quot;onebox&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16136330&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P.S. to all of you from HN, don’t forget to check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://finimize.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Finimize.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also why don’t you put some BTC here to help me with my loans&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://community.finimize.com/images/emoji/apple/point_right.png?v=5&quot; title=&quot;:point_right:&quot; class=&quot;emoji&quot; alt=&quot;:point_right:&quot;/&gt; 1L9o9mst8c4ESEArwu5TAVuT4p7E3TveRT&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 21:10:07 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>prostoalex</dc:creator>
<og:image>http://community.finimize.com/uploads/default/optimized/1X/f3089a9bec11747dd71f96da6bdde9c5f0ff0f7f_1_690x474.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>http://community.finimize.com/t/graphic-of-the-week/1044/25?_escaped_fragment_=</og:url>
<og:title>Graphic of the week</og:title>
<og:description>🤔 What are your thoughts on today’s chart? Drop them below. ==&gt; And for those coming in from HN, you can understand financial news in 3 minutes a day for free at Finimize.com 😉 [0112_Chart]</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://community.finimize.com/t/graphic-of-the-week/1044/25?_escaped_fragment_=</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Advice for First Time Founders</title>
<link>https://blog.ycombinator.com/advice-for-first-time-founders/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.ycombinator.com/advice-for-first-time-founders/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;We operate a platform called Bookface for YC founders to connect with each other, ask questions, find intros, and share advice. Recently on Bookface &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/zachdixongg&quot;&gt;Zach Dixon&lt;/a&gt;, cofounder of the gaming company &lt;a href=&quot;https://playerslounge.co/&quot;&gt;Players’ Lounge&lt;/a&gt; (W18), asked a great question:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.&lt;/strong&gt; What are some things that you should’ve known as a first-time founder but did not?&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.&lt;/strong&gt; How did you learn them?&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.&lt;/strong&gt; How did they help?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were so many useful answers that we’re going to share them here. The numbered answers are replies to the three questions above. The lettered answers are multiple answers to the main question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;David Kofoed Wind – &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.peergrade.io/&quot;&gt;Peergrade&lt;/a&gt; (S17)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.&lt;/strong&gt; I should have known that recruiting a lot of free interns to solve vague tasks is not effective in reality. It generally leads to poor results, we spend a lot of time on communication and management and they don’t even have a really good time. Only hire for roles where you know exactly what the tasks are, and where you have tried doing it yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.&lt;/strong&gt; We have had many interns over the last two years, and in most cases it was not an effective way to spend our time or theirs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.&lt;/strong&gt; We now have a significantly smaller headcount, but a higher absolute productivity. Communication is simpler and the culture is better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Claudio Pinkus – &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codestream.com/&quot;&gt;CodeStream&lt;/a&gt; (W18)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.&lt;/strong&gt; We relied too much on other people’s advice, including board members and investors. When you are starting something new, it takes time to figure out what you have and how to make it work. All of us want to narrow it down to some analogy or comparison to simplify the analysis. You ask around and people tell you: “It’s like Salesforce for giraffes” or “It’s like McDonald’s for fish”. Then the model follows, and you are trying to make your business behave in a particular way to fit that model before you really know what it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my experience, only listening to your customer counts in the end. At Multiply.com we thought we were a social media company. It took us too long to understand that our users were using us as a craigslist with high res photos. Once we understood our users, we found a path forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.&lt;/strong&gt; We had to learn to ask the right questions. Our customers taught us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.&lt;/strong&gt; Our customers made us successful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fred Stevens-Smith – &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rainforestqa.com/&quot;&gt;Rainforest&lt;/a&gt; (S12)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A.&lt;/strong&gt; The importance of good communication with potential and existing investors. Done effectively it significantly increases your chances of keeping the company funded, and therefore of success. Done terribly it makes you borderline un-fundable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned it through being lashed by PG.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It helped by creating an open dialogue between our investors and us, and drove our focus and prioritization on the right things at the right time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B.&lt;/strong&gt; Investors never say no. They always say maybe. Everything is a no except a yes. And a yes is still about 50-50 to an actual term sheet. This is rational behavior by them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We learned it through brutal experience! I remember clearly a large, famous fund saying “maybe we want to do the whole round” – I immediately emailed our YC partners and said “we can stop fundraising, we’ve found our lead!” They quickly reminded me that unless you have a termsheet, the deal isn’t remotely done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It helps tremendously because you know where you are in the fundraising process. Fundraising is a pipeline, just like any sale. The best fundraisers are disciplined and honest about the state of their pipeline and what stage each funding opportunity is at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;C.&lt;/strong&gt; (More for B2B) Marketing tends to be overrated compared to product-market fit in the early days by founders, especially within a batch / cohort of strong companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned this from watching our cohort evolve. Most of the really hyped companies that we felt sure to be successful no longer exist. Some of the least-known and most ‘under the radar’ companies (including Rainforest) are still thriving. While we mustn’t confuse correlation with causality, I do think that many founders that get into top-tier accelerators get distracted by building a personal or business brand, because so many new opportunities to do so arise as a side-benefit of being part of YC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While distribution is important, building the right product and selling to the right users is more important. Luckily we were always terrible at marketing and so didn’t fall into this trap. I could have saved myself some hair loss if I hadn’t been judging myself for not knowing more reporters or speaking at more conferences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Jesse Vollmar – &lt;a href=&quot;https://farmlogs.com/&quot;&gt;Farmlogs&lt;/a&gt; (W12)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t undervalue experience. We made a lot of easily avoidable mistakes early on because we thought paying more to get experienced people wasn’t worth it. If you do need to hire (YC already gives enough advice on not over-hiring), then be sure to be honest about what you don’t know and bring on people that have that experience. Example: we thought because we knew how to code that we didn’t need senior engineers or anyone to manage engineering. Shouldn’t we just be able to teach ourselves? The answer was maybe, but with a lot of wasted time along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Adam Gibson – &lt;a href=&quot;https://skymind.ai/&quot;&gt;Skymind&lt;/a&gt; (W16)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.&lt;/strong&gt; Be ready for skepticism. Startups that survive take feedback well and adapt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.&lt;/strong&gt; Had a bit of mentorship at uni..but really it’s just been the grind. Failing 3 startups (~1 to 1.5 years per) tends to build that in to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.&lt;/strong&gt; Humbles you. It gets rid of that “look I”m a CEO” cockiness young founders run in to when they are (in my case I was 19/20)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t just write code and read PG blog posts. Sell and talk to users. Verify you’re solving a problem. A lot of people applying to YC think this is all it takes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.&lt;/strong&gt; Reality taught me this. Failed YC applications, Failing to close customers,..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.&lt;/strong&gt; Helps you navigate the market&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.&lt;/strong&gt; Do what you love or you’ll burn out I was the CEO 3 times, 4th time I’m the CTO and can’t be happier. A cofounder who compliments you was a saving grace for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.&lt;/strong&gt; Not sure someone can teach you this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.&lt;/strong&gt; Skymind is the best success I’ve had so far. It’s allowed real growth, I’m not 3.5 years in to this and still loving getting up every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.&lt;/strong&gt; Employees rely on you for income. You take on responsibility when you pay for a salary. Salaries also contribute to burn. Spend wisely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.&lt;/strong&gt; Missing employee deadlines on salaries when I was younger caused me to learn cash flow lessons and burn early.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.&lt;/strong&gt; Just like any startup you still make mistakes, but we weigh the real cost of a hire now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.&lt;/strong&gt; Being remote first was one of the best things we ever did. You need to overcommunicate due to being distributed but that overhead pays off when it comes to scaling quickly and finding a different kind of hire (lots of senior folks can only work remotely)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.&lt;/strong&gt; We stumbled in to this by accident. We’re an open core company. We hired from our community and became distributed by default&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s allowed us to scale, we’re not paying obscene amounts of money for real estate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.&lt;/strong&gt; Understand your limitations. For example, I’m not a consumer guy. Enterprise is both what I like doing and what I find myself suited for. I don’t mind wearing a suit and doing sales. It’s better than trying to understand what the masses want at the hopes that they’ll pay you $5/month and then not leave you the next month because the button switched from green to blue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.&lt;/strong&gt; Tried SMB at one of my previous startups, realized I just couldn’t handle the clientele&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.&lt;/strong&gt; Successfully selling to fortune 2000. It’s a lot easier to understand their needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The single most important piece of advice: never undervalue the relationship you have with your cofounders, your significant other, or their significant others. You’ll ultimately spend more time with your cofounders on a daily basis. Knowing your cofounder plans and ambitions and life situation, as well as their significant other’s, and whether they align with yours over a long horizon, really matter. It’s impossible in many cases to overcome incompatibility. Talk about this early, often, and make time for regular updates. Some things to think about: can you survive 3 months at a time apart? Can you move if the business requires it? How will workloads impact family planning? What kind of outcome are we looking for from the business? How long can it take for us to get there? There’s no wrong answers to any of these questions, so long as everyone is on the same page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A.&lt;/strong&gt; As a founder, hiring and firing are the only two jobs you’ll have from founding to exit as a constant. Being bad at either leads to suboptimal outcomes. Embrace the process for both. When you end up a multiple founder, you’ll have done both hundreds of times. They’re both equally difficult to master (and both can save your business at the critical time).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B.&lt;/strong&gt; Distraction comes in a million forms. If it isn’t going to add to your growth, it’s a distraction. Sometimes the line is murky — content is a great example of this. I’ve heard from numerous investors that a CEO that has time to blog doesn’t have time to do the rest of their job. Yet the companies with strong profiles often have tremendous amounts of content. When in doubt though, it’s a distraction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some things that feel like a lot of activity but (usually) aren’t without a well thought out plan: conferences, seeking press, forum participations, coffee with folks that aren’t your core customers, fundraising, micromanaging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;C.&lt;/strong&gt; Conflicting advice exists for a reason. You’re going to get a ton of it. What works for one company, at one stage, won’t work for another company at the same stage. “Don’t overhire” is a great mantra, until you’re bottlenecking scale. Waiting for less dilution makes perfect sense until you’re out of money. Figuring out what’s right for your company (and not being paralyzed by fear of being wrong if it turns out that’s the case) is the knack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D.&lt;/strong&gt; Periods of growth are amazing; periods of contraction are disheartening. Moving from a large team to a small team sucks. Avoid it if you can! If you can’t, double down on communicating the plan on how you’ll recover from where you are. If you don’t, you’ll only end up with folks that are excited about a paycheck, not the mission (and understandably so).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;E.&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t enter into relationships adversarially. It’s really easy to think in us versus them terms of investors, partners, and even cofounders. One of the most sincerely toxic things I’ve seen in startup is ultimately shortsighted thinking: investor X is useless, I shouldn’t have taken their money, they’re not letting me do what I want to do. Even if all of those things are true, our careers are longer than our individual startups… and when you entered into the relationship, you gained something. Spend as much emotional time as you can thinking about the perspectives of everyone around you, plan for the outcomes and concerns they might have, and maintain good relationships. When you start thinking in terms of us – our investment team, etc. you’ve won.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Erica Brescia – &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitnami.com/&quot;&gt;Bitnami&lt;/a&gt; (W13)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I haven’t seen: Hire people who have experience and that are better than you. There is so much romance in the startup world around hiring “ambitious, smart people who can get things done” without talking about the importance of building a team that has more experience than you in their fields around you. I was definitely guilty of looking for “diamonds in the rough” in the early days, rather than hiring true executives who could help us to grow and scale in roles ranging from BD to finance to engineering. You need to invest the time to understand what a great VP of X looks like and then go and sell someone with that skillset on joining you. Trying to hire bright people with no experience and hoping they will “figure it out” will almost certainly slow you down and cause you a lot of heartache when those people don’t scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Brad Van Vugt – &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sendwithus.com/&quot;&gt;Sendwithus&lt;/a&gt; (W14)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interviewing and hiring are skills that must be learned and practiced. Don’t wing it and then expect good results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a few bad hires, we realized we sucked at interviewing. This was an expensive way to learn. We solved it by bringing mentors and advisors into our interview process to teach us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Doug Hoang – &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.getenflux.com/&quot;&gt;Enflux&lt;/a&gt; (W16)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suck at firing people that need to be fired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The wrong way, which is what I’ve done a couple of times, is to fire someone and not properly gathering evidence as to why the person should be fired. To properly document performance, make sure to set expectations clear by give clear warnings and you and the employee should track progress through time task keeping and weekly (or maybe daily tasks, if you’re in a rush to fire) to do lists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Already, I have had these people come back and threaten to sue me. Otherwise, it is will end up with endless arguing. Getting sued is ultimate leverage against a startup , especially if during fundraising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The time and progress tracking really helped avoid these things. I wish I knew to do it from the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Kevin Tom – &lt;a href=&quot;http://yumbin.com/&quot;&gt;Yumbin&lt;/a&gt; (W14)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adding to Doug Hoang’s comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are firing people correctly it will not be a surprise to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Setting clear expectations helps them see what they need to change and if they are making those changes or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If they are not rising to the challenge, they know it and are not surprised if it ends with them moving on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Oleg Rogynskyy – &lt;a href=&quot;https://people.ai/&quot;&gt;People.ai&lt;/a&gt; (S16)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let go faster. It is very rare that an average employee will step up the game and become stellar. Meanwhile, a lot of the CEO’s and team’s time is spent trying to improve underperforming employee’s performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hence, an average/underperforming employee not only costs money but also imposes a severe morale and time-spent tax on a young company. The faster you let go, the faster you will bring in a materially better person who will do the job well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understand how important it is to take care of myself physically and mentally: sleeping, exercising, eating well and having a social life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we know, startup success is largely a function of its founders’ ability to execute, so investing in founders’ wellbeing is some of the highest ROI things the company can do. Very few things allow me or you to be more effective than sleeping 8h a night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought I should be like Elon Musk and tried working 100h a week and sleeping under my desk. I learned that in fact I’m not Elon Musk and found myself on the brink of a burnout a couple times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all know that startup is not a sprint. I don’t think it’s a marathon either, but rather a decade-long series of interval exercises (the ultimate Cross-Fit workout?). Instead of grinding away slowly at a steady pace (marathon) you’ll get the best results in the shortest time by working very intensely for a bit and then actively resting (sleep, family time, exercise, weekends) before the next interval.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s amazing to notice how much nicer person I am when I sleep enough and eat well. I thought I had ADD but realized that all the symptoms disappeared when I just slept more and exercise regularly. It’s stunning to realize that I’ll actually get the same amount of work done in 9.5h as I would in 14h previously (also: see &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parkinson%27s_law&quot;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parkinson%27s_law&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Alyona Medelyan – &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.getthematic.com/&quot;&gt;Thematic&lt;/a&gt; (S17)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.&lt;/strong&gt; Being a technical founder, I was told that I should do what I do best (tech) and bring in a business person as a CEO. I have listened to this advice and wasted a ton of time testing out two potential business people to join as co-founders. This was a mistake and I wish I knew that I have / can acquire the right skills to be a CEO. And the key skill here is “sales”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.&lt;/strong&gt; In the end, a friend recommended that I do an enterprise sales course. I learned that sales is about listening, relationships, process and discipline. And that sales applies to many other tasks of a founder (hiring, fundraising etc.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.&lt;/strong&gt; After a 2 day course, within 3 months I signed 3 significant first deals for our company. When focusing on growth during YC, as a 2-person team, we have 3x our MRR, signing up big brands without any existing personal connections. It also helped a lot with fundraising and hiring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Corry Flatt – &lt;a href=&quot;http://gobonfire.com/&quot;&gt;Bonfire&lt;/a&gt; (W15)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Aesthetics really matter&lt;/em&gt; in the early stage. Spend time and/or money early on nailing a cool logo and beautiful slide template. It really matters. Even copying other beautiful stuff is fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For getting our first 3/10/100 clients, the fact that we looked and sounded totally pro meant a lot. We seemed like a larger more innovative company because of it. Even for our Series A, the fact that our deck looked world-class helps build the belief. For hiring too it helps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People’s visual senses are easy to recruit to your cause and are powerful influencers. Why not look like you’re already a billion dollar company?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think this is under-optimized for &lt;em&gt;in general&lt;/em&gt; even within the YC community. So many cool companies that scream SMALL TIME given their visual sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Learning how to create FOMO&lt;/em&gt; is the most important negotiating dynamic you can learn. FOMO = fear of missing out. Whether it’s with fundraising, hiring, even clients (i.e. limited promotions etc) it is so so so powerful to have FOMO working for you. There are ways to do this that you figure out through trial an error. Time-boxing things. Have multiple options that are openly competing. Spend time developing strong back-up plans. Defining unique/custom value props for individuals. The fact is that everyone in startups will SAY “creating FOMO is great” but very little is actually written about creating it in various environments. So try to deliberately get good at this and your life will be much easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Maintain optionality on most decisions&lt;/em&gt;. I’m notorious internally for wanting to keep my options open for things – i.e. avoiding prematurely locking into something or trying to avoid making a decision among only 1 or 2 options. Yes, this can be detrimental too. But early stage is all about being shrewd about your decisions, and in my experience, often the best move is to just wait a bit or pursue some other avenue. I’ve found that with individuals on our team, often they want to suggest a single course of action vs. really exploring the problem space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hiring a VP? Get 3 top candidates that you’d be happy to work with right on the finish line, and now you’re negotiating from a position of strength.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making a big infrastructure choice? Try to see if there’s a way it can be less all-or-nothing. Is there a more incremental change we can do and then see what we learn over the next 90 days?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Garros Li – &lt;a href=&quot;https://edusight.co/&quot;&gt;Edusight&lt;/a&gt; (IK12)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.&lt;/strong&gt; If you plan on having cofounders, you need to determine how decisions will be made before starting a company together. Titles and vague “roles/responsibilities” won’t be enough. Play out scenarios to hash out decisions and set the right expectations, ask tough questions, and don’t let ego get in the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.&lt;/strong&gt; As the company grew, there was internal conflict and push-back on decisions being made at the company. This caused us to make decisions slowly and not react to the market/competition as quickly as we could’ve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.&lt;/strong&gt; My cofounders and I had several transparent discussions about this decision-making issue. We reflected and tried our best to come to a solution. Ultimately, we had clearer roles and decision-making structures so that we were able to make decisions much quicker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Kwindla Hultman Kramer – &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.daily.co&quot;&gt;Daily&lt;/a&gt; (W16)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are my top 5, based both on my own experience and the questions/trajectory I’ve seen other people go through over the years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A.&lt;/strong&gt; Nobody makes real progress on a startup until the startup is a full-time job.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B.&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t worry much (early on) about competition.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;C.&lt;/strong&gt; Tech startup success depends surprising little on technology.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D.&lt;/strong&gt; Fire faster.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;E.&lt;/strong&gt; At the beginning, almost all that matters is shipping quickly, then iterating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mostly I learned by failing at these things and trying to figure out, every week, what I could be doing better. In fact, I think that’s a really good meta-lesson: you have to focus on figuring out what you’re not doing well as a founder to get better at being a founder. That’s an every-day job, and it’s subtly different from figuring out what your company as a while needs to be doing better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most useful things I ever heard from an advisor was Alfred Lin’s description of what his job was when he was COO at Zappos. He said, “I came in every day and figured out what I could make 1% better.” This is both the best job definition I’ve ever heard for a growth-stage COO, but also a useful lens for approaching the job of founder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote a thing a while back about the above 5 things I didn’t know as a first-time founder. I just dug up the text and re-posted it. — &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@kwindla/five-things-that-are-non-obvious-as-a-first-time-startup-founder-9dd5a5d8a758&quot;&gt;https://medium.com/@kwindla/five-things-that-are-non-obvious-as-a-first-time-startup-founder-9dd5a5d8a758&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.&lt;/strong&gt; Some investors have more time than money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.&lt;/strong&gt; One investor in particular was just looking for a way out. So I did some research on him on angel.co, and crunchbase. He hasn’t invested in about 4 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.&lt;/strong&gt; Do research on the investors before accepting the meeting. Sometimes investors are trying to hide things from you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Ravi Parikh – &lt;a href=&quot;https://heapanalytics.com/&quot;&gt;Heap&lt;/a&gt; (W13)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A.&lt;/strong&gt; If you want the folks at your company to know something (e.g. high-level company goals, product direction, etc) it’s not enough to just say it once. You have to repeat it many times and weave it into the operational rhythm of the company. At any given time, an employee at your company has so much on their plate in terms of their day-to-day job and their personal life that “that one slide in your all hands with the mission statement” isn’t going to leave much of an impression. This is something I’ve heard other founders say but I didn’t fully get it until we hit ~50 employees and observed how hard it was to keep everyone on the same page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B.&lt;/strong&gt; Many founders I know are “first-principles” thinkers. Elon Musk quote about what this means: “I do think there’s a good framework for thinking. It is physics. You know, the sort of first principles reasoning. Generally I think there are — what I mean by that is, boil things down to their fundamental truths and reason up from there, as opposed to reasoning by analogy.” I think this can be a positive trait, but I’ve definitely been guilty of using this approach to the exclusion of relying on experience / advice from others. For example, we designed an early sales compensation plan from scratch via first-principles thinking. It seemed logical and reasonable at the time but it caused unforeseen problems that would have been very easy to avoid by just asking around at other SaaS companies how their plans were designed, understanding the logic behind those plans, and making changes based on what we thought was specific to our business, rather than inventing something new from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Amitav Chakravartty – &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vaycayhero.com/&quot;&gt;VaycayHero&lt;/a&gt; (W13)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A.&lt;/strong&gt; Hire slowly and fire quickly.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B.&lt;/strong&gt; Do not avoid the elephant in the room and though it’s hard, solve that issue first.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;C.&lt;/strong&gt; If you have more than one founder, let CEO focus outside and rest focus inside.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D.&lt;/strong&gt; Always keep eyes on how your business will make money.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;E.&lt;/strong&gt; If current idea is not make sense from business don’t hesitate to pivot.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;F.&lt;/strong&gt; Always keep looking for options while you know all doors are closed for you either it’s a customer acquisition or fundraising.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;G.&lt;/strong&gt; Use your fund wisely, track your earnings and cost from day 1.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;H.&lt;/strong&gt; Hire the people you need most and play the role before you hire for the position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Nathan Wenzel – &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.simplelegal.com/&quot;&gt;SimpleLegal&lt;/a&gt; (S13)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A.&lt;/strong&gt; Starting a company really is one of the hardest things you can choose to do to yourself. To add to the misery, the “hard part” of starting a company will last a lot longer than you might think. The Airbnb story of their first 1,000 days is incredible. I got lucky by having the best possible cofounder anyone could ever hope for and by having a supportive family who basically gave up 100% of their weekends for nearly a year so I could focus on launching the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B.&lt;/strong&gt; About 99% of what you read around early-stage startups who are “crushing it” is actually false. Founders have a great reality distortion field. It’s practically a requirement to make it through the tough times. But, comparing yourself to what you read in the tech press is a losing battle against a fictional opponent. Save yourself the mental anguish – don’t create unrealistic comparisons for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;C.&lt;/strong&gt; Venture investors want to hear crazy ideas, not pragmatic plans. When I first pitched investors, I was talking about how we would add customers slowly at first, because that’s how enterprise SaaS works. Honesty is always a good policy. But those pitches did not go well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D.&lt;/strong&gt; As a company grows from one stage to the next, you have to throw out what worked and change your mindset to the next mode for success. For the early team, optimize for ability to get things done, not any specific experience. Very few people can actually push a task over the finish line. But, once you hit initial traction, you have to switch to optimizing for hiring people who can build systems. Through that transition, adding bodies without systems and process only creates more chaos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;E.&lt;/strong&gt; The #1 requirement to be successful in your startup is to never stop. Just being sufficiently determined by itself is almost enough to make any decent idea work. Believing in that truth will make the tough days (and weeks and months) a little less painful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Ian Burgess – &lt;a href=&quot;http://validere.com/&quot;&gt;Validere&lt;/a&gt; (S16)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t fall in love with your technology. Fall in love with your customer. Many others posted something like this in the other thread already. Customers are the most important people to be talking to. Like most startups at the early stage, we underestimated how much we needed to spend time with customers and slightly overestimated how much we needed to talk to everyone else (e.g. investors, advisors, other founders, etc.). In the end, they are the only people that matter. As the startup community has become so big and connected, it is remarkably easy to be networking and taking advice every single day without talking to a single customer. As a university spinout, this can be particularly dangerous, as many of the prospective partners and advisors introduced to a startup by university tech transfer people (tech scouts at large companies, granting agencies, etc) do not have interests aligned with the startup’s success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.&lt;/strong&gt; We learned this most by basically tuning out everyone except for customers for about a year post YC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.&lt;/strong&gt; We were able to focus all in on an single customer base. We ended up with a fairly significant refinement of our solution that gives a much larger value to that customer-base, and we built close relationships with the most important decision makers and thought leaders in our industry, earning their trust while gaining their insights. These people became valuable promoters for us as well, both within their companies and across the industry. In one case, a key industry advisor ended up coming to join our team and has become a critical asset on BD. The traction followed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.&lt;/strong&gt; Pay deep attention to your co-founder relationship, especially when you encounter failure you haven’t been through before. They must be able to communicate respectfully and be a team player. Everyone says startups are hard and stick through it, but there are some hardships that are just not worth to stick with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.&lt;/strong&gt; The school of hard knocks. Spent some years in an unhealthy cofounder relationship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.&lt;/strong&gt; Relationship broke up, cofounder left. We made a much more practical plan, which has been executed very well by the team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Haseeb Awan – &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitaccess.ca/&quot;&gt;Bitaccess&lt;/a&gt; (S14)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.&lt;/strong&gt; Never underestimate others. Be good at firing people &amp;amp; don’t delay solving a problem. Take responsibility of failures and give credit to people who contribute. Inspire by doing rather than talking. Trust people and let them make mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.&lt;/strong&gt; Experiences and dealing with multiple people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.&lt;/strong&gt; Better execution &amp;amp; planning. Improvement in relationships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Ethan Perlstein – &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.perlara.com/&quot;&gt;Perlara&lt;/a&gt; (W16)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When starting out, I wish I learned as much about finances as I did about financing/fundraising. Tons of advice out there about how to raise a round but practically nothing on how to spend it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s why I committed to a pay-it-forward policy of open finances. It also helps that we’re a benefit corp, but anyone can share: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.perlara.com/blog/perlara-open-finances-2017/&quot;&gt;https://www.perlara.com/blog/perlara-open-finances-2017/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our financial data is most relevant to biotech/biopharma startups and discovery/preclinical companies, but the more founders put company financial data out there the easier it will be for the next first-timer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Gabriel Lim – &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.saleswhale.com/&quot;&gt;Saleswhale&lt;/a&gt; (S16)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The relationship between co-founders matter much more than you think. And having co-founders who are as equally committed, share similar values, able to communicate openly &amp;amp; honestly with each other, and genuinely like each other, turned out to be a lot more important than the initial product idea or engineering chops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learnt this when we were stuck in the trough of sorrow, and going through a very rough patch. There was a point in time I wanted to just throw in the towel, and give up – but the determination of not wanting to let my co-founders down kept me going. We were struggling hard to find product-market fit – and it was the constant brutal, intellectually honest conversations, mutual encouragement and rapid iteration that allowed us to find our stride – we ended up finding happy customers and raising a $1.2mm seed round; instead of giving up / failing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowing what I know now, I realise that I was incredibly lucky – and I’m not sure if I would start another startup again if I didn’t have co-founders (before the startup) whom I share this kind of relationship with. Doing a startup is brutally hard, and it’s even harder if your co-founders are not aligned, committed, or fond of each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;João de Paula – &lt;a href=&quot;https://glio.com/&quot;&gt;Glio&lt;/a&gt; (S13)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest responsibility of a founder is making the right decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not sleeping, not exercising, being unhealthy, stressing about paying bills, etc., will hurt your decisions – and your company. Take care of yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Delegate and automate day to day operations as much as possible. As founders, we usually have a tendency to be hands on with everything and it’s easier to congratulate yourself on fixing some random bug than to spend 3 days deciding how to tackle the current elephant in the room. It also has the bad side effect of hurting your culture by teaching your employees that you are are not CXO, but the chief firefighter. Make sure you are not too busy that you don’t have time and energy to focus on what you really should be doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Andrei Klochko – &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.airthium.com/&quot;&gt;Airthium&lt;/a&gt; (S17)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.&lt;/strong&gt; How much crucial time a founder can lose on the wrong events and meetings. Especially in France, startups are in a strong hype right now, and at the beginning I attended many such events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.&lt;/strong&gt; A few deadlines taught me the hard way that most, if not all, of those events are non-essential. On the other hand, a few of the right events in the valley (from YC and others) showed me just how efficient a gathering event should be. Finally, our advisor at our VC firm showed us just how useful an investor can (and should) be, if that investor pretends to be helping you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.&lt;/strong&gt; Now, me and my co-founder deny any event/meeting without a clear gain in knowledge (first or second order through the right connections) or investor money, that can be predicted beforehand. For example, we only meet with specialists or advisors with strong relevant connections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowing this beforehand would probably have saved us several month’s worth of work in the early days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Nate Matherson – &lt;a href=&quot;https://lendedu.com/&quot;&gt;LendEDU&lt;/a&gt; (W16)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.&lt;/strong&gt; I should have known not to hire expensive contractors, consultants, and advisors. As a startup you get bombarded by industry expert contractors and consultants who make big promises. It is easy to get caught up in the excitement. And it feels easy to hire someone to do a job or task (ex. PR, Business Development, Social Media, Customer Service) that is new to you. Unfortunately, these “expert” contractors and consultants always over promise and under deliver.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.&lt;/strong&gt; In our first couple years we hired a number of contractors, consultants, and advisors. Virtually all of them were fired for over charging and under delivering. We wasted quite a bit of money and a lot of time learning this lesson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.&lt;/strong&gt; We no longer hire outside contractors, consultants, or advisors. We push ourselves to learn by doing instead. As a founder you can do everything and anything that might be promised to you by a consultant…. and you will learn a whole lot through the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.helloinnerspace.org/&quot;&gt;Innerspace&lt;/a&gt; and improve your communication style so that you have a positive and productive relationship with your cofounder. It’s the number one thing and makes the difference!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Daniel Ahmadizadeh – &lt;a href=&quot;https://getrileynow.com/&quot;&gt;Riley&lt;/a&gt; (W17)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A.&lt;/strong&gt; Define your customer/who you are selling too as early/precisely as you can. We ran into product-market-fit issues during YC and allowed anyone to sign-up + were unclear as to who was in our target market. Had we have done this; it would have saved us time later on, though at the expense of growth during the batch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B.&lt;/strong&gt; Have a super clear message as to what your value proposition is to your customer (once defined!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;C.&lt;/strong&gt; Be ruthless when it comes to quality of service early on (we outsourced our operation and had no metrics/visibility over quality control). How did we learn this? Bucketing reasons for churn and looking into what patterns existed amongst our userbase by speaking with them on the phone and looking into their accounts. Michael Seibel, Lyle Fong, Gustaf Alstromer, and Walker Williams have also been incredibly helpful when it comes to surfacing areas where we can improve. Being in SF and doing office hours in person have accelerated our learning for sure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Chad Powell – &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomthat.com/&quot;&gt;BloomThat&lt;/a&gt; (S13)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A.&lt;/strong&gt; Compromise. As kids, we’re taught to compromise with our friends and peers. As cofounders, compromise makes bad products, results in horrible hires and can kill companies. Compromise accommodates egos and feelings rather than reach best outcomes. Never compromise. Instead, disagree behind closed doors then commit to one clear idea/hire/strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B.&lt;/strong&gt; Fundraising. Fundraising as a founding team is an awful strategy. It prevents an individual (likely the CEO) from building important relationships and telling a coherent story. Team fundraising signals that there’s either not a lot of work to be done at the office or the team is insecure and doesn’t trust the CEO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;C.&lt;/strong&gt; Cofounders. Define roles from the start and understand that in founding teams &amp;gt; 2, your leverage in major disagreements is effectively zero. Accordingly, soft skills like communication, empathy and the ability to convince others without playing politics or compromising are very important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D.&lt;/strong&gt; Venture Capital. Understanding the basics of venture capital may prevent raising too much/too little or taking institutional money at the wrong time. Raising the first priced round is hard and additional rounds are exponentially more difficult. If institutional investors from the first round do not invest a multiple of every $1 they invested in the previous round, you’re most likely default dead and everyone in the valley will know it. Of course there are exceptions, but in those cases knowledge of VC basics doesn’t matter much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;E.&lt;/strong&gt; Hiring. In tech-enabled companies, non-technical hires will rapidly outpace technical headcount. Larger teams will quickly define company culture and begin to split founding teams. When non-tech headcount &amp;gt; tech, fact based experimentation may lose to less ideal values within a startup.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 20:49:23 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>craigcannon</dc:creator>
<og:title>Advice for First Time Founders</og:title>
<og:url>https://blog.ycombinator.com/advice-for-first-time-founders/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>YC founders respond to the question: What are some things that you should've known as a first-time founder but did not?</og:description>
<og:image>http://blog.ycombinator.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/Advice-for-First-Time-Founders.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.ycombinator.com/advice-for-first-time-founders/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>