<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Bike crash left Spokane man unconscious, so his Apple Watch called 911</title>
<link>https://www.seattletimes.com/seattle-news/bike-crash-left-spokane-man-unconscious-but-his-apple-watch-called-911</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.seattletimes.com/seattle-news/bike-crash-left-spokane-man-unconscious-but-his-apple-watch-called-911</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;SPOKANE — Bob Burdett was on his bike just before noon on Sept. 15, heading to meet his son for an afternoon of mountain biking at Riverside State Park.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was several miles from his South Hill home and was going to be early for his 12:30 p.m. rendezvous with his son. As he coasted to the bottom of Doomsday Hill, Burdett, 62, approached a turn at a little more than 20 mph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His bike veered right. His body flew left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then his helmeted head hit the ground so hard it knocked him unconscious — hard enough for his Apple Watch to feel it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“A hit that hard could have killed me if I weren’t wearing it,” Burdett said. He had to replace the helmet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Burdett was bleeding profusely above his left eye. His shoulder and some ribs were put out of place. Road rash extended from his elbow to his shoulder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Burdett’s memory went black moments before the crash. Then he woke up in an ambulance on the  way to Providence Sacred Heart Medical Center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-container u-ofh u-bg-dark-off-white full-width-inset mb-4 mt-4 pt-0 ad-container-multiple body1&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-label font-micro u-tc u-mid-light-gray u-sans pv-10 u-upper&quot;&gt;Advertising&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His Apple Watch had called 911 through the fall-detection feature, which sends out an alert if the wearer is immobile for 60 seconds after a fall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His watch messaged emergency medical services at 12:02 p.m., and an ambulance was there within a minute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spokane Fire Chief Brian Schaeffer said Burdett’s crash is the first instance he’s aware of in Spokane where an Apple Watch alerted 911 to a hard fall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I think it’s just another opportunity for the fire service to leverage technology and use it to improve people’s lives,” Schaeffer said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spokane Valley Fire Department spokesperson Julie Happy said dispatchers did not recall an instance where an Apple Watch had alerted medical personnel to an accident scene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As opposed to social media or GPS tracking apps, Schaeffer said the Apple Watch fall-detection feature offers extra reassurance by not relying on a person to alert first responders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-container u-ofh u-bg-dark-off-white full-width-inset mb-4 mt-4 pt-0 ad-container-single&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-label font-micro u-tc u-mid-light-gray u-sans pv-10 u-upper&quot;&gt;Advertising&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It calls 911 automatically, which is pretty remarkable,” said Schaeffer, who uses the feature himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Apple Watch also alerted Gabe Burdett that his dad had fallen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gabe Burdett saw the text as he pulled up to their meeting spot in Riverside State Park, but his dad was already being treated. He searched the bottom of Doomsday Hill and was headed back toward Riverside State Park when his dad’s location updated to Providence Sacred Heart Medical Center.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It was amazing,” Gabe Burdett said. “I’m incredibly thankful.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He said the crash might have been spotted by other people in the Doomsday Hill area if not by the Apple Watch. But he imagines things playing out differently if his dad had been knocked unconscious on a more remote section of trail that day without an Apple Watch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s worth the price of admission for a piece of hardware like that. It’s invaluable,” Gabe Burdett said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He said he plans to buy his own Apple Watch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Burdett was released from the hospital the evening after his crash with a concussion and some stitches above his eye. A week after his crash, he went for another ride.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I tried to hop on the bike I crashed on and it definitely had a lot of issues,” he said with a laugh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Burdett started cycling in 2015 and the health app on his phone motivated him to keep pushing himself harder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It became one of those things where I knew I was going to be riding alone a lot,” he said. The fall-detection feature “was the reason I bought the watch in the first place.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I didn’t know if it was going to work, but I guess it does,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;div class=&quot;extended-byline&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;single-byline&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;name&quot;&gt;Jared Brown&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 21:42:55 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>throwaway413</dc:creator>
<og:title>Bike crash left Spokane man unconscious, so his Apple Watch called 911</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.seattletimes.com/seattle-news/bike-crash-left-spokane-man-unconscious-but-his-apple-watch-called-911/</og:url>
<og:image>https://static.seattletimes.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/09242019_teaser_tzr_104458-780x501.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>The Apple Watch has a fall-detection feature, which sends out an alert if the wearer is immobile for 60 seconds after a fall. Bob Burdett suffered a concussion and abrasions but is recovering — and has already been back on...</og:description>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.seattletimes.com/seattle-news/bike-crash-left-spokane-man-unconscious-but-his-apple-watch-called-911/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>OSSU: A path to a free self-taught education in computer science</title>
<link>https://github.com/ossu/computer-science</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/ossu/computer-science</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;Box-body&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content p-5&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/ab1e7ce255025d6c6b9431d43409217c21f70b6a/687474703a2f2f692e696d6775722e636f6d2f6b5959435874432e706e67&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/ab1e7ce255025d6c6b9431d43409217c21f70b6a/687474703a2f2f692e696d6775722e636f6d2f6b5959435874432e706e67&quot; alt=&quot;Open Source Society University (OSSU)&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/kYYCXtC.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;Open Source Society University&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;Path to a free self-taught education in Computer Science!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sindresorhus/awesome&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Awesome&quot; src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/13c4e50d88df7178ae1882a203ed57b641674f94/68747470733a2f2f63646e2e7261776769742e636f6d2f73696e647265736f726875732f617765736f6d652f643733303566333864323966656437386661383536353265336136336531353464643865383832392f6d656469612f62616467652e737667&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://cdn.rawgit.com/sindresorhus/awesome/d7305f38d29fed78fa85652e3a63e154dd8e8829/media/badge.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ossu/computer-science&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Open Source Society University - Computer Science&quot; src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/55b0f02a52ab8cc845332858f47f4e14b2182f83/68747470733a2f2f696d672e736869656c64732e696f2f62616467652f4f5353552d636f6d70757465722d2d736369656e63652d626c75652e737667&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/OSSU-computer--science-blue.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.patreon.com/ossu&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Contribute with OSSU on Patreon&quot; src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/69922d5ca3228de5530cf915a9854f35a4b80dda/68747470733a2f2f696d672e736869656c64732e696f2f62616467652f50617472656f6e2d636f6e747269627574652d79656c6c6f772e737667&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/Patreon-contribute-yellow.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The OSSU curriculum is a &lt;strong&gt;complete education in computer science&lt;/strong&gt; using online materials. It's not merely for career training or professional development. It's for those who want a proper, &lt;em&gt;well-rounded&lt;/em&gt; grounding in concepts fundamental to all computing disciplines, and for those who have the discipline, will, and (most importantly!) good habits to obtain this education largely on their own, but with support from a worldwide community of fellow learners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is designed according to the degree requirements of undergraduate computer science majors, minus general education (non-CS) requirements, as it is assumed most of the people following this curriculum are already educated outside the field of CS. The courses themselves are among the very best in the world, often coming from Harvard, Princeton, MIT, etc., but specifically chosen to meet the following criteria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Courses must&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Be open for enrollment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run regularly (ideally in self-paced format, otherwise running at least once a month or so)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fulfill the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ossu/computer-science/blob/dev/REQUIREMENTS.md&quot;&gt;academic requirements&lt;/a&gt; of OSSU&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fit neatly into the progression of the curriculum with respect to topics and difficulty level&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be of generally high quality in teaching materials and pedagogical principles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;When no course meets the above criteria, the coursework is supplemented with a book. When there are courses or books that don't fit into the curriculum but are otherwise of high quality, they belong in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ossu/computer-science/blob/dev/extras/courses.md&quot;&gt;extras/courses&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ossu/computer-science/blob/dev/extras/readings.md&quot;&gt;extras/readings&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Organization&lt;/strong&gt;. The curriculum is designed as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Intro CS&lt;/em&gt;: for students to try out CS and see if it's right for them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Core CS&lt;/em&gt;: corresponds roughly to the first three years of a computer science curriculum, taking classes that all majors would be required to take&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Advanced CS&lt;/em&gt;: corresponds roughly to the final year of a computer science curriculum, taking electives according to the student's interests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Final Project&lt;/em&gt;: a project for students to validate, consolidate, and display their knowledge, to be evaluated by their peers worldwide&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pro CS&lt;/em&gt;: graduate-level specializations students can elect to take after completing the above curriculum if they want to maximize their chances of getting a good job&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Duration&lt;/strong&gt;. It is possible to finish Core CS within about 2 years if you plan carefully and devote roughly 18-22 hours/week to your studies. Courses in Core CS should be taken linearly if possible, but since a perfectly linear progression is rarely possible, each class's prerequisites is specified so that you can design a logical but non-linear progression based on the class schedules and your own life plans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost&lt;/strong&gt;. All or nearly all course material prior to Pro CS is available for free. However, some courses may charge money for assignments/tests/projects to be graded. Note that Coursera offers &lt;a href=&quot;https://learner.coursera.help/hc/en-us/articles/209819033-Apply-for-Financial-Aid&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;financial aid&lt;/a&gt;. Decide how much or how little to spend based on your own time and budget; just remember that you can't purchase success!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Process&lt;/strong&gt;. Students can work through the curriculum alone or in groups, in order or out of order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;For grouping up, please use the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ossu/cohorts&quot;&gt;cohorts repository&lt;/a&gt; to find or create a cohort suited to you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We recommend doing all courses in Core CS, only skipping a course when you are certain that you've already learned the material previously.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For simplicity, we recommend working through courses (especially Core CS) in order from top to bottom, as they have already been &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Topological_sorting&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;topologically sorted&lt;/a&gt; by their prerequisites.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Courses in Advanced CS are electives. Choose one subject (e.g. Advanced programming) you want to become an expert in, and take all the courses under that heading. You can also create your own custom subject, but we recommend getting validation from the community on the subject you choose.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Content policy&lt;/strong&gt;. If you plan on showing off some of your coursework publicly, you must share only files that you are allowed to. &lt;em&gt;Do NOT disrespect the code of conduct&lt;/em&gt; that you signed in the beginning of each course!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to contribute&lt;/strong&gt;. Please see &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ossu/computer-science/blob/dev/CONTRIBUTING.md&quot;&gt;CONTRIBUTING&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Getting help&lt;/strong&gt;. Please check our &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ossu/computer-science/blob/dev/FAQ.md&quot;&gt;Frequently Asked Questions&lt;/a&gt;, and if you cannot find the answer, file an issue or talk to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ossu/computer-science#community&quot;&gt;friendly community&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Curriculum version&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code&gt;8.0.0&lt;/code&gt; (see &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ossu/computer-science/blob/dev/CHANGELOG.md&quot;&gt;CHANGELOG&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ossu/computer-science#core-cs&quot;&gt;Core CS&lt;/a&gt; assumes the student has already taken high school math and physics, including algebra, geometry, and pre-calculus. Some high school graduates will have already taken AP Calculus, but this is usually only about 3/4 of a college calculus class, so the calculus courses in the curriculum are still recommended.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ossu/computer-science#advanced-cs&quot;&gt;Advanced CS&lt;/a&gt; assumes the student has already taken the entirety of Core CS and is knowledgeable enough now to decide which electives to take.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Note that &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ossu/computer-science#advanced-systems&quot;&gt;Advanced systems&lt;/a&gt; assumes the student has taken a basic physics course (e.g. AP Physics in high school).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Introduction to Computer Science&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This course will introduce you to the world of computer science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Topics covered&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code&gt;computation&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;imperative programming&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;basic data structures and algorithms&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;and more&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Core CS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All coursework under Core CS is &lt;strong&gt;required&lt;/strong&gt;, unless otherwise indicated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Core programming&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Topics covered&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code&gt;functional programming&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;design for testing&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;program requirements&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;common design patterns&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;unit testing&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;object-oriented design&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;Java&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;static typing&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;dynamic typing&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;ML-family languages (via Standard ML)&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;Lisp-family languages (via Racket)&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;Ruby&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;and more&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Readings&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Core math&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Topics covered&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code&gt;linear transformations&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;matrices&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;vectors&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;mathematical proofs&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;number theory&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;differential calculus&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;integral calculus&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;sequences and series&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;discrete mathematics&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;basic statistics&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;O-notation&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;graph theory&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;vector calculus&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;discrete probability&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;and more&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;: Students struggling with MIT Math for CS can consider taking the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/specializations/discrete-mathematics&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Discrete Mathematics Specialization&lt;/a&gt; first. It is more interactive but less comprehensive, and it costs money to unlock full interactivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Core systems&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Topics covered&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code&gt;procedural programming&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;manual memory management&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;boolean algebra&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;gate logic&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;memory&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;computer architecture&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;assembly&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;machine language&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;virtual machines&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;high-level languages&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;compilers&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;operating systems&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;network protocols&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;and more&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Core theory&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Topics covered&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code&gt;divide and conquer&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;sorting and searching&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;randomized algorithms&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;graph search&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;shortest paths&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;data structures&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;greedy algorithms&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;minimum spanning trees&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;dynamic programming&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;NP-completeness&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;and more&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Core applications&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Topics covered&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code&gt;Agile methodology&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;REST&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;software specifications&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;refactoring&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;relational databases&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;transaction processing&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;data modeling&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;neural networks&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;supervised learning&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;unsupervised learning&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;OpenGL&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;raytracing&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;block ciphers&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;authentication&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;public key encryption&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;and more&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Advanced CS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After completing &lt;strong&gt;every required course&lt;/strong&gt; in Core CS, students should choose a subset of courses from Advanced CS based on interest. Not every course from a subcategory needs to be taken. But students should take &lt;em&gt;every&lt;/em&gt; course that is relevant to the field they intend to go into.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Advanced CS study should then end with one of the Specializations under &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ossu/computer-science#advanced-applications&quot;&gt;Advanced applications&lt;/a&gt;. A Specialization's Capstone, if taken, may act as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ossu/computer-science#final-project&quot;&gt;Final project&lt;/a&gt;, if permitted by the Honor Code of the course. If not, or if a student chooses not to take the Capstone, then a separate Final project will need to be done to complete this curriculum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Advanced programming&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Topics covered&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code&gt;debugging theory and practice&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;goal-oriented programming&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;GPU programming&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;CUDA&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;parallel computing&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;object-oriented analysis and design&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;UML&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;large-scale software architecture and design&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;and more&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Advanced math&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Topics covered&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code&gt;parametric equations&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;polar coordinate systems&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;multivariable integrals&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;multivariable differentials&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;probability theory&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;and more&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Advanced systems&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Topics covered&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code&gt;digital signaling&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;combinational logic&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;CMOS technologies&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;sequential logic&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;finite state machines&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;processor instruction sets&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;caches&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;pipelining&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;virtualization&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;parallel processing&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;virtual memory&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;synchronization primitives&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;system call interface&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;and more&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Note&lt;/strong&gt;: These courses assume knowledge of basic physics. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ossu/computer-science/blob/dev/FAQ.md#why-is-the-curriculum-missing-some-pre-requisites&quot;&gt;Why?&lt;/a&gt;) If you are struggling, you can find a physics MOOC or utilize the materials from Khan Academy: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.khanacademy.org/science/physics&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Khan Academy - Physics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Advanced theory&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Topics covered&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code&gt;formal languages&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;Turing machines&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;computability&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;event-driven concurrency&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;automata&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;distributed shared memory&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;consensus algorithms&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;state machine replication&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;computational geometry theory&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;propositional logic&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;relational logic&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;Herbrand logic&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;concept lattices&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;game trees&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;and more&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Advanced applications&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These Coursera Specializations all end with a Capstone project. Depending on the course, you may be able to utilize the Capstone as your Final Project for this Computer Science curriculum. Note that doing a Specialization with the Capstone at the end always costs money. So if you don't wish to spend money or use the Capstone as your Final, it may be possible to take the courses in the Specialization for free by manually searching for them, but not all allow this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Final project&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OSS University is &lt;strong&gt;project-focused&lt;/strong&gt;. You are encouraged to do the assignments and exams for each course, but what really matters is whether you can &lt;em&gt;use&lt;/em&gt; your knowledge to solve a real world problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After you've gotten through all of Core CS and the parts of Advanced CS relevant to you, you should think about a problem that you can solve using the knowledge you've acquired. Not only does real project work look great on a resume, but the project will also &lt;em&gt;validate&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;consolidate&lt;/em&gt; your knowledge. You can create something entirely new, or you can find an existing project that needs help via websites like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codetriage.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;CodeTriage&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.firsttimersonly.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;First Timers Only&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another option is using the Capstone project from taking one of the Specializations in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ossu/computer-science#advanced-applications&quot;&gt;Advanced applications&lt;/a&gt;; whether or not this makes sense depends on the course, the project, and whether or not the course's Honor Code permits you to display your work publicly. In some cases, it may not be permitted; do &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; violate your course's Honor Code!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put the OSSU-CS badge in the README of your repository! &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ossu/computer-science&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/55b0f02a52ab8cc845332858f47f4e14b2182f83/68747470733a2f2f696d672e736869656c64732e696f2f62616467652f4f5353552d636f6d70757465722d2d736369656e63652d626c75652e737667&quot; alt=&quot;Open Source Society University - Computer Science&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/OSSU-computer--science-blue.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Markdown: &lt;code&gt;[![Open Source Society University - Computer Science](https://img.shields.io/badge/OSSU-computer--science-blue.svg)](https://github.com/ossu/computer-science)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HTML: &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ossu/computer-science&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img alt=&quot;Open Source Society University - Computer Science&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/OSSU-computer--science-blue.svg&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Evaluation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon completing your final project, submit your project's information to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ossu/computer-science/blob/dev/PROJECTS.md&quot;&gt;PROJECTS&lt;/a&gt; via a pull request and use our &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ossu/computer-science#community&quot;&gt;community&lt;/a&gt; channels to announce it to your fellow students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your peers and mentors from OSSU will then informally evaluate your project. You will not be &quot;graded&quot; in the traditional sense — everyone has their own measurements for what they consider a success. The purpose of the evaluation is to act as your first announcement to the world that you are a computer scientist and to get experience listening to feedback — both positive and negative — and taking it in stride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final project evaluation has a second purpose: to evaluate whether OSSU, through its community and curriculum, is successful in its mission to guide independent learners in obtaining a world-class computer science education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Cooperative work&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can create this project alone or with other students! &lt;strong&gt;We love cooperative work&lt;/strong&gt;! Use our &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ossu/computer-science#community&quot;&gt;channels&lt;/a&gt; to communicate with other fellows to combine and create new projects!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Which programming languages should I use?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My friend, here is the best part of liberty! You can use &lt;strong&gt;any&lt;/strong&gt; language that you want to complete the final project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The important thing is to &lt;strong&gt;internalize&lt;/strong&gt; the core concepts and to be able to use them with whatever tool (programming language) that you wish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Pro CS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After completing the requirements of the curriculum above, you will have completed the equivalent of a full bachelor's degree in Computer Science, or quite close to one. You can stop in the Advanced CS section, but the next step to completing your studies is to develop skills and knowledge in a specific domain. Many of these courses are graduate-level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choose one or more of the following &lt;strong&gt;specializations&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These aren't the only specializations you can choose. Check the following websites for &lt;strong&gt;more options&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Where to go next?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Look for a job as a developer!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ossu/computer-science/blob/dev/extras/readings.md&quot;&gt;readings&lt;/a&gt; for classic books you can read that will sharpen your skills and expand your knowledge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Join a local developer meetup (e.g. via &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.meetup.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;meetup.com&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pay attention to emerging technologies in the world of software development:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Explore the &lt;strong&gt;actor model&lt;/strong&gt; through &lt;a href=&quot;http://elixir-lang.org/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Elixir&lt;/a&gt;, a new functional programming language for the web based on the battle-tested Erlang Virtual Machine!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explore &lt;strong&gt;borrowing and lifetimes&lt;/strong&gt; through &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rust-lang.org/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Rust&lt;/a&gt;, a systems language which achieves memory- and thread-safety without a garbage collector!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explore &lt;strong&gt;dependent type systems&lt;/strong&gt; through &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.idris-lang.org/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Idris&lt;/a&gt;, a new Haskell-inspired language with unprecedented support for type-driven development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/15a5e1c20a0a4a22f1db4c752e6629c81614ab7e/687474703a2f2f692e696d6775722e636f6d2f5245514b3056552e6a7067&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/15a5e1c20a0a4a22f1db4c752e6629c81614ab7e/687474703a2f2f692e696d6775722e636f6d2f5245514b3056552e6a7067&quot; alt=&quot;keep learning&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/REQK0VU.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ossu/code-of-conduct&quot;&gt;OSSU's code of conduct&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Subscribe to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://tinyletter.com/ossu&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use our &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ossu/forum&quot;&gt;forum&lt;/a&gt; if you need some help.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can also interact through &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ossu/computer-science/issues&quot;&gt;GitHub issues&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We also have a chat room! &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitter.im/open-source-society/computer-science?utm_campaign=pr-badge&amp;amp;utm_content=badge&amp;amp;utm_medium=badge&amp;amp;utm_source=badge&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/da2edb525cde1455a622c58c0effc3a90b9a181c/68747470733a2f2f6261646765732e6769747465722e696d2f4a6f696e253230436861742e737667&quot; alt=&quot;Join the chat at https://gitter.im/open-source-society/computer-science&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://badges.gitter.im/Join%20Chat.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add &lt;strong&gt;Open Source Society University&lt;/strong&gt; to your &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/school/11272443/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Linkedin&lt;/a&gt; profile!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PS&lt;/strong&gt;: A forum is an ideal way to interact with other students as we do not lose important discussions, which usually occur in communication via chat apps. &lt;strong&gt;Please use our forum for important discussions&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How to show your progress&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Create an account in &lt;a href=&quot;https://trello.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Trello&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy &lt;a href=&quot;https://trello.com/b/7NIfi40X&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; board to your personal account. See how to copy a board &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.trello.com/article/802-copying-cards-lists-or-boards&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now that you have a copy of our official board, you just need to pass the cards to the &lt;code&gt;Doing&lt;/code&gt; column or &lt;code&gt;Done&lt;/code&gt; column as you progress in your study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also have &lt;strong&gt;labels&lt;/strong&gt; to help you have more control through the process. The meaning of each of these labels is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Main Curriculum&lt;/code&gt;: cards with that label represent courses that are listed in our curriculum.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Extra Resources&lt;/code&gt;: cards with that label represent courses that were added by the student.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Doing&lt;/code&gt;: cards with that label represent courses the student is current doing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Done&lt;/code&gt;: cards with that label represent courses finished by the student. Those cards should also have the link for at least one project/article built with the knowledge acquired in such course.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Section&lt;/code&gt;: cards with that label represent the section that we have in our curriculum. Those cards with the &lt;code&gt;Section&lt;/code&gt; label are only to help the organization of the Done column. You should put the &lt;em&gt;Course's cards&lt;/em&gt; below its respective &lt;em&gt;Section's card&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The intention of this board is to provide our students a way to track their progress, and also the ability to show their progress through a public page for friends, family, employers, etc. You can change the status of your board to be &lt;em&gt;public&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;private&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Team&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 17:51:18 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>paulygarcia</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars3.githubusercontent.com/u/14957346?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>ossu/computer-science</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/ossu/computer-science</og:url>
<og:description>:mortar_board: Path to a free self-taught education in Computer Science! - ossu/computer-science</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/ossu/computer-science</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>WeWork CEO, Adam Neumann, Stepping Down Under Pressure</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/09/24/business/dealbook/wework-ceo-adam-neumann.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2019/09/24/business/dealbook/wework-ceo-adam-neumann.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Adam Neumann turned WeWork into one of the most valuable start-ups in the world largely through the force of his outsize personality. He persuaded investors to give him billions of dollars and employees to believe that the shared-office company was changing the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;That same mix of ambition and idealism forced Mr. Neumann to step down as chief executive after a lengthy board meeting on Tuesday. He was under pressure from directors and investors after he led a botched attempt to take the closely watched company public. The announcement marked a swift and stunning fall for Mr. Neumann, who had enormous control over WeWork and spoke about the company with missionary zeal — he has said the company aimed to “elevate the world’s consciousness.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;WeWork expanded with breakneck speed in recent years, putting co-working locations in dozens of countries and becoming the largest commercial tenant in Manhattan. It attracted a private valuation of $47 billion as recently as January, with top Wall Street bankers telling Mr. Neumann that his company could be worth a lot more once its shares traded on the stock market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Neumann, 40, was the company’s charismatic frontman, a towering, hard-partying Israeli with long hair and a penchant for leather jackets and tequila. He used the company to fund his pet projects, maintained a lavish lifestyle complete with private jets and luxury homes. And Mr. Neumann was highly impulsive — he once banned meat at the company, forcing executives to quickly come up with a rationale for why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;When it came time to list WeWork on the stock market, this all proved too much for the institutional investors who make or break the fortunes of publicly traded companies. After the company &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/08/14/business/dealbook/wework-ipo.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;filed its offering documents with the Securities and Exchange Commission&lt;/a&gt; last month, investors began scrutinizing its business model and Mr. Neumann’s behavior, and sentiment quickly turned against WeWork.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Last week, the company &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/09/17/business/dealbook/wework-ipo.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;decided to delay&lt;/a&gt; its offering after bankers and investors signaled that the company might be worth just $15 billion. Now, with his resignation as chief executive, Mr. Neumann joins an ignominious club that includes Travis Kalanick, who was ousted as the chief of Uber before he could take it public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“Spending too much too soon on unproven business models only heightens the risk that a company’s race for global domination can become a race to oblivion,” said Len Sherman, an adjunct professor at Columbia Business School and an expert in entrepreneurship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Neumann will be nonexecutive chairman of WeWork’s parent, the We Company. WeWork named two current executives, Sebastian Gunningham and Artie Minson, co-chief executives. The company will conduct a search for a new permanent chief executive, according to four people who asked for anonymity to discuss a delicate subject.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;A WeWork spokeswoman, Gwen Rocco, said in an emailed statement, “There is no search for another chief executive either underway or planned.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Neumann, who controlled a majority of the shareholder votes, was ultimately the one who decided to step down. But he did so after he lost the support of some of his key backers, including SoftBank, the Japanese technology giant, which is WeWork’s biggest outside investor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;On Sunday, Mr. Neumann met with the chairman and chief executive of JPMorgan Chase, Jamie Dimon, and later in the day had dinner with Bruce Dunlevie, a partner at Benchmark Capital and a director of the We Company, to discuss his options. Then on Tuesday, Mr. Neumann and his board met at the Midtown Manhattan offices of JPMorgan to nail down the management shake-up, according to two people familiar with the meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In a statement, Mr. Neumann said the scrutiny of his personal life and management was hurting the company. “Since the announcement of our I.P.O., too much of the focus has been placed on me,” he said in a note to employees that was reviewed by The New York Times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The management shake-up is the most significant step the company has taken to win over Wall Street after the botched initial public offering and signals that power may be swinging away from the founders of fast-growing businesses toward investors. Other high-flying start-ups, including the ride-hailing companies Uber and Lyft, have also struggled this year, and their share prices have fallen sharply after their stock market debuts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“Investors saw through Lyft, and they saw through Uber as well,” said Matt Stoller, a fellow at the Open Markets Institute, a Washington think tank. “This one has simply been rejected. Investors are saying, ‘We’re not going to tolerate this nonsense anymore.’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;One of investors’ biggest concerns has been that Mr. Neumann exercised too much control over the company through special voting shares. He will now lose much of his power over the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Each of his special shares will have three votes, down from 20 votes earlier this year, according to two people briefed on the change, who were not authorized to disclose it. Mr. Neumann will not be able to control more than a minority of the board’s directors, and he won’t have control over any of the board’s committees, according to one of those people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Analysts also criticized deals in which Mr. Neumann took stakes in buildings and leased them to WeWork, an arrangement that might have allowed him to personally profit at the company’s expense. A WeWork entity later took over the management of the properties, a move designed to eliminate conflicts of interest. He also returned a $5.9 million payment the company made to him for use of the trademarked word “We.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“The fundamental question here is: Does it help to be a really strong and at times abrasive personality to be innovative?” said Walter Isaacson, a professor of history at Tulane University who knows Mr. Neumann. “The answer is it doesn’t always help, and at times it goes too far.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Still, Mr. Neumann’s departure as chief executive might not be enough to bolster interest in WeWork’s shares. Investors have also expressed concerns that the company is spending too much money and is unlikely to turn a profit in the foreseeable future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;WeWork is now considering slowing down that growth sharply. It could lay off as many as 5,000 employees, according to one person briefed on the matter. We employed more than 12,500 employees as of June 30, according to its regulatory filings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The company’s losses have ballooned as it has spent huge sums taking on new leases and refurbishing its locations. In the first half of the year, its operating losses totaled $1.37 billion, about twice as much as it lost in the same period last year. The company used up nearly $1.5 billion to run its business and expand in the first half of the year and had just under $2.5 billion in cash at the end of June.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;WeWork had hoped to raise up to $4 billion from the public offering and up to $6 billion more in bank loans that were contingent on the I.P.O. The new chief executives will now have to perform a delicate dance with investors. They probably need to slow We’s expansion to allay fears about its finances, but not so much that the company loses its allure as a turbocharged business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“Our core business is strong, and we will be taking clear actions to balance WeWork’s high growth, profitability and unique member experience while also evaluating the optimal timing for an I.P.O.,” Mr. Minson and Mr. Gunningham said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Despite the company’s problems, analysts say, Mr. Neumann and WeWork have been the driving force in the flexible-office-space business, which is transforming commercial real estate. Professionals, start-ups and big corporations alike are flocking to locations run by WeWork and others, attracted by shorter leases and nicely designed spaces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;But it might take a more seasoned chief executive who has run businesses with a steady hand to convince investors that WeWork can become a sustainable business, not just a fast-growing one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Other so-called unicorn companies — businesses backed by venture capital firms that are worth more than $1 billion — have had to make similar transitions. In 2017, under pressure from investors, Mr. Kalanick resigned as chief executive of Uber. He was replaced by Dara Khosrowshahi, a former chief executive at Expedia, who set about trying to improve the culture at Uber and preparing the company for an I.P.O.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Uber and WeWork have something else in common: Their growth was fueled in part by money from SoftBank. The Japanese company has plowed billions of dollars into WeWork and other start-ups. Softbank’s chief executive, Masayoshi Son, has given founders of those businesses wide leeway and has looked the other way at excesses until investors in the public markets push back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 17:02:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>aaronbrethorst</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/09/24/business/dealbook/wework-ceo-adam-neumann.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>WeWork C.E.O. Adam Neumann Steps Down Under Pressure</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/09/25/business/25wework-silo/25wework-silo-facebookJumbo-v3.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>The shake-up is the most significant step that the start-up, valued at nearly $50 billion at one point, has taken to win over Wall Street after a botched I.P.O.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/09/24/business/dealbook/wework-ceo-adam-neumann.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Prashanth Chandrasekar Replacing Joel Spolsky as Stack Overflow CEO</title>
<link>https://stackoverflow.blog/2019/09/24/announcing-stack-overflows-new-ceo-prashanth-chandrasekar?</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://stackoverflow.blog/2019/09/24/announcing-stack-overflows-new-ceo-prashanth-chandrasekar?</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;m-post-card__excerpt&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;Custom Filters are available to public Stack Overflow users today! The new feature allows a new way of navigating and discovering questions that are relevant to you on Stack Overflow....&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;m-post-card__excerpt&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;A loooong time ago, we used to post an annual “State of the Stack” update on the company and community. Then at some point it became an infographic which was…...&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;m-post-card__excerpt&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;In 2009, Stack Overflow’s three employees (or associates, as they were then called) were inspired to end the year by giving back. To recognize our amazing community of moderators, we...&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 16:55:27 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>matrixunloaded</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Announcing Stack Overflow’s New CEO, Prashanth Chandrasekar! - Stack Overflow Blog</og:title>
<og:description>Last March, I shared that we were starting to look for a new CEO for Stack Overflow. We were looking for that rare combination of someone who could foster the community while accelerating the growth of our businesses, especially Teams, where we are starting to close many huge deals and becoming a hyper-growth enterprise software company very quickly. This is not something I’m particularly good at, and I thought it was time to bring on more experienced leadership.The Board of Directors nominated a search committee and we went through almost 200 candidates. It speaks to how well respected  a company Stack Overflow is that we found ourselves in the rare position of having plenty of highly qualified executives who were excited about the opportunity. Nevertheless, one of them really stood out, and we are pleased to let you know that we have selected Prashanth Chandrasekar as our next CEO. His first day will be October 1st.Prashanth was born in Bangalore, India, the city with the highest number of Stack Overflow users in the world, one of the global capitals for software developers writing the script for the future. He started out as a software engineer before moving over to management. He has a BS in Computer Engineering from the University of Maine, a Masters in Engineering Management from Cornell, and an MBA from Harvard. He worked at Capgemini as a management consultant and Barclays as an investment banker in their technology group before joining Rackspace in San Antonio, Texas.At Rackspace, Prashanth really proved his mettle, creating from scratch a completely new business unit inside the company, the Global Managed Public Clouds Business. This group serves companies around the world who need help running on AWS, Azure, Google, and so on. Under his leadership, Rackspace successfully pivoted from a leading managed hosting company to a cloud services company. And he did this while working with developers both inside Rackspace and outside, so he understands our vision of “writing the script for the future” better than anyone I’ve met.This is an exciting time for Stack Overflow, and we have some big goals for the year ahead. We want to make Stack Overflow more diverse, inclusive, and welcoming. And we want to make it possible for knowledge workers everywhere to use Stack Overflow to get answers to the proprietary questions that are specific to their organizations and teams. We’re doing great work and making great progress in these areas, and I’m confident that Prashanth has some great ideas about how to move forward faster on all our goals.As you know, I’m keeping my job as Chairman of the Board, so I’ll continue to be closely involved. Being Stack Overflow’s CEO has been an honor, and I can’t wait to see the things the team accomplishes in the year ahead. This will be a great new chapter for Stack Overflow.</og:description>
<og:url>https://stackoverflow.blog/2019/09/24/announcing-stack-overflows-new-ceo-prashanth-chandrasekar/</og:url>
<og:image>https://149351115.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Image-from-iOS.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://stackoverflow.blog/2019/09/24/announcing-stack-overflows-new-ceo-prashanth-chandrasekar/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>WeWork’s Adam Neumann Steps Down as CEO</title>
<link>https://www.wsj.com/articles/neumann-expected-to-step-down-as-we-ceo-11569343912?mod=rsswn</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.wsj.com/articles/neumann-expected-to-step-down-as-we-ceo-11569343912?mod=rsswn</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;is-lead-inset&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div data-layout=&quot;header&amp;#10;              &quot; data-layout-mobile=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&amp;#10;        media-object&amp;#10;        type-InsetMediaIllustration&amp;#10;          header&amp;#10;  article__inset&amp;#10;        article__inset--type-InsetMediaIllustration&amp;#10;          article__inset--header&amp;#10;    article__inset--lead&amp;#10;  &quot;&gt;
      
      
          
    &lt;figure class=&quot;media-object-image enlarge-image renoImageFormat- img-header article__inset__image&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot;&gt;&lt;div data-mobile-ratio=&quot;66.66666666666666%&quot; data-layout-ratio=&quot;66.66666666666666%&quot; data-subtype=&quot;photo&quot; class=&quot;image-container  responsive-media article__inset__image__image&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img srcset=&quot;https://images.wsj.net/im-109851?width=140&amp;amp;size=1.5 140w,&amp;#10;https://images.wsj.net/im-109851?width=540&amp;amp;size=1.5 540w,&amp;#10;https://images.wsj.net/im-109851?width=620&amp;amp;size=1.5 620w,&amp;#10;https://images.wsj.net/im-109851?width=700&amp;amp;size=1.5 700w,&amp;#10;https://images.wsj.net/im-109851?width=860&amp;amp;size=1.5 860w,&amp;#10;https://images.wsj.net/im-109851?width=1260&amp;amp;size=1.5 1260w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 140px) 100px,&amp;#10;(max-width: 540px) 500px,&amp;#10;(max-width: 620px) 580px,&amp;#10;(max-width: 700px) 660px,&amp;#10;(max-width: 860px) 820px,&amp;#10;1260px&quot; src=&quot;https://images.wsj.net/im-109851?width=620&amp;amp;size=1.5&quot; data-enlarge=&quot;https://images.wsj.net/im-109851?width=1260&amp;amp;size=1.5&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Adam Neumann’s eccentric behavior that was detailed in a WSJ article last week, including a...&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

    
      &lt;figcaption class=&quot;wsj-article-caption article__inset__image__caption&quot; itemprop=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;wsj-article-caption-content&quot;&gt;Adam Neumann’s eccentric behavior that was detailed in a WSJ article last week, including a party-heavy lifestyle, undercut his position. &lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;wsj-article-credit article__inset__image__caption__credit&quot; itemprop=&quot;creator&quot;&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;wsj-article-credit-tag&quot;&gt;
              Photo: 
            &lt;/span&gt;
        Michael Kovac/Getty Images for WeWork
          &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt; 
    &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;clearfix byline-wrap&quot;&gt;


      
      &lt;div class=&quot;byline article__byline&quot;&gt;
      
      
          &lt;span&gt;By&lt;/span&gt;
              &lt;div class=&quot;author mobile-scrim hasMenu&quot; data-scrim=&quot;{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;author&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;header&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Eliot Brown&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;subhead&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;The Wall Street Journal&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;list&amp;quot;:[{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;bio&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.wsj.com/news/author/7207&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Biography&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;twitter&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://twitter.com/eliotwb&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;@eliotwb&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;facebook&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://facebook.com/&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;email&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;mailto:Eliot.Brown@wsj.com&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Eliot.Brown@wsj.com&amp;quot;}]}&quot;&gt;
                  &lt;span class=&quot;name&quot; itemprop=&quot;name&quot;&gt;Eliot Brown&lt;/span&gt;, 
                  &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;author mobile-scrim hasMenu&quot; data-scrim=&quot;{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;author&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;header&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Dana Cimilluca&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;subhead&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;The Wall Street Journal&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;list&amp;quot;:[{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;bio&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.wsj.com/news/author/7235&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Biography&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;twitter&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://twitter.com/danacimilluca&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;@danacimilluca&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;email&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;mailto:Dana.Cimilluca@wsj.com&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Dana.Cimilluca@wsj.com&amp;quot;}]}&quot;&gt;
                  &lt;span class=&quot;name&quot; itemprop=&quot;name&quot;&gt;Dana Cimilluca&lt;/span&gt;, 
                  &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;author mobile-scrim hasMenu&quot; data-scrim=&quot;{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;author&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;header&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;David Benoit&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;subhead&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;The Wall Street Journal&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;list&amp;quot;:[{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;bio&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.wsj.com/news/author/7444&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Biography&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;twitter&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://twitter.com/DaveCBenoit&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;@DaveCBenoit&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;facebook&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://facebook.com/&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;email&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;mailto:David.Benoit@wsj.com&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;David.Benoit@wsj.com&amp;quot;}]}&quot;&gt;
                  &lt;span class=&quot;name&quot; itemprop=&quot;name&quot;&gt;David Benoit&lt;/span&gt; and 
                  &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;author mobile-scrim hasMenu&quot; data-scrim=&quot;{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;author&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;header&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Maureen Farrell&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;subhead&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;The Wall Street Journal&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;list&amp;quot;:[{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;bio&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.wsj.com/news/author/8560&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Biography&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;twitter&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://twitter.com/Maureenmfarrell&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;@Maureenmfarrell&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;email&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;mailto:maureen.farrell@wsj.com&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;maureen.farrell@wsj.com&amp;quot;}]}&quot;&gt;
                  &lt;span class=&quot;name&quot; itemprop=&quot;name&quot;&gt;Maureen Farrell&lt;/span&gt;
                  &lt;/div&gt;

      &lt;/div&gt;
      
        &lt;time class=&quot;timestamp article__timestamp flexbox__flex--1&quot;&gt;
          Updated Sept. 24, 2019 8:22 pm ET
        &lt;/time&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  

  &lt;div class=&quot;article-content &quot;&gt;

       &lt;p&gt;Barely a week ago, 




      Adam Neumann




       was sitting atop the most valuable startup in the U.S. and getting ready for a blockbuster initial public offering. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Now he’s out of a job. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The charismatic, high-octane 40-year-old resigned under pressure as chief executive of WeWork’s parent Tuesday and will relinquish control of the shared-office company, a rapid fall from grace that is unusual in the startup world and bucks a trend of highflying founders with unchecked control.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;div class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt;




       &lt;p&gt;Mr. Neumann and his advisers agreed following a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/adam-neumanns-ouster-wouldnt-change-wework-equation-11569342629?mod=article_inline&quot; class=&quot;icon none&quot;&gt;tumultuous few weeks &lt;/a&gt;for the startup that the best path forward was for him to relinquish the CEO role, people familiar with the matter said. “Too much focus has been placed on me,” Mr. Neumann said in a staff email following the announcement Tuesday. &lt;/p&gt; 






      &lt;div data-layout=&quot;wrap&amp;#10;              &quot; data-layout-mobile=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&amp;#10;        media-object&amp;#10;        type-InsetRichText&amp;#10;          wrap&amp;#10;    scope-web|mobileapps&amp;#10;  article__inset&amp;#10;        article__inset--type-InsetRichText&amp;#10;          article__inset--wrap&amp;#10;  &quot;&gt;
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
          &lt;div class=&quot;media-object-rich-text&quot;&gt;
    	

&lt;h4&gt;REGISTER NOW: ON CALL WITH WSJ&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;p&gt;Join WSJ journalists in a live member-only call Wednesday, Sept. 25, on the future of WeWork and what’s next for one of the U.S.’s most valuable startups. &lt;a href=&quot;https://event.on24.com/eventRegistration/eventRegistrationServlet?referrer=&amp;amp;eventid=2099036&amp;amp;sessionid=1&amp;amp;key=86026C23F025A1CA5F0BCF662BFEEA6F&amp;amp;regTag=&amp;amp;mod=article_inline&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;icon none&quot;&gt;Register here, and send your questions&lt;/a&gt; to subscribercall@wsj.com.)&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      &lt;/div&gt; 




       &lt;p&gt;Mr. Neumann will remain nonexecutive chairman and be succeeded by two of his deputies, who as co-CEOs are expected to cut staff and try to stem the company’s substantial losses. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; 




      Artie Minson, 




       finance chief of We Co., as the parent is known, will focus on finance, legal and human resources. 




      Sebastian Gunningham, 




       a veteran of 






        &lt;a href=&quot;https://quotes.wsj.com/AMZN&quot;&gt;Amazon.com&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;span&gt; Inc.,&lt;/span&gt;


       will tend to marketing and technology.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Mr. Neumann will also cede majority control of the company, with his supervoting shares reduced to 3-to-1 from 10-to-1, the people said. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Mr. Neumann’s wife, Rebekah, a co-founder who also held the title of chief brand and impact officer, is expected to step away from her roles at the company—including as CEO of its private elementary school, the type of unusual venture that defined Mr. Neumann’s desire to make We more than just an office-space company. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Mr. Neumann’s position became tenuous after We &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/wework-parent-expected-to-postpone-ipo-11568671322?mod=article_inline&quot; class=&quot;icon none&quot;&gt;postponed a planned IPO&lt;/a&gt; earlier this month amid &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/wework-to-list-shares-on-nasdaq-make-governance-changes-11568348421?mod=article_inline&quot; class=&quot;icon none&quot;&gt;concerns from prospective investors&lt;/a&gt; about its governance and ballooning losses. The company, once valued privately at $47 billion, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/wework-parent-weighs-slashing-its-valuation-roughly-in-half-11567689174?mod=article_inline&quot; class=&quot;icon none&quot;&gt;slashed its hopes for a public valuation&lt;/a&gt; to as low as $15 billion.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Further undercutting his position: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/this-is-not-the-way-everybody-behaves-how-adam-neumanns-over-the-top-style-built-wework-11568823827?mod=article_inline&amp;amp;mod=article_inline&quot; class=&quot;icon none&quot;&gt;eccentric behavior&lt;/a&gt; that was detailed in a Wall Street Journal article last week, such as a party-heavy lifestyle that included marijuana use in an airplane and unpredictable management decisions.&lt;/p&gt; 






       




       &lt;p&gt;The end came swiftly for Mr. Neumann, who co-founded WeWork in 2010 and was the force behind its quirky vibe and vision. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;As recently as last week it seemed unlikely that he would ever loosen his iron grip on the company. Key backers, including 






        &lt;a href=&quot;https://quotes.wsj.com/JPM&quot;&gt;JPMorgan&lt;/a&gt;
        


       Chase &amp;amp; Co. CEO 




      James Dimon




       and 




      Bruce Dunlevie, 




       a venture capitalist who sits on We’s board, indicated that he had their support. In internal meetings and those with outside advisers, Mr. Neumann was still expressing confidence that the company could pull off the IPO later this year with him at the helm.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;But things changed after the company chose to postpone the listing. What followed was a five-day stretch in which the backers whose money and loose reins had fueled Mr. Neumann’s rise turned against him, people familiar with the matter said.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A pivotal moment came when he lost the backing of 






        &lt;a href=&quot;https://quotes.wsj.com/9984.TO&quot;&gt;SoftBank Group&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;span&gt; Corp.&lt;/span&gt;


      , which owns nearly a third of We and had been a major supporter of Mr. Neumann. The Japanese conglomerate by last week was holding internal discussions about how to remove him.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In addition to being We’s biggest shareholder, SoftBank has influence by virtue of its ability to keep pumping in the cash We needs. SoftBank had been expected to contribute as much as a third of the $3 billion We hoped to raise in the IPO. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Mr. Neumann huddled with close advisers over the weekend and into Tuesday in talks led by Mr. Dimon. Mr. Neumann had counted the bank chief as a confidant and taken to calling him his “personal banker” according to people familiar with their relationship. &lt;/p&gt; 






      &lt;div data-layout=&quot;wrap&amp;#10;              &quot; data-layout-mobile=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&amp;#10;        media-object&amp;#10;        type-InsetRichText&amp;#10;          wrap&amp;#10;    scope-web&amp;#10;  article__inset&amp;#10;        article__inset--type-InsetRichText&amp;#10;          article__inset--wrap&amp;#10;  &quot;&gt;
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
          &lt;div class=&quot;media-object-rich-text&quot;&gt;
    	

&lt;h4&gt;Share Your Thoughts &lt;/h4&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;em&gt;What will the future of WeWork look like without Adam Neumann at the helm?&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Join the conversation below. &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      &lt;/div&gt; 




       &lt;p&gt;Mr. Dimon had his own reasons for being hands-on: JPMorgan is deeply entwined with We. Its investment funds were early backers; it had promised to lend the company and Mr. Neumann hundreds of millions of dollars; and it was the lead bank on the IPO. The full-court press on We, dating back years, was part of Mr. Dimon’s strategy to cozy up to promising startups that might pay JPMorgan to take them public and broker deals. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;As of Friday and into the weekend, multiple members of We’s board, including Mr. Dunlevie, indicated that they planned to support Mr. Neumann as CEO. Mr. Dimon and JPMorgan’s money-management arm also told him they didn’t think he had to leave. By Sunday, Mr. Dunlevie, once a staunch ally, met with Mr. Neumann to tell him he would stand with SoftBank in pushing for the entrepreneur to leave.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Tuesday morning, Mr. Neumann convened with bankers and lawyers to finalize the details of his departure, one of the people said. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Mr. Neumann had long been betting that investors would focus on We’s rocket-ship growth and value it like a technology company. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Instead, analysts, prospective investors and media commentators harped on the company’s losses, $1.6 billion last year. They were growing as fast as revenue, suggesting the company wasn’t getting the benefits of scale that startups rely on to turn profitable.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;With its core business of leasing office space tricked out in millennial-friendly décor, many would-be investors saw the company not as a tech darling, but as an overvalued real-estate company with potential conflicts of interest. Evidence of success in prior efforts to expand into new areas—dormlike apartments, fitness, retail—was scant. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Investors approached by We’s bankers at JPMorgan and 






        &lt;a href=&quot;https://quotes.wsj.com/GS&quot;&gt;Goldman Sachs Group&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;span&gt; Inc.&lt;/span&gt;


       balked at the price. We slashed its expected valuation by roughly two thirds, erasing $30 billion or more.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The fate of the IPO now remains to be seen, but people familiar with the matter said it is unlikely to take place this year as planned. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We is in talks with JPMorgan and Goldman about a new $3 billion loan, which would likely require the startup to raise several hundred million dollars of new equity. SoftBank is expected to chip in for more equity, and big real-estate firms may, too, one of the people said. Together with the cost cuts, that could give We enough cash to keep operating through the end of next year. &lt;/p&gt; 






       




       &lt;p&gt;The company is considering shedding extraneous businesses and cutting costs, in part by axing a few thousand of its more than 12,000 employees, another person said. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In an email to staff, the two incoming CEOs suggested cutbacks could be coming for the company. “We will closely review all aspects of our company with the intention of strengthening our core business,” they wrote, saying they anticipated “difficult decisions ahead.” &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The tumult atop We represents the latest threat to the widespread practice among Silicon Valley startups of giving nearly unchecked control to founders. Venture capitalists who once kept founders on a short leash now frequently hand over control to founders under the belief that they should be able to make big, long-term decisions without interference. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Taken with a similar ouster of the CEO of 






        &lt;a href=&quot;https://quotes.wsj.com/UBER&quot;&gt;Uber Technologies&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;span&gt; Inc.&lt;/span&gt;


       in 2017, now two of the most valuable U.S. startups have dethroned founders over concerns about their leadership styles. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Mr. Neumann will remain a wealthy man. Entities he controls own roughly 30% of the company’s shares—it’s unclear how much of this is his and how much belongs to the other founder and early investors—and he has already taken out hundreds of millions of dollars from the company in stock sales, people familiar with the matter have said. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;He also has borrowed $380 million tied to his shares in the company, according to securities filings, one of the issues prospective investors objected to. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Some of his wealth has gone into real estate. He has at least five homes on both coasts, including a $21 million home near San Francisco with a room shaped like a guitar. And Mr. Neumann has a collection of commercial properties in San Jose, Calif., that he has been expecting to turn into a downtown campus of We buildings, according to people briefed on the plans. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class=&quot;articleTagLine&quot;&gt;—Liz Hoffman &lt;br/&gt;and Julie Steinberg contributed to this article.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Write to &lt;/strong&gt;Eliot Brown at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:eliot.brown@wsj.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;icon &quot;&gt;eliot.brown@wsj.com&lt;/a&gt;, Dana Cimilluca at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:dana.cimilluca@wsj.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;icon &quot;&gt;dana.cimilluca@wsj.com&lt;/a&gt;, David Benoit at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:david.benoit@wsj.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;icon &quot;&gt;david.benoit@wsj.com&lt;/a&gt; and Maureen Farrell at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:maureen.farrell@wsj.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;icon &quot;&gt;maureen.farrell@wsj.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;






      &lt;/div&gt;



  
  &lt;p&gt;Copyright ©2019 Dow Jones &amp;amp; Company, Inc. All Rights Reserved. 87990cbe856818d5eddac44c7b1cdeb8&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;/div&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 16:54:52 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mudil</dc:creator>
<og:title>WeWork’s Adam Neumann Steps Down as CEO</og:title>
<og:description>WeWork co-founder and Chief Executive Adam Neumann was forced to step down and cede control of the shared-office startup after its much-anticipated initial public offering was derailed, capping a swift fall from grace for the leader of one of the country’s most valuable startups.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.wsj.com/articles/neumann-expected-to-step-down-as-we-ceo-11569343912</og:url>
<og:image>https://images.wsj.net/im-109851/social</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.wsj.com/articles/neumann-expected-to-step-down-as-we-ceo-11569343912?mod=rsswn</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>iPadOS</title>
<link>https://www.apple.com/ipados/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.apple.com/ipados/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;apple-arcade feature column large-6 small-12&quot; readability=&quot;9.4594594594595&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;feature-headline&quot;&gt;Apple Arcade.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;feature-copy&quot;&gt;Play over 100 groundbreaking new games, where storytelling and design are pushed further than ever before, all in a game subscription service unlike any other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/apple-arcade/&quot; data-analytics-title=&quot;learn more about apple arcade&quot; data-analytics-region=&quot;learn more&quot; aria-label=&quot;Learn more about Apple Arcade&quot; class=&quot;icon-wrapper&quot; data-rid-store=&quot;{&amp;quot;288&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;arc-0-pados-lrn-apl-avl-190919&amp;quot;}&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;icon-copy&quot;&gt;Learn more&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;voice-control feature column large-6 small-12&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;feature-headline&quot;&gt;Voice Control.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;feature-copy&quot;&gt;Control your iPad with just your voice. Rich text editing features let you make corrections as you dictate. Navigate comprehensively using voice commands and gestures. You can even see numbers or names next to everything you can tap, and superimpose a grid onscreen to tap when there aren’t controls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;siri feature column large-6 small-12&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;feature-headline&quot;&gt;A new voice for Siri.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;feature-copy&quot;&gt;The new Siri voice uses advanced neural text‑to‑speech technology to sound just as natural while speaking longer phrases, like when reading the news or answering knowledge questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;siri-shortcuts feature column large-6 small-12&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;feature-headline&quot;&gt;Siri Shortcuts.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;feature-copy&quot;&gt;The Shortcuts app is a single place for all your Siri shortcuts. New Conversational Shortcuts let Siri ask questions to clarify your requests, like finding out which location you want to go to when you say, “order my usual coffee.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;share feature column large-6 small-12&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;feature-headline&quot;&gt;Smarter ways to share.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;feature-copy&quot;&gt;When you share a photo or document, your iPad suggests who you might want to share it with and which app you may want to use, so you can quickly share with just a tap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;maps feature column large-6 small-12&quot; readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;feature-headline&quot;&gt;More useful ways to look at Maps.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;feature-copy&quot;&gt;Look Around shows you where you’re going with a seamless, high-resolution experience.&lt;sup/&gt; An all-new map features more realistic details for roads, beaches, and more.&lt;sup/&gt; And Collections let you track and share your must-see spots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;messages feature column large-6 small-12&quot; readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;feature-headline&quot;&gt;Custom Memoji in Messages.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;feature-copy&quot;&gt;Make your Memoji one in a trillion with new hairstyles, headwear, makeup, and piercings. And now Memoji automatically become sticker packs you can use in Messages, Mail, and third-party apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;reminders feature column large-6 small-12&quot; readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;feature-headline&quot;&gt;An all-new Reminders app.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;feature-copy&quot;&gt;Now it’s even easier to create and organize reminders. Smart lists make it easy to display and track your upcoming reminders. The quick toolbar lets you add dates, times, locations, flags, photos, and scanned documents. And Siri suggests reminders you might want to add.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;mail feature column large-6 small-12&quot; readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;feature-headline&quot;&gt;Text formatting tools in Mail.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;feature-copy&quot;&gt;Now you can write professional-looking email on the go with formatting options that include font style, size, and color, alignment, indenting and outdenting text, and numbered and bulleted lists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;notes feature column large-6 small-12&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;feature-headline&quot;&gt;New and improved Notes.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;feature-copy&quot;&gt;A new gallery view and more powerful search help you find whatever note you need, right when you need it. The new checklist options help you get more done, and shared folders make it easier to collaborate with others on folders and notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;airpods feature column large-6 small-12&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;feature-headline&quot;&gt;Audio sharing with AirPods.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;feature-copy&quot;&gt;Now you can pair two sets of AirPods to one iPad and easily listen to a song or watch a movie along with a friend.&lt;sup/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;homepod feature column large-6 small-12&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;feature-headline&quot;&gt;A personalized experience on HomePod.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;feature-copy&quot;&gt;Siri can now learn and recognize the voices of family members using HomePod, so everyone has a personalized experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;whats-new feature column large-12&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;feature-headline&quot;&gt;See a full list of what’s&lt;br/&gt;new in iPadOS.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/ipados/features/&quot; data-analytics-title=&quot;learn more about what's new in ipados&quot; data-analytics-region=&quot;learn more&quot; aria-label=&quot;Learn more about what's new in iPadOS&quot; class=&quot;icon-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;icon-copy&quot;&gt;Learn more&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 15:40:55 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>plg</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://www.apple.com/v/ipados/c/images/meta/og__e8v1tbed61yu.png?201909240913</og:image>
<og:title>iPadOS</og:title>
<og:description>iPadOS makes iPad more powerful and capable with new enhancements to Slide Over and Split View, Apple Pencil, text editing, keyboard, and more.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.apple.com/ipados/</og:url>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.apple.com/ipados/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How to Cold Email Investors [video]</title>
<link>https://blog.ycombinator.com/how-to-cold-email-investors-michael-seibel/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.ycombinator.com/how-to-cold-email-investors-michael-seibel/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;loop-post-excerpt clearfix&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;loop-post-text grid-col-16 single-img&quot; id=&quot;feature-img&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;loop-thumbnail&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe title=&quot;How To Cold Email Investors - Michael Seibel&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;576&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/A3MmYbH1hbs?width=1024&amp;amp;height=1024&amp;amp;autoplay&amp;amp;origin=https%3A%2F%2Fblog.ycombinator.com&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;fvp-onload&quot; src=&quot;https://blog.ycombinator.com/wp-content/plugins/featured-video-plus/img/playicon.png&quot; alt=&quot;Featured Video Play Icon&quot; onload=&quot;(function() {('initFeaturedVideoPlus' in this) &amp;amp;&amp;amp; ('function' === typeof initFeaturedVideoPlus) &amp;amp;&amp;amp; initFeaturedVideoPlus();})();&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot; readability=&quot;54.913090128755&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Y Combinator CEO and Partner &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mwseibel&quot;&gt;Michael Seibel&lt;/a&gt; on how to cold email investors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Topics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/A3MmYbH1hbs?t=0s&quot;&gt;00:00&lt;/a&gt; – Intro&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/A3MmYbH1hbs?t=17s&quot;&gt;00:17&lt;/a&gt; – Make it short, i.e. 60 seconds or less to read&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/A3MmYbH1hbs?t=58s&quot;&gt;00:58&lt;/a&gt; – Interested in: the problem you’re trying to solve, what your solution is, have you launched, do you have growth, how big you think the market could be, do you have cofounders, are you technical, and do you know something about the problem that you think is controversial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/A3MmYbH1hbs?t=1m38s&quot;&gt;1:38&lt;/a&gt; – Not interested in: a long history of how you came up with the idea or jargon (see: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pQnOBHNKlgs&quot;&gt;customer pitch vs investor pitch&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/A3MmYbH1hbs?t=2m17s&quot;&gt;2:17&lt;/a&gt; – Send your email from a company email address with your name in it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/A3MmYbH1hbs?t=3m5s&quot;&gt;3:05&lt;/a&gt; – Decks aren’t required but use a common format if including one&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/A3MmYbH1hbs?t=4m2s&quot;&gt;4:02&lt;/a&gt; – Track opens&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/A3MmYbH1hbs?t=4m14s&quot;&gt;4:14&lt;/a&gt; – Don’t make it long&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/A3MmYbH1hbs?t=5m27s&quot;&gt;5:27&lt;/a&gt; – Don’t immediately request an in-person meeting&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/A3MmYbH1hbs?t=6m4s&quot;&gt;6:04&lt;/a&gt; – Don’t send multiple follow-ups quickly&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/A3MmYbH1hbs?t=6m26s&quot;&gt;6:26&lt;/a&gt; – Don’t forget to describe what your company does&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;mc_embed_signup&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;mc_copy&quot;&gt;Sign up for weekly updates from Y Combinator.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 15:12:49 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>sahin-boydas</dc:creator>
<og:title>How To Cold Email Investors - Michael Seibel</og:title>
<og:url>https://blog.ycombinator.com/how-to-cold-email-investors-michael-seibel/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Y Combinator CEO and Partner Michael Seibel on how to cold email investors.</og:description>
<og:image>https://blog.ycombinator.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/How-To-Cold-Email-Investors-Michael-Seibel.jpeg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.ycombinator.com/how-to-cold-email-investors-michael-seibel/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Comparing Database Types</title>
<link>https://www.prisma.io/blog/comparison-of-database-models-1iz9u29nwn37</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.prisma.io/blog/comparison-of-database-models-1iz9u29nwn37</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;styles__Strong-fvdpr4-15 eHeecn&quot;&gt;Database types&lt;/strong&gt;, sometimes referred to as database models or database families, are the patterns and structures used to organize data within a database management system. Many different database types have been developed over the years. Some are mainly historic predecessors to current databases, while others have stood the test of time. In the last few decades, new types have been developed to address changing requirements and different use patterns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;Your choice of database type can have a profound impact on what kind of operations your application can easily perform, how you conceptualize your data, and the features that your database management system offers you during development and runtime. In this guide, we'll take a look at how database types have evolved over time and what advantages and trade-offs are present in each design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;styles__H3-fvdpr4-10 fdlJWJ&quot; id=&quot;legacy-databases-paving-the-way-for-modern-systems&quot;&gt;Legacy databases: paving the way for modern systems&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;Legacy database types represent milestones on the path to modern databases. These may still find a foothold in certain specialized environments, but have mostly been replaced by more robust alternatives for production environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;This section is dedicated to historic database types that aren't used much in modern development. You can &lt;a class=&quot;styles__A-fvdpr4-7 hLlHFt&quot; href=&quot;https://www.prisma.io/blog/comparison-of-database-models-1iz9u29nwn37#relational-databases-working-with-tables-as-a-standard-solution-to-organize-well-structured-data&quot;&gt;skip ahead to the section on relational databases&lt;/a&gt; if you aren't interested in that background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;styles__H4-fvdpr4-9 hpabDE&quot; id=&quot;flat-file-databases-simple-data-structures-for-organizing-small-amounts-of-local-data&quot;&gt;Flat-file databases: simple data structures for organizing small amounts of local data&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;The simplest way to manage data on a computer outside of an application is to store it in a basic file format. The first solutions for data management used this approach and it is still a popular option for storing small amounts of information without heavy requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;The first flat file databases represented information in regular, machine parse-able structures within files. Data is stored in plain text, which limits the type of content that can be represented within the database itself. A special character or other indicator is chosen to use as a &lt;em&gt;delimiter&lt;/em&gt;, or marker for when one field ends and the next begins. For example, a comma is used in CSV (comma-separated values) files, while colons or white-space are used in many data files in &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; class=&quot;styles__A-fvdpr4-7 hLlHFt&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unix-like&quot;&gt;Unix-like&lt;/a&gt; systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;styles__Strong-fvdpr4-15 eHeecn&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;styles__InlineCode-fvdpr4-14 kPyZAF&quot;&gt;/etc/passwd&lt;/code&gt; on *nix systems:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;styles__Pre-fvdpr4-13 gqUzOk&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;root&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;x&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;root&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;root&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;bin&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;bash
daemon&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;x&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;daemon&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;usr&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;sbin&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;usr&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;sbin&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;nologin
bin&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;x&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;bin&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;bin&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;usr&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;sbin&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;nologin
sys&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;x&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;sys&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;dev&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;usr&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;sbin&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;nologin
sync&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;x&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;65534&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;sync&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;bin&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;bin&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;sync
games&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;x&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;60&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;games&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;usr&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;games&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;usr&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;sbin&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;nologin
man&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;x&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;6&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;12&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;man&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;cache&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;man&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;usr&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;sbin&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;nologin
lp&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;x&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;7&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;7&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;lp&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;spool&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;lpd&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;usr&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;sbin&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;nologin
mail&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;x&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;mail&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;mail&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;usr&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;sbin&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;nologin
news&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;x&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;news&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;spool&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;news&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;usr&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;sbin&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;nologin
backup&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;x&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;34&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;34&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;backup&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;backups&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;usr&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;sbin&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;nologin
list&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;x&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;38&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;38&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;Mailing List Manager&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;list&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;usr&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;sbin&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;nologin
nobody&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;x&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;65534&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;65534&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;nobody&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;nonexistent&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;usr&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;sbin&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;nologin
syslog&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;x&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;102&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;106&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;home&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;syslog&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;usr&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;sbin&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;nologin
bob&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;x&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;1000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;1000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;Bob Smith&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;home&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;bob&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;bin&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;bash
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;styles__InlineCode-fvdpr4-14 kPyZAF&quot;&gt;/etc/passwd&lt;/code&gt; file defines users, one per line. Each user has attributes like name, user and group IDs, home directory and default shell, each separated by a colon.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;While flat file databases are simple, they are very limited in the level of complexity they can handle. The system that reads or manipulates the data cannot make easy connections between the data represented. File-based systems usually don't have any type of user or data concurrency features either. Flat file databases are usually only practical for systems with small read or write requirements. For example, many operating systems use flat-files to store configuration data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;In spite of these limitations, flat-file databases are still widely used for scenarios where local processes need to store and organized small amounts of data. A good example of this is for configuration data for many applications on Linux and other Unix-like systems. In these cases, the flat-file format serves as an interface that both humans and applications can easily read and manage. Some advantages of this format are that it has robust, flexible tooling, is easily managed without specialized software, and is easy to understand and work with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;Examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;styles__H4-fvdpr4-9 hpabDE&quot; id=&quot;hierarchical-databases-using-parent-child-relationships-to-map-data-into-trees&quot;&gt;Hierarchical databases: using parent-child relationships to map data into trees&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;styles__Strong-fvdpr4-15 eHeecn&quot;&gt;Initial introduction: 1960s&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;Hierarchical databases were the next evolution in database management development. They encode a relationship between items where every record has a single parent. This builds a tree-like structure that can be used to categorize records according to their parent record.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Image__Wrapper-sc-152tu6s-0 iUrdCz&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;Image-sc-152tu6s-1 cmQiWS&quot; src=&quot;https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/b55ec5eec5909adebf94917694dc264513b678ab/81681/blog/posts/database-type-comparison/hierarchical.png&quot; alt=&quot;Diagram of a hierarchical database&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Image__Title-sc-152tu6s-2 uHBje&quot;&gt;Diagram of a hierarchical database&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;This simple relationship mapping provides users with the ability to establish relationships between items in a tree structure. This is very useful for certain types of data, but does not allow for complex relationship management. Furthermore, the meaning of the parent-child relationship is implicit. One parent-child connection could be between a customer and their orders, while another might represent an employee and the equipment they have been allocated. The structure of the data itself does not distinguish between these relationships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;Hierarchical databases are the beginning of a movement towards thinking about data management in more complex terms. The trajectory of database management systems that were developed afterwards continues this trend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;Hierarchical databases are not used much today due to their limited ability to organize most data and because of the overhead of accessing data by traversing the hierarchy. However, a few incredibly important systems could be considered hierarchical databases. A filesystem, for instance, can be thought of as a specialized hierarchical database, as the system of files and directories fit neatly into the single-parent / multiple-child paradigm. Likewise, DNS and LDAP systems both act as databases for hierarchical datasets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;Examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;styles__H4-fvdpr4-9 hpabDE&quot; id=&quot;network-databases-mapping-more-flexible-connections-with-non-hierarchical-links&quot;&gt;Network databases: mapping more flexible connections with non-hierarchical links&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;styles__Strong-fvdpr4-15 eHeecn&quot;&gt;Initial introduction: late 1960s&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;Network databases built on the foundation provided by hierarchical databases by adding additional flexibility. Instead of always having a single parent, as in hierarchical databases, network database entries can have more than one parent, which effectively allows them to model more complex relationships. When talking about network databases, it is important to realize that &lt;em&gt;network&lt;/em&gt; is being used to refer to connections between different data entries, not connections between different computers or software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Image__Wrapper-sc-152tu6s-0 iUrdCz&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;Image-sc-152tu6s-1 cmQiWS&quot; src=&quot;https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/aa729517f8d420f8d36d1f984dea57b80343be07/748ae/blog/posts/database-type-comparison/network.png&quot; alt=&quot;Diagram of a network database&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Image__Title-sc-152tu6s-2 uHBje&quot;&gt;Diagram of a network database&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;Network databases can be represented by a generic &lt;em&gt;graph&lt;/em&gt; instead of a &lt;em&gt;tree&lt;/em&gt;. The meaning of the graph was defined by a &lt;strong class=&quot;styles__Strong-fvdpr4-15 eHeecn&quot;&gt;schema&lt;/strong&gt;, which lays out what each data node and each relationship represents. This gave structure to the data in a way that could previously only be reached through inference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;styles__Blockquote-fvdpr4-6 dEZflj&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;styles__Strong-fvdpr4-15 eHeecn&quot;&gt;Definition: Schema&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;A database schema is a description of the logical structure of a database or the elements it contains. Schemas often include declarations for the structure of individual entries, groups of entries, and the individual attributes that database entries are comprised of. These may also define data types and additional constraints to control the type of data that may be added to the structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;Network databases were a huge leap forward in terms of flexibility and the ability to map connections between information. However, they were still limited by the same access patterns and design mindset of hierarchical databases. For instance, to access data, you still needed to follow the network paths to the record in question. The parent-child relationship carried over from hierarchical databases also affected the way that items could connect to one another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;It is difficult to find modern examples of network database systems. Setting up and working with network databases required a good deal of skill and specialized domain knowledge. Most systems that could be approximated using network databases found a better fit once relational databases appeared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;Examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;styles__H3-fvdpr4-10 fdlJWJ&quot; id=&quot;relational-databases-working-with-tables-as-a-standard-solution-to-organize-well-structured-data&quot;&gt;Relational databases: working with tables as a standard solution to organize well-structured data&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;styles__Strong-fvdpr4-15 eHeecn&quot;&gt;Initial introduction: 1969&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;Relational databases are the oldest general purpose database type still widely used today. In fact, &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; class=&quot;styles__A-fvdpr4-7 hLlHFt&quot; href=&quot;https://db-engines.com/en/ranking_categories&quot;&gt;relational databases comprise the majority of databases currently used in production&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;Relational databases organize data using &lt;em&gt;tables&lt;/em&gt;. Tables are structures that impose a schema on the records that they hold. Each column within a table has a &lt;em&gt;name&lt;/em&gt; and a &lt;em&gt;data type&lt;/em&gt;. Each row represents an individual record or data item within the table, which contains values for each of the columns. Relational databases get their name from the fact that relationships can be defined between tables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Image__Wrapper-sc-152tu6s-0 iUrdCz&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;Image-sc-152tu6s-1 cmQiWS&quot; src=&quot;https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/ecc7aa3cce3fc59da9a7fc71a27186f7093fa445/07559/blog/posts/database-type-comparison/relational.png&quot; alt=&quot;Diagram of relational schema used to map entities for a school&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Image__Title-sc-152tu6s-2 uHBje&quot;&gt;Diagram of relational schema used to map entities for a school&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;Special fields in tables, called &lt;em&gt;foreign keys&lt;/em&gt;, can contain references to columns in other tables. This allows the database to bridge the two tables on demand to bring different types of data together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;The highly organized structure imparted by the rigid table structure, combined with the flexibility offered by the relations between tables makes relational databases very powerful and adaptable to many types of data. Conformity can be enforced at the table level, but database operations can combine and manipulate that data in novel ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;While not inherent to the design of relational databases, a querying language called SQL, or structured query language, was created to access and manipulate data stored with that format. It can query and join data from multiple tables within a single statement. SQL can also filter, aggregate, summarize, and limit the data that it returns. So while SQL is not a part of the relational system, it is often a fundamental part of working with these databases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;styles__Blockquote-fvdpr4-6 dEZflj&quot; readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;styles__Strong-fvdpr4-15 eHeecn&quot;&gt;Definition: SQL&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;SQL, or structured querying language, is a language family used to query and manipulate data within relational databases. It excels at combining data from multiple tables and filtering based on constraints which allow it to be used to express complex queries. Variants of the language has been adopted by almost all relational databases due to its flexibility, power, and ubiquity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;In general, relational databases are often a good fit for any data that is regular, predictable, and benefits from the ability to flexibly compose information in various formats. Because relational databases work off of a schema, it can be more challenging to alter the structure of data after it is in the system. However, the schema also helps enforce the integrity of the data, making sure values match the expected formats, and that required information is included. Overall, relational databases are a solid choice for many applications because applications often generate well-ordered, structured data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;Examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;styles__H3-fvdpr4-10 fdlJWJ&quot; id=&quot;nosql-databases-modern-alternatives-for-data-that-doesnt-fit-the-relational-paradigm&quot;&gt;NoSQL databases: modern alternatives for data that doesn't fit the relational paradigm&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;NoSQL is a term for a varied collection of modern database types that offer approaches that differ from the standard relational pattern. The term NoSQL is somewhat of a misnomer since the databases within this category are more of a reaction against the relational archetype rather than the SQL querying language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;styles__H4-fvdpr4-9 hpabDE&quot; id=&quot;key-value-databases-simple-dictionary-style-lookups-for-basic-storage-and-retrieval&quot;&gt;Key-value databases: simple, dictionary-style lookups for basic storage and retrieval&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;styles__Strong-fvdpr4-15 eHeecn&quot;&gt;Initial introduction: 1970s | Rise in popularity: 2000-2010&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;Key-value databases, or key-value stores, are one of the simplest database types. Key-value stores work by storing arbitrary data accessible through a specific &lt;em&gt;key&lt;/em&gt;. To store data, you provide a key and the blob of data you wish to save, for example a JSON object, an image, or plain text. To retrieve data, you provide the key and will then be given the blob of data back. The database does not evaluate the data it is storing and allows limited ways of interacting with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Image__Wrapper-sc-152tu6s-0 iUrdCz&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;Image-sc-152tu6s-1 cmQiWS&quot; src=&quot;https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/0aee61f5bb32b11ff51d6aedb636645c35e70b9d/7f22a/blog/posts/database-type-comparison/key-value.png&quot; alt=&quot;Diagram of key-value data store&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Image__Title-sc-152tu6s-2 uHBje&quot;&gt;Diagram of key-value data store&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;If key-value stores appear simple, it's because they are. But that simplicity is often an asset in the kinds of scenarios where they are most often deployed. Key-value stores are often used to store configuration data, state information, and any data that might be represented by a &lt;em&gt;dictionary&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;hash&lt;/em&gt; in a programming language. Key-value stores provide fast, low-complexity access to this type of data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;Key-value databases don't prescribe any schema for the data they store, and as such, are often used to store many different types of data at the same time. The user is responsible for defining any naming scheme for the keys that will help identify the values and are responsible for ensuring the value is of the appropriate type and format. Key-value storage is most useful as a lightweight solution for storing simple values that can be operated on externally after retrieval.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;One of the most popular uses for key-value databases are to store configuration values and application variables and flags for websites and web applications. Programs can check the key-value store, which is usually very fast, for their configuration when they start. This allows you to alter the runtime behavior of your services by changing the data in the key-value store. Applications can also be configured to recheck periodically or to restart when they see changes. These configuration stores are often persisted to disk periodically to prevent loss of data in the event of a system crash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;Examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;styles__H4-fvdpr4-9 hpabDE&quot; id=&quot;document-databases-storing-all-of-an-items-data-in-flexible-self-describing-structures&quot;&gt;Document databases: Storing all of an item's data in flexible, self-describing structures&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;styles__Strong-fvdpr4-15 eHeecn&quot;&gt;Rise in popularity: 2009&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;Document databases, also known as document-oriented databases or document stores, share the basic access and retrieval semantics of key-value stores. Document databases also use a key to uniquely identify data within the database. In fact, the line between advanced key-value stores and document databases can be fairly unclear. However, instead of storing arbitrary blobs of data, document databases store data in structured formats called documents, often using formats like JSON, BSON, or XML.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Image__Wrapper-sc-152tu6s-0 iUrdCz&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;Image-sc-152tu6s-1 cmQiWS&quot; src=&quot;https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/8d2bd5dcb7f55efcb3d59103706be7459f3664df/a7fc4/blog/posts/database-type-comparison/document.png&quot; alt=&quot;Diagram of document database&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Image__Title-sc-152tu6s-2 uHBje&quot;&gt;Diagram of document database&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;Though the data within documents is organized within a structure, document databases do not prescribe any specific format or schema. Each document can have a different internal structure that the database interprets. So, unlike with key-value stores, the content stored in document databases can be queried and analyzed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;In some ways, document databases sit in between relational databases and key-value stores. They use the simple key-value semantics and loose requirements on data that key-value stores are known for, but they also provide the ability to impose a structure that you can use to query and operate on the data in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;The comparison with relational databases shouldn't be overstated, however. While document databases provide methods of structuring data within documents and operating on datasets based on those structures, the guarantees, relationships, and operations available are very different from relational databases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;Document databases are a good choice for rapid development because you can change the properties of the data you want to save at any point without altering existing structures or data. You only need to backfill records if you want to. Each document within the database stands on its own with its own system of organization. If you're still figuring out your data structure and your data is mainly composed discrete entries that don't include a lot of cross references, a document database might be a good place to start. Be careful, however, as the extra flexibility means that you are responsible for maintaining the consistency and structure of your data, which can be extremely challenging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;Examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;styles__H4-fvdpr4-9 hpabDE&quot; id=&quot;graph-databases-mapping-relationships-by-focusing-on-how-connections-between-data-are-meaningful&quot;&gt;Graph databases: mapping relationships by focusing on how connections between data are meaningful&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;styles__Strong-fvdpr4-15 eHeecn&quot;&gt;Rise in popularity: 2000s&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;Graph databases are a type of NoSQL database that takes a different approach to establishing relationships between data. Rather than mapping relationships with tables and foreign keys, graph databases establish connections using the concepts of &lt;em&gt;nodes&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;edges&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;properties&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Image__Wrapper-sc-152tu6s-0 iUrdCz&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;Image-sc-152tu6s-1 cmQiWS&quot; src=&quot;https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/58c2b57b422a61234950932a5cb5f3ac9103913c/d0c9a/blog/posts/database-type-comparison/graph.png&quot; alt=&quot;Diagram of a graph database structure&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Image__Title-sc-152tu6s-2 uHBje&quot;&gt;Diagram of a graph database structure&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;Graph databases represents data as individual nodes which can have any number of properties associated with them. Between these nodes, edges (also called relationships) are established to represent different types of connections. In this way, the database encodes information about the data items within the nodes and information about their relationship in the edges that connect the nodes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;At a glance, graph databases appear similar to earlier network databases. Both types focus on the connections between items and allow for explicit mapping of relationships between different types of data. However, network databases require step-by-step traversal to travel between items and are limited in the types of relationships they can represent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;Graph databases are most useful when working with data where the relationships or connections are highly important. It is essential to understand that when talking about relational databases, the word &quot;relational&quot; refers to the ability to tie information in different tables together. On the other hand, with graph databases, the primary purpose is defining and managing relationships themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;For example, querying for the connection between two users of a social media site in a relational database is likely to require multiple table joins and therefore be rather resource intensive. This same query would be straightforward in a graph database that directly maps connections. The focus of graph databases is to make working this type of data intuitive and powerful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;styles__H4-fvdpr4-9 hpabDE&quot; id=&quot;column-family-databases-databases-with-flexible-columns-to-bridge-the-gap-between-relational-and-document-databases&quot;&gt;Column-family databases: databases with flexible columns to bridge the gap between relational and document databases&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;styles__Strong-fvdpr4-15 eHeecn&quot;&gt;Rise in popularity: 2000s&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;Column-family databases, also called non-relational column stores, wide-column databases, or simply column databases, are perhaps the NoSQL type that, on the surface, looks most similar to relational databases. Like relational databases, wide-column databases store data using concepts like rows and columns. However, in wide-column databases, the association between these elements is very different from how relational databases use them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;In relational databases, a schema defines the column layout in a table by specifying what columns the table will have, their respective data types, and other criteria. All of the rows in a table must conform to this fixed schema.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;Instead of tables, column-family databases have structures called &lt;em&gt;column families&lt;/em&gt;. Column families contain rows of data, each of which define their own format. A row is composed of a unique row identifier — used to locate the row — followed by sets of column names and values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;With this design, each row in a column family defines its own schema. That schema can be easily modified because it only affects that single row of data. Each row can have different numbers of columns with different types of data. Sometimes it helps to think of column family databases as key-value databases where each key (row identifier) returns a dictionary of arbitrary attributes and their values (the column names and their values).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Image__Wrapper-sc-152tu6s-0 iUrdCz&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;Image-sc-152tu6s-1 cmQiWS&quot; src=&quot;https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/af4de7c5814d0c3ebdf9b6b29fe7645a79799214/795c4/blog/posts/database-type-comparison/column.png&quot; alt=&quot;Diagram of column-family database structure&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Image__Title-sc-152tu6s-2 uHBje&quot;&gt;Diagram of column-family database structure&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;Column-family databases are good when working with applications that requires great performance for row-based operations and highly scalability. Since all of the data and metadata for an entry is accessible with a single row identifier, no computationally expensive joins are required to find and pull the information. The database system also typically makes sure all of the data in a row is collocated on the same machine in a cluster, simplifying data sharding and scaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;However, column-family databases do not work well in all scenarios. If you have highly relational data that requires joins, this is not the right type of database for your application. Column-family databases are firmly oriented around row-based operations. This means that aggregate queries like summing, averaging, and other analytics-oriented processes can be difficult or impossible. This can have a great impact on how you design your applications and what types of usage patterns you can use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;Examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;styles__H3-fvdpr4-10 fdlJWJ&quot; id=&quot;newsql-databases-bringing-modern-scalability-and-performance-to-the-traditional-relational-pattern&quot;&gt;NewSQL databases: bringing modern scalability and performance to the traditional relational pattern&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;styles__Strong-fvdpr4-15 eHeecn&quot;&gt;Rise in popularity: 2010s&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;NoSQL databases are great options for situations where your data does not fit neatly into the relational pattern. Since they were developed more recently, NoSQL systems tend to be designed with scalability and modern performance requirements in mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;However, until recently, no solution existed to easily &lt;em&gt;scale&lt;/em&gt; relational data. To address this need, a new type of relational databases called NewSQL databases were developed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;NewSQL databases follow the relational structure and semantics, but are built using more modern, scalable designs. The goal is to offer greater scalability than relational databases and greater &lt;em&gt;consistency guarantees&lt;/em&gt; than NoSQL alternatives. They achieve this by sacrificing certain amounts of availability in the event of a networking partition. The trade offs between consistency and availability is a fundamental problem of distributed databases described by the &lt;em&gt;CAP theorem&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;styles__Blockquote-fvdpr4-6 dEZflj&quot; readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;styles__Strong-fvdpr4-15 eHeecn&quot;&gt;Definition: CAP Theorem&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;The CAP theorem is a statement about the trade offs that distributed databases must make between availability and consistency. It asserts that in the event of a network partition, a distributed database can choose either to remain available or remain consistent, but it cannot do both. Cluster members in a partitioned network can continue operating, leading to at least temporary inconsistency. Alternatively, at least some of the disconnected members must refuse to alter their data during the partition to ensure data consistency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;To address the availability concern, new architectures were developed to minimize the impact of partitions. For instance, splitting data sets into smaller ranges called &lt;em&gt;shards&lt;/em&gt; can minimize the amount of data that is unavailable during partitions. Furthermore, mechanisms to automatically alter the roles of various cluster members based on network conditions allow them to regain availability quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;Because of these qualities, NewSQL databases are best suited for use cases with high volumes of relational data in distributed, cloud-like environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;While NewSQL databases offer most of the familiar features of conventional relational databases, there are some important differences that prevent it from being a one-to-one replacement. NewSQL systems are typically less flexible and generalized than their more conventional relational counterparts. They also usually only offer a subset of full SQL and relational features, which means that they might not be able to handle certain kinds of usage. Many NewSQL implementations also store a large part of or their entire dataset in the computer's main memory. This improves performance at the cost of greater risk to unpersisted changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;NewSQL databases are a good fit for relational datasets that require scaling beyond what conventional relational databases can offer. Because they implement the relational abstraction and provide SQL interfaces, transitioning to a NewSQL database is often more straightforward than moving to a NoSQL alternative. However, it's important to keep in mind that although they mostly seek to replicate the conventional relational environments, there are differences that may affect your deployments. Be sure to research these differences and identify situations where the resemblance breaks down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;Examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;styles__H3-fvdpr4-10 fdlJWJ&quot; id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;Database types have changed a lot since their initial introduction and new database ideas are actively being developed today. Each of the types used in modern systems have distinct advantages that are worth exploring given the right access patterns, data properties, and requirements. One of the first and most important decisions when starting a new project is evaluating your needs and finding the type that matches your project's demands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;styles__Paragraph-fvdpr4-5 hNKcsf&quot;&gt;Many times, using a mixture of different database types is the best approach for handling the data of your projects. Your applications and services will influence the type of data being generated as well as the features and access patterns you require. For example, user information for your system might fit best in a relational database, while the configuration values for your services might benefit from an in-memory key-value store. Learning what each type of database offers can help you recognize which systems are best for all of your different types of data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 14:57:41 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ironcutter</dc:creator>
<og:title>Comparing Database Types: How Database Types Evolved to Meet Different Needs | Prisma</og:title>
<og:description>Many types of databases exist, each with their own benefits. In this guide, we'll compare the relational, document, key-value, graph, and wide-column databases and talk about what each of them offer.</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.prisma.io/blog/posts/database-type-comparison.png</og:image>
<og:url>https://www.prisma.io/blog/comparison-of-database-models-1iz9u29nwn37</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.prisma.io/blog/comparison-of-database-models-1iz9u29nwn37</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Facebook to acquire CTRL-Labs, a startup for controlling computers with the mind</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-09-23/facebook-to-buy-startup-for-controlling-computers-with-your-mind</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-09-23/facebook-to-buy-startup-for-controlling-computers-with-your-mind</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-09-23/facebook-to-buy-startup-for-controlling-computers-with-your-mind&quot;&gt;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-09-23/facebook-to-buy-startup-for-controlling-computers-with-your-mind&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=21058975&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=21058975&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 246&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 125&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 11:52:20 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Bostonian</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/tosv2.html?vid=&amp;uuid=009b1ae0-df30-11e9-9b62-35f3f73ee6b7&amp;url=L25ld3MvYXJ0aWNsZXMvMjAxOS0wOS0yMy9mYWNlYm9vay10by1idXktc3RhcnR1cC1mb3ItY29udHJvbGxpbmctY29tcHV0ZXJzLXdpdGgteW91ci1taW5k</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Voidcall – Making of 13kb JavaScript RTS Game</title>
<link>https://phoboslab.org/log/2019/09/voidcall-making-of</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://phoboslab.org/log/2019/09/voidcall-making-of</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Like last year with &lt;a href=&quot;https://phoboslab.org/log/2018/09/underrun-making-of&quot;&gt;Underrun&lt;/a&gt;, I participated in this year's &lt;a href=&quot;https://js13kgames.com/&quot;&gt;js13kGames&lt;/a&gt; – a JavaScript game development competition with a file size limit of 13kb, including code, assets and everything else. My entry was &lt;a href=&quot;https://phoboslab.org/voidcall&quot;&gt;Voidcall&lt;/a&gt;, a Real-time Strategy game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://phoboslab.org/voidcall/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://phoboslab.org/content/assets/voidcall-screenshot.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Voidcall&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;Play Voidcall – A WebGL Real-time Strategy game in 13kb of JavaScript&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I played the original Command &amp;amp; Conquer (later dubbed &quot;Tiberian Dawn&quot;) again. I spent a whole summer of my childhood exploring the game in a friends basement. Compared to later real-time strategy games it's quite simple, yet very compelling. I set out to capture a bit of the game's essence for js13k.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Squeezing everything I wanted for this game into the tiny size of 13kb was a tough challenge. Much more so than last year. The technology is quite ambitious: a 3d rendered height map, fully polygonal and textured models with smooth keyframe interpolated vertex animations, comprehensive mouse control with accurate picking and solid pathfinding. It's a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article presents the various pieces of the puzzle with in-depth explanations. Everything is open source, so you can follow along on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/phoboslab/voidcall&quot;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Terrain Generation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially I thought about implementing the game in a simpler Canvas2D rendered view, but realized that I would need a lot of different graphics for the map (and much more for animated characters). Using a 3d rendered height map was the &lt;em&gt;easier&lt;/em&gt; way to get a good looking terrain on the screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://phoboslab.org/content/assets/voidcall-collisionmap.png&quot; alt=&quot;Perlin Noise Collision Map&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;The collision map: 2-octave perlin noise, converted to 1bit&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An initial 256x256 Canvas2D image is generated using a perlin noise function. This function produces random values with a smooth gradient for nearby pixels. The key is to layer several perlin noise values with different frequencies on top of each other. In this case each pixel is the sum two perlin noise values. You can create the broad features of the terrain with just one value at a low frequency and add finer detail with a second one at a higher frequency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-js&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; y &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; i &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; y &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;def&quot;&gt;MAP_SIZE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; y&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;++)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; x &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; x &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;def&quot;&gt;MAP_SIZE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; x&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;++,&lt;/span&gt; i&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;++)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; height &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; 
            noise&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;x&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;def&quot;&gt;35&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; y&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;def&quot;&gt;35&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;             noise&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;x&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;def&quot;&gt;50&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; y&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;def&quot;&gt;50&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the result is visually already quite pleasing, it's not of much use for the game I wanted to build. I needed discrete distinction between walkable and un-walkable terrain for the pathfinding to work properly. So this image is converted to just 1 bit with a carefully chosen threshold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This 1 bit image becomes the initial collision map for the game logic. For the height map that is used for the graphics this collision map is further processed. The first step is a bit of blur, so we get some smooth edges around the hills again. After that a bunch of high frequency perlin noise is layered on top.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://phoboslab.org/content/assets/voidcall-heightmap.png&quot; alt=&quot;Perlin Noise Height Map&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;The height map: blurred and detailed with high frequency perlin noise&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the Canvas2D API does not provide a cross-browser blur function. Applying a box blur on each pixel using a convolution filter is not only computationally expensive, but also requires a bit more code than I wanted to spend on this. My solution was just to draw the height map on top of itself a bunch of times:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-js&quot;&gt;ctx&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;globalAlpha &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; x &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; x &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; x&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;++)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; y &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; y &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; y&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;++)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
                ctx&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;drawImage&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;canvas&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; x&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; y&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt; 
    &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the details a number of perlin noise values are computed and mashed together until it looked &lt;em&gt;right&lt;/em&gt;. The higher frequency noise is applied more strongly to the hills and less so to the valleys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-js&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; y &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; i &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; y &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;def&quot;&gt;MAP_SIZE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; y&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;++)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; x &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; x &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;def&quot;&gt;MAP_SIZE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; x&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;++,&lt;/span&gt; i&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;++)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt;
            coarse &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; px&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;[(&lt;/span&gt;y&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;def&quot;&gt;MAP_SIZE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;x&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;)*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;],&lt;/span&gt;
            mid &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; noise&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;x&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;def&quot;&gt;12&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; y&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;def&quot;&gt;12&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
            fine &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; 
                noise&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;x&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;def&quot;&gt;30&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; y&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;def&quot;&gt;30&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;
                noise&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;x&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;def&quot;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; y&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;def&quot;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;
                noise&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;x&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; y&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; 
                noise&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;x&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; y&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt;
            height &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; 
                coarse &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;6&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;                 fine &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;def&quot;&gt;300&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;                 mid &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;                 &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;coarse &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;mid&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;                 &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;coarse &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;fine&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;                 &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;((&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;def&quot;&gt;255&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;coarse&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; mid&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;*-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;)*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we have the height map, we can create the 3d geometry. For each pixel of this height map a quad (2 triangles) is created and pushed to the render buffer. Each quad is randomly textured with one of two different grass-like tiles – just enough to make it not look repetitive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The normal vector (the vector perpendicular to the surface) is computed once for each quad. This is later used for light calculations in the shader. The same normal vector is initially stored for each of the 4 vertices of the quad. This results in a flat shaded look.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final buffer for the height map contains 131k triangles consisting of 393k vertices, each described by 8 Float32 values. In total about 12 MB of data - which may sound like a lot, but your GPU laughs at these numbers. I'll talk more about how this is actually rendered later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://phoboslab.org/content/assets/voidcall-terrain-flat-shaded.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Perlin Noise Terrain&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Flat shaded terrain, without smooth normals. Interesting, but not what I was going for.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Computing smooth normals turned out to be a particularly hairy problem to solve in this very size constrained code. The solution I ended up with is to walk through the otherwise final buffer, gather all normals from adjacent vertices, average them and put the averaged normals straight back into the buffer. This &lt;em&gt;in place&lt;/em&gt; editing of the normal vectors produces quite terse code, but is otherwise horrible in every aspect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result of all this is stored in a &lt;code&gt;gl.STATIC_DRAW&lt;/code&gt; buffer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the final detailing a few thousand models of rocks and trees are randomly sprinkled over the map. The 1 bit collision map is used, so that these models are only placed in the valleys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was important for the mouse picking to work correctly to have &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; the height map without trees in it's own buffer. So all detailed models combined are stored in second &lt;code&gt;gl.STATIC_DRAW&lt;/code&gt; buffer, separate from the height map geometry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://phoboslab.org/content/assets/voidcall-terrain.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Perlin Noise Terrain&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;The final Perlin Noise generated terrain, with smoothed normals and detail models&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though the terrain generation is based on randomness, it was important for the gameplay that you always end up with the same terrain each time you load the game. So using JavaScript's built-in &lt;code&gt;Math.random()&lt;/code&gt; would not do. Instead, the game makes use of a very simple &lt;em&gt;seedable&lt;/em&gt; random number generator. Initializing it with the same seed value before generating the terrain always produces exactly the same result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A fun problem I encountered with my perlin noise function was that it still produced different results in different browsers. To initialize the perlin noise function an array of sequential values is shuffled using JavaScripts built-in &lt;code&gt;Array.sort&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-js&quot;&gt;p&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;sort&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; random_float&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While &lt;code&gt;random_float()&lt;/code&gt; always correctly produced the same sequence of numbers in all browsers, browsers still implement the sort algorithm differently. So in Chrome you will end up with a different shuffled array than in Firefox. Of course &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/JavaScript/Reference/Global_Objects/Array/sort&quot;&gt;MDN warns you about this&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The time and space complexity of the sort cannot be guaranteed as it depends on the implementation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's not exactly the right way to shuffle an array with an nonsensical comparator function anyway. Lesson learned. (The &lt;em&gt;right&lt;/em&gt; way is to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/phoboslab/voidcall/blob/master/source/perlin_noise.js#L12-L18&quot;&gt;walk through the array and swap each element with a random other element&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the final game I just plugged in different seed values until I found a terrain that was interesting and suitable for the gameplay. Not all terrains generated with this method produce usable results. Sometimes one half of the map is completely cut off from the other half. Sometimes &quot;islands&quot; of unreachable terrain are generated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://phoboslab.org/content/assets/voidcall-terrain-seeds.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Perlin Noise Terrain&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Terrains generated with different seed values&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though the terrain I initially settled on was quite nice, I later discovered that an area that I thought was reachable in fact wasn't. I didn't want to search for a new terrain and carefully place all game objects again. So I just fudged it by drawing a rectangle on a certain spot on the map to make a traversable path. It's the nasty secrets of game development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final code for the terrain generation is all in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/phoboslab/voidcall/blob/master/source/map.js#L4&quot;&gt;map_generate()&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;3D Models, Textures &amp;amp; Vertex Animations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of work has gone into making the animated models and compressing them down to a reasonable size.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm still a doofus when it comes to 3d modeling, but the amazingly ingenious &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wings3d.com&quot;&gt;Wings3D&lt;/a&gt; once again saved the day. It works great with low-poly models. Turns out low-poly modeling is a lot like creating low-res pixel art: you just push things around until it looks right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://phoboslab.org/content/assets/voidcall-unit-model.png&quot; alt=&quot;Low Poly Character Model&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;The main character model – 36 vertices, 62 faces, 6 animation frames, compressed to 572 bytes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main character model is as low-poly as you can possibly get with a convincing humanoid. All limbs are just triangular and end in a single point. Still, as you previously saw with the terrain, 3d data can get absolutely huge. Even for this model, if we'd store each of the 62 faces with 3x3 Float32 values, we'd end up with 2kb of data - for a single animation frame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, the character model contains 6 animation frames. I looked into skeletal animations, but this would have required a lot of code to get working. So instead I opted for the simplest possible solution: vertex animations. I.e. each frame of an animation contains the whole model again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the character model contains a full set of vertex positions for each of the 6 animation frames, but still compresses to just 572 bytes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://phoboslab.org/content/assets/voidcall-unit-animations.png&quot; alt=&quot;Animation Frames&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;The six different animation frames: 4x run, 1x shoot, 1x idle&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's two techniques I used to get there. The first one is just common sense (and used by almost any model data format): each of the 36 vertices is shared by multiple faces. So we just store the x,y,z position for each of the 36 vertices once and use an index into the vertex positions for each of the 3 corners of a face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, if we don't change the topology of the model in each animation frame, we just need to store the vertex positions again. The set of indices for the faces remains the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we restrict ourselves to a maximum of just 255 vertices, we can store each index as a single byte. Similarly, if we convert the Float32 x,y,z vertex positions to a single byte each, we can save 9 bytes per vertex. &quot;Compressing&quot; arbitrary precision numbers down to a set of discrete values (in this case 0–255) is called quantization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So with the x,y,z position as one byte each, we need 3 bytes to store each vertex. Similarly, with each face using 3 x 1 byte indices (one for each corner) into the vertex data, we need 3 bytes to store a single face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;36 vertices * 6 animation frames * 3 byte = 648 bytes
 +
62 faces * 3 byte = 186 byte
 =
834 bytes&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not too bad, but still too much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I noticed that with models this simple, we don't actually need the 1 byte &quot;precision&quot; of 256 discrete values for the x,y,z positions. We can lower the resolution even more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next logical step is to pack all 3 values into just 2 bytes or 16 bit. This leaves us with 5 bits for each x,y,z value. (Technically 5.333 bits per value. We could use the extra 1 bit to give one of the x,y,z axis more resolution, but here I didn't. The extra 1 bit is just unused.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5 bits gives us values from 0–31. So each of the vertex positions is essentially snapped into a grid of 32x32x32 values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course I wanted to compress the face data similarly, but with values in the range 0–31 we wouldn't be able to address all 36 vertices. Luckily I noticed that Wings3D exports the face data with the vertex index for the first corner of each face in ascending order:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;f 1// 22// 2//
f 2// 3// 1//
f 2// 24// 18//
f 3// 4// 1//
f 3// 8// 6//
f 4// 23// 17//
f 5// 3// 6//
…
f 32// 35// 33//
f 33// 26// 32//
f 33// 34// 26//
f 33// 35// 34//
f 34// 32// 27//
f 36// 30// 29//&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The exported model contains one row per face, 3 indices into the vertex data. Notice how the first index is in ascending order and increases by 2 at most.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The logical conclusion is to store a 2 bit address increment for the first vertex index of each face and use 2 x 7 bit numbers for the two remaining indices. This allows us to store models with up to 127 vertices. Plenty!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course we need to store a bit of metadata with each model: the number of vertices, faces and animation frames. Described as a C-struct, the final model format looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;struct&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    uint8_t num_frames&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    uint8_t num_verts&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;     uint16_t num_indices&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;struct&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        uint8_t reserved &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
        int8_t x &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
        int8_t y &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
        int8_t z &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; vertices&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;num_frames &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; num_verts&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;];&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;struct&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        uint8_t a_address_inc &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
        uint8_t b_index &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;7&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
        uint8_t c_index &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;7&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; indices&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;num_indices&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;];&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; rmf_data&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course Wings3D doesn't have an exporter for this esoteric format. Instead I exported my models in the Wavefront OBJ format. This format contains easily parsable plain text data. A &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/phoboslab/voidcall/blob/master/obj_to_rmf.php&quot;&gt;simple PHP script&lt;/a&gt; is used to convert the OBJ format into this binary format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game contains a total of 10 different models. All those are concatenated into a single file for easier loading and better ZIP compression, totaling in 1328 bytes. The model format is so terse that it barely ZIP-compresses (1203 bytes zipped).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://phoboslab.org/content/assets/voidcall-all-models.png&quot; alt=&quot;All Voidcall Models&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;From left to right: tree, boulder (re-used for gibs and energy well), blade of grass (yes, really), waypoint, unit selection bracket, ship, harvester, turret, enemy, unit.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The models then get textured, each with a single tile of the texture image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://phoboslab.org/content/assets/voidcall-textures.png&quot; alt=&quot;Textured Model&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;All the textures used in the game, 1643 bytes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because my model format doesn't contain any texture coordinates I opted for a very simple hack to lay textures over the models: the tile is just projected from the front onto the model. Essentially the x,y coordinates of each vertex &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; the texture coordinates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://phoboslab.org/content/assets/voidcall-unit-models-textured.png&quot; alt=&quot;Textured Model&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Textured Model, with the texture projected directly from the front&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice how the feet and hands of the untextured model are very pointy, ending in a single vertex. Using transparent pixels in the textures for all unit types the hand and feet are cut off, expect for the military unit where a black texture indicates the gun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To blend between the different animation frames the game just linearly interpolates between the vertex positions of the last and current frame. The frame interpolation, as well as unpacking of the face indices into vertex positions and Y-rotation of the models is all handled in JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/phoboslab/voidcall/blob/master/source/model.js&quot;&gt;code to load and render a model&lt;/a&gt; clocks in at just 150 lines. It's wholly unoptimized (e.g. loaded models are not cached) but it just doesn't matter for these kinds of poly-counts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Mouse Picking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My game requires accurate mouse controls. I need to know exactly where the mouse cursor is, not in screen space, but &lt;em&gt;in world space&lt;/em&gt;. Typically you'd project a ray from the mouse cursor, through the screen and onto the 3d geometry. This requires quite a bit of math that I so far avoided throughout the project. Plus, you'd need a hit-test function on the height map.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another technique – one that has fallen out of favor for modern games – is to render a specially encoded view of the game and read back the pixels. For instance, you could render each object that you can hit in a different color, then read back the pixel color under the mouse cursor and determine which object you have hit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my game I wasn't really interested in any particular object, but where exactly the mouse cursor is on the height map. If I know that, I can easily determine the objects nearby in JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://phoboslab.org/content/assets/voidcall-mouse-picking.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mouse picking&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;World position (x, y, z) encoded in RGB colors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game renders just the height map, nothing else, with a simple shader that encodes the x, y, z coordinates in RGB colors. This leaves us with a resolution of just 0–255 in each dimension, but as it turned out the low resolution is not really noticeable in game. The game space is divided into a tile grid anyway, so the accuracy to hit a single tile is plenty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The shader looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;void&lt;/span&gt; main&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;void&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    gl_FragColor &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; vec4&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;
        vertex_pos&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;x &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;def&quot;&gt;512&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
        vertex_pos&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;y &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;def&quot;&gt;MAP_HEIGHT&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
        vertex_pos&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;z &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;def&quot;&gt;512&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The x, z offset and the divisions are carefully selected for the normal camera distance. The Z-axis is just divided by the maximum height of the map. If the game would allow you to zoom out, we'd need to account for this in the shader. However, the game's zoom level always stays the same, so these values can be hardcoded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course these RGB colors are offset by the current camera position, so we have account for that when determining the mouse position:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-js&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; px &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; Uint8Array&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
gl&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;readPixels&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;
    mouse_x&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
    screen_height &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; mouse_y&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; gl&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;def&quot;&gt;RGBA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; gl&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;def&quot;&gt;UNSIGNED_BYTE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; px
&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;

mouse_world_x &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;px&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;def&quot;&gt;255&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;def&quot;&gt;512&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; camera_x&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; mouse_world_y &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;px&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;def&quot;&gt;255&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;def&quot;&gt;MAP_HEIGHT&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;           mouse_world_z &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;px&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;def&quot;&gt;255&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;def&quot;&gt;512&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; camera_z&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Allow me to complain about OpenGLs coordinate system. OpenGL has it's 0,0 position in the lower left corner of screen, because apparently it's more scientific this way. It seems trivial to just invert everything, but the number of times and the hours I spent dealing with this just leaves me bitter. Whether it was for &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/phoboslab/ejecta&quot;&gt;Ejecta&lt;/a&gt;, simple things like my &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/phoboslab/WebGLImageFilter&quot;&gt;WebGLImageFilter&lt;/a&gt; or for this game – you have to flip the screen and your coordinates ALL THE FKING TIME. I hate it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This way of mouse picking – implemented with another render pass – is discouraged these days because you typically stall your program while waiting for &lt;code&gt;gl.readPixels()&lt;/code&gt; to render the view and return the color buffer, instead of letting the GPU do its thing and compute the next frame. It just absolutely kills performance. But as with so many other things for this game, it just doesn't matter. Computers are fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Rendering&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The renderer borrows most of its code from my last year's entry &lt;a href=&quot;https://phoboslab.org/log/2018/09/underrun-making-of&quot;&gt;Underrun&lt;/a&gt;. Underun pushed everything into a single buffer and rendered the whole game in just one draw call. For Voidcall I needed to divide that into several draw calls, but the overall structure remains the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The terrain geometry is stored in a separate static buffer and first rendered in faux-colors for the mouse picking described above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afterwards the terrain is rendered again with a special shader that desaturates the texture color based on the y position. This nicely &quot;blends&quot; the grass texture into gray-ish stone for the hills. On top of that follows another static buffer with all decorative geometry, trees and bolders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A dynamic buffer is used to render all the models, then flushed and re-used for another pass for the shadows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The object shadows are just quads with a shadow blurred shadow blob as texture. But because they are transparent, we need to render these on top of all the other objects, with the depth buffer disabled. Otherwise the semi-transparent pixels of the shadow texture would hide all objects below them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://phoboslab.org/content/assets/voidcall-render-phases.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Voidcall render passes&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Four draw calls produce the final image&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game allows for a maximum of 16 dynamic lights. They work basically the same as in Underrun, but this time the light calculations are done in the pixel shader, instead of in the vertex shaders. This gives us a smoother look, compared to the low-fi visuals of last year's game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ingame &quot;chat&quot; of your units is just an HTML element overlayed over the canvas. I didn't want to deal with text-rendering inside of WebGL. After all we are running in a browser here, so why not use it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The code for the renderer can be found in the aptly named &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/phoboslab/voidcall/blob/master/source/renderer.js&quot;&gt;renderer.js&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Pathfinding&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Voidcall uses a pretty standard A-Star algorithm for pathfinding. To optimize the performance a bit my A-Star implementation allocates all neccessary data up-front. It never has to allocate any data during run-time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of storing the set of visited nodes and their costs in objects pushed into a plain JavaScript arrays, all state information is stored in a number of separate TypedArrays. To make this work, my implementation works directly with the &quot;addresses&quot; of nodes instead of their x, z position. The address is just &lt;code&gt;z * MAP_SIZE + x&lt;/code&gt; – i.e. the index into these typed arrays. Consequently, this also reduced the code size quite a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-js&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; 
    nodes_parent &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; Uint16Array&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;def&quot;&gt;MAP_SIZE&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;def&quot;&gt;MAP_SIZE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt;
    nodes_state &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; Uint8Array&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;def&quot;&gt;MAP_SIZE&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;def&quot;&gt;MAP_SIZE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt;
    nodes_g &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; Float32Array&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;def&quot;&gt;MAP_SIZE&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;def&quot;&gt;MAP_SIZE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt;
    nodes_f &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; Float32Array&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;def&quot;&gt;MAP_SIZE&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;def&quot;&gt;MAP_SIZE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt;
    open_nodes &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; Uint16Array&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;def&quot;&gt;MAP_SIZE&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt; 
    &lt;span class=&quot;def&quot;&gt;NEIGHBORS&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;def&quot;&gt;MAP_SIZE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;def&quot;&gt;MAP_SIZE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;def&quot;&gt;MAP_SIZE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;                     &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;def&quot;&gt;MAP_SIZE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;def&quot;&gt;MAP_SIZE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;def&quot;&gt;MAP_SIZE&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;],&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;def&quot;&gt;STATE_UNKNOWN&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;def&quot;&gt;STATE_OPEN&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;def&quot;&gt;STATE_CLOSED&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;while&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;num_open_nodes    &lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; current_addr &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; open_nodes&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;num_open_nodes&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;];&lt;/span&gt;
    …

    &lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; i &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; i &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;def&quot;&gt;NEIGHBORS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;length&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; i&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;++)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; neighbor_addr &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; current_addr &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;def&quot;&gt;NEIGHBORS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;i&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;],&lt;/span&gt;

                …

                nodes_parent&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;neighbor_addr&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; current_addr&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
        nodes_state&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;neighbor_addr&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;def&quot;&gt;STATE_OPEN&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
        nodes_g&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;neighbor_addr&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; g&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
        nodes_f&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;neighbor_addr&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; f&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
        num_open_nodes&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;++;&lt;/span&gt;

                …
    &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, to compute the cost for each node we need to get the x, z position from the address again, which is simply:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-js&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; x &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; address &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;def&quot;&gt;MAP_SIZE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
    z &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;address &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;def&quot;&gt;MAP_SIZE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;)|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or, as I knew my MAP_SIZE is 256, I can just use some bit-twiddling instead of costly divisions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-js&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; x &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; address &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;0xff&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;     z &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; address &lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;punct&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;    &lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://phoboslab.org/content/assets/voidcall-astar-nodes.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;AStar Pathfinding&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;All visited nodes (white) and the found path (blue)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a final step the found path is condensed to the minimum number of waypoints: For each waypoint all subsequent waypoints are removed if they are visible across the map until we find one that is not. This eliminates extraneous waypoints that would result in stiff movement in a checkerboard fashion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://phoboslab.org/content/assets/voidcall-astar-path.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;AStar Pathfinding&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;The condensed set of nodes necessary to reach the target&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this all, plotting a path across the whole map takes about 1.5ms. Still costly, but good enough. The complete implementation fits in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/phoboslab/voidcall/blob/master/source/astar.js&quot;&gt;just 120 lines of code&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sound &amp;amp; Music&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like last year, I used the brilliant &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nicolas-van/sonant-x&quot;&gt;Sonant-X&lt;/a&gt; library for sound and music. My dear friend Andreas Lösch of &lt;a href=&quot;http://no-fate.net&quot;&gt;no-fate.net&lt;/a&gt; once again produced an amazing soundtrack in &lt;a href=&quot;https://nicolas-van.github.io/sonant-x-live/&quot;&gt;Sonant-X Live&lt;/a&gt;. Likewise, the few sound effects also use this library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did however overhaul the library; almost rewriting it. Instead of using generator functions for the sine, square, sawtooth and triangle oscillators everything is precomputed into a single lookup table. This tremendously sped up the time needed to render the soundtrack. It allowed me to remove all of the asynchronous &lt;code&gt;setTimeout()&lt;/code&gt; calls that were originally implemented to make the page more responsive while loading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole library is now &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/phoboslab/voidcall/blob/master/source/audio.js&quot;&gt;about 250 lines of code&lt;/a&gt; and generates the 120 seconds of music in just 900ms – down from 5900ms for the original library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Gameplay&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Admittedly the gameplay is a bit of a weak spot. With all the tech implemented I had very little time to tune the actual game mechanics. The game is probably a bit too hard, even if you know exactly what to do. Worse, most players are initially totally lost. The game really could have used a bit of tutorial or maybe just a slower start to give players more time to get familiar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cursor controls stress test with a lot of units&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm pretty proud of how the mouse controls turned out: selecting single units, dragging selection areas, ordering them around, building turrets and harvesters all work pretty much like in any other full-blown RTS. The code to get this working however is &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/phoboslab/voidcall/blob/master/source/entity_cursor.js#L16&quot;&gt;a big mess of spaghetti&lt;/a&gt;. And it's not &lt;em&gt;feature-complete&lt;/em&gt; either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can't order one of your grunts to attack a specific enemy. Instead, they will only attack the closest one. Similarly, your medic will only heal the unit closest to him – even if that unit has full health already and another unit that really needs healing is in range. I simply ran out of time and space to implement these things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The logic to spawn enemies and their AI is pretty bare bones, too: Enemies spawn in decreasing time intervals, depending on the total amount of energy you're creating. A random position outside the map is chosen for the spawn point. The enemy then walks down the hills to the valley and searches for the nearest player unit or building. The initial random target for the enemy can be overridden if the enemy is attacked. It will then move towards the attacker. That's it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game has a bit of animation when you successfully get your power levels up and return with all (remaining) units to the ship. I doubt many people have seen it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Minification&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of the same techniques as in &lt;a href=&quot;https://phoboslab.org/log/2018/09/underrun-making-of&quot;&gt;Underrun&lt;/a&gt; were used to compress the game. This time however I had to work harder to keep the game's size under the 13kb limit. The uncompressed code weighs in at about 96kb, so minifying was absolutely crucial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some random observations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Aliasing lengthy JavaScript function names or &lt;code&gt;document&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;window&lt;/code&gt; to shorter names doesn't help when you ZIP-compress your code anyway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Every file in a ZIP carries a considerable overhead of about 100 bytes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The order in which you concat your source files does matter for ZIP compression. Grouping code that &lt;em&gt;looks&lt;/em&gt; similar can give you another 100-200 bytes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The final game consists of just three files: the textures PNG, the models in binary format and an index.html with all the code. The PNG and models are just about 2kb; the rest, about 11kb, is all code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://phoboslab.org/content/assets/voidcall-code.png&quot; alt=&quot;Voidcall code&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;The complete minified code just about fits on my screen in the default font size&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The full uncompressed source for Voidcall is on github: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/phoboslab/voidcall&quot;&gt;github.com/phoboslab/voidcall&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fun fact: this article contains 28000 characters – more than twice as much as was allowed for the game. It does ZIP-compress to just 10kb, though.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 10:47:13 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ash</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://phoboslab.org/log/2019/09/voidcall-making-of</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>