<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>How not to replace email: lessons from Google Wave</title>
<link>https://jamey.thesharps.us/2018/02/16/how-not-to-replace-email/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://jamey.thesharps.us/2018/02/16/how-not-to-replace-email/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;As of a month ago, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://incubator.apache.org/projects/wave.html&quot;&gt;Apache Wave&lt;/a&gt; project is “retired”. Few people noticed; in the seven years that Wave was an Apache Incubator open source project, it never had an official release, and was stuck at version 0.4-rc10 for the last three years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before being handed off to Apache in 2011, Wave was a Google product, first announced in 2009. Google made Wave fully accessible to the public in May of 2010, but announced they would no longer be developing it just three months later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2017 was a year of rapidly growing interest in federated communications tools such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://joinmastodon.org/&quot;&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt;, which is an alternative to Twitter that doesn’t rely on a single central corporation. So this seems like a good time to revisit an early federated attempt to reinvent how we use the internet to communicate with each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Responding to the announcement that Wave is now officially retired, my friend &lt;a href=&quot;https://what.happens.when.computer/&quot;&gt;Getty Ritter&lt;/a&gt; wrote in a private Slack (quoted by permission):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was one of about four people who thought that Wave would have been a good project if only they didn’t oversell it and also if it had been, like, not Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We used Wave for project planning in creating a video game back in the day, and it was &lt;em&gt;perfect&lt;/em&gt; for that, but not for any of the reasons they advertised or were proud of. We didn’t care about the cool live editing algorithms, but having this sort of nice rich media environment that permitted a hybrid messages and collaborative editing environment was great. We’d start sending messages with lots of diagrams, sketches, and stuff cribbed from Google Images, and then be able to turn those sort of longer-than-IM-shorter-than-email messages into actual design documents gradually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, I’d argue that even having a system that’s a messaging system designed for “a paragraph or two” was on its own worthwhile: even Slack isn’t &lt;em&gt;quite&lt;/em&gt; geared toward that, and contrariwise, email […] felt more heavyweight than that. Wave &lt;em&gt;felt&lt;/em&gt; like it encouraged the right amount of information per message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getty’s description gets at some of the issues I have with existing tools when trying to collaborate on a project with other people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I desperately want tool support for taking unstructured thoughts and ideas, and incrementally and collaboratively transforming them into coherent documents. I believe every task in a group project follows this pattern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, in a software project, any bug report starts with scraps of information, posted in IRC or on Twitter or buried in the middle of a seemingly-unrelated mailing list message. I see the process of resolving the bug as mostly about collecting all those pieces of evidence into a coherent story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Human communications is literally not one-size-fits-all. When someone wants to explore a problem or a new idea, they need an easy way to just start chatting with potential collaborators about it; at that stage, short messages like in Slack or Twitter or IRC are perfect. But if the idea goes anywhere, those short messages need to coalesce into larger units of thought: first “a paragraph or two”, and eventually whole blog posts or design documents or other artifacts whose purpose is to convey the most important parts of the idea to people who weren’t involved in the original conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No one technology today spans this range. Instead we switch between instant messaging and email and Google Docs and wikis and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;git&lt;/code&gt;, none of which really play nicely with each other, and we lose history at every step. Wave was explicitly an attempt to unify all those tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;To me, it’s pretty clear why someone might want a tool like Wave just based on the above points. But wait, there’s more!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a technology perspective, Wave was built around two key ideas that it’s hard to imagine Google, as we know it in 2018, would pursue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wave acknowledged that communications via the internet can be delayed enough that humans will notice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These days every Google product seems to assume that your internet connection is always on, that you’re close enough to the nearest Google server that your brain won’t notice the speed-of-light delay, and that you have practically unlimited bandwidth. These assumptions are barely true in Mountain View, let alone in most of the rest of the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first key technology underpinning Wave was “&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Operational_transformation&quot;&gt;Operational Transformation&lt;/a&gt;” (OT), and it allowed people to edit documents together in real time even though their connections to each other might be slow and unreliable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More surprisingly, Wave was explicitly designed to keep Google from being the sole central authority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They released sample implementations under open source licenses, encouraged others to run their own Wave servers independent of Google infrastructure, and defined a federation protocol (on top of Jabber/&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/XMPP&quot;&gt;XMPP&lt;/a&gt;) so that people on different servers could still talk with each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This seems weird, a decade later, when Google and Facebook are each trying to get everyone into their walled gardens so they can serve ads to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;I often find myself disheartened when I see situations like this: that the Wave project tried to tackle these problems almost a decade ago, and failed. But rather than giving up, let’s try to learn some lessons from that failure. Why aren’t we all using Wave today?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The day after Google announced they were ending development on Wave, staffers at Ars Technica wrote “&lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2010/08/google-wave-why-we-didnt-use-it/&quot;&gt;Google Wave: why we didn’t use it&lt;/a&gt;”, a post-mortem which reads much like the analysis of many other failed technologies. To summarize:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The initial implementation was a JavaScript-heavy web application in an era when people weren’t used to that. Browsers weren’t optimized to run so much code and so the user experience was terrible: one Ars staffer reported that he gave up when Safari ground to a halt trying to load the Wave site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google’s interface design aesthetic for Wave was the old-school “Multiple Document Interface” (MDI), rarely seen these days (&lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20080530025541/http://pixelcentric.net/x-shame/docs.html&quot;&gt;for good reason&lt;/a&gt;). An Ars staffer wrote that this “made it ugly and initially confusing for even the savviest of users.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both of those would have been recoverable problems, especially because Google’s web interface was intended to be just one of many. If a variety of Wave-compatible apps had materialized, people could have just chosen the ones that worked better. Unfortunately, the Wave protocol was complex, so the few implementations that eventually appeared came from big companies like Novell and SAP, who only cared about the enterprise market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assuming you could stand Wave’s interface, it’d still be useless unless the people you wanted to communicate and collaborate with were also using it. Wave was intended to completely replace existing systems like email and chat, so it had no provisions for interoperating with those systems. To succeed, Wave required a revolution, a critical mass of people switching to the new way and dragging the rest of the world with them—and those haven’t worked out very often.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making the revolution even more unlikely, initially Google offered Wave accounts by invitation only, so the people you wanted to talk with probably couldn’t even get an account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the end, Wave failed because it was designed assuming everyone would agree to switch to it, but at its launch it had too many issues keeping it from getting enough momentum to reach that critical mass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, I think that’s actually quite a hopeful conclusion! Because here’s the good news:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wave’s failure didn’t have anything to do with the ideas that went into it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those ideas and goals are sound, and this failure even provided good evidence that there’s a real need for something kind of like Wave: fifty thousand people signed a petition to “Save Google Wave” after Google announced they were shutting Wave down. Like so many petitions, it didn’t help (obviously), but if a mediocre implementation got tens of thousands of passionate fans, what could a good implementation do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d say the single most important lesson to take away here, for a technology project at least, is that interoperability is key.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Assume that no matter how amazing your new tech is, people are going to adopt it slowly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give your early adopters every chance you can to use your offering &lt;em&gt;together&lt;/em&gt; with the existing tools that they will continue to need in order to work with people who haven’t caught up yet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And if you’re building a communication tool, make it as simple as possible for others to build compatible tools, because they will expand the network of people your users can communicate with to populations you haven’t thought of and probably don’t understand.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a final thought, I’d like to briefly describe three projects I’ve worked on that I think embodied this principle well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My most widely used open source project, &lt;a href=&quot;https://xcb.freedesktop.org/&quot;&gt;XCB&lt;/a&gt;, was initially intended to be revolutionary. XCB completely replaces Xlib, a C library dating back to 1987, which had accumulated so much cruft that at one point it had an entire color management system which was literally unusable because if you ever called its initialization function, it would immediately crash—and nobody noticed that bug for six months. XCB is in no way compatible with Xlib: initially we thought that people would be excited to rewrite their code rather than deal with Xlib any longer. That has actually been kind of vaguely true, which mostly goes to show how much of a mismatch Xlib is for modern use cases. But XCB really only took off after &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usenix.org/legacy/events/usenix04/tech/freenix/sharp.html&quot;&gt;we rewrote a core part of Xlib to use XCB internally&lt;/a&gt;, and allowed developers to mix and match calls to both libraries in the same application. Now the XCB-based Xlib is used in basically every X Window System installation, on every OS—Linux, BSD, Solaris, Windows, etc—which means that odds are good that you’ve used software that I’ve written.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.comic-rocket.com/&quot;&gt;Comic Rocket&lt;/a&gt; is a site my friends and I built for helping people discover, read, and follow their favorite webcomics. One of my early design decisions was that Comic Rocket would not host any comics itself; instead it acts more like a feed aggregator or a search engine for webcomics. I knew that no matter how good of a job I might do at building tools for creators to publish their comics, I’d never convince everyone to switch to my platform. Through careful architecture decisions and a very clever web-crawler (if I do say so myself), Comic Rocket is able to provide bookmarking and update notifications for comics no matter where they’re hosted on the web. Because its features enhance readers’ experience without any effort from the creators, it has become popular enough among webcomic readers to in turn be a significant source of traffic for creators, and everyone wins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mozilla’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rust-lang.org/&quot;&gt;Rust&lt;/a&gt; is sometimes put on a pedestal as a revolutionary programming language, with a few over-zealous proponents pestering all sorts of projects with arguments that they should rewrite all their software in Rust. (It’s unfair to call Rust revolutionary, though, simply because they’ve put so much work into compatibility and FFI.) To be honest, I’m fully in favor of that idea: I would love to see all the world’s C and C++ software rewritten in Rust, using Rust’s compiler-enforced safety features to discover and fix many lurking bugs and crashes. Of course, as I’ve written about before, there are plenty of &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamey.thesharps.us/2017/01/03/which-projects-should-convert-to-rust/&quot;&gt;reasons why people shouldn’t rewrite everything in Rust&lt;/a&gt;. One major reason is that a by-hand rewrite is error-prone and likely to introduce new bugs. That’s why I started writing &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jameysharp/corrode&quot;&gt;Corrode&lt;/a&gt;, a fully automatic C to Rust translator. Building automatic tools to migrate from the old way to your awesome new way significantly reduces the barriers for getting people to switch. If Corrode (or any of the other similar tools people have written) were complete, then developers and managers could no longer object to using Rust solely on the grounds that all their existing code is in C. They’d be left with other good reasons, like that none of their team knows Rust, or that their static analysis tools only work on C, but each of those objections can be addressed given time. Creating a solid transition plan makes adoption significantly more likely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To sum up: Google Wave tackled real problems, but failed because it relied on a revolution that never happened, which is the outcome you should expect for any technology project that expects everyone to switch to it right away. Would somebody please try again but with less hubris this time?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2018 04:26:23 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>eadmund</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://jamey.thesharps.us/2018/02/16/how-not-to-replace-email/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How to make a game from scratch using Lua and Löve</title>
<link>https://github.com/SSYGEN/blog/issues/30</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/SSYGEN/blog/issues/30</guid>
<description>&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tutorial series will cover the creation of a complete game with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lua.org/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Lua&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://love2d.org/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;LÖVE&lt;/a&gt;. It's aimed at programmers who have some experience but are just starting out with game development, or game developers who already have some experience with other languages or frameworks but want to figure out Lua or LÖVE better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game that will be created is a mix of &lt;a href=&quot;http://store.steampowered.com/app/433950/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Bit Blaster XL&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pathofexile.com/passive-skill-tree&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Path of Exile's Passive Skill Tree&lt;/a&gt;. It's simple enough that it can be covered in a number of articles without extending for too long, but with enough content that a beginner would feel uncomfortable with the code and end up giving up before finishing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SSYGEN/blog/raw/master/images/bytepath-shielder.gif&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/SSYGEN/blog/raw/master/images/bytepath-shielder.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's also at a level of complexity that most game development tutorials don't cover. Most of the problems beginners have when starting out with game development have to do with scope. The usual advice is to start small and work your way up, and while that might be a good idea, if the types of projects you're interested in cannot be made any smaller then there are very few resources out there that attempt to guide you through the problems that come up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my case, I've always been interested in making games with lots and lots of items/passives/skills and so when I was starting out it was really hard to figure out a good way to structure my code so that I wouldn't get lost. Hopefully these tutorials can help someone with that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SSYGEN/blog/raw/master/images/bytepath-skill-tree.gif&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/SSYGEN/blog/raw/master/images/bytepath-skill-tree.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you start there are some programming knowledge requirements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;3.6984126984127&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The basics of programming, like variables, loops, conditionals, basic data structures and so on;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The basics of OOP, like knowing what classes, instances, attributes and methods are;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the very basics of Lua, &lt;a href=&quot;https://learnxinyminutes.com/docs/lua/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;this quick tutorial&lt;/a&gt; should be good enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Essentially this is not for people who are just getting started with programming in general. Also, this tutorial series will have exercises. If you've ever been in the situation where you finish a tutorial and you don't know what to do next it's probably because it had no exercises, so if you don't want that to happen here then I recommend at least trying to do them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SSYGEN/blog/raw/master/images/bytepath-lightning.gif&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/SSYGEN/blog/raw/master/images/bytepath-lightning.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Contents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SSYGEN/blog/issues/15&quot;&gt;1. Game Loop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SSYGEN/blog/issues/16&quot;&gt;2. Libraries&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SSYGEN/blog/issues/17&quot;&gt;3. Rooms and Areas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SSYGEN/blog/issues/18&quot;&gt;4. Exercises&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SSYGEN/blog/issues/19&quot;&gt;5. Game Basics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SSYGEN/blog/issues/20&quot;&gt;6. Player Basics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SSYGEN/blog/issues/21&quot;&gt;7. Player Stats and Attacks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SSYGEN/blog/issues/22&quot;&gt;8. Enemies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SSYGEN/blog/issues/23&quot;&gt;9. Director and Gameplay Loop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SSYGEN/blog/issues/24&quot;&gt;10. Coding Practices&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SSYGEN/blog/issues/25&quot;&gt;11. Passives&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SSYGEN/blog/issues/26&quot;&gt;12. More Passives&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SSYGEN/blog/issues/27&quot;&gt;13. Skill Tree&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SSYGEN/blog/issues/28&quot;&gt;14. Console&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SSYGEN/blog/issues/29&quot;&gt;15. Final&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you liked these tutorials and want to support the writing of more like these in the future:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buying the tutorial on itch.io gives you access to the game's full source code, answers to exercises from articles 1 through 9, the code separated by articles (what the code should look like at the end of each article) and a Steam key to the game.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2018 03:08:14 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>adnzzzzZ</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars1.githubusercontent.com/u/409773?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>BYTEPATH #0 - Introduction · Issue #30 · SSYGEN/blog</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/SSYGEN/blog/issues/30</og:url>
<og:description>Introduction This tutorial series will cover the creation of a complete game with Lua and LÖVE. It's aimed at programmers who have some experience but are just starting out with game development, o...</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/SSYGEN/blog/issues/30</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Books I used to develop a game engine</title>
<link>https://www.haroldserrano.com/blog/books-i-used-to-develop-a-game-engine</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.haroldserrano.com/blog/books-i-used-to-develop-a-game-engine</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-layout sqs-grid-12 columns-12&quot; data-layout-label=&quot;Post Body&quot; data-type=&quot;item&quot; data-updated-on=&quot;1516080781076&quot; id=&quot;item-5a5d8e7ec8302520d476d3fa&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row sqs-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col sqs-col-12 span-12&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block markdown-block sqs-block-markdown&quot; data-block-type=&quot;44&quot; id=&quot;block-d96174d649704d0d159c&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have decided to develop your game engine, you may be wondering where to start, what books to start reading, etc. If you are in this situation, I recommend getting a copy of the following books found &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.haroldserrano.com/blog/best-books-to-develop-a-game-engine?rq=books&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Out of all the books I've read, they are the best of the best, so I strongly recommend them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, if you want a comprehensive list, the list below should help you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;books-to-develop-the-math-engine&quot;&gt;Books to develop the Math Engine&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Mathematics-Programming-Computer-Graphics-Third/dp/1435458869/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1516083405&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=3D+mathematics&quot;&gt;Mathematics for 3D Game Programming and Computer Graphics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0691102988/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o02_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;Quaternions and Rotation Sequences: A Primer with Applications to Orbits, Aerospace and Virtual Reality&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0857297597/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o02_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;Quaternions for Computer Graphics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1556229119/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o08_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;3D Math Primer For Graphics and Game Development&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1568812345/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o04_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;Practical Linear Algebra: A Geometry Toolbox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0120884003/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o05_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;Visualizing Quaternions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0387241965/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o05_s01?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;Curves and Surfaces for Computer Graphics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0123742978/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o07_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;Essential Mathematics for Games and Interactive Applications: A Programmer's Guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;books-to-develop-the-rendering-engine&quot;&gt;Books to develop the Rendering Engine&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1849514763/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o05_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;OpenGL 4.0 Shading Language Cookbook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1439893764/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o01_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;OpenGL Insights&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1568814240/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o01_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;Real-Time Rendering, Third Edition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0321637631/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o08_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;OpenGL Shading Language&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0262017350/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o06_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;Foundations of 3D Computer Graphics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0122287304/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o08_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;Texturing and Modeling, Second Edition: A Procedural Approach&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0672337479/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o05_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;OpenGL Superbible: Comprehensive Tutorial and Reference&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1568814348/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o02_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;Graphics Shaders: Theory and Practice, Second Edition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1584502991/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o03_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;Graphics Programming Methods&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Real-Time-Shadows-Elmar-Eisemann/dp/1568814380/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1516083351&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=real+time+shadows&quot;&gt;Real-Time Shadows&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;books-to-develop-the-physics-engine&quot;&gt;Books to develop the Physics Engine&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1449392512/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o04_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;Physics for Game Developers: Science, math, and code for realistic effects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0486652416/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o07_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;Numerical Methods for Scientists and Engineers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0521171903/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o08_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;A Student's Guide to Vectors and Tensors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1558607323/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o09_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;Real-Time Collision Detection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0123819768/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o00_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;Game Physics Engine Development: How to Build a Robust Commercial-Grade Physics Engine for your Game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/3540779736/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o01_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;Computational Geometry: Algorithms and Applications&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1568814747/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o09_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;Game Physics Pearls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1852338342/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o00_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;Geometry for Computer Graphics: Formulae, Examples and Proofs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1558605940/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o03_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;Geometric Tools for Computer Graphics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0521649765/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o09_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;Computational Geometry in C&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/155860801X/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o02_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;Collision Detection in Interactive 3D Environments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0123749034/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o03_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;Game Physics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;learning-3d-modeling-tools-blender-&quot;&gt;Learning 3D Modeling tools (Blender)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are wondering why you need to learn Blender, read the following &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.haroldserrano.com/blog/game-character-modeling-for-game-engine-developers&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1593274777/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o09_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;Blender Master Class: A Hands-On Guide to Modeling, Sculpting, Materials, and Rendering&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0240814304/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o00_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;Blender Foundations: The Essential Guide to Learning Blender 2.6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0133886174/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o02_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;Learning Blender: A Hands-On Guide to Creating 3D Animated Characters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1849511268/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o06_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;Python 3 Object Oriented Programming&lt;/a&gt;- Blender provides an API which allows you to extract 3D modeling information. To use the API, you need to know a bit of Python.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0321700899/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o09_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;Digital Modeling&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;game-engine-architecture&quot;&gt;Game Engine Architecture&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0596008678/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o07_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;Head First Object-Oriented Analysis and Design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1584500492/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o05_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;Game Programming Gems&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1584505710/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o06_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;Best of Game Programming Gems&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/012229064X/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o00_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;3D Game Engine Architecture&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0122290631/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o01_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;3D Game Engine Design: A Practical Approach&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0321321928/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o01_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;C++ Common Knowledge: Essential Intermediate Programming&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0471049980/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o01_s01?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;C++ Pointers and Dynamic Memory Management&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0321334876/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o02_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;Effective C++: 55 Specific Ways to Improve Your Programs and Designs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0201734842/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o03_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;C++ Templates: The Complete Guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0201633612/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o04_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;Design Patterns: Elements of Reusable Object-Oriented Software&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0321623215/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o01_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;The C++ Standard Library: A Tutorial and Reference&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0139798099/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o03_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;Thinking in C++, Vol. 1: Introduction to Standard C++, 2nd Edition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0130353132/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o02_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;Thinking in C++, Volume 2: Practical Programming&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0321940156/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o08_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;Game Programming Algorithms and Techniques&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0123850037/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o01_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;API Design for C++&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0990582906/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o06_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;Game Programming Patterns&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hope it helps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 22:48:28 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ingve</dc:creator>
<og:title>Books I had to read to develop a game engine</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.haroldserrano.com/blog/books-i-used-to-develop-a-game-engine</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>If you have decided to develop your game engine, you may be wondering where to start, what books to start reading, etc. If you are in this situation, I recommend getting a copy of the following books found here. Out of all the books I've read, they are the best of the best, so I strongly recommend t</og:description>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.haroldserrano.com/blog/books-i-used-to-develop-a-game-engine</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Reach for Markdown, not LaTeX</title>
<link>https://blog.jez.io/reach-for-markdown/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.jez.io/reach-for-markdown/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve written &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.jez.io/2014/10/06/offline-latex-development/&quot;&gt;in the past&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.jez.io/2015/01/10/offline-latex-development-part-2/&quot;&gt;twice&lt;/a&gt;) about how to streamline the writing process when using LaTeX. Since then, I’ve found that I enjoy writing even more when I don’t have to reach for LaTeX at all. By reaching first for Markdown, then for LaTeX when necessary, writing is easier and more enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Writing at the Command Line&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year, I &lt;a href=&quot;https://jez.io/talks/writing-at-the-command-line/&quot;&gt;gave a talk&lt;/a&gt; about the merits of writing primarily at the command line. My main claims were that when writing we want:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;an open document format (so that our writings are future proof)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to be using open source software (for considerations of privacy and cost)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to optimize for the “common case”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to be able to write for print and digital (PDFs, web pages, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Markdown solves these constraints nicely:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;It’s a plain text format—plain text has been around for decades and will be for decades more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Given a plain text format, we can bring our own text editor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plenty of open source programs manipulate Markdown.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When we need advanced features, we can mix LaTeX into our Markdown documents.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;For those unfamiliar with Markdown, it’s super quick to pick up. If you only look at one guide, see this one:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to start comparing features available in certain implementations of Markdown:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more on why you should want to be writing at the command line, you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://jez.io/talks/writing-at-the-command-line/&quot;&gt;check out the talk slides&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Pandoc Starter&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The central tool I spoke about in &lt;em&gt;Writing at the Command Line&lt;/em&gt; is &lt;a href=&quot;https://pandoc.org/&quot;&gt;Pandoc&lt;/a&gt;. Pandoc is an amazingly simple command line program that takes in Markdown files and spits out really anything you can think of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make using Pandoc even easier than it already is, I put together a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jez/pandoc-starter&quot;&gt;collection of starter templates&lt;/a&gt;. They’re all available &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jez/pandoc-starter&quot;&gt;on Github&lt;/a&gt; if you’d prefer to dive right in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are currently six different templates, specialized for the kind of document you’d like to create. Each has a &lt;code&gt;README&lt;/code&gt; for installation and usage instructions, as well as a &lt;code&gt;Makefile&lt;/code&gt; for invoking &lt;code&gt;pandoc&lt;/code&gt; correctly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the templates generate PDFs from Markdown by way of LaTeX. In addition to Pandoc, you’ll also need LaTeX installed locally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jez/pandoc-starter/tree/master/article&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;article&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This template uses the standard LaTeX &lt;code&gt;article&lt;/code&gt; document class. It’s a no frills, no nonsense choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jez/pandoc-starter/blob/master/article/src/sample.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.jez.io/images/pandoc-starter-article.png&quot; alt=&quot;article template&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jez/pandoc-starter/tree/master/tufte-handout&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;tufte-handout&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an alternative to the &lt;code&gt;article&lt;/code&gt; document class, there’s also the &lt;code&gt;tufte-handout&lt;/code&gt; document class. It originates from the style Edward Tufte popularized in his books and articles on visualization and design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from a different font (it uses Palatino instead of the default Computer Modern), this template features the ability add side notes to your documents. I often find myself reaching for this template when I want to disguise the fact that I’m secretly using LaTeX.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jez/pandoc-starter/blob/master/tufte-handout/src/sample.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.jez.io/images/pandoc-starter-tufte-handout.png&quot; alt=&quot;tufte-handout template&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jez/pandoc-starter/tree/master/tufte-handout&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;homework&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A second alternative to the &lt;code&gt;article&lt;/code&gt; document class is the &lt;code&gt;homework&lt;/code&gt; document class. It works nicely for homework assignments and problem sets. The class itself has a number of handy features, like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;the option to put your name on every page, or only on the first page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an option to use wide or narrow margins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;most of the AMS Math packages you’d include in the process of typesetting a math assignment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a convenient environment for typesetting induction proofs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;For more features and usage information, check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.jez.io/2015/01/10/the-latex-homework-document-class/&quot;&gt;this blog post&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jez/latex-homework-class&quot;&gt;the source&lt;/a&gt; on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jez/pandoc-starter/blob/master/homework/src/sample.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.jez.io/images/pandoc-starter-homework.png&quot; alt=&quot;homework template&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jez/pandoc-starter/tree/master/beamer&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;beamer&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LaTeX provides the &lt;code&gt;beamer&lt;/code&gt; document class for creating slides; this template makes it even easier to use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Make a new slide with a “&lt;code&gt;##&lt;/code&gt;” header&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a section divider with a “&lt;code&gt;#&lt;/code&gt;” header&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mix lists, links, code, and other Markdown features you’re familiar with to create the content for a slide.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;So basically, just write the outline for your talk, and Pandoc takes care of making the slides—it doesn’t get much simpler.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jez/pandoc-starter/blob/master/beamer/src/sample.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.jez.io/images/pandoc-starter-beamer.png&quot; alt=&quot;beamer template&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jez/pandoc-starter/tree/master/beamer-solarized&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;beamer-solarized&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The default beamer styles are pretty boring. To add a bit of flair and personality to my slide decks, I made a Solarized theme for beamer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the screenshot below, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jez.io/talks/writing-at-the-command-line/&quot;&gt;Writing at the Command Line&lt;/a&gt; slides I linked to earlier also use this theme, if you want to see a less contrived example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jez/pandoc-starter/blob/master/beamer-solarized/src/sample.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.jez.io/images/pandoc-starter-beamer-solarized.png&quot; alt=&quot;beamer solarized template&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jez/pandoc-starter/tree/master/book-writeup&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;book-writeup&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, sometimes a simple article or slide deck doesn’t cut it. Usually this means I’d like to group the writing into chapters. This template makes writing a chapter as easy as using a “&lt;code&gt;#&lt;/code&gt;” Markdown header.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jez/pandoc-starter/blob/master/book-writeup/src/sample.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.jez.io/images/pandoc-starter-book-writeup.png&quot; alt=&quot;book writeup template&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Writing Plugins for Vim&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you happen to use Vim, I’d highly recommend installing &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/junegunn/goyo.vim&quot;&gt;goyo.vim&lt;/a&gt; for writing. It removes all the visual frills Vim includes to make writing code easier so you can focus on your writing without distractions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also really enjoy &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/vim-pandoc/vim-pandoc&quot;&gt;vim-pandoc&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/vim-pandoc/vim-pandoc-syntax&quot;&gt;vim-pandoc-syntax&lt;/a&gt;. They’re a pair of complementary plugins for highlighting and working with Pandoc Markdown-flavored documents. They work so well that I use them for Markdown documents even when not using Pandoc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Reach for Markdown&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing should be a pleasant experience. With the right tools, it can be. LaTeX is powerful but cumbersome to use. With Markdown, we can focus on our writing, and worry about the presentation later. Pandoc can take care of the presentation for us, so the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jez/pandoc-starter&quot;&gt;only thing left to do is start&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;footer class=&quot;entry-meta&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;entry-tags&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.jez.io/categories/#latex&quot; title=&quot;Pages tagged latex&quot; class=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;latex&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.jez.io/categories/#markdown&quot; title=&quot;Pages tagged markdown&quot; class=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;markdown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.jez.io/categories/#vim&quot; title=&quot;Pages tagged vim&quot; class=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;vim&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;entry-date date published updated&quot;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&quot;2017-02-26T21:26:53-05:00&quot;&gt;February 26, 2017&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/footer&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 22:20:49 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>sridca</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://blog.jez.io/reach-for-markdown</og:url>
<og:title>Reach for Markdown, not LaTeX</og:title>
<og:description>Writing should be a pleasant experience. With the right tools, it can be. LaTeX is powerful but cumbersome to use. With Markdown, we can focus on our …</og:description>
<og:image></og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.jez.io/reach-for-markdown/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>MacOS may lose data on APFS-formatted disk images</title>
<link>https://bombich.com/blog/2018/02/15/macos-may-lose-data-on-apfs-formatted-disk-images</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://bombich.com/blog/2018/02/15/macos-may-lose-data-on-apfs-formatted-disk-images</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;This week &lt;a href=&quot;rdar://37497030&quot;&gt;we reported to Apple&lt;/a&gt; a serious flaw in macOS that can lead to data loss when using an APFS-formatted disk image. Until Apple issues a macOS update that resolves this problem, we're dropping support for APFS-formatted disk images.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Note: What I describe below applies to APFS &lt;strong&gt;sparse disk images&lt;/strong&gt; only — ordinary APFS volumes (e.g. your SSD startup disk) are not affected by this problem. While the underlying problem here is very serious, &lt;strong&gt;this is not likely to be a widespread problem&lt;/strong&gt;, and will be most applicable to a small subset of backups. Disk images are not used for most backup task activity, they are generally only applicable when making backups to network volumes. If you make backups to network volumes, read on to learn more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Disk images are handy devices. They're files, but they act like a hard drive – you mount a disk image by double-clicking the file, then it behaves like it's another hard drive attached to your Mac. macOS has been using disk images for decades, and we find them particularly useful when making backups to network volumes. By formatting the disk image volume using an Apple-native format, we can do things like back up system files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally, when Apple introduced APFS in macOS High Sierra, we sought to offer support for using APFS on destination disk images when doing so would match the format of the source volume. As far as creating and mounting disk images is concerned, APFS and HFS+ are easily interchangeable, so adding support for APFS was very straightforward. Unnoticed by us, Apple, and thousands of developers, however, is a very subtle behavioral difference that is specific to APFS on a sparse disk image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this week I noticed that an APFS-formatted sparsebundle disk image volume showed ample free space, despite that the underlying disk was completely full. Curious, I copied a video file to the disk image volume to see what would happen. The whole file copied without error! I opened the file, verified that the video played back start to finish, checksummed the file – as far as I could tell, the file was intact and whole on the disk image. When I unmounted and remounted the disk image, however, the video was corrupted. If you've ever lost data, you know the kick-in-the-gut feeling that would have ensued. Thankfully, I was just running some tests and the file that disappeared was just test data. Taking a closer look, I discovered two bugs in macOS's &quot;diskimages-helper&quot; service that lead to this result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;An APFS volume's free space doesn't reflect a smaller amount of free space on the underlying disk&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past with HFS+ formatted disk images, the disk image volume would automatically adjust its free space to accommodate any differences between the disk image volume's capacity and the actual amount of free space on the underlying disk. So for example, if you had created a disk image with a capacity of 500GB on a 500GB network volume, but then you added 400GB of stuff to the network volume outside of the disk image, now there's only 100GB of space for stuff on the disk image. Accordingly, when you mount the disk image, it would report its own disk usage as 400GB and its free space as 100GB (even if there is literally nothing on the disk image volume). The math always felt weird, but the result was right – the disk image can't practically accommodate more than 100GB of data, so the free space should reflect that. This behavior is documented in Apple's &lt;code&gt;hdiutil&lt;/code&gt; man page:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;To prevent errors when a filesystem inside of a sparse image has more free space than the volume holding the sparse image, HFS+ volumes inside sparse images will report an amount of free space slightly less than the amount of free space on the volume on which image resides.&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This behavior has been a known quantity for many, many years. HFS+ still performs this adjustment on High Sierra, so it does not appear to be a regression, rather just an oversight that is specific to APFS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If this were the only bug, however, this issue would be just an annoyance. The larger issue occurs when any application tries to write more data to the disk image volume than the underlying disk can accommodate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The diskimages-helper application doesn't report errors when write requests fail to grow the disk image&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The diskimages-helper application works quietly in the background, responding to filesystem requests made to the disk image volume. It's essentially a broker, or middle-man. There's a disk image file on disk, but applications don't interact directly with the file, they need to interact with a filesystem. So the diskimages-helper application presents a filesystem interface on top of that disk image file. When you make a write request to a mounted disk image volume, the request goes to the diskimages-helper application, which translates that request into changes to the disk image file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you initially create a &quot;sparse&quot; disk image file, that file is very small, e.g. &amp;lt;100MB. It's just large enough to hold some pre-allocated space for the filesystem structures. As you copy files to the disk image volume, the file grows. Herein lies the bug. Following the earlier example, suppose you attempt to copy 200GB of data to that 500GB disk image file. This shouldn't be possible, because there was only 100GB of free space left on the underlying disk. The APFS disk image reports that there's 500GB of free space available, though, so what the heck, let's do this! The first 100GB of data does successfully get written into the disk image file – the disk image file has grown now to 100GB. But now the underlying disk is completely full, and the disk image file can no longer grow – the diskimages-helper application is getting &quot;No space left on device&quot; errors when trying to write data to its band files. At this point, you'd think that the diskimages-helper application would do one of the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Report a &quot;No space left on device&quot; error to the process making the write request&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Refuse additional write requests – sorry, no more space&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Unmount the disk image – we have to stop this insanity&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Quit – please, just stop pretending to do something that you're not actually doing!&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Panic the kernel – &lt;strong&gt;we're writing data into a VOID, STOP!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alas, none of those things happen (and no, it should never panic the kernel, but writing to the void is equally unreasonable). diskimages-helper continues to accept writes, and the application asking to write the data continues to send data, eventually completing with apparent success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The final illusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After files failed to actually make it to a physical disk somewhere, you'd think (hope?) that perhaps, at least, the file would appear smaller on the disk image. This is probably the most alarming part of this bug – because the filesystem structures are stored on a section of pre-allocated space on the underlying disk, the diskimages-helper application has no trouble updating filesystem metadata. So file size, modification date, permissions, etc – all of those attributes are fine. In yet another bizarre twist, we found that many times a truncated file would even validate a checksum test. Presumably the diskimages-helper retains some of the file data in RAM, because again, the data never made it to the underlying disk. This part is perhaps the hardest to explain in text, so I created a video to demonstrate the problem:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe allow=&quot;encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;embed-responsive-item&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/k60NvrJnNOY?rel=0&quot; width=&quot;560&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Proactively avoiding data loss&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CCC creates and uses disk images when you select &quot;New disk image...&quot; from the Destination selector. Starting in CCC 5.0.4 and up to CCC 5.0.8, CCC will automatically create an APFS-formatted disk image if the source is an APFS-formatted volume. &lt;strong&gt;Today we're posting an update to CCC (5.0.9) that will revoke support for creating APFS-formatted disk images.&lt;/strong&gt; Additionally, if you have a task that is currently backing up to an APFS-formatted disk image, CCC will issue a warning when that task completes indicating that APFS-formatted disk images are no longer supported by CCC. This will not prevent you from using an APFS-formatted disk image, and indeed, if your underlying destination is not overly full, there's no need for panic here. Nevertheless, disk images eventually fill up, so our recommendation to our users will be to migrate away from an APFS-formatted disk image at your earliest convenience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What should the average user do?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The average CCC user will be unaffected by this APFS shortcoming. CCC 4 users are completely unaffected; users not yet on High Sierra are unaffected. Our usage statistics indicate that less than 7% of CCC backup tasks leverage a sparse disk image, and of those, less than 12% are APFS-formatted. &lt;strong&gt;We recommend that CCC 5 users update to 5.0.9, and then make a brief review of your backup tasks&lt;/strong&gt; – open CCC and select each task, and read the task plan. If the task is configured to back up to a disk image, it will plainly state that, e.g.:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;CCC will copy selected items from &lt;strong&gt;Macintosh HD&lt;/strong&gt; into a disk image at &lt;strong&gt;Macintosh HD.sparsebundle&lt;/strong&gt; on &lt;strong&gt;NAS Backup&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do have a task that is configured to back up to a &lt;strong&gt;sparsebundle&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;sparseimage&lt;/strong&gt; disk image, hover your mouse over the source icon. A tooltip will indicate how the source volume is formatted. If your source's filesystem is APFS, then your destination disk image &lt;strong&gt;might&lt;/strong&gt; be formatted as APFS as well. When you run that backup task, CCC will update the disk image as usual, and then when the task completes, CCC will issue an error if that disk image is formatted as APFS. If you see that warning, &lt;a href=&quot;https://bombich.com/kb/ccc5/backing-up-disk-image#37497030&quot;&gt;we recommend deleting the destination disk image &lt;em&gt;at your earliest convenience&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Again, if the underlying destination is not very full and has never been near capacity (e.g. if it has always had more than 50GB of free space), then there's no reason to be alarmed and you can remove the destination disk image on a weekend or at night when you have ample time to allow CCC to recreate an HFS+ formatted disk image. If your underlying disk has ever filled up to capacity, though, you should delete the disk image and allow CCC to replace it with &lt;span&gt;an HFS+ formatted disk image&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: Disk images that end with a .dmg suffix are not affected by this problem. The storage for dmg disk image files is pre-allocated when those files are created, so their storage space is guaranteed. CCC specifically does still provide support for APFS formatted dmg files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Is this a problem specific to CCC?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No, this problem will affect any application that writes to APFS-formatted sparse disk images that reside on a full or nearly-full disk. I tested this scenario with copies via the Terminal application, Finder copies, and even exported a file from QuickTime. In every case, the application that was copying or creating the file was completely unaware that any problem had occurred when writing the data to disk. In the QuickTime case, I was able to immediately open the exported file and play it start to finish. After ejecting and remounting the disk image, QuickTime qouldn't open the file. The core of this problem resides in macOS's diskimages-helper application and can only be resolved by an update to macOS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until Apple resolves this disk images bug, we strongly recommend that people avoid using APFS-formatted sparse disk images for any purpose with any application.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 21:18:06 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mpweiher</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://bombich.com/blog/2018/02/15/macos-may-lose-data-on-apfs-formatted-disk-images</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>In Switzerland, it&amp;#039;s now illegal to boil a live lobster</title>
<link>https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/world/2018/02/16/new-swiss-law-pain-free-deaths-lobsters-flushing-goldfish-down-toilet-breaking-law-according-new-swi/341412002/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/world/2018/02/16/new-swiss-law-pain-free-deaths-lobsters-flushing-goldfish-down-toilet-breaking-law-according-new-swi/341412002/</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;module-position-Qp6SccnewFM&quot; class=&quot;story-asset video-asset&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui-video-wrapper&quot; itemprop=&quot;video&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/VideoObject&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;js-ui-video-init ui-pluto-video js-video-aps js-uw-iframe-video uw-iframe-video story-video inline-story-video priority smallarticleattophtml5&quot; data-video-id=&quot;110457390&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;js-ptb pluto-title-bar&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;js-ptb-close pluto-title-bar-vcenter pluto-title-bar-close&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;CLOSE&lt;img class=&quot;pluto-title-bar-close-icon&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gannett-cdn.com/uxstatic/usatoday/usat-web-static-3562.0/images/sprites/icon_close.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui-video-controls story-video inline-story-video priority&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;video-desc&quot; itemprop=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Switzerland's unique animal welfare laws are miles ahead of the rest of the world. &lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;USA Today&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;module-position-Qp6Sccp_gps&quot; class=&quot;story-asset story-metadata-asset&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article-metadata-wrap&quot;&gt;
&lt;section id=&quot;module-position-Qp6SccYD56Y&quot; class=&quot;storymetadata-bucket expandable-photo-module story-expandable-photo-module&quot;&gt;&lt;aside itemprop=&quot;associatedMedia&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot; class=&quot;single-photo expandable-collapsed&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;expand-img-horiz&quot; itemprop=&quot;url&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gannett-cdn.com/-mm-/56bc642fb5d7cc590795f8a445e7c797e4491da4/c=199-0-3306-2336&amp;amp;r=x404&amp;amp;c=534x401/local/-/media/2018/02/15/USATODAY/USATODAY/636543079409732950-AP-Warming-Ocean-Lobster.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;AP WARMING OCEAN LOBSTER A FILE USA ME&quot; data-mycapture-src=&quot;https://www.gannett-cdn.com/media/2018/02/15/USATODAY/USATODAY/636543079409732950-AP-Warming-Ocean-Lobster.jpg&quot; data-mycapture-sm-src=&quot;https://www.gannett-cdn.com/-mm-/4044b1e7645488621f157de466cf1a990870caa2/r=500x333/local/-/media/2018/02/15/USATODAY/USATODAY/636543079409732950-AP-Warming-Ocean-Lobster.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;image-credit-wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;js-caption-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;cutline js-caption&quot;&gt;In this July 2007, file photo, a scientist holds a lobster underwater on Friendship Long Island, Maine.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;(Photo: Robert F. Bukaty, AP)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;speakable-p-1 p-text&quot;&gt;GENEVA — When it comes to cooking fresh lobster, the Swiss are now saying: We feel your pain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;speakable-p-2 p-text&quot;&gt;A law goes into effect March 1 that bans the common cooking method of tossing a live lobster into a big pot of boiling water, quickly killing the tasty crustacean. That practice is being outlawed because the Swiss say it's cruel and lobsters can sense pain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;The first national legislation of its kind in the world calls for a more humane death for lobsters, by “rendering them unconscious” before plunging them into scalding water. Two methods are recommended: Electrocution or sedating the lobster by dipping it into salt water and then thrusting a knife into its brain. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;The same law also gives domestic pets further protections, such as dogs can no longer be punished for barking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;The measure is part of the broad principle of “animal dignity” enshrined in Switzerland’s constitution, the only country to have such a provision. The constitution already protects how various species must be treated and specifies that animals need socialization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;That means cats must have a daily visual contact with other felines, and hamsters or guinea pigs must be kept in pairs. And anyone who flushes a pet goldfish down the toilet is breaking the law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;The new lobster legislation that boils down to a pain-free death was driven by research, including a study by Queen’s University in Belfast that found crustaceans are sentient creatures. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;“These studies show that lobsters, like other animals, experience pain and distress,” said Stefan Kunfermann, a spokesman for the Federal Office of Food Safety and Veterinary Affairs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;Although lobster consumption in this land-locked country is &quot;negligible,&quot; the parliament had tried to ban the import of all live lobsters to prevent them from an agonizing death at the hands of Swiss restaurant cooks, Kunfermann said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;That drastic measure against imports would violate international trade agreements, so authorities instead issued new rules on how to make the lobsters’ demise as painless as possible. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;The law also stipulates that lobsters must be transported to their final Swiss destination in their natural environment — seawater — rather than on ice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;The government vows that offenders will not slip through the net. State officials will be responsible for enforcement, and Kunfermann said offenders could land in a lot of hot water, with sentences of up to three years in prison.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;Animal rights activists applaud the new lobster law and call for more action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;“While this may end one of the cruelest methods of killing these fascinating beings in Switzerland, there are no laws protecting them from being boiled alive in other countries — including the U.S.,” People for the Ethical Treatment of Animals (PETA) said on its website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;“Globally, Switzerland is in the forefront of animal welfare legislation,” said Antoine Goetschel, an attorney and founder of the Zurich-based Global Animal Law Association.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;In 2010, Goetschel represented in court a 22-pound pike that he said suffered when a local fisherman roughly yanked it for 10 minutes before pulling it from icy Lake Zurich.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;The fisherman was eventually acquitted, but Goetschel spearheaded a national referendum that same year to grant animals the constitutional right to be represented by lawyers in court. The proposal was rejected by 70% of the voters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;Not everyone is happy with the regulation. Chef René Widmer, founder of Prorest Culinary School in the town of Rafz, complained to &lt;em&gt;Blick&lt;/em&gt; newspaper that the new law is useless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;&quot;I always turned the lobster upside down before throwing it into the boiling water — then it dies within seconds,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;article-print-url&quot;&gt;Read or Share this story: https://usat.ly/2oddavw&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 20:05:59 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>fmihaila</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://www.gannett-cdn.com/-mm-/6e98fb0a048d49277f6905691322ad7459ccaa99/c=0-178-3504-2158&amp;r=x1683&amp;c=3200x1680/local/-/media/2018/02/15/USATODAY/USATODAY/636543079409732950-AP-Warming-Ocean-Lobster.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>In a world first, Switzerland deems it illegal to boil a lobster</og:title>
<og:description>A law goes into effect March 1 that requires a humane death for lobsters before they are cooked because they sense pain.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/world/2018/02/16/new-swiss-law-pain-free-deaths-lobsters-flushing-goldfish-down-toilet-breaking-law-according-new-swi/341412002/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/world/2018/02/16/new-swiss-law-pain-free-deaths-lobsters-flushing-goldfish-down-toilet-breaking-law-according-new-swi/341412002/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The case for ending Amazon’s dominance</title>
<link>http://timharford.com/2018/02/the-case-for-ending-amazons-dominance/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://timharford.com/2018/02/the-case-for-ending-amazons-dominance/</guid>
<description>&lt;a href=&quot;http://timharford.com/articles/undercovereconomist/&quot; title=&quot;Undercover Economist&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;article-perm&quot; src=&quot;http://timharford.com/wp-content/themes/timharford-v4/img//icon-ue.png&quot; width=&quot;36&quot; height=&quot;36&quot; alt=&quot;Undercover Economist&quot; title=&quot;Undercover Economist&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;h2&gt;The case for ending Amazon’s dominance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should not be difficult to love Amazon. To consumers, it offers choice and convenience. Countless internet ventures have relied on its cheap, flexible cloud computing services to start and scale up. Amazon makes titans such as Walmart work hard for their revenue, offers a shopping search engine that is Google’s only serious rival, raises the bar for television networks and sells tablet computers at a price to make Apple loyalists stop and think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon is also giving the US economy what it needs. Two economists, Germán Gutiérrez and Thomas Philippon, have argued that corporate America is underinvesting. One reason is that companies are impatiently funnelling cash to investors and executives rather than take a long-term view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If that is a worrisome state of affairs — and it should be — then Amazon is the shining counterexample. The online retailer’s strategy is driven not by short-term profit but by investment, innovation and growth. If only there were a few more companies like Amazon, capitalism would be in a happier spot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there’s the rub: there aren’t more companies like it. It’s unique, and an increasingly terrifying force in online commerce. Should regulators act? If so, how? It’s worth first disposing of a bad argument: that Amazon must be challenged because it makes life miserable for its competitors, some of which are plucky mom-and-pop operations. However emotionally appealing this might seem, it should not be the business of regulators to prop up such businesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regulators have a tendency to slip into the role of protecting incumbents with surprising ease. Marc Levinson’s history of container shipping, &lt;em&gt;The Box &lt;/em&gt;(&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/2Drf8Dh&quot;&gt;UK&lt;/a&gt;) (&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/2DmO97u&quot;&gt;US&lt;/a&gt;), describes Malcom McLean — the entrepreneur behind containerisation, a risk-taking visionary reminiscent of Amazon’s founder Jeff Bezos. When McLean tried to expand his operations, one of his largest obstacles was the Interstate Commerce Commission in the US, which regulated US railways from 1887 and interstate trucking from 1935.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ICC, writes Mr Levinson, had to approve each new route, every new commodity and any new price schedule. When McLean wanted to start a trucking route at a low price, he had to hire lawyers and argue his case at the ICC, while his competitors protested bitterly — “unfair and destructive”, said the railways. He did not always get his way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Antitrust authorities should not be in the business of making life easy for incumbents. What, then, should they do? There are two schools of thought. One is to focus on consumers’ interest in quality, variety and price. This has been the standard approach in US antitrust policy for several decades. Since Amazon makes slim profits and charges low prices, it raises few antitrust questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The alternative view — which harks back to an earlier era of antitrust during which Standard Oil and later AT&amp;amp;T were broken up — argues that competition is inherently good even if it is hard to quantify a benefit to consumers and that society should be wary of large or dominant companies even if their behaviour seems benign. The collapse of companies from Lehman Brothers to construction services business Carillion reminds us that size can be a problem when a company is weak as well as when it is strong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The narrowing in antitrust thinking is described by Lina Khan in a much-read article, “Amazon’s Antitrust Paradox”. Ms Khan berates modern antitrust thinking for its “hostility to false positives”, arguing that it has become incapable of saying anything insightful about modern tech companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike Ms Khan, I share modern antitrust’s hostility to false positives; there is a real cost to cumbersome and unnecessary meddling in a dynamic and rapidly-evolving marketplace. Donald Trump’s history of publicly attacking Mr Bezos is worth pondering too: do we really want the US government to have more discretion as to who is targeted, and why? We should not wish to return to a world in which a plucky new competitor must beg regulators — over the objections of incumbents — for permission to cut prices. We should be grateful that Mr Bezos did not face in the 1990s the regulatory obstacles that Malcom McLean dodged in the 1950s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet for all this, I am deeply uneasy about Amazon’s apparently unassailable position in online retail. Yes, customers are being well served at the moment. Yet the company has acquired formidable entrenched advantages, from the information about customers and the suppliers who sell through it, to the bargaining power it has over delivery companies, to the vast network of warehouses. Those advantages were earned, but they can also be abused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Antitrust authorities face a difficult balancing act. Regulate Amazon and you may snuff out the innovation that we all say we want more of. Punish it for success and you send a strange message to entrepreneurs and investors. Ignore it and you risk leaving vital services in the hands of an invincible monopolist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are no easy options, but it is time to look for a way to split Amazon into two independent companies, each with the strength to grow and invest. If Amazon is such a wonderful company, wouldn’t two Amazons be even better?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written for and first published in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ft.com/content/aba8d444-fb94-11e7-a492-2c9be7f3120a&quot;&gt;Financial Times&lt;/a&gt; on 19 January 2018.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;My recent book is “Fifty Inventions That Shaped The Modern Economy”. Grab yourself a copy in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/2q2Tdq8&quot;&gt;US&lt;/a&gt; or in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/2rye7jg&quot;&gt;UK&lt;/a&gt; (slightly different title) or through your local bookshop.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;robots-nocontent sd-block sd-social sd-social-icon sd-sharing&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Share this:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 15:02:09 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>imartin2k</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>The case for ending Amazon’s dominance</og:title>
<og:url>http://timharford.com/2018/02/the-case-for-ending-amazons-dominance/</og:url>
<og:description>It should not be difficult to love Amazon. To consumers, it offers choice and convenience. Countless internet ventures have relied on its cheap, flexible cloud computing services to start and scale…</og:description>
<og:image>https://s0.wp.com/i/blank.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://timharford.com/2018/02/the-case-for-ending-amazons-dominance/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>New studies zero in on roots of depression and how ketamine affects it</title>
<link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2018/02/new-studies-zero-in-on-roots-of-depression-and-why-ketamine-reverses-it/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://arstechnica.com/science/2018/02/new-studies-zero-in-on-roots-of-depression-and-why-ketamine-reverses-it/</guid>
<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Screen-Shot-2018-02-17-at-8.37.53-AM.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;aside id=&quot;social-left&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;56 posters participating&quot; class=&quot;comment-count icon-comment-bubble-down&quot; href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/science/2018/02/new-studies-zero-in-on-roots-of-depression-and-why-ketamine-reverses-it/?comments=1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;comment-count-before&quot;&gt;reader comments&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;comment-count-number&quot;&gt;91&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;share-links&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Share this story&lt;/span&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;While we have a number of treatments available for clinical depression, many of them have a significant side effects, and a lot of people struggle to find a drug that they respond to. The situation is made worse by our limited understanding of the biology underlying depression. We don't know how to create targeted drugs, so most of the available treatments are blunt instruments that can take weeks to months before having an effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In that light, it came as a bit of a shock when we discovered a drug we'd been using recreationally and for anesthesia could lift the symptoms of depression in less than 24 hours. Unfortunately, the drug in question, ketamine, also has a collection of unpleasant side-effects, and we had no idea how it was working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there's been significant progress in unravelling the confusion over ketamine, with researchers &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/science/2016/05/understanding-ketamine-to-make-a-fast-acting-safe-antidepressant/&quot;&gt;identifying a ketamine derivative&lt;/a&gt; that tackles depression with far fewer side effects. And this week, a team of researchers at China's Zhejiang University announced that they've figured out where in the brain ketamine acts when it blocks depression, a finding that gives us significant insights into the biology of the disorder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Ketamine and depression&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;pullbox sidebar story-sidebar right&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new studies rely on the work of a number of other labs, which have identified a specific structure deep in the brain that's associated with depression. Called the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Habenula&quot;&gt;lateral habenula&lt;/a&gt;, it's been associated with a variety of activities, the most relevant of which seems to be the processing of unpleasant outcomes and punishment. Electrodes implanted there have been used to relieve depression in at least one instance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To test whether this might be the site of ketamine's activity, one team of researchers infused the drug directly into the lateral habenula of rats with depression-like symptoms; it blocked them. So did a separate chemical that inhibits the same proteins that ketamine acts on. Tracking the activity in the area, the researchers were able to show that there are bursts of activity in rats with symptoms of depression that are absent in healthy rats. The drugs that blocked depression suppressed these bursts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To confirm that was really causal, the researchers performed the converse experiment, engineering cells in the lateral habenula to emit bursts of activity in response to light. This showed that the bursts themselves were enough to drive depressive symptoms in these animals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A second paper, produced by many of the same researchers, describes what's going on at the cellular level in the habenula. In this work the team induced depression in rats either chemically or by inducing what's called &quot;learned helplessness.&quot; (The latter involves training the rats to recognize that they have no control over negative consequences in their environment.) The team then obtained tissue samples from the lateral habenula and examined every single protein produced there, looking for differences between depressed and healthy animals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Ion flow&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most interesting result to come out of this was a protein that controls the flow of ions between a cell and its environment. That's not much of a surprise, given that nerve impulses are driven by the exchange of ions across a nerve cell's membrane. But the protein identified here isn't made by nerve cells. Instead, it's made by a type of cell called an astrocyte.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Astrocytes were once thought to be merely support cells that helped provide a good environment for nerve cells. But we've developed a significant body of evidence that hints that they may be involved in signaling with nerves as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the case of depression, it doesn't seem that direct signaling is involved. Instead, it's involved in the process of resetting the nerve cell after an impulse, which requires gathering back all the ions that flowed out of the cell during the impulse. By changing the amount of potassium available to the nerve cell, the protein identified by this team alters the ease with which a nerve cell can fire again. By increasing the dose of this gene, the researchers were able to induce depression-like symptoms in mice; knocking the gene down reduced their ability to induce depressive behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None of this is to say that this team has found a &quot;cause of depression&quot; or something similar. Depression is a complicated disorder, and it's unlikely that there's going to be a single underlying cause. What they have found, however, is something that's likely to be central to the generation of the symptoms we associate with the disorder. Excess activity of a brain region thought to be involved in processing negative rewards makes a lot of sense as a trigger for the symptoms of depression, while the protein identified here makes sense as a trigger for this excess activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just as critically, the work shows that drugs are able to disrupt this process. We're still at the point where these drugs have significant side effects, but we now know a bit about what their targets are doing and where they have to act. That will hopefully lead to something a bit more specific before too long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nature&lt;/em&gt;, 2017. DOI: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature25509&quot;&gt;10.1038/nature25509&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature25752&quot;&gt;10.1038/nature25752&lt;/a&gt;  (&lt;a href=&quot;http://arstechnica.com/science/news/2010/03/dois-and-their-discontents-1.ars&quot;&gt;About DOIs&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 14:57:41 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rbanffy</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://arstechnica.com/science/2018/02/new-studies-zero-in-on-roots-of-depression-and-why-ketamine-reverses-it/</og:url>
<og:title>New studies zero in on roots of depression and why ketamine reverses it</og:title>
<og:image>https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Screen-Shot-2018-02-17-at-8.37.53-AM-642x380.png</og:image>
<og:description>Understanding the biology may help us develop more targeted therapies.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://arstechnica.com/science/2018/02/new-studies-zero-in-on-roots-of-depression-and-why-ketamine-reverses-it/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>JMESPath – A query language for JSON</title>
<link>http://jmespath.org/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://jmespath.org/</guid>
<description>&lt;nav class=&quot;navbar navbar-inverse navbar-static-top&quot; role=&quot;navigation&quot;&gt;
&lt;/nav&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;jumbotron&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;container&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;img id=&quot;main-logo&quot; src=&quot;http://jmespath.org/_static/img/logo.png&quot; alt=&quot;JMESPath Logo&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;JMESPath is a query language for JSON.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;container&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot; readability=&quot;10.140916808149&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4&quot; readability=&quot;7.4319526627219&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-distinct&quot;&gt;A Complete Specification&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The JMESPath language is described in an &lt;a href=&quot;http://jmespath.org/specification.html&quot;&gt;ABNF grammar&lt;/a&gt; with a complete specification. This ensures that the language syntax is precisely defined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4&quot; readability=&quot;8.2019704433498&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-distinct&quot;&gt;A compliance test suite&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JMESPath has a full suite of data driven testcases. This ensures parity for multiple libraries, and makes it easy for developers to &lt;a href=&quot;http://jmespath.org/compliance.html&quot;&gt;implement JMESPath&lt;/a&gt; in their language of choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4&quot; readability=&quot;9.2558139534884&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-distinct&quot;&gt;Libraries in Multiple Languages&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each &lt;a href=&quot;http://jmespath.org/libraries.html&quot;&gt;JMESPath library&lt;/a&gt; passes a complete suite of compliance tests to ensure they work as intended. There are libraries in multiple languages including python, php, javascript and lua.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Clicky&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://in.getclicky.com/100732121ns.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;© Copyright 2014-2015, James Saryerwinnie.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 11:59:50 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>selrond</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://jmespath.org/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>An American served a year in prison for copyright conduct that is legal in EU</title>
<link>https://blogs.harvard.edu/infolaw/2018/02/13/an-american-served-1-year-in-prison-for-conduct-that-is-100-legal-in-europe-but-its-not-drugs-its-copyright-heres-why-it-matters/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blogs.harvard.edu/infolaw/2018/02/13/an-american-served-1-year-in-prison-for-conduct-that-is-100-legal-in-europe-but-its-not-drugs-its-copyright-heres-why-it-matters/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The Administration is receiving some unusual advice from the content industries as it undertakes to renegotiate the North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA). It’s not surprising that content providers would weigh in, given the multiple obligations Article 17 of NAFTA imposes on Canada, Mexico, and the United States concerning intellectual property protections. If it’s your ox being gored, you’re going to have some strong opinions; it would be weird if you didn’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What makes the content industries’ position unusual is that they are apparently attempting to take some issues off the table entirely as subjects for negotiation. According to this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.techdirt.com/articles/20180209/13230239199/hollywood-has-some-wild-ideas-copyright-nafta.shtml&quot;&gt;recent TechDirt article&lt;/a&gt; (emphasis mine):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the entertainment industries are arguing that &lt;em&gt;exceptions and limitations are outdated and unnecessary&lt;/em&gt; in trade agreements. They say that copyright holders should be protected from piracy and unlawful use of their works, claiming that &lt;em&gt;any exceptions and limitations are a barrier&lt;/em&gt; to the protection of American artists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is, the content industries want the final agreement to mandate strong copyright protections without mandating (or, depending on how you read the word “any” in the preceding quotation, permitting) signatory countries to recognize exceptions or limitations on those rights. Copyright rights, on this view, are a one-way ratchet: they can only be strengthened everywhere, never reduced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of reasons to quarrel with this view, assuming it has been accurately reported. It’s profoundly ahistorical; &lt;em&gt;every&lt;/em&gt; international agreement that defines copyright rights also fixes outer boundaries of protection. Article 10(1) of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wipo.int/treaties/en/ip/berne/&quot;&gt;Berne Convention&lt;/a&gt; requires every country to allow quotations from published works, and other parts of Berne allow copyright exceptions for teaching, news reporting, and other socially valuable purposes. The WTO &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wto.org/english/docs_e/legal_e/31bis_trips_01_e.htm&quot;&gt;TRIPS Agreement&lt;/a&gt;, another landmark multilateral treaty, incorporates long-recognized copyright limitations (for example, Article 9(2)’s idea/expression dichotomy) into international law. An argument that copyright limitations and exceptions have no place in trade agreements isn’t an argument against NAFTA; it’s an argument against every copyright treaty ever concluded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An argument for international copyright law to ignore copyright limitations and exceptions is also bad policy, which is why civil society and public-interest groups have been loudly insisting that NAFTA renegotiations &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.recreatecoalition.org/recreate-coalition-u-s-trade-representative-robert-lighthizer-copyright-provisions-nafta-must-include-fair-use-safe-harbor-protections/&quot;&gt;protect fair use&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.publicknowledge.org/news-blog/blogs/our-call-for-copyright-balance-in-nafta-renegotiations&quot;&gt;maintain balance&lt;/a&gt; between the rights of content creators and users. It’s why the American Library Association, the Center for Democracy and Technology, and over 80 other individuals and organizations from several nations issued the &lt;a href=&quot;http://infojustice.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Washington-Principles-on-Copyright-Balance-in-Trade-Agreements-November-15-2017.pdf&quot;&gt;Washington Principles on Copyright Balance in Trade Agreements&lt;/a&gt; last fall as NAFTA renegotiation got underway in earnest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But most of all, it’s just shortsighted &lt;em&gt;even from the perspective of people who want to maximize the scope of copyright rights&lt;/em&gt; to take limitations and exceptions off the table as a subject of trade negotiations. To understand why, let’s look at two recent cases involving an American citizen and a European company who did the same thing: they distributed a tool that allowed owners of Nintendo Wii entertainment systems to play games that had not been authorized by Nintendo. These systems, colloquially known as “mod chips,” bypassed the internal authentication system that the Wii used to verify that the games users were seeking to play on their consoles had been approved by Nintendo. Nintendo complained to the authorities in each jurisdiction that helping Wii owners play unauthorized games was against the law because it circumvented a technological protection that Nintendo had put in place to ensure that only authorized games were playable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both the United States and Europe have laws against that sort of thing. They have laws of that type because they are required, under Article 11 of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wipo.int/treaties/en/ip/wct/&quot;&gt;WIPO Copyright Treaty&lt;/a&gt;, to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;provide adequate legal protection and effective legal remedies against the circumvention of effective technological measures … that restrict acts, in respect of their works, which are not authorized by the authors concerned or permitted by law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The EU Court of Justice, however, &lt;a href=&quot;http://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/HTML/?uri=CELEX:62012CJ0355&amp;amp;from=EN&quot;&gt;refused&lt;/a&gt; to condemn the making of a device to circumvent the Wii’s technological protections, because those protections appeared to the court to be broader than necessary to protect Nintendo’s copyright rights. It required, in assessing the legality of the circumvention tool, a consideration of “how often [the] devices are in fact used in order to allow unauthorised copies … and how often that equipment is used for purposes which do not infringe copyright[.]”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In contrast, the American who circumvented the Wii’s technological protection went to prison for twelve months and one day; the &lt;a href=&quot;https://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=13897503857017391741&quot;&gt;opinion&lt;/a&gt; of the Court of Appeals did not even address the question whether the “mod chips” he sold could have been put to noninfringing uses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These two cases involved the same underlying offense and essentially identical substantive laws, written to implement a single treaty obligation, yet they reached opposite outcomes for reasons neither opinion said a word about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you believe in meaningful limitations to copyright holders’ exclusive rights (or, for that matter, in the rule of lenity which usually governs complex criminal issues of first impression), you probably prefer the European outcome to the American one: perhaps tools &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be evaluated based on whether they are mostly put to infringing or noninfringing use. Maybe the limitation on copyright holders’ exclusive rights that the European court recognized would be a good rule for the United States, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, if you believe that copyright holders should have the power to control how their works (such as Nintendo’s game console) are used, then the European approach probably infuriates you and the American one probably seems correct. Maybe you wish that European law didn’t recognize a limitation on copyright holder’s exclusive rights in this instance, and that the American view prevailed instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point is, &lt;strong&gt;whichever outcome you favor, the only way to get to that outcome is for international treaty negotiators to discuss limitations and exceptions.&lt;/strong&gt; Taking limitations and exceptions off the table makes it impossible to move the ball in &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; direction, not just the one the content industries claim to oppose. That’s a foolish way to conduct negotiations, and one all the players in the NAFTA debate should reject.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;postinfo&quot;&gt;Filed under: &lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.harvard.edu/infolaw/category/copyright/&quot; rel=&quot;category tag&quot;&gt;Copyright&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.harvard.edu/infolaw/category/court-decisions/&quot; rel=&quot;category tag&quot;&gt;Court Decisions&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.harvard.edu/infolaw/category/digital-media/&quot; rel=&quot;category tag&quot;&gt;Digital Media&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.harvard.edu/infolaw/category/dmca/&quot; rel=&quot;category tag&quot;&gt;DMCA&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.harvard.edu/infolaw/category/international/&quot; rel=&quot;category tag&quot;&gt;international&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 11:15:54 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>severine</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blogs.harvard.edu/infolaw/2018/02/13/an-american-served-1-year-in-prison-for-conduct-that-is-100-legal-in-europe-but-its-not-drugs-its-copyright-heres-why-it-matters/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>