<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Goodbye Docker and Thanks for all the Fish</title>
<link>https://technodrone.blogspot.com/2019/02/goodbye-docker-and-thanks-for-all-fish.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://technodrone.blogspot.com/2019/02/goodbye-docker-and-thanks-for-all-fish.html</guid>
<description>Back in &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/maishsk/status/1019115484673970176&quot;&gt;July 2018&lt;/a&gt;, I started to write a blog post about the upcoming death of Docker as a company (and also perhaps as a technology) but I never got round to completing and publishing the post. It is time to actually get that post out.&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;OK .. Time to share my thoughts on the soon to be death of &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/docker?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#docker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
— Maish Saidel-Keesing (☁️🚀☁️) (@maishsk) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/maishsk/status/1019115484673970176?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;July 17, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So here you go....&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;Of course Docker is still here, and of course everyone is still using Docker and will continue to do so the near and foreseeable future (how far that foreseeable future is - is yet to be determined). The reason I chose this title for the blogpost is because, in my humble opinion the days for Docker as a company are numbered and maybe also a technology as well. If would indulge me with a few minutes of your time - I will share with you the basis for my thoughts.&lt;p&gt;A number of years ago - Docker was the company that changed the world - and we can safely say - is still changing the world today. Containers and the technology behind containers has been around for many years, long before the word docker was even thought of, even turned into a verb (“Dockerize all the things”), but Docker was the company that enabled the masses to consume the technology of containers, in a easy and simple fashion. Most technology companies (or at least companies that consider themselves to be a modern tech company) will be using Docker or containers as part of their product or their pipeline - because it makes so much sense and brings so much benefit to whole process.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the past 12-24 months, people are coming to the realization that docker has run its course and as a technology is not going to be able to provide additional value to what they have today - and have decided to start to look elsewhere for that extra edge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kubernetes has won the container orchestration war, I don’t think that anyone can deny that fact. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.servethehome.com/kubernetes-wins-docker-acquiesces-adopts-kubernetes/&quot;&gt;Docker itself has adopted Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt;. There will always be niche players that have specific use cases for Docker Swarm, Mesos, Marathon, Nomad - but the de-facto standard is Kubernetes. All 3 big cloud providers, now have a managed Kubernetes solution that they offer to their customers (and as a result will &lt;a href=&quot;https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/azure-container-service-will-retire-on-january-31-2020/&quot;&gt;eventually sunset&lt;/a&gt; their own home-made solutions that they built over the years - because there can be only one). Everyone is building more services and providing more solutions, to bring in more customers, increase their revenue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Story is done. Nothing to see here. Next shiny thing please..&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the moment, Kubernetes uses docker as the underlying container engine. I think that the Kubernetes community understood that Docker as a container runtime (and I use this term specifically) was the ultimate solution to get a product out of the gate as soon as possible. They also (wisely) understood quite early on they needed to have the option of switching out that container runtime - and allowing the consumers of Kubernetes to make a choice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.opencontainers.org/&quot;&gt;Open Container Initiative&lt;/a&gt; - brought with it the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/opencontainers/runtime-spec&quot;&gt;Runtime Spec&lt;/a&gt; - which opened the door to allow us all to use something else besides docker as the runtime. And they are growing - &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/opencontainers/runtime-spec/blob/master/implementations.md&quot;&gt;steadily&lt;/a&gt;. Docker is no longer the only runtime that is being used. Their is a growth in the community - that are slowly sharing the knowledge of how use something else besides Docker. Kelsey Hightower - has updated his &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kelseyhightower/kubernetes-the-hard-way&quot;&gt;Kubernetes the hard way&lt;/a&gt; (amazing work - honestly) over the years from &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kubernetes-incubator/cri-o)%20v1.0.0-beta.0&quot;&gt;CRI-O&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/containerd/containerd&quot;&gt;containerd&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/google/gvisor&quot;&gt;gvisor&lt;/a&gt;. All the cool kids on the block are no longer using docker as the underlying runtime. There are many other options out there today &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/clearcontainers/runtime&quot;&gt;clearcontainers&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://katacontainers.io/&quot;&gt;katacontainers&lt;/a&gt; and the list is continuously growing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Most people (including myself) do not have enough knowledge and expertise of how to swap out the runtime to what ever they would like and usually just go with the default out of the box. When people understand that they can easily make the choice to swap out the container runtime, and the knowledge is out there and easily and readily available, I do not think there is any reason for us to user docker any more and therefore Docker as a technology and as a company will slowly vanish. The other container runtimes that are coming out will be faster, more secure, smarter, feature rich (some of them already are) compared to what Docker has to offer. If you have a better, smarter, more secure product - why would people continue to use technology that no longer suits their ever increasing needs?&lt;p&gt;For Docker - to avert this outcome - I would advise to invest as much energy as possible - into creating the best of breed runtime for any workload - so that docker remains the de-facto standard that everyone uses. The problem with this statement - is that there no money in a container runtime. Docker never made money on their runtime, they looked for their revenue on the enterprise features above and on top the container runtime. How they are going to solve this problem - is beyond me and the scope of this post.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The docker community has been steadily declining, the popularity of the events has been declining, the number of new features, announcements - is on the decline and has been on the decline for the past year or two.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Someone told me a while back - that speaking bad about things or giving bad news is usually very easy. We can easily say that this is wrong, this is no useful, this should change. But without providing a positive twist on something - you become the “doom and gloom”. The “grim reaper”. Don’t be that person.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I would like to heed their advice, and with that add something about - what that means for you today. You should start investing in understanding how these other runtimes can help you, where they fit, increase your knowledge and expertise - so that you can prepare for this and not be surprised when everyone else stops using docker and you find yourself having to rush into adapting all your infrastructure. I think it is inevitable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;That was the post I wanted to write 8 months ago...&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What triggered me to finish this post today was a post from &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/fatherlinux&quot;&gt;Scott Mccarty&lt;/a&gt; - about the upcoming RHEL 8 beta - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.redhat.com/en/blog/red-hat-enterprise-linux-8-beta-new-set-container-tools&quot;&gt;Enterprise Linux 8 Beta: A new set of container tools&lt;/a&gt; - and my tweet that followed&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;

— Maish Saidel-Keesing (☁️🚀☁️) (@maishsk) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/maishsk/status/1098295411117309952?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;February 20, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Lo and behold - no more docker package available in RHEL 8.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re a container veteran, you may have developed a habit of tailoring your systems by installing the “docker” package. On your brand new RHEL 8 Beta system, the first thing you’ll likely do is go to your old friend yum. You’ll try to install the docker package, &lt;strong&gt;but to no avail&lt;/strong&gt;. If you are crafty, next, you’ll search and find this package:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;podman-docker.noarch : &quot;package to Emulate Docker CLI using podman.&quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is this Podman we speak of? The &lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;docker package is replaced&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt; by the Container Tools module, which consists of Podman, Buildah, Skopeo and several other tidbits. There are a lot of new names packed into that sentence so, let’s break them down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://maishsk.com/blog/images/20190224-goodbye-docker/podman.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;203&quot; data-original-width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;161&quot; src=&quot;https://maishsk.com/blog/images/20190224-goodbye-docker/podman.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;(Source - Tutorial - Doug Tidwell (https://youtu.be/bJDI_QuXeCE)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

I think a picture is worth more than a thousand words..&lt;p&gt;Please feel free to share this post and share your feedback with me on Twitter (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/maishsk&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@maishsk&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 09:53:59 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Corrado</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://technodrone.blogspot.com/2019/02/goodbye-docker-and-thanks-for-all-fish.html</og:url>
<og:title>Goodbye Docker and Thanks for all the Fish</og:title>
<og:description>docker, kubernetes, cloud</og:description>
<og:image>https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/proxy/fvBd2HHnFt8hEOQDkwloVXIRPD1hgiVOfiGANVcr5GlSHEjIdbmkdQ2tS1KOOy5Mv0JirgSRNzhqEj1dM3mVPQ5XeiOXunC5z6atQ0gnVQJPnM-qDho=w1200-h630-p-k-no-nu</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://technodrone.blogspot.com/2019/02/goodbye-docker-and-thanks-for-all-fish.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Hackers ransack Citrix, make off with 6TB+ of emails, biz docs, secrets</title>
<link>https://www.theregister.co.uk/2019/03/08/citrix_hacked_data_stolen/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theregister.co.uk/2019/03/08/citrix_hacked_data_stolen/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;trailer&quot;&gt;Updated&lt;/strong&gt; Citrix today warned its customers that foreign hackers romped through its internal company network and stole corporate secrets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The enterprise software giant – which services businesses, the American military, and various US government agencies – said it was told by the FBI on Wednesday that miscreants had accessed Citrix's IT systems and exfiltrated files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to infosec firm Resecurity, which claimed it had earlier alerted the Feds and Citrix to the cyber-intrusion, at least &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://resecurity.com/blog/supply-chain-the-major-target-of-cyberespionage-groups/&quot;&gt;six terabytes of sensitive internal files&lt;/a&gt; were swiped from the US corporation by the Iranian-backed IRIDIUM hacker gang. The spies hit in December, and Monday this week, we're told, lifting emails, blueprints, and other documents. The hackers have ways to bypass multi-factor login systems to slip into private networks, it is claimed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The incident has been identified as a part of a sophisticated cyberespionage campaign supported by nation-state due to strong targeting on government, military-industrial complex, energy companies, financial institutions and large enterprises involved in critical areas of economy,&quot; Team Resecurity said in a statement earlier today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Based our recent analysis, the threat actors leveraged a combination of tools, techniques and procedures, allowing them to conduct targeted network intrusion to access at least six terabytes of sensitive data stored in the Citrix enterprise network, including email correspondence, files in network shares, and other services used for project management and procurement.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LA-based Resecurity added that IRIDIUM &quot;has hit more than 200 government agencies, oil and gas companies, and technology companies including Citrix.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resecurity also said it warned Citrix on December 28 that the software giant had been turned over by the hacker crew during the Christmas period. Citrix, meanwhile, said it took action – launching an internal probe and securing its networks – after hearing from the FBI earlier this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;crosshead&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Ongoing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier today, Citrix chief information security officer Stan Black gave &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.citrix.com/blogs/2019/03/08/citrix-investigating-unauthorized-access-to-internal-network/&quot;&gt;his company's side of the story&lt;/a&gt;. He said that, as of right now, Citrix does not know exactly which documents the hackers obtained nor how they got in – the FBI thinks it was by brute-force &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://resources.infosecinstitute.com/password-spraying/&quot;&gt;password spraying&lt;/a&gt; – nor for how long they may have been camping on the corporate network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;While our investigation is ongoing, based on what we know to date, it appears that the hackers may have accessed and downloaded business documents,&quot; Black said. &quot;The specific documents that may have been accessed, however, are currently unknown.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, Citrix reckons the intrusion was limited to its corporate network, and thus believes customer records and data were not stolen nor touched.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond that, however, it's anyone's guess as to what exactly the hackers may have lifted. As a massive provider of remote management, networking, and videoconferencing products, Citrix has a large portfolio spread across a number of sectors in the business and government IT markets. Its customers include the White House and the FBI, though it's not known at the moment whether the hack involved or menaced Uncle Sam's operations directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;promo_article&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://regmedia.co.uk/2016/03/10/password_648x429.jpg?x=174&amp;amp;y=115&amp;amp;crop=1&quot; width=&quot;174&quot; height=&quot;115&quot; alt=&quot;citrix&quot;/&gt;&lt;h2 title=&quot;No reason to panic, apparently: Redoing login details to become a regular thing&quot;&gt;Customers baffled as Citrix forces password changes for document-slinging Sharefile outfit&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.co.uk/2018/12/04/password_change_for_sharefile/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;READ MORE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the investigation is in its extremely early phases, Citrix said it will provide customers with regular updates as it gets more details. For now, Citrix said it is planning to cooperate fully with the FBI probe, and has also brought in an outside security firm to help investigate the intrusion and make sure that hackers will not be able to get back in to the network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Citrix is moving as quickly as possible, with the understanding that these investigations are complex, dynamic and require time to conduct properly,&quot; Black said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;In investigations of cyber incidents, the details matter, and we are committed to communicating appropriately when we have what we believe is credible and actionable information.&quot; ®&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;crosshead&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Update&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This story was revised after publication to include Resecurity's version of events. A spokesperson for Citrix confirmed &quot;Stan’s blog refers to the same incident&quot; described by Resecurity, adding: &quot;We have no further comment at this time, but as promised, we will provide updates when we have what we believe is credible and actionable information.&quot; Resecurity declined to comment further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was it the Iranians, or not? Is it too early to tell? On the one hand, Resecurity previously &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://resecurity.com/blog/parliament_races/&quot;&gt;claimed&lt;/a&gt; the Iran-linked IRIDIUM team attacked the Australian parliament's computers, while sources close to the Oz government &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theregister.co.uk/2019/02/18/australia_pm_scott_morrison_state_level_hackers_parliament_breach/&quot;&gt;reckoned&lt;/a&gt; it appeared to be the work of China, though it could be another nation state masquerading as the Chinese.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, Microsoft &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/iranian-hackers-have-hit-hundreds-of-companies-in-past-two-years-11551906036&quot;&gt;this week&lt;/a&gt; said hundreds of companies have been hacked by Iranian miscreants over the past two years. The plot thickens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wptl btm&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Sponsored:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://go.theregister.co.uk/tl/1818/-7142/becoming-a-pragmatic-security-leader?td=wptl1818&quot;&gt;Becoming a Pragmatic Security Leader&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 02:35:27 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>cow9</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://regmedia.co.uk/2018/12/21/shutterstock_us_iran.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.theregister.co.uk/2019/03/08/citrix_hacked_data_stolen/</og:url>
<og:title>Iranian-backed hackers ransacked Citrix, swiped 6TB+ of emails, docs, secrets, says cyber-biz</og:title>
<og:description>Remote-desktop giant 'among more than 200 govt agencies, oil, gas, tech corps' hit by gang</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theregister.co.uk/2019/03/08/citrix_hacked_data_stolen/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ask HN: How to speak like a leader, not like an engineer?</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19349676</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19349676</guid>
<description>&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.58823529411765&quot;&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=&quot;#FF6600&quot;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;pagespace&quot; title=&quot;Ask HN: How to speak like a leader, not like an engineer?&quot;&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.5255972696246&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;fatitem&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.8941979522184&quot;&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing&quot; id=&quot;19349676&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;title&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19349676&quot; class=&quot;storylink&quot;&gt;Ask HN: How to speak like a leader, not like an engineer?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.74074074074074&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;subtext&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;score&quot; id=&quot;score_19349676&quot;&gt;368 points&lt;/span&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/user?id=yogrish&quot; class=&quot;hnuser&quot;&gt;yogrish&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;age&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19349676&quot;&gt;14 hours ago&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span id=&quot;unv_19349676&quot;/&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/hide?id=19349676&amp;amp;goto=item%3Fid%3D19349676&quot;&gt;hide&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://hn.algolia.com/?query=Ask%20HN%3A%20How%20to%20speak%20like%20a%20leader%2C%20not%20like%20an%20engineer%3F&amp;amp;sort=byDate&amp;amp;dateRange=all&amp;amp;type=story&amp;amp;storyText=false&amp;amp;prefix&amp;amp;page=0&quot; class=&quot;hnpast&quot;&gt;past&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=Ask%20HN%3A%20How%20to%20speak%20like%20a%20leader%2C%20not%20like%20an%20engineer%3F&quot;&gt;web&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/fave?id=19349676&amp;amp;auth=fa462f36abfd423b830d92b8de8c9c7092b84fd3&quot;&gt;favorite&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19349676&quot;&gt;168 comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I am a technical manager and currently in a leadership role. My manager who is an executive, keeps telling me“ don’t talk like an engineer, talk like a leader” when I go to him for any people or operational Issues. I always see from an engineer lens and possibly missing leader or executive perspective. How do I develop or change the way I talk as a leader. Did any one face this issue in the transition. Any pointers can be of great help.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.73972602739726&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ycombinator.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Applications are open for YC Summer 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;yclinks&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsguidelines.html&quot;&gt;Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsfaq.html&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Support&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/HackerNews/API&quot;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/security.html&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/lists&quot;&gt;Lists&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/bookmarklet.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Bookmarklet&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/legal/&quot;&gt;Legal&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Apply to YC&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Contact&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 01:36:37 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>yogrish</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19349676</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>GoFundMe CEO: ‘Gigantic Gaps’ in Health System Showing Up in Crowdfunding</title>
<link>https://khn.org/news/gofundme-ceo-gigantic-gaps-in-health-system-showing-up-in-crowdfunding/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://khn.org/news/gofundme-ceo-gigantic-gaps-in-health-system-showing-up-in-crowdfunding/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;article-body&quot;&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;related partner-box top&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;related-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Use Our Content&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;replublish-story&quot;&gt;This story can be republished for free (&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://khn.org/news/gofundme-ceo-gigantic-gaps-in-health-system-showing-up-in-crowdfunding/view/republish/&quot;&gt;details&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scrolling through the GoFundMe website reveals seemingly an endless number of people who need help or community support. A common theme: the cost of health care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It didn’t start out this way. Back in 2010, when the crowdfunding website began, it suggested fundraisers for “ideas and dreams,” “wedding donations and honeymoon registry” or “special occasions.” A spokeswoman said the bulk of collection efforts from the first year were “related to charities and foundations.” A category for medical needs existed, but it was farther down the list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the nine years since, campaigns to pay for health care have reaped the most cash. Of the $5 billion the company says it has raised, about a third has been for medical expenses from more than 250,000 medical campaigns conducted annually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take, for instance, the 25-year-old California woman who had a stroke and “needs financial support for rehabilitation, home nursing, medical equipment and uncovered medical expenses.” Or the Tennessee couple who want to get pregnant, but whose insurance doesn’t cover the $20,000 worth of “medications, surgeries, scans, lab monitoring, and appointments [that] will need to be paid for upfront and out-of-pocket” for in vitro fertilization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The prominence of the medical category is the symptom of a broken system, according to CEO Rob Solomon, 51, who has a long tech résumé as an executive at places like Groupon and Yahoo. He said he never realized how hard it was for some people to pay their bills: “I needed to understand the gigantic gaps in the system.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, &lt;a href=&quot;http://time.com/collection/health-care-50/5425152/rob-solomon/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Time Magazine&lt;/a&gt; named Solomon one of the 50 most influential people in health care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We didn’t build the platform to focus on medical expenses,” Solomon said. But it turned out, he said, to be one of those “categories of need” with which many people struggle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solomon talked to Kaiser Health News’ Rachel Bluth about his company’s role in financing health care and what it says about the system when so many people rely on the kindness of strangers to get treatment. The conversation has been edited for length and clarity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;related inline&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;slab email-slab&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;email-signup&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;signup-text&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Email Sign-Up&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;slab-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subscribe to KHN’s free Morning Briefing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://khn.org/news/no-cash-no-heart-transplant-centers-require-proof-of-payment/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;KHN&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;and other news outlets have reported that hospitals often advise patients to crowdfund their transplants. It’s become almost institutionalized to use GoFundMe. How do you feel about that?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It saddens me that this is a reality. Every single day on GoFundMe we see the huge challenges people face. Their stories are heartbreaking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some progress has been made here and there with the Affordable Care Act, and it’s under fire, but there’s ever-widening gaps in coverage for treatment, for prescriptions, for everything related to health care costs. Even patients who have insurance and supposedly decent insurance [come up short]. We’ve become an indispensable institution, indispensable technology and indispensable platform for anyone who finds themselves needing help because there just isn’t adequate coverage or assistance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would love nothing more than for “medical” to not be a category on GoFundMe. The reality is, though, that access to health care is connected to the ability to pay for it. If you can’t do that, people die. People suffer. We feel good that our platform is there when people need it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q: Did anyone expect medical funding would become such a big part of GoFundMe?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t think anyone anticipated it. What we realized early on is that medical need is a gigantic category.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of insurance doesn’t cover clinical trials and research and things like that, where people need access to leading-edge potential treatments. We strive to fill these gaps until the institutions that are supposed to handle this handle it properly. There has to be a renaissance, a dramatic change in public policy, in how the government focuses on this and how the health care companies solve this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is very interesting. In the places like the United Kingdom, Canada and other European countries that have some form of universal or government-sponsored health coverage, medical [costs] are still the largest category. So it’s not just medical bills for treatment. There’s travel and accommodations for families who have to support people when they fall ill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q: What have you learned that you didn’t know before?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess what I realized [when I came] to this job is that I had no notion of how severe the problem is. You read about the debate about single-payer health care and all the issues, the partisan politics. What I really learned is the health care system in the United States is really broken. Way too many people fall through the cracks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The government is supposed to be there and sometimes they are. The health care companies are supposed to be there and sometimes they are. But for literally millions of people they’re not. The only thing you can really do is rely on the kindness of friends and family and community. That’s where GoFundMe comes in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was not ready for that at all when I started at the company. When you live and breathe it every day and you see the need that exists, when you realize there are many people with rare diseases but they aren’t diseases a drug company can make money from, they’re just left with nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q: But what does this say about the system?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The system is terrible. It needs to be rethought and retooled. Politicians are failing us. Health care companies are failing us. Those are realities. I don’t want to mince words here. We are facing a huge potential tragedy. We provide relief for a lot of people. But there are people who are not getting relief from us or from the institutions that are supposed to be there. We shouldn’t be the solution to a complex set of systemic problems. They should be solved by the government working properly, and by health care companies working with their constituents. We firmly believe that access to comprehensive health care is a right and things have to be fixed at the local, state and federal levels of government to make this a reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q: Do you ever worry that medical fundraising on your site is taking away from other causes or other things that need to be funded?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have billions being raised on our platform on an annual basis. Everything from medical, memorial and emergency, to people funding Little League teams and community projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another thing that’s happened in the last few years is we’ve really become the “take action button.” Whenever there’s a news cycle on something where people want to help, they create GoFundMe campaigns. This government shutdown, for example: We have over a thousand campaigns right now for people who have been affected by it — they’re raising money for people to pay rent, mortgages, car payments while the government isn’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;related partner-box bottom&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;related-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Use Our Content&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;replublish-story&quot;&gt;This story can be republished for free (&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://khn.org/news/gofundme-ceo-gigantic-gaps-in-health-system-showing-up-in-crowdfunding/view/republish/&quot;&gt;details&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;aside class=&quot;meta-authors meta&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;author-name&quot;&gt;Rachel Bluth:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:rbluth@kff.org&quot;&gt;rbluth@kff.org&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/RachelHBluth&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@RachelHBluth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;meta-tags&quot;&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Related Topics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;categories&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://khn.org/topics/cost-and-quality/&quot; rel=&quot;category tag&quot;&gt;Cost and Quality&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://khn.org/topics/health-care-costs/&quot; rel=&quot;category tag&quot;&gt;Health Care Costs&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://khn.org/topics/health-industry/&quot; rel=&quot;category tag&quot;&gt;Health Industry&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://khn.org/topics/insurance/&quot; rel=&quot;category tag&quot;&gt;Insurance&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://khn.org/topics/the-health-law/&quot; rel=&quot;category tag&quot;&gt;The Health Law&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 01:31:36 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>aaronbrethorst</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>GoFundMe CEO: ‘Gigantic Gaps’ In Health System Showing Up In Crowdfunding</og:title>
<og:url>https://khn.org/news/gofundme-ceo-gigantic-gaps-in-health-system-showing-up-in-crowdfunding/</og:url>
<og:description>Fundraising for medical expenses leads this crowdfunding website and, according to its chief executive, highlights a deep national need to address the high costs of health care.</og:description>
<og:image>https://kaiserhealthnews.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/go-fund-me-qa.jpg?w=1200</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://khn.org/news/gofundme-ceo-gigantic-gaps-in-health-system-showing-up-in-crowdfunding/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Sad State of Logging Bugs for Apple</title>
<link>https://www.corbinstreehouse.com/blog/2019/03/the-sad-state-of-logging-bugs-for-apple/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.corbinstreehouse.com/blog/2019/03/the-sad-state-of-logging-bugs-for-apple/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;You find a bug in macOS or iOS. Something in the software isn’t working the way it should work. You decide to let Apple know, and head over to &lt;a href=&quot;http://bugreport.apple.com&quot;&gt;http://bugreport.apple.com&lt;/a&gt; and login with your Apple ID. You fill out the required form, list the reproduction steps, hit the special key chord to generate a fat sysdiagnose, attach some screen shots, and hope they fix it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What happens to your bug?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All bugs are tracked with an internal application called Radar; internal Apple employees simply log bugs directly into this application. External people use the website “Bug Reporter”, which only shows specific developer interactions with the bug, and hide all other details of the bug. Those details are engineer comments, progress on the bug, when they “expect” to fix it or which build it is fixed in, and priority. Priority is important for bugs; they are considered “unscreened” if they don’t have a priority set. Bugs with a high priority (1) are highly likely to get fixed, whereas bugs with a lower priority (3 or 4) are not likely to ever get fixed.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each bug is placed into a particular top level component, which can have sub components. Savvy internal developers will log bugs directly into the component that the bug corresponds to, such as “AppKit / NSTableView”. This will get it directly to the right person who needs to look at it. Top level components have a large dropping areas that generic bugs can fall into, such as “iTunes / All”. These components get saturated with bug reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once your bug hits Radar someone will look at it. Developer Support will often take a first look at bugs that are related to SDK/programming issues. They will then pass it on to a more specific top level component, or directly to a more specific component (ie: NSWindow).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where things get screwy depending on the component your bug lands in, since bug management is group dependent. Many groups will have only one or two QA people to do the initial screening of those large drop areas for bugs. QA engineers are sometimes instructed to screen bugs with a priority and “fix period” before passing them off to the engineer responsible for the code. This is terrible because many engineers will not look at bugs with a low priority. It is much better for the engineer who “owns the code” to look at a bug and determine the priority. The QA engineers will frequently get a huge back log of bugs to screen, and it can take weeks, or even months, for some bugs to get screened. Sometimes this leads to a mass screening of bugs, marking them all with a low priority&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; Bug originators have to notice this, and complain about it for the priority to get increased. Worse yet, some groups mass close bugs older than a year or so, and ask the originator to re-open the bug if the issue still exists. A lot of people don’t pay attention to bugs that need verification, and they simply become lost. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From an internal developer’s perspective, it was quite frustrating to take the time to log a detailed bug, only to see it sit “unscreened” for weeks and weeks. It is demoralizing to see this happen to your bugs. But worse yet, sometimes your bug would get forward-duped. Someone else at a later time logs the same bug, and your older bug report gets duplicated to it. More often than not, this is simply because of the delayed screening of bugs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From an external developer’s perspective, it is even worse. There is very little feedback on bugs when they are in progress. You don’t know what priority the bug has, or if it has even been looked at and screened. This is Apple intentionally being opaque. More transparency could easily leak features or products, so this is expected. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully a bug ends up with an individual engineer who works on the code. A lot of these bugs will still be unscreened, and Apple engineers seem to loathe the process of screening bugs. So they let them sit around for a while, sometimes for weeks or months. People would rather focus on coding something new up, or working on already screened bugs that they &lt;strong&gt;have to fix&lt;/strong&gt;, as opposed to taking the time to read a bug report and figure out what needs to be done with it. They don’t have to read it and fix it right then, but just do a screening: determine priority, when to fix it (this is sometimes nebulous), and possibly ask the originator for more information (or mark it as a duplicate.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Engineers also dislike screening bugs because sometimes they have to add them to their queue for the current release. This increases their required workload for that release, which is something people don’t like doing. So, instead, many bugs stay unscreened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unscreened bugs indicate potential software problems that need to be fixed. Obviously this is bad, and management doesn’t like to have high unscreened bug counts. Managers will frequently instruct engineers to screen bugs, or ask QA engineers to do it (which is bad).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes QA screen bugs with a low priority and holds onto them. They &lt;strong&gt;never &lt;/strong&gt;get moved to the appropriate code engineers, and effectively become lost in the system. Sadly, I had seen this happen way too often.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bugs screened with a low priority and a nebulous-future fix date are also lost. They rarely will be revisited and fixed. Sometimes this is okay. Some bugs are just too obscure or rare to spend time fixing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some bug owners don’t want to take the time to go back and forth with the originator to find out some piece of information they may need. They sit on bugs for a long time, and eventually try to reproduce a bug on a later version of the un-released OS. They can’t reproduce it, so they just assume it is fixed, and send it back to the originator. This is particularly bad for external developers, and I’ll describe why below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a bug is sent back as fixed, the internal developer who originated the bug is supposed to verify the problem is resolved. They can send it back if the problem isn’t resolved. However, internal developers don’t really have an incentive to verify bugs. Management doesn’t keep track of bugs that need verification or really require developers to verify them. Most engineers do verify bugs; they like to make sure problems are resolved. But external developers are left in a more sad state. The bug becomes closed for them, and is dead. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;External developers do get notified when bugs are fixed, but only after the fix is available in a public release of the OS. This means it could take about a year for some bugs to get back to the external developer, since bugs start to get fixed *before* an OS is released to the public.  Generally, the bug will ask the external developer to verify the bug by installing the latest OS. For some people, including me, this just isn’t possible; they need to run and support an older OS, and don’t have the ability to install a newer OS on a particular machine. Or, they just won’t want to install the latest OS because it doesn’t have anything they want or need (that’s me, I run 10.13). Even if they do install the OS, they may find the bug isn’t fixed. At this point, it is simply too late; engineering has likely closed the bug, and it is lost in the ether.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What can Apple do? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is simple: Internal engineers need to take more responsibility in promptly screening bugs. Management needs to allow engineers to have more time to do this, which is at the expense of working on features or fixing already screened bugs. Engineers should always be expected to have a very low unscreened bug count. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Internal engineers need to promptly verify bugs when they are sent back to them. They need to install beta versions of the OS and do some testing. If it isn’t fixed, send it back. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a bug report refers to some problem, then the developer should look at the code that interacts with the area described and try to think about what would cause such a problem to happen. For instance, if a button is incorrectly disabled in iTunes, then the developer should try to figure out why that could happen instead of just asking for “how to reproduce this?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I worked at Apple I practiced what I am now preaching. I would screen all my bugs within a day or so. I would verify bugs within a week or so. I would poke around at code and attempt to make theoretical fixes for bugs I couldn’t reproduce. I felt like it was part of my job, and I just did these things as a daily task. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What can you do?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, you have to log bug reports. It’s okay to log bugs that are missing information; developers can ask for specifics of what they need. In general, for AppKit related bugs, I would find that a “sysdiagnose” rarely would provide any useful information. I would hate it when people (usually QA, and not the engineers who worked on the code) would ask me for a sysdiagnose, when I know it wouldn’t help them figure anything out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Log duplicates. If you know someone else logged a bug, but you are encountering the same issue, then log the same bug. It will get marked as a duplicate, but this will help increase the priority of a bug. It is sad, but Apple does look at this, and bugs with “high dupe counts” are looked at. &lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 01:23:17 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>fireflies_</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>The Sad State of Logging Bugs for Apple</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.corbinstreehouse.com/blog/2019/03/the-sad-state-of-logging-bugs-for-apple/</og:url>
<og:description>You find a bug in macOS or iOS. Something in the software isn’t working the way it should work. You decide to let Apple know, and head over to login with your Apple ID. You fill out the required fo…</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.corbinstreehouse.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Screen-Shot-2019-03-07-at-7.05.42-PM.png</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.corbinstreehouse.com/blog/2019/03/the-sad-state-of-logging-bugs-for-apple/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Gotify – a self-hosted push-notifications service</title>
<link>https://github.com/gotify</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/gotify</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gotify&quot;&gt;https://github.com/gotify&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19347848&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19347848&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 425&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 89&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 19:10:25 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>adraenwan</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars2.githubusercontent.com/u/36410427?s=280&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>profile</og:type>
<og:title>Gotify</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/gotify</og:url>
<og:description>A self-hosted push notification service. Gotify has 13 repositories available. Follow their code on GitHub.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/gotify</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>ArchiveBox: Open-source self-hosted web archive</title>
<link>https://github.com/pirate/ArchiveBox</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/pirate/ArchiveBox</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;Box-body p-6&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ArchiveBox takes a list of website URLs you want to archive, and creates a local, static, browsable HTML clone of the content from those websites (it saves HTML, JS, media files, PDFs, images and more).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use it to preserve access to websites you care about by storing them locally offline. ArchiveBox works by rendering the pages in a headless browser, then saving all the requests and fully loaded pages in multiple redundant common formats (HTML, PDF, PNG, WARC) that will last long after the original content dissapears off the internet. It also automatically extracts assets like git repositories, audio, video, subtitles, images, and PDFs into separate files using &lt;code&gt;youtube-dl&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;pywb&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;wget&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ArchiveBox doesn't require a constantly running server or backend, instead you just run the &lt;code&gt;./archive&lt;/code&gt; command each time you want to import new links and update the static output. It can import and export JSON (among other formats), so it's easy to script or hook up to other APIs. If you run it on a schedule and import from browser history or bookmarks regularly, you can sleep soundly knowing that the slice of the internet you care about will be automatically preserved in multiple, durable long-term formats that will be accessible for decades (or longer).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;sub&gt;. . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . .&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get started, you can install ArchiveBox &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pirate/ArchiveBox/wiki/Quickstart&quot;&gt;automatically&lt;/a&gt;, follow the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pirate/ArchiveBox/wiki/Install&quot;&gt;manual instructions&lt;/a&gt;, or use &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pirate/ArchiveBox/wiki/Docker&quot;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;There are only &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pirate/ArchiveBox/wiki/Install#dependencies&quot;&gt;3 main dependencies&lt;/a&gt; beyond &lt;code&gt;python3&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;code&gt;wget&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;chromium&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;youtube-dl&lt;/code&gt;, and you can skip installing them if you don't need those archive methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
git clone https://github.com/pirate/ArchiveBox.git
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;cd&lt;/span&gt; ArchiveBox
./setup

&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; Export your bookmarks, then run the archive command to start archiving!&lt;/span&gt;
./archive &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;~&lt;/span&gt;/Downloads/bookmarks.html

&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; Or pass in links to archive via stdin&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;https://example.com&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; ./archive
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open &lt;code&gt;output/index.html&lt;/code&gt; in a browser to view your archive. &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.sweeting.me&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;DEMO: archive.sweeting.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;For more information, see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pirate/ArchiveBox/wiki/Quickstart&quot;&gt;Quickstart&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pirate/ArchiveBox/wiki/Usage&quot;&gt;Usage&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pirate/ArchiveBox/wiki/Configuration&quot;&gt;Configuration&lt;/a&gt; docs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because modern websites are complicated and often rely on dynamic content, ArchiveBox archives the sites in &lt;strong&gt;several different formats&lt;/strong&gt; beyond what public archiving services like Archive.org and Archive.is are capable of saving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ArchiveBox imports a list of URLs from stdin, remote url, or file, then adds the pages to a local archive folder using wget to create a browsable html clone, youtube-dl to extract media, and a full instance of Chrome headless for PDF, Screenshot, and DOM dumps, and more...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using multiple methods and the market-dominant browser to execute JS ensures we can save even the most complex, finicky websites in at least a few high-quality, long-term data formats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Can import links from:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/9894ac0fc703d4f4173cb17034b70f025c473879/68747470733a2f2f676574706f636b65742e636f6d2f66617669636f6e2e69636f&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/9894ac0fc703d4f4173cb17034b70f025c473879/68747470733a2f2f676574706f636b65742e636f6d2f66617669636f6e2e69636f&quot; height=&quot;22px&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://getpocket.com/favicon.ico&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Pocket, Pinboard, Instapaper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/3a8b6fe2d2fceb5714222a0c4f290ffebab72f06/68747470733a2f2f6e69636b7377656574696e672e636f6d2f696d616765732f7273732e737667&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/3a8b6fe2d2fceb5714222a0c4f290ffebab72f06/68747470733a2f2f6e69636b7377656574696e672e636f6d2f696d616765732f7273732e737667&quot; height=&quot;22px&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://nicksweeting.com/images/rss.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; RSS, XML, JSON, HTML, Markdown, or plain text lists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/55c9f054da13bbf7044a5c672dd29a6571a3e911/68747470733a2f2f6e69636b7377656574696e672e636f6d2f696d616765732f626f6f6b6d61726b732e706e67&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/55c9f054da13bbf7044a5c672dd29a6571a3e911/68747470733a2f2f6e69636b7377656574696e672e636f6d2f696d616765732f626f6f6b6d61726b732e706e67&quot; height=&quot;22px&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://nicksweeting.com/images/bookmarks.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Browser history or bookmarks (Chrome, Firefox, Safari, IE, Opera, and more)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Shaarli, Delicious, Reddit Saved Posts, Wallabag, Unmark.it, and any other text with links in it!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Can save these things for each site:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;favicon.ico&lt;/code&gt; favicon of the site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;example.com/page-name.html&lt;/code&gt; wget clone of the site, with .html appended if not present&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;output.pdf&lt;/code&gt; Printed PDF of site using headless chrome&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;screenshot.png&lt;/code&gt; 1440x900 screenshot of site using headless chrome&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;output.html&lt;/code&gt; DOM Dump of the HTML after rendering using headless chrome&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;archive.org.txt&lt;/code&gt; A link to the saved site on archive.org&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;warc/&lt;/code&gt; for the html + gzipped warc file .gz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;media/&lt;/code&gt; any mp4, mp3, subtitles, and metadata found using youtube-dl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;git/&lt;/code&gt; clone of any repository for github, bitbucket, or gitlab links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;index.html&lt;/code&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;code&gt;index.json&lt;/code&gt; HTML and JSON index files containing metadata and details&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;By default it does everything, but can disable or tweak &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pirate/ArchiveBox/wiki/Configuration&quot;&gt;individual options&lt;/a&gt; via environment variables or config file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The archiving is additive, so you can schedule &lt;code&gt;./archive&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pirate/ArchiveBox/wiki/Scheduled-Archiving&quot;&gt;run regularly&lt;/a&gt; and pull new links into the index. All the saved content is static and indexed with JSON files, so it lives forever &amp;amp; is easily parseable, it requires no always-running backend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Related Projects&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are tons of great web archiving tools out there. In particular &lt;a href=&quot;https://webrecorder.io&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://webrecorder.io&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/webrecorder/pywb&quot;&gt;pywb&lt;/a&gt;) and &lt;a href=&quot;https://getpolarized.io/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://getpolarized.io/&lt;/a&gt; are robust, stable pieces of software that have lots of overlap with ArchiveBox. ArchiveBox differentiates itself by being primarily a one-shot CLI tool that specializing in importing streams of links from RSS, JSON (good for automatically archiving from a stream of browser history or bookmarks on a schedule), as opposed to a desktop application or web service that requires human interaction to add links.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn more about the motivation for this project and how it fits into the broader community, see our &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pirate/ArchiveBox/wiki/Web-Archiving-Community&quot;&gt;Web Archiving Community&lt;/a&gt; wiki page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/d2e0fb21fdf1c6671deb25b1eb0a1181235e380a/68747470733a2f2f692e696d6775722e636f6d2f50564f3838415a2e706e67&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/d2e0fb21fdf1c6671deb25b1eb0a1181235e380a/68747470733a2f2f692e696d6775722e636f6d2f50564f3838415a2e706e67&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/PVO88AZ.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Recently &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pirate/ArchiveBox/issues/108&quot;&gt;renamed&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;code&gt;Bookmark Archiver&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;We use the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pirate/ArchiveBox/wiki&quot;&gt;Github wiki system&lt;/a&gt; for documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also access the docs locally by looking in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pirate/ArchiveBox/wiki/Home&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;ArchiveBox/docs/&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; folder.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;Vast treasure troves of knowledge are lost every day on the internet to link rot. As a society, we have an imperative to preserve some important parts of that treasure, just like we preserve our books, paintings, and music in physical libraries long after the originals go out of print or fade into obscurity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether it's to resist censorship by saving articles before they get taken down or editied, or just to save a collection of early 2010's flash games you love to play, having the tools to archive internet content enables to you save the stuff you care most about before it dissapears.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The balance between the permanence and ephemeral nature of content on the internet is part of what makes it beautiful. I don't think everything should be preserved in an automated fashion, making all content permanent and never removable, but I do think people should be able to decide for themselves and effectively archive specific content that they care about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aim of ArchiveBox is to go beyond what the Wayback Machine and other public archiving services can do, by adding a headless browser to replay sessions accurately, and by automatically extracting all the content in multiple redundant formats that will survive being passed down to historians and archivists through many generations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read more:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn more about ArchiveBox's past history and future plans, check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pirate/ArchiveBox/wiki/Roadmap&quot;&gt;roadmap&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pirate/ArchiveBox/wiki/Changelog&quot;&gt;changelog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/29d08f225597d86cc595cc5e174c50143baefca1/68747470733a2f2f692e696d6775722e636f6d2f76696b6c5a4e472e706e67&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/29d08f225597d86cc595cc5e174c50143baefca1/68747470733a2f2f692e696d6775722e636f6d2f76696b6c5a4e472e706e67&quot; width=&quot;75%&quot; alt=&quot;Desktop index screenshot&quot; align=&quot;top&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/viklZNG.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/b8386086cb3e115306146d702663aa28b35d6414/68747470733a2f2f692e696d6775722e636f6d2f6d5732644954672e706e67&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/b8386086cb3e115306146d702663aa28b35d6414/68747470733a2f2f692e696d6775722e636f6d2f6d5732644954672e706e67&quot; width=&quot;25%&quot; alt=&quot;Mobile details page screenshot&quot; align=&quot;top&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/mW2dITg.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/88720083607bb268b75ab54353b94dfbd2726f70/68747470733a2f2f692e696d6775722e636f6d2f776e706441564d2e6a7067&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/88720083607bb268b75ab54353b94dfbd2726f70/68747470733a2f2f692e696d6775722e636f6d2f776e706441564d2e6a7067&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; alt=&quot;Desktop details page Screenshot&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/wnpdAVM.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/37503f97be600661e3da1f27493fd7b9bb3ffcc9/68747470733a2f2f692e696d6775722e636f6d2f3374424c3750552e706e67&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/37503f97be600661e3da1f27493fd7b9bb3ffcc9/68747470733a2f2f692e696d6775722e636f6d2f3374424c3750552e706e67&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; alt=&quot;CLI Screenshot&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/3tBL7PU.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Monadical-SAS/redux-time/HEAD/examples/static/jeremy.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Monadical-SAS/redux-time/HEAD/examples/static/jeremy.jpg&quot; height=&quot;40px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;em&gt;This project is maintained mostly in my spare time with the help from generous contributors.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.patreon.com/theSquashSH&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/3b315b472c5d8d82d7d57ed85ddd2fd8f03e4963/68747470733a2f2f696d672e736869656c64732e696f2f62616467652f446f6e6174655f746f5f737570706f72745f646576656c6f706d656e742d7669615f50617472656f6e2d2532334444354437362e7376673f7374796c653d666c6174&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/Donate_to_support_development-via_Patreon-%23DD5D76.svg?style=flat&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/thesquashSH&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/8aea6981dcaa12429ba5d19e19a4ec9caae6861c/68747470733a2f2f696d672e736869656c64732e696f2f62616467652f54776565742d25343074686553717561736853482d626c75652e7376673f7374796c653d666c6174&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/Tweet-%40theSquashSH-blue.svg?style=flat&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pirate/ArchiveBox&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/7f0752dc6cb0f982928cac9f95b1fa121daf2741/68747470733a2f2f696d672e736869656c64732e696f2f6769746875622f73746172732f7069726174652f41726368697665426f782e7376673f7374796c653d666c6174266c6162656c3d537461722b6f6e2b476974687562&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/stars/pirate/ArchiveBox.svg?style=flat&amp;amp;label=Star+on+Github&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 16:48:31 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>based2</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars2.githubusercontent.com/u/511499?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>pirate/ArchiveBox</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/pirate/ArchiveBox</og:url>
<og:description>🗃 The open source self-hosted web archive. Takes browser history/bookmarks/Pocket/Pinboard/etc., saves HTML, JS, PDFs, media, and more... - pirate/ArchiveBox</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/pirate/ArchiveBox</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>What Happens Now That China Won&amp;#039;t Take U.S. Recycling</title>
<link>https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2019/03/china-has-stopped-accepting-our-trash/584131/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2019/03/china-has-stopped-accepting-our-trash/584131/</guid>
<description>&lt;section class=&quot;l-article__section s-cms-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot; id=&quot;article-section-0&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;After decades of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gLbiwZi1t7w&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'0',r'None'&quot;&gt;earnest&lt;/a&gt; public-information campaigns, Americans are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epa.gov/facts-and-figures-about-materials-waste-and-recycling/national-overview-facts-and-figures-materials&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'1',r'None'&quot;&gt;finally recycling&lt;/a&gt;. Airports, malls, schools, and office buildings across the country have bins for plastic bottles and aluminum cans and newspapers. In some cities, you can be &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/business/archive/2015/06/recycling-enforcement/396734/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'2',r'None'&quot;&gt;fined&lt;/a&gt; if inspectors discover that you haven’t recycled appropriately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But now much of that carefully sorted recycling is ending up in the trash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For decades, we were sending the bulk of our recycling to China—tons and tons of it, sent over on ships to be made into goods such as shoes and bags and new plastic products. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wto.org/english/news_e/news17_e/impl_03oct17_e.htm&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'3',r'None'&quot;&gt;But last year, the country restricted&lt;/a&gt; imports of certain recyclables, including mixed paper—magazines, office paper, junk mail—and most plastics. Waste-management companies across the country are telling towns, cities, and counties that there is no longer a market for their recycling. These municipalities have two choices: pay much higher rates to get rid of recycling, or throw it all away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most are choosing the latter. “We are doing our best to be environmentally responsible, but we can’t afford it,” said Judie Milner, the city manager of Franklin, New Hampshire. Since 2010, Franklin has offered curbside recycling and encouraged residents to put paper, metal, and plastic in their green bins. When the program launched, Franklin could break even on recycling by selling it for $6 a ton. Now, Milner told me, the transfer station is charging the town $125 a ton to recycle, or $68 a ton to incinerate. One-fifth of Franklin’s residents live &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nhes.nh.gov/elmi/products/cp/profiles-htm/franklin.htm&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'4',r'None'&quot;&gt;below the poverty line&lt;/a&gt;, and the city government didn’t want to ask them to pay more to recycle, so all those carefully sorted bottles and cans are being burned. Milner hates knowing that Franklin is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.no-burn.org/burning-plastic-incineration-causes-air-pollution-dioxin-emissions-cost-overruns/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'5',r'None'&quot;&gt;releasing toxins&lt;/a&gt; into the environment, but there’s not much she can do. “Plastic is just not one of the things we have a market for,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;l-article__section s-cms-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot; id=&quot;article-section-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same thing is happening across the country. Broadway, Virginia, had a recycling program for 22 years, but recently suspended it after Waste Management told the town that prices would increase by 63 percent, and then stopped offering recycling pickup as a service. “It almost feels illegal, to throw plastic bottles away,” the town manager, Kyle O’Brien, told me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without a market for mixed paper, bales of the stuff started to pile up in Blaine County, Idaho; the county eventually stopped collecting it and took the 35 bales it had hoped to recycle to a landfill. The town of Fort Edward, New York, &lt;a href=&quot;https://poststar.com/news/local/after-town-s-halt-of-recycling-services-fort-edward-village/article_f6b3d677-baaf-53bb-a7de-3dac622e5534.html&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'6',r'None'&quot;&gt;suspended&lt;/a&gt; its recycling program in July and admitted it had actually been taking recycling to an incinerator for months. Determined to hold out until the market turns around, the nonprofit Keep Northern Illinois Beautiful has collected 400,000 tons of plastic. But for now, it is piling the bales behind the facility where it collects plastic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This end of recycling comes at a time when the United States is creating more waste than ever. In 2015, the most recent year for which national data are available, America generated &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epa.gov/sites/production/files/2018-07/documents/2015_smm_msw_factsheet_07242018_fnl_508_002.pdf&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'7',r'None'&quot;&gt;262.4 million&lt;/a&gt; tons of waste, up 4.5 percent from 2010 and 60 percent from 1985. That amounts to nearly five pounds per person a day. New York City &lt;a href=&quot;https://dsny.cityofnewyork.us/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/about_dsny-curbside-collections-FY2018-1.pdf&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'8',r'None'&quot;&gt;collected&lt;/a&gt; 934 tons of metal, plastic, and glass a day from residents last year, a 33 percent increase from 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-recirculation-link&quot; data-id=&quot;injected-recirculation-link&quot; id=&quot;injected-recirculation-link-0&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2018/08/online-shopping-and-accumulation-of-junk/567985/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'9',r'None'&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read: ‘&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2018/08/online-shopping-and-accumulation-of-junk/567985/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'10',r'None'&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;We are all accumulating mountains of things&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2018/08/online-shopping-and-accumulation-of-junk/567985/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'11',r'None'&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;’&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a long time, Americans have had little incentive to consume less. It’s inexpensive to buy products, and it’s even cheaper to throw them away at the end of their short lives. But the costs of all this garbage are growing, especially now that bottles and papers that were once recycled are now ending up in the trash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of those costs is environmental: When organic waste sits in a landfill, it decomposes, emitting methane, which is bad for the climate—landfills are the third-largest source of methane emissions in the country. Burning plastic may create some energy, but it also &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com/news/science-environment-43120041&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'12',r'None'&quot;&gt;produces&lt;/a&gt; carbon emissions. And while many incineration facilities bill themselves as “waste to energy” plants, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.grid.unep.ch/waste/html_file/42-43_climate_change.html&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'13',r'None'&quot;&gt;studies&lt;/a&gt; have found that they release more harmful chemicals, such as mercury and lead, into the air per unit of energy than do coal plants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And as cities are now learning, the other cost is financial. The United States still has a fair amount of landfill space left, but it’s getting expensive to ship waste hundreds of miles to those landfills. Some dumps are raising costs to deal with all this extra waste; according to one estimate, along the West Coast, landfill fees increased by $8 a ton from 2017 to 2018. Some of these costs are already being passed on to consumers, but most haven’t—yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Americans are going to have to come to terms with a new reality: All those toothpaste tubes and shopping bags and water bottles that didn’t exist 50 years ago need to go somewhere, and creating this much waste has a price we haven’t had to pay so far. “We’ve had an ostrich-in-the-sand approach to the entire system,” said Jeremy O’Brien, director of applied research at the Solid Waste Association of North America, a trade association. “We’re producing a lot of waste ourselves, and we should take care of it ourselves.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;l-article__section s-cms-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot; id=&quot;article-section-2&quot;&gt;&lt;hr class=&quot;c-section-divider&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the trash piles up, American cities are scrambling to figure out what to do with everything they had previously sent to China. But few businesses want it domestically, for one very big reason: Despite all those advertising campaigns, Americans are &lt;em&gt;terrible&lt;/em&gt; at recycling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About 25 percent of what ends up in the blue bins is contaminated, according to the National Waste &amp;amp; Recycling Association. For decades, we’ve been throwing just about whatever we wanted—wire hangers and pizza boxes and ketchup bottles and yogurt containers—into the bin and sending it to China, where low-paid workers sorted through it and cleaned it up. That’s no longer an option. And in the United States, at least, it rarely makes sense to employ people to sort through our recycling so that it can be made into new material, because virgin plastics and paper are still cheaper in comparison.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even in San Francisco, often &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2018/07/13/how-san-francisco-became-a-global-leader-in-waste-management.html&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'14',r'None'&quot;&gt;lauded&lt;/a&gt; for its environmentalism, waste-management companies struggle to keep recycling uncontaminated. I visited a state-of-the-art facility operated by San Francisco’s recycling provider, Recology, where million-dollar machines separate aluminum from paper from plastic from garbage. But as the Recology spokesman Robert Reed walked me through the plant, he kept pointing out nonrecyclables gumming up the works. Workers wearing masks and helmets grabbed laundry baskets off a fast-moving conveyor belt of cardboard as some non-cardboard items escaped their gloved hands. Recology has to stop another machine twice a day so a technician can pry plastic bags from where they’ve clogged up the gear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; data-srcset=&quot;https://cdn.theatlantic.com/assets/media/img/posts/2019/03/IMG_7772/8bea8d007.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lazyload&quot;/&gt;Bales of plastic are piled at a Recology facility in San Francisco. (Alana Semuels / The Atlantic)
&lt;p&gt;Cleaning up recycling means employing people to slowly go through materials, which is expensive. Jacob Greenberg, a commissioner in Blaine County, Idaho, told me that the county’s mixed-paper recycling was about 90 percent clean. But its paper broker said the mixed paper needed to be 99 percent clean for anyone to buy it, and elected officials didn’t want to hike fees to get there. “At what point do you feel like you’re spending more money than what it takes for people to feel good about recycling?” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then there’s the challenge of educating people about what can and can’t be recycled, even as the number of items they touch on a daily basis grows. Americans tend to be “aspirational” about their recycling, tossing an item in the blue bin because it makes them feel less guilty about consuming it and throwing it away. Even in San Francisco, Reed kept pointing out items that aren’t easily recyclable but that keep showing up at the Recology plant: soy-sauce packets and pizza boxes, candy-bar wrappers and dry-cleaner bags, the lids of to-go coffee cups and plastic take-out containers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we can somehow figure out how to better sort recycling, some U.S. markets for plastics and paper may emerge. But selling it domestically will still be harder than it would be in a place such as China, where a booming manufacturing sector has constant demand for materials. The viability of recycling varies tremendously by locale; San Francisco can recycle its glass back into bottles in six weeks, according to Recology, while many other cities are finding that glass is so heavy and breaks so easily that it is nearly impossible to truck it to a place that will recycle it. Akron, Ohio, is just one of many cities that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cleveland.com/akron/2018/12/akrons-ban-on-recycling-glass-based-on-faulty-information.html&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'15',r'None'&quot;&gt;have ended&lt;/a&gt; glass recycling since the China policy changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;l-article__section s-cms-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot; id=&quot;article-section-3&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, it’s still often cheaper for companies to manufacture using new materials than recycled ones. Michael Rohwer, a director at Business for Social Responsibility, works with companies that try to be more environmentally friendly. He told me that recycled plastic costs pennies more than new plastic, and those pennies add up when you’re manufacturing millions of items. Items made of different types of plastic nearly always end up in the trash, because recyclers can’t separate the plastics from one another—Reed equates it with trying to get the sugar and eggs out of a cake after you’ve baked it. But because companies don’t bear the costs of disposal, they have no incentive to manufacture products out of material that will be easier to recycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best way to fix recycling is probably persuading people to buy less stuff, which would also have the benefit of reducing some of the upstream waste created when products are made. But that’s a hard sell in the United States, where consumer spending accounts for 68 percent of the GDP. The strong economy means more people have more spending money, too, and often the things they buy, such as new phones, and the places they shop, such as Amazon, are designed to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2018/10/amazon-selling-machine/574045/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'16',r'None'&quot;&gt;sell them&lt;/a&gt; even more things. The average American spent 7 percent more on food and 8 percent more on personal-care products and services in 2017 than in 2016, according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bls.gov/news.release/cesan.nr0.htm&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'17',r'None'&quot;&gt;government data&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;c-recirculation-link&quot; data-id=&quot;injected-recirculation-link&quot; id=&quot;injected-recirculation-link-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2018/10/amazon-selling-machine/574045/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'18',r'None'&quot;&gt;Read: The Amazon selling machine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some places are still trying to get people to buy less. The city of San Francisco, for instance, is trying to get residents to think of a fourth &lt;em&gt;r&lt;/em&gt; beyond “reduce, reuse, and recycle”—“refuse.” It wants people to be smarter about what they purchase, avoiding plastic bottles and straws and other disposable goods. But it’s been tough in a place centered on acquiring the newest technology. “This is our big challenge: How do you take a culture like San Francisco and get people excited about less?” Debbie Raphael, the director of the San Francisco Department of the Environment, told me. The city passed an ordinance that required that 10 percent of beverages sold be available in reusable containers, and it is trying to make reuse “hip” through an online campaign and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.recology.com/better-at-the-bin/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'19',r'None'&quot;&gt;dedicated website&lt;/a&gt;, Raphael said. San Francisco and other Bay Area cities have banned plastic bags and plastic straws, but that option isn’t available in many other parts of the country, where recently passed &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pewtrusts.org/en/research-and-analysis/blogs/stateline/2018/01/29/banning-the-bans-state-and-local-officials-clash-over-plastic-bags&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'20',r'None'&quot;&gt;state laws&lt;/a&gt; prevent cities from banning products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But even in San Francisco, the most careful consumers still generate a lot of waste. Plastic clamshell containers are difficult to recycle because the material they’re made of is so flimsy—but it’s hard to find berries not sold in those containers, even at most farmers’ markets. Go into a Best Buy or Target in San Francisco to buy headphones or a charger, and you’ll still end up with plastic packaging to throw away. Amazon has tried to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aboutamazon.com/sustainability/packaging&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'21',r'None'&quot;&gt;reduce waste&lt;/a&gt; by sending products in white and blue plastic envelopes, but when I visited the Recology plant, they littered the floor because they’re very &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2019/02/11/why-amazons-new-streamlined-packaging-is-jamming-up-recycling-centers/?utm_term=.508cb51285ba&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'22',r'None'&quot;&gt;hard to recycle&lt;/a&gt;. Even at Recology, an employee-owned company that benefits when people recycle well, the hurdles to getting rid of plastics were evident. Reed chided me for eating my daily Chobani yogurt out of small, five-ounce containers rather than out of big, 32-ounce tubs, but I saw a five-ounce Yoplait container in a trash can of the control room of the Recology plant. While there, Reed handed me a pair of small orange earplugs meant to protect my ears from the noise of the plant. They were wrapped in a type of flimsy plastic that is nearly impossible to recycle. When I left the plant, I kept the earplugs and the plastic in my bag, not sure what to do with them. Eventually, I threw them in the trash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;c-letters-cta&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;c-letters-cta__text&quot;&gt;We want to hear what you think about this article. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/contact/letters/&quot; class=&quot;c-letters-cta__link&quot;&gt;Submit a letter&lt;/a&gt; to the editor or write to letters@theatlantic.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;address id=&quot;article-writer-0&quot; class=&quot;c-article-writer lazyload&quot; data-author-id=&quot;8079&quot; data-include=&quot;css:https://cdn.theatlantic.com/assets/static/a/frontend/dist/theatlantic/css/components/article-writer.ccce81ff6d92.css&quot; itemprop=&quot;author&quot; itemtype=&quot;https://schema.org/Person&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;c-article-writer__image&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot;&gt;


&lt;a class=&quot;o-media__object&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/author/alana-semuels/&quot; title=&quot;Alana Semuels's writer page&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;c-article-writer__img o-media__img&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.theatlantic.com/assets/media/None/asheadshot_bw/200.jpg?mod=1550787755&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;c-article-writer__img o-media__img lazyload&quot; data-src=&quot;https://cdn.theatlantic.com/assets/media/None/asheadshot_bw/200.jpg?mod=1550787755&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;c-article-writer__content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;c-article-writer__bio&quot; itemprop=&quot;description&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/author/alana-semuels/&quot; class=&quot;author-link&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;inherit&quot;&gt;Alana Semuels&lt;/a&gt; is a staff writer at &lt;em&gt;The Atlantic&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 14:46:19 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>edward</dc:creator>
<og:title>Is This the End of Recycling?</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2019/03/china-has-stopped-accepting-our-trash/584131/</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn.theatlantic.com/assets/media/img/mt/2019/03/RTXRA6K/facebook.jpg?1551873810</og:image>
<og:description>Americans are consuming more and more stuff. Now that other countries won’t take our papers and plastics, they’re ending up in the trash.  </og:description>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2019/03/china-has-stopped-accepting-our-trash/584131/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Speedrunning Windows 95</title>
<link>https://hackaday.com/2019/03/09/speedrunning-windows-95/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://hackaday.com/2019/03/09/speedrunning-windows-95/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Speedrunning is the practice of attempting to beat a videogame in as short a time as possible. There are a huge variety of methods and styles. There are 100% completion speedruns, tool-assisted speedruns, and speedruns that just focus on getting to the game over screen as quickly as possible by hook or by crook. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GbTptOHZDmk&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Now, there’s a world record speedrun, installing Windows 95B in just 1 minute 10.9 seconds.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current best attempts are &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1gJkoQ-_3MS2FP7aUlO5v4pQrhrwy0XjQvuojKlnre48/edit#gid=0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;collected in a Google Sheets document&lt;/a&gt;. So far, there have been few competitors but we expect to see more activity in future. The current rules for world record competition require original floppy and CD-ROM images to be used, but there are no limits on hardware, so records should tumble as time goes on. All the top times have been completed in virtual machines, but we’d love to see an attempt made on raw hardware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It all kicked off when [oscareczek] grew tired of trying to compete in traditional gaming speedruns, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/speedrun/comments/9yvns6/wr_windows_95b_installation_desktop_in_34999/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;so invented a new category instead.&lt;/a&gt; Competition has already come a long way from that original 4 minute time, and competitors are now considering advanced techniques such as RAM disks to speed their runs. All keystrokes are by hand at the moment, but we could see a tool-assisted competition starting up in future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve seen speedrunning techniques pushed to impressive limits before – &lt;a href=&quot;https://hackaday.com/2014/01/10/teaching-mario-to-play-pong-and-snake-through-innumerable-exploits/&quot;&gt;like running Pong within Super Mario World, just for fun.&lt;/a&gt; Video after the break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;embed-youtube&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe class=&quot;youtube-player&quot; type=&quot;text/html&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/GbTptOHZDmk?version=3&amp;amp;rel=1&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;autohide=2&amp;amp;showsearch=0&amp;amp;showinfo=1&amp;amp;iv_load_policy=1&amp;amp;wmode=transparent&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;embed-youtube&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe class=&quot;youtube-player&quot; type=&quot;text/html&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/RVREuYY6dg8?version=3&amp;amp;rel=1&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;autohide=2&amp;amp;showsearch=0&amp;amp;showinfo=1&amp;amp;iv_load_policy=1&amp;amp;start=2045&amp;amp;wmode=transparent&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 14:43:23 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>zdw</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Speedrunning Windows 95</og:title>
<og:url>https://hackaday.com/2019/03/09/speedrunning-windows-95/</og:url>
<og:description>Speedrunning is the practice of attempting to beat a videogame in as short a time as possible. There are a huge variety of methods and styles. There are 100% completion speedruns, tool-assisted spe…</og:description>
<og:image>https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/03/800-5.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://hackaday.com/2019/03/09/speedrunning-windows-95/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>“No, we’re telling everyone we are using Java”</title>
<link>https://twitter.com/joeerl/status/1104298407231922176</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://twitter.com/joeerl/status/1104298407231922176</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/joeerl/status/1104298407231922176&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/joeerl/status/1104298407231922176&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19346017&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19346017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 378&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 335&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 13:32:36 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tosh</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mobile.twitter.com/joeerl/status/1104298407231922176</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>