<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>AMP for email is a terrible idea</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2018/02/13/amp-for-email-is-a-terrible-idea/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2018/02/13/amp-for-email-is-a-terrible-idea/</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot;&gt;Google just &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/02/13/google-wants-to-use-amp-to-make-email-more-interactive/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;announced a plan&lt;/a&gt; to “modernize” email with its &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2017/05/18/googles-amp-now-powers-2b-mobile-pages-and-900k-domains-loads-2x-faster/&quot;&gt;Accelerated Mobile Pages&lt;/a&gt; platform, allowing “engaging, interactive, and actionable email experiences.” Does that sound like a terrible idea to anyone else? It sure sounds like a terrible idea to me, and not only that, but an idea borne out of competitive pressure and existing leverage rather than user needs. Not good, Google. Send to trash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See, email belongs to a special class. Nobody really &lt;em&gt;likes&lt;/em&gt; it, but it’s the way nobody really &lt;em&gt;likes&lt;/em&gt; sidewalks, or electrical outlets, or forks. It not that there’s something wrong with them. It’s that they’re mature, useful items that do exactly what they need to do. They’ve transcended the world of likes and dislikes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As evidence consider the extreme rarity of anything other than normal versions of those things. Moving sidewalks, weirdo outlets, sporks — they only exist in extreme niches like airports and lunchables. The originals have remained unchanged for as long as millennia for a good reason.&lt;/p&gt;

Email too is simple. It’s a known quantity in practically every company, household, and device. The implementation has changed over the decades, but the basic idea has remained the same since the very first email systems in the ’60s and ’70s, certainly since its widespread standardization in the ’90s and shift to web platforms in the ’00s. The parallels to snail mail are deliberate (it’s a payload with an address on it) and simplicity has always been part of its design (interoperability and privacy came later).
&lt;p&gt;No company owns it. It works reliably and as intended on every platform, every operating system, every device. That’s a rarity today and a hell of a valuable one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the tech industry has never been one to let elegance, history, or interoperability stand in the way of profit (RIP Google Reader), so that’s not much of an argument. Still, I thought it worth saying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More important are two things: the moat and the motive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The moat is the one between communications and applications. Communications say things, and applications interact with things. There are crossover areas, but something like email is designed and overwhelmingly used to &lt;em&gt;say&lt;/em&gt; things, while websites and apps are overwhelmingly designed and used to &lt;em&gt;interact with&lt;/em&gt; things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s fundamentally useful to have a divide here the way it’s useful to have a divide between a book about fire and a book of matches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emails are static because messages are meant to be static. The entire concept of communication via the internet is based around the telegraphic model of exchanging one-way packets with static payloads, the way the entire concept of a fork is based around piercing a piece of food and allowing friction to hold it in place during transit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The moat between communication and action is important because it makes it very clear what certain tools are capable of, which in turn lets them be trusted and used properly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We know that all an email can ever do is say something to you (tracking pixels and read receipts notwithstanding). It doesn’t download anything on its own, it doesn’t run any apps or scripts, attachments are discrete items, unless they’re images in the HTML, which is itself optional. Ultimately the whole package is always just going to be a big , static chunk of text sent to you, with the occasional file riding shotgun. Open it a year or ten from now and it’s the same email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that proscription goes both ways. No matter what you try to do with email, you can only ever say something with it — with another email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; something, you leave the email behind and do it on the other side of the moat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the great genius and curse of email, that all you can do is send messages back and forth. It’s not always the best option, but it’s rarely the worst. If it’s more complicated than that, you use something other than email: a chat app, a video call, a file host. These useful items are often located &lt;em&gt;adjacent&lt;/em&gt; to email, sometimes closely integrated, but they’re never actually part of it. This is a &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt; thing. The closest you get is little things like adding something automatically to your calendar or scraping flight info from an itinerary. Ultimately it’s still just reading something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What Google wants to do is bridge that moat, essentially to allow applications to run inside emails, limited ones to be sure, but by definition the kind of thing that belongs on the other side of the moat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/gmailamp-pinterest-blog-01.gif&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-1597702&quot; src=&quot;https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/gmailamp-pinterest-blog-01.gif?w=1000&amp;amp;h=500&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;500&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Why do this? Are we running out of tabs? Were people complaining that clicking “yes” on an RSVP email took them to the invitation site? Were they asking to have a video chat window open inside the email with the link? No. No one cares. No one is being inconvenienced by this aspect of email (inbox overload is a different problem), and no one will gain anything by changing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, &lt;em&gt;almost&lt;/em&gt; no one. Which brings us to the motive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AMP is, to begin with, Google exerting its market power to extend its control over others’ content. Facebook is doing it, so Google has to. Using its privileged position as the means through which people find a great deal of content, Google is attempting to make it so that the content itself must also be part of a system it has defined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“AMP started as an effort to help publishers, but as its capabilities have expanded over time, it’s now one of the best ways to build rich webpages,” it writes in the blog post announcing the AMP for Gmail test. No, it isn’t. AMP is a way to adapt and deliver, on Google’s terms, real webpages built with real tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The excuse that the mobile web isn’t fast enough is threadbare, and the solution of a special Google-designed sub-web transparently self-serving. It’s like someone who sells bottled water telling you your tap runs too slow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AMP for email is just an extension of that principle. People leave Gmail all the time to go to airline webpages, online shops, social media, and other places. Places that have created their own user environments, with their own analytics, their own processes that may or may not be beneficial or even visible to Google. Can’t have that!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But if these everyday tasks take place inside Gmail, Google exerts control over the intimate details, defining what other companies can and can’t do inside the email system — rather than using the natural limitations of email, which I hasten to reiterate are a feature, not a bug.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And as if that play wasn’t enough, the other one is as baldly avaricious as anything the company has ever done. Dynamic content in emails. Where have I heard that one before? That’s right: it’s Google’s entire business model for offering a free email service. Ads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the vast majority of “live” content on the web, stuff that needs to call home and update itself? Not articles like this one, or videos or songs — those are just resources you request. Not chats or emails. Cloud-based productivity tools like shared documents, sure, granted. But the rest — and we’re talking like 99.9 percent here — is ads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ads and trackers that adapt themselves to the content around them, the data they know about the viewer, and the latest pricing or promotions. That’s how Google wants to “modernize” your inbox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does “engaging, interactive, and actionable email experiences” ring a little different now?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t use this. Don’t encourage it. AMP and other initiatives like it are already a blight on the web, and they will be equally bad for email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;small&gt;Featured Image: &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.shutterstock.com/gallery-1376932p1.html&quot;&gt;HeiroGraphic&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.shutterstock.com&quot;&gt;Shutterstock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;



</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 00:17:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>coloneltcb</dc:creator>
<og:title>AMP for email is a terrible idea</og:title>
<og:description>Google just announced a plan to &quot;modernize&quot; email, allowing &quot;engaging, interactive, and actionable email experiences.&quot; Does that sound like a terrible idea to..</og:description>
<og:image>https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/email-money-wide.png</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2018/02/13/amp-for-email-is-a-terrible-idea/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2018/02/13/amp-for-email-is-a-terrible-idea/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Don&amp;#039;t use VPN services</title>
<link>https://gist.github.com/joepie91/5a9909939e6ce7d09e29</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://gist.github.com/joepie91/5a9909939e6ce7d09e29</guid>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;No, seriously, don't. You're probably reading this because you've asked what VPN service to use, and this is the answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: The content in this post does not apply to using VPN for their intended purpose; that is, as a virtual private (internal) network. It only applies to using it as a glorified proxy, which is what every third-party &quot;VPN provider&quot; does.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(A Russian translation of this article can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://tdemin.github.io/posts/2017-08-13-dont-use-vpn-services_ru&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, contributed by Timur Demin.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why not?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because a VPN in this sense is just a glorified proxy. The VPN provider can see all your traffic, and do with it what they want - including logging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;But my provider doesn't log!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no way for you to verify that, and of course this is what a malicious VPN provider would claim as well. In short: the only safe assumption is that &lt;em&gt;every&lt;/em&gt; VPN provider logs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And remember that it is in a VPN provider's best interest to log their users - it lets them deflect blame to the customer, if they ever were to get into legal trouble. The $10/month that you're paying for your VPN service doesn't even pay for the lawyer's &lt;em&gt;coffee&lt;/em&gt;, so expect them to hand you over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;But a provider would lose business if they did that!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll believe that when HideMyAss goes out of business. They gave up their users years ago, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theregister.co.uk/2011/09/26/hidemyass_lulzsec_controversy/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;this was widely publicized&lt;/a&gt;. The reality is that most of their customers will either not care or not even be aware of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;But I pay anonymously, using Bitcoin/PaysafeCard/Cash/drugs!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doesn't matter. You're still connecting to their service from your own IP, and they can log that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;But I want more security!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VPNs don't provide security. They are just a glorified proxy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;But I want more privacy!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VPNs don't provide privacy, with a few exceptions (detailed below). They are just a proxy. If somebody wants to tap your connection, they can still do so - they just have to do so at a different point (ie. when your traffic leaves the VPN server).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;But I want more encryption!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use SSL/TLS and HTTPS (for centralized services), or end-to-end encryption (for social or P2P applications). VPNs can't magically encrypt your traffic - it's simply not technically possible. If the endpoint expects plaintext, there is &lt;em&gt;nothing&lt;/em&gt; you can do about that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When using a VPN, the &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; encrypted part of the connection is from you to the VPN provider. From the VPN provider onwards, it is the same as it would have been without a VPN. And remember, &lt;strong&gt;the VPN provider can see and mess with all your traffic.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;But I want to confuse trackers by sharing an IP address!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your IP address is a largely irrelevant metric in modern tracking systems. Marketers have gotten wise to these kind of tactics, and combined with increased adoption of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Carrier-grade_NAT&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;CGNAT&lt;/a&gt; and an ever-increasing amount of devices per household, it just isn't a reliable data point anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marketers will almost always use some kind of other metric to identify and distinguish you. That can be anything from a useragent to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://panopticlick.eff.org/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;fingerprinting profile&lt;/a&gt;. A VPN cannot prevent this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;So when should I use a VPN?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are roughly two usecases where you might want to use a VPN:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;You are on a known-hostile network (eg. a public airport WiFi access point, or an ISP that is known to use MITM), and you want to work around that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You want to hide your IP from a very specific set of non-government-sanctioned adversaries - for example, circumventing a ban in a chatroom or preventing anti-piracy scareletters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the second case, you'd probably just want a regular proxy &lt;em&gt;specifically&lt;/em&gt; for that traffic - sending &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; of your traffic over a VPN provider (like is the default with almost every VPN client) will still result in the provider being able to snoop on and mess with your traffic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, in practice, &lt;strong&gt;just don't use a VPN provider at all, even for these cases.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;So, then... what?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you absolutely need a VPN, and you understand what its limitations are, purchase a VPS and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Nyr/openvpn-install&quot;&gt;set up your own&lt;/a&gt;. I will not recommend any specific providers (diversity is good!), but there are plenty of cheap ones to be found on &lt;a href=&quot;http://lowendbox.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;LowEndBox&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;But how is that any better than a VPN service?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A VPN provider &lt;em&gt;specifically seeks out&lt;/em&gt; those who are looking for privacy, and who may thus have interesting traffic. Statistically speaking, it is more likely that a VPN provider will be malicious or a honeypot, than that an arbitrary generic VPS provider will be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;So why do VPN services exist? Surely they must serve some purpose?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because it's easy money. You just set up OpenVPN on a few servers, and essentially start reselling bandwidth with a markup. You can make every promise in the world, because nobody can verify them. You don't even have to know what you're doing, because again, nobody can verify what you say. It is 100% snake-oil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So yes, VPN services do serve a purpose - it's just one that benefits the provider, not you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 21:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>miles</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars1.githubusercontent.com/u/1663259?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>Don't use VPN services.</og:title>
<og:url>https://gist.github.com/joepie91/5a9909939e6ce7d09e29</og:url>
<og:description>Don't use VPN services.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://gist.github.com/joepie91/5a9909939e6ce7d09e29</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Italian Anti-Corruption Authority Adopts Onion Services</title>
<link>https://blog.torproject.org/italian-anti-corruption-authority-anac-adopts-onion-services</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.torproject.org/italian-anti-corruption-authority-anac-adopts-onion-services</guid>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;Millions of people use Tor every day to evade surveillance and censorship. Tor’s security and privacy protections enable activists to mobilize, journalists to report, and ordinary people to access blocked resources and avoid tracking. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whistleblowers, those brave individuals who report illicit activity, also depend on Tor to protect their identities when they come forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.torproject.org/news-orgs-activists-onionize-your-sites-against-censorship&quot;&gt;highlighted&lt;/a&gt; how onion services can be used to secure the web. Now, we're starting to see anonymity technologies become a legal requirement for public agency and corporate anti-corruption compliance, with the first well-known implementation by Xnet in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://xnet-x.net/en/whistleblowing-platform-barcelona-city-council/&quot;&gt;City Hall of Barcelona&lt;/a&gt; in Spain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many national laws (such as Italian &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fcpablog.com/blog/2018/1/11/sillaman-and-bernardi-italy-steps-up-whistleblowing-regulati.html&quot;&gt;Dlgs. 231/2001&lt;/a&gt;) require companies to adopt corporate governance structures and risk prevention systems, which can include allowing whistleblowing submissions. However, most whistleblowing laws only protect whistleblowers when their identity is disclosed, which can put the person reporting corruption at risk. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2016, the International Standards Organization (ISO) released a new model for organizations setting up and operating anti-bribery management systems, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iso.org/iso-37001-anti-bribery-management.html&quot;&gt;ISO 37001:2016&lt;/a&gt;. To meet ISO standards, organizations or companies implementing anti-corruption procedures must allow anonymous reporting, as explicitly indicated in point 8.9 of section C of ISO 37001:2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, national laws (such as recent Italian &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.radicalcompliance.com/2017/11/15/italy-whistleblower-protection-law/&quot;&gt;179/2017&lt;/a&gt;) require the adoption of IT systems for whistleblowing, leading to the practical integration and use of Tor for its technological anonymity features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To comply with these standards, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anticorruzione.it/&quot;&gt;Italian Anti-Corruption Authority&lt;/a&gt; (ANAC), an administrative watchdog, just launched their national online whistleblowing platform using onion services, giving whistleblowers who come forward a secure way to report illegal activity while protecting their identities. Most anti-corruption whistleblowers first speak out anonymously, and only when they know that their concerns are being addressed do they disclose their identities, as reported by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.transparency.it/alac/&quot;&gt;Transparency International Italy&lt;/a&gt;, an organization advocating uses of Tor in the fight against corruption since 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ANAC software is based on a customized version of &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.torproject.org/tor-heart-globaleaks&quot;&gt;GlobaLeaks&lt;/a&gt;, a whistleblowing platform by the Hermes Center that integrates Tor natively. GlobaLeaks is expected to be redistributed to all Italian public agencies (~20.000 in total) to comply with Law 179/2017 and in line with the country’s recent strategic &lt;a href=&quot;https://fosdem.org/2018/schedule/event/community_italy_most_hacker_friendly_country/&quot;&gt;commitment to open-source software&lt;/a&gt; and the reuse of code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given that Tor is the world’s strongest internet anonymity tool, we expect to see usage of onion services for secure communication systems across all sectors continue to gain traction. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read more about ANAC’s whistleblowing platform (in Italian) &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.anticorruzione.it/portal/public/classic/Servizi/ServiziOnline/SegnalazioneWhistleblowing&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to use onion services for your organization, check our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.torproject.org/docs/tor-onion-service.html.en&quot;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; and see if the &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.torproject.org/volunteer-spotlight-alec-helps-companies-activate-onion-services&quot;&gt;Enterprise Onion Toolkit&lt;/a&gt; is a good fit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Tor Project is a 501(c)(3) nonprofit, and we depend on your help to protect privacy and resist repressive censorship and surveillance. If you can, please &lt;a href=&quot;https://donate.torproject.org/&quot;&gt;donate today&lt;/a&gt; and help us continue developing these critical tools.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 19:41:51 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jakobdabo</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.torproject.org/italian-anti-corruption-authority-anac-adopts-onion-services</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>What I wish I knew when I became CTO</title>
<link>https://medium.com/sketchdeck-developer-blog/what-i-wish-i-knew-when-i-became-cto-fdc934b790e3</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://medium.com/sketchdeck-developer-blog/what-i-wish-i-knew-when-i-became-cto-fdc934b790e3</guid>
<description>&lt;p name=&quot;d9ce&quot; id=&quot;d9ce&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;Over the last four years I’ve been the CTO at &lt;a href=&quot;https://sketchdeck.com&quot; data-href=&quot;https://sketchdeck.com&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;SketchDeck&lt;/a&gt; and now, as I leave and hand the reins onto the team, I wanted to reflect on the experience and what I wish I’d known at the start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;b7e0&quot; id=&quot;b7e0&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;It’s been a wild and wonderful experience. Founding a startup is an upside-down version of traditional employment: initially you’ve no idea if the company will take off nor if it’ll ever turn into a full-time job, then as it grows you keep on being thrust into new and different jobs. It’s reasonably common to end up doing jobs you’ve never done before. &lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;You can accumulate responsibility faster than you can learn how to harness it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;4b56&quot; id=&quot;4b56&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Startups are agile boats, but the decisions you make on day one do have rippling consequences over time. &lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;I now appreciate that the infrastructure, frameworks and languages you choose will stick with you for a really long time&lt;/strong&gt; (hence why cloud providers can offer $100,000 initial credit). As the company grows there is an incredibly strong pressure to build more features and sub-systems, each one further locking you into your choices. As you gain more momentum the feature-pressure grows and stopping to re-write things is unaffordable and unthinkable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;1b3e&quot; id=&quot;1b3e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I’ve been pretty happy with our choices: Amazon Web Services, Elastic Beanstalk, Firebase, AngularJS, Coffeescript, Kafka, Simple Queue System, SocketStream, Docker, SemaphoreCI, MySQL. &lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;Of the list, AngularJS and MySQL have been the only ones to give us scaling problems&lt;/strong&gt;. Our monolithic AngularJS code-bundle has got too big and the initial download takes quite a while and the application is a bit too slow. MySQL (in RDS) crashes and restarts due to growing BI query complexity and it’s been hard to fix this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;c608&quot; id=&quot;c608&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;I appreciate now that technologies have a surprisingly short lifespan.&lt;/strong&gt; CoffeeScript and AngularJS are our most obviously tired components (we plan to migrate to TypeScript and latest Angular). All of our technologies were fairly bleeding-edge when we adopted them and it’s a blessing that my predilection for hipster technologies has not caused any serious problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;84f5&quot; id=&quot;84f5&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I’ve hugely appreciated the succinct functional syntax of CoffeeScript and &lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;believe it’s helped me achieve greater personal productivity over the years.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;82f3&quot; id=&quot;82f3&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Building on the above, &lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;I now know that you need to budget time and strategize for the replacement of technologies. You accept long-term “technical debt” with the adoption of any technology.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;2cb2&quot; id=&quot;2cb2&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Similarly, components and libraries you write are going to hang around for a long time. However nicely or badly you write them, they’ll remain in the same state — therefore &lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;it’s good to invest a little more time than is comfortable building them well for the sake of future maintainers.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;031f&quot; id=&quot;031f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I’ve always been resistant to “the grand re-write”, where one pauses on feature building and just re-creates parts of the system. It’s been a famous death spiral for many projects. One technique that has worked well for us is &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;The Boy Scout Rule&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;28e5&quot; id=&quot;28e5&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--pullquote graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--p&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Try and leave this world a little better than you found it” — Robert Baden Powell, Founder of the Boy Scouts and Girl Guides&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;be2d&quot; id=&quot;be2d&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--pullquote&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;We try to make small improvements to the areas of code we work on.&lt;/strong&gt; Sometimes it can be stressful to think about the (always imperfect) overall state of the codebase, instead I focus on continual small improvements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;da73&quot; id=&quot;da73&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Finally, a short note on testing: &lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;I’ve found it a real struggle to get our team to adopt writing tests.&lt;/strong&gt; I’ve written tests of many different parts of the system, and set up servers to automatically run the tests on every check-in. Despite this, I seldom see anyone else add tests. I always wanted testing to flourish based on its inherit merit, but sadly this didn’t happen. My ideas for resolving this are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;postList&quot;&gt;&lt;li name=&quot;7586&quot; id=&quot;7586&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Run refresher sessions on how to write tests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;0326&quot; id=&quot;0326&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;Require significant features to include at least one test&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;de0b&quot; id=&quot;de0b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;Optimize our test server to complete within 10 seconds instead of ten minutes (ouch!) so its output is relied upon by code authors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p name=&quot;0f96&quot; id=&quot;0f96&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--li&quot;&gt;Stepping aside from pure technical decisions, the life-blood of being a CTO is people management. The majority of your day-to-day will be managing, leading, hiring and firing people. I’ve had to learn all of this on the way and it certainly could have been smoother.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;495a&quot; id=&quot;495a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;No matter how many times I’ve read about how a company’s most important asset are the people, it never prepared me for how exhausting and excruciating hiring is.&lt;/strong&gt; To anyone new to hiring: you probably need to spend more time hiring and reject more people. You probably need to filter more stringently. I never could have guessed how rare the perfect startup team member is, nor how much time and effort would be needed to find them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;11f0&quot; id=&quot;11f0&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Knowing when to hire is an early conundrum: do I hire for this role now, or later, and which roles do I hire first? This is particularly hard if you have received funding as now you feel obliged to put the money to work. Fortunately, we received some helpful advice on this from Michael Siebel and YC:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;postList&quot;&gt;&lt;li name=&quot;3fea&quot; id=&quot;3fea&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--li-strong&quot;&gt;Only hire when you feel you’re completely desperate for the role&lt;/strong&gt; (e.g. you cannot keep up with building the features needed to close new contracts)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;f99b&quot; id=&quot;f99b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--li-strong&quot;&gt;Hire to keep up with growth, not to generate it&lt;/strong&gt; (this applies primarily to early stage companies before you have scalable, repeatable sales process)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;c43a&quot; id=&quot;c43a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--li-strong&quot;&gt;Don’t hire someone to do something you’ve not yet figured out&lt;/strong&gt; (some exceptional candidates can bring new capabilities to companies, but often the most reliable route is for some “founder magic” to re-assemble the company until it can perform the new thing)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p name=&quot;1913&quot; id=&quot;1913&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--li&quot;&gt;Summarizing those two pieces of advice, &lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;if you feel uncertain if you need to hire a particular role, it’s probably too early&lt;/strong&gt;. We went through quite a few cycles of trying to hire people to generate growth in ways we’d personally not mastered, and it mostly failed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;c05c&quot; id=&quot;c05c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Managing people has been relatively smooth sailing — having regular open and honest check-ins about what is good and what is bad has kept me and my colleagues having healthy productive relationships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;6fbe&quot; id=&quot;6fbe&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I’ve found firing people a tough part of the job. A lot of useful advice has been written elsewhere, I’ll simply re-iterate that &lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;your gut often knows you need to fire someone long before you rationally accept and perform it, and it’s always difficult.&lt;/strong&gt; Having good check-ins can help both parties prepare for negative outcomes. Finally, given a personal development plan, some people really do rise to the occasion and become great productive team members; everyone should have the opportunity to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;f439&quot; id=&quot;f439&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p graf--trailing&quot;&gt;One of the greatest joys in watching the company grow has been seeing other people emerging as new leaders of their areas. I offer my respect and congratulation to the entire team.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 19:34:54 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>edmack</dc:creator>
<og:title>What I wish I knew when I became CTO – SketchDeck developer blog – Medium</og:title>
<og:url>https://medium.com/sketchdeck-developer-blog/what-i-wish-i-knew-when-i-became-cto-fdc934b790e3</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*XQt_TyJk4PjuyKJeDU6sOw.png</og:image>
<og:description>Over the last four years I’ve been the CTO at SketchDeck and now, as I leave and hand the reins onto the team, I wanted to reflect on the…</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://medium.com/sketchdeck-developer-blog/what-i-wish-i-knew-when-i-became-cto-fdc934b790e3</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: Curated, Pre-trained ML Models for Transfer Learning</title>
<link>https://modeldepot.io/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://modeldepot.io/</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://modeldepot.io/&quot;&gt;https://modeldepot.io/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16368653&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16368653&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Points: 282&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 26&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 16:59:21 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>hsikka</dc:creator>
<og:title>ModelDepot</og:title>
<og:description>Curated Machine Learning models to supercharge your product</og:description>
<og:image>/logo.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://modeldepot.io/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Case for the “Self-Driven Child”</title>
<link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/the-case-for-the-ldquo-self-driven-child-rdquo/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/the-case-for-the-ldquo-self-driven-child-rdquo/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;mura-region&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;mura-region-local&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are raising the anxious generation, and the conversation about the causes, and the potential cures, has just begun.  In &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.penguinrandomhouse.com/books/549564/the-self-driven-child-by-william-stixrud-phd-and-ned-johnson/9780735222519/&quot;&gt;The Self-Driven Child&lt;/a&gt;, authors William Stixrud and Ned Johnson focus on the ways that children today are being denied a sense of controlling their own lives—doing what they find meaningful, and succeeding, or failing, on their own. Screen time, the authors say, is part of the problem, but so are well-meaning parents and schools, who are unwittingly taking from children the opportunities they need to grown stronger, more confident, and more themselves. Stixrud and Johnson answered questions from Mind Matters editor &lt;a href=&quot;http://garethcook.net/&quot;&gt;Gareth Cook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What makes you think that children do not have enough control over their live?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Stixrud: We know that a low sense of control is highly associated with anxiety, depression, and virtually all mental health problems. Researchers have found that a low sense of control is one of the most stressful things that people can experience. And since the 1960’s, we’ve seen a marked rise in stress-related mental health problems in children and adolescents, including anxiety, depression, and self-harm. Just in the last six or seven years, there has been an unprecedented spike in the incidence of anxiety and depression in young people. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a neurological perspective, when we experience a healthy sense of control, our prefrontal cortex (the executive functioning part of our brain) regulates the amygdala (a part of the brain’s threat detection system that initiates the fight or flight response). When the prefrontal cortex is in charge, we are in our right minds. We feel in control and not anxious. So, the fact that kids are feeling more anxiety, by definition, suggests that their amygdalas are more active, which indicates that they are more likely to feel overwhelmed, stuck, or helpless. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research on motivation has suggested that a strong sense of autonomy is &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; key to developing the healthy self-motivation that allows children and teens to pursue their goals with passion and to enjoy their achievements. But what we see in many of the kids we test or tutor is motivational patterns that are at the extremes of one, an obsessive drive to succeed and two, seeing little point in working hard. Many of these clients say that they feel overwhelmed by the demands placed on them, that they feel tired all the time, and that they don’t have enough downtime in their lives (related, in part, to the increasing presence of technology). Many talk about the expectations that they feel they have to live up to, and many complain about the fact that they have little “say” over their own lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is this a new problem?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Stixrud: It’s one that has progressed over several decades. When psychologist Dr. Jean Twenge compared college students from the 1960’s to college students in 2002, the latter reported a dramatically lower sense of control over their lives. Changes in our culture in the last 10 or 15 years appear to have contributed to an even sharper decline in a sense of control. For one, kids play much less than they did even a decade ago, as their time is taken up by more school hours, more scheduled activities, and more screen time than ever before. Researcher Peter Gray was one of the first to connect fewer opportunities to play to a decline in a sense of control. When kids could spend most of their Saturday playing, they could choose their own games and how to play them. They had a lot more autonomy and a lot more agency than kids do today. A typical Saturday now is often packed with homework and organized sports events. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, for a whole host of reasons, ranging from technology to packed schedules to anxiety, kids today sleep much less than they did even a few years ago. Fifty percent of teenagers fifteen years and older now sleep less than seven hours a night, whereas adolescents on average require 9 ¼ hours of sleep not to feel tired. When we don’t get enough sleep, the connections between our prefrontal cortex and our amygdala are weakened, resulting in lower ability of the former to regulate the latter. When children are tired, they invariably experience a lowered sense of control, as they are more easily stressed, have reduced coping skills, and are more apt to experience frustration and discouragement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there’s technology, which obviously has grown ubiquitous. More kids are reliant on social media, and there may be nothing more externalizing or control-lowering than posting a photo of yourself on the internet and waiting for people to judge you. A recent article by Dr. Twenge actually suggested that the smartphone and social media have likely contributed enormously to the dramatic increase in mental health problems seen in adolescents since 2012. And studies have found that at least 10% of boys have an addictive relationship to video games. Kids who are addicted to things often tell themselves, “I know I shouldn’t be doing this but I can’t stop,” which is a pretty clear indictor that they lack a sense of control. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We agree with Dr. Twenge that this problem has been increasing since the 1960’s because our culture has increasingly valued extrinsic and self-centered goals such as money, status, and physical attractiveness, and devalued community, affiliation, and the pursuit of meaning in life. Also, with technology driving an increasingly fast pace of life, it will only get worse unless we recognize how important having a sense of control is and make some changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do attempts at controlling a child backfire?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Johnson: In addition to the physical and emotional consequences (more stress, anxiety, and depression), trying to control a child has really negative effects on motivation. According to one of the best supported theories in psychology, self-determination theory, humans have three basic needs: a sense of autonomy, a sense of competence, and a sense of relatedness. Autonomy is built in to our wiring, so to speak, in the same way hunger or thirst. When we lack this basic need, we experience decreased motivation, or the motivation we do have becomes fear-based. (“I’d better do this, or else!”) Both are terribly unhealthy. You can’t become a self-driven person if you don’t have a sense that your life is your own. We think the phenomenon of “failure to launch”—the preponderance of people in their twenties and thirties living at home—is in part attributable to the idea that young adults don’t have the same drive for independence they used to have. They want to sit at home and play on their phones. They don’t want to drive as much, date as much, have sex as much. They are accustomed to someone else being in charge of their life, and their internal motivation system is stymied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s another way to look at it, too. Evaluate what you gain when you try to control a child. Let’s say you think your son—who struggles in math—should see a tutor all summer, and he disagrees. But you insist. It’s possible that tutoring would help some, but the truth is that kids benefit very little from academic help they resist and don’t feel they want or need. Even if it does help him, it comes at a great cost. It causes strain in your relationship with him. His competency &lt;em&gt;might&lt;/em&gt; be improved, but his relatedness (his relationship with you) and his autonomy are lowered.  Think of a three-legged stool where you make one leg longer and the other two shorter.  You cannot reach higher on that stool.  The most likely outcome is that it will tip over.  And, you have signaled to him that you know better than he does, that his opinion doesn’t matter. He also misses out on seeing what it’s like to make decisions for himself. Kids need experience checking in with themselves and their decisions, and they can’t do that if you’re making each one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can you please explain the idea of home as a “safe base”?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Johnson: Just as in baseball, when you reach home base, you’re in a place where you can catch your breath and not have to worry about being pegged with the ball or being called out, home should be a place for kids to rest and recover. They are facing stressors each day, from school demands to social dynamics. You want home to be the place they can go to seek a respite from it all, where they feel safe and loved unconditionally, where they can fully relax, so that they can gather the energy to go back out. But if home is a stressful environment—if parents are an anxious or controlling presence—kids will seek that respite somewhere—or somehow—else. And most of the time, it’s a place you don’t want them to go. Or, if nowhere can be that safe base, they are really in trouble, as being chronically stressed is about the worst thing imaginable for brains, especially developing ones. That’s why we tell parents that one of the most important things they can say to their kids is, “I love you too much to fight with you about your homework,” and why we want them to move in the direction of being a non-anxious presence for their kids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What else can we do to give children more of a sense of self control?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Johnson: We can give kids opportunities to learn to handle as much as they can, without being overwhelmed. Children thrive and grow when they feel challenged but not threatened. Personal pastimes (especially when kids can turn up or down the pace or intensity themselves) are great for this. Think of how video games work: the better you can play and the further you advance, the harder the game gets. You don’t actually die; you just have to try again. It’s fantastic! Games can be incredibly frustrating but almost no one wants a “cheat code” to get ahead. It just doesn’t offer the same satisfaction. In life, kids want to &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; that their successes were earned. Give your kid every opportunity to stretch himself through music, sports, coding, after school jobs, hiking, martial arts, whatever inspires his passion. That sense of mastery and autonomy in an activity he loves can cascade into other facets of his life. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can nurture habits and a lifestyle that support healthy minds: Above all, promote rest. Encourage sleep, meditation if they’re interested, and downtime. Many of the students I see complain that the moment they have a free hour, their parent rushes in to fill it. Rest is not laziness. It is the basis of all activity. Foster what we call Radical Digital Downtime. No phones. No screens. Those times of mind-wandering (some call it boredom) activate neural circuits in the Default Mode Network, a system that involves reflecting on the past and projecting into the future, processing life. Radical downtime increases the control that the prefrontal cortex exerts over the amygdala, keeping you in your “right mind.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, make it your highest priority to simply enjoy your kids. As they are. Right now. Flaws and all.  For the development of babies, one of the most important inputs is parents who are warm and responsive.  When do you think kids outgrow that need? We think, never.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 15:06:26 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>artsandsci</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>The Case for the &quot;Self-Driven Child&quot;</og:title>
<og:description>In a new book, an argument for giving children more of a sense of control over their lives</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.scientificamerican.com/sciam/cache/file/D0E9D3EF-E580-4607-A9475AA1519C4DAE_agenda.jpg?w=600&amp;h=335</og:image>
<og:url>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/the-case-for-the-ldquo-self-driven-child-rdquo/</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/the-case-for-the-ldquo-self-driven-child-rdquo/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Chrome will stop displaying ads that are repeatedly flagged as disruptive</title>
<link>https://www.blog.google/products/chrome/browser-web-worth-protecting/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.blog.google/products/chrome/browser-web-worth-protecting/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The web is an incredible asset. It’s an engine for innovation, a platform for sharing, and a universal gateway to information. When we built Chrome, we wanted to create a way for people to interact with the magic that is the web, without the browser getting in the way. We created a browser that took up minimal space on your screen, made the omnibar so you could quickly search or get directly to a website, and built our pop-up blocker to help you avoid unwanted content. Since then we’ve also added features such as Safe Browsing, pausing autoplay Flash and more—all aimed at protecting your experience of the web.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your feedback has always played a critical part in the development of Chrome. This feedback has shown that a big source of frustration is annoying ads: video ads that play at full blast or giant pop-ups where you can’t seem to find the exit icon. These ads are designed to be disruptive and often stand in the way of people using their browsers for their intended purpose—connecting them to content and information. It’s clear that annoying ads degrade what we all love about the web. That’s why starting on February 15, Chrome will stop showing all ads on sites that repeatedly display these most disruptive ads after they’ve been flagged. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To determine which ads not to show, we’re relying on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.betterads.org/standards/&quot;&gt;Better Ads Standards&lt;/a&gt; from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.betterads.org/&quot;&gt;Coalition for Better Ads&lt;/a&gt;, an industry group dedicated to improving the experience of the ads we see on the web. It’s important to note that some sites affected by this change may also contain Google ads. To us, your experience on the web is a higher priority than the money that these annoying ads may generate—even for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The web is an ecosystem composed of consumers, content producers, hosting providers, advertisers, web designers, and many others. It’s important that we work to maintain a balance—and if left unchecked, disruptive ads have the potential to derail the entire system. We’ve already seen more and more people express their discontent with annoying ads by installing ad blockers, but blocking all ads can hurt sites or advertisers who aren’t doing anything disruptive. By focusing on filtering out disruptive ad experiences, we can help keep the entire ecosystem of the web healthy, and give people a significantly better user experience than they have today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe these changes will not only make Chrome better for you, but also improve the web for everyone. The web is a vital part of our day-to-day. And as new technologies push the web forward, we’ll continue working to build a better, more vibrant ecosystem dedicated to bringing you only the best experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 14:45:13 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kevincennis</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>The browser for a web worth protecting</og:title>
<og:description>Annoying ads degrade what we all love about the web. Starting on February 15, Chrome will stop showing all ads on sites that repeatedly display these most disruptive ads after they’ve been flagged.</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.blog.google/static/blog/images/google-200x200.7714256da16f.png</og:image>
<og:url>https://www.blog.google/products/chrome/browser-web-worth-protecting/</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.blog.google/products/chrome/browser-web-worth-protecting/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Upwork banned my account for &amp;#039;being dishonest&amp;#039;</title>
<link>https://www.ribice.ba/upwork-suspended/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.ribice.ba/upwork-suspended/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;There are plenty of articles online despising Upwork. For those that don’t know, Upwork is ‘the world’s largest online workplace where savvy businesses and professional freelancers go to work!’ Once I felt comfortable writing Go - I decided I could take some small side gigs to make connections and earn some extra cash. For reasons still unclear to me, that didn’t last for long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;update&quot;&gt;Update:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the post reached #1 on HackerNews, an UpWork representetive contacted me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.ribice.ba/img/9/upwork-support1.jpg#c&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.ribice.ba/img/9/upwork-support2.jpg#c&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end, posting on social media did work (as usually). I believe there are lots of developers that face similar issues as I did, but do not pust it publicly or their issue doesn’t get viral. Also noting that if I could get in touch directly to someone from UpWork instead of outsourced support personal, this issue probably wouldn’t occur at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.ribice.ba/img/9/upwork.png#c&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve registered on both oDesk and Elance (companies that merged into UpWork) before I was serious about programming. I’ve heard from friends, colleagues and local forums how they earn extra side money by completing some ‘simple’ gigs - translation, transcription, data entry etc. After applying to few gigs, I wasn’t quite successful in getting a gig and decided it wasn’t for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward few years, being a software developer for 5 years I felt comfortable looking for gigs besides my full-time job. I was mostly interested in small tasks that should take few days to complete. On Upwork, I found plenty of them. The good thing is/was that very few people apply for Golang related gigs - so it isn’t hard to find one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first contract I received was from a client that wanted to implement Swagger into their Go project - lovely. I even wrote an article on that few weeks ago - &lt;a href=&quot;https://ribice.ba/swagger-golang/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;. Even though the gig was way underpaid ($15) - I did it mostly to get a positive review, as reviews are very important on such sites. Besides adding the annotations needed for auto-generation of Swagger, the client asked me to fix issue she had with CORS and then to show her how to run swagger locally via Docker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I did both, the client paid me a total of $45 and left a 5-star review (“Great Guy..Helped me a lot).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two days later I get another contract - a simple CLI in Go. Great. Client’s budget was a bigger ($40), although I proposed $50 which he immediately accepted. At the same time, I get an email from Upwork - that I need to verify my identity by a ‘10-minute video chat.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.ribice.ba/img/9/verification-email.png#c&quot; alt=&quot;Profile verification email&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before starting the verification process, I completed the second gig but didn’t send the code yet - I wanted to review it a bit later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I clicked on the link from the email, joined the conversation and turned on my microphone and camera. After the interviewer introduced herself, she asked me for my address, city, country. The call quality was far from perfect, as (from my perspective) she had a very bad connection during the verification process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon answering these questions, I was asked: “How is it possible to propagate a session id in PHP”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I don’t write PHP” - I replied. She talked a bit more, but I could barely understand her anything due to connection issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Please wait for an email regarding your account status in 24 hours or less. I appreciate your cooperation. I’ll be closing this chat now. Thank you for contacting Upwork. Have an amazing day!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“That went far easier and quicker than I expected. Lovely.” I had no clue what’s going to happen next. Eight minutes later I received the following email:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.ribice.ba/img/9/verification-suspend.png#c&quot; alt=&quot;Account suspended&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I felt disappointed. I provided everything they asked for, and now my account is suspended for not being honest. I opened another chat instance, that was nearly immediately closed with the message:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;--------------------------------------------------
Agent : Feb 3, 2018, 1:47:26 PM
Hi, Thank you for contacting Upwork! This is Agent M.
Please give me a few minutes to pull up your account.
Please Stay on the Line.

--------------------------------------------------
Visitor : Feb 3, 2018, 1:47:32 PM
OK
--------------------------------------------------
Agent : Feb 3, 2018, 1:49:11 PM
I see that your account has been permanently suspended. For more information
regarding your account status, you will need to contact our Customer Support team
by submitting a support ticket at https://support.upwork.com/hc/en-us/requests/new

Thank you for contacting Upwork.
Have a great day.
Agent M. just closed this chat.
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I had the time to read this reply the chat was closed. I did open another chat instance few hours later, and instead of saying ‘OK’ wrote the issue I had before chat was closed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;Visitor : Feb 3, 2018, 4:09:07 PM
Hi,

I talked to one of your colleagues today.

After trying to verify my profile (by video, providing my details), my call was closed,
and I received an email that my account was suspended for being dishonest.
I finished work for a client and would like to deliver now, but I'm unsure what 
happens now because my account is suspended.
Can you please look at the ticket and instruct me further how to verify my profile?

Thank you!
--------------------------------------------------
Agent N : Feb 3, 2018, 4:09:23 PM
Good day! This is Agent N and I will be assisting you today.
Please give me a few minutes to pull up your account.
--------------------------------------------------
Agent N : Feb 3, 2018, 4:15:12 PM
Thank you for waiting. I am sorry but your account has been closed and I am unable
to help you any further. There must be an email sent to you that explains why your
account was closed.
--------------------------------------------------
Visitor : Feb 3, 2018, 4:15:41 PM
You can look it up under ticket number: (#TicketNUM)
--------------------------------------------------
Agent N : Feb 3, 2018, 4:16:29 PM
Please refer to the ticket sent to you regarding your issue.
--------------------------------------------------
Agent N : Feb 3, 2018, 4:17:18 PM
I am sorry but your account has been closed and I am unable to help you any further.
--------------------------------------------------
Agent N : Feb 3, 2018, 4:17:26 PM
Thank you for contacting Upwork.
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I did receive some feedback, it was meaningless. I still didn’t know why my account was suspended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I messaged my client, telling him I did finish what he wanted but I’ll wait until tomorrow to send it, hoping that I would resolve my issue by then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next morning I saw a message from the client saying:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;Hi Emir,

A few minutes ago, I just received an email from Upwork stating:
---
Hello Client,

I’m happy to report that Emir Ribic’s Upwork profile has been verified.
Should you have any questions or need further assistance, please don't hesitate to get in touch.
Regards,

Upwork Trust &amp;amp; Safety
---
Can you test Upwork.com again?

Thanks!
Client
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, I thought that the issue was resolved and that I can proceed using my account. Instead, when I logged into my account, I noticed that my profile was indeed verified but the account was still suspended. The message I received from their support:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.ribice.ba/img/9/upwork-verified.jpg#c&quot; alt=&quot;Account verified&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The message clearly states that I can submit proposals and accept offers from client - which was not the case. A paradox - my account was suspended for not being honest during the verification process, a day later I got verified but my account was still suspended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I replied to this ticket (as it was a newly created one by their support team) asking whether my account is going to be ‘unsuspended’ but the ticket was closed without any answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I completed the gig day before, I sent my client the solution we agreed to. Instead of the agreed $50, the client paid me $100 and left a positive review:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;Excellent work! Very technically skilled and very detailed oriented.
Developed a very helpful golang solution.
Delivered project early while always delivering amazing, high-quality work!
Very highly recommended!
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I felt quite happy knowing that I helped someone and earned extra $100. On the other hand, my account was still suspended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upwork has a support account on Twitter, to which I sent a message and explained my problem - my account was suspended for no obvious reasons. They did reply:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;Hi Emir. I'm sorry to hear about the suspension of your account. Unfortunately,
the suspension of the account was due to a violation of Upwork ToS and, in this case,
I kindly ask you to refer to the notification sent to you about this matter.
We have systems in place to check freelancer accounts to make sure they are not
violating our Terms of Service and suspend accounts as needed.
Please, review our ToS for more reference on this topic.
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was this message automated/scripted? Probably yes. Still, I tried to recall whether I violated their TOS. I did remember that on an occasion or two, I sent a proposal to a client or two including a link to my &lt;a href=&quot;https://ribice.ba/resume&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;resume&lt;/a&gt;. I’ve read from many redditors that they do the same quite often. I felt I might get the job easier if someone lands on this blog, reads the articles and opens my GitHub. At the end, someone from Upwork can use this as an evidence against me - true, as it it violates the ToS, but let’s be honest - if you are freelancing as a software developer, it’s very, very hard not to give any contact information to your client. There are many ways that even if you refuse to communicate outside of UpWork (which I totally support), that you will need to do so. If your client demands usage of git (which they will if the project is anything larger than small tools), you’ll probably share your contact information by committing to that repo (commits contain email and your account info, e.g. GitHub account).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not to mention that my name, surname and employment history is publicly available on my profile. A simple google search involving ‘full name + company name’ gets my contact info (I found Linkedin and Facebook).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could that be the reason I was suspended? I didn’t have to wait for long. The last client I worked with (Golang CLI tool) contacted me in an hour, telling me that the &lt;strong&gt;money was refunded to him&lt;/strong&gt; with a message containing the reason my account was suspended:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;... Unfortunately, Emir Ribic did not pass our identity screening. ...
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet again, they repeat that my account was suspended because I did not pass the identity screening, despite them verifying my account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At that time, I opened a thread on UpWork’s community forum (containing same explanation). Two days later I was banned from it (without any proper answer) because ‘my UpWork account is suspended.’ A few hours later, I received two emails (ticket replies) from UpWork’s support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.ribice.ba/img/9/upwork-checking.jpg#c&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.ribice.ba/img/9/upwork-final-email.jpg#c&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn’t reply to this ticket or create a new one. I felt it was enough, even though I still didn’t know the reason my account was suspended. If someone from UpWork reads this and is not a freelancer hired by them (as was the case for every single person from support) I would like to know the real reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I assume the ToS I agreed to while signing up allows them to suspend my account for no particular reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end, I would recommend anyone to never focus and rely on a single stream of income. Imagine working hard on building UpWork (or similar site) portfolio, quitting a full-time job to go fully remote, and then getting suspended for no obvious reason.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 13:21:49 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ribice</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.ribice.ba/upwork-suspended/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>High Salaries Are Weapons in the AI Talent War</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-02-13/in-the-war-for-ai-talent-sky-high-salaries-are-the-weapons</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-02-13/in-the-war-for-ai-talent-sky-high-salaries-are-the-weapons</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lede-media-image__caption caption&quot;&gt;An attendee at SoftBank Robot World tries out the company’s Pepper humanoid robot in Tokyo on Nov. 21, 2017.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;163.87795275591&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to command a multiyear, seven-figure salary, you used to have only four career options: chief executive officer, banker, celebrity entertainer, or pro athlete. Now there’s a fifth—artificial intelligence expert. One reason: No one can quite agree on how many there are.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/GOOGL:US&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/FB:US&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/APPL:US&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/AMZN:US&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Amazon.com&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/0084207D:US&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Uber Technologies&lt;/a&gt;, and others dangle dazzling pay packages to lure top academics to work on teams developing facial recognition, digital assistants, and self-driving cars. Even newly minted Ph.D.s in machine learning and data science can make more than $300,000. Beyond the tech industry, among those betting on similar expertise tailored to their interests are banks, hedge funds, carmakers, and drug companies.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;aside class=&quot;pullquote&quot; data-align=&quot;center&quot; readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;passage&quot;&gt;“You’ve got to break the scale for at least one person”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Don’t balk at such pricey hires, Kai-Fu Lee, who previously ran Google’s business in China, told an audience of CEOs at this year’s World Economic Forum in Davos, Switzerland. “Google is paying a million dollars for these superstars,” said Lee, now a venture capitalist. “You may not need someone that high, but you’ve got to break the scale for at least one person.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Designing AI systems requires a hard-to-come-by blend of high-level mathematics and statistical understanding, a grounding in data science and computer programming, and a dose of intuition. There are widely varied estimates of exactly how shallow the talent pool is. The answer matters, because it helps companies decide whether to build their systems in-house or rely on outside vendors. It also determines how much leverage experts have in salary negotiations.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;On Feb. 7, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/1475064D:CN&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Element AI&lt;/a&gt;, a Montreal startup that helps businesses design and implement machine learning systems, published a report concluding that about 22,000 Ph.D.-level computer scientists around the world are capable of building AI systems. Of those, only about 3,000 are currently looking for a job. In contrast, at least 10,000 related positions are open in the U.S. alone, says Element CEO Jean-Francois Gagné.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These figures are well below another estimate put out in December by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/700:HK&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Tencent Holdings Ltd.&lt;/a&gt;, the Chinese internet giant. It wrote that the world has perhaps 200,000 to 300,000 “AI practitioners and researchers.” Element says Tencent counted too many coders who merely contribute to projects and lack the expertise to create novel algorithms and applications from scratch. The Montreal company, however, acknowledges that its own methodology had shortcomings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;pullquote&quot; data-align=&quot;center&quot; readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;passage&quot;&gt;Newly minted Ph.D.s in machine learning can make more than $300,000&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Element scoured LinkedIn for people whose profiles included doctorates earned since 2015, mentioned key phrases (natural language processing, computer vision), and listed among their skills the programming languages (Python, TensorFlow) that underlie most AI software. The company says this might exclude a lot of researchers in places where LinkedIn isn’t relevant or who have experience but not a fancy degree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vishal Chatrath, co-founder and CEO of Prowler.io, an automation startup in Cambridge, England, hasn’t had trouble recruiting AI developers. “Talent hires talent,” he says. The important thing, he says, is to have intriguing problems to solve and some outstanding mathematicians and technicians already on staff to stoke expert interest. An added attraction is that Chatrath and his co-founders sold their previous company, voice recognition startup VocalIQ, to Apple Inc. in 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;inline-newsletter&quot; data-state=&quot;ready&quot;/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Element has an incentive to highlight scarcity. The more companies despair of hiring their own experts, the more they’ll need vendors such as Element to do the work for them. “The talent shortage is real,” says Gagné, adding that he’s been struggling to hire even with AI pioneer Yoshua Bengio among his co-founders. Bengio, a computer scientist at the University of Montreal, is one of three men credited with helping to lead the AI boom. The other two are Yann LeCun, now at Facebook Inc., and Geoffrey Hinton, now at Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Governments and universities need to spend more money on training, Gagné says, especially at the undergraduate and master’s levels. At the current education rate, an influx of new experts will start to moderate salaries in three to four years, he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most businesses don’t want to wait that long. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/INTC:US&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Intel&lt;/a&gt;, Facebook, and Google are creating their own internal AI training programs. Google is also one of the companies experimenting with automatic machine learning, or AutoML, meaning AI that can create its own AI. The search giant recently began offering the service to cloud customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the possibility of automatic machine learning, the demand for expertise has attracted swarms of headhunters to once-staid academic confabs with names such as the Neural Information Processing Systems (NIPS) conference. To woo candidates, recruiters organize increasingly swanky private dinners and after-parties. Chris Rice, head of global talent acquisition for Intel’s AI product group, says there’s little choice but to recruit aggressively at such events. “With talent this scarce,” he said at a NIPS conference in December, “it can be hard to find people.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;bottom-line__label&quot;&gt;BOTTOM LINE -&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;bottom-line__text&quot;&gt;Research from Element AI indicates only 22,000 people around the world have the AI skills most tech companies want, but that isn’t an especially scientific estimate.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 13:07:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>angpappas</dc:creator>
<og:description>Want to command the crazy wages? Here’s what you need to bring.</og:description>
<og:image>https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iWY9QPUwOqfI/v0/1200x630.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Sky-High Salaries Are the Weapons in the AI Talent War</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-02-13/in-the-war-for-ai-talent-sky-high-salaries-are-the-weapons</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-02-13/in-the-war-for-ai-talent-sky-high-salaries-are-the-weapons</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Humble Bundle Books: Functional Programming</title>
<link>https://www.humblebundle.com/books/functional-programming-books</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.humblebundle.com/books/functional-programming-books</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More awesome tech ebooks for you.&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;span&gt;We've teamed up with O’Reilly for another bundle full of top-quality books! Get titles like&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Functional Thinking, Clojure Programming, Learning Scala&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;, and&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Programming Rust.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;Plus, your purchase will support Code for America!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pay what you want.&lt;/strong&gt; All together, these ebooks would cost over $515. Here at Humble Bundle, you choose the price and increase your contribution to upgrade your bundle! This bundle has a minimum $1 purchase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read them anywhere.&lt;/strong&gt; These books are available in PDF, ePUB, and MOBI formats, meaning you can read them anywhere at any time. Instructions and a list of recommended reading programs can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.humblebundle.com/hc/en-us/articles/202712300-How-do-I-read-the-eBook-on-my-Android-NOOK-and-iOS-devices-&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Support charity.&lt;/strong&gt; Choose where the money goes – between the creators and Code for America via the &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.humblebundle.com/hc/en-us/articles/205183597&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PayPal Giving Fund&lt;/a&gt;. If you like what we do, you can leave us a Humble Tip too!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 12:46:05 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ranit</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:title>Humble Book Bundle: Functional Programming by O'Reilly</og:title>
<og:description>Pay what you want for awesome ebooks and support charity!</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.humblebundle.com/books/functional-programming-books</og:url>
<og:image>https://humblebundle.imgix.net/misc/files/hashed/a5091e9dc2ec96bb0eab6f4aa079f99fa961b837.png?auto=compress&amp;w=1200&amp;h=630&amp;s=2d838ea3e7fda1d7f8e996f81019d1db</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.humblebundle.com/books/functional-programming-books</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>