<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>We Need to Save What Made Linux and FOSS Possible</title>
<link>https://www.linuxjournal.com/content/we-need-save-what-made-linux-and-foss-possible</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.linuxjournal.com/content/we-need-save-what-made-linux-and-foss-possible</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If we take freedom and openness for granted, we'll lose both. That's already happening, and we need to fight back. The question is how.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am haunted by this passage in a letter we got from reader Alan E. Davis (the full text is in our Letters section):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...the real reason for this letter comes from my realization—in seeking online help—that the Linux Documentation Project is dead, and that the Linuxprinting.org project—now taken over by open printing, I think, is far from functioning well. Linux has been transformed into containers, and embedded systems. These and other such projects were the heart and soul of the Free Software movement, and I do not want for them to be gone!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the kind of thing &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bradley_M._Kuhn&quot;&gt;Bradley Kuhn&lt;/a&gt; (of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://sfconservancy.org&quot;&gt;Software Freedom Conservancy&lt;/a&gt;) lamented in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PLJjAupCMUg&amp;amp;index=10&amp;amp;list=PLsYAJYM22VA2NMo61bxIXowgXXHufwPm8&amp;amp;t=0s&quot;&gt;his talk&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;https://freenode.live&quot;&gt;Freenode.live&lt;/a&gt; last year. So did &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linuxjournal.com/users/kyle-rankin&quot;&gt;Kyle Rankin&lt;/a&gt; in his talk at the same event (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=17JowhH57kg&amp;amp;list=PLsYAJYM22VA2NMo61bxIXowgXXHufwPm8&amp;amp;index=15&quot;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://kylerank.in/talks/misc/ljfoss.html&quot;&gt;slides&lt;/a&gt; and later, an &lt;em&gt;LJ&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linuxjournal.com/content/what-linux-journals-resurrection-taught-me-about-foss-community&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt;). In &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oOFuQLTVdZc&quot;&gt;an earlier conversation&lt;/a&gt; on the same stage (it was a helluva show), &lt;a href=&quot;https://webmink.com&quot;&gt;Simon Phipps&lt;/a&gt; (of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://opensource.org&quot;&gt;Open Source Initiative&lt;/a&gt;) and I had our own lamentations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all said it has become too easy to take Linux and FOSS for granted, and the risks of doing that were dire. Some specifics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We collaborate inside proprietary environments&lt;/strong&gt;, such as Slack and Google Hangouts. Most of the chat and messaging systems in use today are also proprietary and closed. So are most video-conferencing systems and the codecs they use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Many Linux and FOSS geeks today use Linux only professionally.&lt;/strong&gt; Most of their personal work is on proprietary Apple and Microsoft gear. Many use Windows or macOS boxes in presentations about FOSS topics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We're not modeling our values.&lt;/strong&gt; Bradley sourced this line from &lt;a href=&quot;https://mako.cc/writing/hill-free_tools.html&quot;&gt;Benjamin Mako Hill&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;The use of nonfree tools sends an unacceptable message...'Software freedom is important for you as users', developers seem to say, 'but not for us'. Such behavior undermines the basic effectiveness of the strong ethical commitment at the heart of the free software movement.&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We've allowed foundational ideas to collapse.&lt;/strong&gt; We've gone along with complicating the web, no longer respecting the simplicities in HTTP and HTML, which allowed the web to work in the first place. For example, we hardly still design for what Bradley calls &quot;progressive enhancement and graceful degradation&quot;. We see this failure in the web development world, which now depends almost utterly on JavaScript, most of which is proprietary and downloaded constantly on the fly to run in browsers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We are also forgetting (or perhaps never learned) how a reciprocal license, such as the GPL, can keep a project alive and a community together.&lt;/strong&gt; Simon blames SourceForge's failures on a decision to replace its original free (GPL-licensed) software base with a proprietary one. And now, even though we have Git, he says too many of us don't know the difference between Git and GitHub, or that GitHub runs proprietary JavaScript executed in our browsers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;There were signs this was coming in 2002, when I wrote &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linuxjournal.com/article/5912&quot;&gt;&quot;A Tale of Three Cultures&quot;&lt;/a&gt;. I'll unpack those a bit:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geeks&lt;/strong&gt; at the time were busy inventing the world's basic software building materials. They operated in a culture that valued freedom, openness and maximized usefulness to everybody and everything. They also had a strong sense that they were winning the fight for freedom and openness in software development and product design. In geek slang, they said they were at &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://catb.org/jargon/html/G/GandhiCon.html&quot;&gt;GandhiCon&lt;/a&gt; 3&quot;. (The context is a Mohandas Gandhi one-liner: &quot;First they ignore you. Then they laugh at you. Then they fight you. Then you win.&quot;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hollywood&lt;/strong&gt; as a label stood for all that is proprietary about business. I chose that label because the biggest public fight at the time was over copyright, and Hollywood was (and remains) the embodiment of copyright maximalism. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lawrence_Lessig&quot;&gt;Larry Lessig&lt;/a&gt;, who with &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aaron_Swartz&quot;&gt;Aaron Swartz&lt;/a&gt; and others had recently minted &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creative_Commons&quot;&gt;Creative Commons&lt;/a&gt;, characterized the fight as Silicon Valley vs. Hollywood, and Northern vs. Southern California.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Embedded developers&lt;/strong&gt; were what I called &quot;purely technical...pre-Net, pre-UNIX and maybe even pre-cultural&quot;, with concerns that were &quot;utterly practical&quot;. In other words, &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; about free software, open source or Linux—beyond its utilitarian value. I wrote that after attending the Embedded Systems Conference that Rich Lehrbaum wrote about for &lt;em&gt;Linux Journal&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linuxjournal.com/article/5969&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. (That may be the only surviving record of the conference on the web.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;What I didn't see back then was that Hollywood andembedded would become pretty much the same thing: business as usual. That happened because it was too easy for too many developers to build proprietary and closed stuff, heads down, in utterly practical ways, usually for what amounted to embedded purposes, on top of Linux and FOSS foundations, with little respect for the virtues embodied in those foundations. And by now, we've built a lot of it. One might even argue that most of the Linux deployed in the world today is embedded inside proprietary and closed devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the question is &lt;em&gt;What should we do now?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From my notes, here are some things Bradley, Kyle, Simon and others said at Freenode.live. It's not all verbatim, but close enough:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&quot;Having real-time chat is absolutely essential to the advancement of free software.&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;We're the resistance now.&quot; &quot;We need to create mass movement.&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;Volunteer to write free and open code, to participate in communities.&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;If you didn't live the history, learn from those who did.&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;If you did learn from history, teach those who need to know it. Respectfully.&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;Be patient. Remember that the tortoise won not only because it was patient, but because it ignored insult, ridicule and dismissal.&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;Model your values. Use free software and hardware.&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;Remember always how 'the rights to copy, share, modify, redistribute and improve software' are fundamental rights that matter to people.&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;Work to convince developers that their software freedom matters.&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;That's all necessary, but not sufficient. We need something more. Something big.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suggest we pick a fight. Because fights raise emotions and have goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just ran a playoff between many different fights on many tabs in a browser. The winner—the last tab standing—is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nextplatform.com/2019/02/05/the-era-of-general-purpose-computers-is-ending&quot;&gt;&quot;The Era of General Purpose Computers Is Ending&quot;&lt;/a&gt;, by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nextplatform.com/author/michael&quot;&gt;Michael Feldman&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nextplatform.com&quot;&gt;The Next Platform website&lt;/a&gt;. It's a sad bookend to the history of a losing fight that &lt;a href=&quot;https://craphound.com&quot;&gt;Cory Doctorow&lt;/a&gt; forecast in 2011 with &lt;a href=&quot;https://boingboing.net/2012/01/10/lockdown.html&quot;&gt;&quot;Lockdown: the coming war on general-purpose computing&quot;&lt;/a&gt; and a year later in &lt;a href=&quot;https://boingboing.net/2012/08/23/civilwar.html&quot;&gt;&quot;The Coming Civil War over General Purpose Computing&quot;&lt;/a&gt;. Read all three.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I chose general-purpose computing as the winning fight—the one most worth having—because we wouldn't have Linux, free software or open source today if there weren't general-purpose computers to develop and use them on. General-purpose computing is the goose that laid all our golden eggs. The fight is to keep it alive.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 19:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>brewski</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.linuxjournal.com/content/we-need-save-what-made-linux-and-foss-possible</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Alpine Linux Docker images have NULL for root password</title>
<link>https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2019-5021</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2019-5021</guid>
<description>&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;CVE-ID&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.232044198895&quot;&gt;&lt;td nowrap=&quot;nowrap&quot; align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;CVE-2019-5021&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;ltgreybackground&quot; readability=&quot;4.1676646706587&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• CVSS Severity Rating • Fix Information • Vulnerable Software Versions • SCAP Mappings • CPE Information&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;Versions of the Official Alpine Linux Docker images (since v3.3) contain a NULL password for the `root` user. This vulnerability appears to be the result of a regression introduced in December of 2015. Due to the nature of this issue, systems deployed using affected versions of the Alpine Linux container which utilize Linux PAM, or some other mechanism which uses the system shadow file as an authentication database, may accept a NULL password for the `root` user.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;References&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.7986577181208&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; class=&quot;note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://cve.mitre.org/data/refs/index.html&quot;&gt;References&lt;/a&gt; are provided for the convenience of the reader to help distinguish between vulnerabilities. The list is not intended to be complete.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;Assigning CNA&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;Talos&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;Date Entry Created&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.3795918367347&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20190104&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;ltgreybackground&quot;&gt;Disclaimer: The &lt;a href=&quot;https://cve.mitre.org/about/faqs.html#date_entry_created_in_cve_entry&quot;&gt;entry creation date&lt;/a&gt; may reflect when the CVE ID was allocated or reserved, and does not necessarily indicate when this vulnerability was discovered, shared with the affected vendor, publicly disclosed, or updated in CVE.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;Phase (Legacy)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;Assigned (20190104)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;Votes (Legacy)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;Comments (Legacy)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;Proposed (Legacy)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;N/A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.7264957264957&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;3&quot; class=&quot;note&quot;&gt;This is an entry on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://cve.mitre.org/cve/&quot;&gt;CVE List&lt;/a&gt;, which provides common identifiers for publicly known cybersecurity vulnerabilities.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;1.6129032258065&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; class=&quot;search&quot; readability=&quot;4.0322580645161&quot;&gt;


&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;1.3157894736842&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; class=&quot;search&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;For More Information:&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:cve@mitre.org&quot;&gt;cve@mitre.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 18:45:29 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>alpb</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2019-5021</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Google Fights Back</title>
<link>https://stratechery.com/2019/google-fights-back/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://stratechery.com/2019/google-fights-back/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;For a company famed for its engineering culture, you wouldn’t expect a video at Google’s annual I/O developer conference to have such emotional resonance. And yet, just watch (I have included the context around the video in question, which starts at the 2:33 mark):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I liked that very much.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Screen-Shot-2019-05-08-at-9.45.21-PM.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Screen-Shot-2019-05-08-at-9.45.21-PM-1024x572.png&quot; alt=&quot;&amp;quot;I liked that very much&amp;quot;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;358&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-4196&quot; srcset=&quot;https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Screen-Shot-2019-05-08-at-9.45.21-PM-1024x572.png 1024w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Screen-Shot-2019-05-08-at-9.45.21-PM-300x168.png 300w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Screen-Shot-2019-05-08-at-9.45.21-PM-768x429.png 768w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Screen-Shot-2019-05-08-at-9.45.21-PM-1128x630.png 1128w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Screen-Shot-2019-05-08-at-9.45.21-PM.png 1300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the most direct statement of what was a clear theme from Google’s entire keynote:&lt;br/&gt;“Technology, particularly Google’s technology, is a good thing, and we are going to remind you why you like it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Google’s Mission&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As he opened &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lyRPyRKHO8M&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&quot;&gt;the keynote&lt;/a&gt;, CEO Sundar Pichai, as he always does, repeated Google’s mission statements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/GoogleIO1.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/GoogleIO1-1024x573.png&quot; alt=&quot;Google's Mission&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;358&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-4191&quot; srcset=&quot;https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/GoogleIO1-1024x573.png 1024w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/GoogleIO1-300x168.png 300w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/GoogleIO1-768x430.png 768w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/GoogleIO1-1125x630.png 1125w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/GoogleIO1.png 1300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It all begins with our mission to organize the world’s information and make it universally accessible and useful, and today, our mission feels as relevant as ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pichai, though, quickly pivoted to something rather different than simply organizing and presenting information:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way we approach it is constantly evolving. We are moving from a company that helps you find answers to a company that helps you get things done…We want our products to work harder for you in the context of your job, your home, and your life, and they all share a single goal: to be helpful, so we can be there for you in moments big and small over the course of your day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, the mission statement may be the same, but what that means for Google and its products has shifted:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/GoogleIO2.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/GoogleIO2-1024x578.png&quot; alt=&quot;Google's goal&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;361&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-4192&quot; srcset=&quot;https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/GoogleIO2-1024x578.png 1024w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/GoogleIO2-300x169.png 300w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/GoogleIO2-768x434.png 768w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/GoogleIO2-1116x630.png 1116w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/GoogleIO2.png 1300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our goal is to build a more helpful Google for everyone. And when we say helpful, we mean giving you the tools to increase your knowledge, success, health, and happiness. We feel so privileged to be developing products for billions of users, and with that scale comes a deep sense of responsibility to create things that improve people’s lives. By focusing on these fundamental attributes, we can empower individuals and benefit society as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This set the stage for the rest of the keynote, including the video above: Google spent most of the keynote demonstrating — both with actual products, and whole bunch of vaporware — how Google could take a much more proactive role in its users’ lives in ways they ought appreciate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Google’s Data Collection&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be sure, not all of the demos were of unassailably positive use cases like helping an illiterate person navigate the world; take, for example, this demonstration of Duplex for the Web:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the caveat that this is one of the pieces of vaporware I referenced earlier (Duplex, it should be noted, did finally launch several months after last year’s Google I/O), the demonstration is very impressive. What is worth noting, though, is the degree to which the demo relies on Google’s having access to your data; to that end, perhaps the most striking takeaway is that Google didn’t bother hiding this fact:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/GoogleIO4.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/GoogleIO4-1024x577.png&quot; alt=&quot;Duplex on Web uses your data&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;361&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-4194&quot; srcset=&quot;https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/GoogleIO4-1024x577.png 1024w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/GoogleIO4-300x169.png 300w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/GoogleIO4-768x432.png 768w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/GoogleIO4-1119x630.png 1119w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/GoogleIO4.png 1300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The implicit message was clear: “Yes, we have all of your data, but the fact we have all of your data is a good thing, because it allows us to make your life easier.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice that Aparna Chennapragada, the Vice President of Google’s AR, VR, and Vision-based Products whose video I opened with, makes the same point:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What you are seeing here is text-to-speech, computer vision, the power of translate, and 20 years of language understanding from search, all coming together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To put it more succinctly: “Yes, we collect a lot of data. But that data makes amazing things possible.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Google’s Strategy Credits&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was one more thing Chennapragada said at the end of her presentation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The power to read is the power to buy a train ticket, to shop in a store, to follow the news. It’s the power to get things done, so we want to make this feature accessible to as many people as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is another feather in Google’s cap: it really does serve everyone in the way a company like Apple does not. Pichai made this point as well:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, we have talked about building a more helpful Google. It is equally important to us it for everyone. “For everyone” is a core philosophy for us at Google. That’s why from the earliest days Search works the same whether you’re a professor at Stanford or a student in rural Indonesia. It’s why we build affordable laptops for classrooms everywhere. And it’s why we care about the experience on low-cost phones in countries where users are just starting to come on-line, with the same passion as we do with premium phones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What was unmentioned is that this is very much a &lt;a href=&quot;https://stratechery.com/2013/strategy-credit/&quot;&gt;Strategy Credit&lt;/a&gt;. Google spends billions of dollars on research and development and global-scaling infrastructure in order to deliver superior products to, first and foremost, users on premium phones (who have a huge amount of overlap with the set of customers most attractive to advertisers). That expenditure, though, is a fixed cost, while serving a marginal user is effectively free; it follows, then, that the best way to leverage those costs is to serve as many people as possible, even if the revenue from doing so is quite meager, at least for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be clear, to say that something is a Strategy Credit is not a bad thing: it is simply an observation that doing the “right thing” requires no trade-offs when it comes to a company’s core business model; I originally created the term to explain why Apple could commit to not collecting data in a way that a company like Google could not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even so, it is striking how Google leaned into its core business model during the keynote: while Facebook likes to talk about connecting everyone, the company mostly tries to &lt;a href=&quot;https://stratechery.com/2019/facebooks-privacy-cake/&quot;&gt;have its privacy cake and eat it too&lt;/a&gt;, that is, talk a lot about privacy and major moves it claims it is making in that direction, while actually changing nothing about its core business (or acknowledging that those moves are for &lt;a href=&quot;https://stratechery.com/2019/microsoft-and-slack-follow-up-f8-facebook-versus-snapchat/&quot;&gt;competitive reasons&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google, on the other hand, didn’t just admit it collects data, it highlighted how that collection makes Google more helpful. Google didn’t just admit that its goal is to be the Aggregator of information for every customer on earth, it bragged about that fact. And Google certainly didn’t engage in any self-effacing comments about how technology could be used for both good and bad: the entire keynote was arguing that technology is not only good, it is going to get better, and Google will lead the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Google’s Opportunities&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There should be, to be sure, concerns about Google believing their own hype: many of &lt;a href=&quot;https://stratechery.com/2019/youtube-and-toxic-videos-youtubes-problematic-incentives-sins-of-omission-and-commission/&quot;&gt;the problems with YouTube&lt;/a&gt;, for example, stem from &lt;a href=&quot;https://stratechery.com/2017/the-pollyannish-assumption/&quot;&gt;The Pollyannish Assumption&lt;/a&gt; that treats technology as an inherent good instead of an &lt;a href=&quot;https://stratechery.com/2013/friction/&quot;&gt;amoral force&lt;/a&gt; that makes everything — both positive outcomes and negative ones — easier and more efficient to achieve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, from a purely strategic perspective, the positive message makes sense. Presuming that everything about technology is bad is just as mistaken as the opposite perspective, and the fact of the matter is that lots of people like Google products, and reminding them of that fact is to Google’s long-term benefit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, a world of assistants and machine-learning based products is very much to Google’s advantage: the argument to not simply tolerate Google’s collection of data, but to actually give them more, is less about some lame case about better-targeted ads but about making actually useful products better. The better-targeted ads are a Strategy Credit!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It certainly appears that Google is pressing its advantage: after several years of including iPhones in Google I/O demos and/or alluding to products coming out on iOS — a welcome correction to &lt;a href=&quot;https://stratechery.com/2013/the-android-detour/&quot;&gt;The Android Detour&lt;/a&gt; — the only mention of iPhones was in a camera comparison to Google’s Pixel phone.&lt;a href=&quot;https://stratechery.com/2019/google-fights-back/#footnote_0_4189&quot; id=&quot;identifier_0_4189&quot; class=&quot;footnote-link footnote-identifier-link&quot; title=&quot;It was pretty lame that Google used an iPhone X instead of an iPhone XS for the comparison, though&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt; Notably, Pixel’s headline feature — its camera — is very Google-like; Sabrina Ellis, Vice Product of Product Management, said while introducing the $399 Pixel 3a:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Delivering premium features with high performance on a phone at this price point has been a huge engineering challenge, and I’m really proud of what our team has been able to accomplish with Pixel 3a…What Pixel is really known for is its incredible camera. With software optimizations we found a way to bring our exclusive camera features and our industry-leading image quality into Pixel 3a. So photos look stunning in any light. What other smartphone cameras try to do with expensive hardware, we can deliver with software and AI, including high-end computational photography.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While phones are certainly not a zero marginal cost item, the point is that Google applies overwhelming computer resources that can be leveraged through software instead of premium hardware, lowering the price of a phone, thus allowing it to be sold more broadly (better leveraging Google’s investment).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Google’s Challenges&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, while many of today’s trends are in Google’s favor, the Pixel is a reminder that the company still has significant challenges: Google has struggled to sell Pixels not because it hasn’t invested in a quality phone, but because it hasn’t invested in marketing and distribution. To that end, what was even more notable than the Pixel 3a price point is the fact it will be available on more than one U.S. carrier for the first time; unfortunately for Google, that is only one country, and there remain the massive investments in marketing necessary to become a major smartphone player.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More importantly, while Google Assistant continues to impress — putting everything on device promises a major breakthrough in speed, a major limiting factor for Assistants today — it is not at all clear what Google’s business model is. It is hard to imagine anything as profitable as search ads, which benefit not only from precise targeting — the user explicitly says what they want! — but also an auction format that leverages the user to pick winners, and incentivizes those winners to overpay for the chance of forming an ongoing relationship with that user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, this was both the promise and pitfall of Google’s overall presentation: organizing the world’s information was (relatively) easy when that information was widely available, and it was easy to monetize. Everything was aligned. The future, though, is a lot messier: getting information is more difficult, presenting that information is more challenging, and making money is very much an open question. Just because Google is better positioned in this race than anyone else doesn’t matter quite as much when the race is harder, even as the prize is less lucrative, while an increasing number of spectators are cheering for failure. Might as well bring cheerleaders!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;li id=&quot;footnote_0_4189&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;It was pretty lame that Google used an iPhone X instead of an iPhone XS for the comparison, though [&lt;a href=&quot;https://stratechery.com/2019/google-fights-back/#identifier_0_4189&quot; class=&quot;footnote-link footnote-back-link&quot;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 15:57:35 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>denzil_correa</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Google Fights Back</og:title>
<og:url>https://stratechery.com/2019/google-fights-back/</og:url>
<og:description>At Google I/O, Google was the opposite of defensive: the company set out to make the case that its approach made for better products that makes people’s lives better</og:description>
<og:image>https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Screen-Shot-2019-05-08-at-9.45.21-PM.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://stratechery.com/2019/google-fights-back/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Estimating Number of Jupyter Notebooks on Github</title>
<link>https://kyso.io/KyleOS/nbestimate</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://kyso.io/KyleOS/nbestimate</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://kyso.io/KyleOS/nbestimate&quot;&gt;https://kyso.io/KyleOS/nbestimate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19859484&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19859484&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 221&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 114&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 15:04:06 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>eoinmurray92</dc:creator>
<og:title>Estimating Number of Jupyter Notebooks on Github</og:title>
<og:image>https://d1kser01wv8mbw.cloudfront.net/390e08d1938fbff5ffc670d2cacae5c8_file-0N33S2ivMP-preview.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Using fbprophet to predict the number of public Jupyter Notebooks on Github for the next 2 years.</og:description>
<og:url>https://kyso.io/KyleOS/nbestimate</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://kyso.io/KyleOS/nbestimate</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Britain passes one week without coal power for first time since 1882</title>
<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2019/may/08/britain-passes-1-week-without-coal-power-for-first-time-since-1882</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2019/may/08/britain-passes-1-week-without-coal-power-for-first-time-since-1882</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Britain has gone a week without using coal to generate electricity for the first time since Queen Victoria was on the throne, in a landmark moment in the transition away from the heavily polluting fuel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last coal generator came off the system at 1.24pm on 1 May, meaning the UK reached a week without coal at 1.24pm on Wednesday, according to the National Grid Electricity System Operator, which runs the network in England, Scotland and Wales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coal-fired power stations still play a major part in the UK’s energy system as a backup during high demand but the increasing use of renewable energy sources such as wind power means it is required less. High international coal prices have also made the fuel a less attractive source of energy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The latest achievement – the first coal-free week since 1882, when a plant opened at Holborn in London – comes only two years after Britain’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2017/apr/21/britain-set-for-first-coal-free-day-since-the-industrial-revolution&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;first coal-free day&lt;/a&gt; since the Industrial Revolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Burning coal to generate electricity is thought to be incompatible with avoiding catastrophic climate change, and the UK government has committed to phasing out coal-fired power by 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reductions in coal use in the UK have been responsible for halving electricity generation emissionssince 2013, according to the Committee on Climate Change (CCC), whose report last week called for the UK to pursue a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2019/may/02/do-it-now-uk-must-set-zero-carbon-target-for-2050-say-official-advisers&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;target of net-zero carbon emissions by 2050&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fintan Slye, the director of National Grid ESO, said he believed Britain’s electricity system could be run with zero carbon as soon as 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He said: “Zero-carbon operation of the electricity system by 2025 means a fundamental change to how our system was designed to operate – integrating newer technologies right across the system – from large-scale offshore wind to domestic-scale solar panels to increased demand-side participation, using new smart digital systems to manage and control the system in real-time.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greg Clark, the business secretary, hailed the achievement. He said the UK is “on a path to become the first major economy to legislate for net-zero emissions” in the wake of the report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the government has also faced criticism over some of its policies. The CCC’s chief executive, Chris Stark, said on Wednesday that proposals to impose higher VAT on solar panels and its failure to give its full backing to onshore wind generation would make meeting a net-zero emissions target more difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We will need to throw everything at this challenge, including onshore wind and solar,” Stark told MPs on the business committee. “Anything that makes it harder is really not in line with the net-zero challenge overall.”&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 13:46:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>andyjohnson0</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://www.theguardian.com/environment/2019/may/08/britain-passes-1-week-without-coal-power-for-first-time-since-1882</og:url>
<og:description>Landmark follows government pledge to phase out electricity from coal by 2025</og:description>
<og:image>https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/33617f6dfd312c598e8ed693d573ad3607c7b63e/0_365_5472_3283/master/5472.jpg?width=1200&amp;height=630&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;overlay-align=bottom%2Cleft&amp;overlay-width=100p&amp;overlay-base64=L2ltZy9zdGF0aWMvb3ZlcmxheXMvdGctZGVmYXVsdC5wbmc&amp;s=753ae17410d5f045d5a323d4edbf048d</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Britain passes one week without coal power for first time since 1882</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2019/may/08/britain-passes-1-week-without-coal-power-for-first-time-since-1882</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>CBS censors a ‘Good Fight’ segment whose topic was Chinese censorship</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/05/07/arts/television/cbs-good-fight-chinese-censorship.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2019/05/07/arts/television/cbs-good-fight-chinese-censorship.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Midway through the most recent episode of “The Good Fight,” a legal drama that &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/05/03/opinion/the-good-fight-trump.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;deals with Trump-era politics&lt;/a&gt;, a scene depicting a confrontation between lawyers and their clients abruptly stops. Shortly after, for about eight seconds, a black screen flashes the words, “CBS HAS CENSORED THIS CONTENT.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Some viewers saw the message as satire, just part of the show’s irreverent approach to current events, Michelle King, one of the showrunners, said in an interview on Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Others, Ms. King said, took it as the producers had intended: literally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The show, which runs on the CBS All Access streaming channel, and is a spinoff of “The Good Wife,” often breaks from its plot for an animated musical short that digs into controversial political issues of the day with an explanatory style similar to “Schoolhouse Rock!” A theme of last Thursday’s episode was American companies that want to do business in China and the pressures they face to appease Chinese government censors. An animated short was created on that same theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;But the short was pulled from the show at the request of CBS about two weeks before it was scheduled to stream, said Ms. King, who created the show with her husband, Robert King.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Jonathan Coulton, the songwriter who makes the shorts, said in an interview that this particular video started with the fact that “The Good Wife” had been banned in China, most likely because of an episode that showed a Chinese dissident character being tortured. (The spinoff “The Good Fight” has not been banned.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Coulton said the animated short included a host of references to topics that have been censored on the internet in China. Those include Falun Gong, a spiritual movement that is repressed by the Chinese government; Tiananmen Square, a reference to the violent crackdown on pro-democracy demonstrators in 1989; &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/07/17/world/asia/china-winnie-the-pooh-censored.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Winnie-the-Pooh&lt;/a&gt;, to whom China’s president, Xi Jinping, is often compared; &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/02/28/world/asia/china-censorship-xi-jinping.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;and the letter N,&lt;/a&gt; used by critics of the recent change to the Chinese Constitution that lets Mr. Xi stay in power indefinitely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“It was a little bit like poking the bear,” Mr. Coulton said. “They had gotten approval all along, and at the last minute, a couple of weeks before, they got word that they couldn’t put it in the show.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-79elbk&quot; data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-wrapper&quot;&gt;

&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-children&quot; class=&quot;css-1a48zt4 ehw59r15&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1xdhyk6 erfvjey0&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;css-1m50asq&quot; src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/05/07/arts/07goodfight2/07goodfight2-articleLarge.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;disable=upscale&quot; srcset=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/05/07/arts/07goodfight2/07goodfight2-articleLarge.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 600w,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/05/07/arts/07goodfight2/07goodfight2-jumbo.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 808w,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/05/07/arts/07goodfight2/07goodfight2-superJumbo.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 808w&quot; sizes=&quot;((min-width: 600px) and (max-width: 1004px)) 84vw, (min-width: 1005px) 60vw, 100vw&quot; itemprop=&quot;url&quot; itemid=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/05/07/arts/07goodfight2/07goodfight2-articleLarge.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;disable=upscale&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;The image that appeared just before the censorship message. “The Good Fight” is known for its humorous animated segments.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e1z0qqy90&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;CBS All Access&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In a statement, CBS All Access said: “We had concerns with some subject matter in the episode’s animated short. This is the creative solution that we agreed upon with the producers.” A spokeswoman declined to comment further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/culture-desk/cbs-censors-the-good-fight-for-a-musical-short-about-china&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The New Yorker&lt;/a&gt; first reported the details of CBS’s decision to censor the animated short.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Ms. King said she and her husband were taken aback by what they called CBS’s “highly unusual” decision, because of how much controversial material the network normally allows in the show and its musical shorts. The shorts have previously delivered tutorials &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.cbs.com/shows/the-good-fight/video/9yVkPQaORId0RGVQR2vF_y0QN82EpCbG/the-good-fight-short-cartoon-nazi-frog/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;on neo-Nazi frog memes&lt;/a&gt;, Russian troll farms and how Congress could impeach President Trump.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Ms. King said that she and her husband initially told CBS that they would quit the show if the song was pulled but that they eventually agreed on inserting a message saying that the company had censored it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“We love the show, and we love the cast,” she said, “One doesn’t want to walk away from something that is so creatively fulfilling.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Coulton said that he was told that CBS had concerns for the safety of its employees in China if the segment were included. CBS also has a Chinese audience, and when releasing content that is critical of China, American entertainment companies often have to weigh the risk of having their shows or movies blocked in the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Just before the censorship message, in fact, the show’s characters discuss a fictional tech company’s decision to appease Chinese censors. The company, called ChumHum, is engaged in a secret project to build a “customized” search engine for China. (Google was said last year &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/08/01/technology/china-google-censored-search-engine.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;to be considering such a product&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“Customized? As in it allows China to censor its content?” one of the characters says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;A ChumHum executive responds: “We don’t like to call it censoring. It just obeys the laws of the land.” Seconds afterward, the show cut to its brief “censored” message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Coulton said he bore no ill will toward CBS, understanding that as a large multinational corporation, it had some “tough choices to make.” Still, the whole situation is the “definition of irony,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“The song ends with me saying, ‘I hope this song is banned in China,’ ” Mr. Coulton said. “Now it’ll never get the chance.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 13:10:01 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>leavjenn</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/05/07/arts/television/cbs-good-fight-chinese-censorship.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>CBS Censors a ‘Good Fight’ Segment. Its Topic Was Chinese Censorship.</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/05/08/arts/07goodfight/07goodfight-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>The show often includes humorous animated videos on current topics. One video that criticized China’s war on free speech was removed at the network’s request.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/05/07/arts/television/cbs-good-fight-chinese-censorship.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: CSSFX – Click-to-copy CSS effects</title>
<link>https://cssfx.dev/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://cssfx.dev/</guid>
<description>&lt;nav data-v-07a7291c=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cssfx.dev/_nuxt/img/2337d4b.svg&quot; alt=&quot;cssfx&quot; class=&quot;logo&quot; data-v-07a7291c=&quot;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/nav&gt;&lt;header data-v-d816f126=&quot;&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p data-v-d816f126=&quot;&quot;&gt;A carefully crafted collection designed with a focus on fluidity, simplicity, and ease of use. Powered by CSS with minimal markup. Completely open source and MIT licensed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/header&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;container&quot; data-v-3345a1a4=&quot;&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid&quot; data-v-3345a1a4=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;button data-v-1ec90567=&quot;&quot; data-v-3345a1a4=&quot;&quot;&gt;Bubble&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;button data-v-aab6e864=&quot;&quot; data-v-3345a1a4=&quot;&quot;&gt;Bubble&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;button data-v-15007f13=&quot;&quot; data-v-3345a1a4=&quot;&quot;&gt;Bubble&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;button data-v-0fefa2cc=&quot;&quot; data-v-3345a1a4=&quot;&quot;&gt;Bubble&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;button data-v-d21a648e=&quot;&quot; data-v-3345a1a4=&quot;&quot;&gt;Bubble&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;button data-v-1f0b7430=&quot;&quot; data-v-3345a1a4=&quot;&quot;&gt;Jelly&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;button data-v-143226e8=&quot;&quot; data-v-3345a1a4=&quot;&quot;&gt;Pulse&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;button data-v-7af042da=&quot;&quot; data-v-3345a1a4=&quot;&quot;&gt;Shine&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;button data-v-40573c8a=&quot;&quot; data-v-3345a1a4=&quot;&quot;&gt;Slide&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;button data-v-c9f431ca=&quot;&quot; data-v-3345a1a4=&quot;&quot;&gt;Slide&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;button data-v-573154d4=&quot;&quot; data-v-3345a1a4=&quot;&quot;&gt;Slide&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;button data-v-1e316af2=&quot;&quot; data-v-3345a1a4=&quot;&quot;&gt;Slide&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-v-5c4b9bbf=&quot;&quot; data-v-3345a1a4=&quot;&quot;&gt;Bars&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-v-055e5054=&quot;&quot; data-v-3345a1a4=&quot;&quot;&gt;Bars&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-v-600581f3=&quot;&quot; data-v-3345a1a4=&quot;&quot;&gt;Bars&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-v-248421dd=&quot;&quot; data-v-3345a1a4=&quot;&quot;&gt;Highlight&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-v-55c55940=&quot;&quot; data-v-3345a1a4=&quot;&quot;&gt;Highlight&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-v-d81f296a=&quot;&quot; data-v-3345a1a4=&quot;&quot;&gt;Overline&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-v-3beb007f=&quot;&quot; data-v-3345a1a4=&quot;&quot;&gt;Overline&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-v-5fef28b5=&quot;&quot; data-v-3345a1a4=&quot;&quot;&gt;Pillars&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-v-71ff63f0=&quot;&quot; data-v-3345a1a4=&quot;&quot;&gt;Pillars&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-v-d91b4d34=&quot;&quot; data-v-3345a1a4=&quot;&quot;&gt;Pillars&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-v-ce45ee88=&quot;&quot; data-v-3345a1a4=&quot;&quot;&gt;Strikethrough&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-v-7dca515c=&quot;&quot; data-v-3345a1a4=&quot;&quot;&gt;Underline&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-v-123704b5=&quot;&quot; data-v-3345a1a4=&quot;&quot;&gt;Underline&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-v-28e5acc5=&quot;&quot; data-v-3345a1a4=&quot;&quot;&gt;Underline&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



















&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 12:04:12 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jolaleye</dc:creator>
<og:title>CSSFX - Beautifully simple click-to-copy CSS effects</og:title>
<og:description>Browse a carefully crafted collection of loaders, hover effects, transitions, and other CSS effects to use in your next project. Effects are designed with an emphasis on fluidity, simplicity, and ease of use.</og:description>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://cssfx.dev</og:url>
<og:image>http://cssfx.dev/static/logo.png</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://cssfx.dev/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>HTTP headers for the responsible developer</title>
<link>https://www.twilio.com/blog/a-http-headers-for-the-responsible-developer</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.twilio.com/blog/a-http-headers-for-the-responsible-developer</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;rich-text&quot; readability=&quot;61.983870967742&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article is a written version of the talk “HTTP headers for the responsible developer”. You can check&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://speakerdeck.com/stefanjudis/http-headers-for-the-responsible-developer&quot;&gt;the slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; or&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1jD7dBsg_Nw&amp;amp;list=PLPcgQFk9n9y_kZkCkvGhVhUnwhfypNoeI&amp;amp;index=5&quot;&gt;the recording&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Being online is the default state for many people these days. We all spend our time shopping, chatting, reading articles, and looking for information like directions. The web connects us with the whole world, but most certainly the web connects people. I myself have been using the web now for 20 years, and my relationship to it changed eight years ago when I became a web developer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Developers connect people.&lt;br/&gt;Developers help people.&lt;br/&gt;Developers enable people.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developers have the power to build the web for everyone, but that power needs to be used responsibly. What matters, in the end, is building things that help and enable people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, I want to share how HTTP headers can help you build better products for a better web for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;HTTP – HyperText Transfer Protocol&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s talk about HTTP first. HTTP is the protocol used by computers to request and send data over the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a browser requests a resource from a server it uses HTTP. This request includes a set of key-value pairs giving information like the version of the browser or what file formats it understands. These key-value pairs are called &lt;strong&gt;request headers&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The server answers with the requested resource but also sends &lt;strong&gt;response headers&lt;/strong&gt; giving information on the resource or the server itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;markdown&quot; readability=&quot;11.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;codehilite&quot; readability=&quot;18&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;twlo-code&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Request&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;GET&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;https&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;://&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;the&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;responsible&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;dev&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Accept&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;text&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sr&quot;&gt;/html,application/xhtml+xml,application/x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ml&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Accept&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Encoding&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;gzip&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;deflate&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;br&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Accept&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Language&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;en&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;GB&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;en&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;US&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;q&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mf&quot;&gt;0.9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;en&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;q&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mf&quot;&gt;0.8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;de&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;q&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mf&quot;&gt;0.7&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;...&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Response&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Connection&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;keep&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;alive&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Content&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Type&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;text&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;html&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;charset&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;utf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Date&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Mon&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;11&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Mar&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2019&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;12&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;59&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;38&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;GMT&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;...&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Response&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Body&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;rich-text&quot; readability=&quot;67.624140565317&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HTTP is the foundation of the web today and it offers many ways to improve user experience. Let's dive into how you can use HTTP headers to build a web that is &lt;strong&gt;safe, affordable and respectful.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The web has to be safe&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I never used to feel unsafe while browsing the internet. The more I learned about the web, the more concerned I became though. You can read about &lt;a href=&quot;https://shoptalkshow.com/episodes/special-one-one-hacker/&quot;&gt;hackers potentially changing global CDN-hosted libraries&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://thenextweb.com/contributors/2018/03/10/protect-website-cryptojacking-attacks/&quot;&gt;random websites mining cryptocurrency in the browser of their visitors&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.npmjs.org/post/180565383195/details-about-the-event-stream-incident&quot;&gt;people social engineering their way into successful open source projects regularly&lt;/a&gt;. That’s not good, but why should you care?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re building for the web today, it is not only you writing the code. Web development these days includes lots of people working on the same site. You are probably shipping lots of open source code, too. Additionally, you may include several third-party scripts for marketing purposes. Hundreds of people provide the code running on your site. Developers have to deal with this reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Should you trust all these people and all their source code?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t think you can trust any third party code out there. Luckily, there are ways to secure your site and make it safer. Additionally, tools like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.twilio.com/blog/securing-your-express-app-html&quot;&gt;helmet can be helpful to secure e.g. your express application&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you want to analyze how much 3rd party code runs on your website, you can have a look at the network panel of your developer tools of choice or can give&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://requestmap.webperf.tools/&quot;&gt;Request Map Generator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; a try.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;HTTPS and HSTS – make sure your connection is safe&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A secure connection is the foundation of a safe internet. Without encrypted &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/web/fundamentals/security/encrypt-in-transit/why-https&quot;&gt;requests running over&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/web/fundamentals/security/encrypt-in-transit/why-https&quot;&gt;HTTPS&lt;/a&gt;, you cannot be sure that there is no one in between your site and your visitors. A person can quickly spin up a public wifi network and perform &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.troyhunt.com/the-beginners-guide-to-breaking-website/&quot;&gt;a&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.troyhunt.com/the-beginners-guide-to-breaking-website/&quot;&gt;man in the middle attack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.troyhunt.com/the-beginners-guide-to-breaking-website/&quot;&gt; against anyone who connects&lt;/a&gt;. How often do you use public wifi? And moreover, how often do you check if it’s trustworthy?        &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, &lt;a href=&quot;https://letsencrypt.org/&quot;&gt;TLS certificates are free today&lt;/a&gt;; HTTPS has become a standard and browser vendors allow cutting-edge features only over secure connections and even mark non-HTTPS websites as unsafe, which drives HTTPS adoption. Unfortunately, we’re not browsing safe all the time. When someone wants to open a website they are not entering the protocol into the address bar (and why should they?). This action leads to an unencrypted HTTP request. Securely running sites then redirect to HTTPS. But what if someone intercepts the first unsecured request?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTTP/Headers/Strict-Transport-Security&quot;&gt;HSTS&lt;/a&gt; response headers (HTTP Strict Transport Security) to tell browsers that your site only works via HTTPS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;markdown&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;codehilite&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;twlo-code&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;Strict-Transport-Security&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;max-age&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;1000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;includeSubDomains&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;preload&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;rich-text&quot; readability=&quot;59.564330543933&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This header tells the browser that you don’t want to use HTTP requests, and it will automatically make the following requests to the same origin with a secured connection. When you try to access the same URL via HTTP again browsers will use HTTPS and redirect internally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can configure how long this setting should be active (&lt;code&gt;max-age&lt;/code&gt; in seconds) for the case that you might want to use HTTP again. If you want to include subdomains you can configure that using &lt;code&gt;includeSubDomains&lt;/code&gt; too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to go the extra mile and want to ensure a browser will never request your site over HTTP, you can also set the &lt;code&gt;preload&lt;/code&gt; directive and &lt;a href=&quot;https://hstspreload.org/&quot;&gt;submit your site&lt;/a&gt; to a global list. If your site’s HSTS configuration fulfills the requirements of a minimum &lt;code&gt;max-age&lt;/code&gt; of one year and is active for subdomains it can be included in an internal browser record of sites that only work over HTTPS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you ever wonder why you can’t use local environments like &lt;code&gt;my-site.dev&lt;/code&gt; via HTTP with your browser anymore? This internal record is the reason – &lt;code&gt;.dev&lt;/code&gt; domains are automatically included in this list since it became a real top-level domain in February 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The HSTS header not only makes your site a little bit safer but also speeds it up. Imagine someone visiting your site on a slow mobile connection. If the first request is made via HTTP only to receive a redirect the user can spend several seconds without seeing anything. Using HSTS, you can save these seconds, and the browser uses HTTPS automatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;CSP – be clear about what is allowed on your site&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that your site runs over a secure connection you might run into the problem that browsers start blocking requests that go out to an insecure address due to mixed-content policies. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTTP/CSP&quot;&gt;Content Security Policy (CSP)&lt;/a&gt; header offers an excellent way to handle these cases. You can define your CSP ruleset via meta elements in your served HTML or via HTTP headers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;markdown&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;codehilite&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;twlo-code&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;Content-Security-Policy: upgrade-insecure-requests
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;rich-text&quot; readability=&quot;46.60393258427&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;upgrade-insecure-requests&lt;/code&gt; directive tells the browser to upgrade all HTTP requests to HTTPS magically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CSP is not only about the used protocol though. It offers granular ways to define what resources and actions are allowed on your site. You can define for example which scripts should be executed or where images should be loaded from. If something is not allowed the browser blocks it and prevents your site from potential attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Browser console telling that it blocked requests violating CSP rules&quot; class=&quot;richtext-image full-width&quot; height=&quot;247&quot; sizes=&quot;800px&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/com.twilio.prod.twilio-docs/images/OgnYZBz1NTYoxy42rxnEatqsFJoozi-T6o5G9apTEAIZcM.width-800.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/com.twilio.prod.twilio-docs/images/OgnYZBz1NTYoxy42rxnEatqsFJoozi-T6o5G9apTEAIZcM.width-800.jpg 800w, https://s3.amazonaws.com/com.twilio.prod.twilio-docs/images/OgnYZBz1NTYoxy42rxnEatqsFJoozi-T6o5G9apTEAIZc.width-1600.jpg 1098w&quot; width=&quot;800&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time of writing, there are 24 different configuration options for CSP. These options range from scripts over stylesheets to even service worker origins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Overview of 24 CSP directives listed on MDN&quot; class=&quot;richtext-image full-width&quot; height=&quot;433&quot; sizes=&quot;800px&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/com.twilio.prod.twilio-docs/images/Q0VKdwaOOJg19jVUtF-H2nyr_cU1L5B8zxjkM9vCEo2CsH.width-800.png&quot; srcset=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/com.twilio.prod.twilio-docs/images/Q0VKdwaOOJg19jVUtF-H2nyr_cU1L5B8zxjkM9vCEo2CsH.width-800.png 800w, https://s3.amazonaws.com/com.twilio.prod.twilio-docs/images/Q0VKdwaOOJg19jVUtF-H2nyr_cU1L5B8zxjkM9vCEo2Cs.width-1600.png 1600w&quot; width=&quot;800&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can find a complete overview&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTTP/CSP&quot;&gt;on MDN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using CSP, you can nail down what your site should include and what not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;markdown&quot; readability=&quot;7.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;codehilite&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;twlo-code&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;Content-Security-Policy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;default-src&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'self'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;script-src&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'self'&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;just-comments&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;com&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;www&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;google-analytics&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;com&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;production-assets&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;codepen&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;io&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;storage&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;googleapis&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;com&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;style-src&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'self'&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'unsafe-inline'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;img-src&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'self'&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;images&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;contentful&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;com&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;images&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;ctfassets&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;net&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;www&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;gravatar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;com&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;www&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;google-analytics&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;com&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;just-comments&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;com&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;font-src&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'self'&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;connect-src&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'self'&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;cdn&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;contentful&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;com&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;images&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;contentful&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;com&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;videos&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;contentful&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;com&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;images&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;ctfassets&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;net&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;videos&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;ctfassets&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;net&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;service&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;just-comments&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;com&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;www&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;google-analytics&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;com&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;media-src&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'self'&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;videos&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;contentful&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;com&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;videos&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;ctfassets&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;net&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;object-src&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'self'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;frame-src&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;codepen&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;io&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;frame-ancestors&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'self'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;worker-src&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'self'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;block-all-mixed-content&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;manifest-src&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'self'&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'self'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;disown-opener&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;prefetch-src&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'self'&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;rich-text&quot; readability=&quot;38&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ruleset above is the one I ship for my personal site and if you think that this CSP example definition is very tough to come up with – you’re entirely right. Implementing the CSP ruleset on my personal site took me three attempts to get right. I deployed it and rolled back because it broke my site several times. There is a better way to do this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To avoid breaking your site, CSP also provides a report-only option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;markdown&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;codehilite&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;twlo-code&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;Content-Security-Policy-Report-Only&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;default-src&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'self'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;...&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;report-uri&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;https&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;://&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;stefanjudis&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;report-uri&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;com&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;r&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;d&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;csp&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;reportOnly&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;rich-text&quot; readability=&quot;73.69623144271&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the &lt;code&gt;Content-Security-Policy-Report-Only&lt;/code&gt; mode browsers only log resources that would be blocked to the console instead of blocking them. This reporting mechanism gives you a way to check and adjust your ruleset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both headers, &lt;code&gt;Content-Security-Policy&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Content-Security-Policy-Report-Only&lt;/code&gt;, also offer a way to define an endpoint to send the violation and log information to (&lt;code&gt;report-uri&lt;/code&gt;). You can set up a logging server and use the sent log information to tweak your CSP rules until it’s ready to ship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The recommended process is: deploy CSP in report mode only first, analyze the incoming violations with real traffic, and only when there are no violations of your controlled resources showing up anymore turn it on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you’re looking for a service that can help you deal with these logs, I’m using&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://report-uri.com/&quot;&gt;Report URI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;, and it’s a great help.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Overall CSP adoption&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://caniuse.com/#search=csp&quot;&gt;Browser support for CSP is good these days&lt;/a&gt;, but unfortunately, not many sites are using it. To see how many sites serve content with CSP I ran a query &lt;a href=&quot;https://httparchive.org/&quot;&gt;on HTTP Archive&lt;/a&gt; and found out that only 6% of the crawled sites use CSP. I think we can do better to make the web a safer place and to avoid our &lt;a href=&quot;https://thenextweb.com/contributors/2018/03/10/protect-website-cryptojacking-attacks/&quot;&gt;users&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://thenextweb.com/contributors/2018/03/10/protect-website-cryptojacking-attacks/&quot;&gt;mining&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://thenextweb.com/contributors/2018/03/10/protect-website-cryptojacking-attacks/&quot;&gt;cryptocurrency without knowing it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;img alt=&quot;Pie chart showing that 6% of all sites use CSP&quot; class=&quot;richtext-image full-width&quot; height=&quot;631&quot; sizes=&quot;800px&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/com.twilio.prod.twilio-docs/images/jAQW_VflYXdzcl9ER0yTVPGpTBRQAOVZrIvgjSW6ucayZH.width-800.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/com.twilio.prod.twilio-docs/images/jAQW_VflYXdzcl9ER0yTVPGpTBRQAOVZrIvgjSW6ucayZH.width-800.jpg 800w, https://s3.amazonaws.com/com.twilio.prod.twilio-docs/images/jAQW_VflYXdzcl9ER0yTVPGpTBRQAOVZrIvgjSW6ucayZ.width-1600.jpg 1046w&quot; width=&quot;800&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The web has to be affordable&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I write this article, I sit in front of a relatively new MacBook using my fast Wi-Fi connection at home. Developers often forget that a setup like this is not the default for most of our users. People visiting our sites use old phones and are on crappy connections. Heavy and bloated sites with hundreds of requests give them a bad experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not only about the experience though. &lt;a href=&quot;https://whatdoesmysitecost.com/&quot;&gt;People pay different amounts for data depending on where they live&lt;/a&gt;. Imagine, you’re building a hospital site. The information on this particular site might be crucial and life-saving for people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a page on a hospital site is 5MB it is not only slow but also could be too expensive for people needing it the most. The price of 5MB in Europe or the United States is nothing compared to the price of 5MB of data in Africa. Developers are responsible for keeping the web affordable for everybody. This responsibility includes serving the right resources, evaluation of the right tools to use (do you really need a JS framework for a landing page?), and avoiding requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Cache-Control – avoid requests for the unchanged resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A website today easily contains hundreds of resources ranging from stylesheets to script files to images. &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTTP/Headers/Cache-Control&quot;&gt;Using the &lt;code&gt;Cache-Control&lt;/code&gt; header&lt;/a&gt; developers can define how long a resource should be considered “fresh” and can be served from the browser cache.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;markdown&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;codehilite&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;twlo-code&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;Cache-Control: max-age=30, public
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;rich-text&quot; readability=&quot;50.110552763819&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By setting proper &lt;code&gt;Cache-Control&lt;/code&gt; data transfer is saved, and files can be used from the browser cache for a certain amount of seconds (&lt;code&gt;max-age&lt;/code&gt;). Browsers should revalidate cached resources after the time span is over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, when visitors refresh a page, &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.fb.com/web/this-browser-tweak-saved-60-of-requests-to-facebook/&quot;&gt;browsers still revalidate the page including referenced resources&lt;/a&gt; to ensure the cached data is still valid. Servers respond with a 304 header signaling that the cached data is still good or 200 serving the updated data. This can save transferred data but not necessarily made requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where the &lt;code&gt;immutable&lt;/code&gt; feature comes into play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;immutable – never request a resource twice&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In modern Frontend applications, stylesheet and script files usually have a unique file name like &lt;code&gt;styles.123abc.css&lt;/code&gt;. This file name depends on the contents of the particular file. When the content of these files changes, it results in a different file name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These unique files could potentially be cached forever including the situation when a user refreshes a page. &lt;a href=&quot;https://hacks.mozilla.org/2017/01/using-immutable-caching-to-speed-up-the-web/&quot;&gt;The &lt;code&gt;immutable&lt;/code&gt; feature&lt;/a&gt; can tell the browser not to revalidate a resource in a certain timeframe. This makes much sense for finger-printed assets and helps to avoid revalidation requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;markdown&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;codehilite&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;twlo-code&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;Cache-Control: max-age=31536000, public, immutable
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;rich-text&quot; readability=&quot;45.908346972177&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Optimal caching is very hard and in particular browser caching is not very intuitive because it provides multiple configurations. I recommend having a look at the following resources:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Accept-Encoding – compress to the maximum (uhm… minimum)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using &lt;code&gt;Cache-control&lt;/code&gt;, we can save requests and reduce the amount of data that repeatedly goes over the wire. We can not only save requests but also shrink what is transferred.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When serving resources, developers should make sure to send as little data as possible. For text-based resources like HTML, CSS and JavaScript compression plays a significant role in saving transferred data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most commonly used compression these days is GZIP. Servers are fast enough to compress text files on the fly and serve compressed data when requested. GZIP is not the best option anymore though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you inspect the requests your browser makes for text-based files like HTML, CSS, and JavaScript and have a look at the request headers you’ll find the &lt;code&gt;accept-encoding&lt;/code&gt; header.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;markdown&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;codehilite&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;twlo-code&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;Accept-Encoding: gzip, deflate, br
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;rich-text&quot; readability=&quot;67.736925515055&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This header tells the server what compression algorithms it understands. The not so well known &lt;code&gt;br&lt;/code&gt; stands for &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/google/brotli&quot;&gt;Brotli compression&lt;/a&gt; and is the compression used by high-traffic sites like Google and Facebook. To use Brotli your site has to run on HTTPS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This compression algorithm was created with small file sizes in mind. When you give it a try on your local machine and compress a file by hand, you’ll find out that Brotli indeed compresses better than GZIP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Terminal with the same css files. Original size 101kb, gzip compressed size 15kb and brotli compressed size 9.4kb&quot; class=&quot;richtext-image full-width&quot; height=&quot;331&quot; sizes=&quot;800px&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/com.twilio.prod.twilio-docs/images/WdigoLiMIP2UPVhDrABHt_bJYNztLyO6-FFLQ8Jo8wyrXh.width-800.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/com.twilio.prod.twilio-docs/images/WdigoLiMIP2UPVhDrABHt_bJYNztLyO6-FFLQ8Jo8wyrXh.width-800.jpg 800w, https://s3.amazonaws.com/com.twilio.prod.twilio-docs/images/WdigoLiMIP2UPVhDrABHt_bJYNztLyO6-FFLQ8Jo8wyrX.width-1600.jpg 1372w&quot; width=&quot;800&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may have heard that Brotli compression performs slower, too. The reason for that is that Brotli has 11 compression modes and the default mode was chosen to guarantee small file sizes resulting in long encoding times. GZIP, on the other hand, has 9 modes and the default mode was chosen taking both, speed and file size, into consideration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This decision makes Brotli’s default mode unsuitable for on-the-fly compression, but if you change the compression mode you can achieve smaller file sizes with comparable speed to GZIP. You can even use it to compress on-the-fly and treat it as a potential GZIP replacement for supporting browsers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to that, if you want to gain maximal file savings you could forget the idea of dynamically compressing your files and pre-generate &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.telerik.com/blogs/maximize-compression-with-zopfli&quot;&gt;optimized GZIP files using zopfli&lt;/a&gt; and Brotli files in your build process to statically serve them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you want to read more about Brotli compression and how it compares to GZIP, the folks at Akamai did&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.akamai.com/2016/02/understanding-brotlis-potential.html&quot;&gt;extensive research around this topic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Accept and Accept-CH – serve tailored resources to the user&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Optimizing text assets is great to save kilobytes but what about the heavier resources like images to save even more data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Accept – serve the right image format&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Browsers not only tell us about what compression algorithms they understand. When your browser requests an image, it also gives information about what file formats it understands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;markdown&quot; readability=&quot;7.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;codehilite&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;twlo-code&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Accept&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sr&quot;&gt;/webp, image/apng, image/*,*/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;*;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;q&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mf&quot;&gt;0.8&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;rich-text&quot; readability=&quot;42.298850574713&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The competition around a new image format was on for a few years, but now it looks like &lt;code&gt;webp&lt;/code&gt; won. &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/speed/webp/&quot;&gt;Webp is an image format invented by Google&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://caniuse.com/#feat=webp&quot;&gt;the support for webp images&lt;/a&gt; is pretty good these days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using this request header, developers can serve a &lt;code&gt;webp&lt;/code&gt; image even when the browser requested &lt;code&gt;image.jpg&lt;/code&gt; which results in smaller file size. Dean Hume wrote &lt;a href=&quot;https://deanhume.com/service-workers-dynamic-responsive-images-using-webp-images/&quot;&gt;a nice guide&lt;/a&gt; on how to do this in a service worker. That’s pretty cool!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Chrome network panel showing a request for a JPEG which gets a webp response&quot; class=&quot;richtext-image full-width&quot; height=&quot;541&quot; sizes=&quot;800px&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/com.twilio.prod.twilio-docs/images/9JczExPcmc402uz1B2mY_KmhuaQNl6UExmSYcs2ZH7yNDk.width-800.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/com.twilio.prod.twilio-docs/images/9JczExPcmc402uz1B2mY_KmhuaQNl6UExmSYcs2ZH7yNDk.width-800.jpg 800w, https://s3.amazonaws.com/com.twilio.prod.twilio-docs/images/9JczExPcmc402uz1B2mY_KmhuaQNl6UExmSYcs2ZH7yND.width-1600.jpg 1600w&quot; width=&quot;800&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Accept-CH - serve a properly sized image&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also enable &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/web/updates/2015/09/automating-resource-selection-with-client-hints&quot;&gt;client hints&lt;/a&gt; for supporting browsers. Client hints are a way to tell browsers to send additional headers giving information on viewport width, image width and even network conditions like RTT (round trip time) and connection type like &lt;code&gt;2g&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can enable them by including a meta element:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;markdown&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;codehilite&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;twlo-code&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;meta&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;http-equiv&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;Accept-CH&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;content&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;Viewport-Width, Downlink&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;meta&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;http-equiv&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;Accept-CH-Lifetime&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;content&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;86400&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;rich-text&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or setting headers on the initial HTML request:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;markdown&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;codehilite&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;twlo-code&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;Accept-CH: Width, Viewport-Width
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;Accept-CH-Lifetime: 100
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;rich-text&quot; readability=&quot;38&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supporting browsers will start sending additional information for the defined timespan (&lt;code&gt;Accept-CH-Lifetime&lt;/code&gt; in seconds) in the following requests that can help developers to tailor for examples images to user conditions without changing any HTML.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To receive for example additional information like image width on the server side you can equip your images with a &lt;code&gt;sizes&lt;/code&gt; attribute to give the browser additional information on how this image will be laid out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;markdown&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;codehilite&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;twlo-code&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;!-- this images is laid over the full width | 100 viewport width --&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;img&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;w-100&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;src&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;/img/header.jpg&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;alt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;sizes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;100vw&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;rich-text&quot; readability=&quot;38&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the initially received &lt;code&gt;Accept-CH&lt;/code&gt; response header and images equipped with the &lt;code&gt;sizes&lt;/code&gt; attribute supporting browsers will include &lt;code&gt;viewport-width&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;width&lt;/code&gt; headers in the image requests telling you what image would be the best fit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Chrome network panel showing a request including viewport-width and width header for a particular image&quot; class=&quot;richtext-image full-width&quot; height=&quot;541&quot; sizes=&quot;800px&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/com.twilio.prod.twilio-docs/images/8u07oEaYg3fBaV6Z35RcBDXW7hehK8wPrPSthhRpQlHN3i.width-800.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/com.twilio.prod.twilio-docs/images/8u07oEaYg3fBaV6Z35RcBDXW7hehK8wPrPSthhRpQlHN3i.width-800.jpg 800w, https://s3.amazonaws.com/com.twilio.prod.twilio-docs/images/8u07oEaYg3fBaV6Z35RcBDXW7hehK8wPrPSthhRpQlHN3.width-1600.jpg 1600w&quot; width=&quot;800&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having the supported image format and image dimensions at hand you can send tailored media without the need to write error-prone picture elements taking care of file formats and sizes like the following repeatedly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;markdown&quot; readability=&quot;18.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;codehilite&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;twlo-code&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;picture&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;!-- serve WebP to Chrome, Edge, Firefox and Opera --&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;source&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;media&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;(min-width: 50em)&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;sizes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;50vw&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;srcset&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;/image/thing-200.webp 200w, /image/thing-400.webp 400w,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;        /image/thing-800.webp 800w, /image/thing-1200.webp 1200w,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;        /image/thing-1600.webp 1600w, /image/thing-2000.webp 2000w&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;type&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;image/webp&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;source&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;sizes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;(min-width: 30em) 100vw&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;srcset&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;/image/thing-crop-200.webp 200w, /image/thing-crop-400.webp 400w,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;        /image/thing-crop-800.webp 800w, /image/thing-crop-1200.webp 1200w,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;        /image/thing-crop-1600.webp 1600w, /image/thing-crop-2000.webp 2000w&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;type&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;image/webp&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;!-- serve JPEG to others --&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;source&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;media&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;(min-width: 50em)&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;sizes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;50vw&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;srcset&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;/image/thing-200.jpg 200w, /image/thing-400.jpg 400w,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;        /image/thing-800.jpg 800w, /image/thing-1200.jpg 1200w,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;        /image/thing-1600.jpg 1600w, /image/thing-2000.jpg 2000w&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;source&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;sizes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;(min-width: 30em) 100vw&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;srcset&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;/image/thing-crop-200.jpg 200w, /image/thing-crop-400.jpg 400w,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;        /image/thing-crop-800.jpg 800w, /image/thing-crop-1200.jpg 1200w,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;        /image/thing-crop-1600.jpg 1600w, /image/thing-crop-2000.jpg 2000w&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;!-- fallback for browsers that don't support picture --&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;img&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;src&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;/image/thing.jpg&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;width&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;50%&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;picture&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;rich-text&quot; readability=&quot;66.246798029557&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the possibility to access viewport width and image sizes you can potentially move asset resize logic in a central place on your servers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have to consider though, that just because you have the exact image width at hand you don’t want to create images for every width. Sending images for certain dimension ranges (&lt;code&gt;image-200&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;image-300&lt;/code&gt;, ...) helps to leverage CDN caches and saves computation time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, with current technologies like service workers, you could even intercept and change request right in the client to serve the best image files. With enabled client hints service workers have access to layout information and in combination with an images API like for example &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloudinary.com/&quot;&gt;Cloudinary&lt;/a&gt; you could adjust the image url right in the browser to receive properly sized images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you’re looking for more information on client hints, you can check&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/web/fundamentals/performance/optimizing-content-efficiency/client-hints/&quot;&gt;Jeremy Wagner’s article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; or&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/web/updates/2015/09/automating-resource-selection-with-client-hints&quot;&gt;Ilya Grigorik’s article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; on the topic.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The web has to be respectful&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all of us being online many hours a day there is the last aspect that I consider to be very important – the web has to be respectful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;preload – reduce the waiting time&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As developers, we want to make sure to value the time of our users. Nobody wants to waste time. As discussed in the previous sections serving the right data plays a big role in saving time and data. It’s not only about what requests are made but also about the timing and order of these.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s think of an example: if you include a stylesheet in your site browsers will show nothing until it is loaded. While nothing is displayed the browser still continues to parse the HTML looking for other resources to fetch. When the stylesheet is loaded and parsed it might include references to other critical resources like fonts which have to be requested. This sequential process can increase the loading time for your visitors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/TR/preload/&quot;&gt;Using the &lt;code&gt;rel=preload&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; you can give the browser information on what resources will be requested in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can preload resources via HTML elements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;markdown&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;codehilite&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;twlo-code&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;link&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;rel&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;preload&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;href&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;/font.woff2&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;as&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;font&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;type&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;font/woff2&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;crossorigin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;anonymous&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;rich-text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or headers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;markdown&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;codehilite&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;twlo-code&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;Link&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;font&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;woff2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;rel&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;preload&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;as&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;font&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;no-push&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;rich-text&quot; readability=&quot;49.75737704918&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This way the browser receives the header or discovers the link element and immediately requests the resources so that these sit already in the browser cache when they are needed. This process values your visitor’s time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To preload your resources in the best way and understand all the configurations I recommend having a look at the following resources:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Feature-Policy – don’t be the annoying person&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there is one last thing that I don’t want to see any longer, it is websites asking me for permissions for no reason. I can only quote &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/uo-UOvq3-0Y?t=1020&quot;&gt;my colleague Phil Nash on that topic&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not demand notification permission on page load.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developers should be respectful and not build sites that annoy their visitors. People just click away all the permission dialogs. Websites and developers lose much trust, and all the new shiny web features will lose their power if we as developers are not using them carefully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, what if it is mandatory for your site to include lots of third-party code and all these scripts trigger one permission dialog after another? How can you make sure that all of the included scripts behave?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTTP/Headers/Feature-Policy&quot;&gt;the &lt;code&gt;Feature-Policy&lt;/code&gt; header&lt;/a&gt; comes into play. Using this header you can define what features are allowed and limit the popping up permission dialogs that may be triggered by someone else running code in your site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;markdown&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;codehilite&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;twlo-code&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;Feature-Policy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;vibrate&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'none'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;geolocation&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'none'&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;rich-text&quot; readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can define it for your site using headers but also define it for embedded content like iframes which can be mandatory for third-party integrations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;markdown&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;codehilite&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;twlo-code&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;code-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;iframe&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;allow&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;camera 'none'; microphone 'none'&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;rich-text&quot; readability=&quot;59.045801526718&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time of writing &lt;code&gt;Feature-Policy&lt;/code&gt; is highly experimental but if you have a look at upcoming options, it’s very exciting. In the not too distant future developers cannot only limit themselves and prevent the shipping of annoying dialogs but also potentially block non-optimized media. These features will make a big difference in user experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Overview of 24 Feature policy directives listed on MDN&quot; class=&quot;richtext-image full-width&quot; height=&quot;428&quot; sizes=&quot;800px&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/com.twilio.prod.twilio-docs/images/9kC_q_Icf-bbsY5eGHjS0u3KTLtTpM__7uqqmh-WfVgPc6.width-800.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/com.twilio.prod.twilio-docs/images/9kC_q_Icf-bbsY5eGHjS0u3KTLtTpM__7uqqmh-WfVgPc6.width-800.jpg 800w, https://s3.amazonaws.com/com.twilio.prod.twilio-docs/images/9kC_q_Icf-bbsY5eGHjS0u3KTLtTpM__7uqqmh-WfVgPc.width-1600.jpg 1600w&quot; width=&quot;800&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can find a complete overview&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTTP/Headers/Feature-Policy&quot;&gt;on MDN&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at the feature policy list above you might wonder what happened to the most annoying one – push notifications. It turned out that the implementation of &lt;code&gt;Feature-Policy&lt;/code&gt; for push notifications is harder than expected. You can follow &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/w3c/webappsec-feature-policy/issues/243&quot;&gt;the filed GitHub issue&lt;/a&gt; if you want to learn more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using feature policy, you can make sure that you and your third parties won’t turn your site into &lt;a href=&quot;https://2018.bloomca.me&quot;&gt;a permission dismissal race&lt;/a&gt; which unfortunately is already the default state for many sites today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The web has to be for everybody&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, I only covered a few headers that could help improve the user experience. If you want to see an almost complete overview of headers and their possibilities I can recommend having a look at &lt;a href=&quot;https://mobile.twitter.com/derSchepp&quot;&gt;Christian Schaefer&lt;/a&gt;’s slide deck &lt;a href=&quot;https://schepp.github.io/HTTP-headers&quot;&gt;“HTTP headers – the hidden champions”&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know that building a great website today is very challenging. Developers have to consider designs, devices, frameworks, and yes… headers play a role, too. Hopefully, this article gave you some ideas and you’ll consider safety, affordability, and respect in your next web projects because these are the factors that make the web truly great for everybody.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you want to say “Hi” you can reach me under the following channels:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article-coauthors&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Authors&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;article-coauthors-list&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.gravatar.com/avatar/6e3fabe3cc4504c24f353ba22116279e?d=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.twilio.com%2Fmarketing%2Fbundles%2Fcompany-brand%2Fimg%2Flogos%2Fred%2Ftwilio-mark-red.png&amp;amp;s=40&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.twilio.com/blog/author/sjudis&quot;&gt;Stefan Judis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;noscript readability=&quot;1.15625&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please enable JavaScript to view the &lt;a href=&quot;https://disqus.com/?ref_noscript&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;comments powered by Disqus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 06:42:29 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kiyanwang</dc:creator>
<og:title>HTTP headers for the responsible developer</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.twilio.com/blog/a-http-headers-for-the-responsible-developer</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://s3.amazonaws.com/com.twilio.prod.twilio-docs/original_images/hero-header.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.twilio.com/blog/a-http-headers-for-the-responsible-developer</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Let&amp;#039;s Get Going with Org-Mode</title>
<link>https://beorg.app/orgmode/letsgetgoing/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://beorg.app/orgmode/letsgetgoing/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Org mode uses plain text files&lt;/strong&gt; which can be used in any text editor. The real power comes when you use an environment which understands Org mode. The best place to use Org mode files is Emacs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This beginners’ guide uses ‘plain’ Emacs.&lt;/strong&gt; There are many Emacs distributions which pre-configure it to improve the UI, selection of installed packages, keyboard shortcuts and more. If you decide you like Emacs it is worth checking out &lt;a href=&quot;http://spacemacs.org&quot;&gt;Spacemacs&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://prelude.emacsredux.com/en/latest/&quot;&gt;Emacs Prelude&lt;/a&gt; - they can add a lot of value to the Emacs experience without requiring a massive time investment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There are no &lt;em&gt;keyboard shortcuts&lt;/em&gt; used in this beginners’ guide.&lt;/strong&gt; I want this to be as gentle an introduction as possible. Follow up articles will get into Org mode in more detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://beorg.app/images/orgmode/letsgetgoing_artwork_downloading.png#graphic&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;macos&quot;&gt;macOS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are using macOS, Emacs is already installed. However the bundled Emacs is ancient so you should install Emacs yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a number of different ‘builds’ of Emacs. Feel free to look at the options - or just go ahead and install &lt;a href=&quot;https://emacsformacosx.com&quot;&gt;Emacs For Mac OS X&lt;/a&gt; which is a pretty good choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;linux&quot;&gt;Linux&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are on a recent version of Linux you probably have an up-to-date version of Emacs installed. You’ll want either Emacs 25 or Emacs 26. You can check what version you have from the command line:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;emacs --version
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For versions prior to 25 you should install something newer. Check your package manager to see what’s available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;windows&quot;&gt;Windows&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The simplest way to get going with Emacs is by &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/arbv/emacs-msi-installer/releases&quot;&gt;downloading an installer&lt;/a&gt;. This installer packages up the Emacs you can download from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/&quot;&gt;the official GNU Emacs page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not necessarily obvious which file to download. If you have a recent Windows installation (i.e. 64-bit Windows 10) then you want the file which ends &lt;code&gt;-x86_64.msi&lt;/code&gt;. For example &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/arbv/emacs-msi-installer/releases/download/v26.2/emacs-26.2-x86_64.msi&quot;&gt;emacs-26.2-x86_64.msi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The installer will add a shortcut to Emacs on your desktop, in the Start menu and from the file context menu (so you can easily open files in Emacs.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most obvious use for Org mode is as a task manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Org mode files have a &lt;code&gt;.org&lt;/code&gt; extension. Let’s run Emacs and create a new file called &lt;code&gt;tasks.org&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://beorg.app/images/orgmode/letsgetgoing_artwork_newlist.png#graphic&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To create a new file tap the leftmost toolbar button&lt;/strong&gt;, select where you want to save the file and give it the name &lt;code&gt;tasks.org&lt;/code&gt;. The &lt;code&gt;.org&lt;/code&gt; extension is important, as Emacs can work with lots of different sorts of files. You may want to place tasks.org on your Desktop for easy access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://beorg.app/images/orgmode/letsgetgoing_createfile.png#desktop&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As your new file has the extension &lt;code&gt;.org&lt;/code&gt; Emacs will automatically turn on Org mode. If you look carefully you’ll see some new menus appear in the Emacs menu bar - Org, Tbl and Text. These contain easy access to features useful for working with Org files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://beorg.app/images/orgmode/letsgetgoing_menu.png#desktop&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From the Org menu select &lt;code&gt;New Heading&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; Emacs will insert a &lt;code&gt;*&lt;/code&gt; followed by a space. You can now enter the name of something you want to get done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go ahead and create a few tasks. Here are mine for this weekend:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;* Clear out utility room
* Take utility room rubbish to recycling center
* Buy paint for utility room
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A core concept in any task management system is that of a task &lt;em&gt;state&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; Currently our list of tasks doesn’t specify the state of those tasks. As Org mode can be used as a general &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Outliner&quot;&gt;outliner&lt;/a&gt; we need to provide a little more information to make it clear that these are things to be done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Position the cursor, using the mouse or cursor keys, on your first task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From the &lt;code&gt;Org&lt;/code&gt; menu, select the &lt;code&gt;TODO Lists&lt;/code&gt; submenu and then &lt;code&gt;TODO/DONE/-&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; Emacs will insert a TODO after the &lt;code&gt;*&lt;/code&gt;. Note that it doesn’t matter where your cursor is on the line. Emacs helpfully changes the text color of the task state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://beorg.app/images/orgmode/letsgetgoing_todo.png#desktop&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Org files are plain text. There is nothing to stop you creating a new heading by typing the &lt;code&gt;*&lt;/code&gt; and then setting the state by typing &lt;code&gt;TODO&lt;/code&gt;. Until you start using keyboard shortcuts this is often quicker than using the menu if you are a reasonable typist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The state of a task is determined by the TODO &lt;em&gt;keyword&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By default Org mode will understand TODO and DONE. You can cycle between the available task states using the &lt;code&gt;TODO/DONE/-&lt;/code&gt; menu option. If an item has the state &lt;code&gt;TODO&lt;/code&gt; and you hit &lt;code&gt;TODO/DONE/-&lt;/code&gt; it will be changed to DONE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://beorg.app/images/orgmode/letsgetgoing_artwork_complete.png#graphic&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is my list of tasks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;* TODO Clear out utility room
* TODO Take utility room rubbish to recycling center
* TODO Buy paint for utility room
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve now completed the first of my tasks so I’m going to set it to DONE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Position the cursor anywhere on the line and then select the same &lt;code&gt;TODO/DONE/-&lt;/code&gt; menu option you used before.&lt;/strong&gt; The list now becomes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;* DONE Clear out utility room
* TODO Take utility room rubbish to recycling center
* TODO Buy paint for utility room
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can add dates to items to say when they should be done or when a deadline is.&lt;/strong&gt; If needed you can both schedule a task and provide a separate deadline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://beorg.app/images/orgmode/letsgetgoing_artwork_schedule.png#graphic&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s schedule taking the utility room rubbish to the recycling center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put the cursor somewhere on the relevant line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bring up the &lt;code&gt;Org&lt;/code&gt; menu, go to the submenu &lt;code&gt;Dates and Scheduling&lt;/code&gt; and choose &lt;code&gt;Schedule Item&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Org mode date picker will appear at the bottom of the Emacs window.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://beorg.app/images/orgmode/letsgetgoing_scheduling.png#desktop&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use the mouse to pick a date this weekend (don’t worry there are quicker ways to pick dates, which we’ll learn about later). Org mode will now insert a new line below your task, which will now look something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;* TODO Take utility room rubbish to recycling center
  SCHEDULED: &amp;lt;2019-05-04 Sat&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can clearly see the date the task is scheduled for. If you want to update it just do &lt;code&gt;Schedule Item&lt;/code&gt; again and Org mode will update the existing date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Org mode works with text files. You’ll need to remember to save. If you quit Emacs then it will remind you about any unsaved files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://beorg.app/images/orgmode/letsgetgoing_artwork_save.png#graphic&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To proactively save a file select &lt;code&gt;Save&lt;/code&gt; from the &lt;code&gt;File&lt;/code&gt; menu.&lt;/strong&gt; If this is grayed out then the file doesn’t need saving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Once you’ve got some tasks scheduled it can be handy to see a weekly view of what needs to be done.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://beorg.app/images/orgmode/letsgetgoing_artwork_agenda.png#graphic&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you are using the agenda for the first time you’ll need to tell it which files your tasks are in.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure you are viewing your &lt;code&gt;tasks.org&lt;/code&gt; file in Emacs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Select the &lt;code&gt;Org&lt;/code&gt; menu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;…the submenu &lt;code&gt;File List for Agenda&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and then &lt;code&gt;Add/Move Current File to Front of List&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can do this for any number of Org files you might create.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To view your agenda, first make sure that you have saved any newly created files. Then…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From the &lt;code&gt;Org&lt;/code&gt; menu select &lt;code&gt;Agenda Command...&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Press the &lt;code&gt;a&lt;/code&gt; key on your keyboard&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://beorg.app/images/orgmode/letsgetgoing_agendacommands.png#desktop&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can move between weeks by selecting the &lt;code&gt;Agenda&lt;/code&gt; menu (this only appears when you are viewing the agenda), &lt;code&gt;Agenda Dates&lt;/code&gt; submenu and then one of the options. You’ll see next to each option a letter on the right. These can be used to quickly move about the agenda. For example when viewing the agenda press the &lt;code&gt;f&lt;/code&gt; key on the keyboard to go to the next week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this article we’ve covered the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Downloading and installing Emacs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creating your first Org file&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adding some tasks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Setting a task to TODO or DONE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scheduling a task&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Saving files&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Viewing your agenda&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you are new to Emacs or applications like Emacs (it’s a completely different world to that of Omnifocus or Things) then you might need some time to play with what we’ve looked at. It can seem a long way around to doing some quite simple things. However once you progress onto using the keyboard everything changes and the true power of Org mode and Emacs will be revealed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check back soon for next part of &lt;em&gt;Learning Org mode&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;noscript readability=&quot;1.15625&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please enable JavaScript to view the &lt;a href=&quot;https://disqus.com/?ref_noscript&quot;&gt;comments powered by Disqus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 04:49:08 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>luu</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://beorg.app/orgmode/letsgetgoing/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>GM lays off engineer who helped expose VW’s diesel fraud</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/05/06/business/hermanth-kappanna-vw-emissions-gm.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2019/05/06/business/hermanth-kappanna-vw-emissions-gm.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;FRANKFURT — Hemanth Kappanna might seem like just another victim of corporate restructuring, a foreign worker whose skills were no longer needed, a middle-aged man with dashed American dreams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;But Mr. Kappanna, an engineer born in India who was laid off by General Motors in February, changed automotive history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In 2013, he was part of a small team of engineering students in West Virginia whose research helped expose Volkswagen’s decade-long conspiracy to lie about its diesel cars’ emissions. The German carmaker has paid $23 billion to resolve criminal charges and lawsuits in the United States, and $33 billion over all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The cost to Volkswagen rose on Tuesday. The company’s Porsche division said it had agreed to pay a fine of 535 million euros, or $600 million, after the German authorities &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://www.staatsanwaltschaft-stuttgart.de/pb/,Lde/Startseite/Presse/Porsche/?LISTPAGE=1235504&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;accused the sports&lt;/a&gt;-&lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://www.staatsanwaltschaft-stuttgart.de/pb/,Lde/Startseite/Presse/Porsche/?LISTPAGE=1235504&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;car maker&lt;/a&gt; of selling nearly 100,000 diesel sport utility vehicles with software designed to conceal excess emissions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Kappanna’s role as a hero in bringing the Volkswagen scandal to light did not protect him when his supervisor called him into a conference room in Milford, Mich., this past winter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Kappanna, who had studied and lived in the United States for 17 years, joined G.M. in December 2014 after finishing his doctorate. His most recent job involved communicating with the Environmental Protection Agency about the American carmaker’s emissions technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The supervisor said it was nothing personal, Mr. Kappanna, 41, recalled by telephone from Michigan last week. His severance package consisted of two months’ pay and a one-way ticket to India. He was one of about 4,000 G.M. workers laid off in what the company called a &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://media.gm.com/media/us/en/gm/news.detail.html/content/Pages/news/us/en/2018/nov/1126-gm.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;“strategic transformation.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“They let me go,” he said, still sounding bewildered. Unable to find a job before his work visa’s 60-day grace period expired, Mr. Kappanna returned to Bangalore, his hometown, a few days later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-79elbk&quot; data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-wrapper&quot;&gt;

&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-children&quot; class=&quot;css-1a48zt4 ehw59r15&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1xdhyk6 erfvjey0&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;css-1m50asq&quot; src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/05/01/business/00vwwhistleblower-2/merlin_151445670_ec391688-037c-48ea-9a29-c212b796683c-articleLarge.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;disable=upscale&quot; srcset=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/05/01/business/00vwwhistleblower-2/merlin_151445670_ec391688-037c-48ea-9a29-c212b796683c-articleLarge.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 600w,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/05/01/business/00vwwhistleblower-2/merlin_151445670_ec391688-037c-48ea-9a29-c212b796683c-jumbo.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 1024w,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/05/01/business/00vwwhistleblower-2/merlin_151445670_ec391688-037c-48ea-9a29-c212b796683c-superJumbo.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 2048w&quot; sizes=&quot;((min-width: 600px) and (max-width: 1004px)) 84vw, (min-width: 1005px) 80vw, 100vw&quot; itemprop=&quot;url&quot; itemid=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/05/01/business/00vwwhistleblower-2/merlin_151445670_ec391688-037c-48ea-9a29-c212b796683c-articleLarge.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;disable=upscale&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;A Volkswagen plant in Wolfsburg, Germany. The carmaker has paid $23 billion so far to resolve criminal charges and lawsuits in the United States related to the emissions scheme, and $33 billion over all.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e1z0qqy90&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Sean Gallup/Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Kappanna was a graduate student when he got involved in a “Mad Max” sort of experiment on Volkswagens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;He was studying at West Virginia University in Morgantown, which is known for its research on auto emissions, when the director of his program asked him to complete a grant application from the International Council on Clean Transportation. The council, a nonprofit group, wanted to test the emissions of German diesel cars sold in America. Mr. Kappanna was pursuing a doctorate, and his proposal helped the university win a modest $70,000 grant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The university planned a real-time test of emissions, and it rigged up an ingenious way to scrutinize the exhaust generated under open-road conditions. The standard practice was to test cars in specially equipped garages, which is much easier than trying to analyze fumes from a moving vehicle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Kappanna and two other graduate students, &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2016/07/25/business/vw-wvu-diesel-volkswagen-west-virginia.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Marc Besch from Switzerland and Arvind Thiruvengadam from India&lt;/a&gt;, were chosen to do the fieldwork. They bolted portable emissions-testing equipment to a sheet of plywood and crammed it into the back of a Volkswagen diesel station wagon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The rig, powered by a portable gasoline generator, was noisy and smelly, but with every mile, it churned out data that challenged sticker-price assurances. The emissions were dirtier than anyone would have imagined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Kappanna and his fellow students did not know it, but they were gathering evidence of a crime. Volkswagen engineers had devised so-called defeat device software that could recognize the standardized procedure used by regulators in their testing labs. In the labs, the software dialed up a car’s pollution controls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;But when officials were not looking or, more important, when the cars were being used by regular motorists, the software dialed down to save wear and tear on the fragile emissions-control equipment. Volkswagen never expected anyone, much less a group of graduate students, to test the cars on the highway, when the defeat device would not work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Kappanna, Mr. Besch and Mr. Thiruvengadam documented that Volkswagens polluted far more than regulations allowed when they were driven on highways and city streets. In March 2014, Mr. Besch &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theicct.org/sites/default/files/publications/WVU_LDDV_in-use_ICCT_Report_Final_may2014.pdf&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;presented the findings at a conference for emissions experts in San Diego&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Their paper did not directly accuse Volkswagen of wrongdoing. But the data it included raised red flags for officials with the California Air Resources Board and the Environmental Protection Agency who were in the audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The regulators began an investigation that, a year and a half later, forced Volkswagen to confess that it had installed the cheating software in 11 million diesel cars worldwide, including almost 600,000 in the United States. The inquiry called attention to the health hazards of diesel fuel and spurred consumers to shun the technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-79elbk&quot; data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-wrapper&quot;&gt;

&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-children&quot; class=&quot;css-1a48zt4 ehw59r15&quot;&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;Volkswagen’s Wolfsburg factory. The company has confessed to installing cheating software in 11 million diesel cars worldwide, including almost 600,000 in the United States.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e1z0qqy90&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Sean Gallup/Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Today, two former Volkswagen executives are serving prison terms in the United States for their roles in trying to cover up the emissions fraud. Martin Winterkorn, Volkswagen’s former chief executive, faces &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/former-ceo-volkswagen-ag-charged-conspiracy-and-wire-fraud-diesel-emissions-scandal&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;criminal charges in the United States and Germany&lt;/a&gt; for his alleged role in the scheme. He has denied wrongdoing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.jato.com/europe-q1-19-dacia-and-tesla-were-the-big-winners-while-suvs-offset-mpvs-drop/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;market share of diesel&lt;/a&gt; cars in Europe, once the most popular engine option in the region, was only 31 percent in March, the lowest level since 2000, according to data compiled by JATO Dynamics, a research firm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Ironically, Mr. Kappanna’s most recent position at G.M. involved complying with tougher disclosure requirements that the E.P.A. imposed on carmakers after the Volkswagen scandal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Kappanna is proud of his role in unmasking Volkswagen’s wrongdoing, but he also wonders whether he was seen within G.M. as overly zealous about compliance and too friendly to regulators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“Certainly they could have seen me as biased,” he said. “I can’t really say.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;G.M. said this week that Mr. Kappanna’s dismissal “was not related to any emissions compliance concerns or related issues.” That he was not a United States citizen also played no role, G.M. said in an emailed statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Whatever the reason, Mr. Kappanna and other G.M. workers arrived at work in Milford on Feb. 4 to find notices taped to conference room doors: The rooms had been reserved for human resources meetings. Mr. Kappanna soon received a phone call from the director of his division to meet him in one of the rooms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“I felt it even before I stepped into the room,” Mr. Kappanna said about the loss of his job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;He turned in his company laptop, and a security guard escorted him out of the building. He was one of three people let go in a department of about 50. Colleagues, he said, reassured him that his dismissal was “one of those shortsighted decisions taken to meet the numbers.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“It was completely wrong on the part of leadership,” he said they had told him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Still, when his co-workers invited Mr. Kappanna for a farewell beer that evening, he declined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“I was still coming to terms with what had just happened,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;He said he had a lead on a job with another automaker and still hoped to return to the United States. But the industry is suffering a slowdown, and his prospects are uncertain. Single and with no children, he was apprehensive about returning to India after spending nearly half his life in America.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“I’m a little skeptical how I’m going to adapt,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 02:59:10 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>sundvor</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/05/06/business/hermanth-kappanna-vw-emissions-gm.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Six Years Ago, He Helped Expose VW’s Diesel Fraud. This Year, G.M. Let Him Go.</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/05/01/business/00vwwhistleblower-1/00vwwhistleblower-1-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Hemanth Kappanna’s research helped plunge Volkswagen into a scandal that continues to plague it. In February, he got two months’ pay and a one-way ticket to India.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/05/06/business/hermanth-kappanna-vw-emissions-gm.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>