<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Apple Cancels AirPower Product</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/29/apple-cancels-airpower-product-citing-inability-to-meet-its-high-standards-for-hardware/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/29/apple-cancels-airpower-product-citing-inability-to-meet-its-high-standards-for-hardware/</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/apple&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;apple&quot;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt; has canceled the AirPower product completely, citing difficulty meeting its own standards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“After much effort, we’ve concluded AirPower will not achieve our high standards and we have cancelled the project. We apologize to those customers who were looking forward to this launch. We continue to believe that the future is wireless and are committed to push the wireless experience forward,” said Dan Riccio, Apple’s senior vice president of Hardware Engineering in an emailed statement today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;After a delay of over a year since it was first announced in September of 2017, the AirPower charging mat has become something of a focal point for Apple’s recent habit of announcing envelope tickling products and not actually shipping them on time. The AirPods, famously, had a bit of a delay before becoming widely available, and were shipped in limited quantities before finally hitting their stride and becoming a genuine cultural moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;AirPower, however, has had far more time to marinate in the soup of public opinion since it was announced. Along with recent MacBook keyboard troubles, this has functioned as a sort of flash point over discussion that something isn’t right with Apple’s hardware processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;Everything I’ve personally heard (Apple is saying nothing officially) about the AirPower delay has been related to tough engineering problems related to the laws of physics. Specifically, I’ve heard that they ran too hot because the 3D charging coils in close proximity to one another required very, very cautious power management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed breakout&quot; readability=&quot;7.5405405405405&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-width=&quot;550&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot; readability=&quot;9.2162162162162&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Always worth reading &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/gruber?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@gruber&lt;/a&gt;’s show recaps. The AirPower situation is real – heat is a problem and it was shown off too early. Sometimes Apple does this and eng rises to the challenge and delivers. Sometimes, physics. &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/2YNlpPO1qO&quot;&gt;https://t.co/2YNlpPO1qO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Matthew Panzarino (@panzer) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/panzer/status/1041363624755781638?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;September 16, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;Obviously, it would do Apple very little good to release a charging mat that caused devices to overheat, perhaps even to the point of damage. So, it has canceled the project. If you know more about this, feel free to reach out, I’m fascinated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;There have been other scenarios where Apple has pushed the hardware envelope hard and managed to pull it off and ship them, the iPhone 7 Plus, its first with a twin-lens system, being one that jumps to mind. Apple had a fallback plan in a single-lens version but at some point had to commit and step off a ledge to get it done in time to ship — even though knowing they still had problems to solve. Apple has done this many times over the years, but has managed to ship a lot of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;AirPower, however, was the other kind of case. The project was apparently canceled so recently that boxes of the new AirPod cases &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/rjonesy/status/1111629174593208322&quot;&gt;even have pictures of AirPower&lt;/a&gt; on them and the new AirPod sets have mentions of AirPower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a very, very rare public misstep for Apple. Never, throughout the discussion about when AirPower might be released, did the overall trend of the discussion lean toward “never.” That’s a testament to the ability of its hardware engineering teams to consistently execute features that seemed to be nearly impossible over the years. In this case, it appears that the engineering issues have proven, at least at this point, insurmountable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fact of the matter is that hardware is, well, hard. The basic concepts of wireless charging are well known and established, but by promising the ability to place multiple devices anywhere on a pad, allowing them to charge simultaneously while communicating charge levels and rates, Apple set its bar incredibly high for AirPower. Too high, in this case.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 19:18:32 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>gtCameron</dc:creator>
<og:title>Apple cancels AirPower product, citing inability to meet its high standards for hardware</og:title>
<og:description>Apple has canceled the AirPower product completely, citing difficulty meeting its own standards. “After much effort, we’ve concluded AirPower will not achieve our high standards and we have cancelled the project. We apologize to those customers who were looking forward to this launch. We continue t…</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/dims1.jpg?w=600</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2019/03/29/apple-cancels-airpower-product-citing-inability-to-meet-its-high-standards-for-hardware/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/29/apple-cancels-airpower-product-citing-inability-to-meet-its-high-standards-for-hardware/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why GNU grep is fast (2010)</title>
<link>https://lists.freebsd.org/pipermail/freebsd-current/2010-August/019310.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://lists.freebsd.org/pipermail/freebsd-current/2010-August/019310.html</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;title&gt;why GNU grep is fast&lt;/title&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;Index&quot; href=&quot;index.html&quot; /&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;made&quot; href=&quot;mailto:freebsd-current%40freebsd.org?Subject=why%20GNU%20grep%20is%20fast&amp;amp;In-Reply-To=&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;robots&quot; content=&quot;index,nofollow&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;Content-Type&quot; content=&quot;text/html; charset=utf-8&quot; /&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;Previous&quot; href=&quot;019322.html&quot; /&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;Next&quot; href=&quot;019323.html&quot; /&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body bgcolor=&quot;#FFFFFF&quot; id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;65.150861023527&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mike Haertel&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:freebsd-current%40freebsd.org?Subject=why%20GNU%20grep%20is%20fast&amp;amp;In-Reply-To=&quot; title=&quot;why GNU grep is fast&quot;&gt;mike at ducky.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sat Aug 21 03:00:30 UTC 2010&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;pre&gt;
Hi Gabor,

I am the original author of GNU grep.  I am also a FreeBSD user,
although I live on -stable (and older) and rarely pay attention
to -current.

However, while searching the -current mailing list for an unrelated
reason, I stumbled across some flamage regarding BSD grep vs GNU grep
performance.  You may have noticed that discussion too...

Anyway, just FYI, here's a quick summary of where GNU grep gets
its speed.  Hopefully you can carry these ideas over to BSD grep.

#1 trick: GNU grep is fast because it AVOIDS LOOKING AT
EVERY INPUT BYTE.

#2 trick: GNU grep is fast because it EXECUTES VERY FEW
INSTRUCTIONS FOR EACH BYTE that it *does* look at.

GNU grep uses the well-known Boyer-Moore algorithm, which looks
first for the final letter of the target string, and uses a lookup
table to tell it how far ahead it can skip in the input whenever
it finds a non-matching character.

GNU grep also unrolls the inner loop of Boyer-Moore, and sets up
the Boyer-Moore delta table entries in such a way that it doesn't
need to do the loop exit test at every unrolled step.  The result
of this is that, in the limit, GNU grep averages fewer than 3 x86
instructions executed for each input byte it actually looks at
(and it skips many bytes entirely).

See &quot;Fast String Searching&quot;, by Andrew Hume and Daniel Sunday,
in the November 1991 issue of Software Practice &amp;amp; Experience, for
a good discussion of Boyer-Moore implementation tricks.  It's
available as a free PDF online.

Once you have fast search, you'll find you also need fast input.

GNU grep uses raw Unix input system calls and avoids copying data
after reading it.

Moreover, GNU grep AVOIDS BREAKING THE INPUT INTO LINES.  Looking
for newlines would slow grep down by a factor of several times,
because to find the newlines it would have to look at every byte!

So instead of using line-oriented input, GNU grep reads raw data into
a large buffer, searches the buffer using Boyer-Moore, and only when
it finds a match does it go and look for the bounding newlines.
(Certain command line options like -n disable this optimization.)

Finally, when I was last the maintainer of GNU grep (15+ years ago...),
GNU grep also tried very hard to set things up so that the *kernel*
could ALSO avoid handling every byte of the input, by using mmap()
instead of read() for file input.  At the time, using read() caused
most Unix versions to do extra copying.  Since GNU grep passed out
of my hands, it appears that use of mmap became non-default, but you
can still get it via --mmap.  And at least in cases where the data
is already file system buffer caches, mmap is still faster:

  $ time sh -c 'find . -type f -print | xargs grep -l 123456789abcdef'
  real  0m1.530s
  user  0m0.230s
  sys   0m1.357s
  $ time sh -c 'find . -type f -print | xargs grep --mmap -l 123456789abcdef'
  real  0m1.201s
  user  0m0.330s
  sys   0m0.929s

[workload was a 648 megabyte MH mail folder containing 41000 messages]
So even nowadays, using --mmap can be worth a &amp;gt;20% speedup.

Summary:

- Use Boyer-Moore (and unroll its inner loop a few times).

- Roll your own unbuffered input using raw system calls.  Avoid copying
  the input bytes before searching them.  (Do, however, use buffered
  *output*.  The normal grep scenario is that the amount of output is
  small compared to the amount of input, so the overhead of output
  buffer copying is small, while savings due to avoiding many small
  unbuffered writes can be large.)

- Don't look for newlines in the input until after you've found a match.

- Try to set things up (page-aligned buffers, page-sized read chunks,
  optionally use mmap) so the kernel can ALSO avoid copying the bytes.

The key to making programs fast is to make them do practically nothing. ;-)

Regards,

        Mike
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lists.freebsd.org/mailman/listinfo/freebsd-current&quot;&gt;More information about the freebsd-current mailing list&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 14:17:41 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jacobedawson</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://lists.freebsd.org/pipermail/freebsd-current/2010-August/019310.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Dogs demonstrate the existence of an epileptic seizure odour in humans</title>
<link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-019-40721-4</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-019-40721-4</guid>
<description>&lt;h3 class=&quot;h3 strong mb4&quot; data-test=&quot;sub-heading&quot;&gt;Ethics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study received approval by the institutional review board of OHS de Lorraine for collection techniques used to obtain odour samples from patients with epilepsy. All institutional (Medical Mutts) and published guidelines (Assistance Dogs International) for the use of positive reinforcement in the care and use of the dogs were followed. The Animal Ethics Committee of Rennes was consulted for this study and confirmed there was no need to request an authorization for this research, since it did not affect dog welfare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The present research was non-invasive and did not involve pharmacological interventions. Hence, in accordance with the Ethics Committee’s guidelines, parents gave only an informed written consent to allow the child’s participation in the experiment prior to their inclusion in the study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;narrow-divider&quot;/&gt;&lt;h3 class=&quot;h3 strong mb4&quot; data-test=&quot;sub-heading&quot;&gt;Subjects&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Five trained dogs participated in this study (Supplementary Table &lt;a data-track=&quot;click&quot; data-track-label=&quot;link&quot; data-track-action=&quot;supplementary material anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-019-40721-4#MOESM1&quot;&gt;S2&lt;/a&gt;). All subjects lived in Medical Mutts facilities (USA) and had never been exposed to the experimental five patient odours. Medical Mutts selected dogs from shelters to be trained by professional trainers as service dogs. Selection criteria included temperament traits compatible for service dog training&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a data-track=&quot;click&quot; data-track-action=&quot;reference anchor&quot; data-track-label=&quot;link&quot; data-test=&quot;citation-ref&quot; aria-label=&quot;Reference 40&quot; title=&quot;Haverbeke, A., Laporte, B., Depiereux, E., Giffroy, J.-M. &amp;amp; Diederich, C. Training methods of military dog handlers and their effects on the team&amp;#x2019;s performances. Appl. Anim. Behav. Sci. 113, 110&amp;#x2013;122 (2008).&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-019-40721-4#ref-CR40&quot; id=&quot;ref-link-section-d14738e1130&quot;&gt;40&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and physical aptitudes. Dogs are trained for obedience for certification for public access in addition to scent discrimination. Dogs spent one hour per day, five days per week in a training session&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a data-track=&quot;click&quot; data-track-action=&quot;reference anchor&quot; data-track-label=&quot;link&quot; data-test=&quot;citation-ref&quot; aria-label=&quot;Reference 15&quot; title=&quot;Hardin, D. S., Anderson, W. &amp;amp; Cattet, J. Dogs Can Be Successfully Trained to Alert to Hypoglycemia Samples from Patients with Type 1 Diabetes. Diabetes Ther. 6, 509&amp;#x2013;517 (2015).&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-019-40721-4#ref-CR15&quot; id=&quot;ref-link-section-d14738e1134&quot;&gt;15&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;narrow-divider&quot;/&gt;&lt;h3 class=&quot;h3 strong mb4&quot; data-test=&quot;sub-heading&quot;&gt;Odour samples&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patients were recruited in the Healthcare Centre OHS Flavigny, Flavigny sur Moselle, France. Ten participants were initially invited to participate after medical recommendations. One declined and the other 4 did not experience a seizure through the sample collection time of one week in December 2017. Thus, odours were collected from 5 females who were residents of the Healthcare Centre OHS. All had a confirmed diagnosis of epilepsy (See Supplementary Table &lt;a data-track=&quot;click&quot; data-track-label=&quot;link&quot; data-track-action=&quot;supplementary material anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-019-40721-4#MOESM1&quot;&gt;S3&lt;/a&gt;) and none experienced psychogenic non-epileptic seizures. Psychogenic non-epileptic seizures (exclusive or in addition to epileptic seizures) were actually a factor of exclusion when recruiting patients on the basis of their medical diagnosis. Since they all lived in a medicalized structure at the time of the sampling, the diagnosis was further confirmed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They received the same food without dietary restrictions. Since the seizures could be experienced at any time, the collection of epilepsy seizure samples could occur randomly at any time (night or day), whereas all other samples were collected during day. Patients were not given any specific recommendation (e.g. regarding hormonal contraception, perfume, smoking etc.), so as to maintain an “ecological” individual variability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;narrow-divider&quot;/&gt;&lt;h3 class=&quot;h3 strong mb4&quot; data-test=&quot;sub-heading&quot;&gt;Odour sampling procedure&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three types of samples were collected: (a) a “seizure sample”, collected during or right after (&amp;lt;5 min) an ictal event; (b) a “physical exercise sample”, collected right after (&amp;lt;5 min) moderate exercise (defined as 1 min during which the patient ran approximately 30 m, and did leg and arm movements as step-touch and punches). Physical exercise samples served as control for movements or arousal that can be made or experienced during a seizure&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a data-track=&quot;click&quot; data-track-action=&quot;reference anchor&quot; data-track-label=&quot;link&quot; data-test=&quot;citation-ref&quot; aria-label=&quot;Reference 41&quot; title=&quot;King, J. et al. Isoprene and acetone concentration profiles during exercise on an ergometer. J. Breath Res. 3, 027006 (2009).&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-019-40721-4#ref-CR41&quot; id=&quot;ref-link-section-d14738e1162&quot;&gt;41&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a data-track=&quot;click&quot; data-track-action=&quot;reference anchor&quot; data-track-label=&quot;link&quot; data-test=&quot;citation-ref&quot; aria-label=&quot;Reference 42&quot; title=&quot;King, J. et al. Dynamic profiles of volatile organic compounds in exhaled breath as determined by a coupled PTR-MS/GC-MS study. Physiol. Meas. 31, 1169 (2010).&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-019-40721-4#ref-CR42&quot; id=&quot;ref-link-section-d14738e1165&quot;&gt;42&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. And (c) a “day sample” was collected at a pseudo-random moment during calm activity (e.g. drawing, paper crafting) in day time. The non-seizure samples were collected a minimum of 6 hours before or after a seizure in order to avoid a pre- or post-ictal collection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For each patient, two physical exercise samples were collected on two different days and four day samples on four different days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Odour collection was performed in accordance with the procedure used at Medical Mutts for training assistance dogs&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a data-track=&quot;click&quot; data-track-action=&quot;reference anchor&quot; data-track-label=&quot;link&quot; data-test=&quot;citation-ref&quot; aria-label=&quot;Reference 15&quot; title=&quot;Hardin, D. S., Anderson, W. &amp;amp; Cattet, J. Dogs Can Be Successfully Trained to Alert to Hypoglycemia Samples from Patients with Type 1 Diabetes. Diabetes Ther. 6, 509&amp;#x2013;517 (2015).&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-019-40721-4#ref-CR15&quot; id=&quot;ref-link-section-d14738e1175&quot;&gt;15&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;: Patients were instructed to use a sterile cotton pad (10*10 cm, 4 fold) to wipe their hands, forehead and back of the neck, allowing a multiplicity of odour origins. The cotton pad was then placed into a zip-locked bag (Ziplock brand, SC Johnson, Racine, WI, USA) and the patient was instructed to exhale into the bag before sealing it. Two cotton pads were collected from each patient, for each of the 7 types of odour. Each bag was labelled with the patient’s initials, day and time of collection and the corresponding odour type (normal, physical exercise or seizure). The samples were stored in the freezer (Temperature −12 °C) then shipped from France to USA at ambient temperature and stored again in the freezer until use (average of 47 days, SD = 18). Freezing has been shown to preserve samples of human body odour without altering perceptions of these odours and freeze–thaw cycles to not affect sample quality&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a data-track=&quot;click&quot; data-track-action=&quot;reference anchor&quot; data-track-label=&quot;link&quot; data-test=&quot;citation-ref&quot; aria-label=&quot;Reference 43&quot; title=&quot;Lenochova, P., Roberts, S. C. &amp;amp; Havlicek, J. Methods of Human Body Odor Sampling: The Effect of Freezing. Chem. Senses 34, 127&amp;#x2013;138 (2009).&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-019-40721-4#ref-CR43&quot; id=&quot;ref-link-section-d14738e1179&quot;&gt;43&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;narrow-divider&quot;/&gt;&lt;h3 class=&quot;h3 strong mb4&quot; data-test=&quot;sub-heading&quot;&gt;Training&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dogs that participated in the study were trained using positive reinforcement methods [12, 13]. They underwent the general training for assistance dog (30 commands, staying under control in public areas, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More specifically, the training for SAD required three main steps. First a positive association is created between the scent of a seizure and treats in order to induce a conditioned emotional response. Then the dog learns to go to the scent and to stand still above it. This indication behaviour (dog standing above the scent) is developed by adding distance and duration and using the command “Check”. The second step consisted in a discrimination task, for additional scents (distractors, inter-ictal scent) were progressively added and the dog learned to only indicate the seizure scent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the third phase of training, the seizure scent was placed on a person. The ‘stay-stand’ indication was replaced by teaching the dog to alert by a poke of the nose on the person’s body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The odours used for training were not from the patients. Therefore, the dogs included in the present study were completely unfamiliar with these particuliar odours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;narrow-divider&quot;/&gt;&lt;h3 class=&quot;h3 strong mb4&quot; data-test=&quot;sub-heading&quot;&gt;Experimental Setup&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tests took place from January 2018 to February 2018, in a closed room (9.1 × 6.1 m, 4 m high, 21 °C in average) (Supplementary Fig. &lt;a data-track=&quot;click&quot; data-track-label=&quot;link&quot; data-track-action=&quot;supplementary material anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-019-40721-4#MOESM1&quot;&gt;S1&lt;/a&gt;) in the training facility. No experimenter was present in the testing room during a trial (see also&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a data-track=&quot;click&quot; data-track-action=&quot;reference anchor&quot; data-track-label=&quot;link&quot; data-test=&quot;citation-ref&quot; aria-label=&quot;Reference 15&quot; title=&quot;Hardin, D. S., Anderson, W. &amp;amp; Cattet, J. Dogs Can Be Successfully Trained to Alert to Hypoglycemia Samples from Patients with Type 1 Diabetes. Diabetes Ther. 6, 509&amp;#x2013;517 (2015).&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-019-40721-4#ref-CR15&quot; id=&quot;ref-link-section-d14738e1214&quot;&gt;15&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;). Experimenter was in a room nearby, separated from the first one by a wooden door. One camera was linked to a monitoring system, and another recorded the trials. At the beginning of a trial, the room was open, the trainer gave the command (“Check”), then closed the door and stayed out of view or reach in the second room. The dog was free to explore the experimental set-up until the correct identification of the seizure sample. It was then rewarded with a treat from an automatic dispenser remotely activated by the trainer (Pet Tutor®). Then the trainer opened the door and called the dog out of the room. The dog stayed in the second room in between two trials, while the experimenter changed the samples and put the cans in the right locations for the next trial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The experimental set-up consisted of seven steel cans (18 cm high × 17 cm in diameter), each containing one small canister (5.2 cm in diameter, 2 cm high) in which one odour sample was placed. These canisters prevented the dog from being in direct contact with samples. The cans were in a semicircle arrangement, equidistant (2.08 m) from the Pet Tutor®. Each can contained an odour sample that could be either a seizure, physical exercise or calm activity sample. Compared to the literature on similar experiments, this is a high average for the number of samples presented in line-up methods and the distance between cans (about 50 centimeters) was comparable&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a data-track=&quot;click&quot; data-track-action=&quot;reference anchor&quot; data-track-label=&quot;link&quot; data-test=&quot;citation-ref&quot; aria-label=&quot;Reference 8&quot; title=&quot;Sonoda, H. et al. Colorectal cancer screening with odour material by canine scent detection. Gut gut.2010.218305,   https://doi.org/10.1136/gut.2010.218305    (2011).&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-019-40721-4#ref-CR8&quot; id=&quot;ref-link-section-d14738e1221&quot;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a data-track=&quot;click&quot; data-track-action=&quot;reference anchor&quot; data-track-label=&quot;link&quot; data-test=&quot;citation-ref&quot; aria-label=&quot;Reference 15&quot; title=&quot;Hardin, D. S., Anderson, W. &amp;amp; Cattet, J. Dogs Can Be Successfully Trained to Alert to Hypoglycemia Samples from Patients with Type 1 Diabetes. Diabetes Ther. 6, 509&amp;#x2013;517 (2015).&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-019-40721-4#ref-CR15&quot; id=&quot;ref-link-section-d14738e1224&quot;&gt;15&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a data-track=&quot;click&quot; data-track-action=&quot;reference anchor&quot; data-track-label=&quot;link&quot; data-test=&quot;citation-ref&quot; aria-label=&quot;Reference 26&quot; title=&quot;Ehmann, R. et al. Canine scent detection in the diagnosis of lung cancer: revisiting a puzzling phenomenon. Eur. Respir. J. 39, 669&amp;#x2013;676 (2012).&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-019-40721-4#ref-CR26&quot; id=&quot;ref-link-section-d14738e1227&quot;&gt;26&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At each test, all seven cans contained an odour from the same person: one seizure sample, two physical exercise samples and four calm sample.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;narrow-divider&quot;/&gt;&lt;h3 class=&quot;h3 strong mb4&quot; data-test=&quot;sub-heading&quot;&gt;Test procedure&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trials took place as follows: each dog had the first 5 trials using the same person’s odour, a 2-hour break, and then one trial with each of the 4 remaining patients (See Fig. &lt;a data-track=&quot;click&quot; data-track-label=&quot;link&quot; data-track-action=&quot;figure anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-019-40721-4#Fig2&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;). Thus, each dog had 9 trials in one day. Each test trial lasted a maximum of 5 minutes, with a 2 min break between each trial in order to remove and replace the cans. Odour locations were pseudo-randomly determined prior to the sessions and changed between trials, with the constraint that the same location could not be used more than three times in a row for the same type of odour in order to avoid learning bias and inducing A-not-B errors (Smith &lt;em&gt;et al&lt;/em&gt;., 1999).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;narrow-divider&quot;/&gt;&lt;h3 class=&quot;h3 strong mb4&quot; data-test=&quot;sub-heading&quot;&gt;Behavioural coding&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each trial was videotaped (30 fps, Sony Handycam HDR-CX380) and coded using frame-by-frame playback for accuracy of determination of investigatory behaviour. The latency of first response was measured as well as the time spent by the dog in the olfactory investigation of cans (i.e. nose at less than ten centimeters from the cans&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a data-track=&quot;click&quot; data-track-action=&quot;reference anchor&quot; data-track-label=&quot;link&quot; data-test=&quot;citation-ref&quot; title=&quot;Horowitz, A. Smelling themselves: Dogs investigate their own odours longer when modified in an &amp;#x201C;olfactory mirror&amp;#x201D; test. Behav. Processes 143, 17&amp;#x2013;24 (2017).&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-019-40721-4#ref-CR44&quot; id=&quot;ref-link-section-d14738e1258&quot;&gt;44&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a data-track=&quot;click&quot; data-track-action=&quot;reference anchor&quot; data-track-label=&quot;link&quot; data-test=&quot;citation-ref&quot; title=&quot;Lisberg, A. E. &amp;amp; Snowdon, C. T. The effects of sex, gonadectomy and status on investigation patterns of unfamiliar conspecific urine in domestic dogs, Canis familiaris. Anim. Behav. 77, 1147&amp;#x2013;1154 (2009).&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-019-40721-4#ref-CR45&quot; id=&quot;ref-link-section-d14738e1258_1&quot;&gt;45&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a data-track=&quot;click&quot; data-track-action=&quot;reference anchor&quot; data-track-label=&quot;link&quot; data-test=&quot;citation-ref&quot; aria-label=&quot;Reference 46&quot; title=&quot;Salvin, H. E., McGrath, C., McGreevy, P. D. &amp;amp; Valenzuela, M. J. Development of a novel paradigm for the measurement of olfactory discrimination in dogs (Canis familiaris): A pilot study. J. Vet. Behav. Clin. Appl. Res. 7, 3&amp;#x2013;10 (2012).&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-019-40721-4#ref-CR46&quot; id=&quot;ref-link-section-d14738e1261&quot;&gt;46&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;). Given the indication behavior (remain standing with the head above the cans), an indication was counted if it lasted more than 3 seconds. The same person (A.C.), blind to the cans’ contents, coded all trials. Another coder, unfamiliar with the goals of the study, verified the reliability of this coding on all trials. Inter-observer agreement was high (&lt;em&gt;κ&lt;/em&gt; = 0.91).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;narrow-divider&quot;/&gt;&lt;h3 class=&quot;h3 strong mb4&quot; data-test=&quot;sub-heading&quot;&gt;Statistical analyses&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sensitivity and specificity were calculated after pooling the data across all trials for all dogs in accordance with&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a data-track=&quot;click&quot; data-track-action=&quot;reference anchor&quot; data-track-label=&quot;link&quot; data-test=&quot;citation-ref&quot; aria-label=&quot;Reference 15&quot; title=&quot;Hardin, D. S., Anderson, W. &amp;amp; Cattet, J. Dogs Can Be Successfully Trained to Alert to Hypoglycemia Samples from Patients with Type 1 Diabetes. Diabetes Ther. 6, 509&amp;#x2013;517 (2015).&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-019-40721-4#ref-CR15&quot; id=&quot;ref-link-section-d14738e1277&quot;&gt;15&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, as the data were not normally distributed, non-parametric statistical tests were used&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a data-track=&quot;click&quot; data-track-action=&quot;reference anchor&quot; data-track-label=&quot;link&quot; data-test=&quot;citation-ref&quot; aria-label=&quot;Reference 47&quot; title=&quot;Siegel, S. Nonparametric statistics for the behavioral sciences (1956).&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-019-40721-4#ref-CR47&quot; id=&quot;ref-link-section-d14738e1284&quot;&gt;47&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Performances for individual dogs were statistically assessed with binomial tests. A Friedman test compared the time spent exploring the different sample categories, with all dogs and trials pooled. To assess potential differences between the odours of each patient, all dogs were pooled on the cumulated exploration time for the five different patients (first presentation of the repeated person and the last four persons). The concordance among dogs’ performances according to persons was estimated using a Kendall test by permutation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 14:12:55 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>howard941</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-019-40721-4</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Dogs demonstrate the existence of an epileptic seizure odour in humans</og:title>
<og:image>https://media.springernature.com/m685/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41598-019-40721-4/MediaObjects/41598_2019_40721_Fig1_HTML.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-019-40721-4</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Boston Dynamics’ new robot stacks boxes [video]</title>
<link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5iV_hB08Uns</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5iV_hB08Uns</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;eow-description&quot; class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Handle is a mobile manipulation robot designed for logistics. Handle autonomously performs mixed SKU pallet building and depalletizing after initialization and localizing against the pallets. The on-board vision system on Handle tracks the marked pallets for navigation and finds individual boxes for grasping and placing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When Handle places a boxes onto a pallet, it uses force control to nestle each box up against its neighbors. The boxes used in the video weigh about 5 Kg (11 lbs), but the robot is designed to handle boxes up to (15 Kg) (33 lb). This version of Handle works with pallets that are 1.2 m deep and 1.7 m tall (48 inches deep and 68 inches tall).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 13:25:33 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>oedmarap</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5iV_hB08Uns</og:url>
<og:title>Handle Robot Reimagined for Logistics</og:title>
<og:image>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/5iV_hB08Uns/hqdefault.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Handle is a mobile manipulation robot designed for logistics. Handle autonomously performs mixed SKU pallet building and depalletizing after initialization a...</og:description>
<og:type>video.other</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5iV_hB08Uns</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>OCaml on Baremetal Shakti RISC-V Processor</title>
<link>http://kcsrk.info/ocaml/riscv/shakti/2019/03/29/1400-ocaml-baremetal-shakti/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://kcsrk.info/ocaml/riscv/shakti/2019/03/29/1400-ocaml-baremetal-shakti/</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;65.908979089791&quot;&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;post-date&quot;&gt;29 Mar 2019&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been 3 months since I joined &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iitm.ac.in/&quot;&gt;IIT Madras&lt;/a&gt; and it has been good fun so far. Along with the members of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://rise.cse.iitm.ac.in/&quot;&gt;RISE group&lt;/a&gt;, we’ve initiated a project to build secure applications on top of secure extensions of the open-source &lt;a href=&quot;http://shakti.org.in/&quot;&gt;Shakti&lt;/a&gt; RISC-V processor ecosystem. Unsurprisingly, my language of choice to build the applications is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ocaml.org/&quot;&gt;OCaml&lt;/a&gt;. Given the availability of rich ecosystem of libraries under the &lt;a href=&quot;https://mirage.io/&quot;&gt;MirageOS&lt;/a&gt; library operating system for building unikernels, we hope to minimise the amount of unsafe C code that the hardware has to contend with and protect exploits against. As a first step, we have managed to get OCaml programs to run on directly on top of the Shakti processor running in simulation under QEMU and Spike ISA simulators &lt;em&gt;without an intervening operating system&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A custom bootloader performs the necessary hardware initialisation and transfers control directly to the OCaml program. We have &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/shaktiproject/tools/shakti-tee/ocaml-baremetal-riscv&quot;&gt;open-sourced&lt;/a&gt; all of the tools necessary to build your own kernel. This handy &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/shaktiproject/tools/shakti-tee/ocaml-baremetal-riscv/tree/master/docker&quot;&gt;dockerfile&lt;/a&gt; documents the entire process. For the impatient, an image is available in the dockerhub:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-bash highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;11.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;18&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;docker run &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-it&lt;/span&gt; iitmshakti/riscv-ocaml-baremetal:0.1.0

&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# Write your program&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'let _ = print_endline &quot;A camel treads on hardware!&quot;'&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; hello.ml
&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# Compile for Shakti&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;ocamlopt &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-output-obj&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-o&lt;/span&gt; payload.o hello.ml
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;file payload.o
payload.o: ELF 64-bit LSB relocatable, UCB RISC-V, version 1 &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;SYSV&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;, not stripped

&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# Link with bootcode and build the kernel&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;make &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-C&lt;/span&gt; ../build
make: Entering directory &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'/root/ocaml-baremetal-riscv/build'&lt;/span&gt;
make[1]: Entering directory &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'/root/ocaml-baremetal-riscv/build'&lt;/span&gt;
make[2]: Entering directory &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'/root/ocaml-baremetal-riscv/build'&lt;/span&gt;
make[2]: Leaving directory &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'/root/ocaml-baremetal-riscv/build'&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt; 64%] Built target boot
make[2]: Entering directory &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'/root/ocaml-baremetal-riscv/build'&lt;/span&gt;
make[2]: Leaving directory &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'/root/ocaml-baremetal-riscv/build'&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt; 78%] Built target freestanding-compat
make[2]: Entering directory &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'/root/ocaml-baremetal-riscv/build'&lt;/span&gt;
make[2]: Leaving directory &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'/root/ocaml-baremetal-riscv/build'&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt; 85%] Built target asmrun_t
make[2]: Entering directory &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'/root/ocaml-baremetal-riscv/build'&lt;/span&gt;
make[2]: Leaving directory &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'/root/ocaml-baremetal-riscv/build'&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt; 92%] Built target nolibc_t
make[2]: Entering directory &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'/root/ocaml-baremetal-riscv/build'&lt;/span&gt;
make[2]: Leaving directory &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'/root/ocaml-baremetal-riscv/build'&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;100%] Built target kernel
make[1]: Leaving directory &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'/root/ocaml-baremetal-riscv/build'&lt;/span&gt;
make: Leaving directory &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'/root/ocaml-baremetal-riscv/build'&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;file kernel 
kernel: ELF 64-bit LSB executable, UCB RISC-V, version 1 &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;SYSV&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;, statically linked, with debug_info, not stripped

&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# Run under spike RISC-V ISA simulator&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;spike kernel
ocaml-boot: heap@0x80042be8 stack@0x8002fbc0
A camel treads on hardware!
ocaml-boot: caml runtime returned. shutting down!

&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# Run under QEMU&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;qemu-system-riscv64 &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-machine&lt;/span&gt; spike_v1.10 &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-smp&lt;/span&gt; 1 &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-m&lt;/span&gt; 1G &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-serial&lt;/span&gt; stdio &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-kernel&lt;/span&gt; kernel
VNC server running on 127.0.0.1:5900
ocaml-boot: heap@0x80042be8 stack@0x8002fbc0
A camel treads on hardware!
ocaml-boot: caml runtime returned. shutting down!
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The immediate next step will be getting the code to run on a Shakti softcore on an FPGA. In addition to targeting high-end FPGAs, we will also be targeting the $100 &lt;a href=&quot;https://store.digilentinc.com/arty-a7-artix-7-fpga-development-board-for-makers-and-hobbyists/&quot;&gt;Arty A7&lt;/a&gt; hobbyist board and release all of the software under liberal open-source licenses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further along, we will port mirage libraries to Shakti following similar to the setup in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/well-typed-lightbulbs/&quot;&gt;Well-typed lightbulbs&lt;/a&gt; and implementing hardware security enhancements in Shakti for preventing spatial and temporal attacks while running unsafe C code (with the ability to dynamically turn it off when running OCaml!), hardware-assisted compartments, etc. Lots of exciting possibilities on the horizon!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;acknowledgements&quot;&gt;Acknowledgements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much of this work was done by the incredible &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sl33k&quot;&gt;Malte&lt;/a&gt;, who is a visiting student at IIT Madras on a semester away from Leibniz University Hannover, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/arjun-menon/?originalSubdomain=in&quot;&gt;Arjun&lt;/a&gt;, Lavanya, Ambika, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cse.iitm.ac.in/~chester/&quot;&gt;Chester&lt;/a&gt;, and the rest of the Shakti team. The RISC-V port of OCaml is developed and maintained by &lt;a href=&quot;https://nojb.github.io/&quot;&gt;Nicolás Ojeda Bär&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 11:20:27 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>lelf</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://kcsrk.info/ocaml/riscv/shakti/2019/03/29/1400-ocaml-baremetal-shakti/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>‘The Wolf of Wall Street’ film was also a real-life scam</title>
<link>https://melmagazine.com/en-us/story/the-perfect-irony-that-the-wolf-of-wall-street-was-also-a-real-life-scam</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://melmagazine.com/en-us/story/the-perfect-irony-that-the-wolf-of-wall-street-was-also-a-real-life-scam</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;It’s April 2013 in New York. Ensconced in a Chelsea studio bubbling with celebrities and champagne, an international man of mystery records his vanity music project. The ballad the 30-year-old sings is called “Void of a Legend.” The man calls himself Jho Low. At one point in his recording session, rapper Busta Rhymes and super-producer Pharrell Williams show up. Low shouts at Busta, “Yo! I own you! You’re my bitch!”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Malaysian financial wunderkind is drunkenly referring to the fact that he now co-owns&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/EMI&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;EMI Group Limited&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, a music publishing company, and thus, Busta’s rhymes. Nonetheless, it’s obviously a tense moment — a non-black man telling a black man that he&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;owns&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;him. Pharrell has to step in and calm the situation down. This is the beginning of the end, but no one knows it yet.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Five months later, halfway around the world in Thailand, a man named Xavier Justo plots revenge against his former business partners, men who are also partnered with Jho Low. A son of Spaniards who’d emigrated to Switzerland, Justo is a former Swiss banker, but more importantly, he’s a man with a world-shaking grudge. His ex-partners cut him out of a business that’s suddenly, mysteriously, worth more than a billion dollars. He wants the $2 million promised to him in his severance agreement that he never received, money he feels is rightfully his.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;He&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2016/jul/28/1mdb-inside-story-worlds-biggest-financial-scandal-malaysia&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;decides to blackmail his former partners&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;and emails them a threat: He has 90 gigabytes of incriminating emails and data on illegal investments and money transfers; unless he gets his two mill, he’ll leak it to the press. It’s a risky move. After all, his former partners have powerful friends — one of the co-founders of the company is a Saudi prince.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In that same summer of 2013, Leonardo DiCaprio has just finished shooting&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Wolf of Wall Street&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;. It’s one of his finest performances. The film details the rise and fall of a financial crimes mastermind, Jordan Belfort, based on&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedailybeast.com/the-real-wolf-of-wall-street-jordan-belforts-vulgar-memoirs&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;his searingly-honest memoir&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. The great irony is that there’s a far greedier international money-laundering scheme secretly paying for the film. One day, it will probably inspire best-selling books and possibly a movie, too. Which raises the question: Who will play Leonardo DiCaprio?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://giphy.com/gifs/street-wall-jordan-LrC1m7Ay3xsha&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.giphy.com/media/LrC1m7Ay3xsha/giphy.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Wolf Of Wall Street Laugh GIF - Find &amp;amp; Share on GIPHY&quot; width=&quot;365&quot; height=&quot;254&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Because whoever it is, they’ll have a big part in the film — i.e., both Low and DiCaprio have starring roles in a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.justice.gov/opa/press-release/file/973671/download&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;251-page Department of Justice indictment&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;documenting the multibillion dollar criminal scheme. Low, the alleged mastermind of what Attorney General Loretta Lynch&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.justice.gov/opa/speech/attorney-general-loretta-e-lynch-delivers-remarks-press-conference-announcing-significant&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;referred to as the greatest kleptocracy the world has ever seen&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, was DiCaprio’s friend. They’d partied together in Vegas and Cannes; they schemed together to beat the system in Hollywood. Most of all, though, he handed DiCaprio the money to make his dream project —&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Wolf of Wall Street&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;— that no one in Hollywood would bankroll.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Again, in a cosmic irony, DiCaprio desperately wanted to make a movie that deeply examined the sort of greed that rots the soul and ruins our natural world, yet this highly intelligent, sensitive actor never recognized this same greed when he partnered with it in reality. He somehow missed it when Low gave him a Basquiat painting worth $9.2 million and a Picasso worth $3.2 million. He also missed it when, in that same summer of 2013, two producers of the original&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Dumb and Dumber&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;were excluded from the sequel and&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://deadline.com/2013/07/dumb-and-dumber-sequel-lawsuit-heats-up-546882/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;countersued Red Granite&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, the production company that was making both that movie and&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Wolf of Wall Street.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;The veteran producers&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://sarawak.s3.amazonaws.com/documents/Steve-Stabler-Brad-Krevoy%201-First_Amended_Complaint.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;alleged in their lawsuit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, later amended, that they’d been informed of a vast criminal conspiracy underwriting the company:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;“Red Granite is funded with monies that include proceeds from offenses against a foreign nation that involve bribery of public officials, or misappropriation, theft or embezzlement of public funds by a public official. Plaintiffs are informed and believe that public officials in Asia and the Middle East have taken bribes and/or misappropriated, stolen or embezzled funds, and that those ill-gotten funds have then been invested in Red Granite.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In the wake of this multibillion dollar legal scandal, DiCaprio said nothing, right until the U.S. government filed a criminal asset forfeiture and demanded he hand over his ill-gotten artwork and an Oscar he’d been given as a gift (to be clear, though, not the one he’d earned for his work in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Revenant&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;). The feds also asked the actor to secretly testify before a grand jury.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2016/10/18/1mdb-scandal-leonardo-dicaprio-says-hes-cooperating-with-doj-in-malaysian-probe.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;In a prepared statement&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;from his reps, DiCaprio signaled his new willingness to learn about what justice will look like for the Malaysian people who were robbed by his former friend and partner, Jho Low: “Both Mr. DiCaprio and (the Leonardo DiCaprio Foundation) continue to be entirely supportive of all efforts to assure that justice is done in this matter. Mr. DiCaprio is grateful for the lead and instruction of the government on how to accomplish this.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Since they can’t get back the stolen millions used to bankroll DiCaprio’s dreams, part of accomplishing justice in this case means the U.S. government now owns the rights and royalties of&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Wolf of Wall Street&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;. As far as justice goes, it’s extremely poetic: a film about guys who believed they were above the law until they got caught by the feds was made by guys who believed they were above the law until they, too, got caught by the feds.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Art imitating life imitating art.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;* * * * *&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Low Taek Jho was born a Malaysian son of privilege in 1981, but he wasn’t from an ultra-wealthy Malaysian family. If anything, good with numbers and sharp-minded, his family placed their future in his hands. In particular, they sent him to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.harrowschool.org.uk/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Harrow&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, a private school in London founded by a charter from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Elizabeth_I_of_England&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Elizabeth I&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;back in 1572. His classmates were sons of kings and nephews of prime ministers. And in many ways, British private schools are a lot like prison — they’re a great place to learn to be a better criminal.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;To that end, Low has said his private-school days absolutely&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thestar.com.my/story/?file=%2f2010%2f7%2f29%2fnation%2f6756730&amp;amp;sec=nation&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;shaped his future&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;: “There were a few key relationships which I started to develop there. Harrow had lots of children of prominent European, Asian and Middle Eastern families. That’s when I met the former King of Jordan’s son, among others. … That’s when I felt that I built the core foundation of contacts for the future. That’s quite important, because that’s when you know them as friends, and you build the trust level for the future as opposed to meeting someone during the course of your business life.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;After Harrow, Low transferred to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wharton_School_of_the_University_of_Pennsylvania&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Wharton School of Business&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. He made a name for himself on campus with the nickname “the Asian Great Gatsby.” He was a schemer, a striver, an operator, and everyone knew it. He once invited his Wharton classmate Ivanka Trump on a gambling trip to Atlantic City that he organized. She declined his invite, or so he claimed. He told friends Ivanka said,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.com/books?id=_ulMDwAAQBAJ&amp;amp;pg=PT37&amp;amp;lpg=PT37&amp;amp;dq=shed+never+set+foot+in+one+of+her+fathers+skeevy+casinos.&amp;amp;source=bl&amp;amp;ots=yCAfRgdHUj&amp;amp;sig=ACfU3U1zQ6VsyNT-cF2aRGguc7RQejMl4w&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=2ahUKEwjt2v7L5fzgAhWsT98KHXc2ArQQ6AEwAHoECAkQAQ#v=onepage&amp;amp;q&amp;amp;f=false&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;“She’d never set foot in one of her father’s ‘skeevy casinos.’”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;It seems the socially-awkward Low had a thing for rich, mildly attractive, blonde daughters of famous American families. Because while at Wharton, Low developed a well-known crush on Paris Hilton. His roommates say he watched&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/House_of_Wax_(2005_film)&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;House of Wax&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, her debut movie, at least a half-dozen times. Little did Low know that, one day, a drunken Paris Hilton would regularly party with him, and be photographed with his sweaty, alcohol-flushed face on her shoulder.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-36357 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://melmagazine.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/image1-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;511&quot; height=&quot;453&quot; srcset=&quot;https://melmagazine.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/image1-3.jpg 511w, https://melmagazine.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/image1-3-300x266.jpg 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 511px) 100vw, 511px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;After Wharton, Low returned to Malaysia. He tried his hand at a few businesses, but none was very successful.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2015/02/09/nyregion/jho-low-young-malaysian-has-an-appetite-for-new-york.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;According to the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;New York Times&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, Low did help “a Kuwaiti bank purchase a high-rise complex.” The&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Times&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;reports that Low next “formed an investment group that included a Malaysian prince, a Kuwaiti sheikh and a friend from the United Arab Emirates who went on to become ambassador to the United States and Mexico.” After that, he partnered with Riza Aziz, a friend he’d met back when they both attended private school in London.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Together, Low and Aziz won the backing of Aziz’s stepfather,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Najib_Razak&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Najib Razak&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, a man who at the time was the Deputy Prime Minister of Malaysia, but in a very short time was elected the country’s sixth Prime Minister. Together, the trio conspired to create a state-owned development investment program. The 2008 financial meltdown had nearly killed the capitalist monetary system, but Malaysia wanted in, and in a big way.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;As such, when Low returned to the U.S. in 2009, he was suddenly insanely wealthy and eager to spend his newfound cash. He first showed-up in the gossip rags, though, not the business section. Page Six spotted him on the Manhattan nightclub scene in November 2009. In&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://pagesix.com/2009/11/10/clubs-court-low-key-mr-low/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;his very first news story&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, Low appeared the way he often would thereafter, sweaty-faced and champagne drunk — just another finance bro in Manhattan, down to treat women like objects and objects like people.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The second sentence ever written about him reads like the opening line of a fairy tale about a money launderer. As&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://pagesix.com/2009/11/10/clubs-court-low-key-mr-low/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;New York&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Post&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;reported:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;“‘A Jho Low comes around once in a lifetime,’ marveled one industry veteran.” In this instance, the industry wasn’t investment banking, it was New York nightclubs. In that same story, the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://pagesix.com/2009/11/10/clubs-court-low-key-mr-low/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Post&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;noted&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, “Low just celebrated his 28th birthday in Las Vegas, a four-day affair that started out last Wednesday at Caesars Palace, where sources said the swimming pool was stocked with bikini-clad party girls and surrounded by caged lions and tigers.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;After that pool party, Low and his birthday entourage kept things pulsing at a nightclub in the casino where Paris Hilton and Usher danced and drank with Low. Jamie Foxx reportedly gave Low a sports car as a birthday present. At the end of the article, a friend of Low’s tried to dispel the mystery but&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://pagesix.com/2009/11/10/clubs-court-low-key-mr-low/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;instead only enlarged it&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;: “He’s not an arms dealer,” said his friend. “And he doesn’t want all this publicity.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Gawker&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;smelled bullshit — and clicks. And so, it published&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://gawker.com/5401369/jho-low-manhattans-mysterious-big-spending-party-boy&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;its first story on Low&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;six hours after the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Post’&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;s. “Megan Fox was flown out to Vegas to hang out with the birthday boy, who routinely surrounds himself with models,” it reported. The gossip site also said that Low “rents several apartments in the Park Imperial on West 57th Street in Midtown that house him and his staff — including several body guards. Famous neighbors include Daniel Craig and Sean Combs.” In&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Gawker&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;’s second Low article,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://gawker.com/5403873/is-jho-low-just-a-front-for-the-real-money&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Ravi Somaiya correctly guessed&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;that Low was a front for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;real&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;foreign money. But he&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://gawker.com/5406406/the-source-of-the-jho-low-arms-dealer-rumors&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;guessed incorrectly about who the source was&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. Or at least he picked the wrong arms dealer.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Probably for that reason, Low tried to regain control of the narrative by giving his first official interview. But not to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Forbes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;or the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Wall Street Journal.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;No, he sat down for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thestar.com.my/story/?file=%2f2010%2f7%2f29%2fnation%2f6756730&amp;amp;sec=nation&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;a Q&amp;amp;A with the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Toronto Star&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. Most of what he said were banal attempts at shoving the genie back in the bottle. But one question stuck out. He was asked if he was the fall guy for his ultra-wealthy friends. Low responded, “I wouldn’t say I was the fall guy.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In the meantime, Low grew even more flagrant. In July 2010, he traveled to South Africa to watch the World Cup and was spotted with a group of people that notably included DiCaprio and Paris Hilton. Later that same month,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.com/books?id=_ulMDwAAQBAJ&amp;amp;pg=PT105&amp;amp;lpg=PT105&amp;amp;dq=%E2%80%9CShe+told+friends+that+Low+paid+around+$100,000+per+event.%E2%80%9D&amp;amp;source=bl&amp;amp;ots=yCAfUmhIYk&amp;amp;sig=ACfU3U0d8WjzcMBfoVnMj7vVR4EfYMtcaw&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=2ahUKEwi5i6OQsofhAhUCnZ4KHWWqCQMQ6AEwAHoECAEQAQ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;there were printed rumors that Low paid Hilton a million dollars to hang out and party with him in St. Tropez&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. She denied any rumors they were dating.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nypost.com/p/pagesix/paris_for_free_DDWaeRGp98XcmB7im3CcnJ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;According to the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;New York Post&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, her rep clarified and stated that “they are friends.” (Her friends, though, claimed that Low paid Hilton $100,000 each time he hung out with her.) While in St. Tropez, Low reportedly rented a yacht from billionaire Paul Allen, his mega-boat&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Tatoosh&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;, a 303-foot stupid fancy yacht, the kind that has a movie theater and a parking spot for your helicopter.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;According to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/recommends/read/billion-dollar-whale-an-absurd-tale-of-financial-fraud&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;the book&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Billion Dollar Whale&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;by Tom Wright and Bradley Hope&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, both&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;reporters, Low was by Hilton’s side as she celebrated her 29th birthday. Their entourage partied in Vegas at the Palazzo. To make it memorable, Low gave his longtime crush a Cartier watch, and then, as the book reports, Low “handed her $250,000 in gambling chips and asked her to join him at the baccarat table.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;To give you a sense of what kind of cash Low was regularly dropping: “Between October 2009 and June 2010 — a period of only eight months — Low and his entourage spent $85 million on alcohol, gambling in Vegas, private jets, renting super yachts and to pay Playmates and Hollywood celebrities to hang out with them.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Smooth. The people of Malaysia were paying a shit ton of money for Low to live his Paris Hilton dream.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;* * * * *&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;If you stole a billion dollars, what would you do with it?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Would you make&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Dumb and Dumber To&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;? That’s what happened. That’s why that movie exists –– because Jho Low looted his national treasury. It’s not the only reason, but his stolen money definitely paid for it. In fact, that movie was the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://variety.com/2014/biz/news/dumb-and-dumber-producers-claim-red-granite-used-ill-gotten-gains-to-finance-sequel-1201155260/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;first time people began to make concrete legal claims&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;that not everything was as it appeared with Low. He’d made the mistake of going full Hollywood, a place where rumors are a form of currency — and so are lawsuits.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;He made his movie business turn in 2010, with, of course, Aziz by his side. Neither had any experience in Hollywood. In a rare interview from around that time,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/news/red-granite-pictures-riza-aziz-327206&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Aziz was asked by the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Hollywood Reporter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;about his lack of experience and where the money came from. His co-founder Joey McFarland said, “We do not talk about that.” But Aziz went ahead and answered anyway, “I will say that I have money invested in the company. It shows that I have skin in the game and am committed from a financial point of view. We also have a group of investors, mainly from the Middle East and Asia.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Aziz had been a banker in London, but after the 2008 financial collapse, he decided to get out of banking. In 2009, his stepfather, the newly-elected Prime Minister Najib, formed 1MDB (1 Malaysian Development Berhard). It was the sovereign wealth fund that Low had conspired with Aziz and his stepfather to create to ostensibly “invest in green energy and tourism to create high-quality jobs for all Malaysians.” But it was mostly a piggy bank for lazy criminals to loot.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;To achieve its stated aim, the Malaysian government partnered with a Saudi investment arm called&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.petrosaudi.com/en/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;PetroSaudi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. Malaysia is an oil producing, conservative Muslim nation so it made perfect sense to partner with Saudi Arabia. Malaysia and PetroSaudi contributed $2.5 billion to the 1MDB fund, ostensibly, for new infrastructure and oil development projects. Instead, $700 million was directed into a shell company called Good Star, a company owned and controlled by Jho Low.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Over the course of the criminal conspiracy, $10 billion would be raised by 1MDB through a series of loans and bonds, and half of that sum would disappear. Evidence discovered by Malaysian investigators shows that&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2016/jan/26/malaysian-pm-najib-razak-cleared-corruption-gift-saudi-royals&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;$681 million was deposited in personal bank accounts of Prime Minister Najib&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. He claims it was a gift from Saudi Arabia. There were also the many bribes and payoffs to Malaysian officials necessary to grease the wheels of their conspiracy. And there were the exorbitant fees paid to international investment banks like Goldman Sachs.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Tim Leissner and Roger Ng, two of the bank’s top executives in Asia, helped make the 1MDB scheme pass compliance and beat the regulators’ watchful eye. Both men are currently under criminal investigation. Last week, in fact, the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/03/12/business/goldman-sachs-malaysia-fraud.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Federal Reserve banned both of them&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;from ever working in the banking industry. Goldman Sachs maintains that the bank is innocent and money laundering crimes were conducted by employees who were&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/01/16/business/goldman-malaysia-1mdb-leissner.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;“rogue operators.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;As&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2016/jul/28/1mdb-inside-story-worlds-biggest-financial-scandal-malaysia&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Guardian&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;reported&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, the DoJ is “investigating whether Goldman Sachs violated U.S. banking law in its handling of $6.5 billion in bond offerings that it carried out for 1MDB. The Wall Street behemoth earned $593 million in fees for the issue.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Whether Goldman Sachs is innocent or not, it sure didn’t leave much money for green energy projects. In 2010, using his portion of the money illegally embezzled from 1MDB and disbursed through Low’s front company, Good Star, Aziz took a cut of the hundreds of millions and bought a production company. He named it Red Granite, and named himself co-founder and CEO. To make their name on the Hollywood film scene, Low did what he did best: threw an epic party.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;At&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/news/kanye-west-pharrell-williams-cannes-188485&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;the 2011 Cannes Film Festival, Red Granite announced&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;that they’d purchased the rights to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Wolf of Wall Street&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;and intended to make it with DiCaprio and Martin Scorsese. It was huge news. DiCaprio had finally found someone to pay for his dream project. Mired in development hell, it had theretofore been deemed too risky (with its hard R-rating) and too expensive (with its $100 million budget). To celebrate the occasion, Red Granite flew in Kanye West to perform. (Pharrell opened for him.) Bradley Cooper and DiCaprio danced in the crowd. Later, Jamie Foxx joined Kanye and together they&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZWBOVFLQkhQ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;performed “Golddigger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;.” The song about how some people are dangerously obsessed with money and materialism was a not-at-all subtle comment on this French party scene.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;568&quot; height=&quot;426&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/o3s_6rQWm5Y?feature=oembed&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://collider.com/riza-aziz-angels-in-exile-wolf-of-wall-street-interview/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;a contemporaneous interview with&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Collider&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, Aziz answered some of the many questions about what an amateur like him was doing in Hollywood producing a movie with one of the greatest living directors and one of the world’s most famous leading men. Aziz called&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Wolf of Wall Street&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;a compelling story about “a guy who comes from nothing, gets everything overnight and becomes rich, and in that journey from nothing to everything, he gets sidetracked with all the drugs, the hookers and the alcohol. And once he gets to the top, he gets taken down by the government.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;He had to know he had just told his own story, too. Is that why they wanted to make the film –– to tell their story? Aziz promised, “When you see the film, it’s a good snapshot of what American capitalism is like.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;But that doesn’t address the question. How did they come out of nowhere and get Scorsese and DiCaprio to work with them? To answer that, Aziz pointed to the same power of persuasion that Low would credit: relationships. Aziz&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://collider.com/riza-aziz-angels-in-exile-wolf-of-wall-street-interview/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;explained to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Collider&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, “The reason we were able to get our hands on the film, in the first place, is because we have very close relationships with DiCaprio and his team. When we were talking about various things we wanted to do together, he said, ‘Well, we have a few things cooking, but the main project that we’re really wanting to get off the ground is&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Wolf of Wall Street&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;, which is in turn-around at Warner Bros.’ In 2007, they wanted to do the film, and Marty and Leo were on board, but there was some kind of tug-of-war between Paramount and Warner Bros, so they never got the movie made.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Aziz finished his anecdote with a businessman’s efficiency, “We bought the script and the book rights from Warner Bros and signed Leo on, and then waited for Marty to finish with&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Hugo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;and signed him on. Once you get those two guys on board, it’s a fast-moving train, right after. It’s been a great ride, so far.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;All the while, Low went on a hardcore spending spree. Maybe the biggest purchase: Through a shell company, he bought himself a Manhattan penthouse in the Time Warner Center condominiums for $30.55 million. The skyscraping condo’s&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2015/02/09/nyregion/jho-low-young-malaysian-has-an-appetite-for-new-york.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;previous owners were Beyoncé and Jay Z&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In August 2012, cameras began rolling on&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Wolf of Wall Street&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;. In November, DiCaprio received a very personal birthday gift from Red Granite, something that had thus far evaded him: an Oscar statuette. It was the one that Marlon Brando won for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/On_the_Waterfront&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;On the Waterfront&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. It cost $600,000. For New Year’s Eve, Low and Aziz, Foxx, DiCaprio, and his co-star Jonah Hill, celebrated the New Year in Australia together, then hopped on a private jet and flew to Vegas where they celebrated the New Year a second time. If time is money, and you’re already cheating, why not cheat time, too?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In May 2013, DiCaprio held an art auction for an environmental charity. Low attended and snapped up two pieces to support his friend’s cause. (Earlier in March, Low made his first fine-art purchase, Jean Michel Basquiat’s collage painting&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Red man&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;for $9.2 million.) Two days after DiCaprio’s art auction, Low decided he needed more art, so he bought another Basquiat,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Dust Heads&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;, which cost him $48.8 million, a record at the time for a work by Basquiat. That June, Low grabbed a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mark_Rothko&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Rothko&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;that set him back $71.5 million. After that, he was hooked. He picked up work by Picasso, Van Gogh, Monet, Lichtenstein, Warhol and even more Basquiat. He wasn’t buying them because he loved them; he purchased them as investments, which meant the artwork was crated-up and shipped to storage.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;As&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.artsy.net/article/artsy-editorial-worlds-financial-scandal-ensnared-art&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Artsy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;reported on Low’s time spent tearing through the art world&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;and the eager complicity of the auction houses to casually profit from his crimes, Low was the worst kind of art collector. That is, he was the collector who reduced buying art to a thrill of consumption, no different than eating a potato chip — only he ate famous paintings. That may be why he gave art to his best buddy, DiCaprio. To get some of that good feeling from buying it, and of course, to leverage the art to stoke their relationship.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;By this time, Low had moved on from his crush on Paris Hilton. To start off 2014, he was&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/miranda-kerr-romance-ended-in-8-million-in-jewelry-given-back-to-government-2018-9&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;dating Australian supermodel Miranda Kerr&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. They watched the Super Bowl together in a private box with Aziz and Red Granite co-founder Joey McFarland, who until then had mostly been known as Hilton’s party-planner. While they all watched the game, Katie Holmes stopped in to say “hi,” as did fellow model Kate Upton.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Days later, Low ordered a diamond necklace worth roughly $2 million be created and delivered to Kerr for Valentine’s Day. He used the same jeweler he often used to purchase expensive jewelry for Aziz’s mother, the First Lady of Malaysia. For Kerr’s birthday a short time later, Low put together a 1990s-themed night. To make it feel authentic, he paid Salt-N-Pepa and Vanilla Ice to perform. There was also that one time that Low gave Kerr an&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=i6eZUWcPG_4&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;enormous see-thru, 100-percent translucent grand piano&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. The thing was so large contractors had to build new walls around it once it was in place. At the moment, in fact, the U.S. government has no idea how to seize the piano as part of its civil asset forfeiture claim. It’s likely then that Kerr will get to keep it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;568&quot; height=&quot;320&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/i6eZUWcPG_4?feature=oembed&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The only person to truly see Low for the criminal he was? A fellow conman — the OG Wolf of Wall Street Jordan Belfort, who acted honorably when he crossed paths with Low. As&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.finews.com/news/english-news/25957-jordan-belfort-wolf-of-wall-street-switzerland-speeches-donald-trump-greg-coleman-3&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Belfort recalled&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;: “They flew me to Cannes four or five months after they bought the movie and they wanted to announce it in Cannes. It hadn’t even gone into production yet, and they threw a launch party. They must have spent $3 million on a launch party. They flew in Kayne West, and I said to Anne [his girlfriend], ‘This is a fucking scam, anybody who does this has stolen money.’ You wouldn’t spend money you worked for like that.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Not only did he recognize the scam for what it was, he wouldn’t go along with it. At least, not anymore than he had to. At one point, he turned down half-a-million dollars of Low’s free money.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Why didn’t he take the easy money, like everyone else?&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.finews.com/news/english-news/25957-jordan-belfort-wolf-of-wall-street-switzerland-speeches-donald-trump-greg-coleman-3&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Belfort knew better&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;: “I’ve learned my lesson. They tried to offer me money and give me things, I never even spoke to these guys. I was like, ‘I don’t need these fucking people.’ I knew it, it was so obvious.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;* * * * *&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Xavier Justo joined PetroSaudi because its co-founder was like a little brother to him. Tarek Obaid, a Saudi national who had the backing of a Saudi prince, and Justo were friends and business associates. They partied together in Geneva in the early aughts. At that time, Justo was the more successful one.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2016/jul/28/1mdb-inside-story-worlds-biggest-financial-scandal-malaysia&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;According to the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Guardian&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, Justo was “running a large financial services firm, Fininfor, and the owner of a Geneva nightspot named the Platinum Club.” In 2006, Justo loaned Obaid $30,000 and let him use a desk at Fininfor to start PetroSaudi. A co-founder of the company was&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Turki_bin_Abdullah_Al_Saud&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Prince Turki bin Abdullah&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, one of the sons of the late&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=King+Abdullah+bin+Abdulaziz&amp;amp;oq=King+Abdullah+bin+Abdulaziz&amp;amp;aqs=chrome..69i57j0l5.246j0j7&amp;amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;King Abdullah bin Abdulaziz&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In 2009, Obaid found himself on a 300-foot mega-yacht docked off the coast of Monaco. He was onboard for a meeting with Low, Prince Turki and Malaysian Prime Minister Najib. They wanted to discuss business investment opportunities, ways for both of the oil-rich nations to invest their petro-dollars into infrastructure and development. Low and Najib had created a wealth fund for the Malaysian government, which would soon be known as 1MDB. The prime minister was the chairman of its board; Low was an unofficial advisor.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Months later, Najib traveled to Saudi Arabia, where he signed one of his first major deals. The two nations announced a new joint venture worth $2.5 billion, claiming PetroSaudi and 1MDB would “make strategic investments in high-impact projects.” PetroSaudi pumped $1.5 billion into the partnership, while 1MDB added $1 billion of the Malaysian people’s money.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Guess what happened next?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;According to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.justice.gov/opa/press-release/file/973671/download&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;the Department of Justice’s 251-page criminal complaint&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, documenting the money-laundering conspiracy, “Low and his associates caused $700 million of the $1 billion that was to be invested in the Joint Venture to be sent to an account at RBS Coutts Bank in Zurich held in the name of Good Star Limited.” Later, in 2011, “approximately $330 million in additional funds were wired at the direction of 1MDB officials to the Good Star Account.” It’s not easy to send that kind of money around. There are paper trails, and there are compliance officers at international banks, such as Goldman Sachs, who have to sign off on such large transfers of wealth.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;But,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.justice.gov/opa/press-release/file/973671/download&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;according to the Justice Department&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, “1MDB officials represented, including to Deutsche Bank in Malaysia, that Good Star was a wholly-owned subsidiary of PetroSaudi. This was not true. According to banking records, Good Star was a company controlled by Low, and Low was also the Good Star Account’s beneficial owner and sole authorized signatory. At the time, Low was a 29-year-old with no official position with 1MDB or PetroSaudi.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;To get around bank regulators and compliance officers, Low had to rely on a network of business associates. When one of his associates tried to open a joint venture bank account, the proposed plan to distribute funds set-off alarm bells. The&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.justice.gov/opa/press-release/file/973671/download&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;DoJ alleges&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;“On or about September 22, 2009, the chief investment officer for PetroSaudi (“PETROSAUDI OFFICER”), a U.K. national, contacted BSI in Geneva to discuss the opening of a bank account for the Joint Venture. […] In an email dated September 28, 2009, a banker at BSI in Lugano wrote, ‘I don’t like the transaction at all! In particular the role and involvement of Mr Low Taek Jho ‘looks and feels’ very subspicious [&lt;em&gt;sic&lt;/em&gt;] to me.’ The Joint Venture then approached J.P. Morgan (Suisse) about opening an account, without disclosing the same details about the structure of the investment. The Joint Venture opened an account at J.P. Morgan (Suisse) on or about September 30, 2009.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;For the next few years, Low and his associates relied on Saudi oil money and an Abu Dhabi sovereign wealth fund to obscure the structure of the 1MDB-PetroSaudi venture and to confound auditors. At one point, late in the conspiracy, after people were asking pointed questions about missing funds and loan repayments,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.channelnewsasia.com/news/asia/najib-reveals-documents-prove-rm2-6b-bank-saudi-donation-10703114&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Najib posted a letter from Saudi Prince Abdul Aziz Al-Saud, that claimed&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;the alleged financial improprieties “should not in any event be construed as an act of corruption since this is against the practice of Islam and I personally do not encourage such practices in any manner whatsoever. This is merely a personal token of appreciation of Low’s good work in promoting the Middle East…” But the letter only mentioned $100 million, not nearly enough to settle the missing billions.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;As for Justo’s role in all of this, he’d agreed to come work for Obaid at PetroSaudi back in 2009. And for a couple years, he watched as the Saudi national made millions upon millions for himself and his business partners with their PetroSaudi-1MDB money-laundering scheme. According to Justo, after that, Obaid’s behavior changed. He often erupted in rage. The two men began to fight. And by March 2011, Justo opted to step away from PetroSaudi. It took some negotiating, but PetroSaudi agreed to a severance package with Justo; the company would pay him $6.5 million Swiss francs. But then, days after they’d come to terms, PetroSaudi informed Justo he would only receive $4 million Swiss francs. They’d, however, made one big mistake: Justo still had access to the PetroSaudi servers.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Two years later, in September 2013, Justo decided to get the money that was owed to him. He sent an email to PetroSaudi and informed them that he had gigabytes of evidence of the criminal conspiracy to embezzle billions from 1MDB. An exchange of emails followed. At one point, a rep from PetroSaudi who had negotiated the severance package for Justo warned his former associate, “What troubles me so much is the way in which I see this situation ending — with the destruction of you.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;* * * * *&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Clare Rewcastle Brown, the woman who exposed the rot at the center of the 1MDB embezzlement, is the kind of person DiCaprio would typically really like. She’s a retired British journalist who moved back to Malaysia, where she’d spent the early years of her life. When she returned, she found that there was an active campaign of deforestation underway. As a retired journalist, she decided she could call attention to the issue. She started a blog and reported on the causes of corruption and malfeasance — including the Prime Minister of Malaysia.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;“It was kind of incremental. I was following a strand that concerned me about what was going on and how our global systems were being managed to the enormous disadvantage of people in the environment and what appeared to be very dodgy practice,”&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fraud-magazine.com/cover-article.aspx?id=4295001869&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Rewcastle Brown recalled in an interview with&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Fraud Magazine&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;“Of course, what I found is every time I uncovered the corruption, I was just getting higher and higher. The reason why nothing was being done about any of these appalling actions was because the corruption went right to the top.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;She became known in Malaysia — and around the world — for her independent diligence. People began to leak info to her. One day, a contact offered her details of a massive criminal conspiracy involving PetroSaudi and 1MDB. She was offered Justo’s stolen cache of email and damning financial data. “A bomb went off in my head,” is how&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fraud-magazine.com/cover-article.aspx?id=4295001869&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Rewcastle Brown described that moment&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. It took some wrangling to earn Justo’s trust — and $2 million he demanded for the emails and data (he was going to get his money one way or the other) — but once a promise to pay him was in place (via an Asian publisher), he handed Rewcastle Brown the biggest story of her life, which she titled “&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sarawakreport.org/2015/02/heist-of-the-century-how-jho-low-used-petrosaudi-as-a-front-to-siphon-billions-out-of-1mdb-world-exclusive/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;HEIST OF THE CENTURY!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;” and published on February 28, 2015.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Not surprisingly, 1MDB immediately denounced the story, claiming it was fraudulent. The investment venture reported it not only had recouped its initial investment, in full, but it also earned a reported profit of $488 million. None of that was true, though, no matter what their accounting indicated.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Meanwhile, the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2015/02/09/nyregion/jho-low-young-malaysian-has-an-appetite-for-new-york.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;New York Times&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;had already been asking questions about Low&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, Aziz and Red Granite. Earlier that month, the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Times&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;noted that Aziz had insisted to the paper that “There is no Malaysian money” being used to operate Red Granite or pay for its film production. This, too, was a lie. The&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Times&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;had a solid sense of who Low was, and what his role was in the world. As&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2015/02/09/nyregion/jho-low-young-malaysian-has-an-appetite-for-new-york.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;the paper&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;put it&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, “Mr. Low, 33, is a skillful, and more than occasionally flamboyant, iteration of the sort of operative essential to the economy of the global super rich. Just as many of the wealthy use shell companies to keep the movement of money opaque, they also use people like Mr. Low. Whether shopping for new business opportunities or real estate, he has often done so on behalf of investors or, as he likes to say, friends. Whether the money belongs to others or is his own, the lines are frequently blurry, the identity of the buyer elusive.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Suddenly, everyone knew what DiCaprio and Jamie Foxx seemed to miss when they hung out with Low — he was a massive criminal, a fake and a fraud.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;* * * * *&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;As part of the Department of Justice’s indictment of Low, it filed an asset forfeiture that included the artwork given to DiCaprio as gifts from Red Granite. The actor had to return his works by Picasso, Basquiat and Diane Arbus. He also had to hand over his Oscar that Brando won, a total of more than $13 million in gifts. The money that they’d spent gambling, the money that went for private jets and champagne — that couldn’t be returned.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;But what the U.S. government did manage to seize was nearly as epic as the crimes that bought them. Case in point: Low had purchased a mega-yacht with the people of Malaysia’s money. He named it&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Equanimity&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;. It cost a quarter of a billion dollars. It had a movie theater and a parking spot for a helicopter. It was so massive that when it was seized, the U.S. had to staff it with a full crew just to cruise it back to Malaysia from Bali.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Of course, there was also Miranda Kerr’s multi-million dollar see-thru piano. Peter Tol, the owner of&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.crystal-piano.nl/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Crystal Music Company&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;who custom-made the extravagant piano,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/12/09/arts/jho-low-1mdb-assets-piano.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;told the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;New York Times&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;in December, that he feels duped&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. He said receiving that money that was “destined for the normal people of Malaysia” made him feel terrible. “I don’t like it. It is not my way of life.” Although she may get to keep the piano, Kerr did have to hand the feds a pair of 11-carat diamond earrings and an 11.7-carat heart-shaped diamond, both given to her by Low.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Meanwhile, Low, who was indicted by the Justice Department in absentia, is on the lam. He’s been evading justice by hiding out somewhere in Asia. All rumors and evidence suggest he’s in China, since they have no extradition agreement with Malaysia. His stolen billions still afford him some level of access to power and the means to avoid capture by the U.S.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Plus, as the Malaysian press has been reporting lately, it seems Low is being used as a bargaining chip by China. Najib, now the former Prime Minister of Malaysia, was arrested and is under investigation, pending trial for his part in the criminal enterprise. His assets were also seized. The new prime minister of Malaysia cancelled many of the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://thediplomat.com/2019/01/a-china-bailout-for-malaysias-1mdb-scandal/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;questionable development deals his predecessor had entered&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;into to hide his crimes, such as the East Coast Rail Link that Chinese state companies contracted to build. The evidence shows it was actually a way for China to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://thediplomat.com/2019/01/a-china-bailout-for-malaysias-1mdb-scandal/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;“assume $4.7 billion of 1MDB debt.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;Basically then, China may be willing to handover Low if Malaysia would enter back into an agreement to build that same multi-billion dollar railroad.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Meanwhile, Low can’t stop committing crimes, as he was recently indicted in a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;second&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;Department of Justice complaint. This time the celebrity he dragged into it was&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pras&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Prakazrel “Pras” Michel&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;from the Fugees. According to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/us-seeks-recover-over-73-million-proceeds-traceable-bank-fraud-conceal-involvement-jho-taek&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;a DoJ criminal complaint filed in November&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, Pras was part of a criminal conspiracy to wire and distribute millions to lobby on behalf of Low’s ongoing DoJ criminal prosecution. Pras worked with&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Elliott_Broidy&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Elliott Broidy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, one of President Trump’s top campaign fundraisers, the kind who focused on big donors. Together, they established bank accounts to distribute funds to lobby the Trump administration to kill the DoJ investigation. At the moment, no charges have been filed against Pras. He insists&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/thr-esq/fugees-star-stakes-claim-37-million-seized-by-us-government-1174532&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;he’s the “innocent owner” of the $37 million&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;seized by the DoJ.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;* * * * *&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;One day, Jho Low’s story will make a fine movie. Maybe it’ll even be a better film than&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Wolf of Wall Street&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;. It’s a far crazier story. It has the real Leonardo DiCaprio in it, who will presumably be played by someone else. And therein lies the rub: You can’t separate out DiCaprio from this story, as much as he’d like you to. Whether knowingly or not, DiCaprio casually abetted this massive fraud because he wanted his dream project. And so, this is his story, too.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;It seems all the high-end realtors, art auction houses, international investment bankers, Hollywood people and DiCaprio and Paris Hilton saw Low as something of a sucker, a rich man throwing his money away.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;So, you know, why not take it?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;But some people had to know — or at least suspect. And those people ignored it, or dismissed that little voice because they wanted something, too. Sure, they didn’t directly screw the people of Malaysia, not the way Low did. They didn’t cheat the Malaysians out of their green infrastructure money. But Low’s greed certainly inspired greed in others. Like a ripple.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Maybe that’s the lesson that DiCaprio has learned. He did seem to be wrestling with what greed means to humanity as he did press junkets for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Wolf of Wall Stree&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;t. Or as he said at the time,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://deadline.com/2013/12/wolf-of-wall-street-leonardo-dicaprio-657511/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;“Greed is a timeless virtue.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Jho Low’s story makes it seem like greed is a virus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Maybe the cruelest irony, though, is that no rich person really needed what Low gave them. Meanwhile, there were people who clearly did: his people. It goes back to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thestar.com.my/story/#CVxJoxLKeJEuOHxH.99&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;his first interview with the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Toronto Star&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;when Low said, “Ultimately, I am Malaysian. I am one who does not forget my country and I think there is a lot we can do for Malaysia. But when you build the trust of investors, you need to deliver what you promised.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;As the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Star&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;wondered then, and as time has shown, Low did become the fall guy. And his highly cinematic collapse shows us all how our world operates in its most expensive shadows.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;post-authors&quot;&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;contributor-item -wide&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;contributor-image&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://melmagazine.com/en-us/story/author/zaron-burnett-iii&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://melmagazine.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/0-80x80.jpg&quot; width=&quot;80&quot; height=&quot;80&quot; alt=&quot;0&quot; title=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;contributor-info&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://melmagazine.com/en-us/story/author/zaron-burnett-iii&quot;&gt;Zaron Burnett III&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;contributor-bio&quot;&gt;Zaron Burnett is an investigative journalist and longform features writer based in Los Angeles. He covers culture, politics, race, and other perplexing mysteries for MEL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 07:13:59 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>skilled</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>The Perfect Irony That ‘The Wolf of Wall Street’ Film Was Also a Real-Life Scam - MEL Magazine</og:title>
<og:description>It’s April 2013 in New York. Ensconced in a Chelsea studio bubbling with celebrities and champagne, an international man of mystery records his vanity music...</og:description>
<og:url>https://melmagazine.com/en-us/story/the-perfect-irony-that-the-wolf-of-wall-street-was-also-a-real-life-scam</og:url>
<og:image>https://melmagazine.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/wolfjhow-1.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://melmagazine.com/en-us/story/the-perfect-irony-that-the-wolf-of-wall-street-was-also-a-real-life-scam</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>I Now Have a Cardiologist</title>
<link>https://joecieplinski.com/blog/2019/03/28/i-now-have-a-cardiologist/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://joecieplinski.com/blog/2019/03/28/i-now-have-a-cardiologist/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;With Apple’s release of watchOS 5.2, I see the ECG feature is now more widely available throughout Europe and other regions. That’s great news.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I want to encourage those of you with Apple Watch devices in those supported regions to go grab the update and try out the ECG. Not just because it’s extremely cool tech. But because, well, let me put it this way:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I now have a cardiologist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That isn’t a statement I was planning to make in my forties. But there it is. And it’s only true because of Apple Watch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me back up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last fall, when the ECG feature was finally released, I couldn’t wait to try it out. I’m a total geek for this sort of thing, and I believe health is &lt;em&gt;the next big thing&lt;/em&gt; as far as technology is concerned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wasn’t expecting to see anything other than good old-fashioned Sinus Rhythm. I didn’t know what a good heart rhythm was supposed to look like as it was being recorded, really. So I was just enjoying the cool animations, not noticing the strange pattern. Then the recording finished:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Signs of Atrial Fibrillation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hmm. That has to be a bug, right? Experimental new feature. Maybe I was shaking or moving my wrist a bit. So I try it again:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Signs of Atrial Fibrillation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time, I read the rest of the text more carefully. I didn’t write down the exact wording, but it read something like: “If this is a surprise, you should contact your doctor and talk about it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now is a good point in the story to point out that at the time, I didn’t have a doctor. I’m an indie software consultant in his mid-forties, living in the US, the world’s worst industrialized country for health care. Since I don’t have a “job job,” I pay roughly $500 a month for “health insurance” out of my own pocket. But for most things, this insurance is essentially useless. My deductible is so high that pretty much any doctor visits I make are out of pocket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I continue to pay for my insurance because thanks to the Affordable Care Act, I have to. It’s the law. And I’m okay with that. Because I know paying into the system helps others who make less money than me have access to care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s worth noting that having this insurance also protects me against very serious costs from various serious illnesses, or accidents, etc. If I had &lt;em&gt;cancer&lt;/em&gt;, I’d eat through my deductible pretty quick. But that’s the thing. I’ve never really had &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; serious health issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s actually an understatement. With the exception of appendicitis when I was about 13, I haven’t been to the hospital since I was born. I’ve never had any drugs prescribed to me for more than a few weeks. I barely take aspirin when I get the occasional headache.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, I had my first &lt;em&gt;common cold&lt;/em&gt; in &lt;em&gt;fifteen years&lt;/em&gt;. This is how &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; prone to health issues I am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had no need to go to a doctor beyond the occasional physical, is what I’m saying. Until now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s also worth noting at this point in the story that Atrial Fibrillation is extremely rare in men my age. Less than two percent of people in my demographic have it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go figure. When I do something, I go big I guess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I found a primary care physician and set up an appointment for a routine physical. It had been a while, anyway. I asked him to take an ECG (an official one, with all the wires and stuff). That was going to cost me extra, as it’s not part of a routine physical, but I told him about the watch readings, and he agreed I should take a look.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results? While admitting he was no heart specialist, the primary care doc said my ECG results were definitely a bit of a concern. “Your heart is a little fast, and little irregular.” He was trying not to scare me. I wasn’t going to drop dead that day, but something was definitely up. My watch wasn’t lying to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So then he sent me to the cardiologist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the cardiologist asked why I came in for a visit, I told him about my Apple Watch ECG. “I know, this is new tech. And maybe it’s not scientifically as accurate as the real thing, but it told me I should come in. And I thought I’d better not take a chance.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The doctor didn’t scoff. Quite the opposite, in fact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Oh yeah? Can I see how it works?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was fascinated. I started up a new ECG reading, and within seconds, he said “Yep. That’s AFib.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Persistent AFib, in my case. Over the course of the next month or so, as the doc prescribed some beta blockers and instructed me to continue monitoring my condition, I continued to take readings. No doubt about it. I was in a constant state of AFib. The doctor is still at a loss as to why. (I have none of the genetic indicators and no habits that would increase my chances of this happening. I just have a heart that wants to beat in odd time, as I’ve gotten into the habit of saying.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More alarmingly, I had very few symptoms that I could easily identify. I felt a bit more sluggish than usual (a direct result of my resting heart rate being in the 113-120 bpm range). But I’m not in the best shape, so sluggish isn’t exactly strange for me. I had the occasional discomfort in my chest. And even more occasionally, I’d feel my heart fluttering a bit, as if I had just watched a scene in a scary movie. But it would pass in seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was enough to tell me that something was off, but probably not enough for me to go to a doctor. Seeing the watch reading definitely gave me the push I needed to investigate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In trying to figure out when this condition may have started, the best we could conclude was sometime during the previous summer. It was post-WWDC; I was running betas of iOS and watchOS, as I was developing a new app and wanted to utilize some of the new notification and Siri features. (ECG wasn’t part of the beta.) Once or twice, while sitting on the couch watching tv, I got a notification on my watch saying my heart rate had suddenly jumped into the hundreds, with no indication of a change in activity on my part. I wrote it off as a beta bug, of course. That was certainly more likely than me having a heart condition. And it only happened once or twice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My cardiologist now thinks I was in AFib all the way back then. Almost six months before I made my first appointment. Maybe even earlier. That’s how subtle the symptoms were.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, fast forward to this January. I had an echocardiogram done. (Basically a sonogram for your heart.) Other than the weird rhythm, my heart was perfectly normal. The fast beating and strange rhythm hadn’t caused any muscle or tissue damage—yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next step was to get me out of persistent AFib. This involved what’s called an electro cardioversion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The issue with an electro cardioversion is that while it will zap the patient back into sinus rhythm in most cases, since we don’t know what caused the AFib, there’s every chance that it will come back in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it does come back, you can do the electro cardioversion again, but the next real step is something called a cardiac ablation, which involves sticking a probe up through your leg into your heart, and burning the areas where the incorrect electrical impulses are happening. When you hear the procedure described, it sounds super cool; then you realize it’s &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; heart they want to burn holes in. But hey, it does cure AFib permanently, with relatively low side-effect risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it’s all the same to you, though, I’d prefer to avoid that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, luckily, since my cardioversion in January, my heart has stayed in sinus rhythm. So I haven’t needed to go the ablation route yet. But that remains a possibility for the rest of my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, I’m off all prescriptions, and I’m taking ECGs with my watch regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All told, I’m several thousand dollars out of pocket, still not having hit my deductible, but my heart is doing what it’s supposed to, so I think I’ll call that a win. My useless insurance will become dramatically more expensive next year, while remaining just as useless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But still. A win.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You have all you need to monitor this on your own” the cardiologist told me, pointing to my wrist. “So we’ll know if and when this ever comes back.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did my Apple Watch save my life? I think in my case, that’s a bit of an overstatement. I’ve seen a lot of the stories about people whose lives really have been saved by technology. I'm not in their league. My Apple Watch did help me discover a condition that would likely have gone untreated for a long while. I wasn’t going to die that afternoon. But I might have had a stroke (the most likely result of leaving AFib untreated) a few years down the line. So I’m very grateful to the team at Apple who added this functionality. If any of you are going to be at WWDC in San Jose this June, get in touch. I’d love to buy you all a drink and thank you in person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve seen some news articles where certain doctors expressed concern that false positives from Apple Watches could lead to panic, with patients going to the emergency room needlessly, etc. To those doctors, I have two middle fingers I would happily like to extend. At no point did my watch give me any indication that I was in a true emergency. It just encouraged me to talk to a professional about what seemed to be abnormal heart rhythm. If I had gone to my doctor, and the official ECG had turned up completely normal, the worst thing I’d have to say is that I now had confirmation that my heart rhythm was normal. How could that be a bad thing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ECG function in Apple Watch represents the best value for money I’ve ever spent in technology. There may only be a few people like me who are helped out by this, versus the millions who will just run the ECG for fun and get confirmation of their normal heart rhythms. But helping those few is totally worth it. Trust me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can’t wait to see even more functions built into wearable technology that will help diagnose even more conditions for others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tim Cook believes Apple’s contributions to health will end up dwarfing everything else the company does, when looking back a hundred years from now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have good reason to believe him.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 01:09:03 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Aaronn</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>I Now Have a Cardiologist</og:title>
<og:description>With Apple’s release of watchOS 5.2, I see the ECG feature is now more widely available throughout Europe and other regions. That’s great news. I want to encourage those of you with Apple Watch devices in those supported regions to go grab the update and try out</og:description>
<og:url>http://joecieplinski.com/blog/2019/03/28/i-now-have-a-cardiologist/</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://joecieplinski.com/blog/2019/03/28/i-now-have-a-cardiologist/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>New Bill Would Stop NSA’s Mass Collection of U.S. Phone Data</title>
<link>https://www.thedailybeast.com/wyden-paul-amash-lofgren-bill-would-stop-nsa-mass-collection-of-us-phone-data</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.thedailybeast.com/wyden-paul-amash-lofgren-bill-would-stop-nsa-mass-collection-of-us-phone-data</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Since the 9/11 attacks, the National Security Agency has operated a dragnet of the phone records of hundreds of millions of Americans without specific suspicion of their involvement in terrorism. Almost 18 years later, civil-libertarian legislators from both parties are introducing a bill to abolish a vestige of one of the most infamous surveillance programs in American history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new Ending Mass Collection of Americans’ Phone Records Act would remove any authority for the NSA and FBI to domestically collect phone records “other than those identified by the specific selection term included in [a warrant] application.” Sens. Rand Paul (R-Ky.) and Ron Wyden (D-Ore.) and Reps. Justin Amash (R-Mich.) and Zoe Lofgren (D-Calif.), four of Congress’ leading surveillance skeptics, unveiled the bill on Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s time, finally, to put a stake in the heart of this unnecessary government surveillance program and start to restore some of Americans’ liberties,” Wyden said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In particular, the bill would kill off what’s called the Call Detail Records program under an effort to restrict the domestic phone-data dragnet in the wake of Edward Snowden’s surveillance revelations. Before the so-called USA FREEDOM Act became law in 2015, some civil libertarians warned that its privacy protections, &lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2014/jun/05/edward-snowden-one-year-nsa-surveillance-reform&quot;&gt;watered down by intelligence officials and their allies&lt;/a&gt;, would prove &lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2015/apr/17/surveillance-reform-usa-freedom-act-nsa-civil-libertarians&quot;&gt;inadequate&lt;/a&gt;. They turned out to be prescient: the FREEDOM Act led to &lt;a class=&quot;TrackingLink LinkWrapper&quot; href=&quot;https://www.thedailybeast.com/nsa-admits-it-improperly-collected-a-huge-amount-of-americans-call-records&quot;&gt;an overcollection of call data so massive&lt;/a&gt; that the NSA announced last it was deleting the entire FREEDOM Act trove, which included &lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.dni.gov/files/documents/icotr/2018-ASTR----CY2017----FINAL-for-Release-5.4.18.pdf&quot;&gt;some 685 million phone records&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;PullQuote&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;PullQuote__quote&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“U.S. officials have conceded that the post-9/11 domestic phone-records dragnet has not stopped a single terrorist attack.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The failure of the USA FREEDOM Act was &lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/03/04/us/politics/nsa-phone-records-program-shut-down.html&quot;&gt;significant enough&lt;/a&gt; that the Trump administration “actually hasn’t been using it for the past six months,” a national-security aide to House Republican Leader Kevin McCarthy &lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.lawfareblog.com/lawfare-podcast-luke-murry-and-daniel-silverberg-national-security-congress&quot;&gt;told the Lawfare podcast earlier this month&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That apparent shutdown prompted speculation in surveillance-policy circles that the NSA might have either migrated its domestic phone-data dragnets under authorities outside of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act (FISA) – something the NSA &lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2013/jun/27/james-comey-justice-department-data-monitoring&quot;&gt;has repeatedly done with its post-9/11 warrantless surveillance efforts&lt;/a&gt; – or shut down the collection out of an assessment that analyzing call patterns at scale is an outmoded form of counterterrorism surveillance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, however, U.S. officials have conceded that the post-9/11 domestic phone-records dragnet &lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2014/jan/23/nsa-barack-obama-phone-data-collection-illegal-privacy-board&quot;&gt;has not stopped a single terrorist attack&lt;/a&gt; – &lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2013/jun/18/nsa-surveillance-limited-focused-hearing&quot;&gt;despite misleadingly suggesting otherwise&lt;/a&gt; after &lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2013/jun/06/nsa-phone-records-verizon-court-order&quot;&gt;The Guardian exposed the surveillance in June 2013&lt;/a&gt;, thanks to Snowden. In 2015, a federal appeals court ruled &lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2015/may/07/nsa-phone-records-program-illegal-court&quot;&gt;that the bulk collection of Americans’ phone data was illegal&lt;/a&gt;, adding momentum to the USA FREEDOM Act, whose provisions expire on Dec 15.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The director of the NSA has equivocated on the importance of retaining the domestic phone-records dragnet. “We’re in a deliberative process right now,” Gen. Paul Nakasone &lt;a class=&quot;TrackingLink LinkWrapper&quot; href=&quot;https://www.thedailybeast.com/nsa-chief-hedges-on-future-of-phone-surveillance-dragnet&quot;&gt;told the RSA Conference in San Francisco&lt;/a&gt; on Mar. 6. “We will work very, very closely with the administration and Congress.”   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accordingly, privacy advocates on Capitol Hill see a rare opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usually, the balance of legislative forces favor preserving wide-ranging authorities for NSA surveillance. Despite then-Sen. Barack Obama’s criticisms of “&lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;http://archive.boston.com/news/politics/2008/specials/CandidateQA/ObamaQA/&quot;&gt;unlawful and unconstitutional&lt;/a&gt;” surveillance by the Bush administration, Obama &lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.govtrack.us/congress/votes/110-2008/s168&quot;&gt;voted&lt;/a&gt; for what would prove to be a seminal NSA authority for collecting &lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2013/jun/06/us-tech-giants-nsa-data&quot;&gt;massive amounts of Internet, email and other digital records&lt;/a&gt;, including from Americans’ international communications. Despite President Donald Trump’s heated criticisms of the intelligence agencies, that authority, known as FISA Section 702, &lt;a class=&quot;TrackingLink LinkWrapper&quot; href=&quot;https://www.thedailybeast.com/president-trump-threatens-nsa-mass-surveillance-with-a-tweet&quot;&gt;survived a 2018 reauthorization battle&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the Call Detail Records program created by the USA FREEDOM Act – one that outsourced much of the surveillance activity to telecommunications companies in a cumbersome way – never had substantial support, even before the revelations of the overcollection and subsequent purge and shutdown. While civil libertarians, having lived through numerous legislative defeats since 9/11, are wary of overconfidence, one congressional aide contended that “there’s a clear path forward for abolishing this program.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amash, who &lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2013/jul/25/nsa-surveillance-amash-amendment-narrow-defeat&quot;&gt;led the charge in the House of Representatives&lt;/a&gt; to constrain the NSA after the Snowden revelations, said in a statement: “Getting rid of this program will vindicate Americans’ rights and begin the process of making the broader PATRIOT Act reforms that are going to be necessary to address the law’s serious constitutional flaws.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 23:55:28 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>JumpCrisscross</dc:creator>
<og:title>New Bill Would Finally Stop NSA’s Mass Collection of U.S. Phone Data</og:title>
<og:description>The surveillance giant shut down its flawed dragnet last year. Four legislators are trying to stop one of the security state’s most infamous post-9/11 programs from returning.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.thedailybeast.com/wyden-paul-amash-lofgren-bill-would-stop-nsa-mass-collection-of-us-phone-data</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://img.thedailybeast.com/image/upload/c_crop,d_placeholder_euli9k,h_1687,w_3000,x_0,y_0/dpr_2.0/c_limit,w_740/fl_lossy,q_auto/v1553796696/190328-nsa-tease_s7vwne</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.thedailybeast.com/wyden-paul-amash-lofgren-bill-would-stop-nsa-mass-collection-of-us-phone-data</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>I Miss Rails</title>
<link>https://chanind.github.io/rails/2019/03/28/why-i-miss-rails.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://chanind.github.io/rails/2019/03/28/why-i-miss-rails.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The world of tech moves fast, and there’s always new frameworks and paradigms popping up that make developers’ lives easier and allow us to build more and more powerful applications. But, these transitions don’t always just make things better for developers - sometimes we take steps backwards and undo the progress we made in the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I know Rails isn’t universally beloved by developers, and I’m not suggesting that we give up React and es7 and go back to writing server-templated web-apps like it’s 2012 again. However, I do think that in the transition to the modern web stack (something like React / nodejs / graphql / etc), we’ve unsolved some of what tools like Rails made easy 10 years ago - and I don’t think it needs to be that way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rails took all the boilerplate that comes with building any web application and make it trivial to implement. Since Rails owned the whole application stack, it was easy for the community to contribute plugins that would add any typical functionality you may need. Do you need user accounts with signup / login / forgot password emails / email confirmation? Install devise and you’re done. Do you want to be able to upload images, resize them, and upload them to s3? Great - install paperclip and you’re done. Need to index your data in elasticsearch or sphinx? Easy - just install a rails plugin to do that. Do you need Google and Facebook login? Cool - install omniauth and you’re done. Do you want to clean up your tests using factories? Install factory-girl and everything just works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compare that to the state of the typical web stack now, with something like a nodejs / typescript graphql backend and React / Apollo on the frontend. There’s no longer a standardized way to get user accounts with a login/signup, forgot password and email confirmation flow, despite every application needing it, so instead we need to spend days rewriting this functionality anew on each project. Users need a way to change their account info? Get ready to spend a day working on a standard account settings page. Want to allow users to upload avatar images? Spend a day writing an image upload, resize, push to s3 flow from scratch. Do you want to add a search engine? Great - spend a day writing the code to index and search your documents from scratch. Need to add Google login? Get ready to spend another day on that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All these things that used to be easy in Rails take a fair bit of manual effort today because there’s not a standardized setup and eco-system. We’re spending a lot of time re-solving all these boilerplate issues that every web app needs and everyone has already solved countless times before. Part of this may be inevitable now that there’s both web and mobile frontends to think about, but I think the majority of the problem is just a result of fragmetation in the modern ecosystem. It’s no longer possible to make libraries that automatically handle all the glue code of integration into our apps because there’s no standard setup at all anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That being said, there are some good attempts at unified frameworks out there. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.meteor.com/&quot;&gt;Meteor&lt;/a&gt; was the closest the JS world has come to something like Rails, but may have come too early and missed the graphQL / React / Typescript wave. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gatsbyjs.org/&quot;&gt;Gatsby&lt;/a&gt; is amazing as well, and is the closest project I’ve seen to what Rails used to provide, but it only generates static sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m hopeful that a framework will emerge that can be the Rails of the modern web stack. Gatsby and Meteor show that it’s possible. And if the modern equivalent of Rails already exists, please let me know!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 23:11:10 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>chanind</dc:creator>
<og:title>Why I miss Rails</og:title>
<og:description>The world of tech moves fast, and there’s always new frameworks and paradigms popping up that make developers’ lives easier and allow us to build more and more powerful applications. But, these transitions don’t always just make things better for developers - sometimes we take steps backwards and undo the progress we made in the past.</og:description>
<og:url>https://chanind.github.io/rails/2019/03/28/why-i-miss-rails.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://chanind.github.io/rails/2019/03/28/why-i-miss-rails.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Lyft prices IPO at top of range</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/28/lyft-prices-ipo-at-top-of-range/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/28/lyft-prices-ipo-at-top-of-range/</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/lyft&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;lyft&quot;&gt;Lyft&lt;/a&gt; raised more than $2 billion Thursday afternoon after pricing its shares at $72 apiece, the top of the expected range of $70 to $72 per share. This gives Lyft a fully diluted market value of $24 billion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company will debut on the Nasdaq stock exchange Friday morning, trading under the ticker symbol “LYFT.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The initial public offering is the first-ever for a ride-hailing business and represents a landmark liquidity event for private market investors, which had invested billions of dollars in the San Francisco-based company. In total, Lyft had raised $5.1 billion in debt and equity funding, reaching a valuation of $15.1 billion last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lyft’s blockbuster IPO is unique for a number of reasons, in addition to being amongst transportation-as-a-service companies to transition from private to public. Lyft has the largest net losses of any pre-IPO business, posting losses of $911 million on revenues of $2.2 billion in 2018. However, the company is also raking in the largest revenues, behind only Google and Facebook, for a pre-IPO company. The latter has made it popular on Wall Street, garnering buy ratings from analysts prior to pricing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uber is the next tech unicorn, or company valued north of $1 billion, expected out of the IPO gate. It will trade on the New York Stock Exchange in what is one of the most anticipated IPOs in history. The company, which reported $3 billion in Q4 2018 revenues with net losses of $865 million, is reportedly planning to &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/14/uber-will-reportedly-file-for-ipo-next-month/&quot;&gt;unveil its IPO prospectus&lt;/a&gt; next month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next in the pipeline is Pinterest, which &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/22/pinterest-drops-its-ipo-filing/&quot;&gt;dropped its S-1&lt;/a&gt; last week and revealed a path to profitability that is sure to garner support from Wall Street investors. The visual search engine will trade on the NYSE under the symbol “PINS.” It posted revenue of $755.9 million last year, up from $472.8 million in 2017. The company’s net loss, meanwhile, shrank to $62.9 million last year from $130 million in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other notable companies planning 2019 stock offerings include Slack, Zoom — &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/22/zoom-a-profitable-unicorn-files-to-go-public/&quot;&gt;a rare, profitable pre-IPO unicorn&lt;/a&gt; — and, potentially, Airbnb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Updating&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 21:48:16 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jkw</dc:creator>
<og:title>Lyft prices IPO at top of range</og:title>
<og:description>Lyft begins trading on the Nasdaq under the ticker symbol &quot;LYFT&quot; tomorrow.</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/GettyImages-909455640.jpg?w=600</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2019/03/28/lyft-prices-ipo-at-top-of-range/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/28/lyft-prices-ipo-at-top-of-range/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>