<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>When to Use TypeScript – A Detailed Guide Through Common Scenarios</title>
<link>https://khalilstemmler.com/articles/when-to-use-typescript-guide/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://khalilstemmler.com/articles/when-to-use-typescript-guide/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Have you heard of that little programming language called &lt;strong&gt;TypeScript&lt;/strong&gt;? You know, the one that Microsoft made? The one that's kinda &lt;a href=&quot;https://redmonk.com/sogrady/2019/03/20/language-rankings-1-19/?utm_campaign=digest&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_source=nuzzel&quot;&gt;blowing up&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe you were like me, a true JavaScript purist. I was doing &lt;em&gt;just fine&lt;/em&gt; with React and Node without types. Prop types and Joi validation have been treating me just nicely, thank you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe you caved and gave it a shot. Started playing with it. Maybe you hated it because it reminded you of Java. Maybe you got annoyed with how you couldn't be super productive right away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These were some of &lt;strong&gt;my own initial sentiments&lt;/strong&gt; when I first started with TypeScript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I certainly didn't see the benefit... up until I started experiencing some really annoying stuff. Things like builds not failing when they should, buggy code and typos finding their way into production code somehow started to get to me. In addition to that, as my project demands started to get more complex, I found it increasingly challenging to express my designs in a really clean object-oriented way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9 months later into using TypeScript, I've built new features in Angular apps for clients, I've begun compiling &lt;a href=&quot;https://univjobs.ca&quot;&gt;Univjobs&lt;/a&gt;'s React / Redux front-end with TypeScript, and I ported all of Univjobs' backend services to TypeScript from vanilla Node.js, refactoring mass amounts of code along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we'll take a look at some of the most common scenarios and identify when it might be vital to use TypeScript, and when we could probably do without it and stick to vanilla JS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Why this discussion matters more than ever today&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've come to the very important conclusion that depending on your situation, context, project, skill level and other factors, that it's actually &lt;strong&gt;dangerous&lt;/strong&gt; for your project to &lt;strong&gt;NOT&lt;/strong&gt; be written using TypeScript today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The front-end space, for one- is getting more and more complex. Certain features that were once considered bleeding-edge, are now very-much standard user exprience assumptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, it's almost always expected that your app is going to still work offline in some capacity; and when users ARE online, it's also usually expected that they're going to get real-time notifications without having to refresh the page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are some pretty steep (but definitely not unrealstic in 2019) demands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we dive into different scenarios, we should actually talk about the three categories of really hard software problems to be solved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;3 Categories of Hard Software Problems&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generally speaking, there are 3. The Performant System Problem, the Embedded System Problem, and the Complex Domain Problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1. The Performant System Problem&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's talk about Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twitter is actually a really simple concept.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You sign up, you make tweets, you like other people's tweets and that's pretty much it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If Twitter is that simple, why couldn't someone else do it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's apparent that the real challenge for Twitter is not actually so much as &quot;what it does&quot;, but it's &quot;how it's able to do what it does&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twitter has the unique challenge of serving requests from approximately 500 million users every single day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hard problem that Twitter solves is actually a &lt;strong&gt;perfomance problem&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the challenge is performance, whether we use a strictly typed language or not is less important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;2. The Embedded System Problem&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An embedded system is a combination of computer hardware and software, with the purpose of enabling control over the mechanical or electrical aspects of a system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most systems we use today are built on a very complex layer of code that, if not initially written in, compiles down to C or C++ usually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coding in these languages is not for the faint of heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In C, there is no such thing as objects; and we as humans like objects because we can easily understand them. C is procedural and this makes the code that we have to write in this language more challenging to keep clean. These problems also require knowledge of the lower-level details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C++ does make life a whole lot better because it has object orientation, but the challenge is still fundementally interacting with lower-level hardware details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because we don't really have that much of a choice on the languages we use for these problems, it's irrelevant to discuss TypeScript here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;3. The Complex Domain Problem&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For some problems, that challenge is less about scaling in terms of handling more requests, but scaling in terms of &lt;strong&gt;the codebase's size&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enterprise companies have &lt;strong&gt;complex real-life problems&lt;/strong&gt; to be solved. In these companies, the biggest engineering challenges are usually:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Being able to &lt;strong&gt;logically&lt;/strong&gt; (via domains) separate parts of that monolith into smaller apps. And then, &lt;strong&gt;physically&lt;/strong&gt; (via microservices for bounded contexts) split them up so that teams can be assigned to maintain them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Handling integration and synchronization between these apps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Modeling the domain concepts and actually solving the problems of the domain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating a ubiquitous (all encompassing) language to be shared by developers and domain experts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not getting lost in the mass amounts of code written and slowing down to the point where it becomes impossible to add new features without breaking existing ones&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've essentially described the types of problems that &lt;a href=&quot;https://khalilstemmler.com/blank?todo=domain-driven-design&quot;&gt;Domain Driven Design&lt;/a&gt; solves. For these types of projects, you wouldn't even think about not using a strictly-typed language like TypeScript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Object-oriented JavaScript&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For &lt;strong&gt;Complex Domain&lt;/strong&gt; problems, if you don't choose TypeScript and instead, choose JavaScript, it will require some extra effort to be successful. Not only will you have to be &lt;strong&gt;extra comfortable&lt;/strong&gt; with your object modeling abilities in vanilla JavaScript, but you'll also have to know how to utilize the 4 principles of object-oriented programming (encapsulation, abstraction, inheritance, and polymorphism).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This can be hard to do. JavaScript doesn't naturally come with concepts of interfaces and abstract classes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Interface Segregation&quot; from the SOLID design principles isn't easily achievable with vanilla JavaScript&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using JavaScript alone would also require a certain level of discipline as a developer in order to keep the code clean, and this is vital once the codebase is sufficiently large. You're also left to ensure that your team shares the same discipline, experience and knowledge level on how to implement common design patterns in JavaScript. If not, you'll need to guide them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Domain-Driven projects like this, the strong benefit from using a strictly typed language is &lt;em&gt;less&lt;/em&gt; about expressing what &lt;strong&gt;can be done&lt;/strong&gt;, but more about using encapsulation and information hiding to &lt;u&gt;reduce the surface area of bugs&lt;/u&gt; by limiting what domain objects are &lt;strong&gt;actually allowed to do&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can live without this on the front-end, but it's a &lt;strong&gt;hard language requirement for the backend&lt;/strong&gt; in my books. It's also the reason why I moved my Node.js backend services to TypeScript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's a reason why TypeScript is called &quot;&lt;strong&gt;JavaScript that scales&lt;/strong&gt;&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of all three categories of hard software problems, only the Complex Domain Problem is the one where TypeScript is an absolute necessity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides this, there are other factors that might determine when it's best to use TypeScript for your JavaScript project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Code size&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Code size &lt;em&gt;usually&lt;/em&gt; ties back to the &lt;strong&gt;Complex Domain Problem&lt;/strong&gt;, where a large codebase means a complex domain, but that's not always the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the amount of code a project has gets to a certain size, it becomes &lt;strong&gt;harder&lt;/strong&gt; to keep track of everything that exists, and becomes &lt;strong&gt;easier&lt;/strong&gt; to end up re-implementing something already coded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Duplication is the enemy to well-designed and stable software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is especially heightened when new developers start coding on an already large codebase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visual Studio Code's autocompletion and Intellisense helps to navigate through huge projects. It works really well with TypeScript, but it's somewhat limited with JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For projects that I know will stay simple and small, or if I know that it will be thrown away eventually, I would be less pressed to recommend TypeScript as a necessity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Production software vs. pet projects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Production software&lt;/strong&gt; is code that you care about, or code that you'll get in trouble for if it doesn't work. It's also code that you've written tests for. The general rule of thumb is that if you care about the code, you need to have unit tests for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don't care, don't have tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pet projects&lt;/strong&gt; are self-explanatory. Do whatever you like. You have no professional commitment to uphold any standards of craftsmanship whatsoever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go on and make things! Make small things, make big things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe someday you'll experience the pain when your pet project turns into your main project which turns into production software, which is buggy because it didn't have tests or types 🙃 not like I've been there or anything...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Lack of Unit Tests&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's not always possible to have tests for everything, because, well- &lt;strong&gt;life&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In that case, I'd say that if you don't have Unit Tests, the next best thing you could have is compile-time checking with TypeScript. After that, if you're using React, the next best is thing is to use runtime checking with Prop types.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, compile time checking is &lt;strong&gt;not a subsitute&lt;/strong&gt; for having unit tests. The good thing is that unit tests can be written in any language- so the argument for TypeScript here is irrelevant. What's important is that tests are written and we are confident about our code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Startups&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Definitely use whatever helps you be most productive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this time, the language you choose matters a lot less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most important thing for you to do is to validate your product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choosing a language (Java, for example) or a tool (like Kubernetes) that you heard would help you scale in the future, while being totally unfamiliar with it and needing to spend time learning, may or may not be the best option in the case of a startup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on how early you are, the most important thing for you to do is to be productive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Paul Graham's famous article, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.paulgraham.com/pypar.html&quot;&gt;The Python Paradox&lt;/a&gt;, his main point is that startup engineers should just use the technology that maximizes their productivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, in this case, use whatever you're most comfortable with: types or no types. You can always refactor towards a better design once you know you've built something people actually want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Working on Teams&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on the size of your team and the frameworks you're using, using TypeScript might be a make or break kind-of thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Large teams&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When teams are sufficiently large (because the problems are sufficiently large), it's a good reason to use an opinionated framework, like Angular for the front-end, and TypeScript for the backend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason why using an opinionated framework is benefitial is because you limit the number of possible ways for people to accomplish something. In Angular, there's pretty much one main way to add a Route Guard, use Dependency Injection, hook up Routing, Lazy-Loading and Reactive Forms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The huge benefit here is that the API is well specified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With TypeScript, we save massive amounts of time and make communication efficient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ability to quickly determine the required arguments and it's return type for any method, or the ability to explicitly describe program intent through public, private, and protected variables alone is incredibly useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, some of this is possible with JavaScript, but it's hacky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Communicating patterns &amp;amp; implementing design principles&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only that, but &lt;strong&gt;design patterns&lt;/strong&gt;, the solutions to commonly occuring problems in software, are more easily communicated through explicit strictly-typed languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's a JavaScript example of a common pattern. See if you can identify what it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;javascript&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;language-javascript&quot;&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token class-name&quot;&gt;AudioDevice&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;constructor&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;isPlaying &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token boolean&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;currentTrack &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;null&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

  &lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;play&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token parameter&quot;&gt;track&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;currentTrack &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; track&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;isPlaying &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token boolean&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;handlePlayCurrentAudioTrack&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

  &lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;handlePlayCurrentAudioTrack&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;throw&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token class-name&quot;&gt;Error&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token template-string&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;`Subclasss responsibility error`&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token class-name&quot;&gt;Boombox&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;extends&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token class-name&quot;&gt;AudioDevice&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;constructor&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;super&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

  &lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;handlePlayCurrentAudioTrack&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    
  &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token class-name&quot;&gt;IPod&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;extends&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token class-name&quot;&gt;AudioDevice&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;constructor&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;super&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

  &lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;handlePlayCurrentAudioTrack&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    
    
  &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; AudioDeviceType &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  Boombox&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;'Boombox'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
  IPod&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;'Ipod'&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; AudioDeviceFactory &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token function-variable function&quot;&gt;create&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token parameter&quot;&gt;deviceType&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;switch&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;deviceType&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;case&lt;/span&gt; AudioDeviceType&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;Boombox&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token class-name&quot;&gt;Boombox&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;case&lt;/span&gt; AudioDeviceType&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;IPod&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token class-name&quot;&gt;IPod&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;default&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;null&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; boombox &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; AudioDeviceFactory
  &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;create&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;AudioDeviceType&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;Boombox&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; ipod &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; AudioDeviceFactory
  &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;create&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;AudioDeviceType&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;IPod&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you guessed &lt;strong&gt;Abstract Factory Pattern&lt;/strong&gt;, you're right. Depending on your familiarity with the pattern, it might not have been that obvious to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's look at it in TypeScript now. Look at how much more intent we can signify about &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;AudioDevice&lt;/code&gt; in TypeScript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;typescript&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;language-typescript&quot;&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-typescript&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;abstract&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token class-name&quot;&gt;AudioDevice&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;protected&lt;/span&gt; isPlaying&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token builtin&quot;&gt;boolean&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token boolean&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;protected&lt;/span&gt; currentTrack&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; ITrack &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;null&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;

  &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;constructor&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

  &lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;play&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;track&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; ITrack&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;void&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;currentTrack &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; track&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;isPlaying &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token boolean&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;handlePlayCurrentAudioTrack&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

  &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;abstract&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;handlePlayCurrentAudioTrack&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;void&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Immediate improvements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;We know the class is abstract &lt;strong&gt;right away&lt;/strong&gt;. We needed to sniff around in the JavaScript example.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AudioDevice&lt;/strong&gt; can be instantiated in the JavaScript example. This is bad, we intended &lt;strong&gt;AudioDevice&lt;/strong&gt; to be an abstract class. And abstract classes shouldn't be able to be instantiated, they're only meant to be subclassed and implemented by &lt;a href=&quot;https://khalilstemmler.com/articles/when-to-use-typescript-guide/wiki/concrete-class/&quot;&gt;concrete classes&lt;/a&gt;. This limitation is set in place correctly in the TypeScript example.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We've signaled the scope of the variables.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In this example, &lt;strong&gt;currentTrack&lt;/strong&gt; refers to an interface. As per the &lt;a href=&quot;https://khalilstemmler.com/wiki/dependency-inversion&quot;&gt;Dependency Inversion&lt;/a&gt; design principle, we should always depend on abstractions, not concretions. This isn't possible in the JavaScript implementation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We've also signaled that any subclasses of &lt;strong&gt;AudioDevice&lt;/strong&gt; will need to implement the &lt;strong&gt;handlePlayCurrentAudioTrack&lt;/strong&gt; themselves. In the JavaScript example, we exposed the possibility for someone to introduce runtime errors trying to execute the method from either the illegal abstract class or the non-complete concrete class implementation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Takeaway: If you work on a large team and you need to minimize the potential ways someone could misuse your code, TypeScript is a good way to help fix that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Smaller teams &amp;amp; coding styles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smaller teams are a lot easier to manage coding styles and communication. Paired with linting tools, frequent discussions about how things will get done and pre-commit hooks, I think small teams can be really successful without TypeScript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that success is an equation involving the size of the codebase and the size of the team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As the codebase grows&lt;/strong&gt;, the team might find that they need to rely on some help from the language itself to remember where things are and how they should be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As the team grows&lt;/strong&gt;, they might find they need more rules and restrictions to keep the style consistent and prevent duplicate code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Frameworks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;React &amp;amp; Angular&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much of what draws me and other developers to React is the ability to write code however you want and in an elegant/clever way. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's true that React makes you a better JavaScript developer because it forces you to approach problems differently, it forces you to be aware of how &lt;strong&gt;this binding&lt;/strong&gt; in JavaScript works and enables you to compose large components out of small ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;React also allows you to have a bit of your own style. And because of the number of ways I can implement any given task, I will most often write vanilla React.js apps when:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;the codebase is small&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it's just me coding it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;And I will compile it with TypeScript when:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;more than 3 people are coding it, or&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the codebase is expected to be very large&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;I will also optionally use Angular for the same reason I will compile React with TypeScript.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, these are my personal opinions on when TypeScript is absolutely necessary and I welcome you to disagree with any of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what has worked for me in the past when deciding whether to use TypeScript. However, today- since I've seen the light, it's not much more effort for me to use TypeScript over vanilla JavaScript as I'm equally comfortable with both and would prefer the type safety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My final points here are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;You can always gradually start using TypeScript&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start gradually by adding TypeScript and ts-node to your &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;package.json&lt;/code&gt; and utilizing the &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;allowjs: true&lt;/code&gt;, option in your &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;tsconfig&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is how I migrated all of my Node.js apps over time to TypeScript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Compile time errors are better than runtime ones&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can't argue with that. If catching bugs in production code is especially important to you, TypeScript will help you minimize a lot of these.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;If you are in a position to learn it, learn it. It does wonders for your software design skills&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on where you are in your life and your career, you might not have the time to learn it. If you do have the time, I'd recommend you start learning it and start learning about &lt;strong&gt;SOLID design principles&lt;/strong&gt; and software design patterns. This is the &lt;strong&gt;fastest way to level up as a Junior Developer&lt;/strong&gt; in my honest opinion.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 15:26:12 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>stemmlerjs</dc:creator>
<og:title>When To Use TypeScript - A Detailed Guide Through Common Scenarios</og:title>
<og:image>https://khalilstemmler.com/img/blog/time-for-typescript/typescript-time.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Strap yourself in. In this guide, we compare when it's absolutely vital to be using TypeScript, the strictly-typed programming language, and when it makes sense to stick to vanilla JavaScript.</og:description>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://khalilstemmler.com/articles/when-to-use-typescript-guide/</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://khalilstemmler.com/articles/when-to-use-typescript-guide/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>I Lied When I Said We Did Everything We Could</title>
<link>https://www.doximity.com/doc_news/v2/entries/18293779</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.doximity.com/doc_news/v2/entries/18293779</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.ctfassets.net/uq0sg0aynn6a/5JKqAcL2SeIAuf8n8IxiIY/f0c696ed81097b5969b1f30c91e3a9cf/codeFutile_1_april.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Op-Med ran the “First Stab” contest in February 2019. We are excited to announce this as the runner-up.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I knew it was only a matter of time until a code would be called during my intern ICU rotation. I knew it would leave a lasting impression on me, regardless of the particular circumstances. What I didn’t know was exactly how and when it would do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She was young — late thirties, I think — and had spent most of the past year in the hospital. The unlucky victim of genetics and circumstances still not understood by science, she was dying from sarcoidosis. She had long been beyond any hope of meaningful recovery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had not been taking care of her, but I remembered my attending describing her case with a regrettable helplessness. He had spoken with her family innumerable times explaining her dismal prognosis, the virtues of palliation and hospice care, and the harms of overtreatment. Like many families, anything other than a “full code” meant giving up on their loved one. In the midst of tragedy, changing that mindset, like the code itself, was often an exercise in futility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As my attending and I jogged to her room for the code, this defeat was written all over his face. He already felt he had failed this patient, and now, as the ultimate price to pay for his failure, he had to run the code. And I was his accomplice in harm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With adrenaline coursing through my veins, I was amazed at how easy it was to depress the chest wall. I pushed aside my reservations and concentrated on form and rate. My attending called out orders as I rotated through cycles of compressions with two others. Suddenly, in the midst of my second or third cycle, her eyes shot open and locked on mine. I jumped back in surprise as she made a few agonizing attempts for breath, tensing her body in apparent attempt to sit up. Within seconds, her eyes rolled to the back of her head and she again went limp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The call to resume compressions came. I felt a few ribs pop under my hands. She showed no further sign of life. After about thirty-five minutes, the attending called it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the time it took to run the code, a family member had arrived and was waiting in a conference room for us. Much to my surprise, my attending didn’t come right out and tell the man his loved one had died. Instead, he described every detail of the code, including the brief moment we “got her back,” before eventually concluding with her death. Equally surprising, the man sat, wordless, through the entire description. I imagined what kind of roller coaster this conversation must have and wondered if it was a harsh or gentle way to break it to him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even as I empathized with him, I found myself judging him. Why had he done that to her? Was he glad she spent the last months of her life in the hospital, barely aware of her surroundings other than her struggle to breathe? Was he glad the last thing she saw was me, a stranger, pounding away at her chest? Did he really believe all the prolonged suffering was worth it? Would he do it all again? The year in the hospital? The anoxic brain injuries? The ventilator-associated pneumonia? The bedsores?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hours later, as I was making the long trek out of the hospital to the parking deck, mulling over my involvement in the code, I met her loved one in the hallway. I didn’t recognize him immediately, too caught up in my own thoughts. After walking side-by-side for a few seconds, he spoke.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You were in there, weren’t you?” he asked me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Yes, I was.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You all did everything you could, didn’t you?” he asked hopefully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to tell him no. I wanted to tell him that if we had done everything we could she would have gone to the palliative unit or home on hospice. We could have let her go peacefully. Instead, she died in a room full of strangers assaulting her body. I wanted to tell him about the look of agony in her eyes when she opened them the final time. I wanted him to feel the ribs popping, hear the gurgling as she struggled with her last breath. I wanted him to understand her suffering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But he couldn’t, and, as I looked into his eyes, I knew I didn’t understand his, either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn’t know what it was like to lose a loved one so young. I didn’t know what conversations about the end of life he had had with the patient. I didn’t know what the goals of care conversations were like he was a part of (judging from some of the ones I’ve seen since, likely not great). I didn’t know what other family dynamics fed into the decisions he had made. I didn’t know how helpless it must have felt in his situation. His only power over her disease was exerted vicariously through the medical care she received.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most importantly, she was no longer suffering. He was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Yes,” I replied, “We did everything we could.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tears welled up in his eyes. “Thank you.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together, we walked in silence to the parking deck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;J. Lane Wilson is a full-spectrum family physician at the Brody School of Medicine at East Carolina University in Greenville, NC. He is married to another family physician and is the father of two. He enjoys hiking with his family, running, and is a Major League Soccer fanatic.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Illustration by April Brust&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 15:10:39 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>bookofjoe</dc:creator>
<og:title>I Lied When I Said We Did Everything We Could</og:title>
<og:image>https://res.cloudinary.com/dhttas9u5/image/upload/c_fill,h_600,w_1200/btpprreuot3qisifw2wd.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Op-Med ran the “First Stab” contest in February 2019. We are excited to announce this as the runner-up.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://opmed.doximity.com/articles/i-lied-when-i-said-we-did-everything-we-could</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>It&amp;#039;s VHS vs. Beta all over again, but worse</title>
<link>https://www.johnnygrubb.com/its-vhs-vs-beta-all-over-again-but-worse</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.johnnygrubb.com/its-vhs-vs-beta-all-over-again-but-worse</guid>
<description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;title&quot; class=&quot;p-name&quot;&gt;It's VHS vs Beta all over again, but worse&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;e-content&quot; readability=&quot;70.55082243779&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(HN inspired update: &lt;a href=&quot;https://moviesanywhere.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Movies Anywhere&lt;/a&gt; is the thing I was wanting and can't believe it actually exists)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just bought my first Roku powered TV as an upgrade to the bottom-est bottom tier TV that we bought from Costco a couple years ago. This one is also from Costco, but it's a TCL rather than an Element brand, so it's like the second rung on the ladder. Roku is waaaaay better than the imitation version that was on the Element TV and generally I'm pleased. You can add channels and do all the stuff that I realize now qualifies as the “cord cutting” I've been reading about forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We bought an Apple TV probably 4-5 years ago and at some point in the last 12 months it's crapped out on us, so I'm conscripted into plugging my laptop in to the TV to watch any of the dozens of kids movies we've bought on iTunes over that time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has always irked me because none of those movies ever worked in the car's DVD player/entertainment system thingy when we go on road trips. It's a shame too, because we've only recently discovered that the headphones that came with the car for the DVD player not only work, but will let Michelle and I listen to Wait, Wait without the loud protestations of the kids (since they can watch a movie while we listen to podcasts). I have to stop at Target and trawl through the discount kid's DVDs for the car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In many ways the future is damn handy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But now we got this Roku TV and it comes with Amazon Prime so that's great, but I want to watch one of the movies we bought on iTunes. I don't want to start buying a library of movies on Amazon, because I already have a library of movies on iTunes (that they won't let me watch on anything but an Apple product :| ). Neither of these systems will let me burn to a DVD so we can watch them in the car, and neither of their apps will let me bounce out of my iPhone into the car's V-RCA inputs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it that hard to let things interoperate? Can Apple please just relent and let Roku have an iTunes app? I'm not buying another fucking Apple TV. I'm not. I don't give a shit about games or 4K or an internal drive, I just want to watch the fucking movies I bought (or licensed, fuck you Hollywood). I may as well have to lug around a VHS player to plug in to all these screens, it's absolutely ridiculous and completely anti-customer. You all deserve the eventual death or disruption you suffer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 14:28:36 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Jgrubb</dc:creator>
<og:title>It's VHS vs Beta all over again, but worse</og:title>
<og:description>(HN inspired update: Movies Anywhere is the thing I was wanting and can&amp;#39;t believe it actually exists) I just bought my first Roku po...</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.johnnygrubb.com/its-vhs-vs-beta-all-over-again-but-worse</og:url>
<og:image>https://write.as/img/w-sq-light.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.johnnygrubb.com/its-vhs-vs-beta-all-over-again-but-worse</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>All of Toyota’s electric vehicle patents are now royalty-free</title>
<link>https://www.topgear.com/car-news/electric/toyota-sharing-its-ev-secrets-free</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.topgear.com/car-news/electric/toyota-sharing-its-ev-secrets-free</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;As a general rule, car companies are extremely secretive about their technological developments. Anything that could provide a USP or give an edge over the competition is kept under lock and key – being guarded more fervently than the recipe for Coca-Cola. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, Toyota has now offered royalty-free licences on almost 24,000 of its electric vehicle patents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This essentially means that any company wishing to build a hybrid or fully electric vehicle will have complete access to all of Toyota’s work without having to pay a single penny.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you’re struggling to make sense of the drawings and literature that make up the patent, Toyota will also offer technical support to any manufacturer that requests their assistance. Any advice given will come with a fee of course – you didn’t think everything would be free, did you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In total though, 23,740 patents will be available from the past 20 years of Toyota’s development of hybrid technology. That’s a whole lot of tech. Tech which Toyota helps will speed-up the manufacture and uptake of hybrid or electric vehicles across the world in the face of ever-worsening climate change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Based on the high volume of enquiries we receive about our vehicle electrification systems from companies that recognise a need to popularise hybrid and other electrified vehicle technologies, we believe that now is the time for cooperation,” said Shigeki Terashi, Executive Vice President of Toyota. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If the number of electrified vehicles accelerates significantly in the next ten years, they will become standard, and we hope to play a role in supporting that process.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this the start of a new, sharing-is-caring attitude in the motoring industry?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 12:04:48 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>e2e4</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Toyota is sharing its EV secrets for free</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.topgear.com/car-news/electric/toyota-sharing-its-ev-secrets-free</og:url>
<og:description>As a general rule, car companies are extremely secretive about their technological developments. Anything that could provide a USP or give an edge over the competition is kept under lock and key – being guarded more fervently than the recipe for Coca-Cola. However, Toyota has now offered royalty-free licences on almost 24,000 of its electric vehicle patents.This essentially means that any company wishing to build a hybrid or fully electric vehicle will have complete access to all of Toyota’s work without having to pay a single penny.</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.topgear.com/sites/default/files/styles/16x9_1280w/public/images/news-article/2019/04/b041c7b75df04c09fabdc2e1115efec4/001_prius-plug-in-hybrid-ext-dynamic.jpg?itok=Zh9JuKoc</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.topgear.com/car-news/electric/toyota-sharing-its-ev-secrets-free</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Chrome, Safari, and Edge to Prevent Disabling of Click Tracking Privacy Risk</title>
<link>https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/software/major-browsers-to-prevent-disabling-of-click-tracking-privacy-risk/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/software/major-browsers-to-prevent-disabling-of-click-tracking-privacy-risk/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Privacy&quot; height=&quot;469&quot; src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; data-src=&quot;https://www.bleepstatic.com/images/stock-photos/security/spyware.jpg&quot; class=&quot;b-lazy&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A HTML standard called hyperlink auditing that allows sites to track link clicks is enabled by default on Safari, Chrome, Opera, and Microsoft Edge, but will soon have no way to disable it. As it is considered a privacy risk, browsers previously allowed you to disable this feature. Now they are going in the opposite direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hyperlink auditing is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://html.spec.whatwg.org/multipage/links.html#hyperlink-auditing&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;HTML standard&lt;/a&gt; that allows the creation of special links that ping back to a specified URL when they are clicked on. These pings are done in the form of a POST request to the specified web page that can then examine the request headers to see what page the link was clicked on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To create a hyperlink auditing URL, you can simply create a normal hyperlink HTML tag, but also include a ping=&quot;[url]&quot; variable as shown below. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Ping HTML Link&quot; height=&quot;72&quot; src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==&quot; width=&quot;590&quot; data-src=&quot;https://www.bleepstatic.com/images/news/web-browsers/features/h/hyperlink-auditing/html-example.jpg&quot; class=&quot;b-lazy&quot;/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ping HTML Link&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will render on the page as a normal link to google.com and if you hover over it, will only show you the destination URL. It does not show you the ping back URL of https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/pong.php, so users will not even realize this is happening unless they examine the sites source code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Hover shows link URL, but not ping back URL&quot; height=&quot;398&quot; src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==&quot; width=&quot;785&quot; data-src=&quot;https://www.bleepstatic.com/images/news/web-browsers/features/h/hyperlink-auditing/hover-ping.jpg&quot; class=&quot;b-lazy&quot;/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hover shows link URL, but not ping back URL&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a user clicks on the above link, the browser will first send a POST request back to the ping URL https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/pong.php as shown below. It will then open the www.google.com page.  This means that everytime a user clicks on a hyperlink audited link, the browser will make two requests instead of one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Example Ping POST Request&quot; height=&quot;262&quot; src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==&quot; width=&quot;679&quot; data-src=&quot;https://www.bleepstatic.com/images/news/web-browsers/features/h/hyperlink-auditing/ping.jpg&quot; class=&quot;b-lazy&quot;/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example Ping POST Request&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scripts that receive the ping POST request, can then parse the headers in order to see what page the ping came from and where the hyperlink audited link was going to. The headers associated with the information sent in the ping request are shown below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;    [HTTP_PING_FROM] =&amp;gt; https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/ping.html
    [HTTP_PING_TO] =&amp;gt; https://www.google.com/
    [CONTENT_TYPE] =&amp;gt; text/ping
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, using Hyperlink Auditing developers can track link clicks from any web property that they have access to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Most browsers wont let you disable in the future&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With privacy and online tracking being such a large problem and major concern for many users, you would think that browser developers would give you the option to disable anything that could affect your privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, this seems to be going in the reverse direction when it comes to hyperlink auditing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to developer Jeff Johnson, Safari enabled hyperlink auditing by default, but allowed you to disable it by using the following hidden preference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;defaults write com.apple.Safari com.apple.Safari.ContentPageGroupIdentifier.WebKit2HyperlinkAuditingEnabled -bool false&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Johnson has stated that this flag no longer works with Safari 12.1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Unfortunately, this no longer works in Safari 12.1. I actually discovered the issue in Safari Technology Preview 72, and I filed a Radar on January 2, 2019 as &lt;a href=&quot;rdar://problem/47000341&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;rdar://problem/47000341&lt;/a&gt;,&quot; Johnson stated in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://lapcatsoftware.com/articles/Safari-link-tracking.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Despite several months notice from me, Apple shipped Safari 12.1 last week to the public with no way to disable hyperlink auditing. I hope to raise awareness about this issue, with the ultimate goal of getting hyperlink auditing disabled by default in Safari. Apple claims that Safari is supposed to protect your privacy and prevent cross-site tracking, but hyperlink auditing is a wide open door to cross-site tracking that still exists. To end this article, I'll quote the full text of the Radar that I filed:&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google Chrome also enables this tracking feature by default, but in the current Chrome 73 version it includes a &quot;Hyperlink auditing&quot; flag that can be used to disable it from the chrome://flags URL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Chrome 73 Hyperlink Auditing Flag&quot; height=&quot;131&quot; src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==&quot; width=&quot;920&quot; data-src=&quot;https://www.bleepstatic.com/images/news/web-browsers/features/h/hyperlink-auditing/chrome-flags.jpg&quot; class=&quot;b-lazy&quot;/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chrome 73 Hyperlink Auditing Flag&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Chrome 74 Beta and Chrome 75 Canary builds, though, this flag has been removed and there is no way to disable hyperlink auditing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;No Hyperlink auditing flag in Chrome 74&quot; height=&quot;731&quot; src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==&quot; width=&quot;1204&quot; data-src=&quot;https://www.bleepstatic.com/images/news/web-browsers/features/h/hyperlink-auditing/chrome-74-beta-flag-gone.jpg&quot; class=&quot;b-lazy&quot;/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No Hyperlink auditing flag in Chrome 74&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current version of Microsoft Edge also enables hyperlink auditing by default and provides no way to disable it that I could find. I also took a look at the upcoming Microsoft Edge Insider build and as it's based on Chromium 75, there is no way to disable hyperlink auditing on that browser either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like Edge, Opera is also based on Chromium, and the Opera 61 Developer build removes the option to disable hyperlink auditing as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I also tested it the mobile versions of Chrome and Safari and its enabled by default with no way of disabling it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What this means is that starting next month when Chrome 74 is released to the stable branch, the Edge, Chrome, Opera, and Safari browsers will no longer offer a way of disabling this tracking feature and privacy risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Firefox and Brave win the award&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of all the browsers I tested, only Brave and Firefox currently disable it by default and do not appear to have any plans on enabling it in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firefox 66, Firefox Beta 67, and Firefox Nightly 68 disable Hyperlink auditing by default and allow users to enable it using the &lt;strong&gt;browser.send_pings&lt;/strong&gt; about:config setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Firefox 66 Setting&quot; height=&quot;39&quot; src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==&quot; width=&quot;971&quot; data-src=&quot;https://www.bleepstatic.com/images/news/web-browsers/features/h/hyperlink-auditing/firefox-about-config.jpg&quot; class=&quot;b-lazy&quot;/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Firefox 66 Setting&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The privacy focused Brave Browser also disables it by default and does not allow you to enable it at all. It does have a display bug in the brave://flags that show that Hyperlink auditing is enabled, but this is a carryover from Chrome and is not displayed correctly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going forward, if privacy is important to you and you want to reduce the risk of being tracked online, then you will need to use Firefox or Brave.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 11:05:51 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Athas</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/software/major-browsers-to-prevent-disabling-of-click-tracking-privacy-risk/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Major Browsers to Prevent Disabling of Click Tracking Privacy Risk</og:title>
<og:description>A HTML standard called hyperlink auditing that allows sites to track link clicks is enabled by default on Safari, Chrome, Opera, and Microsoft Edge, but will soon have no way to disable it. As it is considered a privacy risk, browsers previously allowed you to disable this feature. Now they are going in the opposite direction.</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.bleepstatic.com/content/hl-images/2016/04/15/spyware-292-176.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/software/major-browsers-to-prevent-disabling-of-click-tracking-privacy-risk/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How Apps on Android Share Data with Facebook (2018)</title>
<link>https://privacyinternational.org/report/2647/how-apps-android-share-data-facebook-report</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://privacyinternational.org/report/2647/how-apps-android-share-data-facebook-report</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://media.ccc.de/v/35c3-9941-how_facebook_tracks_you_on_android&quot;&gt;A video presentation of the finding of this report can be found here, as presented at 35th Chaos Computer Congress (35C3)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previous research has shown how 42.55 percent of free apps on the Google Play store could share data with Facebook, making Facebook the second most prevalent third-party tracker after Google’s parent company Alphabet. In this report, Privacy International illustrates what this data sharing looks like in practice, particularly for people who do not have a Facebook account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This question of whether Facebook gathers information about users who are not signed in or do not have an account was raised in the aftermath of the Cambridge Analytica scandal by lawmakers in hearings in the United States and in Europe. Discussions, as well as previous fines by Data Protection Authorities about the tracking of non-users, however, often focus on the tracking that happens on websites. Much less is known about the data that the company receives from apps. For these reasons, in this report we raise questions about transparency and use of app data that we consider timely and important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook routinely tracks users, non-users and logged-out users outside its platform through Facebook Business Tools. App developers share data with Facebook through the Facebook Software Development Kit (SDK), a set of software development tools that help developers build apps for a specific operating system. Using the free and open source software tool called &quot;mitmproxy&quot;, an interactive HTTPS proxy, Privacy International has analyzed the data that 34 apps on Android, each with an install base from 10 to 500 million, transmit to Facebook through the Facebook SDK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All apps were tested between August and December 2018, with the last re-test happening between 3 and 11 of December 2018. The full documentation, including the exact date each app was tested, can be found at &lt;a href=&quot;https://privacyinternational.org/appdata&quot;&gt;https://privacyinternational.org/appdata&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Findings&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;• We found that at least &lt;strong&gt;61 percent of apps we tested automatically transfer data to Facebook the moment a user opens the app&lt;/strong&gt;. This happens whether people have a Facebook account or not, or whether they are logged into Facebook or not. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;• Typically, the data that is automatically transmitted first is events data that communicates to Facebook that the Facebook SDK has been initialized by transmitting data such as &quot;App installed” and &quot;SDK Initialized&quot;. This data reveals the fact that a user is using a specific app, every single time that user opens an app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;• In our analysis, apps that automatically transmit data to Facebook share this data together with a unique identifier, the Google advertising ID (AAID). The primary purpose of advertising IDs, such as the Google advertising ID (or Apple’s equivalent, the IDFA) is to allow advertisers to link data about user behavior from different apps and web browsing into a comprehensive profile. &lt;strong&gt;If combined, data from different apps can paint a fine-grained and intimate picture of people’s activities, interests, behaviors and routines, some of which can reveal special category data, including information about people’s health or religion.&lt;/strong&gt; For example, an individual who has installed the following apps that we have tested, &quot;Qibla Connect&quot; (a Muslim prayer app), &quot;Period Tracker Clue&quot; (a period tracker), &quot;Indeed&quot; (a job search app), &quot;My Talking Tom&quot; (a children’s’ app), could be potentially profiled as likely female, likely Muslim, likely job seeker, likely parent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;• If combined, event data such as &quot;App installed”, &quot;SDK Initialized&quot; and “Deactivate app” from different apps also offer a detailed insight into the app usage behavior of hundreds of millions of people. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;• We also found that &lt;strong&gt;some apps routinely send Facebook data that is incredibly detailed and sometimes sensitive.&lt;/strong&gt; Again, this concerns data of people who are either logged out of Facebook or who do not have a Facebook account. A prime example is the travel search and price comparison app &quot;KAYAK&quot;, which sends detailed information about people’s flight searches to Facebook, including: departure city, departure airport, departure date, arrival city, arrival airport, arrival date, number of tickets (including number of children), class of tickets (economy, business or first class).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;• Facebook’s Cookies Policy describes two ways in which people who do not have a Facebook account can control Facebook's use of cookies to show them ads. &lt;strong&gt;Privacy International has tested both opt-outs and found that they had no discernible impact on the data sharing that we have described in this report.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook places the sole responsibility on app developers to ensure that they have the lawful right to collect, use and share people’s data before providing Facebook with any data. However, &lt;strong&gt;the default implementation of the Facebook SDK is designed to automatically transmit event data to Facebook&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since May 25, 2018 – the day that the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) entered into force - developers have been filing bug reports on Facebook’s developer platform, raising concerns that the Facebook SDK automatically shares data before apps are able to ask users to agree or consent. On June 28, 2018, Facebook released a voluntary feature that should allow developers to delay collecting automatically logged events until after they acquire user consent. &lt;strong&gt;The feature was launched 35 days after GDPR took effect and only works on the SDK version 4.34 and later.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In response to this report, Facebook has stated in an email to Privacy International on 28 December 2018: “Prior to our introduction of the “delay” option, developers had the ability to disable transmission of automatic event logging data, &lt;strong&gt;except for a signal that the SDK had been initialized.&lt;/strong&gt; Following the June change to our SDK, we also removed the signal that the SDK was initialized for developers that disabled automatic event logging.” (emphasis added). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This “signal” is the data that we observe in our findings. We assume that prior to the release of this voluntary feature, &lt;strong&gt;many apps that use Facebook SDK in the Android ecosystem were therefore not able to prevent or delay the SDK from automatically collecting and sharing that the SDK has been initialized&lt;/strong&gt;. Such data communicates to Facebook that a user uses a particular app, when they are using it and for how long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Without any further transparency from Facebook, it is impossible to know for certain, how the data that we have described in this report is being used.&lt;/strong&gt; This is particularity the case since Facebook has been less than transparent about the ways in which it uses data of non-Facebook users in the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our findings also raise a number of legal questions.&lt;/strong&gt; As this research was conducted in the UK we have focused on the relevant EU framework, namely EU data protection (“GDPR”) and ePrivacy law (the ePrivacy Directive 2002/58/EC, as implemented by Member State laws) as well as Competition Law. &lt;strong&gt;An underlying theme is the responsibility of the various actors involved, including Facebook.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 08:04:18 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>allwynpfr</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://privacyinternational.org/report/2647/how-apps-android-share-data-facebook-report</og:url>
<og:title>How Apps on Android Share Data with Facebook - Report</og:title>
<og:description>Facebook routinely tracks users, non-users and logged-out users outside its platform through Facebook Business Tools. App developers share data with Facebook through the Facebook Software Development Kit (SDK), a set of software development tools that help developers build apps for a specific operating system. Using the free and open source software tool called &quot;mitmproxy&quot;, an interactive HTTPS proxy, Privacy International has analyzed the data that 34 apps on Android, each with an install base from 10 to 500 million, transmit to Facebook through the Facebook SDK.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://privacyinternational.org/report/2647/how-apps-android-share-data-facebook-report</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>An Iraqi who saved Norway from oil (2009)</title>
<link>https://web.archive.org/web/20100123225932/http://www.ft.com/cms/s/2/99680a04-92a0-11de-b63b-00144feabdc0.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://web.archive.org/web/20100123225932/http://www.ft.com/cms/s/2/99680a04-92a0-11de-b63b-00144feabdc0.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Farouk al-Kasim&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; height=&quot;261&quot; src=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20100123225932im_/http://media.ft.com/cms/502e05de-92b7-11de-b63b-00144feabdc0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;When he boarded his flight from London to Oslo, Farouk al-Kasim, a young Iraqi geologist, knew his life would never again be the same. Norway was a country about as different as it was possible to imagine from his home, the Iraqi port city of Basra. He had no job to go to, and no idea of how he would make a living in the far north. It was May 1968 and al-Kasim had just resigned from his post at the Iraq Petroleum Company. To do so, he had had to come to the UK, where the consortium of western companies that still controlled most of his country’s oil production had its headquarters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For all its uncertainties, al-Kasim’s journey to Norway had a clear purpose: he and his Norwegian wife, Solfrid, had decided that their youngest son, born with cerebral palsy, could only receive the care he needed there. But it meant turning their backs on a world of comforts. Al-Kasim’s successful career had afforded them the prosperous lifestyle of Basra’s upper-middle class. Now they would live with Solfrid’s family until he could find work, though he had little hope of finding a job as rewarding as the one he had left behind. He was not aware that oil exploration was under way on the Norwegian continental shelf, and even if he had known, it wouldn’t have been much cause for hope: after five years of searching, still no oil had been found.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But al-Kasim’s most immediate problem on arriving in Oslo that morning was how to fill the day: his train to Solfrid’s home town did not depart until 6.30pm. “I thought what I am going to do in these hours?” he says. “So I decided to go to the Ministry of Industry and ask them if they knew of any oil companies coming to Norway.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He deposited his luggage and walked to the ministry, where he was received by a baffled official who told him to come back that afternoon. When he returned, expecting only an address list, several men were waiting for him. “They were keen to know what had I been doing, what kind of education I had, whom I worked for. Did I work as a petroleum engineer? Did I work as a geologist? What did I do?” His request for a list of possible employers had turned into an impromptu job interview. “They must have been absolutely desperate for expertise!” says al-Kasim. They were indeed. At the time of his surprise call, Norway’s oil administration numbered just three officials, all in their thirties and all learning essential parts of the job as they went along. Meanwhile, the North Sea exploration results were pouring in and required careful analysis. Al-Kasim must have looked like a godsend: a man rich in academic training and practical experience of the oil industry – and one in need of work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1952, the Iraq Petroleum Company had reluctantly agreed to train young Iraqis to work alongside its colonial-era masters. It would sponsor batches of Iraqi students to study abroad with the promise of a job afterwards. At only 16, the precocious al-Kasim was selected for the first intake and sent to study petroleum geology at Imperial College London. He returned to Iraq in 1957 – by then married to Solfrid, who had been working in London as an au pair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once home, al-Kasim started his working life at the company. Half a century later, eyes shining with glee, he recalls the first time he entered the oil executives’ club in Basra. “I walked across the room, straight up to the bar, where I sat down and ordered a drink. Then I turned around and looked back at all the British managers with their wives, who were staring at me in silence. It was the first time they had seen an Iraqi enter the club, except as a servant.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the company could reassure itself that he was no radical anti-imperialist. “I’m a mild man … I got the impression that I fitted in their scheme as a balanced person who will take over management at one time, and treat IPC fairly.” When he left at 31, he was number five at the company and its highest-ranking Iraqi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table align=&quot;right&quot; cellpadding=&quot;3&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; id=&quot;U2504845726156uE&quot; width=&quot;55%&quot; readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;center&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;An old family portrait of the al-Kasims&quot; height=&quot;190&quot; src=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20100123225932im_/http://media.ft.com/cms/30a926dc-92ba-11de-b63b-00144feabdc0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;250&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;center&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gen-freestyle-fsmaller&quot;&gt;The al-Kasims in the early 1970s&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
Al-Kasim and his family wouldn’t have left Iraq but for their son’s medical problems, but even so, the move was politically sensitive. In the past, he’d been stopped at the border on orders from the secret police, who considered him a key figure for any future nationalisation of the oil industry. Now it took months to secure permission to take his son for what they had to pretend would be short-term medical treatment abroad. “It was a smuggling operation … we were only trying to save the life of our youngest child. But in Iraq, these things don’t matter.”
&lt;p&gt;Nor was it straightforward to resign from his job. When al-Kasim broke the news to his boss in London, “he said: ‘Damn you, Farouk. We were counting on you. Now you are letting us down.’” The top director put pressure on him to stay, but al-Kasim explained that only Norway offered the care his son needed. In the end, his superiors relented. “My immediate boss said: ‘I can’t promise you that you will get a job, but I can say now that we will not stop you getting one.’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so no one interfered when Norway’s Ministry of Industry hired al-Kasim as a consultant. His job would be to analyse the North Sea exploration results – at a salary just above that of the prime minister.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;bodystrong&quot;&gt;. . .&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poor countries dream of finding oil like poor people fantasise about winning the lottery. But the dream often turns into a nightmare as new oil exporters realise that their treasure brings more trouble than help. Juan Pablo Pérez Alfonso, one time Venezuelan oil minister, likened oil to “the devil’s excrement”. Sheikh Ahmed Yamani, his Saudi Arabian counterpart, reportedly said: “I wish we had found water.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such resignation reflects bitter experience of the way that dependency on natural resources can poison a country’s economic and political system. Inflows of hard currency push up prices, squeezing the competitiveness of non-oil businesses and starving them of capital. As a result, productivity growth withers (a phenomenon known as “Dutch disease” after the negative effects of North Sea gas production on the Netherlands). Meanwhile, the state institutions in charge of oil often become corrupt and evade democratic control. And oil-rich states almost invariably waste the income it brings, many ending their oil booms deeper in debt than when they started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is better understood today than it was 40 years ago. When al-Kasim arrived in Oslo, no one was worrying about how oil might challenge Norway – in part because they didn’t think any would be found. The Geological Survey of Norway had dismissed the possibility just 10 years earlier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The politicians and senior bureaucrats had not caught oil fever. A serious mining accident had recently brought down a government, and most did not want to touch oil matters with a bargepole. “Everything I said was met with, ‘Oh, you think so? Mmm. Maybe. Let’s wait and see’,” al-Kasim recalls. “This characteristic saved Norway from the curse of oil: the fact that they are completely incapable of getting carried away by the oil dream. They were very sceptical – plain horse sense basically. They didn’t want to move until it was absolutely proven that it was the right time to act.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His was a lonely, contrarian voice. After examining exploration results, he wrote a report that warned Norway was sleeping, that even though no one had found oil yet, it was only a question of time. And time was short: the country’s leaders needed to prepare Norway to become an oil nation, but they were doing nothing. “I was a constant reminder that they were doing everything wrong,” al-Kasim says pointedly. Only his closest colleagues would listen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;bodystrong&quot;&gt;. . .&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table align=&quot;right&quot; cellpadding=&quot;3&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; id=&quot;U250484572615zV&quot; width=&quot;55%&quot; readability=&quot;2.5&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;center&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;A view inside StatoilHydro's Troll A platform&quot; height=&quot;167&quot; src=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20100123225932im_/http://media.ft.com/cms/abb6decc-92bb-11de-b63b-00144feabdc0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;250&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;center&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gen-freestyle-fsmaller&quot;&gt;Inside StatoilHydro’s Troll A platform, the largest oil and gas source in Europe, supplying 12 per cent of the continent’s natural gas&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
Oil companies were starting to leave Norway. Well after well had turned out dry and Phillips Petroleum, the first company to explore the Norwegian continental shelf and the last one still searching, was getting ready to throw in the towel. In summer 1969, it asked to be relieved of the final exploration well remaining in its work programme. The government’s oil office refused: if Phillips did not drill the well, it would have to pay a fee equal to the cost of drilling. Realising it would be cheaper just to drill, Phillips went ahead one last time. This well banished any thought of leaving. Forty years ago this December, Phillips declared the Ekofisk field one of the world’s largest offshore oil basins.
&lt;p&gt;Overnight, Norway turned into a hydrocarbon superpower. Today, it is the world’s sixth-biggest net exporter of oil and the second-biggest net natural gas exporter. In the years since the Ekofisk discovery, the country has exported oil and gas equivalent to some 30 billion barrels of crude – and the continental shelf still contains, by official estimates, almost twice as much again. Yet the country has escaped the problems that beset most other oil exporters. Rather than stifling productivity, the oil sector has spawned world-class exploration, oil services and construction technology. Norway’s state oil company, StatoilHydro, is internationally recognised as a competitive commercial player and one of the most environmentally and socially conscious ones to boot. Since 1996, every krone the government has earned from oil has gone into a savings fund, which now totals some £240bn – more than a year’s gross domestic product and equivalent to about £50,000 for each of Norway’s 4.8 million citizens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The real achievement, in other words, was not finding oil but coping with its discovery. Norway faced the same dilemma as every other new oil producer with no experience of the industry: if you rely too much on private foreign companies, too little of the oil wealth benefits the country in the form of government revenue or economic development; if you go too far in the other direction, you risk a bloated, politicised oil sector that evades both accountability to the people and competitive pressures to be efficient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A balance had to be struck. Al-Kasim recalls now that one thing was clear in the early 1970s: Norway would join an international trend towards significant state participation in the oil sector. The Labour government “wanted this to be the new impetus in Norwegian industry”, he says. “And for that to be done properly, according to a socialist, the state has to be in the driver’s seat.” Al-Kasim agreed with that view, and so landed the job of writing the nation’s blueprint for how it would organise its fledgling oil industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The office was no place for this work, al-Kasim and a colleague decided. So on a summer day in 1971, they left Oslo for the colleague’s cabin in the woods, where they spent what al-Kasim remembers as the most exciting work week of his life. They worked on the plan into the early hours, taking fishing trips “between the battles”, he recalls. By the time they came home, they had drafted a government white paper that was later presented to parliament and unanimously waved into law. This created the Norwegian Petroleum Directorate, the oil industry regulator, and Statoil, the national oil company (now known as StatoilHydro).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trick of the Norwegian model was to retain the private sector’s competitive drive and its expertise – which Norway sorely needed – by making sure that the regulator was independent enough to rein in the state oil company as well as its private-sector peers. This was not secured without a fight. Statoil, after all, was going to generate a lot of money – and very soon it did. Willy Olsen, a fast-talking former Statoil manager, says: “Statoil and the Norwegian Petroleum Directorate didn’t have the friendliest of relationships. The first 10 to 12 years, the institutions were very unbalanced – Statoil was much heavier. NPD had to fight to gain respect, and for that it needed enthusiasts with enough competence that they could not be dismissed.” That became al-Kasim’s mission – and his job for the next two decades – as the regulator’s director of resource management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;bodystrong&quot;&gt;. . .&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table align=&quot;right&quot; cellpadding=&quot;3&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; id=&quot;U250484572615zH&quot; width=&quot;55%&quot; readability=&quot;1.5&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;center&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;An archive photo of two ships towing a Statfjord A platform into the North Sea&quot; height=&quot;168&quot; src=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20100123225932im_/http://media.ft.com/cms/a9f21d7c-92bb-11de-b63b-00144feabdc0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;250&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;center&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gen-freestyle-fsmaller&quot;&gt;The Statfjord A platform is towed into the North Sea, May 1977&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
“Farouk is perhaps the greatest value creator Norway has had,” says Olsen. And with good reason. Most of the oil found in the world is never recovered: the average extraction rate worldwide is around 25 per cent. Norway averages 45 per cent, and for that, Olsen gives al-Kasim much of the credit: he pushed the government to increase extraction rates; insisted that companies try new technologies, such as water injection in chalk reservoirs or horizontal drilling; and threatened to withdraw operating licences from companies that balked. “It is this culture, a culture of ‘squeezing the last drop out’, which he cultivated,” says Olsen.
&lt;p&gt;The extraction rates al-Kasim forced through significantly boosted oil and gas revenues – and so indirectly, the size of the savings fund. But the culture of pursuing the “last drop” brought greater benefits than just money pouring in. It spurred the development of technological expertise that has enabled Norwegian companies to compete with the best in the world. This, then, is a striking case of strong state regulation ultimately benefiting the private sector. “Norway is the only country in the world where the state and the capitalistic entities work together as partners, and the co-operation works, really works,” says al-Kasim. Paradoxically, state involvement makes this easier. “To put it very simply, you put your wallet where your mouth is … When you take 50 per cent of the risk, and other companies take maybe 15 per cent tops, it is hard for them to say you’re crazy, right?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, al-Kasim is well known and liked within the older generation of Norway’s oil community (for whom his impromptu visit to the Ministry in May 1968 has entered the folklore). Beyond that limited circle, however, he is virtually unknown. The big newspapers have not profiled him; an internet search reveals little. I first learned of his story by coincidence, when a Norwegian development official mentioned him in an off-hand remark. The government has an ambitious aid programme (now called “Oil for Development”) to help poor, oil-rich states manage their natural resources. The official pointed out the irony in this, given that “it was an Iraqi guy who helped us set everything up in the first place. Without him we would just have let the American oil companies decide how to do things.” What a great story, I thought, almost too good to be true. But if it was true, how come so few people in Norway knew about it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I visited al-Kasim in Stavanger twice last winter to hear his account first-hand, he seemed pleased that I had got in touch, but surprised and slightly embarrassed – like someone with a story to tell but who has long since given up hope that anyone would listen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At one point he sighed that young people today have little knowledge of what Norway did in order to succeed. That sounds like the typical complaint of a 73-year-old, but in this case, the disappointment is justified. Norwegians of my generation, born when the oil started to flow, largely take our country’s success for granted. So do many observers abroad, who tend to attribute it to some exceptional feature of Norway’s institutions and national character. This version of events leaves little room for luck, or for outsiders. It is hard to shake off the thought that al-Kasim’s pivotal role does not quite fit his adoptive country’s public self-image – 40 years ago or today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it is not so surprising that al-Kasim’s first years in Norway were not without frustrations. “We were a good team” in the oil office, he says – but relations with the Norwegian government proved delicate. “They obviously needed me, but they knew they couldn’t put me in an office in the ministry. It would be a provocation to the political system that was not ready for it. So the plan was to introduce me gradually, gradually, bit by bit, inch by inch … I was treated with kid gloves.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In spite of the importance of his work, al-Kasim was kept at a safe distance from the main government offices at first, and worked at the hydrological division of the Geological Survey of Norway. For years, he never met the people who were making the strategic and political decisions – his colleagues in the oil office would act as go-betweens, bringing their superiors’ questions to him and taking his answers back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the Ekofisk find, he had to train new recruits. “I, of course, accepted that I am teaching people so that they can make my existence unnecessary … What choice did I have? I had only one hope, and that is that through my contribution, I would become indispensable, which I did.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;bodystrong&quot;&gt;. . .&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table align=&quot;right&quot; cellpadding=&quot;3&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; id=&quot;U220131577693cIH&quot; width=&quot;55%&quot; readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;center&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Solfrid and Farouk al-Kasim&quot; height=&quot;185&quot; src=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20100123225932im_/http://media.ft.com/cms/2eb175c8-92ba-11de-b63b-00144feabdc0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;250&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;center&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gen-freestyle-fsmaller&quot;&gt;Farouk al-Kasim and his wife, Solfrid, in Stavanger in August 2009&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
During my last visit to Stavanger, Norway’s greatest value creator and his wife took me out for dinner. Over seafood on Stavanger harbour, they mused about how unpredictably their lives had turned out. Al-Kasim returned to Iraq only once, as part of an official Norwegian delegation in the late 1970s. Saddam Hussein’s regime wooed him – but “I never trusted that guy”. After Saddam’s regime fell, he drafted oil industry legislation for Iraq that would have “followed what can be followed from the Norwegian model”, but political horse-trading so altered the draft that he has disowned the version that the Iraqi government finally endorsed (it has not been passed into law).
&lt;p&gt;The al-Kasims had got out of Iraq just months before the Ba’ath party took power. “You can’t use the word blessing in disguise, but …” Solfrid said softly. “If I had been given the choice, I would not have wanted my son to be handicapped … but today I may not have had any children at all, since they would have been sent to the war.” (As it is, all three children today live in Stavanger, their youngest son “completely transformed” by the treatment he received in Norway.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her husband nodded. “Not everything in life has been good – but things have mostly come in a fortunate order. It’s got nothing to do with skill, it’s simply luck. Like the idea to drop by the Department of Industry … it was just because I am the kind of person who hates waiting.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When did he start feeling Norwegian, I asked. After a pause, he responded: “I think the answer must be when I started working at Norwegian Petroleum Directorate, for then I had a whole institution depending on me … it was my institution in a way, that’s how I felt. That this was my experiment. My calling in life.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Martin Sandbu is a Financial Times leader writer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 01:20:13 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>sndean</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://web.archive.org/web/20100123225932/http://www.ft.com/cms/s/2/99680a04-92a0-11de-b63b-00144feabdc0.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: Water.css – A just-add-css collection of styles to make websites nicer</title>
<link>https://github.com/kognise/water.css</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/kognise/water.css</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;Box-body&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content p-5&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://kognise.github.io/water.css/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/kognise/water.css/raw/master/logo.svg?sanitize=true&quot; alt=&quot;Water.css&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A just-add-css collection of styles to make simple websites just a little nicer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/webdev/comments/b9m6mv/watercss_a_collection_of_neat_styles_for_simple/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/f29cece8e2bfa7f74740725a5e6734263e7ec516/68747470733a2f2f696d672e736869656c64732e696f2f62616467652f6f6e2d7265646469742d6f72616e67652e737667&quot; alt=&quot;On reddit&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/on-reddit-orange.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.producthunt.com/posts/water-css&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/331cde78a9914c8bf9ecdb928a8e32e81e4391ab/68747470733a2f2f696d672e736869656c64732e696f2f62616467652f6f6e2d70726f6475637425323068756e742d7265642e737667&quot; alt=&quot;On product hunt&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/on-product%20hunt-red.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kognise/water.css/blob/master/LICENSE.md&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/c02f24242d7af76a35a55427b7957d8e0a04227e/68747470733a2f2f696d672e736869656c64732e696f2f6769746875622f6c6963656e73652f6b6f676e6973652f77617465722e6373732e737667&quot; alt=&quot;MIT license&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/license/kognise/water.css.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Responsive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good code quality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good browser support (works on my old kindle's browser :P)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Small size (&amp;lt; 2kb)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beautiful&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No classes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Why?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I commonly make quick demo pages or websites with simple content. For these, I don't want to spend time styling them but don't like the uglyness of the default styles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Water.css is a css framework that doesn't require any classes. You just include it in your &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;head&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; and forget about it, while it silently makes everything nicer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Who?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might want to use Water.css if you're making a simple static or demo website that you don't want to spend time styling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You probably don't want to use it for a production app or something that has more than a simple document. Rule of thumb: if your site has a navbar, don't use Water.css. It's just not meant for that kind of content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just stick this in your head:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-text-html-basic&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&amp;lt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;link&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-e&quot;&gt;rel&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;stylesheet&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-e&quot;&gt;href&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/kognise/water.css@latest/dist/dark.css&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, there's a dark theme and a light theme. If you want the light theme, use &lt;code&gt;light.css&lt;/code&gt; instead of &lt;code&gt;dark.css&lt;/code&gt;. See &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kognise/water.css#theming&quot;&gt;Theming&lt;/a&gt; to make your own theme!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No other classes or code is required to make Water.css work. If you want a specific version, you can replace &lt;code&gt;@latest&lt;/code&gt; with &lt;code&gt;@version&lt;/code&gt;. See &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kognise/water.css/releases&quot;&gt;all the versions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oh, you want a demo you say?&lt;/strong&gt; Cheeky fellah! &lt;a href=&quot;https://kognise.github.io/water.css/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Well, here's your demo.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't like how it looks? Feel free to submit an issue or PR with suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Water.css becomes better for everyone when people like you help make it better!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have any questions or concerns? Did I forget an element or selector? Does something look ugly? Feel free to submit an issue or pull request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you decide to contribute, after downloading a copy of the repository make sure to run &lt;code&gt;yarn&lt;/code&gt; to install dependencies useful for development. Then, you can just run the following to start a server of the demo with live reloading and automatic Sass compiling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;$ yarn dev
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And make sure to run &lt;code&gt;yarn build&lt;/code&gt; before pushing any changes! Thanks for taking the time to contribute :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Theming&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you want to make your own theme different from the light or dark themes? Since Water.css is built with Sass this is super easy to do. There are two methods. Also, here's a list of variables to set:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;$background&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;$background-alt&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;$text-main&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;$text-bright&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;$links&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;$focus&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;$border&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;$code&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;$button-hover&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;$animation-duration&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;$form-placeholder&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;$form-text&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wanna quickly try out theming without installing anything or just explore our build environment?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://repl.it/@Kognise/watercss-node?ref=button&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/8c49657b2f8bb6c32cd8125fa3d77cdb518eb927/68747470733a2f2f7265706c2d62616467652e6a616a6f6f73616d2e7265706c2e636f2f7472792e706e67&quot; alt=&quot;Try on Repl.it&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://repl-badge.jajoosam.repl.co/try.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Based on an existing theme&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can base your theme off of the existing light or dark themes, which already have some variables predefined to make it easier for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's some simple Sass that'll just use the dark theme but color all links red. Of course, you can change any variables you want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-scss&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;$links&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;#ff0000&lt;/span&gt;;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;@import&lt;/span&gt; '&lt;span class=&quot;pl-v&quot;&gt;dark.scss&lt;/span&gt;';
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;From scratch&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also make your theme from scratch. This is less recommended, but feel free to! You just have to define all of the variables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, here's an example of a really ugly theme, made from scratch. &lt;strong&gt;Ouch!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-scss&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;$background&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;#ff48c2&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;!default&lt;/span&gt;;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;$background-alt&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;#00ff00&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;!default&lt;/span&gt;;

&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;$text-main&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;#dbdbdb&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;!default&lt;/span&gt;;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;$text-bright&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;#ffffff&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;!default&lt;/span&gt;;

&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;$links&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;#ff0022&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;!default&lt;/span&gt;;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;$focus&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;#ffc400&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;!default&lt;/span&gt;;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;$border&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;#00ffff&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;!default&lt;/span&gt;;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;$code&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;#001aff&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;!default&lt;/span&gt;;

&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;$button-hover&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;#324759&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;!default&lt;/span&gt;;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;$animation-duration&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;0.1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;s&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;!default&lt;/span&gt;;

&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;$form-placeholder&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;#a9a9a9&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;!default&lt;/span&gt;;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;$form-text&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;#ffffff&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;!default&lt;/span&gt;;

&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;@import&lt;/span&gt; '&lt;span class=&quot;pl-v&quot;&gt;parts/core&lt;/span&gt;';
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also only import parts you want, but this is not recommended. See the &lt;code&gt;src/parts/&lt;/code&gt; folder for a list of parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Todos&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 00:12:14 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>archmaster</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars1.githubusercontent.com/u/42556441?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>kognise/water.css</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/kognise/water.css</og:url>
<og:description>A just-add-css collection of styles to make simple websites just a little nicer - kognise/water.css</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/kognise/water.css</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Polish general who fought with Washington may have been female</title>
<link>https://asunow.asu.edu/20190405-discoveries-asu-bioarchaeologist-uncovers-200-year-old-mystery</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://asunow.asu.edu/20190405-discoveries-asu-bioarchaeologist-uncovers-200-year-old-mystery</guid>
<description>&lt;section itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-hero discoveries&quot;&gt;

&lt;img alt=&quot;image title&quot; class=&quot;img-sr-only&quot; src=&quot;https://asunow.asu.edu/sites/default/files/styles/asu_news_article_hero/public/pulaski-1170x683.jpg?itok=blIQG_d-&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;container article-body first-section discoveries space-bot-xl&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-8 col-md-pull-4 pad-left-md&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;asu-publish-date&quot;&gt;April 5, 2019&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;ASU professor, colleague uncover 200-year-old mystery from the American Revolution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chadds Ford, Pennsylvania, 1777. At the end of a daylong battle, George Washington’s &lt;span class=&quot;article-annotation&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;annotation-term&quot; rel=&quot;annotation-toggle&quot;&gt;right flank&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;annotation-content&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Somewhere on the battlefield is Private Johan Wilhelm Seckel, 40, the first of his family born in America — and ancestor to ASU Now reporter Scott Seckel — serving with the Germantown Battalion Continental Troops in Capt. George Hubley's Company.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; has completely collapsed. British troops are closing in. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A dashing Polish cavalry officer reports to Washington’s bodyguard that they are in danger of being surrounded. Washington orders Casimir Pulaski to gather as many men as he can. Count Pulaski discovers an escape route past the British advance, then wheels and charges enemy lines. The redcoats are astounded to be attacked by what they thought was a fleeing rabble. Washington escapes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pulaski is revered as the father of American cavalry. He came to America of his own volition to fight in the War of Independence. One of the Revolution’s great heroes, he was a loner. A very private person, he was extremely driven and difficult with people. (It’s one reason Washington simply ended up giving Pulaski his own legion, most of whom were Europeans.) Both superiors and subordinates considered him imperious. He was brave in battle to the point of recklessness. Detractors called him a loose cannon. Short and thin, pacing and speaking quickly, he lacked interest in women or drinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And he harbored a secret that lay unknown for more than 200 years, until an Arizona State University bioarchaeologist and a colleague discovered the truth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monday night a documentary unveiling the mystery airs on the Smithsonian Channel. But it doesn’t tell the whole story ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the late 1990s, &lt;a href=&quot;https://isearch.asu.edu/profile/22368&quot;&gt;Charles Merbs&lt;/a&gt; and his wife visited their daughter in Savannah, Georgia. A forensic anthropologist at Arizona State University’s now School of Human Evolution and Social Change, Merbs’ expertise lies in skeletal remains, especially reconstructing behavior from skeletons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The family toured the historic city, including a visit to Casimir Pulaski’s monument. Merbs is Polish on his mother’s side. His mother always told him they were related to the Pulaskis and should be proud of that. (“It’s been impossible to prove,” he said. “The records just aren’t there.”)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pulaski was mortally wounded during the Battle of Savannah. (Like most Revolutionary War battles, the American side lost.) He was hit in the groin by grapeshot. Grapeshot was pingpong-size metal balls collected in a canvas bag and fired from a cannon. It acted like shotgun pellets and was used as an antipersonnel round.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was taken aboard an American ship, where he died a few days later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Then the story gets murky as to what happens to his body,” Merbs, now retired, said. “One story is that he was buried at sea on the way back to Charleston. The other story is that in the dead of night his body was taken ashore and buried by torchlight on a plantation. It was done secretly. The plantation owners knew about it and maintained the burial.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1854, it was decided to build a monument to Pulaski. The bones were exhumed and reburied beneath the monument in a metal box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A week after their visit to Savannah, Merbs’ daughter called. The monument was being taken down. Iron spacers between the stones were rusting. The whole thing was in danger of collapsing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Merbs tracked down the physical anthropologist working with the bones — Karen Burns, of the University of Georgia — and offered to help. She accepted. “That’s how I got involved,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before Merbs was allowed to examine the remains, however, he had to sign a document swearing him to secrecy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Basically I couldn’t say anything about what I found until the final report came out,” he said. “Dr. Burns said to me before I went in, ‘Go in and don’t come out screaming.’ She said study it very carefully and thoroughly and then let’s sit down and discuss it. I went in and immediately saw what she was talking about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The skeleton is about as female as can be.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next — and obvious — question: Was it Pulaski or someone else who had been stuck in the tomb because a skeleton was needed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything seemed to match. The stature, age and general body build were all correct for Pulaski. There’s one contemporary portrait of Pulaski painted from life. There’s a black smudge below his left eye. “On the skull there is a bone defect right exactly there,” Merbs said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pulaski injured his right hand in a battle in Russia. “Sure enough; the fourth and fifth metacarpals in the right hand had fractured and had healed rather poorly, exactly where they were supposed to be,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Merbs has done forensic work with the Maricopa County Medical Examiner’s Office, including working with the skeletons of equestrians. Riding a lot shows up in skeletons. Horse rider’s syndrome is a whole series of issues that affect bones, primarily in the pelvis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“That skeleton definitely showed signs of horseback riding,” Merbs said, including a new one he added to the lexicon of horse rider’s syndrome: the skeleton’s shoulder showed signs of holding arms high, as would be done holding and pulling back on reins or raising a heavy saber. (Cavalrymen killed enemies by swinging their swords directly down on the crown of their heads. Ever notice the tall bearskin caps worn by the guards at Buckingham Palace? They were designed to protect from exactly that blow.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The forehead showed an injury consistent with a wound from a blade, although Merbs couldn’t be sure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption caption-left panopoly-image-original&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-width-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;ASU Charles Merbs examines grapeshot which killed Pulaski&quot; title=&quot;ASU Charles Merbs examines grapeshot which killed Pulaski&quot; class=&quot;media-element file-default panopoly-image-original&quot; data-delta=&quot;1&quot; typeof=&quot;foaf:Image&quot; src=&quot;https://asunow.asu.edu/sites/default/files/styles/panopoly_image_original/public/pulaski-grapeshot-450.jpg?itok=DLgTxfgy&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;Charles Merbs examines the grapeshot that killed Casimir Pulaski. Photo courtesy of Charles Merbs &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Everything matched, except for the sex,” he said. “The sex was as clearly female as anything could be.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something that could be reasonably suspected of a woman in her 30s would be evidence of childbirth. “There were no parturition scars on this pelvis,” Merbs said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next step was a positive DNA identification. When the skeleton was exhumed in the 1850s, most of its teeth were missing, except for a few molars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Those teeth had been taken out when the skeleton was excavated,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was evidence of a macabre but common custom of the time. During the Napoleonic Wars, when millions died in massive clashes, tooth hunters scavenged battlefields. Dead soldiers’ teeth were in great demand for making dentures. (In 1814 an Englishman recorded a meeting with a tooth hunter. When asked how he obtained them, he replied, “Oh sir, only let there be a battle, and there’ll be no want of teeth. I’ll draw them as fast as the men are knocked down.”) After the Battle of Waterloo in 1815, the market became so flooded they became known as Waterloo teeth. Because they came from healthy young men, they were advertised as such.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s very likely around the time the people of Savannah were wearing Pulaski’s teeth,” Merbs said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They had enough of Pulaski’s DNA to turn the investigation in that direction. But who could they compare it to? Burns and Merbs looked at Pulaski’s genealogy and found out he had two brothers and six sisters. Mitochondrial DNA is passed through women. Of the six sisters, only one had a child. Luckily it was a daughter. She had another daughter. Pulaski and his grandniece would share the same mitochondrial DNA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her grave was excavated and samples returned, but nothing usable turned up. “That was 20 years ago,” Merbs said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently three young researchers, one of whom studied archaeology at ASU, decided to look into the mystery. DNA work had come quite a long way in 20 years. Something new might turn up. They got a lab to give them an analysis estimate, which turned out to be $18,000. They contacted the Smithsonian Institute, which funded the research last summer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results came back positive. The mitochondrial DNA was identical in both Pulaski and his grandniece.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Now we know that the bones in the monument were indeed those of Pulaski, but we have the problem of the fact that they are female,” Merbs said. “Here’s the thing: if you go back and look at his life, what we know about it, there are interesting little clues along the way.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aristocratic Polish Catholic families in the 18th century traditionally held public baptisms in church.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“In his case it said he was suffering from some &lt;em&gt;debilitatus,&lt;/em&gt; and they held off on the baptism and privately baptized him at home,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suddenly, Pulaski’s personality traits — aloof, driven, private, brazen in battle — fell into line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We think the problem goes back to his birth and basically deciding whether he was a boy or a girl,” Merbs said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Merbs’ oldest daughter is a professor at Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine. She put him in touch with a specialist in sex and gender issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“With scientists, sex and gender are two totally different things,” Merbs said. “Sex is biological, and gender is social and behavioral. Ordinarily the two go together, but you can have a conflict between the two. That’s what I think we were dealing with here.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Merbs explained to the professor he thought they were dealing with a sex-gender problem. The professor took out a stack of photographs of bare babies and told him and his wife to put them in one of two piles — girls and boys — which they did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“One hundred percent,” the professor said. “You are one hundred percent wrong. You were wrong on every single one.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Merbs thinks the Pulaski family, faced with a similar situation, had to make a decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So Pulaski was raised as a man, in a military family. It was without question he would become an officer, and so he did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I don’t think, at any time in his life, did he think he was a woman,” Merbs said. “I think he just thought he was a man, and something was wrong. He had some kind of defect or something. Back in those days they just didn’t know.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did that perhaps play a part in Pulaski’s aggression on the battlefield?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Oh, I think that’s a big part of it,” Merbs said. “I think his whole personality indicates he was driven, and I think that’s the reason why.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Merbs kept his secret, until now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This was definitely not what the good folks of Savannah wanted us to find, and the whole thing became a political hot potato,” he said. “They wanted us to verify that the remains were indeed those of a male Pulaski, which would then be interred at Arlington.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without conclusive DNA evidence, it was considered that Burns and Merbs' observations were opinion, not fact. The bones were reburied next to the monument. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Burns died several years ago. Merbs has a small credit in the documentary. Both Merbs and Burns names appear in the Pulaski Exhibit in Savannah. Merbs’ contributions are clearly spelled out in an article about to be submitted to the Journal of Forensic Anthropology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“America’s Hidden Stories: The General Was Female?” will air on the Smithsonian Channel at 8 and 11 p.m. Monday, April 8, and at 1 p.m. Tuesday, April 9.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Top image courtesy of the Library of Congress&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;space-bot-lg&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;clearfix&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;author-image&quot; src=&quot;https://asunow.asu.edu/sites/default/files/styles/asu_news_profile_image/public/pictures/seckel_0.jpg?itok=xS5cLMHe&quot; alt=&quot;Scott Seckel &quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;container news-article-heading news-article pad-top-xl&quot;&gt;

&lt;hr class=&quot;space-top-0&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row news-article-headingbody space-bot-lg&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-xs-12 col-sm-10 col-sm-offset-1 space-bot-sm&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;asu-publish-date&quot;&gt;April 5, 2019&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Cairo regionals&quot; src=&quot;https://thesundevils.com/common/controls/image_handler.aspx?thumb_prefix=rp_primary&amp;amp;image_path=/images/2019/4/5/106A9727.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cairo Leonard-Baker won the Baton Rouge Regional bar title with a 9.925 as No. 21 Arizona State gymnastics took third in the second session of the second round on Friday, falling short of advancing to the finals. &lt;span class=&quot;image-with-caption image-with-caption-border-right image-with-caption-float-left&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://asunow.asu.edu/sites/default/files/styles/asu_news_article_image/public/default_images/asu-watermark-lg-dk_0_0.png?itok=YEYgnkGN&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;description&quot;&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://asunow.asu.edu/sites/default/files/default_images/asu-watermark-lg-dk_0_0.png&quot;&gt;Download Full Image&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 20:43:11 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>uxhacker</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>The general was female?</og:title>
<og:url>https://asunow.asu.edu/20190405-discoveries-asu-bioarchaeologist-uncovers-200-year-old-mystery</og:url>
<og:description>Count Casimir Pulaski is revered as the father of American cavalry. He came to America of his own volition to fight in the War of Independence. One of the Revolution’s great heroes, he was a very private person. And he harbored a secret that lay unknown for more than 200 years, until an ASU bioarchaeologist and a colleague discovered the truth. Tonight a documentary unveiling the mystery airs on the Smithsonian Channel. But it doesn’t tell the whole story.</og:description>
<og:image>https://asunow.asu.edu/sites/default/files/pulaski-1170x683.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://asunow.asu.edu/20190405-discoveries-asu-bioarchaeologist-uncovers-200-year-old-mystery</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Nuclear power is the fastest way to slash greenhouse gas emissions, decarbonize</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/04/06/opinion/sunday/climate-change-nuclear-power.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2019/04/06/opinion/sunday/climate-change-nuclear-power.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;As young people rightly demand real solutions to climate change, the question is not &lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; to do — eliminate fossil fuels by 2050 — but &lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;how&lt;/em&gt;. Beyond decarbonizing today’s electric grid, we must use clean electricity to replace fossil fuels in transportation, industry and heating. We must provide for the fast-growing energy needs of poorer countries and extend the grid to a billion people who now lack electricity. And still more electricity will be needed to remove excess carbon dioxide from the atmosphere by midcentury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Where will this gargantuan amount of carbon-free energy come from? The popular answer is renewables alone, but this is a fantasy. Wind and solar power are becoming cheaper, but they are not available around the clock, rain or shine, and batteries that could power entire cities for days or weeks show no sign of materializing any time soon. Today, renewables work only with fossil-fuel backup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Germany, which went all-in for renewables, has seen little reduction in carbon emissions, and, according to our calculations, at Germany’s rate of adding clean energy relative to gross domestic product, it would take the world more than a century to decarbonize, even if the country wasn’t also retiring nuclear plants early. A few lucky countries with abundant hydroelectricity, like Norway and New Zealand, have decarbonized their electric grids, but their success cannot be scaled up elsewhere: The world’s best hydro sites are already dammed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Small wonder that a growing response to these intimidating facts is, “We’re cooked.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;But we actually have proven models for rapid decarbonization with economic and energy growth: France and Sweden. They decarbonized their grids decades ago and now emit less than a tenth of the world average of carbon dioxide per kilowatt-hour. They remain among the world’s most pleasant places to live and enjoy much &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://ec.europa.eu/eurostat/documents/10186/8482435/Q12017_electricity_prices_graphics.pdf&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;cheaper electricity than Germany&lt;/a&gt; to boot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;They did this with nuclear power. And they did it fast, taking advantage of nuclear power’s intense concentration of energy per pound of fuel. France replaced almost all of its fossil-fueled electricity with nuclear power nationwide in just 15 years; Sweden, in about 20 years. In fact, most of the fastest additions of clean electricity historically are countries rolling out nuclear power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;This is a realistic solution to humanity’s greatest problem. Plants built 30 years ago in America, as in France, produce cheap, clean electricity, and nuclear power is the cheapest source in South Korea. The 98 U.S. reactors today provide nearly 20 percent of the nation’s electricity generation. So why don’t the United States and other countries expand their nuclear capacity? The reasons are economics and fear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;New nuclear power plants are hugely expensive to build in the United States today. This is why so few are being built. But they don’t need to be so costly. The key to recovering our lost ability to build affordable nuclear plants is standardization and repetition. The first product off any assembly line is expensive — it cost &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2013/10/06/magazine/and-then-steve-said-let-there-be-an-iphone.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;more than $150 million&lt;/a&gt; to develop the first iPhone — but costs plunge as they are built in quantity and production kinks are worked out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Yet as a former chairman of the Nuclear Regulatory Commission &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/archive/lifestyle/1995/05/29/farewell-gestures/1fa9ca85-f049-4b92-814d-c72780b0bf1e/?utm_term=.5d76a7e454fc&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;put it&lt;/a&gt;, while France has two types of reactors and hundreds of types of cheese, in the United States it’s the other way around. In recent decades, the United States and some European countries have created ever more complicated reactors, with ever more safety features in response to public fears. New, one-of-a-kind designs, shifting regulations, supply-chain and construction snafus and a lost generation of experts (during the decades when new construction stopped) have driven costs to absurd heights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;These economic problems are solvable. China and South Korea can build reactors at one-sixth the current cost in the United States. With the political will, China could replace coal without sacrificing economic growth, reducing world carbon emissions by more than 10 percent. In the longer term, dozens of American start-ups are developing “fourth generation” reactors that can be mass-produced, potentially generating electricity at lower cost than fossil fuels. If American activists, politicians and regulators allow it, these reactors could be exported to the world in the 2030s and ’40s, slaking poorer countries’ growing thirst for energy while creating well-paying American jobs. Currently, fourth-generation nuclear power receives rare bipartisan agreement in Congress, making it a particularly appealing American policy to address climate change. Congress recently passed the Nuclear Energy Innovation and Modernization Act by big margins. Both parties love innovation, entrepreneurship, exports and jobs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;This approach will need a sensible regulatory framework. Currently, as M.I.T.’s Richard Lester, a nuclear engineer, &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://issues.org/a-roadmap-for-u-s-nuclear-energy-innovation/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;has written&lt;/a&gt;, a company proposing a new reactor design faces “the prospect of having to spend a billion dollars or more on an open-​ended, all‑or‑nothing licensing process without any certainty of outcomes.” We need government on the side of this clean-energy transformation, with supportive regulation, streamlined approval, investment in research and incentives that tilt producers and consumers away from carbon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;All this, however, depends on overcoming an irrational dread among the public and many activists. The reality is that nuclear power is the safest form of energy humanity has ever used. Mining accidents, hydroelectric dam failures, natural gas explosions and oil train crashes all kill people, sometimes in large numbers, and smoke from coal-burning kills them in enormous numbers, more than half a million per year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;By contrast, in 60 years of nuclear power, only three accidents have raised public alarm: Three Mile Island in 1979, which killed no one; Fukushima in 2011, which killed no one (many deaths resulted from the tsunami and some from a panicked evacuation near the plant); and Chernobyl in 1986, the result of extraordinary Soviet bungling, which killed 31 in the accident and perhaps several thousand from cancer, around the same number killed by coal emissions &lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;every day&lt;/em&gt;. (Even if we accepted recent claims that Soviet and international authorities covered up tens of thousands of Chernobyl deaths, the death toll from 60 years of nuclear power would still equal about one month of coal-related deaths.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Nuclear power plants cannot explode like nuclear bombs, and they have not contributed to weapons proliferation, thanks to robust international controls: 24 countries have nuclear power but not weapons, while Israel and North Korea have nuclear weapons but not power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Nuclear waste is compact — America’s total from 60 years would fit in a Walmart — and is safely stored in concrete casks and pools, becoming less radioactive over time. After we have solved the more pressing challenge of climate change, we can either burn the waste as fuel in new types of reactors or bury it deep underground. It’s a far easier environmental challenge than the world’s enormous coal waste, routinely dumped near poor communities and often laden with toxic arsenic, mercury and lead that can last &lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;forever&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Despite its demonstrable safety, nuclear power presses several psychological buttons. First, people estimate risk according to how readily anecdotes like well-publicized nuclear accidents pop into mind. Second, the thought of radiation activates the mind-set of disgust, in which any trace of contaminant fouls whatever it contacts, despite the reality that we all live in a soup of natural radiation. Third, people feel better about eliminating a single tiny risk entirely than minimizing risk from all hazards combined. For all these reasons, nuclear power is dreaded while fossil fuels are tolerated, just as flying is scary even though driving is more dangerous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Opinions are also driven by our cultural and political tribes. Since the late 1970s, when No Nukes became a signature cause of the Green movement, sympathy to nuclear power became, among many environmentalists, a sign of disloyalty if not treason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Despite these challenges, psychology and politics can change quickly. As the enormity of the climate crisis sinks in and the hoped-for carbon savings from renewables don’t add up, nuclear can become the new green. Protecting the environment and lifting the developing world out of poverty are progressive causes. And the millennials and Gen Z’s might rethink the sacred values their boomer parents have left unexamined since the Doobie Brothers sang at the 1979 No Nukes concert.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;If the American public and politicians can face real threats and overcome unfounded fears, we can solve humanity’s most pressing challenge and leave our grandchildren a bright future of climate stability and abundant energy. We can dispatch, once and for all, the self-fulfilling prophesy that we’re cooked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1psfkbx etfikam0&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://www.joshuagoldstein.com/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Joshua S. Goldstein&lt;/a&gt;, professor emeritus of international relations at American University, and &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://www.staffanqvist.com/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Staffan A. Qvist&lt;/a&gt;, a Swedish energy engineer, are the authors of “A Bright Future: How Some Countries Have Solved Climate Change and the Rest Can Follow.” &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://stevenpinker.com/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Steven Pinker&lt;/a&gt; is a professor of psychology at Harvard University and is the author of “Enlightenment Now&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1psfkbx etfikam0&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;The Times is committed to publishing&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/01/31/opinion/letters/letters-to-editor-new-york-times-women.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;a diversity of letters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;to the editor. We’d like to hear what you think about this or any of our articles. Here are some&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://help.nytimes.com/hc/en-us/articles/115014925288-How-to-submit-a-letter-to-the-editor&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;tips&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;. And here’s our email:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;mailto:letters@nytimes.com&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;letters@nytimes.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1psfkbx etfikam0&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;Follow The New York Times Opinion section on&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/nytopinion&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://twitter.com/NYTOpinion&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;Twitter (@NYTopinion)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/nytopinion/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 20:16:42 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jseliger</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/04/06/opinion/sunday/climate-change-nuclear-power.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Opinion | Nuclear Power Can Save the World</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/03/31/opinion/31Pinker/31Pinker-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Expanding the technology is the fastest way to slash greenhouse gas emissions and decarbonize the economy.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/04/06/opinion/sunday/climate-change-nuclear-power.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>