<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Silicon Valley is terrified of California’s privacy law</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/19/silicon-valley-terrified-california-privacy-law/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/19/silicon-valley-terrified-california-privacy-law/</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot;&gt;Silicon Valley is terrified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a little over three months, California will see the widest-sweeping state-wide changes to its privacy law in years. California’s Consumer Privacy Act (CCPA) kicks in &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/JustinBrookman/status/1171868417860743174&quot;&gt;on January 1&lt;/a&gt; and rolls out sweeping new privacy benefits to the state’s 40 million residents — and every tech company in Silicon Valley.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;California’s law is &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/01/20/wtf-is-gdpr/&quot;&gt;similar to Europe’s GDPR&lt;/a&gt;. It &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/06/28/landmark-california-privacy-bill-heads-to-governors-desk/&quot;&gt;grants&lt;/a&gt; state consumers a right to know what information companies have on them, a right to have that information deleted and the right to opt-out of the sale of that information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For California residents, these are extremely powerful provisions that allow consumers access to their own information from companies that collect an increasingly alarming amount of data on their users. Look &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/25/facebook-ignored-staff-warnings-about-sketchy-cambridge-analytica-in-september-2015/&quot;&gt;no further&lt;/a&gt; than Cambridge Analytica, which saw Facebook profile page data weaponized and used against millions to try to sway an election. And given &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/08/uks-ico-fines-british-airways-a-record-183m-over-gdpr-breach-that-leaked-data-from-500000-users/&quot;&gt;some of&lt;/a&gt; the &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/09/marriott-data-breach-uk-fine/&quot;&gt;heavy fines&lt;/a&gt; levied in recent months under GDPR, tech companies will have to brace for more fines when the enforcement provision &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/JustinBrookman/status/1171876787166568448&quot;&gt;kicks in&lt;/a&gt; six months later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No wonder the law has Silicon Valley shaking in its boots. It absolutely should.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s no surprise that some of the largest tech companies in the U.S. — most of which are located in California — &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2019/09/thanks-helping-us-defend-california-consumer-privacy-act&quot;&gt;lobbied to weaken&lt;/a&gt; the CCPA’s provisions. These companies don’t want to be on the hook for having to deal with what they see as burdensome requests enshrined in the state’s new law any more than they currently are for Europeans with GDPR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the extensive lobbying, California’s legislature &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/06/28/landmark-california-privacy-bill-heads-to-governors-desk/&quot;&gt;passed the bill&lt;/a&gt; with minor amendments, much to the chagrin of tech companies in the state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Don’t let this post-Cambridge Analytica ‘mea culpa’ fool you into believing these companies have consumers’ best interests in mind,” wrote the ACLU’s Neema Singh Guliani &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aclu.org/blog/privacy-technology/internet-privacy/dont-be-fooled-tech-industrys-push-federal-privacy&quot;&gt;last year&lt;/a&gt;, shortly after the bill was signed into law. “This seeming willingness to subject themselves to federal regulation is, in fact, an effort to enlist the Trump administration and Congress in companies’ efforts to weaken state-level consumer privacy protections,” she wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the law passed, tech giants have pulled out their last card: pushing for an overarching federal bill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In doing so, the companies would be able to control their messaging through &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2019/04/04/votervoice-leak/&quot;&gt;their extensive lobbying efforts&lt;/a&gt;, allowing them to push for a weaker statute that would nullify some of the provisions in California’s new privacy law. In doing so, companies wouldn’t have to spend a ton on more resources to ensure their compliance with a variety of statutes in multiple states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just this month, a group of 51 chief executives — including Amazon’s Jeff Bezos, IBM’s Ginni Rometty and SAP’s Bill McDermott — signed &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessroundtable.org/business-roundtable-ceos-call-on-congress-to-pass-comprehensive-nationwide-consumer-data-privacy-law&quot;&gt;an open letter&lt;/a&gt; to senior lawmakers asking for a federal privacy bill, arguing that consumers aren’t clever enough to “understand rules that may change depending upon the state in which they reside.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, the Internet Association, which counts Dropbox, Facebook, Reddit, Snap, Uber (and &lt;a href=&quot;https://internetassociation.org/internet-association-adds-ziprecruiter-to-its-resume/&quot;&gt;just today&lt;/a&gt; ZipRecruiter) as members, also pushed for &lt;a href=&quot;https://internetassociation.org/internet-industry-launches-campaign-urging-congress-to-pass-comprehensive-federal-privacy-legislation/&quot;&gt;a federal privacy law&lt;/a&gt;. “The time to act is now,” said the industry group. If the group gets its wish before the end of the year, the California privacy law could be sunk before it kicks in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And TechNet, a “national, bipartisan network of technology CEOs and senior executives,” also demanded &lt;a href=&quot;http://technet.org/press-release/technet-statement-on-the-california-consumer-privacy-act&quot;&gt;a federal privacy law&lt;/a&gt;, claiming — and without providing evidence — that any privacy law should ensure “businesses can comply with the law while continuing to innovate.” Its members include major venture capital firms, including Kleiner Perkins and JC2 Ventures, as well as other big tech giants like Apple, Google, Microsoft, Oracle and Verizon (which owns TechCrunch).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know there’s something fishy going on when tech giants and telcos team up. But it’s not fooling anyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s no accident that the tech industry launched this campaign right after the California legislature rejected their attempts to undermine the California Consumer Privacy Act,” Jacob Snow, a technology and civil liberties attorney at the ACLU of Northern California, told TechCrunch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Instead of pushing for federal legislation that wipes away state privacy law, technology companies should ensure that Californians can fully exercise their privacy rights under the CCPA on January 1, 2020, as the law requires,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s little lawmakers in Congress can do in three months before the CCPA deadline, but it won’t stop tech giants from trying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Californians might not have the CCPA for long if Silicon Valley tech giants and their lobbyists get their way, but rest easy knowing the consumer won — for once.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 18:33:23 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ssklash</dc:creator>
<og:title>Silicon Valley is terrified of California’s privacy law. Good. – TechCrunch</og:title>
<og:description>Silicon Valley is terrified. In a little over three months, California will see the widest-sweeping state-wide changes to its privacy law in years. California’s Consumer Privacy Act (CCPA) kicks in on January 1 and rolls out sweeping new privacy benefits to the state’s 40 million reside…</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Screen-Shot-2019-09-19-at-12.03.57-PM.jpg?w=600</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2019/09/19/silicon-valley-terrified-california-privacy-law/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/19/silicon-valley-terrified-california-privacy-law/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Birds Are Vanishing from North America</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/09/19/science/bird-populations-america-canada.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2019/09/19/science/bird-populations-america-canada.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The skies are emptying out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The number of birds in the United States and Canada &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://science.sciencemag.org/lookup/doi/10.1126/science.aaw1313&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;has fallen by 29 percent since 1970&lt;/a&gt;, scientists reported on Thursday. There are 2.9 billion fewer birds taking wing now than there were 50 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The analysis, published in the journal Science, is the most exhaustive and ambitious attempt yet to learn what is happening to avian populations. The results have shocked researchers and conservation organizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In a statement on Thursday, David Yarnold, president and chief executive of the National Audubon Society, called the findings “a full-blown crisis.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Experts have long known that some bird species have become vulnerable to extinction. But the new study, based on a broad survey of more than 500 species, reveals steep losses even among such traditionally abundant birds as robins and sparrows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;There are likely many causes, the most important of which include habitat loss and wider use of pesticides. “Silent Spring,” Rachel Carson’s prophetic book in 1962 about the harms caused by pesticides, takes its title from the unnatural quiet settling on a world that has lost its birds:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“On the mornings that had once throbbed with the dawn chorus of robins, catbirds, doves, jays, wrens, and scores of other bird voices, there was now no sound.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Kevin Gaston, a conservation biologist at the University of Exeter, said that new findings signal something larger at work: “This is the loss of nature.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;css-8qgvsz ebyp5n10&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;[&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;css-8qgvsz ebyp5n10&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://on.fb.me/1paTQ1h&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;Like the Science Times page on Facebook.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;| Sign up for the&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong class=&quot;css-8qgvsz ebyp5n10&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://nyti.ms/1MbHaRU&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;Science Times newsletter.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;css-8qgvsz ebyp5n10&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Common bird species are vital to ecosystems, controlling pests, pollinating flowers, spreading seeds and regenerating forests. When these birds disappear, their former habitats often are not the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“Declines in your common sparrow or other little brown bird may not receive the same attention as historic losses of bald eagles or sandhill cranes, but they are going to have much more of an impact,” said Hillary Young, a conservation biologist at the University of California, Santa Barbara, who was not involved in the new research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;A team of researchers from universities, government agencies and nonprofit organizations collaborated on the new study, which combined old and new methods for counting birds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;For decades, professional ornithologists have been assisted by an army of devoted amateur bird-watchers who submit their observations to databases and help carry out surveys of bird populations each year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In the new study, the researchers turned to those surveys to estimate the populations of 529 species between 2006 and 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-79elbk&quot; data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-wrapper&quot;&gt;

&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-children&quot; class=&quot;css-1a48zt4 ehw59r15&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1xdhyk6 erfvjey0&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;“It’s not just these highly threatened birds that we’re afraid are going to go on the endangered species list,” said Kenneth V. Rosenberg, a conservation scientist. “It’s across the board.”&quot; class=&quot;css-1m50asq&quot; src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/09/19/science/19SCI-MATTER-BIRDS5/19SCI-MATTER-BIRDS5-articleLarge.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;disable=upscale&quot; srcset=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/09/19/science/19SCI-MATTER-BIRDS5/19SCI-MATTER-BIRDS5-articleLarge.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 600w,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/09/19/science/19SCI-MATTER-BIRDS5/19SCI-MATTER-BIRDS5-jumbo.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 1024w,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/09/19/science/19SCI-MATTER-BIRDS5/19SCI-MATTER-BIRDS5-superJumbo.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 2048w&quot; sizes=&quot;((min-width: 600px) and (max-width: 1004px)) 84vw, (min-width: 1005px) 80vw, 100vw&quot; itemprop=&quot;url&quot; itemid=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/09/19/science/19SCI-MATTER-BIRDS5/19SCI-MATTER-BIRDS5-articleLarge.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;disable=upscale&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;“It’s not just these highly threatened birds that we’re afraid are going to go on the endangered species list,” said Kenneth V. Rosenberg, a conservation scientist. “It’s across the board.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e1z0qqy90&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;David Goldman/Associated Press&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-a7yk8a e73j0it0&quot;&gt;

&lt;span aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;A dark-eyed junco.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e1z0qqy90&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Jay McGowan, Macaulay Library at Cornell Lab of Ornithology&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;A cactus wren.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e1z0qqy90&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Brian Sullivan, Macaulay Library at Cornell Lab of Ornithology&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Those estimates include 76 percent of all bird species in the United States and Canada, but represent almost the entire population of birds. (The species for which there weren’t enough data to make firm estimates occur only in small numbers.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The researchers then used bird-watching records to estimate the population of each species since 1970, the earliest year for which there is solid data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“This approach of combining population abundance estimates across all species and looking for an overall trend is really unprecedented,” said Scott Loss, a conservation biologist at Oklahoma State University who was part of the new study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;While some species grew, the researchers found, the majority declined — often by huge numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“We were stunned by the result — it’s just staggering,” said Kenneth V. Rosenberg, a conservation scientist at Cornell University and the American Bird Conservancy, and the lead author of the new study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“It’s not just these highly threatened birds that we’re afraid are going to go on the endangered species list,” he said. “It’s across the board.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Weather radar offered another way to track bird populations. Dr. Rosenberg and his colleagues counted birds recorded on radar at 143 stations across the United States from 2007 to 2018. They focused on springtime scans, when birds were migrating in great numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The team measured a 14 percent decline during that period, consistent with the drop recorded in the bird-watching records.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“If we have two data sets showing the same thing, it’s a home run,” said Nicole Michel, a senior quantitative ecologist at the Audubon Society who was not involved in the study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Among the worst-hit groups were warblers, with a population that dropped by 617 million. There are 440 million fewer blackbirds than there once were.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;section id=&quot;bird-loss-map&quot; data-id=&quot;100000006726409&quot; class=&quot;interactive-content interactive-size-scoop css-evtfcr&quot;&gt;&lt;header id=&quot;interactive-header&quot; class=&quot;css-cl76n0 interactive-header&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;interactive-headline&quot; class=&quot;css-1su19vv interactive-headline&quot;&gt;Three Billion Birds&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p data-testid=&quot;leadin&quot; id=&quot;interactive-leadin&quot; class=&quot;css-1vs7yia interactive-leadin&quot;&gt;A survey of 529 bird species in the United States and Canada found that bird populations have fallen by 29 percent since 1970, a loss of nearly three billion birds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/header&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;css-17ih8de interactive-body&quot; data-sourceid=&quot;100000006726409&quot;&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;g-birdmap-box&quot; class=&quot;ai2html&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-birdmap-900&quot; class=&quot;g-artboard&quot; data-aspect-ratio=&quot;1.32&quot; data-min-width=&quot;900&quot;&gt;

&lt;img id=&quot;g-birdmap-900-img&quot; class=&quot;g-aiImg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/newsgraphics/2019/09/19/bird-loss-map/fbd1a22911cd42c0c391a93f57a270b8aac35056/birdmap-900.png&quot; src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhCgAKAIAAAB8fHwAAACH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAAKAAoAAAIIhI+py+0PYysAOw==&quot;/&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai0-1&quot; class=&quot;g-chart g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle0&quot;&gt;Bird population change since 1970 &lt;span class=&quot;g-cstyle0&quot;&gt;by breeding habitat&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;








&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai0-10&quot; class=&quot;g-chart g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle2&quot;&gt;Grasslands&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai0-11&quot; class=&quot;g-chart g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle2&quot;&gt;Boreal forests&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai0-12&quot; class=&quot;g-chart g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle2&quot;&gt;Western forests&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai0-14&quot; class=&quot;g-chart g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle2&quot;&gt;Generalist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai0-16&quot; class=&quot;g-chart g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle2&quot;&gt;Forest generalist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai0-17&quot; class=&quot;g-chart g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle2&quot;&gt;Eastern forests&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai0-18&quot; class=&quot;g-chart g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle2&quot;&gt;Arid lands&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai0-19&quot; class=&quot;g-map_labels g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle1&quot;&gt;Western&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle1&quot;&gt;forests&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai0-22&quot; class=&quot;g-map_labels g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle2&quot;&gt;Boreal forests&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai0-24&quot; class=&quot;g-map_labels g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle1&quot;&gt;Arid&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle1&quot;&gt;lands&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai0-25&quot; class=&quot;g-time_series g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle3&quot;&gt;200 million&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai0-26&quot; class=&quot;g-map_labels g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle2&quot;&gt;Grasslands&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai0-27&quot; class=&quot;g-map_labels g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle1&quot;&gt;Eastern&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle1&quot;&gt;forests&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai0-28&quot; class=&quot;g-time_series g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle3&quot;&gt;400 million&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai0-29&quot; class=&quot;g-type g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle4&quot;&gt;Note: Wetland and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle4&quot;&gt;coastal habitats&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle4&quot;&gt;are not shown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle4&quot;&gt;Habitat boundaries&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle4&quot;&gt;are approximate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai0-30&quot; class=&quot;g-time_series g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle5&quot;&gt;Net loss of&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle3&quot;&gt;600 million birds&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;





&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-birdmap-600&quot; class=&quot;g-artboard&quot; data-aspect-ratio=&quot;1.226&quot; data-min-width=&quot;600&quot; data-max-width=&quot;719&quot;&gt;

&lt;img id=&quot;g-birdmap-600-img&quot; class=&quot;g-aiImg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/newsgraphics/2019/09/19/bird-loss-map/fbd1a22911cd42c0c391a93f57a270b8aac35056/birdmap-600.png&quot; src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhCgAKAIAAAB8fHwAAACH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAAKAAoAAAIIhI+py+0PYysAOw==&quot;/&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai1-1&quot; class=&quot;g-chart_copy g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle0&quot;&gt;Population change since 1970 &lt;span class=&quot;g-cstyle0&quot;&gt;by breeding habitat&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;








&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai1-10&quot; class=&quot;g-chart_copy g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle2&quot;&gt;Grasslands&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai1-11&quot; class=&quot;g-chart_copy g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle2&quot;&gt;Boreal forests&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai1-12&quot; class=&quot;g-chart_copy g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle2&quot;&gt;Western forests&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai1-15&quot; class=&quot;g-chart_copy g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle2&quot;&gt;Generalist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai1-16&quot; class=&quot;g-chart_copy g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle2&quot;&gt;Forest generalist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai1-17&quot; class=&quot;g-chart_copy g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle2&quot;&gt;Eastern forests&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai1-18&quot; class=&quot;g-map_labels_copy g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle1&quot;&gt;Western&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle1&quot;&gt;forests&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai1-19&quot; class=&quot;g-chart_copy g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle2&quot;&gt;Arid lands&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai1-21&quot; class=&quot;g-map_labels_copy g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle2&quot;&gt;Boreal forests&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai1-24&quot; class=&quot;g-map_labels_copy g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle1&quot;&gt;Arid&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle1&quot;&gt;lands&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai1-25&quot; class=&quot;g-map_labels_copy g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle2&quot;&gt;Grasslands&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai1-26&quot; class=&quot;g-map_labels_copy g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle1&quot;&gt;Eastern&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle1&quot;&gt;forests&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai1-27&quot; class=&quot;g-time_series_copy g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle3&quot;&gt;200 million&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai1-28&quot; class=&quot;g-time_series_copy g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle3&quot;&gt;400 million&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai1-29&quot; class=&quot;g-type_copy g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle4&quot;&gt;Note: Wetland and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle4&quot;&gt;coastal habitats&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle4&quot;&gt;are not shown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle4&quot;&gt;Habitat boundaries&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle4&quot;&gt;are approximate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai1-30&quot; class=&quot;g-time_series_copy g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle5&quot;&gt;Net loss of&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle3&quot;&gt;600 million birds&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;





&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-birdmap-335&quot; class=&quot;g-artboard&quot; data-aspect-ratio=&quot;0.44&quot; data-min-width=&quot;335&quot; data-max-width=&quot;599&quot;&gt;

&lt;img id=&quot;g-birdmap-335-img&quot; class=&quot;g-aiImg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/newsgraphics/2019/09/19/bird-loss-map/fbd1a22911cd42c0c391a93f57a270b8aac35056/birdmap-335.png&quot; src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhCgAKAIAAAB8fHwAAACH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAAKAAoAAAIIhI+py+0PYysAOw==&quot;/&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai2-2&quot; class=&quot;g-map_labels_copy_2 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle0&quot;&gt;Western&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle0&quot;&gt;forests&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai2-3&quot; class=&quot;g-map_labels_copy_2 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle1&quot;&gt;Boreal forests&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai2-4&quot; class=&quot;g-map_labels_copy_2 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle0&quot;&gt;Arid&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle0&quot;&gt;lands&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai2-5&quot; class=&quot;g-map_labels_copy_2 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle1&quot;&gt;Grasslands&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai2-6&quot; class=&quot;g-map_labels_copy_2 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle0&quot;&gt;Eastern&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle0&quot;&gt;forests&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai2-7&quot; class=&quot;g-type_copy_2 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle2&quot;&gt;Note: Wetland and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle2&quot;&gt;coastal habitats&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle2&quot;&gt;are not shown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle2&quot;&gt;Habitat boundaries&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle2&quot;&gt;are approximate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai2-8&quot; class=&quot;g-chart_copy_2 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle3&quot;&gt;Population change since 1970 &lt;span class=&quot;g-cstyle0&quot;&gt;by breeding habitat&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;








&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai2-17&quot; class=&quot;g-chart_copy_2 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle1&quot;&gt;Grasslands&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai2-18&quot; class=&quot;g-chart_copy_2 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle1&quot;&gt;Boreal forests&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai2-19&quot; class=&quot;g-chart_copy_2 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle1&quot;&gt;Western forests&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai2-21&quot; class=&quot;g-chart_copy_2 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle1&quot;&gt;Generalist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai2-22&quot; class=&quot;g-chart_copy_2 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle1&quot;&gt;Forest generalist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai2-23&quot; class=&quot;g-chart_copy_2 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle1&quot;&gt;Eastern forests&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai2-24&quot; class=&quot;g-chart_copy_2 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle1&quot;&gt;Arid lands&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-birdmap-720&quot; class=&quot;g-artboard&quot; data-aspect-ratio=&quot;1.207&quot; data-min-width=&quot;720&quot; data-max-width=&quot;899&quot;&gt;

&lt;img id=&quot;g-birdmap-720-img&quot; class=&quot;g-aiImg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/newsgraphics/2019/09/19/bird-loss-map/fbd1a22911cd42c0c391a93f57a270b8aac35056/birdmap-720.png&quot; src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhCgAKAIAAAB8fHwAAACH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAAKAAoAAAIIhI+py+0PYysAOw==&quot;/&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai3-1&quot; class=&quot;g-chart_copy_3 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle0&quot;&gt;Bird population change since 1970 &lt;span class=&quot;g-cstyle0&quot;&gt;by breeding habitat&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;








&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai3-10&quot; class=&quot;g-chart_copy_3 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle2&quot;&gt;Grasslands&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai3-11&quot; class=&quot;g-chart_copy_3 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle2&quot;&gt;Boreal forests&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai3-12&quot; class=&quot;g-chart_copy_3 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle2&quot;&gt;Western forests&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai3-15&quot; class=&quot;g-chart_copy_3 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle2&quot;&gt;Generalist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai3-16&quot; class=&quot;g-chart_copy_3 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle2&quot;&gt;Forest generalist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai3-17&quot; class=&quot;g-chart_copy_3 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle2&quot;&gt;Eastern forests&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai3-18&quot; class=&quot;g-chart_copy_3 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle2&quot;&gt;Arid lands&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai3-19&quot; class=&quot;g-map_labels_copy_3 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle1&quot;&gt;Western&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle1&quot;&gt;forests&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai3-21&quot; class=&quot;g-map_labels_copy_3 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle2&quot;&gt;Boreal forests&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai3-24&quot; class=&quot;g-map_labels_copy_3 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle1&quot;&gt;Arid&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle1&quot;&gt;lands&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai3-25&quot; class=&quot;g-map_labels_copy_3 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle2&quot;&gt;Grasslands&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai3-26&quot; class=&quot;g-time_series_copy_2 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle3&quot;&gt;200 million&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai3-27&quot; class=&quot;g-map_labels_copy_3 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle1&quot;&gt;Eastern&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle1&quot;&gt;forests&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai3-28&quot; class=&quot;g-time_series_copy_2 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle3&quot;&gt;400 million&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai3-29&quot; class=&quot;g-type_copy_3 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle4&quot;&gt;Note: Wetland and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle4&quot;&gt;coastal habitats&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle4&quot;&gt;are not shown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle4&quot;&gt;Habitat boundaries&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle4&quot;&gt;are approximate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai3-30&quot; class=&quot;g-time_series_copy_2 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle5&quot;&gt;Net loss of&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle3&quot;&gt;600 million birds&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;





&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-birdmap-300&quot; class=&quot;g-artboard&quot; data-aspect-ratio=&quot;0.44&quot; data-min-width=&quot;0&quot; data-max-width=&quot;334&quot;&gt;

&lt;img id=&quot;g-birdmap-300-img&quot; class=&quot;g-aiImg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/newsgraphics/2019/09/19/bird-loss-map/fbd1a22911cd42c0c391a93f57a270b8aac35056/birdmap-300.png&quot; src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhCgAKAIAAAB8fHwAAACH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAAKAAoAAAIIhI+py+0PYysAOw==&quot;/&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai4-2&quot; class=&quot;g-map_labels_copy_4 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle0&quot;&gt;Western&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle0&quot;&gt;forests&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai4-3&quot; class=&quot;g-map_labels_copy_4 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle1&quot;&gt;Boreal forests&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai4-4&quot; class=&quot;g-map_labels_copy_4 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle0&quot;&gt;Arid&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle0&quot;&gt;lands&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai4-5&quot; class=&quot;g-map_labels_copy_4 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle1&quot;&gt;Grasslands&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai4-6&quot; class=&quot;g-map_labels_copy_4 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle0&quot;&gt;Eastern&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle0&quot;&gt;forests&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai4-7&quot; class=&quot;g-type_copy_4 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle2&quot;&gt;Note: Wetland and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle2&quot;&gt;coastal habitats&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle2&quot;&gt;are not shown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle2&quot;&gt;Habitat boundaries&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle2&quot;&gt;are approximate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai4-8&quot; class=&quot;g-chart_copy_4 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;g-cstyle0&quot;&gt;Population change&lt;/span&gt; since 1970 by breeding habitat&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;








&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai4-17&quot; class=&quot;g-chart_copy_4 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle1&quot;&gt;Grasslands&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai4-18&quot; class=&quot;g-chart_copy_4 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle1&quot;&gt;Boreal forests&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai4-19&quot; class=&quot;g-chart_copy_4 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle1&quot;&gt;Western forests&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai4-21&quot; class=&quot;g-chart_copy_4 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle1&quot;&gt;Generalist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai4-22&quot; class=&quot;g-chart_copy_4 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle1&quot;&gt;Forest generalist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai4-23&quot; class=&quot;g-chart_copy_4 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle1&quot;&gt;Eastern forests&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai4-24&quot; class=&quot;g-chart_copy_4 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle1&quot;&gt;Arid lands&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;footer id=&quot;interactive-footer&quot; class=&quot;css-irejme interactive-footer&quot;&gt;&lt;p data-testid=&quot;credit&quot; id=&quot;interactive-credit&quot; class=&quot;css-1g8gl4z interactive-credit&quot;&gt;By The New York Times | Source: Science&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Dr. Rosenberg said he was surprised by how widespread the population drop was. Even starlings — a species that became a fast-breeding pest after its introduction to the United States in 1890 — have dwindled by 83 million birds, a 49 percent decline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Europe is experiencing a similar loss of birds, also among common species, said Dr. Gaston, of the University of Exeter. “The numbers are broadly comparable,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The new study was not designed to determine why birds are disappearing, but the results — as well as earlier research — point to some likely culprits, Dr. Rosenberg said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Grassland species have suffered the biggest declines by far, having lost 717 million birds. These birds have probably been decimated by modern agriculture and development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“Every field that’s plowed under, and every wetland area that’s drained, you lose the birds in that area,” Dr. Rosenberg said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In addition to habitat loss, pesticides may have taken a toll. A study published last week, for example, found that pesticides called neonicotinoids &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://science.sciencemag.org/content/365/6458/1177&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;make it harder for birds to put on weight needed for migration&lt;/a&gt;, delaying their travel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-a7yk8a e73j0it0&quot;&gt;

&lt;span aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;Baltimore oriole.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e1z0qqy90&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Gary Mueller, Macaulay Library at Cornell Lab of Ornithology&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;A wood thrush.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e1z0qqy90&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Michael Parr, American Bird Conservancy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-79elbk&quot; data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-wrapper&quot;&gt;

&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-children&quot; class=&quot;css-1a48zt4 ehw59r15&quot;&gt;

&lt;span aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;Wintering snow geese in the Sacramento Valley.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e1z0qqy90&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Aerial Archives/Alamy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The researchers found some positive signs. Bald eagles are thriving, for example, and falcon populations have grown by 33 percent. Waterfowl are on the upswing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;For the most part, there’s little mystery about how these happy exceptions came to be. Many recovering bird species were nearly wiped out in the last century by pesticides, hunting and other pressures. Conservation measures allowed them to bounce back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“In those cases, we knew what the causes were and we acted on that,” Dr. Rosenberg said. “They’re models of success.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;But some thriving populations are harder to explain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Tiny warbler-like birds called vireos are booming, with 89 million more birds than in 1970 — a jump of 53 percent. Yet warblers, which share the same habitats as vireos, have suffered a 37 percent decline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“I have no idea why vireos are doing well,” Dr. Rosenberg said. “I’d love to do a study of vireos and discover what their secret is.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The sheer scale of the bird decline meant that stopping it would require immense effort, said Dr. Young, of the University of California, Santa Barbara. Habitats must be defended, chemicals restricted, buildings redesigned. “We’re overusing the world, so it’s affecting everything,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The Audubon Society is calling for protection of bird-rich habitats, such as the Great Lakes and the Colorado River Basin, as well as for upholding the Migratory Bird Treaty Act, which the Trump Administration is trying to roll back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The society and other bird advocacy groups also suggest things that individuals can do. They urge keeping cats inside, so they don’t kill smaller birds. Vast numbers of birds die each year after flying into windows; there are ways to make the glass more visible to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;To some birders, the study’s findings confirmed a dreaded hunch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Beverly Gyllenhaal, 62, a retired cookbook author, and her husband, Anders, have spotted 256 species in parks in the eastern United States. But when she visited her mother in North Carolina in recent years, it seemed there weren’t as many birds as she recalled from her childhood there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;And when she talks to people around the United States on her birding travels, many say the same thing. “Oftentimes people will tell you, ‘It’s nothing like it used to be,’” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The estimated losses have left her appalled. “If the cardinals and the blue jays and the sparrows aren’t doing well,” she said, “that’s really scary.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;Burrowing owls. Video by Cornell Lab of Ornithology&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-g92qtk epkadsg3&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1owp1gq epkadsg0&quot;&gt;More articles about birds&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 18:12:23 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>wiggles_md</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/09/19/science/bird-populations-america-canada.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Birds Are Vanishing From North America</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/09/19/science/19SCI-MATTER-BIRDS-sanderling1/19SCI-MATTER-BIRDS-sanderling-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>The number of birds in the United States and Canada has declined by 3 billion, or 29 percent, over the past half-century, scientists find.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/09/19/science/bird-populations-america-canada.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>LLVM 9.0</title>
<link>http://lists.llvm.org/pipermail/llvm-dev/2019-September/135304.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://lists.llvm.org/pipermail/llvm-dev/2019-September/135304.html</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;title&gt;[llvm-dev] LLVM 9.0.0 Release&lt;/title&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;Index&quot; href=&quot;index.html&quot; /&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;made&quot; href=&quot;mailto:llvm-dev%40lists.llvm.org?Subject=Re%3A%20%5Bllvm-dev%5D%20LLVM%209.0.0%20Release&amp;amp;In-Reply-To=%3CCAB8jPheqQjvq21mC8ifK3sPZxZRNu0S0F-eTA73djXwbCqf%3DhA%40mail.gmail.com%3E&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;robots&quot; content=&quot;index,nofollow&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;Content-Type&quot; content=&quot;text/html; charset=utf-8&quot; /&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;Previous&quot; href=&quot;135308.html&quot; /&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;Next&quot; href=&quot;135305.html&quot; /&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body bgcolor=&quot;#FFFFFF&quot; id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;33.963157894737&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hans Wennborg via llvm-dev&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:llvm-dev%40lists.llvm.org?Subject=Re%3A%20%5Bllvm-dev%5D%20LLVM%209.0.0%20Release&amp;amp;In-Reply-To=%3CCAB8jPheqQjvq21mC8ifK3sPZxZRNu0S0F-eTA73djXwbCqf%3DhA%40mail.gmail.com%3E&quot; title=&quot;[llvm-dev] LLVM 9.0.0 Release&quot;&gt;llvm-dev at lists.llvm.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thu Sep 19 10:47:21 PDT 2019&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;pre&gt;
It's my great pleasure to announce that LLVM 9 is now available.

Get it here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://llvm.org/releases/download.html#9.0.0&quot;&gt;https://llvm.org/releases/download.html#9.0.0&lt;/a&gt;

This release is the result of the LLVM community's work over the past
six months (up to trunk r366426 plus commits on the branch). Some
highlights include:

- Support for asm goto, enabling for example the mainline Linux kernel
  for x86_64 to build with Clang
- The RISCV-V target is no longer experimental, but built by default
- Experimental support for C++ for OpenCL

as well as many bug fixes, optimizations, and diagnostics improvements.

For more details, see the release notes:
&lt;a href=&quot;https://llvm.org/releases/9.0.0/docs/ReleaseNotes.html&quot;&gt;https://llvm.org/releases/9.0.0/docs/ReleaseNotes.html&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://llvm.org/releases/9.0.0/tools/clang/docs/ReleaseNotes.html&quot;&gt;https://llvm.org/releases/9.0.0/tools/clang/docs/ReleaseNotes.html&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://llvm.org/releases/9.0.0/tools/clang/tools/extra/docs/ReleaseNotes.html&quot;&gt;https://llvm.org/releases/9.0.0/tools/clang/tools/extra/docs/ReleaseNotes.html&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://llvm.org/releases/9.0.0/tools/lld/docs/ReleaseNotes.html&quot;&gt;https://llvm.org/releases/9.0.0/tools/lld/docs/ReleaseNotes.html&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://llvm.org/releases/9.0.0/projects/libcxx/docs/ReleaseNotes.html&quot;&gt;https://llvm.org/releases/9.0.0/projects/libcxx/docs/ReleaseNotes.html&lt;/a&gt;

Special thanks to the release testers and packagers: Amy Kwan, Andrew
Kelley, Bernhard Rosenkraenzer, Brian Cain, Diana Picus, Dimitry
Andric, Jonas Hahnfeld, Khem Raj, Michał Górny, Neil Nelson, Nick
Desaulniers, Sylvestre Ledru, and Victor Huang. Without your work,
this would not be possible.

For questions or comments about the release, please contact the
community on the mailing lists. Onwards to LLVM 10!

Thanks,
Hans
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.llvm.org/cgi-bin/mailman/listinfo/llvm-dev&quot;&gt;More information about the llvm-dev mailing list&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 17:49:54 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>AndyKelley</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://lists.llvm.org/pipermail/llvm-dev/2019-September/135304.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Stripe’s new funding round values company at $35B</title>
<link>https://www.wsj.com/articles/fintech-company-stripe-joins-silicon-valley-elite-with-35-billion-valuation-11568912443?mod=rsswn</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.wsj.com/articles/fintech-company-stripe-joins-silicon-valley-elite-with-35-billion-valuation-11568912443?mod=rsswn</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;is-lead-inset&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div data-layout=&quot;header&amp;#10;              &quot; data-layout-mobile=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&amp;#10;        media-object&amp;#10;        type-InsetMediaIllustration&amp;#10;          header&amp;#10;  article__inset&amp;#10;        article__inset--type-InsetMediaIllustration&amp;#10;          article__inset--header&amp;#10;    article__inset--lead&amp;#10;  &quot;&gt;
      
      
          
    &lt;figure class=&quot;media-object-image enlarge-image renoImageFormat- img-header article__inset__image&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot;&gt;&lt;div data-mobile-ratio=&quot;66.66666666666666%&quot; data-layout-ratio=&quot;66.66666666666666%&quot; data-subtype=&quot;photo&quot; class=&quot;image-container  responsive-media article__inset__image__image&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img srcset=&quot;https://images.wsj.net/im-108500?width=140&amp;amp;size=1.5 140w,&amp;#10;https://images.wsj.net/im-108500?width=540&amp;amp;size=1.5 540w,&amp;#10;https://images.wsj.net/im-108500?width=620&amp;amp;size=1.5 620w,&amp;#10;https://images.wsj.net/im-108500?width=700&amp;amp;size=1.5 700w,&amp;#10;https://images.wsj.net/im-108500?width=860&amp;amp;size=1.5 860w,&amp;#10;https://images.wsj.net/im-108500?width=1260&amp;amp;size=1.5 1260w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 140px) 100px,&amp;#10;(max-width: 540px) 500px,&amp;#10;(max-width: 620px) 580px,&amp;#10;(max-width: 700px) 660px,&amp;#10;(max-width: 860px) 820px,&amp;#10;1260px&quot; src=&quot;https://images.wsj.net/im-108500?width=620&amp;amp;size=1.5&quot; data-enlarge=&quot;https://images.wsj.net/im-108500?width=1260&amp;amp;size=1.5&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;‘Stripe is more than ever a bet on the internet as an economic engine,’ said...&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

    
      &lt;figcaption class=&quot;wsj-article-caption article__inset__image__caption&quot; itemprop=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;wsj-article-caption-content&quot;&gt;‘Stripe is more than ever a bet on the internet as an economic engine,’ said Will Gaybrick, Stripe’s chief product officer.&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;wsj-article-credit article__inset__image__caption__credit&quot; itemprop=&quot;creator&quot;&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;wsj-article-credit-tag&quot;&gt;
              Photo: 
            &lt;/span&gt;
        Anthony Kwan/Bloomberg News
          &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt; 
    &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;clearfix byline-wrap&quot;&gt;


      
      &lt;div class=&quot;byline article__byline&quot;&gt;
      
      
          &lt;span&gt;By&lt;/span&gt;
              &lt;div class=&quot;author mobile-scrim hasMenu&quot; data-scrim=&quot;{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;author&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;header&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Peter Rudegeair&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;subhead&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;The Wall Street Journal&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;list&amp;quot;:[{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;bio&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.wsj.com/news/author/8240&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Biography&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;twitter&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://twitter.com/rudegeair&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;@rudegeair&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;email&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;mailto:peter.rudegeair@wsj.com&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;peter.rudegeair@wsj.com&amp;quot;}]}&quot;&gt;
                  &lt;span class=&quot;name&quot; itemprop=&quot;name&quot;&gt;Peter Rudegeair&lt;/span&gt;
                  &lt;/div&gt;

      &lt;/div&gt;
      
        &lt;time class=&quot;timestamp article__timestamp flexbox__flex--1&quot;&gt;
          Sept. 19, 2019 1:00 pm ET
        &lt;/time&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  

  &lt;div class=&quot;article-content &quot;&gt;

       &lt;p&gt;Stripe Inc. climbed closer to the top ranks of the highest-priced U.S. startups after a new fundraising round valued the financial-technology company at $35 billion.&lt;/p&gt; 




      &lt;div class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;Venture-capital firms Sequoia Capital, General Catalyst and Andreessen Horowitz were among the investors behind the $250 million investment, the company said Thursday. The $35 billion valuation, up about 50% from an early 2019 funding round, puts Stripe above Silicon Valley darlings Airbnb Inc. and Palantir Technologies Inc.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Stripe’s technology allows internet companies and online marketplaces to accept credit cards for their goods and services and pay out money to the people and firms that sell on their platforms. It processes hundreds of billions of dollars in payments annually for millions of users, including consumer apps and websites such as Airbnb and 






            &lt;a href=&quot;https://quotes.wsj.com/REAL&quot;&gt;The RealReal&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;company-name-type&quot;&gt; Inc.&lt;/span&gt;


       and makers of business software such as GitHub Inc. and 






            &lt;a href=&quot;https://quotes.wsj.com/TWLO&quot;&gt;Twilio&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;company-name-type&quot;&gt; Inc.&lt;/span&gt;


      &lt;/p&gt; 






       




       &lt;p&gt;Investors view payments companies like Stripe as a way to get exposure to a basket of fast-growing public and private tech companies, since Stripe’s revenues are tied to its customers’ growth. The market for payments services is also expanding as more commerce moves away from physical stores and toward digital storefronts.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;“Stripe is more than ever a bet on the internet as an economic engine,” said Will Gaybrick, Stripe’s chief product officer.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2010, Stripe is middle-aged by Silicon Valley standards, but Mr. Gaybrick and Stripe president 




      John Collison




       said it had no plans to go public. It has raised around $1.2 billion over the past nine years.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Still, a raft of younger startups, such as Checkout.com, are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/the-swiss-surfer-behind-2-billion-payments-startup-checkout-com-11558776601?mod=article_inline&quot; class=&quot;icon none&quot;&gt;raising hundreds of millions of dollars&lt;/a&gt; in venture capital to challenge Stripe. Traditional payments processors, meanwhile, are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/fidelity-national-information-services-to-buy-worldpay-for-35-billion-11552895935?mod=article_inline&quot; class=&quot;icon none&quot;&gt;selling themselves to larger financial institutions&lt;/a&gt; in a bid to bulk up their digital-payments offerings.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Some of those companies have had success picking off business from Stripe’s customers. Dutch payments company 






            &lt;a href=&quot;https://quotes.wsj.com/NL/XAMS/ADYEN&quot;&gt;Adyen&lt;/a&gt;
            


       NV said over the summer that it started processing some payments for delivery company Postmates Inc., a longtime Stripe user. 






            &lt;a href=&quot;https://quotes.wsj.com/LYFT&quot;&gt;Lyft&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;company-name-type&quot;&gt; Inc.,&lt;/span&gt;


       one of Stripe’s largest customers, disclosed in its IPO prospectus that it added an additional payments processor last year and may create its own payment products in an attempt to lower its costs.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Mr. Gaybrick said that the vast majority of users rely on Stripe to handle all of their payments, and it is adding more countries to its network to help businesses grow internationally. At a conference last week, Stripe announced it was available in eight new European markets.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Stripe also is using the data it collects from the payments it processes to build out its financial services. Earlier this month, it announced it would start issuing corporate credit cards with cash-back rewards and lending money to businesses that process payments through Stripe, using signals such as the percentage of sales coming from repeat customers to determine creditworthiness.&lt;/p&gt; 






      &lt;div data-layout=&quot;header&amp;#10;              &quot; data-layout-mobile=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&amp;#10;        media-object&amp;#10;        type-InsetMediaVideo&amp;#10;          header&amp;#10;    scope-web|mobileapps&amp;#10;  article__inset&amp;#10;        article__inset--type-InsetMediaVideo&amp;#10;          article__inset--header&amp;#10;  &quot;&gt;
      
      
      
          &lt;figure class=&quot;media-object-video article__inset__video media-object-video--standard&quot;&gt;
  
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;wsj-article-caption article__inset__video__caption&quot;&gt;
          From Uber to Lyft to Airbnb, it's the year of the tech initial public offering. Jonathan DeYoe, a Bay Area financial adviser to some of the new IPO millionaires, explains how many of his clients acquired so much stock and what he suggests they do with their new riches. Illustration: Timothy Wong for The Wall Street Journal.
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt; 




       &lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Write to &lt;/strong&gt;Peter Rudegeair at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:Peter.Rudegeair@wsj.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;icon &quot;&gt;Peter.Rudegeair@wsj.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;






      &lt;/div&gt;



  
  &lt;p&gt;Copyright ©2019 Dow Jones &amp;amp; Company, Inc. All Rights Reserved. 87990cbe856818d5eddac44c7b1cdeb8&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;/div&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 17:08:16 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tempsy</dc:creator>
<og:title>WSJ News Exclusive | Fintech Company Stripe Joins Silicon Valley Elite With $35 Billion Valuation</og:title>
<og:description>Stripe’s latest funding round values the company at $35 billion, putting the financial technology firm above Airbnb and Palantir.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.wsj.com/articles/fintech-company-stripe-joins-silicon-valley-elite-with-35-billion-valuation-11568912443</og:url>
<og:image>https://images.wsj.net/im-108500/social</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.wsj.com/articles/fintech-company-stripe-joins-silicon-valley-elite-with-35-billion-valuation-11568912443?mod=rsswn</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Amazon orders 100K electric delivery trucks from Rivian</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/19/amazon-orders-100k-electric-delivery-trucks-from-rivian-as-part-of-going-carbon-neutral-by-2040/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/19/amazon-orders-100k-electric-delivery-trucks-from-rivian-as-part-of-going-carbon-neutral-by-2040/</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/amazon&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;amazon&quot;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; will be stepping up its efforts to reduce its climate impact, CEO &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/person/jeff-bezos&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;person&quot; data-entity=&quot;jeff-bezos&quot;&gt;Jeff Bezos&lt;/a&gt; announced on Thursday. The company will be ordering 100,000 electric delivery trucks from Michigan’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/tag/rivian/&quot;&gt;Rivian&lt;/a&gt; as part of this commitment, Bezos said. The commerce giant will seek to meet its goal of becoming carbon-neutral by 2040 — 10 years earlier than is outlined by the United Nations Paris Agreement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bezos said at a National Press Club event in Washington where he made the announcement that the updated timeline is due to the increase in climate change, which has been more aggressive than even some of the more serious predictions had anticipated five years ago when the Paris agreement was reached.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon’s overarching efforts to make the company carbon-neutral are bundled under a plan the company is calling the “Climate Pledge,” which will be open to other companies as well. In addition to efforts like the &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/rivian-automotive&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;rivian-automotive&quot;&gt;Rivian&lt;/a&gt; order for emission-free delivery vehicles, Amazon also will be seeking to reduce its footprint through other means, including solar energy and carbon offsets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/rivian-automotive&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;rivian-automotive&quot;&gt;Rivian&lt;/a&gt; noted that this was the largest order to date of any electric delivery vehicles, and that they’d begin actually deploying for &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/15/amazon-leads-700m-round-in-electric-automaker-rivian/&quot;&gt;Amazon starting in 2021&lt;/a&gt;. Amazon led &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/15/amazon-leads-700m-round-in-electric-automaker-rivian/&quot;&gt;a $700 million investment round in Rivian&lt;/a&gt; in February, and the company announced a &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/10/rivian-lands-350-million-investment-from-cox-automotive/&quot;&gt;further $350 million from auto industry giant Cox Automotive&lt;/a&gt; earlier this month. Automaker Ford revealed a &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2019/04/24/ford-invests-500m-in-rivian-and-intends-to-build-a-vehicle-on-rivians-ev-platform/&quot;&gt;$500 million investment in Rivian in April&lt;/a&gt;, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rivian also has plans to build and ship consumer vehicles, including the all-electric pickup truck and SUV it revealed late last year, which it aims to begin delivering to customers in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 15:59:14 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>prostoalex</dc:creator>
<og:title>Amazon orders 100K electric delivery trucks from Rivian as part of going carbon-neutral by 2040 – TechCrunch</og:title>
<og:description>Amazon will be stepping up its efforts to reduce its climate impact, CEO Jeff Bezos announced on Thursday. The company will be ordering 100,000 electric delivery trucks from Michigan’s Rivian as part of this commitment, Bezos said. The commerce giant will seek to meet its goal of becoming car…</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/EE1dQ9YXUAA8Slg.jpeg?w=764</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2019/09/19/amazon-orders-100k-electric-delivery-trucks-from-rivian-as-part-of-going-carbon-neutral-by-2040/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/19/amazon-orders-100k-electric-delivery-trucks-from-rivian-as-part-of-going-carbon-neutral-by-2040/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Six U.S. Cities Make the List of Most Surveilled Places in the World</title>
<link>https://www.routefifty.com/public-safety/2019/09/six-us-cities-make-list-most-surveilled-places-world/159983/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.routefifty.com/public-safety/2019/09/six-us-cities-make-list-most-surveilled-places-world/159983/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Conversations about privacy concerns in recent years have often focused on the online space, given high profile &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.creditcards.com/credit-card-news/equifax-consumer-trust-after-breach.php&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;data breaches&lt;/a&gt; and repeated revelations of tech companies’  &lt;a href=&quot;http://usatoday.com/story/money/2018/11/09/americans-more-concerned-data-privacy-than-healthcare-study-says/1904796002/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;misuse of personal information&lt;/a&gt;. But the private sector isn’t alone in surveilling people, and invasions of privacy aren’t just threats online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Offline surveillance by the government has grown exponentially in the past few years. One estimate found that the number of security cameras in the U.S. &lt;a href=&quot;https://technology.ihs.com/583114/north-american-security-camera-installed-base-to-reach-62-million-in-2016&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;grew from&lt;/a&gt; 33 million in 2012 to 62 million in 2016. Now, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.comparitech.com/vpn-privacy/the-worlds-most-surveilled-cities/?fbclid=IwAR2885rUmMnY5gA_rDE6j8mtSYFURYpt6eDvkewoY8curg9GqYV7JPyQaN4&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;new report&lt;/a&gt; from Comparitech, a technology research firm, takes a count of the number of closed-circuit television cameras owned by both government and private sources in cities around the world and compares that with the city’s population to find the density of cameras. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Atlanta was the only place in the U.S. to crack the top ten, with 15.56 cameras per thousand residents. That may seem low compared to cities higher on the list, most of which are in China and have 39 to 168 cameras per thousand residents, but Atlanta’s rate is high by U.S. standards. The five other municipalities that made the list of the top 50 most surveilled cities in the world included Chicago, Washington D.C., San Francisco, San Diego, and Boston.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chicago has about 13 cameras per thousand residents, and D.C. has 5.6. The other three cities have three or less cameras per thousand residents. Chicago had the highest number of individual cameras amongst U.S. cities, at 35,000. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kenneth Johnson, police commander of the Englewood district in Chicago, said that residents shouldn’t be concerned about privacy because the cameras are out in the open in public places. “This isn’t a secret. This isn’t an Orwellian ‘Big Brother,’” he told the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/05/26/us/chicago-police-surveillance.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Police departments use the cameras in their cities in different ways. San Diego police don’t constantly monitor feeds, but instead use cameras in individual cases, saying they have &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sandiegouniontribune.com/news/watchdog/story/2019-09-14/san-diego-is-fifth-most-surveilled-city-in-america-study-says&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;utilized video&lt;/a&gt; to solve 164 crimes since August 2018. Atlanta’s police department, by contrast, has a Video Integration Center that monitors a network of cameras 24 hours a day, 7 days a week. Over 90% of those cameras aren’t actually owned by the city, but are integrated from a number of public and private sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Atlanta Sgt. John Chafee told &lt;em&gt;Route Fifty&lt;/em&gt; that cameras “play a vital role” in keeping the city safe, and that the police department plans to expand the number of cameras they are currently monitoring. “Access to these cameras multiplies the number of eyes we have on the street looking for criminal activity and assisting with situational awareness during large events and gatherings,” he said. “They allow us to identify criminal activity as it is occurring, prevent and deter criminal activity, and capture video evidence when a crime does occur to aid in criminal investigations and prosecutions.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Privacy rights groups, including the Anti Surveillance Coalition, have said that there isn’t enough public input when it comes to how police use cameras. &quot;I understand that there may be benefits to crime prevention, but the point is, we have rights and until we talk about privacy rights and our concerns, then we can't have the rest of the conversation,&quot; Genevieve Jones-Wright of the ASC told &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nbcsandiego.com/news/local/Surveillance-Cameras-San-Diego-Tracking-Facial-Recognition-Study-560497901.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;NBC San Diego&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether the rest of Americans actually care about living in a surveillance state is another matter. A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.routefifty.com/public-safety/2019/09/pew-law-enforcement-facial-recognition/159824/&quot;&gt;recent study&lt;/a&gt; by the Pew Research Center found that over half of people surveyed trust law enforcement to use facial recognition technology responsibly. That study found clear segmentations along demographic lines, though, as Democrats were less willing to accept facial recognition than Republicans, and black and Hispanic adults were less tolerant of its use by police than white adults. The results also showed a generational gap, with young adults who have grown up with technology finding surveillance more acceptable. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As security cameras evolve into a natural part of the urban landscape, some city leaders are passing legislation to regulate them, ensuring that law enforcement can’t use them with more  invasive technologies like facial recognition. In 2019, &lt;a href=&quot;https://thinkprogress.org/as-facial-recognition-software-stokes-privacy-fears-some-cities-are-imposing-bans-1851a548d63b/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;three cities&lt;/a&gt; banned government agencies from using facial recognition, and all three are known for their tech scenes: San Francisco was the first, followed by Somerville, Massachusetts, and later Oakland, California. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is also a coinciding push at the federal level to regulate the use of facial recognition by private companies. In &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.winston.com/en/privacy-law-corner/us-congress-moves-to-regulate-facial-recognition-technology.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a bill&lt;/a&gt; introduced in the Senate this year, companies would be required to obtain affirmative consent from consumers before deploying the technology in their cameras, but federal, state, and local governments would be exempt, including all law enforcement agencies at those levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Already, local law enforcement has found partnerships to expand their surveillance networks beyond just CCTV cameras. More than 400 cities have &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.banfacialrecognition.com/map/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;partnerships with Amazon&lt;/a&gt; to use Ring Doorbell footage to aid in solving crimes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But law enforcement in some cities may soon find it harder to make new partnerships or invest in further surveillance. The ACLU is leading a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aclu.org/issues/privacy-technology/surveillance-technologies/community-control-over-police-surveillance&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;legislative push&lt;/a&gt; at the local level called Community Control Over Police Surveillance, an effort to ensure that city councils have regulatory power over surveillance technologies. The group says this is important because in most cities, the public and elected officials are unaware when police departments start using surveillance tech. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 14:58:17 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>emrosecoleman</dc:creator>
<og:description>A new report found that CCTV surveillance is increasing in certain areas of the U.S., with one city government watching its citizens from 35,000 cameras.</og:description>
<og:title>Six U.S. Cities Make the List of Most Surveilled Places in the World</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.routefifty.com/public-safety/2019/09/six-us-cities-make-list-most-surveilled-places-world/159983/</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn.routefifty.com/media/img/upload/2019/09/18/shutterstock_1453432997/open-graph.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.routefifty.com/public-safety/2019/09/six-us-cities-make-list-most-surveilled-places-world/159983/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Pragmatic Programmer, 20th Anniversary Edition</title>
<link>https://pragprog.com/book/tpp20/the-pragmatic-programmer-20th-anniversary-edition</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://pragprog.com/book/tpp20/the-pragmatic-programmer-20th-anniversary-edition</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Our site has been optimized for use with newer browsers. We also require that your browser has JavaScript enabled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It looks as if your browser has JavaScript disabled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://enable-javascript.com&quot;&gt;This site&lt;/a&gt; has information about enabling JavaScript, if that's something you want to do.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 14:46:05 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>duck</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://pragprog.com/no_js</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Solar and Wind Power So Cheap They’re Outgrowing Subsidies</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2019-09-19/solar-and-wind-power-so-cheap-they-re-outgrowing-subsidies</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2019-09-19/solar-and-wind-power-so-cheap-they-re-outgrowing-subsidies</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2019-09-19/solar-and-wind-power-so-cheap-they-re-outgrowing-subsidies&quot;&gt;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2019-09-19/solar-and-wind-power-so-cheap-they-re-outgrowing-subsidies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=21015964&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=21015964&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 498&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 404&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 13:31:43 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ph0rque</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/tosv2.html?vid=&amp;uuid=4d1f6b60-db42-11e9-ae12-931f775f4f98&amp;url=L25ld3MvZmVhdHVyZXMvMjAxOS0wOS0xOS9zb2xhci1hbmQtd2luZC1wb3dlci1zby1jaGVhcC10aGV5LXJlLW91dGdyb3dpbmctc3Vic2lkaWVz</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Closing the gap: cross-language LTO between Rust and C/C++</title>
<link>http://blog.llvm.org/2019/09/closing-gap-cross-language-lto-between.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://blog.llvm.org/2019/09/closing-gap-cross-language-lto-between.html</guid>
<description>Link time optimization (LTO) is LLVM's way of implementing whole-program optimization. &lt;em&gt;Cross-language&lt;/em&gt; LTO is a new feature in the Rust compiler that enables LLVM's link time optimization to be performed across a mixed C/C++/Rust codebase. It is also a feature that beautifully combines two respective strengths of the Rust programming language and the LLVM compiler platform:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Rust, with its lack of a language runtime and its low-level reach, has an almost unique ability to seamlessly integrate with an existing C/C++ codebase, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LLVM, as a language agnostic foundation, provides a common ground where the source language a particular piece of code was written in does not matter anymore.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
So, what does cross-language LTO do? There are two answers to that:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;From a technical perspective it allows for codebases to be optimized without regard for implementation language boundaries, making it possible for important optimizations, such as function inlining, to be performed across individual compilation units even if, for example, one of the compilation units is written in Rust while the other is written in C++.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From a psychological perspective, which arguably is just as important, it helps to alleviate the nagging feeling of inefficiency that many performance conscious developers might have when working on a piece of software that jumps back and forth a lot between functions implemented in different source languages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
Because Firefox is a large, performance sensitive codebase with substantial parts written in Rust, cross-language LTO has been a long-time favorite wish list item among Firefox developers. As a consequence, we at Mozilla's Low Level Tools team took it upon ourselves to implement it in the Rust compiler.&lt;p&gt;To explain how cross-language LTO works it is useful to take a step back and review how traditional compilation and &quot;regular&quot; link time optimization work in the LLVM world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Background - A bird's eye view of the LLVM compilation pipeline&lt;/h3&gt;
Clang and the Rust compiler both follow a similar compilation workflow which, to some degree, is prescribed by LLVM:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;The compiler front-end generates an LLVM bitcode module (&lt;code&gt;.bc&lt;/code&gt;) for each compilation unit. In C and C++ each source file will result in a single compilation unit. In Rust each crate is translated into at least one compilation unit.&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;
    .c --clang--&amp;gt; .bc

    .c --clang--&amp;gt; .bc


    .rs --+
          |
    .rs --+--rustc--&amp;gt; .bc
          |
    .rs --+

&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the next step, LLVM's optimization pipeline will optimize each LLVM module in isolation:
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;
    .c --clang--&amp;gt; .bc --LLVM--&amp;gt; .bc (opt)

    .c --clang--&amp;gt; .bc --LLVM--&amp;gt; .bc (opt)


    .rs --+
          |
    .rs --+--rustc--&amp;gt; .bc --LLVM--&amp;gt; .bc (opt)
          |
    .rs --+

&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LLVM then lowers each module into machine code so that we get one object file per module:
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;
    .c --clang--&amp;gt; .bc --LLVM--&amp;gt; .bc (opt) --LLVM--&amp;gt; .o

    .c --clang--&amp;gt; .bc --LLVM--&amp;gt; .bc (opt) --LLVM--&amp;gt; .o


    .rs --+
          |
    .rs --+--rustc--&amp;gt; .bc --LLVM--&amp;gt; .bc (opt) --LLVM--&amp;gt; .o
          |
    .rs --+

&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, the linker will take the set of object files and link them together into a binary:
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;
    .c --clang--&amp;gt; .bc --LLVM--&amp;gt; .bc (opt) --LLVM--&amp;gt; .o ------+
                                                             |
    .c --clang--&amp;gt; .bc --LLVM--&amp;gt; .bc (opt) --LLVM--&amp;gt; .o ------+
                                                             |
                                                             +--ld--&amp;gt; bin
    .rs --+                                                  |
          |                                                  |
    .rs --+--rustc--&amp;gt; .bc --LLVM--&amp;gt; .bc (opt) --LLVM--&amp;gt; .o --+
          |
    .rs --+

&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
This is the regular compilation workflow if no kind of LTO is involved. As you can see, each compilation unit is optimized in isolation. The optimizer does not know the definition of functions inside of other compilation units and thus cannot inline them or make other kinds of decisions based on what they actually do. To enable inlining and optimizations to happen across compilation unit boundaries, LLVM supports link time optimization.&lt;h3&gt;Link time optimization in LLVM&lt;/h3&gt;
The basic principle behind LTO is that some of LLVM's optimization passes are pushed back to the linking stage. Why the linking stage? Because that is the point in the pipeline where the entire program (i.e. the whole set of compilation units) is available at once and thus optimizations across compilation unit boundaries become possible. Performing LLVM work at the linking stage is facilitated via a &lt;a href=&quot;http://llvm.org/docs/GoldPlugin.html&quot;&gt;plugin&lt;/a&gt; to the linker.&lt;p&gt;Here is how LTO is concretely implemented:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;the compiler translates each compilation unit into LLVM bitcode (i.e. it skips lowering to machine code),&lt;br/&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the linker, via the LLVM linker plugin, knows how to read LLVM bitcode modules like regular object files, and&lt;br/&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the linker, again via the LLVM linker plugin, merges all bitcode modules it encounters and then runs LLVM optimization passes before doing the actual linking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
With these capabilities in place a new compilation workflow with LTO enabled for C++ code looks like this:&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;
    .c --clang--&amp;gt; .bc --LLVM--&amp;gt; .bc (opt) ------------------+ - - +
                                                            |     |
    .c --clang--&amp;gt; .bc --LLVM--&amp;gt; .bc (opt) ------------------+ - - +
                                                            |     |
                                                            +-ld+LLVM--&amp;gt; bin
    .rs --+                                                 |
          |                                                 |
    .rs --+--rustc--&amp;gt; .bc --LLVM--&amp;gt; .bc (opt) --LLVM--&amp;gt; .o -+
          |
    .rs --+

&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
As you can see our Rust code is still compiled to a regular object file. Therefore, the Rust code is opaque to the optimization taking place at link time. Yet, looking at the diagram it seems like that shouldn't be too hard to change, right?&lt;h3&gt;Cross-language link time optimization&lt;/h3&gt;
Implementing cross-language LTO is conceptually simple because the feature is built on the shoulders of giants. Since the Rust compiler uses LLVM all the important building blocks are readily available. The final diagram looks very much as you would expect, with &lt;code&gt;rustc&lt;/code&gt; emitting optimized LLVM bitcode and the LLVM linker plugin incorporating that into the LTO process with the rest of the modules:&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;
    .c --clang--&amp;gt; .bc --LLVM--&amp;gt; .bc (opt) ---------+
                                                   |
    .c --clang--&amp;gt; .bc --LLVM--&amp;gt; .bc (opt) ---------+
                                                   |
                                                   +-ld+LLVM--&amp;gt; bin
    .rs --+                                        |
          |                                        |
    .rs --+--rustc--&amp;gt; .bc --LLVM--&amp;gt; .bc (opt) -----+
          |
    .rs --+

&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
Nonetheless, achieving a production-ready implementation still turned out to be a significant time investment. After figuring out how everything fits together, the main challenge was to get the Rust compiler to produce LLVM bitcode that was compatible with both the bitcode that Clang produces and with what the linker plugin would accept. Some of the issues we ran into where:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The Rust compiler and Clang are both based on LLVM but they might be using different versions of LLVM. This was further complicated by the fact that Rust's LLVM version often does not match a specific LLVM release, but can be an arbitrary revision from LLVM's repository. We learned that all LLVM versions involved really have to be a close match in order for things to work out. The Rust compiler's documentation now offers a &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.rust-lang.org/rustc/linker-plugin-lto.html#toolchain-compatibility&quot;&gt;compatibility table&lt;/a&gt; for the various versions of Rust and Clang.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Rust compiler by default performs a special form of LTO, called &lt;a href=&quot;https://clang.llvm.org/docs/ThinLTO.html&quot;&gt;ThinLTO&lt;/a&gt;, on all compilation units of the same crate before passing them on to the linker. We quickly learned, however, that the LLVM linker plugin crashes with a segmentation fault when trying to perform another round of ThinLTO on a module that had already gone through the process. No problem, we thought and instructed the Rust compiler to disable its own ThinLTO pass when compiling for the cross-language case and indeed everything was fine -- until the segmentation faults mysteriously returned a few weeks later even though ThinLTO was still disabled.&lt;p&gt;We noticed that the problem only occurred in a specific, presumably innocent setting: again two passes of LTO needed to happen, this time the first was a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.llvm.org/docs/LinkTimeOptimization.html&quot;&gt;regular LTO&lt;/a&gt; pass within &lt;code&gt;rustc&lt;/code&gt; and the output of that would then be fed into ThinLTO within the linker plugin. This setup, although computationally expensive, was desirable because it produced faster code and allowed for better dead-code elimination on the Rust side. And in theory it should have worked just fine. Yet somehow &lt;code&gt;rustc&lt;/code&gt; produced symbol names that had apparently gone through ThinLTO's mangling even though we checked time and again that ThinLTO was disabled for Rust. We were beginning to seriously question our understanding of LLVM's inner workings as the problem persisted while we slowly ran out of ideas on how to debug this further.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can picture the proverbial lightbulb appearing over our heads when we figured out that Rust's pre-compiled standard library would still have ThinLTO enabled, no matter the compiler settings we were using for our tests. The standard library, including its LLVM bitcode representation, is compiled as part of Rust's binary distribution so it is always compiled with the settings from Rust's build servers. Our local full LTO pass within &lt;code&gt;rustc&lt;/code&gt; would then pull this troublesome bitcode into the output module which in turn would make the linker plugin crash again. Since then ThinLTO is &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/55264&quot;&gt;turned off&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;code&gt;libstd&lt;/code&gt; by default.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After the above fixes, we succeeded in compiling the entirety of Firefox with cross-language LTO enabled. Unfortunately, we discovered that no actual cross-language optimizations were happening. Both Clang and &lt;code&gt;rustc&lt;/code&gt; were producing LLVM bitcode and LLD produced functioning Firefox binaries, but when looking at the machine code, not even trivial functions were being inlined across language boundaries. After days of debugging (and unfortunately without being aware of &lt;a href=&quot;http://llvm.org/docs/Remarks.html&quot;&gt;LLVM's optimization remarks&lt;/a&gt; at the time) it turned out that Clang was emitting a &lt;code&gt;target-cpu&lt;/code&gt; attribute on all functions while &lt;code&gt;rustc&lt;/code&gt; didn't, which made LLVM reject inlining opportunities.&lt;p&gt;In order to prevent the feature from silently regressing for similar reasons in the future we put quite a bit of effort into extending the Rust compiler's testing framework and CI. It is now able to compile and run a compatible version of Clang and uses that to perform end-to-end tests of cross-language LTO, making sure that small functions will indeed get inlined across language boundaries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
This list could still go on for a while, with each additional target platform holding new surprises to be dealt with. We had to progress carefully by putting in regression tests at every step in order to keep the many moving parts in check. At this point, however, we feel confident in the underlying implementation, with Firefox providing a large, complex, multi-platform test case where things have been working well for several months now.&lt;h3&gt;Using cross-language LTO: a minimal example&lt;/h3&gt;
The exact build tool invocations differ depending on whether it is &lt;code&gt;rustc&lt;/code&gt; or Clang performing the final linking step, and whether Rust code is compiled via Cargo or via &lt;code&gt;rustc&lt;/code&gt; directly. Rust's &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.rust-lang.org/rustc/linker-plugin-lto.html&quot;&gt;compiler documentation&lt;/a&gt; describes the various cases. The simplest of them, where &lt;code&gt;rustc&lt;/code&gt; directly produces a static library and Clang does the linking, looks as follows:&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;
    # Compile the Rust static library, called &quot;xyz&quot;
    rustc --crate-type=staticlib -O -C linker-plugin-lto -o libxyz.a lib.rs

    # Compile the C code with &quot;-flto&quot;
    clang -flto -c -O2 main.c

    # Link everything
    clang -flto -O2 main.o -L . -lxyz

&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
The &lt;code&gt;-C linker-plugin-lto&lt;/code&gt; option instructs the Rust compiler to emit LLVM bitcode which then can be used for both &quot;full&quot; and &quot;thin&quot; LTO. Getting things set up for the first time can be quite cumbersome because, as already mentioned, all compilers and the linker involved must be compatible versions. In theory, most major linkers will work; in practice LLD seems to be the most reliable one on Linux, with Gold in second place and the BFD linker needing to be at least version 2.32. On Windows and macOS the only linkers properly tested are LLD and &lt;code&gt;ld64&lt;/code&gt; respectively. For &lt;code&gt;ld64&lt;/code&gt; Firefox uses a patched version because the LLVM bitcode that &lt;code&gt;rustc&lt;/code&gt; produces likes to trigger a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/froydnj/ld64-aliases-bug&quot;&gt;pre-existing issue&lt;/a&gt; this linker has with ThinLTO.&lt;h3&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
Cross-language LTO has been enabled for Firefox release builds on Windows, macOS, and Linux for several months at this point and we at Mozilla's Low Level Tools team are pleased with how it turned out. While we still &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/issues/60059&quot;&gt;need to work&lt;/a&gt; on making the initial setup of the feature easier, it already enabled removing duplicated logic from Rust components in Firefox because now code can simply call into the equivalent C++ implementation and rely on those calls to be inlined. Having cross-language LTO in place and continuously tested will definitely lower the psychological bar for implementing new components in Rust, even if they are tightly integrated with existing C++ code.&lt;p&gt;Cross-language LTO is available in the Rust compiler since version 1.34 and works together with Clang 8. Feel free to give it a try and report any problems in the Rust &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/issues&quot;&gt;bug tracker&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Acknowledgments&lt;/h3&gt;
I'd like to thank my Low Level Tools team colleagues David Major, Eric Rahm, and Nathan Froyd for their invaluable help and encouragement, and I'd like to thank Alex Crichton for his tireless reviews on the Rust side.

</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 12:35:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pedrow</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://blog.llvm.org/2019/09/closing-gap-cross-language-lto-between.html</og:url>
<og:title>Closing the gap: cross-language LTO between Rust and C/C++</og:title>
<og:description>Link time optimization (LTO) is LLVM's way of implementing whole-program optimization. Cross-language LTO is a new feature in the Rust comp...</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://blog.llvm.org/2019/09/closing-gap-cross-language-lto-between.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>iPhone 11 Pro Camera Review</title>
<link>http://austinmann.com/trek/iphone-11-pro-review-china</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://austinmann.com/trek/iphone-11-pro-review-china</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Many of us iPhone photographers have watched as other phones like the Pixel and the Huawei P30 have passed us in low light. It feels so good to see the iPhone 11 Pro has caught up in low light performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;In the audience image above, notice the preservation of skin tone warmth and color, even in the super dim blue light being cast from the stage. I was really impressed by Night mode’s overall preservation of color — in some scenarios, the iPhone 11 Pro pulled out colors in low light scenes I couldn’t even see with my naked eye.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;I think I can say this is easily the most dramatic leap forward we’ve seen since the introduction of panorama mode on the iPhone 5 in 2012. It’s the first time in a long time I’ve looked at an image and said to myself “wow, I can’t believe I shot this with my phone.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;How Night Mode Works on iPhone 11 Pro&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt; (skip if you don’t care about how geeky things work)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;I’ve been caught off guard by the ability to handhold multi-second Night mode shots and maintain sharpness even while in a moving car on a bumpy road or shooting Huang Gaohui on a rocking boat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;If you are a pro familiar with shooting long exposures, you'll immediately realize something is fundamentally different about how the iPhone 11 Pro collects light in Night mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;From what I understand, the way Night mode actually works is the camera captures a bunch of short exposures and slightly longer exposures, checks them for sharpness, throws out the bad ones and blends the good ones. On a traditional dSLR/mirrorless camera, a 5 second exposure is one single, continuous recording of the light throughout the duration of the shutter so any movement (of subject or camera) is recorded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;But with iPhone 11 Pro the rules are different… it’s not capturing one single continuous frame but blending a whole bunch of shots with variable lengths (some shorter exposures to freeze motion and longer shots to expose the shadows.) This means the subject can actually move during your exposure but still remain sharp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;I’m sure some of you are wondering, “well this is cool for handholding but what if you want to do light trails?” The iPhone actually detects when it is on a tripod and changes exposure method so that light trails and movement can still be captured.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;This new way of thinking took me a good bit of testing/questioning to really figure out what is going on and it is yet another place where the computational side of photography really shines, leveraging powerful software — instead of a big lens with big glass — to capture more light.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 11:37:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dsego</dc:creator>
<og:title>iPhone 11 Pro Camera Review — Austin Mann</og:title>
<og:url>http://austinmann.com/trek/iphone-11-pro-review-china</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>iPhone 11 Pro Camera Review: China &amp;nbsp; Nĭ hăo (hello from China!) &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; I’m here as I continue on-going work photographing&amp;nbsp; The Bach Project w/ Yo-Yo Ma , a world tour where Yo-Yo is performing Bach in unconventional places around the globe. It’s been a privilege t</og:description>
<og:image>http://static1.squarespace.com/static/50730c37e4b03adec668905b/50b51624e4b060066a4a84a5/5d76bcd13fb3900c5de2239d/1568938904052/iPhone11pro-camera-nightmode.jpg?format=1500w</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://austinmann.com/trek/iphone-11-pro-review-china</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>