<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Canada to Scrap IBM Payroll Plan Gone Awry Costing $1B</title>
<link>http://www.itprotoday.com/hybrid-cloud/canada-scrap-ibm-payroll-plan-gone-awry-costing-c1-billion</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.itprotoday.com/hybrid-cloud/canada-scrap-ibm-payroll-plan-gone-awry-costing-c1-billion</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;(Bloomberg) --Canada plans to scrap a major IBM federal payroll plan that created chaos for thousands of government workers and will have cost the government almost C$1 billion ($780 million) by the time it’s over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Phoenix project was originally chosen by Prime Minister Justin Trudeau’s Conservative predecessors 10 years ago to centralize the government payroll.  International Business Machines Corp. won the contract to install and help run the system, which uses Oracle Corp. software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It went live in 2016, just months after Trudeau won office. From the beginning, it didn’t work like it was supposed to. Some people were paid too much, others not at all. Those issues snowballed with the deluge of requests to fix incorrect paychecks. The fear of not getting paid still hangs over the country’s more than 260,000 federal public servants. Some put off major financial decisions. Others declined promotions or retirement, fearing any change in their pay could cause more trouble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two years later, some employees are still having problems. The latest data showed a backlog of 384,000 cases linked to the program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IBM said it’s “fulfilling its obligations on the Phoenix contract, and the software is functioning as intended.” The company “continues to work in partnership with the government’s efforts to resolve the project’s issues, and remains committed to the project’s overall success,” it said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An Oracle representative declined to comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Debi Daviau, president of one of the main unions representing government workers, said the blame falls mostly on the senior government officials who ran the project and opened it even though there were glaring warning signs it wasn’t ready. But she also questions why IBM went ahead when it was clear there would be problems, and why the company benefits from a project that never worked as promised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“They should have known better,” Daviau said in an interview. When the company’s warnings that more testing was needed went unheeded, IBM didn’t put its foot down and hold up the project until it was ready, she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“IBM got into a contract with the government that was very beneficial to IBM, which meant that the contract -- despite non-delivery -- could continue to be extended and IBM could continue to come back to the pot for money,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Treasury Board President Scott Brison has said IBM has a responsibility to help the government fix the program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“IBM, as a sophisticated global company, needs to recognize that we as the government of Canada are not just an important client for IBM but there is reputational risk for IBM in not helping us fix this,” Brison said last June during an appearance at the Senate’s finance committee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fiasco illustrates how difficult it is to bring governments into the 21st century when it comes to technology, and the risks and limitations faced by companies like IBM, who get a large amount of their business from governments. IBM, based in Armonk, New York, doesn’t disclose how much of its revenue comes from government contracts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not the first time IBM has been embroiled in a payroll system disaster. The Australian state of Queensland scrapped a similar project after an initial contract went off the rails and ended up costing the government around A$1 billion ($772 million) to fix. A public inquiry mostly blamed government officials, but determined IBM shouldn’t have been chosen for the job. IBM disputed some of the inquiry’s findings in 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Canadian Finance Minister Bill Morneau said Wednesday that the previous government made mistakes in dismissing staff needed to implement Phoenix but that, “it’s not about seeking blame, it’s about trying to get it right.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Canada announced Tuesday it would start moving away from Phoenix and set aside money to find a new solution. The government will spend C$431 million to keep the program running in the near term, on top of C$460 million already spent to put Phoenix in place and fix the problems it generated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project was meant to save costs by firing 1,200 employees handling payroll at various departments around the country and replacing them with about 500 people in a centralized location using Phoenix to handle most of the government’s payroll needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An inquiry from Canada’s auditor general, a position similar to the U.S. Government Accountability Office, found many of the new employees were poorly trained and overworked. The software platform itself, a heavily modified version of Oracle’s PeopleSoft program, had yet to be encoded with many of the payroll complexities faced by a massive and diverse public service, such as unique shift rules for Coast Guard officers or prison guards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phoenix is a classic example of a government wanting to save money on an expensive new technology project by cutting the number of employees working on it, only to discover later that those people were essential to seeing it through, said Nigel Wallis, a vice president with research firm IDC Canada. Other companies considered the project and decided against bidding because it looked too complex, but IBM went ahead, Wallis said. “The promise of short term savings are often illusory,” Wallis said “That’s a real issue not just for government but also for a lot of large scale technology transformations. You need to approach them with a level of seriousness that I don’t think necessarily was done in this instance.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most major technology change-over projects -- for the private and public sectors -- either fail or face significant challenges, according to researcher Standish Group, which tracks thousands of projects every year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Wednesday, a New Democratic Party representative stood up in Parliament to ask Trudeau what he was doing for one of her constituents who was out C$40,000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We didn’t create this mess,” the prime minister said. “But we are going to fix it.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 17:57:12 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>RmDen</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Canada to Scrap IBM Payroll Plan Gone Awry Costing C$1 Billion</og:title>
<og:url>http://www.itprotoday.com/hybrid-cloud/canada-scrap-ibm-payroll-plan-gone-awry-costing-c1-billion</og:url>
<og:description>The Phoenix project was originally chosen by Prime Minister Justin Trudeau’s Conservative predecessors 10 years ago to centralize the government payroll. International Business Machines Corp. won the contract to install and help run the system, which uses Oracle Corp. software.</og:description>
<og:image>http://www.itprotoday.com/sites/itprotoday.com/files/sever-3100049_1920.jpg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.itprotoday.com/hybrid-cloud/canada-scrap-ibm-payroll-plan-gone-awry-costing-c1-billion</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Machine Learning Crash Course</title>
<link>https://developers.google.com/machine-learning/crash-course/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://developers.google.com/machine-learning/crash-course/</guid>
<description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-self-study-guide-for-aspiring-machine-learning-practitioners&quot;&gt;A self-study guide for aspiring machine learning practitioners&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Machine Learning Crash Course features a series of lessons with video lectures, real-world case studies, and hands-on practice exercises.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 16:39:50 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>matant</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://developers.google.com/machine-learning/crash-course/</og:url>
<og:title>Machine Learning Crash Course  |  Google Developers</og:title>
<og:description>Educational resources for machine learning</og:description>
<og:image>https://developers.google.com/machine-learning/crash-course/images/mlcc-hero.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://developers.google.com/machine-learning/crash-course/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ask HN: Who is hiring? (March 2018)</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16492994</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16492994</guid>
<description>&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.55737704918033&quot;&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=&quot;#FF6600&quot;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.9610894941634&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;fatitem&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.7496757457847&quot;&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing&quot; id=&quot;16492994&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;title&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16492994&quot; class=&quot;storylink&quot;&gt;Ask HN: Who is hiring? (March 2018)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.71428571428571&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;subtext&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;score&quot; id=&quot;score_16492994&quot;&gt;357 points&lt;/span&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/user?id=whoishiring&quot; class=&quot;hnuser&quot;&gt;whoishiring&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;age&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16492994&quot;&gt;7 hours ago&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span id=&quot;unv_16492994&quot;/&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/hide?id=16492994&amp;amp;goto=item%3Fid%3D16492994&quot;&gt;hide&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://hn.algolia.com/?query=Ask%20HN%3A%20Who%20is%20hiring%3F%20(March%202018)&amp;amp;sort=byDate&amp;amp;dateRange=all&amp;amp;type=story&amp;amp;storyText=false&amp;amp;prefix&amp;amp;page=0&quot; class=&quot;hnpast&quot;&gt;past&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=Ask%20HN%3A%20Who%20is%20hiring%3F%20(March%202018)&quot;&gt;web&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/fave?id=16492994&amp;amp;auth=7cd411e8bf8db2572933877a411f86b2d1d10a6f&quot;&gt;favorite&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16492994&quot;&gt;647 comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;Please lead with the location of the position and include the keywords REMOTE, INTERNS and/or VISA when the corresponding sort of candidate is welcome. When remote work is not an option, include ONSITE.
&lt;p&gt;Submitters: please only post if you personally are part of the hiring company—no recruiting firms or job boards. Only one post per company, please. If it isn't a household name, please explain what your company does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Readers: please only email submitters if you personally are interested in the job—no recruiters or sales calls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also use kristopolous' console script to search the thread: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=10313519.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.73972602739726&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ycombinator.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Applications are open for YC Summer 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;yclinks&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsguidelines.html&quot;&gt;Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsfaq.html&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Support&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/HackerNews/API&quot;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/security.html&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/lists&quot;&gt;Lists&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/bookmarklet.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Bookmarklet&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/legal/&quot;&gt;Legal&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Apply to YC&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Contact&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 16:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>whoishiring</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16492994</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>February 28th DDoS Incident Report</title>
<link>https://githubengineering.com/ddos-incident-report/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://githubengineering.com/ddos-incident-report/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;On Wednesday, February 28, 2018 GitHub.com was unavailable from 17:21 to 17:26 UTC and intermittently unavailable from 17:26 to 17:30 UTC due to a distributed denial-of-service (DDoS) attack. We understand how much you rely on GitHub and we know the availability of our service is of critical importance to our users. To note, at no point was the confidentiality or integrity of your data at risk. We are sorry for the impact of this incident and would like to describe the event, the efforts we’ve taken to drive availability, and how we aim to improve response and mitigation moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;background&quot;&gt;Background&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cloudflare described an amplification vector using memcached over UDP in their blog post this week, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.cloudflare.com/memcrashed-major-amplification-attacks-from-port-11211/&quot;&gt;“Memcrashed - Major amplification attacks from UDP port 11211”&lt;/a&gt;. The attack works by abusing memcached instances that are inadvertently accessible on the public internet with UDP support enabled. Spoofing of IP addresses allows memcached’s responses to be targeted against another address, like ones used to serve GitHub.com, and send more data toward the target than needs to be sent by the unspoofed source. The vulnerability via misconfiguration described in the post is somewhat unique amongst that class of attacks because the amplification factor is up to 51,000, meaning that for each byte sent by the attacker, up to 51KB is sent toward the target.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past year we have deployed additional transit to our facilities. We’ve more than doubled our transit capacity during that time, which has allowed us to withstand certain volumetric attacks without impact to users. We’re continuing to deploy additional transit capacity and &lt;a href=&quot;https://githubengineering.com/transit-and-peering-how-your-requests-reach-github/&quot;&gt;develop robust peering relationships across a diverse set of exchanges&lt;/a&gt;. Even still, attacks like this sometimes require the help of partners with larger transit networks to provide blocking and filtering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-incident&quot;&gt;The incident&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Between 17:21 and 17:30 UTC on February 28th we identified and mitigated a significant volumetric DDoS attack. The attack originated from over a thousand different autonomous systems (ASNs) across tens of thousands of unique endpoints. It was an amplification attack using the memcached-based approach described above that peaked at 1.35Tbps via 126.9 million packets per second.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At 17:21 UTC our network monitoring system detected an anomaly in the ratio of ingress to egress traffic and notified the on-call engineer and others in our chat system. This graph shows inbound versus outbound throughput over transit links:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/579876/36830510-bd9ea02e-1cd8-11e8-96c0-dc199a530164.png&quot; alt=&quot;more inbound than outbound traffic graph&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the increase in inbound transit bandwidth to over 100Gbps in one of our facilities, the decision was made to move traffic to Akamai, who could help provide additional edge network capacity. At 17:26 UTC the command was initiated via our ChatOps tooling to withdraw BGP announcements over transit providers and announce &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.peeringdb.com/net/5152&quot;&gt;AS36459&lt;/a&gt; exclusively over our links to Akamai. Routes reconverged in the next few minutes and access control lists mitigated the attack at their border. Monitoring of transit bandwidth levels and load balancer response codes indicated a full recovery at 17:30 UTC. At 17:34 UTC routes to internet exchanges were withdrawn as a follow-up to shift an additional 40Gbps away from our edge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/579876/36830539-e48f683a-1cd8-11e8-9ef7-ec7e923a0c7f.png&quot; alt=&quot;graph showing traffic movement off exchanges&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first portion of the attack peaked at 1.35Tbps and there was a second 400Gbps spike a little after 18:00 UTC. This graph provided by Akamai shows inbound traffic in bits per second that reached their edge:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/579876/36830593-2ae2cf98-1cd9-11e8-944d-dde6248ac0e5.png&quot; alt=&quot;traffic to akamai edge&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;next-steps&quot;&gt;Next steps&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making GitHub’s edge infrastructure more resilient to current and future conditions of the internet and less dependent upon human involvement requires better automated intervention. We’re investigating the use of our monitoring infrastructure to automate enabling DDoS mitigation providers and will continue to measure our response times to incidents like this with a goal of reducing mean time to recovery (MTTR).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re going to continue to expand our edge network and strive to identify and mitigate new attack vectors before they affect your workflow on GitHub.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We know how much you rely on GitHub for your projects and businesses to succeed. We will continue to analyze this and other events that impact our availability, build better detection systems, and streamline response.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 15:44:40 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jnewland</dc:creator>
<og:title>February 28th DDoS Incident Report</og:title>
<og:description>On Wednesday, February 28, 2018 GitHub.com was unavailable from 17:21 to 17:26 UTC and intermittently unavailable from 17:26 to 17:30 UTC due to a distributed denial-of-service (DDoS) attack. We understand how much you rely on GitHub and we know the availability of our service is of critical importance to our users. To note, at no point was the confidentiality or integrity of your data at risk. We are sorry for the impact of this incident and would like to describe the event, the efforts we’ve taken to drive availability, and how we aim to improve response and mitigation moving forward.</og:description>
<og:url>https://githubengineering.com/ddos-incident-report/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://githubengineering.com/ddos-incident-report/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How not to run a CA</title>
<link>http://blog.koehntopp.info/index.php/3075-how-not-to-run-a-ca/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://blog.koehntopp.info/index.php/3075-how-not-to-run-a-ca/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trustico.eu&quot;&gt;Trustico&lt;/a&gt; is an SSL reseller, which &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/geofft/status/968937746214596610&quot;&gt;just compromised&lt;/a&gt; 23.000 certificates they sold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TL;DR: Forget your EV or other certs. Just run “Let’s Encrypt”. It gets you a cert, it’s fresh, and it does not make any difference whatsoever. At least not any you or anyone else can check for, or cares for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20180301013921/https://www.trustico.com/news/2018/symantec-revocation/certificate-replacement.php&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-3080 size-medium&quot; src=&quot;http://blog.koehntopp.info/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/trustico-ad-300x151.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;151&quot; srcset=&quot;http://blog.koehntopp.info/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/trustico-ad-300x151.png 300w, http://blog.koehntopp.info/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/trustico-ad.png 577w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Actual Trustico ad from their website (Screenshot 01-Mar-2018)
&lt;p&gt;Here is how:&lt;span id=&quot;more-3075&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chrome is going to distrust the Symantec root certificate soon, because they failed at running a Certificate Authority properly, repeatedly. Certificates by a reseller that are being rooted at Symantec will become invalid, no matter what their runtime in the Cert is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trustico wanted to move their customers from Symantec to Comodo, another company that failed at running a Certificate Authority properly, repeatedly, but which is not distrusted by Chrome, yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They asked Digicert, who bought the business of Symantec, to revoke (“cancel”) the certs they sold to their customers, just because they say so. That, said Digicert, is not possible, because the conditions for revoking a certificate have not been met, and if you are trying to revoke a certificate just because someone said so you are not running a Certificate Authority properly and they would like stopping to do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently Digicert also gave examples of proper causes for certificate revokation, and the one prime cause for revoking a cert is when the private key for a cert (which is supposed to be a secret only known to the proper owner of a cert, which is neither Digicert nor Trustico) being made known to people who have no business knowing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the CEO of Trustico, &lt;a href=&quot;https://uk.linkedin.com/in/zanelucas&quot;&gt;Zane Lucas&lt;/a&gt;, mailed the private keys of 23000 Trustico customers to Digicert, effectively invalidating them and at the same time proving that Trustico has knowledge of all their customers private keys, keeping copies of them, which proves that they never knew how to run a Certficate Authority business in the first place, and compromising all their 23000 customers security retroactively, and also ending their own presence in the security space forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So Digicert needed help to do a mass cert revocation, and also informed the customers of Trustico of the situation, directly. Which angered the CEO of Trustico, because it made their absolute and limitless incompetence public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.trustico.com/news/2018/symantec-revocation/certificate-replacement.php&quot;&gt;Trustico Statement&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.digicert.com/blog/digicert-statement-trustico-certificate-revocation/&quot;&gt;Digicert Statement&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://groups.google.com/forum/m/#!topic/mozilla.dev.security.policy/wxX4Yv0E3Mk&quot;&gt;Mozilla Mailing List Thread&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ceo.ca/@newswire/comodo-and-trustico-team-up-in-strategic-worldwide&quot;&gt;Earlier statement&lt;/a&gt; (Mid 2017) of Comodo and Trustico Partnership, which may need review under the current situation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/sysadmin/comments/80uaq3/digicert_certificates_being_revoked/&quot;&gt;Reddit Thread&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.itwire.com/security/81931-trustico-revokes-ssl-certificates-due-to-stored-private-keys.html&quot;&gt;IT Wire article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cyberscoop.com/trustico-digicert-ssl-certificates-revoked/&quot;&gt;Cyberscoop article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 14:35:02 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>stablemap</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://blog.koehntopp.info/index.php/3075-how-not-to-run-a-ca/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Long Term Depression Permanently Changes the Brain</title>
<link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2018-02-years-depression-brain.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://medicalxpress.com/news/2018-02-years-depression-brain.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;first-block&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is clinical depression always the same illness, or does it change over time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;New brain imaging research from the Centre for Addiction and Mental Health (CAMH) shows that the brain alters after years of &lt;a href=&quot;https://medicalxpress.com/tags/persistent+depression/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot; class=&quot;textTag&quot;&gt;persistent depression&lt;/a&gt;, suggesting the need to change how we think about depression as it progresses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study, led by senior author Dr. Jeff Meyer of CAMH's Campbell Family Mental Health Research Institute, is published in &lt;em&gt;The Lancet Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research shows that people with longer periods of untreated depression, lasting more than a decade, had significantly more brain &lt;a href=&quot;https://medicalxpress.com/tags/inflammation/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot; class=&quot;textTag&quot;&gt;inflammation&lt;/a&gt; compared to those who had less than 10 years of untreated depression. In an earlier study, Dr. Meyer's team discovered the first definitive evidence of inflammation in the brain in &lt;a href=&quot;https://medicalxpress.com/tags/clinical+depression/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot; class=&quot;textTag&quot;&gt;clinical depression&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study provides the first biological evidence for large brain changes in long-lasting depression, suggesting that it is a different stage of illness that needs different therapeutics - the same perspective taken for early and later stages of Alzheimer's disease, he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Greater inflammation in the brain is a common response with degenerative brain diseases as they progress, such as with Alzheimer's disease and Parkinson´s disease,&quot; says Dr. Meyer, who also holds Canada Research Chair in the Neurochemistry of Major Depression. While depression is not considered a degenerative brain disease, the change in inflammation shows that, for those in whom depression persists, it may be progressive and not a static condition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet currently, says Dr. Meyer, regardless of how long a person has been ill, major depressive disorder is mainly treated with the same approach. Some people may have a couple of episodes of depression over a few years. Others may have persistent episodes over a decade with worsening symptoms, and increasing difficulty going to work or carrying out routine activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Treatment options for this later stage of illness, such as medications targeting inflammation, are being investigated by Dr. Meyer and others. This includes re-purposing current medications designed for inflammation in other illnesses to be used in &lt;a href=&quot;https://medicalxpress.com/tags/major+depressive+disorder/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot; class=&quot;textTag&quot;&gt;major depressive disorder&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the study, &lt;a href=&quot;https://medicalxpress.com/tags/brain+inflammation/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot; class=&quot;textTag&quot;&gt;brain inflammation&lt;/a&gt; was measured using a type of brain imaging called positron emission tomography (PET). The brain's immune cells, known as microglia, are involved in the brain's normal inflammatory response to trauma or injury, but too much inflammation is associated with other degenerative illnesses as well as depression. When microglia are activated, they make more translocator protein (TSPO), a marker of inflammation that can be seen using PET imaging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study involved 25 people with more than 10 years of depression, 25 with less than 10 years of illness, and 30 people with no depression as a comparison group. TSPO levels were about 30 per cent higher in different &lt;a href=&quot;https://medicalxpress.com/tags/brain/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot; class=&quot;textTag&quot;&gt;brain&lt;/a&gt; regions among those with long-lasting untreated depression, compared to those with shorter periods of untreated depression. The group with long-term depression also had higher TSPO levels than those with no depression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Meyer also notes that in treatment studies, patients with serious, longstanding &lt;a href=&quot;https://medicalxpress.com/tags/depression/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot; class=&quot;textTag&quot;&gt;depression&lt;/a&gt; tend to be excluded, so there is a lack of evidence of how to treat this stage of &lt;a href=&quot;https://medicalxpress.com/tags/illness/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot; class=&quot;textTag&quot;&gt;illness&lt;/a&gt;, which needs to be addressed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;news-relevant&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/WebPage&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medicalxpress.com/news/2018-02-years-depression-brain.html#&quot; id=&quot;inl-rel-href&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;toolsicon ic-rel&quot; src=&quot;https://b98584f181.site.internapcdn.net/tmpl/v5/img/1x1.gif&quot; width=&quot;14&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Explore further:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a itemprop=&quot;relatedLink&quot; href=&quot;https://medicalxpress.com/news/2015-01-biological-evidence-reveals-link-brain.html&quot;&gt;New biological evidence reveals link between brain inflammation and major depression&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More information:&lt;/strong&gt; Elaine Setiawan et al, Association of translocator protein total distribution volume with duration of untreated major depressive disorder: a cross-sectional study, &lt;em&gt;The Lancet Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt; (2018). &lt;a data-doi=&quot;1&quot; href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S2215-0366(18)30048-8&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;DOI: 10.1016/S2215-0366(18)30048-8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;footer class=&quot;post-floor clearfix&quot; readability=&quot;7.9268292682927&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post-copyright&quot; readability=&quot;8.156862745098&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Provided by:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a rel=&quot;news&quot; class=&quot;textTag&quot; href=&quot;https://medicalxpress.com/partners/centre-for-addiction-and-mental-health/&quot;&gt;Centre for Addiction and Mental Health&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;post-rating&quot; id=&quot;rank&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;flip-box&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;flip&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;shares&quot;&gt;209&lt;/span&gt; shares &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/footer&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 13:56:05 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>thg</dc:creator>
<og:title>Over years, depression changes the brain, new study shows</og:title>
<og:description>Is clinical depression always the same illness, or does it change over time?</og:description>
<og:image>https://b98584f181.site.internapcdn.net/tmpl/v5/img/medx308px.png</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2018-02-years-depression-brain.html</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2018-02-years-depression-brain.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>23,000 HTTPS certificates axed after CEO e-mails private keys</title>
<link>https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2018/03/23000-https-certificates-axed-after-ceo-e-mails-private-keys/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2018/03/23000-https-certificates-axed-after-ceo-e-mails-private-keys/</guid>
<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/broken-key-800x600.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;aside id=&quot;social-left&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;76 posters participating&quot; class=&quot;comment-count icon-comment-bubble-down&quot; href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2018/03/23000-https-certificates-axed-after-ceo-e-mails-private-keys/?comments=1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;comment-count-before&quot;&gt;reader comments&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;comment-count-number&quot;&gt;111&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;share-links&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Share this story&lt;/span&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;A major dust-up on an Internet discussion forum is touching off troubling questions about the security of some browser-trusted HTTPS certificates when it revealed the CEO of a certificate reseller emailed a partner the sensitive private keys for 23,000 TLS certificates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;pullbox sidebar story-sidebar right&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;
The email was sent on Tuesday by the CEO of Trustico, a UK-based reseller of TLS certificates issued by the browser-trusted certificate authorities Comodo and, until recently, Symantec. It was sent to Jeremy Rowley, an executive vice president at DigiCert, a certificate authority that acquired Symantec's certificate issuance business after Symantec was &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2017/03/google-takes-symantec-to-the-woodshed-for-mis-issuing-30000-https-certs/&quot;&gt;caught flouting binding industry rules&lt;/a&gt;, prompting Google to distrust Symantec certificates in its Chrome browser. In communications earlier this month, Trustico notified DigiCert that 50,000 Symantec-issued certificates Trustico had resold should be mass revoked because of security concerns.
&lt;h2&gt;Shockingly cavalier&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Rowley asked for proof the certificates were compromised, the Trustico CEO emailed the private keys of 23,000 certificates, according to an &lt;a href=&quot;https://groups.google.com/forum/#!topic/mozilla.dev.security.policy/wxX4Yv0E3Mk&quot;&gt;account posted to a Mozilla security policy forum&lt;/a&gt;. The report produced a collective gasp among many security practitioners who said it demonstrated a shockingly cavalier treatment of the digital certificates that form one of the most basic foundations of website security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generally speaking, private keys for TLS certificates should never be archived by resellers, and, even in the rare cases where such storage is permissible, they should be tightly safeguarded. A CEO being able to attach the keys for 23,000 certificates to an email raises troubling concerns that those types of best practices weren't followed. (There's no indication the email was encrypted, either, although neither Trustico nor DigiCert provided that detail when responding to questions.) Other critics contend Trustico emailed the keys in an attempt to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/geofft/status/968937773691539458&quot;&gt;force customers with Symantec-issued certificates to move to Comodo-issued certificates&lt;/a&gt;. Although DigiCert took over Symantec's certificate issuance business, it doesn't count Trustico as a reseller.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.trustico.com/news/2018/symantec-revocation/certificate-replacement.php&quot;&gt;statement&lt;/a&gt;, Trustico officials said the keys were recovered from &quot;cold storage,&quot; a term that typically refers to offline storage systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Trustico allows customers to generate a Certificate Signing Request and Private Key during the ordering process,&quot; the statement read. &quot;These Private Keys are stored in cold storage, for the purpose of revocation.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The discussion also raises new questions about Symantec's adherence to industry-binding rules during the time it was a browser-trusted certificate authority that allowed Trustico to resell its certificates. Under the &lt;a href=&quot;https://cabforum.org/wp-content/uploads/CA-Browser-Forum-BR-1.5.4.pdf&quot;&gt;Baseline Requirements&lt;/a&gt; for the Certificate Authority Browser Forum, resellers aren't permitted to archive certificate private keys. The email raises the specter Trustico had been doing just that when it offered to accept certificate-signing requests on its website. As the holder of the root certificate used to sign the TLS certificates Trustico was reselling, Symantec was ultimately responsible for ensuring this requirement was being followed, although in fairness, there was probably no way for Symantec to detect a violation. Trustico officials further called Symantec's security into question on Wednesday when they voiced serious concerns over Symantec's handling of an account Trustico used to resell the certificates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;During our many discussions over the past week we put it to you that we believe Symantec to have operated our account in a manner whereby it had been compromised,&quot; the Trustico officials wrote. They continued: &quot;We believe the orders placed via our Symantec account were at risk and were poorly managed. We have been questioning Symantec without response as to concerning items for about a year. Symantec simply ignored our concerns and appeared to bury them under the next issue that arose.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Symantec officials didn't respond to an email seeking comment for this post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wednesday's flap comes after Google and Mozilla have spent years trying to better secure the security of certificates their browsers trust. DigiCert's transparency and adherence to the Baseline Requirements demonstrates that many certificate authorities and resellers are acting in good faith. Unfortunately, the way the Internet's TLS certificate issuance process works, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.co.uk/2011/08/30/fraudulent_google_cert_update/&quot;&gt;single point of failure is all it takes to create compromises that endanger the entire system&lt;/a&gt;. Readers can expect Google and Mozilla to spend considerable time and resources in the coming weeks unraveling the breakdown that came to light Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;pullbox sidebar story-sidebar right&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; Several hours after this post went live, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2018/03/trustico-website-goes-dark-after-someone-drops-critical-flaw-on-twitter/&quot;&gt;Trustico's website went offline after a Web security expert posted a critical vulnerability on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. The flaw, in a trustico.com website feature that allowed customers to confirm certificates were properly installed on their sites, appeared to allow attackers to run malicious code on Trustico servers with unfettered &quot;root&quot; privileges.</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 13:52:06 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>artsandsci</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2018/03/23000-https-certificates-axed-after-ceo-e-mails-private-keys/</og:url>
<og:title>23,000 HTTPS certificates axed after CEO emails private keys</og:title>
<og:image>https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/broken-key-760x380.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Flap that goes public renews troubling questions about issuance of certificates.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2018/03/23000-https-certificates-axed-after-ceo-e-mails-private-keys/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: Graphite – A decentralized and encrypted Google Docs alternative</title>
<link>https://graphitedocs.com</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://graphitedocs.com</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://graphitedocs.com&quot;&gt;https://graphitedocs.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16490595&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16490595&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Points: 283&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 129&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 09:07:30 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jhunter1016</dc:creator>
<og:title>Graphite</og:title>
<og:image>https://image.ibb.co/hde71b/AppIcon.png</og:image>
<og:url>http://app.graphitedocs.com</og:url>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:description>Graphite allows you to create, communicate, and share without giving up your privacy.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.graphitedocs.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Age of Empires Definitive Edition&amp;#039;s pathing and movement</title>
<link>https://richg42.blogspot.com/2018/02/on-age-des-pathingmovement.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://richg42.blogspot.com/2018/02/on-age-des-pathingmovement.html</guid>
<description>Typical Age DE forum post:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;UserQuote&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;QuoteText&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;The pathfinding in the game is terrible.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;First off, Age of Empires Definitive Edition is a &lt;span&gt;remaster&lt;/span&gt; of Age of Empires. It's not a rewrite, it's not a new engine, and that's what we've been saying for almost a year. Age of Empires 1's path finding was &lt;span&gt;really&lt;/span&gt; bad, as most reviews point out:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;This is the code we started with in DE. Not Age 2, not new code, but the original code which had a ton of flaws and quirks we had to learn about the hard way. This code was almost a quarter of a century old, and it showed. The original movement/pathing code was very weak to say the least. Yet entire complex systems above it (combat, AI, etc.) depended on this super quirky movement/pathing code. It took multiple Ensemble engineers several &lt;em&gt;years&lt;/em&gt; of development to go from Age 1 to Age 2 level pathing.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;We made a number of improvements to the path finding and unit movement code &lt;span&gt;without breaking the original system&lt;/span&gt;. It must be emphasized that Age1's pather and movement code is &lt;span&gt;extremely&lt;/span&gt; tricky and hard to change without breaking a hundred things about the game or AI (sometimes in subtle ways). It was a very tricky balance. The current system still has problems with chokepoints, which can be fixed with more work, but we instead had to focus on multiplayer which had to basically be 85% rewritten.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;Here's a list of fixes made so far to DE's pathing and movement code in the time I had, which was only like 2 months:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;DE's pathing system's findPath() function was speeded up by approx 3-4x faster vs. Age1's&lt;br/&gt;I performed around a dozen separate optimizations passes on the core pather. I implemented the A* early exploration optimization (eliminating 1 open list insertion/removal per iteration), and massively tuned the C++ code to generate reasonably efficient x64 assembly. I transformed the inner loops so much that they barely resemble the original code. We retested the pather and game thoroughly after each major optimization pass. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;Age1's pather's A* implementation was outright broken (the open list management was flawed, so the cheapest node wasn't always expanded upon during each iteration). DE's pather fixes all these bugs and is a proper implementation of A*.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;DE's pather gives up if after many thousands of iterations it can't make forward progress towards the goal, to avoid spending CPU cycles on hopeless pathing unnecessarily. (It's more complex than this, but that's the gist of it.)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Added multiple lane support to villager pathing.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Villagers can use one of two collision sizes (either small or large), so if a villager bumps into another friendly villager we can immediately switch to the smaller radius to avoid stopping. So basically, villagers can get very close to each other, avoiding gathering slowdowns. Villager vs. military combat was preserved because vills use large radii by default, and if a vill vs. vill collision doesn't occur after a set period of time the villager returns back to the large radius. (An unfortunate side effect of this: It's possible to group together a ton of villagers - way more than the original game - and use them to attack other units. Villager Mobs are a game unbalancing issue in DE.)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;Movement of units through single-tile openings was greatly improved and tested with all unit types. Age 1's handling of single tile openings was so bad that players would exploit it:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://artho.com/age/placeb.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://artho.com/age/placeb.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;The DE pather was modified to have a much higher max iteration count than Age1's, so longer and more complex routes can be found.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;The per-turn pathing cap in Age1 was switched to short and long range pathing categories in DE. 8 short range paths can occur per turn, and for long range paths it supports up to 4 findPaths() per turn.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;For short range paths, straight line paths are preferred vs. the tile path returned by findPath() if the straight line path is safe to traverse.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Boat movement was modified to have deceleration.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Waypoints along a path can be skipped if a unit can safely move from its current position to the next waypoint&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Added support for 32-facing angles vs. Age's original 8. Also, the unit direction/facing angle is interpolated in DE, instead of &quot;snapped&quot; to like in Age1. The interpolation is purposely disabled when units switch angles during combat.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Added stuck unit detection logic to DE's movement code, to automatically detect and fix permanently stuck units (rare, but possible).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;We ported Age2's entire obstruction manager into DE, replacing the old bitmap system. Units use circular obstructions, and buildings use square obstructions.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Added several new behaviors to the movement code to help with chokepoints: A &quot;wait&quot; behavior, that checks every second or so for up to 45 seconds to see if the unit can be moved to the destination, and a stuck unit &quot;watchdog&quot;, which watches to see if a unit hasn't made forward progress and tries to switch behaviors to get the unit unstuck. Age1's code would just give up at the slightest problem.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;The pather tries to path starting from the center of each tile, but this sometimes fails in tight spaces or with lots of units around. DE tries harder to find a good starting position, so movement through single tile openings isn't broken.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Path caching system: Villagers and boats can reuse previously found paths in DE, for efficiency.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;In situations that Age1's pather would just outright give up and stop, DE's pather tries a lot harder to get the unit where it needs to go using several randomized fallback behaviors.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Age1's waypoint detection code was very janky and fixed in DE. Age1's code would sometimes cause units to oscillate around their current waypoint until it figured out it was ok to go to the next one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The original Age1 devs used text log files to debug the pather/movement systems. I had to write a 2D/3D debug primitive system so I could see what was actually going on. Here are some development screenshots - notice how complex this stuff is:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-VpMPWNuEUFQ/WphY_hfWv3I/AAAAAAAADxE/yJbLct_u1LgMgaA_XTD7whYSSGO-gNUrgCLcBGAs/s1600/agepath.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;900&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1600&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-VpMPWNuEUFQ/WphY_hfWv3I/AAAAAAAADxE/yJbLct_u1LgMgaA_XTD7whYSSGO-gNUrgCLcBGAs/s640/agepath.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-tPGbJS_2up0/WphZ8X029PI/AAAAAAAADxM/9Gnh-xtPx7snmn3hptqZaDZvfS_YP0UaQCLcBGAs/s1600/agepath2.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;612&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1088&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-tPGbJS_2up0/WphZ8X029PI/AAAAAAAADxM/9Gnh-xtPx7snmn3hptqZaDZvfS_YP0UaQCLcBGAs/s640/agepath2.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;Age1's pathing/movement systems implements a form of randomized, emergent behavior. The units are basically like dumb ants. It's imperfect in chokepoints, but it's a continuation of the essence of what made Age 1 what it was. If all the units are moving in the same direction it can usually handle chokepoints (I tested this over and over with a wide variety of units on a pathing torture test scenario from MS before release). The fundamental behaviors the AI and combat systems expected were accurately preserved in DE's pather, which was our goal.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;Instead of people saying &quot;the pathing in DE sucks!&quot;, I would much rather hear about the specific issues with movement/pathing, and actually constructive suggestions on how to improve the system &lt;span&gt;without breaking the game&lt;/span&gt; or turning it into Age 2.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 08:45:49 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ingve</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://richg42.blogspot.com/2018/02/on-age-des-pathingmovement.html</og:url>
<og:title>On Age DE's pathing/movement</og:title>
<og:description>Typical Age DE forum post: The pathfinding in the game is terrible. First off, Age of Empires Definitive Edition is a  remaster  of...</og:description>
<og:image>https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-VpMPWNuEUFQ/WphY_hfWv3I/AAAAAAAADxE/yJbLct_u1LgMgaA_XTD7whYSSGO-gNUrgCLcBGAs/w1200-h630-p-k-no-nu/agepath.png</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://richg42.blogspot.com/2018/02/on-age-des-pathingmovement.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Mosfet the cat 2001 – 2018</title>
<link>https://blog.adafruit.com/2018/02/28/in-loving-memory-mosfet-the-cat-2001-2018/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.adafruit.com/2018/02/28/in-loving-memory-mosfet-the-cat-2001-2018/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-blog.adafruit.com/uploads/2018/02/2009-3442895435_a031f7b0f5_o.jpg&quot; height=&quot;639&quot; width=&quot;853&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; hspace=&quot;4&quot; vspace=&quot;4&quot; alt=&quot;2009-3442895435 A031F7B0F5 O&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Mosfet the cat passed away last night, Ladyada &amp;amp; pt were present, he passed peacefully, without pain. Mosfet was a wonderful cat and helped us every single day, including helping us say goodbye to him together. There was not a day he wasn’t helping us in his own cat way. He was over 17+ years old.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mosfet was a black “hard to adopt” rescue cat that no one wanted, we think he was thrown away in a garbage bag before he was adopted due his fear of garbage bags in any form (he eventually got over it).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ladyada adopted him, Mosfet went to MIT, and made an adafruit with Ladyada and with pt. Mosfet was the part of our shows for the last 10 or so years, making an appearance live when Adafruit was an apartment company and recently on Desk of Ladyada. There wasn’t an electronic design that he didn’t stop by at Ladyada’s desk to check out what she was doing. Mosfet was up at 5am everyday with pt helping to run Adafruit in his own cat way, every day on his lap, at night hanging out with Ladyada.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-blog.adafruit.com/uploads/2018/02/4759515484_6577992839_o.jpg&quot; height=&quot;571&quot; width=&quot;853&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; hspace=&quot;4&quot; vspace=&quot;4&quot; alt=&quot;4759515484 6577992839 O&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Tonight at 8pm will play a few photos of him over the years to say goodbye on ASK AN ENGINEER. Mosfet started ASK AN ENGINEER with us when Ladyada would do the kitting and pt was doing the shipping at night. He would sit patiently waiting to be picked up or played with and then we’d share whatever was going on at Adafruit from our apartment company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-blog.adafruit.com/uploads/2018/02/2010-pnp.jpg&quot; height=&quot;639&quot; width=&quot;853&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; hspace=&quot;4&quot; vspace=&quot;4&quot; alt=&quot;2010-Pnp&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Mosfet seemed to want us to make “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.adafruit.com/galleries/cats-of-engineering&quot;&gt;Cats of Engineering&lt;/a&gt;” so we did, you can see the photos here, including one of Mosfet in our kitchen, on top of our Pick-and-Place we were able to get inside our apartment at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-blog.adafruit.com/uploads/2018/02/4316119056_5befe13021_o.jpg&quot; height=&quot;678&quot; width=&quot;829&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; hspace=&quot;4&quot; vspace=&quot;4&quot; alt=&quot;4316119056 5Befe13021 O&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;He would even communicate (we think) with other cats live on video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;853&quot; height=&quot;412&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/icnF3og0XW4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Mosfet sometimes would supervise the Pick and place operations at apartment-Adafruit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-blog.adafruit.com/uploads/2018/02/4594539309_489f641132_o.jpg&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; hspace=&quot;4&quot; vspace=&quot;4&quot; alt=&quot;4594539309 489F641132 O&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Mosfet made sure the laser cutter was working and when we once had a laser etching service from our apartment, he would greet the customers that made an appointment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-blog.adafruit.com/uploads/2018/02/4310992871_df410a1391_o.jpg&quot; height=&quot;573&quot; width=&quot;853&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; hspace=&quot;4&quot; vspace=&quot;4&quot; alt=&quot;4310992871 Df410A1391 O&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Mosfet was friendly with all the delivery folks and they all knew him by name. Mosfet helped in receiving. Mosfet caught mice when one of the past apartment-Adafruit apartment was condemned and mice and bugs were everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-blog.adafruit.com/uploads/2018/02/2010-4543863633_95ab7c23b6_o.jpg&quot; height=&quot;567&quot; width=&quot;853&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; hspace=&quot;4&quot; vspace=&quot;4&quot; alt=&quot;2010-4543863633 95Ab7C23B6 O&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Mosfet tested each of the cameras we would buy when we could afford a newer or better one. Mosfet would explore all the boxes that came in and help move around any stray parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-blog.adafruit.com/uploads/2018/02/IMG_2811-1.jpg&quot; height=&quot;832&quot; width=&quot;624&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; hspace=&quot;4&quot; vspace=&quot;4&quot; alt=&quot;Img 2811 (1)&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Thermal cameras too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-blog.adafruit.com/uploads/2018/02/5042991710_3d6e4e9e5c_b.jpg&quot; height=&quot;567&quot; width=&quot;853&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; hspace=&quot;4&quot; vspace=&quot;4&quot; alt=&quot;5042991710 3D6E4E9E5C B&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Back when Ladyada took all the photos of products, Mosfet would always jump up and make sure he was in at least one photo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-blog.adafruit.com/uploads/2018/02/5532954430_1c9b3867d2_o.jpg&quot; height=&quot;763&quot; width=&quot;853&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; hspace=&quot;4&quot; vspace=&quot;4&quot; alt=&quot;5532954430 1C9B3867D2 O&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Mosfet was the first to congratulate Ladyada when she was on the cover of WIRED.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-blog.adafruit.com/uploads/2018/02/coloringbook.jpg&quot; height=&quot;675&quot; width=&quot;843&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; hspace=&quot;4&quot; vspace=&quot;4&quot; alt=&quot;Coloringbook&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Mosfet appeared in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.adafruit.com/coloringbook&quot;&gt;Ladyada’s E is for Electronics coloring book&lt;/a&gt;. M is for MOSFET.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-blog.adafruit.com/uploads/2018/02/02.jpg&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; hspace=&quot;4&quot; vspace=&quot;4&quot; alt=&quot;02&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Mosfet is part of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.adafruit.com/lego&quot;&gt;Adafruit LEGO&lt;/a&gt; set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-blog.adafruit.com/uploads/2018/02/adafruit_2018_0166.jpg&quot; height=&quot;446&quot; width=&quot;360&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; hspace=&quot;4&quot; vspace=&quot;4&quot; alt=&quot;Adafruit 2018 0166&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Mosfet appears in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/adafruit-stickers/id1291627278?mt=8&quot;&gt;Adafruit iOS sticker app with ADABOT&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-blog.adafruit.com/uploads/2018/02/IMG_2228-1.jpg&quot; height=&quot;639&quot; width=&quot;853&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; hspace=&quot;4&quot; vspace=&quot;4&quot; alt=&quot;Img 2228-1&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;He helped test blinky LEDs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-blog.adafruit.com/uploads/2018/02/4113589411_4fbde09bb5_o.jpg&quot; height=&quot;479&quot; width=&quot;853&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; hspace=&quot;4&quot; vspace=&quot;4&quot; alt=&quot;4113589411 4Fbde09Bb5 O&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;So many of you out there would email us about him over the years, send him toys, and make sure we remembered to have him on whatever video we could and would ask us to show a recent photo when we moved Adafruit to our factory a few years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ladyada &amp;amp; pt donated to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mspca.org/donate-now/&quot;&gt;MSPCA-Angell&lt;/a&gt;, a 501(C)(3) Nonprofit (Massachusetts Society for the prevention of cruelty to animals) in Mosfet’s name, this is the group that organized the adoption of Mosfet over 17 years ago, he cost $19.87 in fees. That was a good deal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At events and in person, people would ask about Mosfet. He grew up with all of us, he is us. Thank you so much everyone, this little cat made Adafruit in more ways that we’ll ever be able to express.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-blog.adafruit.com/uploads/2018/02/mosfet_hi.jpg&quot; height=&quot;569&quot; width=&quot;853&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; hspace=&quot;4&quot; vspace=&quot;4&quot; alt=&quot;Mosfet Hi&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;853&quot; height=&quot;412&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/JuTevESueqE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;br/&gt;On Wednesday February 28th, 2018 8pm “ASK AN ENGINEER” was Mosfet’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JuTevESueqE&quot;&gt;final show&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 07:34:45 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jonbaer</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>In loving memory – Mosfet the cat 2001 – 2018</og:title>
<og:url>https://blog.adafruit.com/2018/02/28/in-loving-memory-mosfet-the-cat-2001-2018/</og:url>
<og:description>Mosfet the cat passed away last night, Ladyada &amp; pt were present, he passed peacefully, without pain. Mosfet was a wonderful cat and helped us every single day, including helping us say goodby…</og:description>
<og:image>https://cdn-blog.adafruit.com/uploads/2018/02/2009-3442895435_a031f7b0f5_o.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.adafruit.com/2018/02/28/in-loving-memory-mosfet-the-cat-2001-2018/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>