<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Vim.wasm</title>
<link>https://rhysd.github.io/vim.wasm/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://rhysd.github.io/vim.wasm/</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://rhysd.github.io/vim.wasm/&quot;&gt;https://rhysd.github.io/vim.wasm/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19742599&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19742599&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 256&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 92&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 21:07:43 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>fibo</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://rhysd.github.io/vim.wasm/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Massachusetts Court Blocks Warrantless Access to Real-Time Location Data</title>
<link>https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2019/04/massachusetts-court-blocks-warrantless-access-real-time-cell-phone-location-data</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2019/04/massachusetts-court-blocks-warrantless-access-real-time-cell-phone-location-data</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;There's heartening news for our location privacy out of Massachusetts this week. The Supreme Judicial Court, the state's highest court, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/document/commonwealth-v-almonor-massachusetts-supreme-judicial-court-opinion&quot;&gt;ruled&lt;/a&gt; that police access to real-time cell phone location data—whether it comes from a phone company or from technology like a cell site simulator—intrudes on a person’s reasonable expectation of privacy. Absent exigent circumstances, the court held, the police must get a warrant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/document/commonwealth-v-almonor-massachusetts-supreme-judicial-court-opinion&quot;&gt;Commonwealth of Massachusetts v. Almonor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, police had a phone carrier “ping” the cell phone of a suspect in a murder case—surreptitiously accessing GPS functions and causing the phone to send its coordinates back to the phone carrier and the police. This real-time location data pinpointed Mr. Almonor’s phone to a location inside a private home. The state argued it could warrantlessly get cell phone location data to find anyone, anytime, at any place as long as it was less than &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2015/09/massachusetts-court-rules-cell-tracking-requires-warrant&quot;&gt;six hours&lt;/a&gt; old. A trial court disagreed and the state appealed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EFF filed an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/document/almonor-amicus-brief-eff-aclu&quot;&gt;amicus brief&lt;/a&gt; in this case in partnership with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aclum.org/&quot;&gt;ACLU&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://macdl.com/&quot;&gt;Massachusetts Association of Criminal Defense Lawyers&lt;/a&gt;. We asked the court to recognize, as the Supreme Court did in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2018/06/victory-supreme-court-says-fourth-amendment-applies-cell-phone-tracking&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;U.S. v Carpenter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; that people have a constitutional right to privacy in their physical movements. We argued that, because people have their phones with them all the time, and because the location information produced by the phone can reveal our every move—where and with whom we live, socialize, visit, vacation, worship, and much more—the police must get a warrant to access this sensitive information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Massachusetts court held that “[m]anipulating our phones for the purpose of identifying and tracking our personal location presents an even greater intrusion” than accessing the historical location data at issue in &lt;em&gt;Carpenter.&lt;/em&gt; It concluded that “by causing the defendant's cell phone to reveal its real-time location, the Commonwealth intruded on the defendant's reasonable expectation of privacy in the real-time location of his cell phone.” The court recognized both that cell phone use is ubiquitous in our society, and that a phone’s location is a “proxy” for its owner’s location. The court noted that “society's expectation has been that law enforcement could not secretly and instantly identify a person's real-time physical location at will,” and “[a]llowing law enforcement to immediately locate an individual whose whereabouts were previously unknown by compelling that individual's cell phone to reveal its location contravenes that expectation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much of the majority’s opinion focuses on the fact that, in this case, law enforcement directed the phone company to “manipulate” the defendant’s phone, causing it to send its location to the phone company. In other words, the phone company wouldn’t have collected the data on its own as part of its normal business practices. But two judges, in a concurring opinion, expressed concern that this focus on law enforcement action—rather than on the collection of location data alone—would result in an exception for searches of real-time location data that providers collect automatically. The concurring justices would hold that the Massachusetts constitution “protects us from pings not because of the right to keep the government from interfering with our cellular telephones, but because of the right to keep the government from finding us.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is very concerning because, as the concurring justices note, the majority’s focus on government action here could allow the police to “side-step the constitutional protection” by just asking for the data the cell service provider collects on its own. Although the majority denied that would happen, it remains to be seen, both how officers will implement searches after this opinion and how lower courts will apply constitutional law to those searches. We’ve seen the Commonwealth &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2015/09/massachusetts-court-rules-cell-tracking-requires-warrant&quot;&gt;interpret this court’s prior decisions on location tracking&lt;/a&gt; very narrowly in the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the defendant raised both federal and state constitutional claims in &lt;em&gt;Almonor&lt;/em&gt;, the court based its decision solely on Article 14 of the Massachusetts Declaration of Rights, which was drafted before—and served as one of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mass.gov/guides/john-adams-the-massachusetts-constitution&quot;&gt;models&lt;/a&gt; for—our federal Bill of Rights. Article 14, one of the cornerstones of the Massachusetts Constitution, is the state’s equivalent to the Fourth Amendment. As the court notes, it “does, or may, afford more substantive protection to individuals than that which prevails under the Constitution of the United States.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Courts around the country are now being asked to address the scope of the &lt;em&gt;Carpenter&lt;/em&gt; ruling. &lt;em&gt;Almonor&lt;/em&gt; in Massachusetts and a case called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/document/odonnell-amicus-brief-eff-aclu&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;State of Maine v. O’Donnell&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; in Maine are among the first to deal directly with how &lt;em&gt;Carpenter&lt;/em&gt; should be applied when police track and locate people in real-time. We’re heartened that the Massachusetts court took these issues seriously and made clear that the police must get a warrant, whether they access &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2014/02/massachusetts-requires-warrants-cell-tracking&quot;&gt;historical cell phone location data&lt;/a&gt; or whether they cause a phone to send its real-time location. We’re still waiting for the Maine court’s opinion in &lt;em&gt;O’Donnell,&lt;/em&gt; and we’re actively tracking other cases addressing these issues across the country.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 20:38:10 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Elof</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Massachusetts Court Blocks Warrantless Access to Real-Time Cell Phone Location Data</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2019/04/massachusetts-court-blocks-warrantless-access-real-time-cell-phone-location-data</og:url>
<og:description>There's heartening news for our location privacy out of Massachusetts this week. The Supreme Judicial Court, the state's highest court, ruled that police access to real-time cell phone location data—whether it comes from a phone company or from technology like a cell site simulator—intrudes on a...</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.eff.org/files/issues/icon-privacy-1_0.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2019/04/massachusetts-court-blocks-warrantless-access-real-time-cell-phone-location-data</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Facebook Expects to Be Fined Up to $5B by FTC Over Privacy Issues</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/04/24/technology/facebook-ftc-fine-earnings.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2019/04/24/technology/facebook-ftc-fine-earnings.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;SAN FRANCISCO — Facebook said on Wednesday that it &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://investor.fb.com/investor-news/press-release-details/2019/Facebook-Reports-First-Quarter-2019-Results/default.aspx&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;expected to be fined&lt;/a&gt; up to $5 billion by the Federal Trade Commission for privacy violations. The penalty would be a record by the agency against a technology company and a sign that the United States was willing to punish big tech companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The social network disclosed the amount in its quarterly financial results, saying it estimated a one-time charge of $3 billion to $5 billion in connection with an “ongoing inquiry” by the F.T.C. Facebook added that “the matter remains unresolved, and there can be no assurance as to the timing or the terms of any final outcome.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Facebook has been &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/02/14/technology/facebook-ftc-settlement.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;in negotiations&lt;/a&gt; with the regulator for months over a financial penalty for claims that the company violated a 2011 privacy consent decree. That year, the social network promised a series of measures to protect its users’ privacy after an investigation found that its handling of data had harmed consumers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The F.T.C. opened a new investigation last year after Facebook came under fire again. This time, the company was accused of not protecting its users’ data from being harvested without their consent by &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/03/17/us/politics/cambridge-analytica-trump-campaign.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Cambridge Analytica&lt;/a&gt;, a British political consulting firm that was building voter profiles for the Trump campaign. Facebook also &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/09/28/technology/facebook-hack-data-breach.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;suffered a data breach&lt;/a&gt; that exposed the personal information of nearly 50 million users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Levying a sizable fine on Facebook would go against the reputation of the United States of not restraining the power of big tech companies. For years, American regulators have faced criticism that they allowed Silicon Valley firms to grow unchecked, even as their European counterparts aggressively brought actions against tech companies — including &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/07/18/technology/google-eu-android-fine.html?action=click&amp;amp;module=inline&amp;amp;pgtype=Homepage&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;fining Google a record $5.1 billion&lt;/a&gt; last year for abusing its power in the mobile phone market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;For the Trump administration, penalizing Facebook would be a defining action. Although President Trump has rolled back scores of business regulations, he and others in Washington — including Democrats — have coalesced around calling for greater scrutiny and enforcement of tech companies. Senator Elizabeth Warren, Democrat of Massachusetts and presidential candidate, has &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/03/08/us/politics/elizabeth-warren-amazon.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;called for the breakup&lt;/a&gt; of Amazon, Google and Facebook. And Mr. Trump has sounded alarms over the dominance of the firms and their control over speech and the distribution of information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;It would also be a milestone for the F.T.C., whose biggest fine for a tech company was $22 million against Google in 2012 for misrepresenting how it used some online tracking tools. The agency, which is charged with overseeing deceptive and unfair business practices, is riding a wave of anti-tech sentiment as questions about how tech companies have contributed to misinformation, election meddling and data privacy problems have stacked up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“The F.T.C. is really limited in what they can actually do in enforcing a consent decree, but in the case of Facebook, they had public pressure on their side,” said Justin Brookman, a former official for the regulator who is now a director of privacy at Consumers Union, nonprofit consumer advocacy group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;But some lawmakers said a fine would not suffice in punishing Facebook. Representative David Cicilline, Democrat of Rhode Island, said that “a fine in the low billions of dollars would amount to a slap on the wrist for Facebook” and that Congress needed to act.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“Facebook must be held accountable — not just by fines — but also far reaching reforms in management, privacy practices and culture,” Senator Richard Blumenthal, Democrat of Connecticut, added in a tweet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The F.T.C. declined to comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Officials at the agency have not reached a final decision on Facebook, said two people with knowledge of the situation, who were not authorized to speak publicly. In recent weeks, the agency’s chairman, Joseph Simons, sent strict orders to all commission offices and staff in the consumer protection, enforcement and privacy bureaus to not discuss the Facebook case, two people said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;But Facebook’s estimate of a fine signaled that a settlement with the F.T.C. was near. The Securities and Exchange Commission typically requires that a company notify investors of any significant financial hits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;For Facebook, a $5 billion fine would amount to a fraction of its $56 billion in annual revenue. Any resolution would also alleviate some of the regulatory pressure that has been intensifying against the company over the past two and a half years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“This would be a joke of a fine — a two-weeks-of-revenue, parking-ticket-level penalty for destroying democracy,” said Matt Stoller, a fellow at the Open Markets Institute, a think tank that is a vocal critic of the power of tech companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;More meaningful to Facebook would be any regulatory mandates that curbed its ability to share data with business partners or required it to take more measures to inform consumers when and how it collected data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“Those will have the most lasting impact on consumers’ privacy,” said Ashkan Soltani, a former chief technology officer for the trade commission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Even as the negotiations continue, Facebook’s business remains robust. The company said Wednesday that its revenue increased 26 percent in the first quarter to $15 billion from a year earlier. Net income dropped 51 percent from a year ago to $2.4 billion because of the expected one-time charge related to the F.T.C. investigation. The company has more than $40 billion in cash reserves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;New users continue flocking to Facebook. More than 2.7 billion people use one of the company’s so-called family of apps — Facebook, Messenger, Instagram and WhatsApp — each month. The company said about 1.56 billion people use Facebook every day, up 8 percent from a year ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Last month, Mark Zuckerberg, Facebook’s founder and chief executive, said he planned to &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/03/06/technology/mark-zuckerberg-facebook-privacy.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;start shifting people toward private conversations&lt;/a&gt; and away from public broadcasting on social media, which is likely to help the company manage issues of toxic content and misinformation. On Wednesday in a conference call, Mr. Zuckerberg repeated that vision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“People want a platform that is as strong on privacy as possible,” Mr. Zuckerberg said. He added that “we just don’t know” how the change would affect the company’s business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Zuckerberg also said &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/03/30/technology/mark-zuckerberg-facebook-regulation-explained.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;he welcomed regulations&lt;/a&gt;, an idea that he has increasingly been vocal about this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“I think it’s necessary,” he said. “Getting these issues right is more important than our interests. And I believe that regulation will help establish trust when people know that the right systems of governance and accountability are in place.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 20:27:55 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Dangeranger</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/04/24/technology/facebook-ftc-fine-privacy.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Facebook Expects to Be Fined Up to $5 Billion by F.T.C. Over Privacy Issues</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/04/24/business/24FACEBOOK2/24FACEBOOK2-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Facebook and the agency have been in negotiations over a financial penalty for claims that the company violated a 2011 consent decree.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/04/24/technology/facebook-ftc-fine-privacy.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Inflammation might be the root of preventable disease</title>
<link>https://harvardmagazine.com/2019/05/inflammation-disease-diet</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://harvardmagazine.com/2019/05/inflammation-disease-diet</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;firstwords&quot;&gt;In&lt;/span&gt; 2007, associate professor of medicine Samia Mora and colleagues published a study of exercise that sought to understand why physical activity is salutary. They already knew that exercise reduces the risk of cardiovascular disease as much as cholesterol-lowering statin drugs do. By analyzing biomarkers in the blood of 27,055 women participating in a long-term study, and other objective measures, they hoped to tease out the source of this effect. How much of the benefit was attributable to improved blood pressure? To lower body weight? Or to something else? The women had donated blood in the 1990s when they entered the study. Eleven years later, the researchers analyzed this frozen blood to see if they could find anything that correlated with long-term cardiovascular outcomes such as heart attack and stroke. “We were actually surprised that reduced inflammation was the biggest explainer, the biggest contributor to the benefit of activity,” says Mora, “because we hadn’t hypothesized that. We knew that regular exercise does reduce inflammation over the long term, but we also knew that acute exercise transiently &lt;em&gt;increases&lt;/em&gt; inflammatory biomarkers during and immediately after exertion.” About a third of the benefit of regular exercise, they found, is attributable to reduced inflammation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The anti-inflammatory effect of exercise was much greater than most people had expected. That raised another question: whether inflammation might also play a dominant role in other lifestyle illnesses that have been linked to cardiovascular disease, such as diabetes and dementia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2017, two cardiologists at Brigham and Women’s Hospital in Boston, who suspected such a link, published the results of a human clinical trial that will forever change the way people think about inflammation. The trial, which involved more than 10,000 patients in 39 countries, was primarily designed to determine whether an anti-inflammatory drug, by itself, could lower rates of cardiovascular disease in a large population, without simultaneously lowering levels of cholesterol, as statin drugs do. The answer was yes. But the researchers went a step further, building into the trial additional tests seeking to clarify what effect the same anti-inflammatory drug, canakinumab, might have on illnesses seemingly &lt;em&gt;unrelated&lt;/em&gt; to cardiovascular disease: arthritis, gout, and cancer. Only the researchers themselves, and their scientific colleagues, were unsurprised by the outcome. Lung cancer mortality dropped by as much as 77 percent. Reports of arthritis and gout also fell significantly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In medicine, believing something is true is not the same as being able to prove it. Because the idea that inflammation—constant, low-level, immune-system activation —could be at the root of many noncommunicable diseases is a startling claim, it requires &lt;em&gt;extraordinary&lt;/em&gt; proof. Can seemingly unconnected illnesses of the brain, the vasculature, lungs, liver, and joints really share a deep biological link? Evidence has been mounting that these common chronic conditions—including Alzheimer’s, cancer, arthritis, asthma, gout, psoriasis, anemia, Parkinson’s disease, multiple sclerosis, diabetes, and depression among them—are indeed triggered by low-grade, long-term inflammation. But it took that large-scale human clinical trial to dispel any lingering doubt: the immune system’s inflammatory response is killing people by degrees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the pertinent question is why, and what can be done about it. The pharmaceutical industry is deeply interested in finding ways to stop inflammation with medicines like canakinumab, an orphan drug that blocks a specific pro-inflammatory pathway called IL-1beta. But some researchers suggest that the inflammatory process—a normal and necessary part of the natural immune response—has itself has been misunderstood. Scientists know that the process can be turned on and off, but have only recently understood that this doesn’t mean normal physiology will resume once the inflammation caused by infection, injury, or irritant has been shut down. Instead, the restoration of health is an &lt;em&gt;active phase&lt;/em&gt; of the inflammatory process itself, facilitated by a little-known class of molecules called pro-resolving mediators—the protectins, resolvins, maresins, and lipoxins—brimming with marvelous, untapped, regenerative capacities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Origins of Atherosclerosis&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;firstwords&quot;&gt;The&lt;/span&gt; 2017 clinical trial, called CANTOS (Canakinumab Anti-Inflammatory Thrombosis Outcomes Study), is the result of a long-term collaboration between Paul Ridker and Peter Libby, who suspected as long ago as the 1980s that inflammation played a role in cardiovascular disease. Ridker, an epidemiologist who is Braunwald professor of medicine, came to this conclusion through studies of cardiac patients. He is the physician-scientist who first demonstrated that a molecule called C-reactive protein (CRP), easily measured by a simple and now ubiquitous blood test, could be used like a thermometer to take the temperature of a patient’s inflammation. Elevated CRP, he discovered years ago, predicts future cardiovascular events, including heart attacks. Although nobody knows what it does biologically, this marker is downstream from IL-1beta, and thus provides a reliable yardstick of that pro-inflammatory pathway’s level of activation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imagecenter&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://harvardmagazine.com/sites/default/files/inline_images/2019-MayJune/HM_MJ19_ART_Page_46_Image_0002.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Paul Ridker and Peter Libby&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;Photograph by Jim Harrison&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Libby, the Mallinckrodt professor of medicine, is a bench scientist and clinician with expertise in the study of heart disease. In the 1980s, orthodoxy within the cardiovascular establishment held that circulating fats (including cholesterol) build up in the arteries of patients with progressive cardiovascular disease. But no one knew why or how the plaques formed. It took work by some of the most distinguished cardiology researchers of the era to lay the groundwork that eventually produced an understanding of the molecular mechanisms that drive deposition of those plaques.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, in his Harvard Medical School (HMS) office, Libby sketches the origins of atherosclerosis. The interior walls of blood vessels, he explains, are made from smooth muscle cells, lined in turn with endothelial cells that are in direct contact with circulating blood. When a problem arises, caused by anything from cholesterol to bacteria, the vascular system recruits white blood cells, the immune system’s front-line guardians, to the site. Two Harvard professors of pathology, Michael Gimbrone Jr. and the late Ramzi Cotran, figured out that naturally occurring adhesion molecules could attract these white blood cells and get them to stick to the endothelium lining the arteries. Their experiments implicated a pro-inflammatory signal called interleukin-1 (IL-1), which is produced by both circulating and tissue-based immune cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imageleft&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://harvardmagazine.com/sites/default/files/inline_images/2019-MayJune/HM_MJ19_ART_Page_47_Image_0001.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;The pentameric molecular structure of C-reactive protein, a biomarker of inflammation that circulates in the blood. Cardiologists use CRP to predict a person’s future risk of heart attack.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;Courtesy of T. Greenhough &amp;amp; A. Shrive/Wellcome Image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Libby, then at Tufts, followed their work closely. IL-1 had been discovered in 1977 by one of his Tufts colleagues, Charles Dinarello, who had been focused on understanding what causes fever, one of the cardinal signs of inflammation. The others, described by Aulus Cornelius Celsus in the first century &lt;span class=&quot;firstwords&quot;&gt;c.e.&lt;/span&gt;, are redness (&lt;em&gt;rubor)&lt;/em&gt;, which occurs when the endothelial lining of arteries dilates to permit more blood flow; swelling (&lt;em&gt;tumor),&lt;/em&gt; caused by endothelial cells leaking protein, which carries water; and pain (&lt;em&gt;dolor&lt;/em&gt;). By measuring the factors in rabbits’ blood, Dinarello was able to isolate and then clone the specific factor—called a pyrogen—that causes fever: interleukin-1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But before this inflammatory pyrogen even had a name, Dinarello gave some to Libby, whose lab was down the hall. Libby discovered that arterial wall cells not only responded to IL-1, but could &lt;em&gt;secrete&lt;/em&gt; it. This was heretical, he explains, because it was thought that only “a properly pedigreed immunological cell” could produce such signals. Now it was clear that the cells of the artery walls were capable of summoning an immune response. Libby further found that IL-1, by altering gene expression in local blood vessel cells, &lt;em&gt;amplifies&lt;/em&gt; its signal at the site of the disease. But, “No one in cardiology was interested in inflammation” then, Libby notes. In fact, none of his early work on IL-1 appears in the cardiology literature: “My papers were rejected,” he recalls; “my grants turned down.” In 1986, he published his first paper showing that the lining of the arteries could produce IL-1 in the &lt;em&gt;American Journal of Pathology.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The Evolution of Excessive Inflammation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;firstwords&quot;&gt;Today,&lt;/span&gt; inflammation is a focus of intense research in many fields. Roni Nowarski, assistant professor of neurology and immunology, explains that inflammation is important across a range of seemingly distinct pathologies because immune cells are everywhere, even resident in organs, where they play an important role in monitoring and maintaining health. The paradigm that everyone knows—that the immune system’s front line consists of circulating white blood cells that patrol the body to guard against infection and injury—is a bit misleading. An important arm of the immune system resides outside the blood vessels. Pac-Man-like macrophages occupy tissues, where they engulf and digest invading pathogens, debris, and dying cells. An invaluable role of these tissue macrophages is to “act as sensors,” Nowarski says. “They have hard-wired mechanisms to detect signals that are out of the ordinary,” and so play a critical role in maintaining a healthy equilibrium. “If there is any fluctuation,” he notes, “the role of these cells is to return the system to this point of homeostasis.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These tissue-based white blood cells can also call for backup. When that happens, the heavy guns of the immune system, neutrophils, are first to arrive on the scene. These are “potent, aggressive cells” that can kill infectious agents, Nowarski explains, but “can also cause a lot of damage to healthy tissue.” That’s why most neutrophils are short-lived, with a tightly regulated lifespan of just a few hours: unchecked, they would cause serious harm. Neutrophils, which originate in bone marrow, also play a role in relaxing the endothelial barrier that separates blood from tissue, so immune cells can cross that barrier to reach the site of attack. Other signals—like the IL-1beta protein that Libby and Ridker blocked in their trial—promote adhesion, in order to capture circulating immune cells that reach the damaged tissue. This stickiness, though desirable in the short term, is also the basis of the process that can lead to atherosclerosis if it continues indefinitely. The endgame of a &lt;em&gt;healthy&lt;/em&gt; immune response, on the other hand, involves cleanup, says Nowarski: even the death and uptake of neutrophils as they are gobbled by macrophages serve as signals to resolve inflammation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why inflammation sometimes &lt;em&gt;doesn’t&lt;/em&gt; resolve, and becomes chronic instead, is in some sense easily explained in evolutionary terms. “If I’m living 70,000 years ago at a time of food shortage,” says Ridker, “and there’s a drought, the 5 to 10 percent of people who will survive that drought are likely to have insulin resistance”—a tendency to store more calories as fat. “They’re going to live a little longer,” he continues. “When it finally rains, food comes, and that’s the survivor group. In a modern world of too much food, [insulin resistance] leads to diabetes. But in prehistory, it’s terribly important for survival.” While stored fat is beneficial during times of famine, it also harbors potentially damaging pro-inflammatory signaling molecules (see “Eating to Excess: Metabolic Inflammation,” below).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A second evolved factor is that prior to the development of antibiotics, disease “wiped out half the population before age five. So, people were under evolutionary pressure to have a hyperactive immune system.” Now, “most everybody survives childhood infections,” thanks in large part to vaccines. “But this hyperactive immune system remains, and adversely affects aging.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The third piece—beyond starvation and infection—is trauma,” Ridker says. “The saber-toothed tiger—or for women, bleeding to death during childbirth—selects on a genetic basis for hypercoagulable blood. So here we are, by definition all of us lucky enough to be alive today, with a consistent ancestry all the way back to the beginning. And we have all inherited a pro-inflammatory, insulin resistant, pro-coagulable state. Under the circumstances,” he continues, the fact that “we have an epidemic of diabetes and heart disease makes complete sense.” Evolutionary pressures have shaped a physiological system which is phenomenally well suited for surviving childhood infection, starvation, and predation. “But it contributes to many disorders of chronic aging, because from an evolutionary perspective, if you’ve had your kids, you’re kind of done.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Evolution also explains why the underlying biology appears so similar from one disease to the next. Kennedy professor of child neurology and mental retardation Rudy Tanzi studies Alzheimer’s disease, which is well known for causing plaques and tangles in the brain. In 2008, Tanzi and his colleagues discovered a gene that clearly played a role in the development of the disease, but didn’t know how it worked. Five years later, they discovered that the gene is the “on” switch for inflammation in the brain. Tanzi says the work that has most influenced his thinking is the body of resilience studies conducted by Teresa Gomez-Isla, an associate professor of neurology based at Massachusetts General Hospital, who has shown that “you can have a brain full of plaques and tangles, but if you don’t have neuroinflammation, you don’t get the disease”—a finding that neatly parallels the pathological interactions between plaques and inflammation in atherosclerosis. This basic research on inflammation thus underlies understanding of entire classes of human illness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such similarities among diseases of metabolism and inflammation suggest that they are indeed rooted far back in evolutionary history. Gökhan S. Hotamisligil, Simmons professor of genetics and metabolism at the Harvard T.H. Chan School of Public Health, has constructed his research for the past 25 years on the premise that this shared history suggests shared &lt;em&gt;biological&lt;/em&gt; mechanisms as well. The ailments that cluster most dramatically, he points out, are “chronic metabolic diseases” such as diabetes, cardiovascular disease, stroke, Alzheimer’s, nerve degeneration, and cancer. In general, a person who has any one of these illnesses is more likely to develop the others. “This is exactly the same cluster that emerges during aging,” he says. “All of the age-related pathologies exhibit as clusters of non-communicable diseases, except in a much shorter period of time, and earlier in the lifespan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“That tells us that these illnesses are part of our natural history, our biological heritage,” continues Hotamisligil, who directs the Sabri Ülker Center for Metabolic Research. “If these two clusters emerge in two separate conditions in exactly the same way, that must come from deeply embedded evolutionary vulnerabilities.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;callout&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;“Chronic inflammation is uniformly damaging and is absolutely causal to the process, because if you interfere with it, you can reverse the pathology.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Critics might suggest that inflammation is just a symptom in these diseases, rather than a cause. But Hotamisligil says, unequivocally, “Chronic inflammation is uniformly damaging and is absolutely causal to the process, because if you interfere with it, you can reverse the pathology.” And this ability to control such diseases simply by reversing inflammation is a biological response, dating far back to the time of a common ancestor, that has been retained across diverse species of animals to the present day, he says, pointing to experimental evidence: “If you can make &lt;em&gt;Drosophila&lt;/em&gt; [fruit fly] diabetic, and then block the inflammatory response systems, you can cure diabetes in &lt;em&gt;Drosophila&lt;/em&gt;, the same way you can reverse it in the mouse, in primates, and in humans, provided that you do it with the right tools. Of course, the higher the organism, the more complex these pathways are, so it takes more effort to define the precise mechanisms to manipulate.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Eating to Excess: Metabolic Inflammation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;block-inject-1&quot; class=&quot;block-inject block-inject-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;block-block-102&quot; class=&quot;block block-block adblock mobile&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://adserver.adtechus.com/adlink/3.0/5466.1/3284406/0/0/ADTECH;loc=300;key=Research+Science++++&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://adserver.adtechus.com/adserv/3.0/5466.1/3284406/0/0/ADTECH;loc=300;key=Research+Science++++&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;firstwords&quot;&gt;Seeking the origins&lt;/span&gt; of inflammation, Hotamisligil asks, “What is the most primordial process in the emergence of life? Metabolism. Energy management. And then, of course, the next critical process to emerge within cells is the ability to defend. And so that brings in the immune system, which is younger than metabolism, but much older than many other systems.” In some of the simplest organisms, he points out, energy management and immune functions are packaged in the same organ, such as the fruit fly’s fat body. But even as these functions became specialized and divided among three or four organs in more complex organisms, they retained their evolutionary memory. “They share many tricks,” he says, because the “immune response is enormously expensive, energy-wise.” The intimate relationship between the metabolic and immune systems, he believes, has been maintained because it takes “tremendous energy to mount an effective immune response. While this link is essential to maintain health and homeostasis, abnormalities that develop over time, as in the case of obesity, carry a great risk of damage.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The metabolic stress that is a hallmark of modern life, the stress that the body has &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; evolved to handle, is constant eating, he continues. When people eat, energy and nutrients enter the body rapidly, are processed, produce in turn a lot of by-products, and then need to be reduced to “functional substances that are distributed throughout the body, and then disappear very quickly. Many cells and tissues actually undergo a huge amount of stress during this process,” he explains, “as they store appropriate nutrients and dispose of harmful intermediates.” Part of this process also involves mounting an immune response. “The pancreas, for example, must secrete four to five hundred milliliters of enzymes every day” to be able to manage the incoming energy load with every meal. “If you place these organs under constant stress, they start malfunctioning.” The consequence is that “right now, one out of every 10 individuals has diabetes. One out of every four individuals has fatty liver disease. And if you reach a certain age, one out of every three individuals will develop neurodegenerative disease.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The metabolic stress that underlies these conditions comes from the daily imbalance between how much energy people consume and how much they need, and can process in a healthy manner. The long-term consequence of overconsumption, combined with lack of sufficient expenditure, is stored energy—the accumulation of fat. Excess body fat, especially in the wrong places, is an &lt;em&gt;additional&lt;/em&gt; risk factor for inflammation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clinical studies implicating stored fat as a source of inflammation have been buttressed by basic research that shows that adipose tissue—body fat—is laced with immune cells, which become more abundant with weight gain, perhaps because fat cells can secrete alarm signals that summon white blood cells. “A fat cell is almost like a primitive immune cell,” says Hotamisligil. “It can request the assistance of immune cells when in trouble, but if the stress continues, and the immune cells remain, they start changing their character and behavior from helpful to harmful.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imageright&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://harvardmagazine.com/sites/default/files/inline_images/2019-MayJune/HM_Inflam_Adipose.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;A fat cell, or adipocyte, is more than 90 percent triglyceride. If the thin cell wall enclosing this droplet of fat ruptures, an inflammatory response ensues.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;iStock Images&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there is additional evidence that the &lt;em&gt;physical structure&lt;/em&gt; of fat cells, or adipocytes, which have been described by Stephen O’Rahilly of the University of Cambridge as resembling a fried egg atop a beach ball of fat—with a tiny rim of cytoplasm encircling the droplet of triglyceride—puts them at risk of rupture. Adipocytes are “cells at the edge under the best of circumstances,” explains Hotamisligil. Ninety percent or more of a fat cell’s volume is triglyceride, a substance chemically similar to diesel fuel. The remaining 10 percent is all the space it has for the organelles that perform the normal functions of cell biology. This bloated cell is thus vulnerable to stress, even to the point of bursting and death. When overloaded with stored lipid, fat cells begin to lose their functional and structural integrity and may start spilling their toxic cargo. When cells fail like this, the immune system kicks in, initially to assist in clean-up. Macrophages engorge themselves on the leaking fuel, and may die themselves during this process. But in the long run, what is meant to be a mutually beneficial interaction between the metabolic and immune systems turns into a very dangerous and harmful relationship. Obese individuals thus live in a state of chronic stress and inflammation; in fact, many people do, because their energy intake vastly exceeds their needs. Hotamisligil calls this chronic energy overload, and the resulting abnormal immune response, &lt;em&gt;metaflammation:&lt;/em&gt; metabolic inflammation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It is pretty clear that inflammation is a bad actor in obesity,” says Korsmeyer professor of cell biology and medicine Bruce Spiegelman. His lab was the first to establish the mechanism linking obesity to inflammation—in 1993, when he and Hotamisligil, then a doctoral student, discovered that fat cells produce an inflammatory signal that interferes with the body’s ability to regulate blood sugar. This, in turn, increases the risk of developing Type 2 diabetes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But inflammation in muscle, he says, is “much more complicated.” In fact, “it is likely that you &lt;em&gt;require&lt;/em&gt; inflammation in exercise,” and that the inflammatory response should not be suppressed—for example, by taking ibuprofen—because that signal is likely “telling the muscle to remodel.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together with Rasmussen professor of immunohematology Diane Mathis, Spiegelman is about to begin studying exercised muscle, a natural system that incorporates and manages inflammation on a regular basis. Mathis studies regulatory T-cells (Tregs), white blood cells that are actively involved in maintaining the internal stability (homeostasis) of tissues. Recently, she has sought to understand the role of Tregs in repairing muscle &lt;em&gt;injured&lt;/em&gt; as a consequence of physical trauma or disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, by studying muscle that has been &lt;em&gt;exercised&lt;/em&gt;, she and Spiegelman hope to gain a better understanding of how inflammation is “supposed to happen, and how it eventually &lt;em&gt;resolves&lt;/em&gt;.” The sequence, he says, occurs in four steps: “There’s damage, inflammation, resolution of inflammation, and repair. These phases are very different.” He and Mathis hope to learn how these processes unfold—and ultimately, perhaps, to learn how to stimulate, support, or mimic the body’s natural mechanisms of resolution and repair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Controlling Inflammation, Boosting the Immune System&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;firstwords&quot;&gt;Epidemiological studies&lt;/span&gt; have helped clarify the importance of lifestyle choices in controlling inflammation. Samia Mora’s 2007 research highlighted the role of exercise. In 2018, she and her colleagues published a study of the Mediterranean diet, which is known to improve cardiovascular health (and also thought to protect against neurodegenerative diseases such as Alzheimer’s and Parkinson’s). Mora examined the effect of this diet on the women who previously participated in the exercise research, 20 years after they had entered the original study. They found that adherence to a diet rich in vegetables, fruit, nuts, legumes, and olive oil, that also includes fish and chicken, but that is very low in red and processed meat and sugary foods or drinks, led to a lower risk of adverse cardiovascular events. As in the exercise study, they found that about a third of the benefit was due to reductions in inflammation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imagecenter&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://harvardmagazine.com/sites/default/files/inline_images/2019-MayJune/HM_MJ19_ART_Page_49_Image_0001.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Samia Mora&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;Photograph by Jim Harrison&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But some of the diet’s benefit could not be explained, meaning that an untested factor was enhancing its healthful effect. Mora speculates that the diet (which includes probiotic foods such as Greek yogurt) might support the health of the gut microbiome, or might stimulate the parasympathetic nervous system, as exercise does, to help people relax. Alternatively, the diet might be protective against oxidative stress of the kind that comes from pollution or smoking. Perhaps unsurprisingly, each of these possibilities is linked to inflammation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The great difficulty with interventions involving altered diet and increased exercise is that these healthy habits aren’t aligned with preferences evolved during millennia of food scarcity. People already know what they &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be doing—but for most, that knowledge doesn’t change behavior. Humans are hard-wired to conserve energy (see &lt;a href=&quot;https://harvardmagazine.com/2016/09/born-to-rest&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;“Born to Rest,”&lt;/a&gt; September-October 2016, page 9), for example, and to prefer foods that are fatty, salty, and sugary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This suggests that pharmaceutical interventions that block inflammation may be necessary to check the global epidemic of non-communicable disease. How to do that is not obvious, however. The intervention that Ridker and Libby devised, blocking a single inflammatory pathway with a drug, helped only a fraction of patients with cardiovascular disease. That is probably because a system as important to sustaining life as immune response has evolved redundancies: block one pathway and another will take over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What the CANTOS study did establish was a biological principle, says Ridker: “Anti-inflammatory and immunosuppressive are not the same thing.” Suppressing an immune pathway like IL-1beta could have led to reactivation of tuberculosis infections or complications of HIV. But it didn’t. There &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; a slight increase in the risk of viral and bacterial infections—but these were “run of the mill infections,” he says. “Had we known in advance, we could very easily have taken care of these with some very simple antibiotics.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This kind of experiment is important, he continues, because it will change the way drugs like canakinumab, currently classified as an immunosuppressant, are categorized. That opens new areas to investigate, he says: “We can actually give high-risk patients this kind of anti-inflammatory without risking immunosuppression. And that’s incredibly useful information for my infectious-disease colleagues.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some researchers believe, however, that to prevent certain inflammatory diseases, such as rheumatoid arthritis or lupus, &lt;em&gt;multiple&lt;/em&gt; inflammatory pathways will need to be blocked to have a large effect. And blocking several of these signaling mechanisms simultaneously, they say, will almost surely suppress the immune system, exposing people to potentially fatal infections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hence scientists’ interests in another possibility that doesn’t include any risk of immunosuppression: resolving inflammation through a recently discovered class of molecules called specialized pro-resolving mediators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;A Super Family of Resolving Molecules&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;firstwords&quot;&gt;Gelman professor&lt;/span&gt; of anaesthesia Charles Serhan has been studying how inflammation ends for 25 years. He realized early on that after the immune system’s soldiers have fought off an invader, the battlefield is littered with bodies: dead cells and scattered debris. The fact that infection has been defeated does not mean that the affected tissue will automatically, passively, return to normal function. There is another process at work, factors that clean up the mess, remove bodies, and repair systems so that the physiological balance within the tissue can be restored. Working with other scientists around the world, he discovered a new class of molecules that actively resolve inflammation. “It turns out that there’s a whole super family of these,” he explains, “and it’s their collapse,” which occurs naturally with aging, that leads to chronic, unresolved immune-system stimulation. “These specialized pro-resolving mediators [SPMs] have been shown in many animal models to reverse inflammation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imagecenter&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://harvardmagazine.com/sites/default/files/inline_images/2019-MayJune/HM_MJ19_ART_Page_50_Image_0002.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Charles Serhan&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;Photograph by Jim Harrison&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SPMs are unusual immune-signaling molecules, in the sense that they are fats (lipid-derived small molecules), not proteins. They can also mute pain. Their precursors—the substances the body needs in order to synthesize these potent resolving compounds—are the essential fatty acids, including the omega-3 fatty acids EPA and DHA, and arachidonic acid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In experiments with animals deficient in SPMs, Serhan has shown that injecting SPMs amplifies the magnitude of the healing response, causing injuries to mend more quickly. He emphasizes that reversing inflammation in this way is not the same as blocking it from occurring in the first place. When inflammatory pathways are turned off, there is always a risk that the immune response will be compromised, and that infection will ensue. The SPMs instead work in concert with the immune response by stimulating macrophages “to clear dead cells, debris, and bacteria,” he says. “Then they bring the system back to homeostasis, and begin to push the buttons to signal tissue regeneration.” (They even stimulate the Tregs that Diane Mathis studies to produce an anti-inflammatory signal called IL-10.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about how over-the-counter anti-inflammatories such as ibuprofen and acetaminophen work. They &lt;em&gt;block&lt;/em&gt; a particular signal. But Serhan discovered that aspirin works differently (and in a multi-faceted way): rather than blocking inflammatory signals, it attenuates them. In addition, it has mild anti-coagulant properties that are beneficial in atherosclerosis. And perhaps most importantly, aspirin stimulates the production of at least two classes of health-promoting SPMs. In work published as this magazine went to press, Serhan and colleagues showed that aspirin stimulates the production of a distinct type of SPM that fights cancer tumors in mice, and another SPM that inhibits cancer tumor formation in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Serhan has recently developed a method for creating blood profiles of individuals that reveal whether they have sufficient levels of these circulating resolving molecules, which include classes of compounds called resolvins, protectins, maresins, and lipoxins. Resolvins, for example, have proven beneficial against periodontitis in rabbits and retinopathy and colitis in mice. Protectins have proven effective in preventing ischemic stroke in rats, and against Alzheimer’s in humans. Lipoxins have attenuated pleurisy and cystic fibrosis in mice. And maresins have accelerated wound-healing in mice, and blocked the perception of pain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More broadly, he has demonstrated the benefits of such SPMs in preventing neurodegeneration, and is beginning to study their use by professional football players, who suffer high rates of tissue injuries. Serhan has shown that SPMs can be used to control the inflammation that occurs when blood flow resumes to tissues that have been deprived of oxygen during surgery. And he has created an inflammation-resolving mouth rinse that has been tested in periodontal disease and shown to be safe. In earlier experiments, he demonstrated that pro-resolving eye drops can be used to control inflammation in the eye, which “naturally makes buckets of this stuff in tears, so you are bathing normally in pro-resolving mediators.” SPMs are also abundant in the brain, he has found. These are places where avoiding acute inflammation is absolutely critical: infections of the brain can be fatal, and in the eye can lead to blindness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colleagues of Serhan’s are using resolvins to control asthma and to stimulate surgical-wound healing. They are also investigating their effects on the microbiome. Earlier animal studies showed that resolvins reduce rheumatoid arthritis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imagecenter&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://harvardmagazine.com/sites/default/files/inline_images/2019-MayJune/HM_Inflam_Chart.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because these compounds have not yet been synthesized as pharmaceuticals, maintaining healthy levels of SPMs is best supported by foods rich in the essential fatty acids EPA, DHA, and arachidonic acid. “There’s a reason they are called ‘essential,’” says Serhan. “You can only get them from your diet.” Fish contains all three, although arachidonic acid is also present in chicken, eggs, and beef, and EPA and DHA can be obtained from certain plant sources and algae. It’s ironic, he points out, that veterinary science has ensured that lab animals (and even pets) in the United States eat better than most people do, because animal food is fortified with omega-3s. Most Americans, he believes, don’t eat enough of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;callout&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;“To treat excessive inflammation...we don’t want to block the inflammatory response. We want to stimulate the resolution pathways.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;However illuminating Serhan’s molecular work has proven, though, the conceptual contribution of his research may be his lasting legacy. “One of things that we are trying to teach people from what we are learning is that we don’t want to knock anything out,” he says. “We want to fine-tune it.” Molecules such as IL-1beta—the target of the CANTOS trial—are important in the innate immune response, he explains. “To treat excessive inflammation, whether it is chronic or the result of an acute tissue injury, we don’t want to block the inflammatory response. We want to stimulate the resolution pathways.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scientific study of inflammation has transformed human understanding of this innate biological response. What once were considered merely symptoms—redness, swelling, fever, and pain—are now implicated as the source of many afflictions. For healing, Serhan foresees, we should also look within.  &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 20:16:47 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>bookofjoe</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Raw and Red-Hot</og:title>
<og:url>https://harvardmagazine.com/2019/05/inflammation-disease-diet</og:url>
<og:description>Could inflammation be the cause of myriad chronic conditions?</og:description>
<og:image>https://harvardmagazine.com/sites/default/files/img/article/0419/HM_MJ19_ART_Page_45_Image_0001.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://harvardmagazine.com/2019/05/inflammation-disease-diet</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Brain signals translated into speech using AI</title>
<link>https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-019-01328-x</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-019-01328-x</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;content position-relative cleared clear mq1200-padded&quot; data-component=&quot;article-container&quot; role=&quot;main&quot;&gt;
&lt;header class=&quot;article-item__header clear cleared pull--both&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article__type&quot;&gt;NEWS
&lt;div class=&quot;ml10 article__date&quot;&gt;&lt;time itemprop=&quot;datePublished&quot;&gt;24 April 2019&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;article-item__teaser-text serif&quot;&gt;Technology could one day be used to help people who can’t talk to communicate.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bordered-container clear cleared pull--both&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;author-affiliations&quot; class=&quot;tab-group text14&quot; role=&quot;tablist&quot; data-test=&quot;author-affiliations&quot; data-tab-group=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cleared&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;author-affiliation-news-0&quot; class=&quot;tab-box js-box-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;author-affiliation-news-0-head&quot; data-track=&quot;click&quot; data-track-label=&quot;view author info&quot; class=&quot;sans-serif strong tab tab-skin&quot; role=&quot;tab&quot; aria-controls=&quot;author-affiliation-news-0-content&quot; data-tooltip=&quot;Show author information&quot;&gt;Giorgia Guglielmi&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;author-affiliation-news-0-content&quot; class=&quot;tab-content pin-right grid grid-12 last&quot; role=&quot;tabpanel&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;pa10&quot; aria-labelledby=&quot;author-affiliation-news-0-head&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;clear cleared&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;align-left&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;sans-serif&quot;&gt;Search for this author in:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;align-left&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article__body serif cleared&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed intensity--high&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;figure__image&quot; alt=&quot;Masahiro Fujita in a hospital bed, with a breathing tube. In front of him is a monitor plastered with Japanese signs.&quot; data-src=&quot;//media.nature.com/w800/magazine-assets/d41586-019-01328-x/d41586-019-01328-x_16672812.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;Masahiro Fujita in a hospital bed, with a breathing tube. In front of him is a monitor plastered with Japanese signs.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.nature.com/w800/magazine-assets/d41586-019-01328-x/d41586-019-01328-x_16672812.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;figure__caption sans-serif&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mr10&quot;&gt;People with paralysing conditions such as motor-neuron disease often rely on technology to help them speak.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Credit: BJ Warnick/Alamy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an effort to provide a voice for people who can’t speak, neuroscientists have designed a device that can transform brain signals into speech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This technology isn’t yet accurate enough for use outside the lab, although it can synthesize whole sentences that are mostly intelligible. Its creators described their speech-decoding device in a study&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-019-01328-x#ref-CR1&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; published on 24 April in &lt;em&gt;Nature&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientists have previously used artificial intelligence to translate single words&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-019-01328-x#ref-CR2&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;,&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-019-01328-x#ref-CR3&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, mostly consisting of one syllable, from brain activity, says Chethan Pandarinath, a neuroengineer at Emory University in Atlanta, Georgia, who co-wrote a &lt;a href=&quot;https://preview-www.nature.com/platform/rh/preview/page/nature/brain-implants-that-let-you-speak-your-mind/16645644?view=fragmentPreview&quot; data-track=&quot;click&quot; data-label=&quot;https://preview-www.nature.com/platform/rh/preview/page/nature/brain-implants-that-let-you-speak-your-mind/16645644?view=fragmentPreview&quot; data-track-category=&quot;body text link&quot;&gt;commentary&lt;/a&gt; accompanying the study. “Making the leap from single syllables to sentences is technically quite challenging and is one of the things that makes the current work so impressive,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Mapping movements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people who have lost the ability to speak communicate using technology that requires them to make tiny movements to control a cursor that selects letters or words on a screen. UK physicist Stephen Hawking, who had motor-neuron disease, was one famous example. He used a speech-generating device activated by a muscle in his cheek, says study leader Edward Chang, a neurosurgeon at the University of California, San Francisco.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because people who use such devices must type out words letter by letter, these devices can be very slow, producing up to ten words per minute, Chang says. Natural spoken speech averages 150 words per minute. “It’s the efficiency of the vocal tract that allows us to do that,” he says. And so Chang and his team decided to model the vocal system when constructing their decoder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed intensity--high&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;figure__image&quot; alt=&quot;A hand holding an array of intracranial electrodes: a palm-sized sheet of plastic studded with metal, attached to wires.&quot; data-src=&quot;//media.nature.com/w800/magazine-assets/d41586-019-01328-x/d41586-019-01328-x_16672810.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;A hand holding an array of intracranial electrodes: a palm-sized sheet of plastic studded with metal, attached to wires.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.nature.com/w800/magazine-assets/d41586-019-01328-x/d41586-019-01328-x_16672810.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;figure__caption sans-serif&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mr10&quot;&gt;Researchers implanted electrodes similar to these in participants’ skulls to record their brain signals.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Credit: UCSF&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers worked with five people who had electrodes implanted on the surface of their brains as part of epilepsy treatment. First, the team recorded brain activity as the participants read hundreds of sentences aloud. Then, Chang and his colleagues combined these recordings with data from previous experiments that determined how movements of the tongue, lips, jaw and larynx created sound.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team trained a deep-learning algorithm on these data, and then incorporated the program into their decoder. The device transforms brain signals into estimated movements of the vocal tract, and turns these movements into synthetic speech. People who listened to 101 synthesized sentences could understand 70% of the words on average, Chang says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;c-podcast sans-serif&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed intensity--high&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;c-podcast__container&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;c-podcast__audio-caption&quot;&gt;Two examples of a participant reading a sentence, followed by the synthesized version of the sentence generated from their brain activity.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;c-podcast__download-transcript text14&quot;&gt;&lt;a download=&quot;nature-24 April 2019-MO0&quot; class=&quot;c-podcast__download&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/magazine-assets/d41586-019-01328-x/d41586-019-01328-x_16672814.wav&quot; data-track=&quot;click&quot; data-track-category=&quot;magazine podcast&quot; data-track-action=&quot;download&quot; data-track-label=&quot;MP3 download&quot;&gt;Download MP3&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;c-podcast__copyright text-gray-light&quot;&gt;Credit: Chang lab, UCSF Dept. of Neurosurgery&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In another experiment, the researchers asked one participant to read sentences aloud and then to mime the same sentences by moving their mouth without producing sound. The sentences synthesized in this test were of lower quality than those created from audible speech, Chang says, but the results are still encouraging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Intelligible future&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speech created by mapping brain activity to movements of the vocal tract and translating them to sound is more easily understood than that produced by mapping brain activity directly to sound, says Stephanie Riès, a neuroscientist at San Diego State University in California.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it’s unclear whether the new speech decoder would work with words that people only think, says Amy Orsborn, a neural engineer at the University of Washington in Seattle. “The paper does a really good job of showing that this works for mimed speech,” she says. “But how would this work when someone’s not moving their mouth?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marc Slutzky, a neurologist at Northwestern University in Chicago, Illinois, agrees and says that the decoder’s performance leaves room for improvement. He notes that listeners identified the synthesized speech by selecting words from a set of choices; as the number of choices increased, people had more trouble understanding the words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study “is a really important step, but there’s still a long way to go before synthesized speech is easily intelligible”, Slutzky says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;emphasis&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/d41586-019-01328-x&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article__endnote&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See the related News &amp;amp; Views article, '&lt;a href=&quot;https://preview-www.nature.com/platform/rh/preview/page/nature/brain-implants-that-let-you-speak-your-mind/16645644?view=fragmentPreview&quot; data-track=&quot;click&quot; data-label=&quot;https://preview-www.nature.com/platform/rh/preview/page/nature/brain-implants-that-let-you-speak-your-mind/16645644?view=fragmentPreview&quot; data-track-category=&quot;body text link&quot;&gt;Brain implants that let you speak your mind&lt;/a&gt;'.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;references&quot; class=&quot;references&quot; data-toggle=&quot;anchor-links-section&quot; data-label=&quot;References&quot; data-concertina=&quot;true&quot;&gt;
&lt;section aria-labelledby=&quot;Bib1&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;serif article-section js-article-section cleared clear&quot; id=&quot;Bib1-section&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;js-section-title section-title strong position-relative tighten-line-height background-gray-light pt20 pb6 pl0 pr20 standard-space-below small-space-above mq640-pt10 mq640-pb10 mq640-pl20 mq640-mt0 mq640-ml-20 mq640-mr-20 extend-left&quot; id=&quot;Bib1&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;pl20 mq875-pl0 js-collapsible-section&quot; id=&quot;Bib1-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div data-container-section=&quot;references&quot;&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;clean-list ma0 standard-space-below indented-list&quot; data-test=&quot;references-list&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;small-space-below border-gray-medium border-bottom-1 position-relative js-ref-item&quot; itemprop=&quot;citation&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Article&quot; data-test=&quot;citation&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;indented-counter serif h2 tighten-line-height text-right position-absolute grade-c-hide&quot;&gt;1.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;tiny-space-below&quot; id=&quot;ref-CR1&quot;&gt;Anumanchipalli, G. K., Chartier, J. &amp;amp; Chang, E. F. &lt;em&gt;Nature&lt;/em&gt; https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-019-1119-1 (2019).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;small-space-below border-gray-medium border-bottom-1 position-relative js-ref-item&quot; itemprop=&quot;citation&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Article&quot; data-test=&quot;citation&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;indented-counter serif h2 tighten-line-height text-right position-absolute grade-c-hide&quot;&gt;2.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;tiny-space-below&quot; id=&quot;ref-CR2&quot;&gt;Akbari, H. &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Sci. Rep.&lt;/em&gt; https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-018-37359-z (2019).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;small-space-below border-gray-medium border-bottom-1 position-relative js-ref-item&quot; itemprop=&quot;citation&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Article&quot; data-test=&quot;citation&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;indented-counter serif h2 tighten-line-height text-right position-absolute grade-c-hide&quot;&gt;3.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;tiny-space-below&quot; id=&quot;ref-CR3&quot;&gt;Angrick, M. &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;J. Neural Eng&lt;/em&gt;. https://doi.org/10.1088/1741-2552/ab0c59 (2019).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;hide-print text-right&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-019-01328-x-references.ris&quot; class=&quot;text14 sans-serif strong&quot; data-track=&quot;click&quot; data-track-action=&quot;download citation references&quot; data-track-category=&quot;article body&quot; data-track-label=&quot;link&quot;&gt;Download references&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;c-latest-content mt40 hide-print&quot; data-simple-tab=&quot;&quot; data-tab-group=&quot;&quot; data-component-id=&quot;latest-news&quot; data-track=&quot;in-view&quot; data-track-action=&quot;in-view&quot; data-track-category=&quot;latest content&quot; data-track-label=&quot;visible&quot;&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;latest-content&quot; role=&quot;tablist&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;serif strong&quot;&gt;Latest on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cleared&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;latest-content-0&quot; class=&quot;c-latest-content__container&quot; data-container=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;latest-content-0-head&quot; class=&quot;c-latest-content__category c-latest-content__switch serif&quot; data-switch=&quot;&quot; role=&quot;tab&quot; aria-controls=&quot;latest-content-0-content&quot; data-track=&quot;click&quot; data-track-label=&quot;latest tag (rank:0)&quot;&gt;Neuroscience&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;nature-briefing nature-briefing--article cleared hide-print&quot; data-component-id=&quot;nature-briefing-box&quot; data-track=&quot;in-view&quot; data-track-action=&quot;in-view&quot; data-track-category=&quot;nature briefing&quot; data-track-label=&quot;box visible&quot;&gt;
&lt;header class=&quot;nature-briefing__header&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;Nature Briefing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/header&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;pa10 pt20&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;serif nature-briefing__slogan mr30&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sign up for the daily &lt;span class=&quot;emphasis&quot;&gt;Nature Briefing&lt;/span&gt; email newsletter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;sans-serif nature-briefing__standfirst mr30&quot;&gt;Stay up to date with what matters in science and why, handpicked from &lt;span class=&quot;emphasis&quot;&gt;Nature&lt;/span&gt; and other publications worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cleared&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;nature-briefing__link&quot; data-track-category=&quot;nature briefing&quot; data-track=&quot;click&quot; data-track-label=&quot;nature briefing article link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/briefing/signup/&quot;&gt;Sign Up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;article__aside align-right&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;related-content shrink--aside hide-print&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;aside__title sans-serif&quot;&gt;Related Articles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;div-gpt-ad-right-2&quot; class=&quot;div-gpt-ad advert medium-rectangle js-ad text-center hide-print grade-c-hide&quot; data-gpt-unitpath=&quot;/285/nature.com/article&quot; data-gpt-sizes=&quot;300x250&quot; data-gpt-targeting=&quot;pos=right;artid=/articles/d41586-019-01328-x;path=/articles/d41586-019-01328-x&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pubads.g.doubleclick.net/gampad/jump?iu=/285/nature.com/article&amp;amp;sz=300x250&amp;amp;c=-1013980451&amp;amp;t=pos%3Dright%26artid%3D/articles/d41586-019-01328-x&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-test=&quot;gpt-advert-fallback-img&quot; src=&quot;https://pubads.g.doubleclick.net/gampad/ad?iu=/285/nature.com/article&amp;amp;sz=300x250&amp;amp;c=-1013980451&amp;amp;t=pos%3Dright%26artid%3D/articles/d41586-019-01328-x&quot; alt=&quot;Advertisement&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;250&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 17:43:19 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Balgair</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-019-01328-x</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Brain signals translated into speech using artificial intelligence</og:title>
<og:description>Technology could one day be used to provide a voice for people who can’t talk.</og:description>
<og:image>https://media.nature.com/lw1024/magazine-assets/d41586-019-01328-x/d41586-019-01328-x_16672806.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-019-01328-x</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The &amp;#039;Dark Ages&amp;#039; Weren&amp;#039;t as Dark as We Thought</title>
<link>https://lithub.com/the-dark-ages-werent-as-dark-as-we-thought/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://lithub.com/the-dark-ages-werent-as-dark-as-we-thought/</guid>
<description>&lt;span itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;There can be few more damning or more useless terms than “the Dark Ages.” They sound fun in an orcs‐and‐elves sort of way and suggest a very low benchmark from which we have since, as a race, raised ourselves up into the light—with the present day using as its soundtrack the last movement of Beethoven’s Ninth. But the damage the term does is immense. A simple little mental test is just to quickly imagine a European scene from that era. Now: was the sun shining? Of course not. The default way of thinking about the long, complex era that lasted from the final decades of the Roman Empire to somewhere around the Battle of Hastings is to assume it all looked like the cover of a heavy metal album.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One problem is that the older the period the more chances there are for its material production to be destroyed. Across Lotharingia [ed. note: one of three filial kingdoms born of the Carolingian Empire]  there has been century after century of rebuilding (with the re‐use of every available piece of old dressed stone) with most evidence of earlier churches and palaces removed in the process. In practical terms one cannot imagine that the vast, humorless bulk of Cologne Cathedral is merely the latest in a series stretching back to a Roman temple. Many of the great religious buildings of the Rhine have a display table showing somewhat conjectural models of their ancient predecessors, usually starting with a patronizing little wooden block, looking something like a skew‐whiff Wendy-house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So great is the weight of “the Dark Ages” on our shoulders that it is almost impossible not to think of the makers of this wonky church slithering about on the mud floor cursing the way the roof was leaking and how nobody could design a door that shut properly, resigned to the occasional fiasco when the walls would simply fall in on the gurning, fur‐clad, battle‐axe‐wielding communicants. In practice, these now non‐existent buildings would have been extremely beautiful—drawing on Roman and Byzantine models, and stuffed with all kinds of wonderful stuff from the Roman Empire which now no longer exists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the related problem suffered by “the Dark Ages”—our towns often occupy exactly the same sites as they did then (the same river crossing, the same harbor) and are built on top of them, but there have been simply innumerable points at which older material has been destroyed. There is probably some rough mathematical calculation about how each passing century lowers your chance of anything much surviving at all. The famous fat boy of 1666—who was meant to be watching the baker’s oven, but instead gorged on pies, fell asleep and as a result burned down London—is only one of an elite group who caused mayhem through their momentary inattention over the centuries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;insert-post-ads&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Article continues after advertisement&lt;/span&gt;&lt;!-- /76722702/in_article_banner_2 --&gt;&amp;#13;
&lt;div id=&quot;div-gpt-ad-1482941823113-0&quot;&gt;&amp;#13;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With every household routinely handling flames in wooden surroundings it is unsurprising that so many towns would often find themselves having to start again from scratch. We know far more about more recent horrors—for example, the gunpowder accident that destroyed much of Delft in 1654—but any 24‐hour period over the centuries was always fraught with some fumble‐fingered disaster somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;The true “dark age,” of course, was the early 1940s when, simply as a side effect of industrial killing, great swathes of the past disappeared.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The unrelenting impact of warfare has of course done far more damage, wrecking town after town. Any breakdown in order or lunge for supremacy ends up with further pyres of the material past. Simply looking at recent disasters, many thousands of ancient records, treasures, histories, valued for centuries by custodians, were destroyed in the 1870 Siege of Strasbourg and the 1914 destruction of much of the Catholic University of Leuven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The true “dark age,” of course, was the early 1940s when, simply as a side effect of industrial killing, great swathes of the past disappeared. One small yet major example—the extraordinary series of paintings of the visions of Hildegard of Bingen, made in the 1170s either by the saint herself or under her supervision, disappeared in the general catastrophe that unfolded in Dresden in early 1945. We only know what they looked like (except from black‐and‐white photos) through accurate and beautiful copies painted by a group of nuns, by sheer chance, in the 1930s. So these frail little works of disturbing genius survived nearly eight centuries before succumbing, and exist today only through the most ancient form of devotional copying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an over‐elaborate way of saying that in as much as the era after the Roman Empire is “dark” it is because it has been overlaid by many centuries of further things happening—and I have talked only about human agency rather than the terrors of mold, mice, lightning and damp. Our own “library” at home suffered catastrophic loss from a house‐rabbit called Dusty who in his short life ate the spines of innumerable books. My copy of Hermann Hesse’s &lt;em&gt;Narcissus and Goldmund&lt;/em&gt; is cherished, partly because I have owned it for so long, but also because of its memorial teeth marks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When was the very last beautiful Roman fabric so sun‐rotted that it was chucked away? And that is as nothing compared to the almost totally successful attempts during the early Christian centuries in Europe to erase all trace of native paganism. This last issue is often overlooked. At the back of our minds when thinking about the centuries when the Roman Empire mutated into medieval Europe we are unconsciously taking on the spurious guise of specific communities. We are happy to read about Charlemagne destroying the Avar Empire and taking all its gold because at some level we emotionally sneak ourselves into Charlemagne’s baggage‐train. But the Avars ruled Central Europe for over two centuries, and it is not a given that their civilization had no worth and did not represent a future we would have flourished in.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;insert-post-ads&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Article continues after advertisement&lt;/span&gt;&lt;!-- /76722702/in_article_banner_3 --&gt;&amp;#13;
&lt;div id=&quot;div-gpt-ad-1530020181920-0&quot;&gt;&amp;#13;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or earlier, there are the Alemanni in what is now south‐west Germany and Alsace (and after whom the French call Germany Allemagne) who were broken by the Frankish ruler Clovis. Of course, we are the heirs of Christianity, but only in a passive, non‐contributive way—to see ourselves on one specific side in these ancient contests is awkward. I might hiss at the antics of the Saxons and Vikings, but as someone part English and part Irish I am much more likely to have their genes than Frankish ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These issues become vivid in the town of Tournai—for centuries a French‐ruled enclave squeezed between the County of Flanders and the County of Hainaut and now part of Belgium, a classic crossroads through which every army has marched, from the legionaries of the Roman Empire to Allied troops in 1944. I may as well say here that Tournai is a fantastic historical palimpsest and somewhere that always puts a spring in my step. I once found myself changing trains there late at night and realizing that I had just enough time to haul my bag up the road through the freezing dark to look in renewed wonder at the vast, somber drum—like a stonebuilt gasometer—of the Henry VIII Tower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this current context, however, what makes Tournai so remarkable is the discovery during routine repairs to the Hospice of St Brice in the 1650s of the tomb of Childeric I. This accidental find catapulted everything back some 250 years before Charlemagne, to the century after the Western Roman Empire had collapsed, a world which must have still been densely Roman in its appearance, probably with much smaller populations in towns and more limited trade. Childeric’s son, Clovis I, was baptized, united the Frankish tribes and founded the Merovingian dynasty which lasted until Charlemagne’s dad put the last of them into a monastery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;It was downhill for the hoard from then on.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The management of Childeric’s tomb has not exactly been a curatorial model. It started well as by sheer good luck Tournai was then part of the Spanish Netherlands under the benign and intelligent leadership of Archduke Leopold Wilhelm, who as part of his vast expenditure on art objects commissioned a superb book on the tomb from Jean‐Jacques Chifflet, an antiquarian from the Spanish‐ruled Franche‐Comté. This has immaculate pictures of the heaps of extraordinary stuff Childeric was buried with—gold objects of great variety and beauty from a bull’s head to coins, buckles, a crystal globe, seal‐rings and intricate pieces of cloisonné. It was downhill for the hoard from then on. Leopold Wilhelm took everything back to Vienna when he retired and left it to his nephew the Emperor Leopold I. He gave it to Louis XIV as a present but, in one of the many instances where Louis is so disappointing, he took no interest in the gifts and simply stored them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They survived the Revolution but were stolen in 1831 and dispersed or melted down. The hoard’s great aesthetic intervention came from its including dozens of small gold bees (or possibly cicadas), which must have decorated some object which had since rotted away, perhaps a cloak. In his search for an appropriate new symbol for his dynasty (the ancient fleur‐de‐lys being patently unacceptable to a new era) Napoleon decided to make these bees the imperial motif, scattering them on everything from coats of arms to Josephine’s slippers. They cluster all over the decorations of the French Empire and it is one of the sadder aspects of Napoleon’s defeat and exile that they disappear from the decorative arts until their rather wan revival under his nephew Napoleon III.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What remains in Tournai now however (aside from some reproduction bees) is a too‐good‐to‐be true archaeological museum which lays out everything we can still know about the huge scale of Childeric’s tomb and several associated burials. As his son Clovis turned Christian this was the last of the fabulous, full‐blown pagan Frankish affairs, with 21 cavalry horses buried nearby in an associated mound and what was clearly a sprawling sacred space with Childeric’s body at its center. An aristocratic woman buried nearby slightly later had objects such as scissors, amber and a wine‐strainer which linked her to trade across Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, the more time spent looking at these shield‐bosses, necklaces and pins (and not least a debonair and alarming scramasax—a wonderful word for a long knife), the more clear it becomes that this was a highly sophisticated, confident civilization—which just happened to exist a very long time ago and whose achievements were about to be completely disregarded by the new Christian regime of Clovis, who moved his capital from Tournai to Paris. The process by which Childeric’s tomb became forgotten cannot be pieced together as his dynastic significance lasted so long. Somehow, the King of the Salian Franks and his favorite horses, his crystal globe, bees, scramasax and all sank into oblivion, eventually disappearing completely under church buildings, until being summoned back to the surface nearly twelve hundred years later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;__________________________________&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;112200&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://lithub.com/the-dark-ages-werent-as-dark-as-we-thought/lotharingia/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://s26162.pcdn.co/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/lotharingia.jpg&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;350,525&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;lotharingia&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://s26162.pcdn.co/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/lotharingia-200x300.jpg&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://s26162.pcdn.co/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/lotharingia.jpg&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-112200 size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://s26162.pcdn.co/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/lotharingia-200x300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; srcset=&quot;https://s26162.pcdn.co/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/lotharingia-200x300.jpg 200w, https://s26162.pcdn.co/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/lotharingia.jpg 350w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Excerpted from&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://us.macmillan.com/books/9780374192181&quot; class=&quot;external&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Lotharingia: A Personal History of Europe’s Lost Country&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; by Simon Winder. Published by Farrar, Straus and Giroux on April 23, 2019. Copyright © 2019 by Simon Winder. All rights reserved.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;ctx-article-root&quot;&gt;&lt;!-- --&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 17:08:33 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kjaleshire</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>The ‘Dark Ages’ Weren’t As Dark As We Thought</og:title>
<og:url>https://lithub.com/the-dark-ages-werent-as-dark-as-we-thought/</og:url>
<og:description>There can be few more damning or more useless terms than “the Dark Ages.” They sound fun in an orcs‐and‐elves sort of way and suggest a very low benchmark from which we have since, as a…</og:description>
<og:image>https://s26162.pcdn.co/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/middle-ages.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://lithub.com/the-dark-ages-werent-as-dark-as-we-thought/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>New version of Stripe Checkout</title>
<link>https://stripe.com/docs/payments/checkout</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://stripe.com/docs/payments/checkout</guid>
<description>&lt;header readability=&quot;5.52&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The quickest way to build beautiful, conversion-optimized payment forms, hosted on Stripe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;important neutral&quot; readability=&quot;3.3793103448276&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This overview is for the new version of Stripe Checkout. For the legacy version of Checkout, see &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/docs/checkout&quot;&gt;Checkout Reference&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/header&gt;&lt;section readability=&quot;10.108506363027&quot;&gt;&lt;aside class=&quot;note&quot; readability=&quot;6.6666666666667&quot;&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;migrating&quot;&gt;Migrating?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/docs/checkout&quot;&gt;legacy version&lt;/a&gt; of Checkout, read the &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/docs/payments/checkout/migration&quot;&gt;Migration Guide&lt;/a&gt; for how to upgrade your integration to use the new version of Checkout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;beta-user&quot;&gt;Beta user?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are currently on a beta of the new version of Checkout, read the &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/docs/payments/checkout/migration-from-beta&quot;&gt;Beta Migration Guide&lt;/a&gt; to upgrade to the latest version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Start accepting payments with just a few lines of code. Checkout is a smart payment page that works seamlessly across devices and is designed to increase your conversion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Checkout includes support for:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Payment methods:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;credit and debit cards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apple Pay (with no additional setup required)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Payment types:&lt;/strong&gt; one-time and recurring payments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Payment authentication:&lt;/strong&gt; dynamic &lt;span class=&quot;tooltip-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;tooltip-content&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/docs/payments/3d-secure&quot;&gt;3D Secure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;key-popover&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;3D Secure&lt;/em&gt; provides an additional layer of authentication for credit card transactions that protects merchants from liability for fraudulent card payments. During a transaction that incorporates the 3D Secure authorization process, the customer is prompted to supply a separate password or code to validate their purchase.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; (ready for &lt;span class=&quot;tooltip-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;tooltip-content&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/docs/strong-customer-authentication&quot;&gt;Strong Customer Authentication&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;key-popover&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Strong Customer Authentication&lt;/em&gt; (SCA) is a new regulatory requirement coming into effect on September 14, 2019 which will impact many European online payments. It requires customers to use two-factor authentication like 3D Secure to verify their purchase.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Localization:&lt;/strong&gt; localized for &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.stripe.com/questions/supported-languages-for-stripe-checkout&quot;&gt;14 languages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Email receipts:&lt;/strong&gt; automatically send &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/docs/receipts&quot;&gt;email receipts&lt;/a&gt; to your customers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Checkout is currently in active development. Visit our &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/docs/payments/checkout#checkout-roadmap&quot;&gt;Roadmap&lt;/a&gt; to see what’s coming up next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/img/docs/checkout/overview.gif&quot; class=&quot;zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://stripe.com/img/docs/checkout/overview.gif&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section readability=&quot;6.3231132075472&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;see-how&quot;&gt;See how it works&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can try out Checkout now by clicking the Preview Checkout button below. This sample integration is running in test mode, which means that it won’t create a real charge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use one of Stripe’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/docs/testing&quot;&gt;test card numbers&lt;/a&gt; with any three-digit CVC code and an expiration date in the future to try it out:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;&lt;button id=&quot;preview-button&quot; type=&quot;submit&quot;&gt;Preview Checkout&lt;/button&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section readability=&quot;4.4545454545455&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;choose-your-integration-path&quot;&gt;Choose your integration path&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two ways to integrate with the new version of Checkout. Both integrations support core features, with minor differences. Review the information below to determine which one works best for your business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;comparison-table&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;comparison-table-col&quot;&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;feature-list&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Add products and plans in the Dashboard, then integrate with a client-side snippet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Cannot associate payments with existing &lt;span class=&quot;tooltip-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;tooltip-content&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/docs/api/customers&quot;&gt;Customers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;key-popover&quot;&gt;Stripe &lt;em&gt;Customer&lt;/em&gt; objects allow you to perform recurring charges, and to track multiple charges, that are associated with the same customer.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Cannot use separate authorization and capture for card payments&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;No &lt;span class=&quot;tooltip-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;tooltip-content&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/docs/connect&quot;&gt;Connect&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;key-popover&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Connect&lt;/em&gt; is Stripe’s solution for any business that needs to process payments and pay out to sellers and service providers.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; support&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;comparison-table-col&quot;&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;feature-list&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Pass in one-time payment information or subscription data from your server&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Can associate one-time payments with existing Customers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Can use &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/docs/payments/checkout/server#separate-auth-capture&quot;&gt;separate authorization and capture&lt;/a&gt; for card payments&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Works with Connect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section readability=&quot;8.6569872958258&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;supported-languages&quot;&gt;Supported languages&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By default, Checkout detects the locale of the customer’s browser and displays a translated version of the page in their language if it is &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.stripe.com/questions/supported-languages-for-stripe-checkout&quot;&gt;supported&lt;/a&gt;. You can also provide a specific locale for Checkout to use instead via the &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/docs/stripe-js/reference#stripe-redirect-to-checkout&quot;&gt;client&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/docs/api/checkout/sessions/create#create_checkout_session-locale&quot;&gt;server&lt;/a&gt; integrations. Checkout also uses the locale to format numbers and currencies. For example, when selling a product whose price is set in EUR with the locale set to auto, a browser configured to use English (en) would see €25.00 while one configured for German (de) would see 25,00 €.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;checkout-roadmap&quot;&gt;Checkout roadmap&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the coming months, we plan to add more features to Stripe Checkout. Here are some of the features we’re considering:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Support for Google Pay (in addition to Apple Pay, which is already supported)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for coupons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for iDEAL, SEPA Debit, and other European payment methods, with the most relevant payment methods surfaced to the customer based on their country&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shipping address support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Better support for saving customer details and reusing saved payment methods&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to pre-fill more customer details, such as contact and shipping information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;collect-email-guide&quot; id=&quot;checkout-updates&quot; readability=&quot;1.8947368421053&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;mask-container container-lg&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;collect-email-partial&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;intro-copy column&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;

&lt;form class=&quot;collect-form&quot; action=&quot;https://stripemail.createsend.com/t/d/s/shduru/&quot; readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;email-field&quot; required=&quot;required&quot; type=&quot;email&quot; name=&quot;cm-shduru-shduru&quot; placeholder=&quot;Email&quot; value=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;button class=&quot;submit-button&quot; type=&quot;submit&quot;&gt;Get updates&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;collect-error email&quot;&gt;Please enter a valid email address.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;collect-error connection&quot;&gt;You might have had an internet hiccup. Try again?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;collect-success column&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;icon&quot; src=&quot;https://stripe.com/img/v3/common/success.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Green checkmark&quot;/&gt;&lt;h3 class=&quot;common-BodyTitle&quot;&gt;Thank you!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;common-BodyText&quot;&gt;Check your inbox to confirm your email address. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:checkout-feedback@stripe.com&quot;&gt;let us know&lt;/a&gt; how you would like to use Checkout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section/&gt;&lt;footer readability=&quot;9.7595907928389&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 data-no-anchor=&quot;&quot;&gt;Questions?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're always happy to help with code or other questions you might have! &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/docs/payments/checkout#&quot; id=&quot;search-link&quot; class=&quot;search-link&quot;&gt;Search&lt;/a&gt; our documentation, &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.stripe.com/contact&quot;&gt;contact support&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/contact/sales&quot;&gt;connect with our sales team&lt;/a&gt;. You can also chat live with other developers in &lt;a href=&quot;irc://irc.freenode.net/stripe&quot;&gt;#stripe&lt;/a&gt; on freenode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-csat-step=&quot;poll&quot; class=&quot;csat-widget&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;csat-widget-text&quot;&gt;Was this page helpful?&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span data-csat-poll=&quot;yes&quot; class=&quot;csat-button csat-button-yes common-Button&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span data-csat-poll=&quot;no&quot; class=&quot;csat-button csat-button-no common-Button&quot;&gt;No&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-csat-step=&quot;input&quot; class=&quot;csat-widget&quot;&gt;&lt;input id=&quot;csat-input-text&quot; placeholder=&quot;Feedback about this page?&quot; class=&quot;common-Input&quot;/&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;csat-input-submit&quot; class=&quot;csat-button common-Link&quot;&gt;Send&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-csat-step=&quot;reply&quot; class=&quot;csat-widget&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;csat-reply-main&quot;&gt;Thank you for helping improve Stripe's documentation.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;csat-reply-extended&quot;&gt;If you need help or have any questions, please consider &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.stripe.com/email&quot;&gt;contacting support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/footer&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 15:51:55 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dfabulich</dc:creator>
<og:title>Checkout Overview | Stripe Checkout</og:title>
<og:url>https://stripe.com/docs/payments/checkout</og:url>
<og:description>Online payment processing for internet businesses. Stripe is a suite of payment APIs that powers commerce for businesses of all sizes.</og:description>
<og:image>https://stripe.com/img/v3/home/social.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://stripe.com/docs/payments/checkout</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: Applying the Unix philosophy to neural networks</title>
<link>https://github.com/cloudkj/layer</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/cloudkj/layer</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;Box-body&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content p-5&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;layer&lt;/code&gt; is a program for doing neural network inference the Unix way. Many modern neural network operations can be represented as sequential, unidirectional streams of data processed by pipelines of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Filter_(software)&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;filters&lt;/a&gt;. The computations at each layer in these neural networks are equivalent to an invocation of the &lt;code&gt;layer&lt;/code&gt; program, and multiple invocations can be chained together to represent the entirety of such networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, performing inference on a neural network with two fully-connected layers might look something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;cat input | layer full -w w.1 --input-shape=2 -f tanh | layer full -w w.2 --input-shape=3 -f sigmoid
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;layer&lt;/code&gt; applies the Unix philosophy to neural network inference. Each type of a neural network layer is a distinct subcommand. Simple text streams of delimited numeric values serve as the interface between different layers of a neural network. Each invocation of &lt;code&gt;layer&lt;/code&gt; does one thing: it feeds the numeric input values forward through an instantiation of a neural network layer, then emits the resulting output numeric values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example: a convolutional neural network for &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CIFAR-10&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;CIFAR-10&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
$ cat cifar10_x.csv \
    &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; layer convolutional -w w0.csv -b b0.csv --input-shape=32,32,3  --filter-shape=3,3 --num-filters=32 -f relu \
    &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; layer convolutional -w w1.csv -b b1.csv --input-shape=30,30,32 --filter-shape=3,3 --num-filters=32 -f relu \
    &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; layer pooling --input-shape=28,28,32 --filter-shape=2,2 --stride=2 -f max
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example: a multi-layer perceptron for XOR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
$ &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; Fully connected layer with three neurons&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;-2.35546875,-2.38671875,3.63671875,3.521484375,-2.255859375,-2.732421875&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; layer1.weights
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;0.7958984375,0.291259765625,1.099609375&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; layer1.biases

$ &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; Fully connected layer with one neuron&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;-5.0625,-3.515625,-5.0625&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; layer2.weights
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;1.74609375&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; layer2.biases

$ &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; Compute XOR for all possible binary inputs&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; -e &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;0,0\n0,1\n1,0\n1,1&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; \
    &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; layer full -w layer1.weights -b layer1.biases --input-shape=2 -f tanh \
    &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; layer full -w layer2.weights -b layer2.biases --input-shape=3 -f sigmoid
0.00129012749948779
0.99147053740106
0.991243357927591
0.0111237568184365
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Requirements: BLAS 3.6.0+&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cloudkj/layer/releases&quot;&gt;release&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install BLAS 3.6.0+&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;On Debian-based systems: &lt;code&gt;apt-get install -y libblas3&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On RPM-based system: &lt;code&gt;yum install -y blas&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On macOS 10.3+, BLAS is pre-installed as part of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/documentation/accelerate/blas&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Accelerate framework&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ol start=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Unzip the release and run &lt;code&gt;[sudo] ./install.sh&lt;/code&gt;, or manually relocate the binaries to the path of your choice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h2&gt;About&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;layer&lt;/code&gt; is currently implemented as a proof-of-concept and supports a limited number of neural network layer types. The types of layers are currently limited to feed-forward layers that can be modeled as sequential, unidirectional pipelines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Input values, weights and biases for parameterized layers, and output values are all read and written in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Row-_and_column-major_order&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;row-major order&lt;/a&gt;, based on the shape parameters specified for each layer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;layer&lt;/code&gt; is implemented in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.call-cc.org/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;CHICKEN Scheme&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copyright © 2018-2019&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 14:46:12 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>cloudkj</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars1.githubusercontent.com/u/227462?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>cloudkj/layer</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/cloudkj/layer</og:url>
<og:description>Neural network inference the Unix way. Contribute to cloudkj/layer development by creating an account on GitHub.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/cloudkj/layer</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Private Key Extraction from Qualcomm Hardware-Backed Keystores</title>
<link>https://www.nccgroup.trust/us/our-research/private-key-extraction-qualcomm-keystore/?research=Technical+advisories</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nccgroup.trust/us/our-research/private-key-extraction-qualcomm-keystore/?research=Technical+advisories</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nccgroup.trust/us/our-research/private-key-extraction-qualcomm-keystore/?research=Technical+advisories&quot;&gt;https://www.nccgroup.trust/us/our-research/private-key-extraction-qualcomm-keystore/?research=Technical+advisories&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19738394&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19738394&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 288&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 56&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 13:59:50 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>griffinmb</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nccgroup.trust/us/our-research/private-key-extraction-qualcomm-keystore/?research=Technical+advisories</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>OpenBSD 6.5</title>
<link>http://openbsd.org/65.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://openbsd.org/65.html</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;title&gt;OpenBSD 6.5&lt;/title&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;Content-Type&quot; content=&quot;text/html; charset=utf-8&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;description&quot; content=&quot;OpenBSD 6.5&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;copyright&quot; content=&quot;This document copyright 2019 by OpenBSD.&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;viewport&quot; content=&quot;width=device-width, initial-scale=1&quot; /&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot; href=&quot;openbsd.css&quot; /&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;canonical&quot; href=&quot;https://www.openbsd.org/65.html&quot; /&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body bgcolor=&quot;#FFFFFF&quot; text=&quot;#000000&quot; link=&quot;#24248E&quot; id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;86.304364268966&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openbsd.org/images/Puffystock.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img align=&quot;left&quot; width=&quot;227&quot; height=&quot;343&quot; hspace=&quot;24&quot; src=&quot;https://www.openbsd.org/images/Puffystock-s.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Released May 1, 2019&lt;br /&gt;Copyright 1997-2019, Theo de Raadt.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Artwork by Hans Tseng, Efrain Farias, and Natasha Allegri.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;0.421875&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;See the information on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openbsd.org/ftp.html&quot;&gt;the FTP page&lt;/a&gt; for a list of mirror machines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to the &lt;span&gt;pub/OpenBSD/6.5/&lt;/span&gt; directory on one of the mirror sites.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have a look at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openbsd.org/errata65.html&quot;&gt;the 6.5 errata page&lt;/a&gt; for a list of bugs and workarounds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;See a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openbsd.org/plus65.html&quot;&gt;detailed log of changes&lt;/a&gt; between the 6.4 and 6.5 releases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;3.4730538922156&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/signify.1&quot;&gt;signify(1)&lt;/a&gt; pubkeys for this release:
&lt;table cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.2820512820513&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.54545454545455&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;openbsd-65-base.pub:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ftp.openbsd.org/pub/OpenBSD/6.5/openbsd-65-base.pub&quot;&gt;RWSZaRmt1LEQT9CtPygf9CvONu8kYPTlVEJdysNoUR62/NkeWgdkc3zY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;openbsd-65-fw.pub:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;RWQYdGVtTv5IvpH2c+TLQAC4iV7RjoGZ/v75q8MCuC9Mca7nFVCXRefy&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;openbsd-65-pkg.pub:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;RWS5D4+188RI6jULDOFzga0Cm1zrXYUAHT6xu0mLrZidbn6xrMB5aZeR&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;openbsd-65-syspatch.pub:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;RWT8U2yd3Aq5DnetILjmSoCQxmyt3VqfGS7GBh19oh4Xre4ywc31PEpw&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;All applicable copyrights and credits are in the src.tar.gz, sys.tar.gz, xenocara.tar.gz, ports.tar.gz files, or in the files fetched via ports.tar.gz.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;new&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;What's New&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a partial list of new features and systems included in OpenBSD 6.5. For a comprehensive list, see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openbsd.org/plus65.html&quot;&gt;changelog&lt;/a&gt; leading to 6.5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Improved hardware support, including:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/clang.1&quot;&gt;clang(1)&lt;/a&gt; is now provided on mips64.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The default linker has been switched from the binutils bfd-based linker to lld on amd64 and i386.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;octeon: Now the system automatically detects the number of available cores. However, manual setting of the numcores, or coremask, boot parameter is still needed to enable secondary cores.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;octeon: It is now possible to use the root disk's DUID as the value of the rootdev boot parameter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/octeon/octgpio.4&quot;&gt;octgpio(4)&lt;/a&gt; driver for the OCTEON GPIO controller.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/pvclock.4&quot;&gt;pvclock(4)&lt;/a&gt; driver for KVM paravirtual clock.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/ixl.4&quot;&gt;ixl(4)&lt;/a&gt; driver for Intel Ethernet 700 series controller devices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/abcrtc.4&quot;&gt;abcrtc(4)&lt;/a&gt; driver for Abracon AB1805 real-time clock.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/imxsrc.4&quot;&gt;imxsrc(4)&lt;/a&gt; driver for i.MX system reset controller.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/uxrcom.4&quot;&gt;uxrcom(4)&lt;/a&gt; driver for Exar XR21V1410 USB serial adapters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/mvgicp.4&quot;&gt;mvgicp(4)&lt;/a&gt; driver for Marvell ARMADA 7K/8K GICP controller.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for QCA AR816x/AR817x in &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/alc.4&quot;&gt;alc(4)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for isochronous transfers in &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/xhci.4&quot;&gt;xhci(4)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/uaudio.4&quot;&gt;uaudio(4)&lt;/a&gt; has been replaced by a new driver which supports USB audio class v2.0.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved support for &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/nmea.4&quot;&gt;nmea(4)&lt;/a&gt; devices, providing altitude and ground speed values as sensors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IEEE 802.11 wireless stack improvements:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Reduced usage of RTS frames improves overall throughput and latency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved transmit rate selection in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/iwm.4&quot;&gt;iwm(4)&lt;/a&gt; driver.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved radio hardware calibration in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/athn.4&quot;&gt;athn(4)&lt;/a&gt; driver.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/bwfm.4&quot;&gt;bwfm(4)&lt;/a&gt; driver now provides more accurate device configuration information to userland.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added new routing socket message RTM_80211INFO to provide details of 802.11 interface state changes to &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/dhclient&quot;&gt;dhclient(8)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/route&quot;&gt;route(8)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If an auto-join list is configured, wireless interfaces will no longer connect to unknown open networks by default. This behaviour must now be explicitly enabled by adding the empty network name to the auto-join list, e.g. &lt;tt&gt;ifconfig iwm0 join &quot;&quot;&lt;/tt&gt;, or &lt;tt&gt;join &quot;&quot;&lt;/tt&gt; in hostname.if files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/iwn.4&quot;&gt;iwn(4)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/iwm.4&quot;&gt;iwm(4)&lt;/a&gt; drivers will now automatically try to connect to a network if the radio kill switch is toggled to allow radio transmissions while the interface is marked UP.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generic network stack improvements:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;New &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/bpe.4&quot;&gt;bpe(4)&lt;/a&gt; Backbone Provider Edge pseudo-device.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/mpip.4&quot;&gt;mpip(4)&lt;/a&gt; MPLS IP layer 2 pseudowire driver.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MPLS encapsulation interfaces support configuration of alternative MPLS route domains.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/vlan.4&quot;&gt;vlan(4)&lt;/a&gt; driver bypasses queue processing and outputs directly to the parent interface.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New per SAD counters visible via &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/ipsecctl.8&quot;&gt;ipsecctl(8)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/bpf.4&quot;&gt;bpf(4)&lt;/a&gt; filter drop mechanism has been extended to allow dropping without capturing packets, and use of the mechanism with &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/tcpdump.8&quot;&gt;tcpdump(8)&lt;/a&gt; as a filtering mechanism early in the device receive path.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/ifconfig.8&quot;&gt;ifconfig(8)&lt;/a&gt; gains &lt;tt&gt;txprio&lt;/tt&gt; for controlling the encoding of priority in tunnel headers, and support in drivers including &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/vlan.4&quot;&gt;vlan(4)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/gre.4&quot;&gt;gre(4)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/gif.4&quot;&gt;gif(4)&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/etherip.4&quot;&gt;etherip(4)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Installer improvements:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/rdsetroot.8&quot;&gt;rdsetroot(8)&lt;/a&gt; (a build-time tool) is now available for general use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;During upgrades, some components of old releases are deleted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Security improvements:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/unveil.2&quot;&gt;unveil(2)&lt;/a&gt; has been improved to understand and find covering unveil matches above the working directory of the running process for relative path accesses. As a result many programs now can use unveil in broad ways such as unveil(&quot;/&quot;, &quot;r&quot;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/unveil.2&quot;&gt;unveil(2)&lt;/a&gt; no longer silently allows &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/stat.2&quot;&gt;stat(2)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/access.2&quot;&gt;access(2)&lt;/a&gt; to work on any unveiled path component.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now using &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/unveil.2&quot;&gt;unveil(2)&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/ospfd&quot;&gt;ospfd(8)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/ospf6d&quot;&gt;ospf6d(8)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/rebound&quot;&gt;rebound(8)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/getconf&quot;&gt;getconf(1)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/kvm_mkdb&quot;&gt;kvm_mkdb(8)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/bdftopcf&quot;&gt;bdftopcf(1)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/Xserver&quot;&gt;Xserver(1)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/passwd&quot;&gt;passwd(1)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/spamlogd&quot;&gt;spamlogd(8)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/spamd&quot;&gt;spamd(8)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/sensorsd&quot;&gt;sensorsd(8)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/snmpd&quot;&gt;snmpd(8)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/htpasswd&quot;&gt;htpasswd(1)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/ifstated&quot;&gt;ifstated(8)&lt;/a&gt;. Some &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/pledge.2&quot;&gt;pledge(2)&lt;/a&gt; changes were required to accommodate unveil.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ROP mitigations in &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/clang-local.1&quot;&gt;clang(1)&lt;/a&gt; have been improved, resulting in a significant decrease in the number of polymorphic ROP gadgets in binaries on i386/amd64.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RETGUARD performance and security has been improved in &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/clang-local.1&quot;&gt;clang(1)&lt;/a&gt; by keeping data on registers instead of on the stack when possible, and lengthening the epilogue trapsled on amd64 to consume the rest of the cache line before the return.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RETGUARD replaces the stack protector on amd64 and arm64, since RETGUARD instruments every function that returns and provides better security properties than the traditional stack protector.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Routing daemons and other userland network improvements:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/pcap-filter.3&quot;&gt;pcap-filter(3)&lt;/a&gt; can now filter on MPLS packets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The routing priority for &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/ospfd.8&quot;&gt;ospfd(8)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/ospf6d.8&quot;&gt;ospf6d(8)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/ripd.8&quot;&gt;ripd(8)&lt;/a&gt; is now configurable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/ripd.8&quot;&gt;ripd(8)&lt;/a&gt; is now pledged.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First release of &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/unwind.8&quot;&gt;unwind(8)&lt;/a&gt;, a validating, recursive nameserver for 127.0.0.1. It is particularly suitable for laptops moving between networks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/ifconfig.8&quot;&gt;ifconfig(8)&lt;/a&gt; gains &lt;tt&gt;sff&lt;/tt&gt; and &lt;tt&gt;sffdump&lt;/tt&gt; modes, displaying diagnostic information from fibre transceivers and similar modules. Currently &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/ix.4&quot;&gt;ix(4)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/ixl.4&quot;&gt;ixl(4)&lt;/a&gt; are supported.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/ldpd.8&quot;&gt;ldpd(8)&lt;/a&gt; now supports &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/ldpd.conf.5&quot;&gt;configuration of TCP MD5&lt;/a&gt; for networks, not just specific neighbors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/bgpd.8&quot;&gt;bgpd(8)&lt;/a&gt; improvements:
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assorted improvements:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/kcov.4&quot;&gt;kcov(4)&lt;/a&gt; gained support for &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/kcov#KCOV_MODE_TRACE_CMP&quot;&gt;KCOV_MODE_TRACE_CMP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A 'video' promise was added to &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/pledge.2&quot;&gt;pledge(2)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;kern.witnesswatch&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/sysctl.8&quot;&gt;sysctl(8)&lt;/a&gt; has been renamed to &lt;code&gt;kern.witness.watch&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New pthread &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/pthread_rwlock_init&quot;&gt;rwlock&lt;/a&gt; implementation improving latency of threaded applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/kubsan.4&quot;&gt;kubsan(4)&lt;/a&gt; capable of detecting undefined behavior in the kernel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/signify.1&quot;&gt;signify&lt;/a&gt; -n option to zero date header in -z mode.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove OXTABS from default pty flags.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/install.1&quot;&gt;install(1)&lt;/a&gt; now always copies files safely (as with -S), avoiding race conditions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/syslog.conf.5&quot;&gt;syslog.conf(5)&lt;/a&gt; now supports program names containing dots and underscores.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/tcpdump.8&quot;&gt;tcpdump(8)&lt;/a&gt; already used privsep, &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/pledge.2&quot;&gt;pledge(2)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/unveil.2&quot;&gt;unveil(2)&lt;/a&gt; containment. It now also drops root privileges completely (switching to a reserved uid).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The multi-threaded performance of &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/malloc.3&quot;&gt;malloc(3)&lt;/a&gt; has been improved.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/malloc.3&quot;&gt;malloc(3)&lt;/a&gt; now uses &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/sysctl.2&quot;&gt;sysctl(2)&lt;/a&gt; to get its settings, making it respect the system-wide settings in chroots as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Various improvements to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/join.1&quot;&gt;join&lt;/a&gt; command.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work has started on a ISC-licensed rsync-compatible program called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openrsync.org&quot;&gt;OpenRSYNC&lt;/a&gt;. In this release it has basic functionality such as &lt;strong&gt;-a&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;--delete&lt;/strong&gt;, but lacks &lt;strong&gt;--exclude&lt;/strong&gt;. Work will continue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New Spleen font 8x16, 12x24, 16x32 and 32x64 variants added and enabled in wsfont, along with font selection logic to allow selecting larger fonts when available at runtime in &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/rasops.9&quot;&gt;rasops(9)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OpenSMTPD 6.5.0
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;New Features
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Added the new matching criteria &quot;from rdns&quot; to &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/smtpd.conf.5&quot;&gt;smtpd.conf(5)&lt;/a&gt; to allow matching of sessions based on the reverse DNS of the client.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/regex.3&quot;&gt;regex(3)&lt;/a&gt; support to table lookups in &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/smtpd.conf.5&quot;&gt;smtpd.conf(5)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LibreSSL 2.9.1
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;API and Documentation Enhancements
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;CRYPTO_LOCK is now automatically initialized, with the legacy callbacks stubbed for compatibility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added the SM3 hash function from the Chinese standard GB/T 32905-2016.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added the SM4 block cipher from the Chinese standard GB/T 32907-2016.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added more OPENSSL_NO_* macros for compatibility with OpenSSL.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Partial port of the OpenSSL EC_KEY_METHOD API for use by OpenSSH.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented further missing OpenSSL 1.1 API.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for XChaCha20 and XChaCha20-Poly1305.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for AES key wrap constructions via the EVP interface.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compatibility Changes
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Added pbkdf2 key derivation support to &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/openssl.1&quot;&gt;openssl(1)&lt;/a&gt; enc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed the default digest type of &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/openssl.1&quot;&gt;openssl(1)&lt;/a&gt; enc to sha256.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed the default digest type of &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/openssl.1&quot;&gt;openssl(1)&lt;/a&gt; dgst to sha256.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed the default digest type of &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/openssl.1&quot;&gt;openssl(1)&lt;/a&gt; x509 -fingerprint to sha256.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed the default digest type of &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/openssl.1&quot;&gt;openssl(1)&lt;/a&gt; crl -fingerprint to sha256.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Testing and Proactive Security
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Added extensive interoperability tests between LibreSSL and OpenSSL 1.0 and 1.1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added additional Wycheproof tests and related bug fixes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Internal Improvements
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Simplified sigalgs option processing and handshake signing algorithm selection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added the ability to use the RSA PSS algorithm for handshake signatures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added bn_rand_interval() and use it in code needing ranges of random bn values.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added functionality to derive early, handshake, and application secrets as per RFC8446.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added handshake state machine from RFC8446.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed some ASN.1 related code from libcrypto that had not been used since around 2000.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unexported internal symbols and internalized more record layer structs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed SHA224 based handshake signatures from consideration for use in a TLS 1.2 handshake.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Portable Improvements
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Added support for assembly optimizations on 32-bit ARM ELF targets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for assembly optimizations on Mingw-w64 targets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved Android compatibility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bug Fixes
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Improved protection against timing side channels in ECDSA signature generation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coordinate blinding was added to some elliptic curves. This is the last bit of the work by Brumley et al. to protect against the Portsmash vulnerability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure transcript handshake is always freed with TLS 1.2.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OpenSSH 8.0
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;New Features
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;ssh(1), ssh-agent(1), ssh-add(1): Add support for ECDSA keys in PKCS#11 tokens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ssh(1), sshd(8): Add experimental quantum-computing resistant key exchange method, based on a combination of Streamlined NTRU Prime 4591^761 and X25519.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ssh-keygen(1): Increase the default RSA key size to 3072 bits, following NIST Special Publication 800-57's guidance for a 128-bit equivalent symmetric security level.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ssh(1): Allow &quot;PKCS11Provider=none&quot; to override later instances of the PKCS11Provider directive in ssh_config; bz#2974&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sshd(8): Add a log message for situations where a connection is dropped for attempting to run a command but a sshd_config ForceCommand=internal-sftp restriction is in effect; bz#2960&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ssh(1): When prompting whether to record a new host key, accept the key fingerprint as a synonym for &quot;yes&quot;. This allows the user to paste a fingerprint obtained out of band at the prompt and have the client do the comparison for you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ssh-keygen(1): When signing multiple certificates on a single command-line invocation, allow automatically incrementing the certificate serial number.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;scp(1), sftp(1): Accept -J option as an alias to ProxyJump on the scp and sftp command-lines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ssh-agent(1), ssh-pkcs11-helper(8), ssh-add(1): Accept &quot;-v&quot; command-line flags to increase the verbosity of output; pass verbose flags though to subprocesses, such as ssh-pkcs11-helper started from ssh-agent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ssh-add(1): Add a &quot;-T&quot; option to allowing testing whether keys in an agent are usable by performing a signature and a verification.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sftp-server(8): Add a &quot;lsetstat@openssh.com&quot; protocol extension that replicates the functionality of the existing SSH2_FXP_SETSTAT operation but does not follow symlinks. bz#2067&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sftp(1): Add &quot;-h&quot; flag to chown/chgrp/chmod commands to request they do not follow symlinks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sshd(8): Expose $SSH_CONNECTION in the PAM environment. This makes the connection 4-tuple available to PAM modules that wish to use it in decision-making. bz#2741&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sshd(8): Add a ssh_config &quot;Match final&quot; predicate Matches in same pass as &quot;Match canonical&quot; but doesn't require hostname canonicalisation be enabled. bz#2906&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sftp(1): Support a prefix of '@' to suppress echo of sftp batch commands; bz#2926&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ssh-keygen(1): When printing certificate contents using &quot;ssh-keygen -Lf /path/certificate&quot;, include the algorithm that the CA used to sign the cert.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfixes
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;sshd(8): Fix authentication failures when sshd_config contains &quot;AuthenticationMethods any&quot; inside a Match block that overrides a more restrictive default.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sshd(8): Avoid sending duplicate keepalives when ClientAliveCount is enabled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sshd(8): Fix two race conditions related to SIGHUP daemon restart. Remnant file descriptors in recently-forked child processes could block the parent sshd's attempt to listen(2) to the configured addresses. Also, the restarting parent sshd could exit before any child processes that were awaiting their re-execution state had completed reading it, leaving them in a fallback path.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ssh(1): Fix stdout potentially being redirected to /dev/null when ProxyCommand=- was in use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sshd(8): Avoid sending SIGPIPE to child processes if they attempt to write to stderr after their parent processes have exited; bz#2071&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ssh(1): Fix bad interaction between the ssh_config ConnectTimeout and ConnectionAttempts directives - connection attempts after the first were ignoring the requested timeout; bz#2918&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ssh-keyscan(1): Return a non-zero exit status if no keys were found; bz#2903&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;scp(1): Sanitize scp filenames to allow UTF-8 characters without terminal control sequences; bz#2434&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sshd(8): Fix confusion between ClientAliveInterval and time-based RekeyLimit that could cause connections to be incorrectly closed. bz#2757&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ssh(1), ssh-add(1): Correct some bugs in PKCS#11 token PIN handling at initial token login. The attempt to read the PIN could be skipped in some cases, particularly on devices with integrated PIN readers. This would lead to an inability to retrieve keys from these tokens. bz#2652&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ssh(1), ssh-add(1): Support keys on PKCS#11 tokens that set the CKA_ALWAYS_AUTHENTICATE flag by requring a fresh login after the C_SignInit operation. bz#2638&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ssh(1): Improve documentation for ProxyJump/-J, clarifying that local configuration does not apply to jump hosts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ssh-keygen(1): Clarify manual - ssh-keygen -e only writes public keys, not private.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ssh(1), sshd(8): be more strict in processing protocol banners, allowing \r characters only immediately before \n.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Various: fix a number of memory leaks, including bz#2942 and bz#2938&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;scp(1), sftp(1): fix calculation of initial bandwidth limits. Account for bytes written before the timer starts and adjust the schedule on which recalculations are performed. Avoids an initial burst of traffic and yields more accurate bandwidth limits; bz#2927&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sshd(8): Only consider the ext-info-c extension during the initial key eschange. It shouldn't be sent in subsequent ones, but if it is present we should ignore it. This prevents sshd from sending a SSH_MSG_EXT_INFO for REKEX for buggy these clients. bz#2929&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ssh-keygen(1): Clarify manual that ssh-keygen -F (find host in authorized_keys) and -R (remove host from authorized_keys) options may accept either a bare hostname or a [hostname]:port combo. bz#2935&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ssh(1): Don't attempt to connect to empty SSH_AUTH_SOCK; bz#2936&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sshd(8): Silence error messages when sshd fails to load some of the default host keys. Failure to load an explicitly-configured hostkey is still an error, and failure to load any host key is still fatal. pr/103&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ssh(1): Redirect stderr of ProxyCommands to /dev/null when ssh is started with ControlPersist; prevents random ProxyCommand output from interfering with session output.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ssh(1): The ssh client was keeping a redundant ssh-agent socket (leftover from authentication) around for the life of the connection; bz#2912&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sshd(8): Fix bug in HostbasedAcceptedKeyTypes and PubkeyAcceptedKeyTypes options. If only RSA-SHA2 siganture types were specified, then authentication would always fail for RSA keys as the monitor checks only the base key (not the signature algorithm) type against *AcceptedKeyTypes. bz#2746&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ssh(1): Request correct signature types from ssh-agent when certificate keys and RSA-SHA2 signatures are in use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mandoc 1.14.5
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Improved POSIX compliance in &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/apropos.1&quot;&gt;apropos(1)&lt;/a&gt; by accepting case-insensitive extended regular expressions by default.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New -O &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/mandoc.1#tag&quot;&gt;tag&lt;/a&gt; output option to open a page at the definition of a term.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/tbl.7&quot;&gt;tbl(7)&lt;/a&gt; improvements: line drawing, spanning, horizontal and vertical alignment in HTML output, improved column width calculations in terminal output, use of box drawing characters in UTF-8 output.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Much better HTML output, in particular with respect to paragraphs, line breaks, and vertical spacing in tagged lists. Tooltips are now implemented in pure CSS, the &lt;code&gt;title&lt;/code&gt; attribute is no longer abused.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Xenocara
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/Xorg.1&quot;&gt;Xorg(1)&lt;/a&gt;, the X window server, is no longer installed setuid. &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/xenodm.1&quot;&gt;xenodm(1)&lt;/a&gt; should be used to start X.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The radeonsi Mesa driver is now included for hardware acceleration on Southern Islands and Sea Islands &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/radeondrm.4&quot;&gt;radeondrm(4)&lt;/a&gt; devices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ports and packages:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;C++ ports for non-clang architectures are now compiled with ports gcc, so that more packages can be provided.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dt&gt;Many pre-built packages for each architecture:&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; cellpadding=&quot;2&quot; width=&quot;95%&quot; readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot;25%&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;aarch64: 9654&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;amd64: 10602&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;arm: XXXX&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot;25%&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;i386: 10535&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mips64: XXXX&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mips64el: XXXX&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot;25%&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;powerpc: XXXX&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sparc64: XXXX&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dt&gt;Some highlights:&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; cellpadding=&quot;2&quot; width=&quot;95%&quot; readability=&quot;7.5&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot;25%&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;AFL 2.52b&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Asterisk 16.2.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Audacity 2.3.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CMake 3.10.2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chromium 73.0.3683.86&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Emacs 26.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FFmpeg 4.1.3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GCC 4.9.4 and 8.3.0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GHC 8.2.2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GNOME 3.30.2.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go 1.12.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Groff 1.22.4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JDK 8u202 and 11.0.2+9-3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot;25%&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;LLVM/Clang 7.0.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LibreOffice 6.2.2.2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lua 5.1.5, 5.2.4 and 5.3.5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MariaDB 10.0.38&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mono 5.18.1.0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mozilla Firefox 66.0.2 and ESR 60.6.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mozilla Thunderbird 60.6.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mutt 1.11.4 and NeoMutt 20180716&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Node.js 10.15.0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OCaml 4.07.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OpenLDAP 2.3.43 and 2.4.47&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PHP 7.1.28, 7.2.17 and 7.3.4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Postfix 3.3.3 and 3.4.20190106&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot;25%&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;PostgreSQL 11.2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python 2.7.16 and 3.6.8&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;R 3.5.3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ruby 2.4.6, 2.5.5 and 2.6.2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rust 1.33.0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sendmail 8.16.0.41&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SQLite3 3.27.2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sudo 1.8.27&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Suricata 4.1.3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tcl/Tk 8.5.19 and 8.6.8&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TeX Live 2018&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vim 8.1.1048 and Neovim 0.3.4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Xfce 4.12&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As usual, steady improvements in manual pages and other documentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The system includes the following major components from outside suppliers:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Xenocara (based on X.Org 7.7 with xserver 1.19.7 + patches, freetype 2.9.1, fontconfig 2.12.4, Mesa 18.3.5, xterm 344, xkeyboard-config 2.20 and more)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LLVM/Clang 7.0.1 (+ patches)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GCC 4.2.1 (+ patches) and 3.3.6 (+ patches)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perl 5.28.1 (+ patches)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NSD 4.1.27&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unbound 1.9.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ncurses 5.7&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Binutils 2.17 (+ patches)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gdb 6.3 (+ patches)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Awk Aug 10, 2011 version&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expat 2.2.6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;install&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;How to install&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please refer to the following files on the mirror site for extensive details on how to install OpenBSD 6.5 on your machine:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quick installer information for people familiar with OpenBSD, and the use of the &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/disklabel.8&quot;&gt;disklabel&lt;/a&gt; -E&quot; command. If you are at all confused when installing OpenBSD, read the relevant INSTALL.* file as listed above!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span&gt;OpenBSD/alpha:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Write &lt;em&gt;floppy65.fs&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;floppyB65.fs&lt;/em&gt; (depending on your machine) to a diskette and enter &lt;em&gt;boot dva0&lt;/em&gt;. Refer to INSTALL.alpha for more details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure you use a properly formatted floppy with NO BAD BLOCKS or your install will most likely fail.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span&gt;OpenBSD/amd64:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;If your machine can boot from CD, you can write &lt;em&gt;install65.iso&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;cd65.iso&lt;/em&gt; to a CD and boot from it. You may need to adjust your BIOS options first.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If your machine can boot from USB, you can write &lt;em&gt;install65.fs&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;miniroot65.fs&lt;/em&gt; to a USB stick and boot from it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you can't boot from a CD, floppy disk, or USB, you can install across the network using PXE as described in the included INSTALL.amd64 document.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you are planning to dual boot OpenBSD with another OS, you will need to read INSTALL.amd64.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span&gt;OpenBSD/arm64:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Write &lt;em&gt;miniroot65.fs&lt;/em&gt; to a disk and boot from it after connecting to the serial console. Refer to INSTALL.arm64 for more details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span&gt;OpenBSD/armv7:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Write a system specific miniroot to an SD card and boot from it after connecting to the serial console. Refer to INSTALL.armv7 for more details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span&gt;OpenBSD/hppa:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Boot over the network by following the instructions in INSTALL.hppa or the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openbsd.org/hppa.html#install&quot;&gt;hppa platform page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span&gt;OpenBSD/i386:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;If your machine can boot from CD, you can write &lt;em&gt;install65.iso&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;cd65.iso&lt;/em&gt; to a CD and boot from it. You may need to adjust your BIOS options first.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If your machine can boot from USB, you can write &lt;em&gt;install65.fs&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;miniroot65.fs&lt;/em&gt; to a USB stick and boot from it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you can't boot from a CD, floppy disk, or USB, you can install across the network using PXE as described in the included INSTALL.i386 document.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you are planning on dual booting OpenBSD with another OS, you will need to read INSTALL.i386.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span&gt;OpenBSD/landisk:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Write &lt;em&gt;miniroot65.fs&lt;/em&gt; to the start of the CF or disk, and boot normally.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span&gt;OpenBSD/loongson:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Write &lt;em&gt;miniroot65.fs&lt;/em&gt; to a USB stick and boot bsd.rd from it or boot bsd.rd via tftp. Refer to the instructions in INSTALL.loongson for more details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span&gt;OpenBSD/luna88k:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Copy `boot' and `bsd.rd' to a Mach or UniOS partition, and boot the bootloader from the PROM, and then bsd.rd from the bootloader. Refer to the instructions in INSTALL.luna88k for more details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span&gt;OpenBSD/macppc:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Burn the image from a mirror site to a CDROM, and power on your machine while holding down the &lt;em&gt;C&lt;/em&gt; key until the display turns on and shows &lt;em&gt;OpenBSD/macppc boot&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alternatively, at the Open Firmware prompt, enter &lt;em&gt;boot cd:,ofwboot /6.5/macppc/bsd.rd&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span&gt;OpenBSD/octeon:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;After connecting a serial port, boot bsd.rd over the network via DHCP/tftp. Refer to the instructions in INSTALL.octeon for more details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span&gt;OpenBSD/sgi:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;To install, burn cd65.iso on a CD-R, put it in the CD drive of your machine and select &lt;em&gt;Install System Software&lt;/em&gt; from the System Maintenance menu. Indigo/Indy/Indigo2 (R4000) systems will not boot automatically from CD-ROM, and need a proper invocation from the PROM prompt. Refer to the instructions in INSTALL.sgi for more details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If your machine doesn't have a CD drive, you can setup a DHCP/tftp network server, and boot using &quot;bootp()/bsd.rd.IP##&quot; using the kernel matching your system type. Refer to the instructions in INSTALL.sgi for more details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span&gt;OpenBSD/sparc64:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Burn the image from a mirror site to a CDROM, boot from it, and type &lt;em&gt;boot cdrom&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If this doesn't work, or if you don't have a CDROM drive, you can write &lt;em&gt;floppy65.fs&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;floppyB65.fs&lt;/em&gt; (depending on your machine) to a floppy and boot it with &lt;em&gt;boot floppy&lt;/em&gt;. Refer to INSTALL.sparc64 for details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure you use a properly formatted floppy with NO BAD BLOCKS or your install will most likely fail.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can also write &lt;em&gt;miniroot65.fs&lt;/em&gt; to the swap partition on the disk and boot with &lt;em&gt;boot disk:b&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If nothing works, you can boot over the network as described in INSTALL.sparc64.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;upgrade&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;How to upgrade&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you already have an OpenBSD 6.4 system, and do not want to reinstall, upgrade instructions and advice can be found in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openbsd.org/faq/upgrade65.html&quot;&gt;Upgrade Guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;sourcecode&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Notes about the source code&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;tt&gt;src.tar.gz&lt;/tt&gt; contains a source archive starting at &lt;tt&gt;/usr/src&lt;/tt&gt;. This file contains everything you need except for the kernel sources, which are in a separate archive. To extract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
# &lt;strong&gt;mkdir -p /usr/src&lt;/strong&gt;
# &lt;strong&gt;cd /usr/src&lt;/strong&gt;
# &lt;strong&gt;tar xvfz /tmp/src.tar.gz&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;tt&gt;sys.tar.gz&lt;/tt&gt; contains a source archive starting at &lt;tt&gt;/usr/src/sys&lt;/tt&gt;. This file contains all the kernel sources you need to rebuild kernels. To extract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
# &lt;strong&gt;mkdir -p /usr/src/sys&lt;/strong&gt;
# &lt;strong&gt;cd /usr/src&lt;/strong&gt;
# &lt;strong&gt;tar xvfz /tmp/sys.tar.gz&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both of these trees are a regular CVS checkout. Using these trees it is possible to get a head-start on using the anoncvs servers as described &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openbsd.org/anoncvs.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Using these files results in a much faster initial CVS update than you could expect from a fresh checkout of the full OpenBSD source tree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;ports&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Ports Tree&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A ports tree archive is also provided. To extract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
# &lt;strong&gt;cd /usr&lt;/strong&gt;
# &lt;strong&gt;tar xvfz /tmp/ports.tar.gz&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go read the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openbsd.org/faq/ports/index.html&quot;&gt;ports&lt;/a&gt; page if you know nothing about ports at this point. This text is not a manual of how to use ports. Rather, it is a set of notes meant to kickstart the user on the OpenBSD ports system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;ports/&lt;/em&gt; directory represents a CVS checkout of our ports. As with our complete source tree, our ports tree is available via &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openbsd.org/anoncvs.html&quot;&gt;AnonCVS&lt;/a&gt;. So, in order to keep up to date with the -stable branch, you must make the &lt;em&gt;ports/&lt;/em&gt; tree available on a read-write medium and update the tree with a command like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
# &lt;strong&gt;cd /usr/ports&lt;/strong&gt;
# &lt;strong&gt;cvs -d anoncvs@server.openbsd.org:/cvs update -Pd -rOPENBSD_6_5&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Of course, you must replace the server name here with a nearby anoncvs server.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that most ports are available as packages on our mirrors. Updated ports for the 6.5 release will be made available if problems arise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're interested in seeing a port added, would like to help out, or just would like to know more, the mailing list &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openbsd.org/mail.html&quot;&gt;ports@openbsd.org&lt;/a&gt; is a good place to know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 13:32:49 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>vetelko</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.openbsd.org/65.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>