<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Bullfrog After Populous</title>
<link>https://www.filfre.net/2020/09/bullfrog-after-populous/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.filfre.net/2020/09/bullfrog-after-populous/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2020/09/bullfrog-after-populous/bullfrog-2/&quot; rel=&quot;attachment wp-att-4363&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-4363&quot; src=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/bullfrog.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;323&quot; height=&quot;615&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/bullfrog.jpg 323w, https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/bullfrog-158x300.jpg 158w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 323px) 100vw, 323px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll give you an analogy of what Populous is in my mind. Imagine if I had a blank canvas. Some people that are true artists will take a palette of paint and mix them together and carefully handcraft each and every single brushstroke until they have some beautiful and amazing picture. And then there’s me. I had the blank canvas, accidentally knocked a can of paint over, and it went splat. And an art dealer has seen it and said, “That’s brilliant.” Well, I know all I’ve done is kick a can of paint. And that’s what I believe really happened with Populous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Peter Molyneux&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2016/06/peter-molyneuxs-kingdom-in-a-box&quot;&gt;we last met Peter Molyneux and his little database-developer-turned-games-studio Bullfrog Software&lt;/a&gt;, they had just made &lt;em&gt;Populous&lt;/em&gt; and watched in disbelief as it blew up huge. The radically innovative game joined &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2016/06/simcity-part-1-will-wrights-city-in-a-box&quot;&gt;Will Wright’s &lt;em&gt;SimCity&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; as one of the progenitors of a hazily delineated new genre which the media labelled the “god game” for the way it gave you direct control over an environment but only indirect control over the people therein. As &lt;em&gt;Populous&lt;/em&gt; became a hit on three continents and sold in the hundreds of thousands and eventually millions of copies, Bullfrog struggled to reckon with the cognitive dissonances of their changed circumstances. In a matter of months, they went from a handful of poverty-stricken dreamers pissing in the sink of their miserable, toilet-less hovel of an office to Britain’s single most successful and respected games studio of all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trappings of their success tended to trail behind their sales figures: when a group of Japanese executives stopped by the Bullfrog hole-in-the-wall to discuss plans for publishing &lt;em&gt;Populous&lt;/em&gt; in their country, the senile pensioner who lived below met them at the bottom of the stairs with a mop and proceeded to beat them off the premises. “We had to get out of there as soon as possible,” says Molyneux. They wound up in a more conventional business park, whose more conventional tenants complained endlessly about their penchant for racing skateboards through the hallways and shooting BB guns out the windows. (“We were brats,” admits Molyneux today. “Horrible, horrible brats.”)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While certainly preferable to failure, success could be its own kind of mixed blessing. Expectations of Bullfrog, which had previously been nonexistent, were suddenly sky high. After a quickie add-on disk that brought additional levels and environments to &lt;em&gt;Populous&lt;/em&gt;, they made a rather shockingly unambitious little platformer called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mobygames.com/game/flood&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Flood&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a project of Bullfrog programmer Sean Cooper. Released only in Europe for the Commodore Amiga and Atari ST by Bullfrog’s publisher Electronic Arts, it garnered a collective shrug from the magazines; the market was already flooded with platformers much like this one, often with more compelling level designs. This sort of derivative work wasn’t at all what people had come to expect from Bullfrog after &lt;em&gt;Populous&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, they had something else in the works. Released in late 1990, some eighteen months after &lt;em&gt;Populous&lt;/em&gt;, the real-time war game &lt;em&gt;Powermonger&lt;/em&gt; evinced a lot of innovation on its own terms even as it clearly drew from the same set of techniques and approaches that had yielded Bullfrog’s first hit. Instead of casting you as a god able to alter the very landscape of the world on behalf of your mortal followers, &lt;em&gt;Powermonger&lt;/em&gt; cast you as an ordinary human on a mission to conquer the world — all 195 regional cross-sections of it, one region at a time. The ethos of indirect control that had made &lt;em&gt;Populous&lt;/em&gt; so unique remained: you had to convince the people to rally to your cause, and had to work constantly to keep them loyal to you. Ditto a focus on large-scale environmental effects: you had to worry about the ecology of the land in order to feed, water, house, and equip your people. (After all, it’s hard to build much of anything if you’ve already clear-cut all of the forests…) While &lt;em&gt;Computer Gaming World&lt;/em&gt;‘s Johnny L. Wilson, who was always eager to read meaning into games, may have been overstating the case when he called &lt;em&gt;Powermonger&lt;/em&gt; “a dynamic treatise on the human capacity for aggrandizement and the potential consequences therein,” the same magazine’s description of it as the “thinking person’s &lt;em&gt;Populous&lt;/em&gt;” was a good deal more tenable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, it suffered from many of the same flaws as its predecessor — flaws which would become consistent hallmarks of Molyneux’s work in general. He obviously wanted to give players a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of game by providing 195 levels, but, being all procedurally generated, they didn’t really build upon one another or force the player to reevaluate the tools at her disposal in interesting new ways. &lt;em&gt;Powermonger&lt;/em&gt; was great fun at first — thus all the glowing reviews in the magazines — but it started to feel a little bit rote a little bit too quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_4364&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;48&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2020/09/bullfrog-after-populous/powermonger/&quot; rel=&quot;attachment wp-att-4364&quot;&gt;&lt;img aria-describedby=&quot;caption-attachment-4364&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-4364&quot; src=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/powermonger.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/powermonger.png 640w, https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/powermonger-300x225.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;caption-attachment-4364&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;The graphics in &lt;em&gt;Powermonger&lt;/em&gt; got a dramatic upgrade over those in &lt;em&gt;Populous&lt;/em&gt;, yielding not only aesthetic but also practical benefits: it was now possible to rotate your view of the landscape and zoom it in and out as needed, while the variety of landscape features was dramatically greater. “In &lt;em&gt;Populous&lt;/em&gt;,” noted Molyneux, “we had hills, houses, and rivers. Thanks to this new system, we’re able to generate waterfalls, cliffs, valleys, mountains, proper towns, road networks, forests… it’s a real world!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Molyneux originally conceived of &lt;em&gt;Powermonger&lt;/em&gt; not so much as a standalone game as an engine for running a variety of them. After the first game with its vaguely Medieval theme, he talked of making a World War I version, a high-fantasy version, an Asian version for the Japanese market, and a version focusing on the American Civil War for the punters in the United States. But &lt;em&gt;Powermonger&lt;/em&gt;, while moderately successful, never became the sensation that &lt;em&gt;Populous&lt;/em&gt; was, and most of those plans were abandoned; only the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mobygames.com/game/powermonger-world-war-i-edition&quot;&gt;World War I data disk&lt;/a&gt; ever appeared. &lt;em&gt;Powermonger&lt;/em&gt; “appeals to a lot of people who like very, very high strategic games, but it needed that extra element that would appeal to everybody and it didn’t have that,” said Molyneux after the dust had settled. He blamed the lack largely on the pressure Bullfrog was under from Electronic Arts to complete and release the game in time for Christmas, which meant that it didn’t get &lt;em&gt;played&lt;/em&gt; prior to release to anywhere near the extent of &lt;em&gt;Populous&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still searching for that elusive second million-selling hit, Bullfrog opted to drink even deeper from the old &lt;em&gt;Populous&lt;/em&gt; well next time around. Their game for the Christmas of 1991 was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mobygames.com/game/populous-ii-trials-of-the-olympian-gods&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Populous II&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which mated the improved interface and graphics of &lt;em&gt;Powermonger&lt;/em&gt; to the literal god-game theme of &lt;em&gt;Populous I&lt;/em&gt;. There was slightly more semblance of a plot this time out: you played a minor deity who must fight her way through a pantheon of some 35 Greek gods, culminating in Zeus himself. Your powers too were more varied than last time out; no longer could people scoff that the game was nothing more than an elaborate topography simulator, not with your ability to spawn tidal waves, whirlwinds, and lightning strikes. Yet one only had to glance at the screen, or read about its more than 1000 (!) anonymous, procedurally-generated levels to know that this was still very much &lt;em&gt;Populous&lt;/em&gt;, for both good and bad. It sold well to the committed faithful and spawned the by-now standard &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mobygames.com/game/populous-ii-the-challenge-games&quot;&gt;expansion pack&lt;/a&gt;; in a sop to the Japanese market, where the first &lt;em&gt;Populous&lt;/em&gt; had become so popular as to spawn graphic novels and symphony concerts recreating the game’s soundtrack, the expansion was set in ancient Japan rather than Greece. But even so, &lt;em&gt;Populous II&lt;/em&gt; made relatively few new converts to the cause at home or abroad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_4365&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;39&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2020/09/bullfrog-after-populous/populous2/&quot; rel=&quot;attachment wp-att-4365&quot;&gt;&lt;img aria-describedby=&quot;caption-attachment-4365&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-4365&quot; src=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/populous2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/populous2.png 640w, https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/populous2-300x225.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;caption-attachment-4365&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Populous II&lt;/em&gt;. Molyneux admits to feeling “ashamed” at the time to be doing a sequel at all, but he felt obligated to deliver a direct follow-up to such a massive hit. He considers &lt;em&gt;Populous II&lt;/em&gt; a reasonable but somewhat unimaginative sequel, which in rather typical industry fashion added a lot more &lt;em&gt;stuff&lt;/em&gt; to the template of its predecessor in the form of new godly powers, but failed to drill down on what actually made the original fun. A fair assessment, I think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although their latest games hadn’t sold quite as well as the original world-beating &lt;em&gt;Populous&lt;/em&gt;, Bullfrog remained the preeminent British games studio in the minds of many. Their status was rivaled only by that of DMA Design, whose &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2017/10/games-on-the-mersey-part-5-the-lemmings-effect&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lemmings&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; had become upon its release in early 1991 the most successful single British game since &lt;em&gt;Populous&lt;/em&gt;. But DMA was located way off in Dundee, Scotland, a country away from the press on Fleet Street, and when an intrepid journalist did make the trek out to those hinterlands its founder David Jones didn’t provide as many choice quotes as the gregarious Peter Molyneux, then as now one of his industry’s greatest raconteurs. The press loved him not least because he was so willing to go against the official industry position on many subjects, full speed ahead and damn the torpedoes. Asked about the effects of piracy — a subject guaranteed to produce predictions of an imminent gaming apocalypse from any other prominent industry figure — Molyneux shocked his interviewer by replying mildly that “to be honest, I don’t think that piracy hurts.” Likewise, he never hesitated to air his real feelings about competing products: “If you’ve got a crappy shoot’em-up style game, then that’s going to be pirated to hell — and it should be because it’s not even worth using this planet’s resources to produce the game.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chain-smoking, perpetually hyperactive Molyneux got on particularly splendidly with the laddish British Amiga magazines of the time. He was up for pretty much anything when they came calling — as when he agreed to be interviewed about a recent trip to Japan while sitting on the toilet. From here he regaled his interlocutors with anecdotes about geisha girls, and told them that “Peter Molyneux” meant “wooden tit” in Japanese: “If I wanted to break the ice anywhere I just said ‘Molyneux’ and the whole room would break up.” He cultivated the persona in such interviews of a slightly befuddled ordinary bloke who liked to spend his time down at the pub when he wasn’t making games, who had no idea how he had stumbled into this charmed career of his. Substitute playing games for making them, and remove the charmed career, and he seemed of a piece with most of the people reading the interviews. He never missed an opportunity to run down his programming skills. “When we wrote &lt;em&gt;Populous&lt;/em&gt;,” he said, “we barely knew how to put a sprite onto the screen.” In the end, he claimed, “programming isn’t really that skillful. Anybody can learn to program, anybody, within a week.” Asked to describe Bullfrog in a single sentence, he did so in three words: “Disorganized but keen.” Or, as he put it on another occasion: “We write computer games. We’re not businessmen.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_4366&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;35&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2020/09/bullfrog-after-populous/molyneux-2/&quot; rel=&quot;attachment wp-att-4366&quot;&gt;&lt;img aria-describedby=&quot;caption-attachment-4366&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-4366&quot; src=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/molyneux.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;245&quot; height=&quot;164&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;caption-attachment-4366&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;The Peter Molyneux toilet interview for &lt;em&gt;Zero&lt;/em&gt; magazine in December of 1991. Molyneux had by then perfected the art of press relations, which in the case of the gaming magazines often came down to the simple expedient of taking the youthful journalists down to the pub and getting them blind drunk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In keeping with this everyman persona, Molyneux evinced no interest whatsoever in professional credentials. Recruitment at Bullfrog operated on the principle of “show us what you got,” via little classified advertisements placed in the nether reaches of the same magazines that were featuring Molyneux and his games on their covers. Bullfrog endeared themselves even more by running tutorials in said magazines, teaching graphics and programming tricks; at least one series of tutorials concluded with a contest for those who had been following along diligently, the prize a potential job with Bullfrog. “You too can make games!” was the message. And people loved Molyneux for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there was also another side to Molyneux: the side that &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; a real businessman, whatever his claims to the contrary — a businessman who was watching his industry with eagle eyes. When someone deigned to ask him a serious question, he could deliver a cogent, sometimes even prescient response. For example, when asked whether personal computers would ultimately win out over consoles as game-playing devices, he had this to say:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Definitely not. PCs are too much bother, even with CDs. You’ve got to configure one of the 30 trillion sound cards’ 30 trillion settings. I don’t understand all these DMAs and IRQs and all that crap. I just fiddle around until I get it right. Until they sort that out, the machine is just going to terrify people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the general state of games in the early 1990s, he had this to say:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current trend in games like simulations, adventures, and some sports sims is that they are getting progressively harder, cleverer, and more challenging. But that doesn’t necessarily make them better games. The trouble is that a lot of games are getting so hard that only the very best gamers can play them. The first rule of game design is that you mustn’t produce games that are too complex for people to play. Being overly complex for the sake of being complex is not a good idea. Complexity is good as long as it doesn’t get in the way of the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re into a new thing called interactive drama. Everybody’s doing interactive drama with interactive plots and interactive characters. But I think it’s going to be a tough, tough thing to do. Hollywood spends millions of pounds on scripts. They have hundreds and hundreds of scriptwriters and they get it right once or twice a year. And little game designers like us are coming along and we’re going to write this script which is going to have infinite variations, is going to be as entertaining as any Hollywood film, is going to have cinematic sequences in it, and we’re going to sell it for four times more than you can buy a video for. There’s something wrong there. Either we’re very, very clever chaps and Hollywood has been doing it wrong for the last 100 years, or perhaps we’re talking out of our arses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quotes like these made Molyneux into something of a spokesman for the British games industry, in the mainstream as well as the specialty press. Whatever the intrinsic merits of claims like those above, they had the advantage of poking holes in exactly the sorts of games which British studios tended to lack the resources to do as well as the Americans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this period, British games still largely meant Amiga games. Thus it was tough for Molyneux, both in his role as spokesman for his industry and as a proud Briton, to admit that Bullfrog just couldn’t continue to develop their games on the Amiga first and remain competitive in the international market; the latest MS-DOS machines were pulling too rapidly ahead of Commodore’s trusty old platform. Bullfrog’s next big project after &lt;em&gt;Populous II&lt;/em&gt; would be developed first on MS-DOS and then ported to the Amiga in slightly downgraded form — the opposite of the studio’s earlier approach. For, as Molyneux put it, “you can let your imagination run wild” on an MS-DOS machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same project would be a welcome, much-needed departure in both form and content from the games Bullfrog had spent the last few years making. It would be a much grittier, more down-to-earth affair of rival corporations doing battle with one another in an oligarchic worldwide dystopia of the near future. As such, it was of a piece with many of the print fictions which young men like the Bullfrog crew were reading in the early 1990s — think Neal Stephenson’s &lt;em&gt;Snow Crash&lt;/em&gt; and, reaching just a little further back, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2016/11/the-prophet-of-cyberspace&quot;&gt;William Gibson’s &lt;em&gt;Neuromancer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the original popularizer of cyberpunk cool. (Self-effacing as ever, Molyneux claimed that “I read the first three chapters of &lt;em&gt;Neuromancer&lt;/em&gt;, but it all went a bit above my head.”) Still, Bullfrog did add their own sprinkling of dark British humor to the mountain of cyberpunk clichés. For many months, they called the game simply &lt;em&gt;Bob&lt;/em&gt;, after the infamously ruthless &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2017/08/a-tale-of-the-mirror-world-part-8-life-after-tetris&quot;&gt;British media mogul Robert Maxwell&lt;/a&gt;, whose suspicious death aboard his luxury yacht and the subsequent revelation of financial malfeasance throughout his empire dominated tabloid headlines during the period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, though, &lt;em&gt;Bob&lt;/em&gt; became known as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mobygames.com/game/syndicate&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Syndicate&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Bullfrog spent a full two years working on it, marking the longest gap between games in their entire history as a studio. They claimed the end result to contain as much code and graphics as every one of their previous games combined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whereas &lt;em&gt;Populous&lt;/em&gt; and its descendants were played entirely from a single interface, &lt;em&gt;Syndicate&lt;/em&gt; was a more disparate affair. As the owner of a tiny upstart corporation bent, naturally enough, on taking over the world, you had to allocate research funds for equipment and cybernetic enhancements for your army of operatives, whilst choosing missions to send them on from a &lt;em&gt;Risk&lt;/em&gt;-like strategic map. But it was in the missions themselves, which played out in real time from an isometric perspective, that you spent the vast majority of your time. Here you had more direct control over your operatives than you did in &lt;em&gt;Populous&lt;/em&gt;, but they still had minds of their own, which could cause them to react with a spontaneous burst of gunfire if, for example, an enemy agent popped up in their path; it might also cause them to refuse to obey an obviously dangerous command. The missions took place in living city streets replete with civilians as well as combatants, presenting ample opportunities for mayhem. &lt;em&gt;Syndicate&lt;/em&gt; has been called a proto-&lt;em&gt;Grand Theft Auto&lt;/em&gt;, what with the way it tempts its player to indulge in random violence and acts of destruction for their own sake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_4373&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2020/09/bullfrog-after-populous/syndicate-2/&quot; rel=&quot;attachment wp-att-4373&quot;&gt;&lt;img aria-describedby=&quot;caption-attachment-4373&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-4373&quot; src=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/syndicate.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/syndicate.png 640w, https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/syndicate-300x225.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;caption-attachment-4373&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Syndicate&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, when it finally appeared in late 1993, just weeks before &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2020/06/the-shareware-scene-part-4-doom&quot;&gt;id Software’s landmark &lt;em&gt;DOOM&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Syndicate&lt;/em&gt; struck many as the natural British companion to that American game, another avatar of a movement toward ever more visceral forms of violence in games. As in &lt;em&gt;DOOM&lt;/em&gt;, blood splashed everywhere in &lt;em&gt;Syndicate&lt;/em&gt; with gleeful abandon, and much of the appeal of acquiring new weapons was in the visible carnage they created. This prompted a brief-lived round of nervous stock-taking in the magazines of both countries — until the same magazines, seeing that hordes of players loved the violence, learned to defer to the readers who buttered their bread.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extreme though it was by contemporary standards, the violence in the finished &lt;em&gt;Syndicate&lt;/em&gt; was reportedly toned down from earlier versions, where you had been allowed to kill babies and pets. Play testers “told us we were going too far,” mused Molyneux. “Funnily enough, they objected most to killing the puppies…” Yet he remained unapologetic on the whole:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We made Syndicate high in gore to be more realistic. I know this sounds like a cop-out, but it’s the player who’s violent, not us. All we’ve done is give a loaded weapon to the player and it’s up to them how to use it. I’ve always hated games that gloss over violence. Surely showing the realism of a violent act is better than discussing it? It’s not that &lt;em&gt;Syndicate&lt;/em&gt; had done anything new with violence, it’s just that it shows it like it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For all the changes it evinced over what had come before, &lt;em&gt;Syndicate&lt;/em&gt; was a typical Peter Molyneux game in other ways. It started out thoroughly entrancing, but went on way too long, with only a handful of fixed mission types on offer as you slowly — &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; slowly — took over the world. By the mid-game, you had discovered most of the cool gear and cybernetic enhancements, and what had started out fresh and exciting had begun to turn into a bit of a grind. Thus &lt;em&gt;Syndicate&lt;/em&gt; became another Molyneux game that far more players started than finished. Nevertheless, its initial appeal was enough to make it Bullfrog’s biggest hit since the original &lt;em&gt;Populous&lt;/em&gt;, and the game and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mobygames.com/game/syndicate-american-revolt&quot;&gt;its 1994 expansion pack&lt;/a&gt; are still fondly remembered by many today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By this point, Bullfrog had grown from just a few employees to about forty, enough to have multiple projects on the boil at one time, all receiving varying degrees of attention from the hardworking and endlessly enthusiastic Peter Molyneux. Thus the next game arrived barely six months after &lt;em&gt;Syndicate&lt;/em&gt;. It would prove to be one of Molyneux’s most influential creations of all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project had its genesis in the first game he ever made, a text-only business simulation called &lt;em&gt;Entrepreneur&lt;/em&gt;, of which he had sold exactly two copies — one of them quite possibly to his mother — in 1983. That failure had continued to rankle even amidst all the success he enjoyed in later years, as did the urge to make another, less dry business simulation that would appeal to more people. “Then one day the perfect idea hit me,” Molyneux says. “I’d create a game where you control a theme park.” Molyneux:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love theme parks, and it was a great excuse to do some really good research. It’s also something where you often go back and think, “If I’d been given the chance to design this place I wouldn’t have put this here, or that there, etc.” And it’s also something that people can immediately associate themselves with. If I tell you that this game enables you to design theme parks, then you immediately know what I’m talking about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was indeed a brilliant stroke, one with natural appeal well beyond the typical gamer demographic who enjoyed the likes of &lt;em&gt;Syndicate&lt;/em&gt;. Visually at least, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mobygames.com/game/theme-park&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Theme Park&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; would be the polar opposite of that game, cheerful and bright where it had been gritty and dark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_4369&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2020/09/bullfrog-after-populous/theme_park1/&quot; rel=&quot;attachment wp-att-4369&quot;&gt;&lt;img aria-describedby=&quot;caption-attachment-4369&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-4369&quot; src=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/theme_park1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/theme_park1.png 640w, https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/theme_park1-300x225.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;caption-attachment-4369&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Theme Park&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Released in mid-1994, &lt;em&gt;Theme Park&lt;/em&gt; became a monster hit — bigger than &lt;em&gt;Syndicate&lt;/em&gt;, even bigger than &lt;em&gt;Populous&lt;/em&gt; after it was ported to every viable or semi-viable game-playing gadget in the world. Its bright and bouncy visual aesthetic presaged the Casual Revolution in games that was still some years away, while its impact on the themes and mechanics of games to come would prove even more pronounced. In particular, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mobygames.com/game/windows/rollercoaster-tycoon&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rollercoaster Tycoon&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a direct heir to &lt;em&gt;Theme Park&lt;/em&gt; which was released by MicroProse in 1999, sold even better than Bullfrog’s take on the concept — in fact, became one of the best-selling computer games in history. Today amusement parks and roller coasters remain a staple of gaming, from the more elaborate examples of the breed available at online stores like Steam to more easygoing affairs that you can play right in your browser. Almost all of them owe not just a thematic (hah!) debt to &lt;em&gt;Theme Park&lt;/em&gt; but a direct mechanical and visual one as well, from the thought bubbles that appear over the heads of the guests wandering through the park to their whimsically cartoony graphical style.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It thus pains even more than usual to note how horribly &lt;em&gt;Theme Park&lt;/em&gt; itself has aged, even in comparison to most of the other early Bullfrog games. Few games evidence as profound a mismatch between their surface aesthetics and their underlying gameplay as this one does. The cutesy nature of the former can confuse you for a long time, disguising the fact that the latter really doesn’t represent as great a departure from the worldview of &lt;em&gt;Syndicate&lt;/em&gt; as it seems to let on. At bottom, &lt;em&gt;Theme Park&lt;/em&gt; is a nasty, cynical little game, amoral if not actively immoral — a game where your concern isn’t with the happiness of your guests at all, but strictly with the amount of money you can extract from them; a profitable theme park with miserable patrons is not only possible but the only practical road to success. This is the kind of game where you over-salt the patrons’ fries to get them to buy more soda, which cups you stuff to the brim with ice to… well, you get the picture. If you come to this game wanting to build a beautiful amusement park and show everybody who visits it a great time, as the Molyneux quote above would imply you can, you’ll wind up bankrupt and disillusioned in extremely short order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s really hard to know what parts of Theme Park to attribute to intentional subversiveness and what parts to simple tone-deafness. The intro video is a perfect case in point. Was Bullfrog aware of just how weird and creepy this thing is? The dog has the right idea: “Hell, no, leave me at home!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if you’re willing to play the game on its own cynical terms, it has all sorts of other problems. There’s a paucity of useful feedback on both a global and granular level, which often puts you in the supremely frustrating position of failing for reasons you can’t determine. The interface in general is inscrutable in too many places, the level of micromanagement required is exhausting, and, because this is a Peter Molyneux game, winning is a task so herculean that virtually no one has ever done so: after building your first successful park in Britain, you’re expected to choose another location elsewhere in the world and do so again, ad nauseum. None of these later parks are different in any fundamental way from the first — you have the exact same rides and shops and food stands at your disposal throughout — and so the whole exercise becomes absurdly repetitive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Theme Park&lt;/em&gt; was a hugely innovative and massively influential game, but it just wasn’t a very good one, even in its heyday. Its appeal was always rooted more in what it purported to be than what it actually managed to be. Because everybody loves a theme park, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_4370&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2020/09/bullfrog-after-populous/theme_park2/&quot; rel=&quot;attachment wp-att-4370&quot;&gt;&lt;img aria-describedby=&quot;caption-attachment-4370&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-4370&quot; src=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/theme_park2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/theme_park2.png 640w, https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/theme_park2-300x225.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;caption-attachment-4370&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;A ride goes haywire and a kid goes flying. I’m pretty sure this part &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; deliberately subversive…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bullfrog’s second game of 1994 — also the last one which we’ll be visiting as part of this little survey today — might have appeared at the time to be an attempt to jump onto the 3D-action bandwagon unleashed by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2020/05/the-shareware-scene-part-3-the-id-boys&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wolfenstein 3D&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;em&gt;DOOM&lt;/em&gt;. In reality, though, Bullfrog had been experimenting with first-person 3D in-house for years. Those experiments finally led, after many detours and false starts, to &lt;em&gt;Magic Carpet&lt;/em&gt;, whose namesake you got to fly — because, as Molyneux wryly put it, every other possible form of flight had already been exhaustively simulated by that point. As one of several wizards, your goal was to build up your arsenal of spells and mana in order to conquer all of the opposing wizards and take over the world. And then — remember, this was a Bullfrog game — you were expected to do the same thing in fifty or so more worlds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first Bullfrog game not to be ported at all to lower-powered platforms like the Amiga, &lt;em&gt;Magic Carpet&lt;/em&gt; was a stunning technical achievement in its time. While other 3D action games segmented themselves into discrete levels made up of interior spaces only, it gave you a complete open-ended world to explore. It was a forthrightly artsy game, something &lt;em&gt;DOOM&lt;/em&gt; and the rash of similar games which followed it certainly never aspired to be. In that spirit, it contained no words during actual gameplay, nothing to distract from the evocative wonder of its world. Bullfrog’s staffers talked in interviews about the joy they got just from drifting around above its landscapes before they’d put any enemies in — playing as they did so, they said only half facetiously, their &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=g4w4aKsWzkI&quot;&gt;Enya albums&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Magic Carpet&lt;/em&gt; even had a special stereoscopic 3D mode, for those able to buy or make 3D glasses to suit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_4372&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2020/09/bullfrog-after-populous/magic_carpet-2/&quot; rel=&quot;attachment wp-att-4372&quot;&gt;&lt;img aria-describedby=&quot;caption-attachment-4372&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-4372&quot; src=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/magic_carpet.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/magic_carpet.png 640w, https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/magic_carpet-300x225.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;caption-attachment-4372&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;The graphics in &lt;em&gt;Magic Carpet&lt;/em&gt; remain strikingly beautiful to this day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the time you got four or five levels into it, however, it revealed itself to suffer from the standard set of Bullfrog problems. Each of its worlds was superficially different from the one before, but not in a way that really challenged you or introduced a sense of progression beyond the increasing level number on your status screen. The game shot its bolt at the beginning, then just kept giving you more of the same. Peter Molyneux spoke often in interviews about his desire to give gamers lots of value for their money by making &lt;em&gt;big&lt;/em&gt; games. Yet, like songwriters with a knack for melody who have no clue how to take it to the bridge, he and his mates consistently struggled to find ways of varying their formulas so that their games weren’t just more of the same for hours on end. As it was, what you saw in the first hour of a Bullfrog game was what you would continue to see for the next hundred hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And for once, this Bullfrog game’s presentation and theme alone weren’t enough to save it on store shelves. Its abstracted and almost aggressively artsy personality combined with its high production costs and high system requirements to make it Bullfrog’s first outright money loser since &lt;em&gt;Flood&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;How, then, should we sum up these five busy years in the life of Peter Molyneux and his first company? We can feel certain that anything we do say must apply almost equally to his career since 1994; whether you love or hate his work, its strengths and weaknesses haven’t changed very much over the decades. An unkind assessment — of which there have been many in the last ten years in particular, as Molyneux’s real or perceived penchant for over-hyping and under-delivering has come home to roost — might peg him as a bit of a dilettante, an ideas man unwilling to do the hard work to turn his ideas into balanced games that remain playable and interesting over the long term. But the reality is, as usual, more complex than any single pejorative — or compliment, for that matter — can encompass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some keys to the puzzle of Peter Molyneux can undoubtedly be found in the scene from which he sprang. His design aesthetic, like that of so many British game developers, was to a large extent forged by the limited resources — in terms of both target hardware and finances — which they had at their disposal. Bullfrog’s stubborn reliance on procedurally-generated rather than handcrafted levels, often to their games’ detriment, can be traced back at least to Ian Bell and David Braben’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2013/12/elite&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Elite&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and the vast eight-galaxy universe it packed into a 32 K BBC Micro via the magic of the Fibonacci sequence. When one didn’t have much space to store handcrafted levels and didn’t have many people to hand to make them, procedural generation seemed the only practical way forward. But Bullfrog stuck with it to the exclusion of other approaches for too long — long after other approaches became viable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other pieces of the puzzle are more idiosyncratic to Molyneux himself, a fellow whose own personality was always all but inseparable from that of his company. Already by the mid-1990s, his tendency to stretch himself in too many directions at once was starting to become an issue. During the period of &lt;em&gt;Theme Park&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Magic Carpet&lt;/em&gt;, Bullfrog also worked on something called &lt;em&gt;Creation&lt;/em&gt;, where you would breed predatory fish in an underwater base to attack your rivals on the ocean floor. Molyneux even mooted linking &lt;em&gt;Creation&lt;/em&gt; with &lt;em&gt;Magic Carpet&lt;/em&gt;: “If you’re playing &lt;em&gt;Magic Carpet&lt;/em&gt;, you will be able to jump off the carpet and into the ocean. The computer will then sense whether you have &lt;em&gt;Creation&lt;/em&gt; on your hard disk and plunge you straight into that, based totally on the world you were just flying around [in].” Another work in progress, with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2020/02/myst-or-the-drawbacks-to-success&quot;&gt;highly inadvisable&lt;/a&gt; title of &lt;em&gt;MIST (My Incredible Superhero Team)&lt;/em&gt;, would let you build and control your own superhero: “If you want to make him strong and give him rubber wings and death vision, then you can do that. But of course, they’ve all got their Achilles heel.” And then there was &lt;em&gt;Biosphere&lt;/em&gt;, featuring a more elaborate, planet-wide take on genetic engineering along with a fictional context shamelessly ripped off from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2013/11/douglas-adams&quot;&gt;Douglas Adams&lt;/a&gt;, where you would “run a team of genetic and planet engineers who modify planets for shiploads of colonists. Unfortunately for you, the colonists are generally hairdressers and telephone engineers, so when they get there they’re pretty useless — and they’ll probably be eaten by dinosaurs. So you have to protect them.” None of these games were ever completed, despite a substantial amount of time and resources being devoted to each of them. Indeed, as the resources available to him increased, Molyneux’s proclivity for rushing enthusiastically down such blind alleys increased in equal measure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Molyneux’s passionate prioritization of experimentation over the nuts and bolts of game design made him a less complete designer than, say, a Sid Meier. And yet he, along with other designers of a similar bent, have been scarcely less necessary for the evolution of their medium. Few if any designers have dared to put more &lt;em&gt;new stuff&lt;/em&gt; out there than Molyneux, even if often in imperfect form. Such experiments can become the building blocks for more grounded designers to build upon, as the example of the badly flawed &lt;em&gt;Theme&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Park&lt;/em&gt; begetting the absolutely brilliant &lt;em&gt;Rollercoaster Tycoon&lt;/em&gt; proves in spades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another component of Molyneux’s claim to the status of gaming visionary is more generalized: his complete conviction during the early 1990s that, as he put it, “multiplayer games are the future of gaming.” With the exception only of &lt;em&gt;Theme Park&lt;/em&gt;, every Molyneux game from &lt;em&gt;Populous&lt;/em&gt; on not only supported multiplayer sessions between players on separate computers&lt;sup id=&quot;rf1-4362&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2020/09/bullfrog-after-populous/#fn1-4362&quot; title=&quot;Multiplayer &amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Syndicate&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt; was made available to the public only in the expansion pack.&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; but was literally designed for it first and foremost. That is to say that a serial or network link-up went into &lt;em&gt;Populous&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Powermonger&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Populous II&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Syndicate&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Magic Carpet&lt;/em&gt; long before anyone even began to think about adding a computer opponent. One might even call this fact the perfect riposte to all of my complaints about these Bullfrog games. If you played them alone, you were, in Molyneux’s mind anyway, playing them &lt;em&gt;wrong&lt;/em&gt; in some fundamental sense. Complaints about the sameness of a game from level to level no longer carry much weight when you’re playing against that ultimate agent of unpredictability, a fellow human. While the nature of the times dictated that most people played them solo, there are nevertheless all sorts of anecdotes about the sharing of those early Bullfrog games among friends; my favorite might be the teenage next-door neighbors who made a 25-meter cable to run between their bedroom windows so that they could play &lt;em&gt;Populous&lt;/em&gt; together every night to their hearts’ content. Stories like these, soon to be joined by tales of multiplayer &lt;em&gt;DOOM&lt;/em&gt;, were clear signposts in their day to where much of gaming was heading, just as soon as the world’s telecommunications infrastructure caught up to the designers’ vision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bullfrog and Peter Molyneux have ironically suffered the opposite fate from that of the standard clichés about pioneers. Greatly appreciated in their own time for all of the bold new things they attempted to do and be, their games’ practical deficiencies seem all too obvious to our more jaded eyes of today. But, even if we can’t quite praise any one them as a standalone masterpiece, we can recognize the purpose they served in opening up so much virgin territory for exploration by later, often better games. And if Molyneux himself has sinned by promising too much too often, it should be recognized as well that his transgressions have never had their roots in greed or guile. He just wants to make really, really amazing games — wants to make lots of them, thereby to make lots and lots of people happy. There are worse character flaws to have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;strong&gt;Sources:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Retro Gamer&lt;/em&gt; 39, 40, 43, 69, and 71; &lt;em&gt;New Computer Express&lt;/em&gt; of January 20 1990, October 27 1990, and May 11 1991; &lt;em&gt;CU Amiga&lt;/em&gt; of October 1990, February 1991, December 1991, December 1992, November 1993, January 1994, and February 1994; &lt;em&gt;Computer Gaming World&lt;/em&gt; of January 1991, April 1991, and December 1994; &lt;em&gt;The One&lt;/em&gt; of April 1990, July 1990, December 1990, May 1991, July 1991, December 1991, May 1992, May 1993, June 1993, December 1993, October 1994, and March 1995; &lt;em&gt;Amiga Format&lt;/em&gt; of February 1992, October 1992, 1992 annual, June 1994, and May 1995; &lt;em&gt;Zero&lt;/em&gt; of December 1991; &lt;em&gt;Edge&lt;/em&gt; of January 1994, June 1994, November 1994, March 1995, May 1995, July 1995, and November 1995; &lt;em&gt;PC Zone&lt;/em&gt; of June 1993 and November 1994; &lt;em&gt;PC Review&lt;/em&gt; of July 1992; &lt;em&gt;Next Generation&lt;/em&gt; premier issue. Video sources include the documentary &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.frombedroomstobillions.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;From Bedrooms to Billions&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kNHGG_UU2wY&quot;&gt;series 3 episode 3 of &lt;em&gt;Bad Influence&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gog.com/game/populous_2&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Populous II&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gog.com/game/syndicate&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Syndicate&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gog.com/game/theme_park&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Theme Park&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gog.com/game/magic_carpet&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Magic Carpet&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; are all available as digital purchases from GOG.com.)&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 16:02:51 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>doppp</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.filfre.net/2020/09/bullfrog-after-populous/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>SoftBank unmasked as ‘Nasdaq whale’ that stoked tech rally</title>
<link>https://www.ft.com/content/75587aa6-1f1f-4e9d-b334-3ff866753fa2</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.ft.com/content/75587aa6-1f1f-4e9d-b334-3ff866753fa2</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;SoftBank is the “Nasdaq whale” that has bought billions of dollars’ worth of US equity derivatives in a series of trades that stoked the fevered rally in big tech stocks before a sharp pullback on Thursday and Friday, according to people familiar with the matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Japanese conglomerate had been snapping up options in tech stocks during the past month in huge amounts, fuelling the largest ever trading volumes in contracts linked to individual companies, these people said. One banker described it as a “dangerous” bet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aggressive move into the options market marks a new chapter for the investment powerhouse, which in recent years has made huge bets on privately held technology start-ups through its $100bn Vision Fund. After the coronavirus market tumult hit those bets, the company established an asset management unit for public investments using capital contributed by its founder, Masayoshi Son. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it has also made a splash in trading derivatives linked to some of those new investments, which has shocked market veterans. “These are some of the biggest trades I’ve seen in 20 years of doing this,” said one derivatives-focused US hedge fund manager. “The flow is huge.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The surge in purchases of call options — derivatives that give the user the right to buy a stock at a pre-agreed price — has been the talk of Wall Street, as the sheer size of the trades appears to have exacerbated a “melt-up” in many big technology stocks over the past few months. In August alone, Tesla’s share price shot up 74 per cent, while Apple gained 21 per cent, Google’s parent Alphabet rose 10 per cent and Amazon 9 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One person familiar with SoftBank’s trades said it was “gobbling up” options on a scale that was even making some people within the organisation nervous. “People are caught with their pants down, massively short. This can continue. The whale is still hungry.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SoftBank declined to comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;n-content-layout&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.ft.com/__origami/service/image/v2/images/raw/https%3A%2F%2Fd6c748xw2pzm8.cloudfront.net%2Fprod%2Fbb4db9c0-eea1-11ea-a3eb-6bc7dd6676b0-standard.png?dpr=1&amp;amp;fit=scale-down&amp;amp;quality=highest&amp;amp;source=next&amp;amp;width=700&quot; data-id=&quot;https://api.ft.com/content/ec3e0924-7fc9-4cf6-94ea-6ef8f086ef34&quot; data-image-type=&quot;graphic&quot; data-original-image-width=&quot;700&quot; data-original-image-height=&quot;511&quot; alt=&quot;Chart showing notional volume ($bn) traded in listed US equity options (10-day rolling average), indicating that single stock call option volume has been rising rapidly&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Nasdaq was at one point on Friday down 10 per cent from its peak — the common definition of a correction — yet the options boom means that the US stock market remains vulnerable to further bursts of volatility, according to Charlie McElligott, a strategist at Nomura. “The street is still very much in a dangerous space, and that flow is still out there,” he wrote in a note on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The overall nominal value of calls traded on individual US stocks has averaged $335bn a day over the past two weeks, according to Goldman Sachs. That is more than triple the rolling average between 2017 and 2019. The retail trading boom has played a big part in the frenzy, but investors say the size of many recent option purchases are far too big to be retail-driven. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unusually, single-stock call trading volumes have surged beyond the average daily volumes of calls on the broader US stock market, and are almost as high as the level of trading in index puts — which give the buyer the right to sell at a preset price and act as a popular form of insurance against stocks falling. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;n-content-recommended--single-story&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;n-content-recommended__title&quot;&gt;Recommended&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;o-teaser o-teaser--article o-teaser--small o-teaser--stacked o-teaser--has-image js-teaser&quot; data-id=&quot;41970bab-beb5-4e83-aa78-29e939f4041b&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;o-teaser__image-container js-teaser-image-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;o-teaser__image-placeholder&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;o-teaser__image&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ft.com/__origami/service/image/v2/images/raw/https%3A%2F%2Fd1e00ek4ebabms.cloudfront.net%2Fproduction%2F9b14b629-2244-430c-893f-57e5383d3db0.jpg?source=next&amp;amp;fit=scale-down&amp;amp;dpr=2&amp;amp;width=240&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;The size and aggressiveness of the mysterious call buyer, coupled with the summer trading lull, has been a big factor in the buoyant performance of many big tech names as well as the broader US stock market, according to Mr McElligott. This week, he warned that dynamics around options meant the heavy purchases forced banks on the other side of the trades to hedge themselves by buying stocks, in a “classic ‘tail wags the dog’ feedback loop”. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This explains the US stock market climbing in tandem with the Vix index — often referred to as Wall Street’s “fear gauge” — and meant that equities were fragile and vulnerable to the kind of sudden setback that erupted on Thursday. “The equity volatility complex is acting ‘broken’ and indicative that ‘something’s gotta give’,” Mr McElligott warned in a note shortly before the Nasdaq fell 5 per cent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One banker familiar with the latest options trading activity said &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ft.com/content/acbd4efd-e8ef-4d16-bf0c-83fc4df83601&quot; data-trackable=&quot;link&quot;&gt;Thursday’s market pullback&lt;/a&gt; would have been painful for SoftBank, but he expected the buying to resume. A larger and longer-lasting stock market decline would be more damaging for this strategy, and would probably involve rapid declines, he added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The options buying comes alongside $10bn in public investments SoftBank is targeting through its new asset management arm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://sec.report/Document/0001062993-20-004032/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; data-trackable=&quot;link&quot;&gt;filing&lt;/a&gt; to the Securities and Exchange Commission last month, SoftBank has bought stakes of almost $2bn in Amazon, Alphabet, Microsoft and Tesla — investments that are partially funded by cash from its $41bn asset sale programme that was triggered by a collapse in its share price during the Covid-19 market turmoil. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Additional reporting by James Fontanella-Khan&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article has been updated to correct Tesla’s share price rise&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 14:44:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>xoxoy</dc:creator>
<og:title>SoftBank unmasked as ‘Nasdaq whale’ that stoked tech rally</og:title>
<og:description>Japanese conglomerate has been snapping up options in huge amounts over past month</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.ft.com/__origami/service/image/v2/images/raw/https%3A%2F%2Fd1e00ek4ebabms.cloudfront.net%2Fproduction%2F01e44d82-5be4-43a7-a299-c87a74be55be.jpg?source=next-opengraph&amp;fit=scale-down&amp;width=900</og:image>
<og:url>https://www.ft.com/content/75587aa6-1f1f-4e9d-b334-3ff866753fa2</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-GB</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.ft.com/content/75587aa6-1f1f-4e9d-b334-3ff866753fa2</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>List of YouTube channels for improving web development and programming skills</title>
<link>https://devandgear.com/posts/the-ultimate-list-of-youtube-channels-to-boost-your-web-development-and-programming-skills/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://devandgear.com/posts/the-ultimate-list-of-youtube-channels-to-boost-your-web-development-and-programming-skills/</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-srcset=&quot;https://source.unsplash.com/4-EeTnaC1S4/480 480w, https://source.unsplash.com/4-EeTnaC1S4/640 640w, https://source.unsplash.com/4-EeTnaC1S4/960 960w, https://source.unsplash.com/4-EeTnaC1S4/1280 1280w&quot; data-sizes=&quot;auto&quot; src=&quot;https://source.unsplash.com/4-EeTnaC1S4/50x0&quot; alt=&quot;A man watching his laptop&quot; class=&quot;lazyload&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@sickhews&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Wes Hicks&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article__meta&quot; readability=&quot;8.7631578947368&quot;&gt;&lt;time&gt;Sep 4, 2020&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These YouTubers are followed by thousands for their high-quality programming tutorials, find your favorite channel in this ultimate list to learn and boost your web development skills today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article-meta&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;in &lt;a href=&quot;https://devandgear.com/categories/learning&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;16.66699410609&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article__content&quot; readability=&quot;19.854471955533&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reading and listening to someone might not be the same, especially when learning hard technical topics. With the rise of developers turned YouTubers, there is a vast choice of technical videos from all areas of software development available on YouTube. With that in mind, it has never been easier to learn the web development from scratch or just boost the level of your skills thanks to the enormous YouTube community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But finding the right YouTube channel might not be easy, so we created an ultimate list of channels for you to follow and start learning today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t forget to share, and let us know in the comments if your favorite YouTube channel is not listed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;article__share&quot; readability=&quot;19.61320754717&quot;&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Share this article&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you enjoy this article? Share it with your friends&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;article__aside&quot;&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;mc_embed_signup&quot;&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 13:59:58 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>bojanvidanovic</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://devandgear.com/posts/the-ultimate-list-of-youtube-channels-to-boost-your-web-development-and-programming-skills/</og:url>
<og:title>The Ultimate List of YouTube Channels to Boost your Web Development and Programming Skills · Dev &amp; Gear</og:title>
<og:description>These YouTubers are followed by thousands for their high-quality programming tutorials, find your favorite channel in this ultimate list to learn and boost your web development skills today.</og:description>
<og:image>https://source.unsplash.com/4-EeTnaC1S4/1280</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://devandgear.com/posts/the-ultimate-list-of-youtube-channels-to-boost-your-web-development-and-programming-skills/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Snake in a QR Code</title>
<link>https://itsmattkc.com/etc/snakeqr/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://itsmattkc.com/etc/snakeqr/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The above QR code contains a complete Windows executable that will run on Windows 7 and up. It's a simple but fully playable implementation of Snake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A QR code is a data storage medium like any other, and while it's almost always used to store ASCII text, it can also be used to store binary data. As such, virtually any computer data can theoretically be stored in a QR code provided it can fit within the size limitations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A QR code comes in various standard sizes, the largest being version 40 which can store up to 2,953 bytes (roughly 2.9 KB) of binary data. The above code is not quite that large, it's only storing around 1.4 KB of data (shrunk down from 3.2 KB with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.crinkler.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Crinkler&lt;/a&gt;, slightly larger than the executable shown in the video because I decided to add a little more functionality).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Method 1: Webcam (automatic)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can treat this QR code much like a QR code in the real world by using your computer's webcam to read it (e.g. after loading this page on a phone or printing the QR code out). For this, I recommend using zbarcam. I've included a download link with everything you need:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://itsmattkc.com/etc/snakeqr/zbarcam.zip&quot;&gt;Download zbarcam&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open &quot;Read Snake From QR.bat&quot;. After a moment, your webcam will activate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using either your phone screen or a print-out, hold the QR code up to the camera.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once it recognizes the code, it will close and Snake will appear, freshly read from the QR code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Method 2: Webcam (manual)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This method is the same as the above, however if you'd rather input the commands manually than running my script, go for it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol readability=&quot;-0.9728813559322&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://itsmattkc.com/etc/snakeqr/zbarcam.zip&quot;&gt;Download zbarcam&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open Command Prompt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;code&quot;&gt;cd&lt;/span&gt; to the zbarcam folder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Run the following command:
&lt;p class=&quot;code&quot;&gt;zbarcam --raw --oneshot -Sbinary &amp;gt; snake.exe&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The arguments used are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;code&quot;&gt;--raw&lt;/span&gt; - Disables any character encoding conversion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;code&quot;&gt;--oneshot&lt;/span&gt; - Stops reading and closes zbarcam after the code has been successfully read.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;code&quot;&gt;-Sbinary&lt;/span&gt; - Informs zbarcam that the data in the code is binary data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using either your phone screen or a print-out, hold the QR code up to the camera.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once it recognizes the code, it will close and an executable called &quot;snake.exe&quot; will appear in the same folder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open &quot;snake.exe&quot;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The version of zbarcam provided above has been patched to correctly output binary data on Windows. This project exposed a bug in zbarcam where binary data was incorrectly treated as text, inadvertently corrupting it as Windows attempted to convert LF line endings to CRLF. The fix used here has since been merged into zbar's master source code, but as of July 2020 no stable release version has included the fix yet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The version of zbarcam provided above has been compiled with DirectShow support for greater compatibility with webcam devices. In my video, I use a build that has not been compiled for DirectShow (using VfW instead) which leads to a black and white webcam feed. This build provides a feed in color.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a proof-of-concept, I wrote an implementation of Snake in JavaScript that, when minified, could also fit into the maximum QR code size which I briefly showcased in the video. Some people were interested in playing this, so &lt;a href=&quot;https://itsmattkc.com/etc/snakeqr/snake-minified.html&quot;&gt;it is available here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/QR_code&quot;&gt;QR code on Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;• &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mchehab/zbar&quot;&gt;ZBar on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 13:08:38 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>phit_</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://itsmattkc.com/etc/snakeqr/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Winamp Skin Museum</title>
<link>https://skins.webamp.org/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://skins.webamp.org/</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://skins.webamp.org/&quot;&gt;https://skins.webamp.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24373699&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24373699&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 438&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 202&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>0-_-0</dc:creator>
<og:title>Winamp Skin Museum</og:title>
<og:description>Infinite scroll through 65k Winamp skins with interactive preview</og:description>
<og:image>%PUBLIC_URL*/preview.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://skins.webamp.org/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A Requiem for a Dying Operating System (1994)</title>
<link>https://user.eng.umd.edu/~blj/funny/requium.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://user.eng.umd.edu/~blj/funny/requium.html</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;Content-Type&quot; content=&quot;text/html; charset=UTF-8&quot; /&gt;&lt;title&gt;A Requiem for a Dying Operating System&lt;/title&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;245.96130571395&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;To the Editors, Unix-Haters Handbook,&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have just received by EMAIL a copy of the preface to The Unix-Haters Handbook. For interest, I append my own contribution to this literature, which recently appeared in the &quot;Starlink Bulletin&quot; (the bulletin of the UK Starlink project, which supplies computing facilities to astronomers). It got a pretty good reception -- also a lot of hate-mail on Usenet uk.org.starlink.misc It was good to find that I Was Not Alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I look forward to a copy of the book as soon as my bookstore can get it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regards&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rachael Padman&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;or&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;VMS disappears (disappeared?) from the Cambridge Starlink node on the 1st of April 1994. This is not because no one wants to use it, and it is not because of demonstrable failings. It is because Unix is &lt;em&gt;thought&lt;/em&gt; (by some) to be a great improvement. In some ways it may be; in others it falls far short of what is required in a so-called standard. Of course it is too late to stop this happening, and the trend to Unix extends way beyond astronomy, but neither of these facts means that it is necessarily correct to abandon VMS, nor that we should not bemoan its passing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These views generally result in my being labeled a Luddite by the Unix priesthood. But Ned Ludd was right --- the new machines did &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; make conditions better for ordinary working folk: the people whose conditions were immediately improved were those who owned the machinery, and whose profits thereby increased. Similarly, the change to Unix will, in the short term at least, do more to provide employment for our computers minders than to improve the average astronomer's relationship with her computer. Unix does have its advantages, but few of these are intrinsic --- in the sense that they could &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; be implemented within other operating systems --- and to my mind they are far outweighed by the disadvantages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alright, I have to admit it. I don't like Unix (or is it &quot;unix&quot;?) Of course one can get used to almost anything. But is &quot;rm&quot; (pronounced &quot;remove&quot;) really synonymous with &quot;delete&quot;. Do I call the deleters when I want to move house. How would my first cousins once-deleted feel? And any real language is at least pronounceable. I have only been able to come up with one algorithm for creating Unix command names: think of a good English word to describe what you want to do, then think of an obscure near- or partial-synonym, throw away all the vowels, arbitrarily shorten what's left, and then, finally, as a sop to the literate programmer, maybe reinsert one of the missing vowels. Mnemosyne, goddess of memory, must be rolling in her grave. (She was, incidentally, the mother of the muses, including Urania, the muse of astronomy.) It is notable that all the machines I have used interactively in the past spoke to me in plain English. OK, they didn't necessarily have a big vocabulary, but typing HELP was always likely to return a menu of commands that was almost identical from machine to machine and whose function was immediately obvious. Although there are some really powerful features in Unix --- such as the pipe --- what I &lt;em&gt;see&lt;/em&gt; (and interact with) is a user interface designed by adolescents and constructed deliberately so as to make access to the machine as difficult as possible for a novice. Is this really a suitable foundation for an international standard?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In reply to this criticism one is normally reminded that Unix was invented for a PDP7, which had about as much memory as an earthworm and CPU power to match. That is, the user interface was designed to minimize the time required to decode a command. That meant short, fixed-case, commands, and no minimum matching. But 1969 is a long time ago, and both memory and speed have improved a thousandfold since then. This response thus goes directly to the core of the case against Unix. It is old-fashioned. Why is the world now, 25 years later, adopting as a long-term standard a primitive operating system designed when the capabilities of today's machines were then undreamed of? Actually, the answer is easy. Operating systems cost hardware manufacturers, and therefore consumers (us), money. Unix is free, and whatever its defects at least no one blames the hardware manufacturers. So in a world that thinks megaflops or Specmarks are the only indicator of computer power, Gresham's law holds --- bad software drives out the good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[This lemming-like rush to adopt Unix just now seems slightly curious. It will be ironic if it eventuates that Starlink has felt it necessary to adopt Unix just as Unix is itself superseded. Yet that appears to be a real possibility. Windows NT has been designed with distributed processing and interoperability as the major drivers. Here are two quotes from IEEE Spectrum, December 1993: &quot;... Windows NT, by covering almost all the latest RISC processors, opens the way to a consistent computing environment. Delighted early users are already contemplating making it their new standard.&quot; And: &quot;Thus Unix will go on evolving, but largely in order to keep up with Windows NT&quot;.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even the commands that &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; pronounceable are idiosyncratic to say the least. How can one understand &quot;biff&quot;?. As people never tire of telling me, it is the name of a programmer's dog (but you'll note, just in case you thought this might help you to memorize the command, this name starts with a lower case letter). It comes coupled with a twee American icon, that is meaningless in the UK context. And there are other examples. Grep suggests to me that the author of this one had been reading too much Robert Heinlein (you grok?), or possibly --- and this is in fact quite likely --- was under the influence of psychotropic substances at the time. Unix seems to consist largely of arcanae which be learnt only by taking instruction direct from a priesthood who seem largely to be stuck in the anal-retentive stage. When yesterday's six-year olds take over Unix development (in four or five years) I fully expect to see new commands ldo, nja, mch and rfl. After turtles, dinosaurs. Will the command tRex devour your competitor's data?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As intimated above, Unix documentation, or the lack thereof, is a serious problem. There is &lt;em&gt;no&lt;/em&gt; effective way to find out how to use Unix, other than sitting next to an adept and asking for help (and you know what these people are like. Don't you? Haven't you ever been in a computing centre to pick up some output late at night? Dirty cups half full of stale machine coffee, many with cigarette butts floating in them, the floor littered with Twinkies wrappers, insane giggling over some semi-pornographic picture cleverly printed out on a line printer using different characters overprinted to get the greyscale effect... Grab your output and run!). I remember on one occasion being logged into a Unix machine to send some mail, and, not knowing the command name, being unable to log out. It was an expensive 8000-mile long telephone connection, but the machine steadfastly refused to respond to &quot;help&quot; (or log, logout, logoff or quit). Finally someone suggested I type &quot;man&quot; (hey man, what the hell do I do now?), and it said &quot;Documentation is held in the user area in room 932&quot; (or something like that). Which didn't really help. Anyway, have &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; ever tried to use man? It's fine as long as you know what you are looking for. How would you ever find out the name of command given just the function you wanted to execute? You can't. I just tried to find out what the librarian was called, and man was silent on this issue. Sure it gives you pages of information about &quot;ar&quot;, but nowhere can you find out that it is the pages about &quot;ar&quot; that you need to read. Oh, say the adepts, you just use &quot;apropos&quot;. Apropos (or even &quot;apropos&quot;) means &quot;apt, appropriate&quot;, which, even if you knew the command existed, would not immediately suggest a way to find out information &lt;em&gt;about&lt;/em&gt; something. In addition to their other failings, the authors of this command are illiterate. On occasion, as in this instance, the makers of Unix have gone out of their way to &lt;em&gt;avoid&lt;/em&gt; using the appropriate word. What was wrong with `help'?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What next? Oh yes, case-dependence. Well, e.e.cummings made a fortune, or at least a reputation, out of refusing to use capital letters, and I guess Ken Thompson might very well have regarded him highly back in 1969. But it's only convention isn't it? Long after 1969 most terminals (teletypes we called them then) only had capital letters anyway, and I suppose that was stifling creativity or something. So if you want to use lower case letters of course that should be allowed. But why oh why invent a system where the commands MV, mv, Mv and mV can all do &lt;em&gt;different&lt;/em&gt; things? Here is my question to Unix apologists. Would you return your old-fashioned sneaker-net mail to the sender if he or she had forgotten to capitalize your name? Even if it contained a cheque?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, that's the user interface. As for the applications programs ... Even something fundamental like the SunOS f77 compiler is a disaster. It doesn't include the full standard as a subset (look at their OPEN statement for unformatted direct access if you don't believe me), and it contains, according to my Unix-literate colleagues, several major errors. Gresham's law strikes again. What about the editors? I don't have time to go into that one! One can only conclude that the makers of Unix held, and still hold, the ordinary computer &lt;em&gt;user&lt;/em&gt; in total contempt, and this viewpoint seems to me to be mirrored in the attitudes of the people who are inflicting this awful system on the rest of us. Does Unix's enormously steep learning curve have any function other than to &lt;em&gt;deter&lt;/em&gt; the faint-hearted, those who may want to use computers without necessarily dedicating their lives to them? It does not seem fanciful to suggest that Unix is primarily about separating out the elite from the proletariat, the real programmers from the quiche-eaters. It is about taking back the mantle of the priesthood, that was lost when manufacturers like DEC introduced operating systems like VMS. But of course it's all worthwhile really, because Unix is a standard, and that means it's the same everywhere, and will never change (see what I mean about self-defeating arguments?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me quote again from IEEE Spectrum: &quot;In reality, however, there are many Unix-based operating systems; the major ones include Apple Computer's AUX, Digital Equipment's Ultrix, Hewlett-Packard's HP-UX, IBM's AIX, the Open Software Foundation's OSF-1, Sun Microsystems' Sun OS and Solaris, and the Santa Cruz Operation's Xenix and SCO Unix. With such an assortment, users [who work] with platforms from several manufacturers [are] caught in the bind of supporting multiple releases of multiple versions of Unix.&quot; This monoculture is divided by a supposedly common tongue. Unix is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; a standard any more than English is. One of the touted virtues of Unix is that you can unplug any component and plug in something else with the same name, so that you can tailor it to your needs (indeed the Starlink .cshrc does this with your Tex commands!). So while you can go to any VMS system anywhere in the world and be instantly at home, you can't depend on a Unix command to do what you think it should anyway. Sometimes even the options are different. Take the tar command (please!), which is already a nightmare where lower-case `a' means &quot;check first&quot; and upper-case `A' means &quot;delete all my disk files without asking&quot; (or something like that --- I may not have the details exactly right). In some versions of tar these meanings are &lt;em&gt;reversed&lt;/em&gt;. This is a virtue?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OK, I admit it, I was joking there. But I'm not joking when I quote from SUN 145:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&quot;Ctrl-D End of File&quot;: Used to terminate data or text entry from the keyboard. &lt;em&gt;If you use it when being prompted for a command it will log you out!&lt;/em&gt;&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;File size is shown in Kbyte on a DECstation or Alpha, but in units of 512 bytes on a Sun.&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;Starlink's Unix software can be run from the C-shell or T-C shell, but not from the Bourne or Korn shells.&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;... but briefly, if the first line of a shell script is a normal command the Bourne shell is used [but it doesn't run Starlink software --- see above]; a comment, the C-shell is used, except that ...&quot; &lt;em&gt;Aaaaarrrrghhhhhh!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Douglas Adams may well have had Unix in mind when he described the products of the Sirius Cybernetics Corporation thus: &lt;a name=&quot;Sirius&quot; id=&quot;Sirius&quot;&gt;&quot;It is very easy to be blinded to the essential uselessness of them by the sense of achievement you get from getting them to work at all. In other words --- and this is the rock solid principle on which the whole of [its] Galaxy-wide success is founded --- their fundamental design flaws are completely hidden by their superficial design flaws.&quot;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a distressing mindset amongst Unix cognoscenti. Most attacks on Unix are answered with statements to the effect that make and grep are wonderful, that redirection and piping are very clever, and that the whole system is much more &quot;elegant&quot; than VMS. Well, I admit that make is wonderful. Still, it is only an application, and as such &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; be implemented on any operating system. As for grep... A few days ago I thought to search for each occurrence of the $ character in a piece of code (so that I could move it from its non-standard position at one end of the FORMAT statement to the alternative non-standard position at the other end, to make it work on a Sun). Dutifully I translated &quot;SEARCH [-...]*.FOR&quot;, and typed &quot;grep '$' ../*/*.f | lpr&quot; (Note the clever redirection of the output to the line printer.) The following morning I found the entire source code of SPECX in a heap beside the OKI printer. This does not strike me as very elegant! Neither is it elegant that the X-terminal driver is so primitive that it reflects characters immediately rather than waiting until input is requested, nor that everyone has to include keyboard remappings in their .Xthingy files (in fact this part of it is worse than a PC), nor that when talking to an applications program you can't edit the line you are typing except by using the delete key. It is not elegant that logical names --- sorry, environment variables --- are not inherited by programs, so that each program has to include code to parse input and translate the logical name before opening a file or whatever. Well, I'm sure I could go on forever. And the minute you criticize Unix to your Starlink friends they say &quot;Yes, I agree, but I'm not allowed to say that!&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Starlink mole has suggested to me that project staff are not unaware of the sort of Unix failing detailed here, but that the change to Unix was largely mandated by external pressures. Canute could not hold back the tide (and knew it), and obviously neither can Starlink, even it wants to. It's a pity however that the tide seems to be largely composed of lemmings --- that is, slightly computer-literate users, who are persuaded by the Unix hype, fancy joining the grep-awk priesthood, and mistakenly confuse the time spent learning how to use Unix with productive work. Unfortunately they never have to suffer the defects of the system they have foisted on the rest of us.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, it's not really funny. The change to Unix has real implications for astronomers, which have generally not been addressed. Yes, it means that we can all run Unix mega-packages like IRAF and SAO-Image (name your favourite). Unix and C however form a powerful deterrent to the average astronomer to write her or his own code (and the average astronomer's C is much, much worse than his Fortran used to be). The powers-that-be in the software world of course have always felt that &quot;ordinary&quot; users (astronomers in this case) should be using software and not writing it. The cynic might feel that since those same powers nearly all make their living by writing software, and get even more pay when they manage other programmers, then they have a vested interest in bringing about a state of affairs where the rest of us are reduced to mere supplicants, dependent on them for all our software needs. It is clear that Unix does not pose an insuperable barrier --- the ever-expanding armies of hackers out there are evidence enough that the barrier can be scaled given enough time and enthusiasm for the task. But hacking is not astronomy, and hackers are not astronomers, and it is astronomy and astronomers I worry about. We shouldn't have to scale the Unix barrier, and it is all the sadder because, since the advent of a VMS-based Starlink, ordinary astronomers have had something denied to most other scientists in this country --- readily accessible, reliable, user-friendly computing power that can be easily harnessed to a particular astronomical requirement. Maybe VMS does baby its users. Maybe we have paid more per Specmark so that we could use the Specmarks we had efficiently. But along with the rest of the world, we are now losing this nice friendly system. As with instrumentation and the National Observatories, we are having to teach our students how to fit their problems to facilities provided by others, whereas the UK reputation in astronomy was created by fitting the facilities to the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 08:13:22 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>aphrax</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://user.eng.umd.edu/~blj/funny/requium.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Reddit app got 50M downloads by making mobile web experience miserable</title>
<link>https://www.androidpolice.com/2020/09/02/reddit-gets-its-app-to-50-million-play-store-downloads-mostly-by-making-the-mobile-web-experience-miserable/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.androidpolice.com/2020/09/02/reddit-gets-its-app-to-50-million-play-store-downloads-mostly-by-making-the-mobile-web-experience-miserable/</guid>
<description>&lt;header class=&quot;post-header&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;comment-btn&quot; href=&quot;https://www.androidpolice.com/2020/09/02/reddit-gets-its-app-to-50-million-play-store-downloads-mostly-by-making-the-mobile-web-experience-miserable/#disqus_thread&quot; data-disqus-identifier=&quot;705932 https://www.androidpolice.com/?p=705932&quot;&gt;76&lt;/a&gt;





&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;post-hero post-hero-single&quot; href=&quot;https://www.androidpolice.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Reddit-official-app-dark-mode-hero.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-hero&quot; src=&quot;https://www.androidpolice.com/wp-content/themes/ap2/ap_resize/ap_resize.php?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.androidpolice.com%2Fwp-content%2Fuploads%2F2020%2F01%2FReddit-official-app-dark-mode-hero.png&amp;amp;w=728&quot; width=&quot;728&quot; height=&quot;437&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot; readability=&quot;51.147330960854&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyone who's tried to browse Reddit on their phone's web browser will be familiar with the constant popups prompting users to download the mobile app instead. Well, it looks like making their mobile site virtually unusable has paid off for the site, as its official Android app has just passed 50 million downloads on the Play Store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.androidpolice.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/02/ezgif.com-video-to-gif-1.gif&quot; class=&quot; no-style&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-705963&quot; src=&quot;https://www.androidpolice.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/02/ezgif.com-video-to-gif-1.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;711&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Video from a year ago &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/assholedesign/comments/9oy75c/reddits_mobile_website_design_somehow_got_even/&quot; class=&quot;external&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;via r/AssholeDesign&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center side-by-side-images images-3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.androidpolice.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/02/red1.png&quot; data-ratio=&quot;0.5607&quot; class=&quot;image-container no-style&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-smallish-size wp-image-705934&quot; src=&quot;https://www.androidpolice.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/02/red1-217x387.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;217&quot; height=&quot;387&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.androidpolice.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/02/red1-217x387.png 217w, https://www.androidpolice.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/02/red1-329x587.png 329w, https://www.androidpolice.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/02/red1-161x287.png 161w, https://www.androidpolice.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/02/red1.png 373w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 217px) 100vw, 217px&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.androidpolice.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/02/red2.png&quot; data-ratio=&quot;0.5681&quot; class=&quot;image-container no-style&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-smallish-size wp-image-705935&quot; src=&quot;https://www.androidpolice.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/02/red2-217x382.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;217&quot; height=&quot;382&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.androidpolice.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/02/red2-217x382.png 217w, https://www.androidpolice.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/02/red2-329x579.png 329w, https://www.androidpolice.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/02/red2-161x284.png 161w, https://www.androidpolice.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/02/red2.png 377w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 217px) 100vw, 217px&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.androidpolice.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/02/red3.png&quot; data-ratio=&quot;0.5578&quot; class=&quot;image-container no-style&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-smallish-size wp-image-705936&quot; src=&quot;https://www.androidpolice.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/02/red3-217x389.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;217&quot; height=&quot;389&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.androidpolice.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/02/red3-217x389.png 217w, https://www.androidpolice.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/02/red3-329x589.png 329w, https://www.androidpolice.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/02/red3-161x288.png 161w, https://www.androidpolice.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/02/red3.png 374w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 217px) 100vw, 217px&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Screenshots from two years ago &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18723583&quot; class=&quot;external&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;via Hacker News&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reddit only debuted its official app in 2016, so the 50-million milestone in that timespan is pretty impressive. Also impressive are the tactics that the company used on the mobile version of its site to get people to download said app (on both Android and iOS). Try to use the mobile site, and you'd be greeted with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/assholedesign/comments/9oy75c/reddits_mobile_website_design_somehow_got_even/&quot; class=&quot;external&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;endless popups and flashing buttons&lt;/a&gt; begging you to download the app. Reddit went as far as to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.androidpolice.com/2020/02/17/reddit-forcing-users-to-log-in-mobile-website/&quot;&gt;force people to log in to see content on the mobile site&lt;/a&gt; earlier this year, which people obviously weren't thrilled about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.androidpolice.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/02/red4.png&quot; class=&quot; no-style&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-medium wp-image-705988&quot; src=&quot;https://www.androidpolice.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/02/red4-329x695.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;329&quot; height=&quot;695&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.androidpolice.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/02/red4-329x695.png 329w, https://www.androidpolice.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/02/red4-668x1410.png 668w, https://www.androidpolice.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/02/red4-161x340.png 161w, https://www.androidpolice.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/02/red4-217x458.png 217w, https://www.androidpolice.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/02/red4-728x1537.png 728w, https://www.androidpolice.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/02/red4.png 1440w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 329px) 100vw, 329px&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We must go deeper...&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems that the popups and flashing buttons have since subsided slightly, but we're sure that many of the downloads occurred purely because of those. That said, if you're still looking for a mobile Reddit client, there are plenty of good third-party alternatives; I personally use &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=me.ccrama.redditslide&amp;amp;hl=en_US&quot; class=&quot;external&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Slide for Reddit&lt;/a&gt;, but there are many more if you just do a bit of digging around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wpappbox wpappbox-3e758dd3637ce54c77084133494f50e8 googleplay colorful simple&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;qrcode&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://chart.googleapis.com/chart?cht=qr&amp;amp;chl=https%3A%2F%2Fplay.google.com%2Fstore%2Fapps%2Fdetails%3Fid%3Dcom.reddit.frontpage&amp;amp;chs=200x200&amp;amp;chld=L%7C0&quot; alt=&quot;Reddit&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;appicon&quot;&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.reddit.frontpage&quot; class=&quot; no-style external&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.androidpolice.com/wp-content/cache/wp-appbox/3e758dd3637ce54c77084133494f50e8/ai-c3b62ced61fc3ad2f5a781a0fd00e48a&quot; alt=&quot;Reddit&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;appdetails&quot;&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;price&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;label&quot;&gt;Price:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;value&quot;&gt;Free&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;ains ains-10 ains-ap2_below_post_body ai-track&quot; data-ai=&quot;WzEwLDJd&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;ai-adb-show&quot; data-ai-tracking=&quot;WzMwLDAsImFwMl9iZWxvd19wb3N0X2JvZHlfYWRiIiwiIiwwXQ==&quot; data-ai-debug=&quot;10 &amp;lt;= 30&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;ap2_below_post_body_adb&quot; href=&quot;https://scroll.com/signup?affiliateId=5e2945ebc82069585a19a2bb&amp;amp;utm_source=androidpolice&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.androidpolice.com/wp-content/themes/ap2/images/scroll/scroll-728250-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Try Scroll&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 07:25:55 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>alborzb</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Reddit gets its app to 50 million Play Store downloads, mostly by making the mobile web experience miserable</og:title>
<og:description>Anyone who's tried to browse Reddit on their phone's web browser will be familiar with the constant popups prompting users to download the mobile app</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.androidpolice.com/2020/09/02/reddit-gets-its-app-to-50-million-play-store-downloads-mostly-by-making-the-mobile-web-experience-miserable/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.androidpolice.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Reddit-official-app-dark-mode-hero.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.androidpolice.com/2020/09/02/reddit-gets-its-app-to-50-million-play-store-downloads-mostly-by-making-the-mobile-web-experience-miserable/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Costs of running a Python webapp for 55k monthly users</title>
<link>https://keepthescore.co/blog/posts/costs-of-running-webapp/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://keepthescore.co/blog/posts/costs-of-running-webapp/</guid>
<description>&lt;header readability=&quot;0.975&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;blog-post-meta&quot;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&quot;2020-09-04T00:00:00+02:00&quot;&gt;Fri Sep 4, 2020&lt;/time&gt; by Caspar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/header&gt;&lt;p&gt;How much does running a webapp in production actually cost? Maybe more than you think. Keepthescore.co is a Python flask application running on DigitalOcean and Firebase. It currently has around 55k unique visitors per month, per day it’s around 3.4k.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://keepthescore.co/blog/money-tree.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A money tree&quot;/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@micheile&quot;&gt;Micheile Henderson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a monthly breakdown with some background information on each cost:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;servers-and-database-on-digitalocean&quot;&gt;Servers and database on DigitalOcean&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Costs per month: $95&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The webapp runs on two identical DigitalOcean servers (4 vCPUs, 8GB RAM, 80GB disk). We use a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blue-green_deployment&quot;&gt;blue-green deployment&lt;/a&gt;, which is a great way of running and hosting a webapp (more on that in a future post) but it does mean that you need 2 identical production servers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The database is a hosted Postgres instance also on DigitalOcean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: the servers are oversized for the load we’re currently seeing. The reason for that is that we tried to solve a production issue by increasing the server specs. It didn’t solve the problem, and now we can’t down-size the servers without re-provisioning them 🤷‍♀️.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;code-repo-on-github&quot;&gt;Code repo on GitHub&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Costs per month: $0&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is free. Thanks GitHub!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;amazon-web-services&quot;&gt;Amazon Web Services&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Costs per month: $60&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use a reporting tool called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.metabase.com/&quot;&gt;Metabase&lt;/a&gt; to generate insights and reports from the database. The tool itself is opensource and free, but hosting it is fairly expensive. Currently it runs on an EC2 instance. There are definitely some savings that could be realised here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;google-cloud&quot;&gt;Google Cloud&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Costs per month: $1.32&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use Firebase for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://keepthescore.co/basketball-scoreboard/&quot;&gt;realtime basketball scoreboard&lt;/a&gt;. We also use the Google Sheets API for some custom scoreboards. Overall it must be said that the Google Cloud APIs are great value for money (so far).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have plans to move away from DigitalOcean and onto Google Cloud infrastructure in the next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;dns-hosting&quot;&gt;DNS hosting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Costs per month: $5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our domain is registered with &lt;a href=&quot;https://dnsimple.com/&quot;&gt;DNSimple.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Costs per month: $10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scoreboards and this blog have the option of allowing a discussion on the same page – this uses the &lt;a href=&quot;https://disqus.com/&quot;&gt;Disqus&lt;/a&gt; service. Disqus has a free tier but they began showing ads so we were forced to move to the paid tier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are planning to move to &lt;a href=&quot;https://commento.io/&quot;&gt;Commento&lt;/a&gt; in the future, which is cheaper, has no ads, and respects your privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;is-it-worth-it-is-there-revenue&quot;&gt;Is it worth it? Is there revenue?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In total that’s around &lt;strong&gt;$171 USD per month&lt;/strong&gt;. If you’re running a company with employees that would be peanuts, but in this case the cost is being borne by a single indie-developer out of his own pocket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bigger issue is that on the revenue side there’s a big fat zero. This is the reason why we are currently working on monetization. This will include banner ads and payments via Stripe. Expect to see these features land by next week!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, more about that in a future post. So long, 👋&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the way: this post generated an interesting discussion on &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24372084&quot;&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;footer readability=&quot;0.48888888888889&quot;&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Share&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;nav class=&quot;nav sharing-icons&quot;&gt;  &lt;/nav&gt;&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;noscript readability=&quot;1.15625&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please enable JavaScript to view the &lt;a href=&quot;https://disqus.com/?ref_noscript&quot;&gt;comments powered by Disqus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://disqus.com&quot; class=&quot;dsq-brlink&quot;&gt;comments powered by &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/footer&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 05:46:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>caspii</dc:creator>
<og:title>Costs of running a Python webapp for 55k monthly users</og:title>
<og:description>A look at the monthly costs of running a webapp on DigitOcean</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://keepthescore.co/blog/posts/costs-of-running-webapp/</og:url>
<og:image>https://keepthescore.co/blog/money-tree.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://keepthescore.co/blog/posts/costs-of-running-webapp/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Digital pregnancy tests have an internal paper test</title>
<link>https://twitter.com/Foone/status/1301707401024827392</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://twitter.com/Foone/status/1301707401024827392</guid>
<description>and why does it do that? so it can detect the lines on the paper! 
In other words, the whole point of the digital part, the battery, IC, LEDs, and photodiodes... is to read the lines and tell you &quot;PREGNANT&quot; and &quot;NOT PREGNANT&quot; instead of &quot;||&quot; or &quot;|+&quot; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/uTlKUTkiCY&quot; data-pre-embedded=&quot;true&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; data-entity-id=&quot;1301710927205548032&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; data-url=&quot;https://twitter.com/Foone/status/1301711188904927232/photo/1&quot; data-tco-id=&quot;uTlKUTkiCY&quot; class=&quot;twitter_external_link dir-ltr tco-link has-expanded-path&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot; data-expanded-path=&quot;/Foone/status/1301711188904927232/photo/1&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/uTlKUTkiCY&lt;/a&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 04:27:27 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>nsriv</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mobile.twitter.com/Foone/status/1301707401024827392</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Libvirt – The Unsung Hero of Cloud Computing (2013)</title>
<link>https://vyomtech.com/2013/12/17/libvirt_the_unsung_hero_of_cloud_computing.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://vyomtech.com/2013/12/17/libvirt_the_unsung_hero_of_cloud_computing.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Based on above terms &lt;strong&gt;“The goal of libvirt is to provide a common and stable layer sufficient to securely manage domains on a node, possibly remote”&lt;/strong&gt;. So libvirt should provide all APIs needed to do the management, such as: provision, create, modify, monitor, control, migrate and stop the domains - within the limits of the support of the hypervisor for those operations. This implies following sub-goals:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So libvirt is intended to be a building block for higher level management tools and for applications focusing on virtualization of a single node (the only exception being domain migration between node capabilities which involves more than one node).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;libvirt-driver-based-architecture&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Libvirt Driver Based Architecture&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;libvirt driver based architecture&quot; class=&quot;align-left&quot; src=&quot;https://vyomtech.com/_images/libvirt_architecture.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Libvirt to support wide variety of hypervisor implements a driver-based architecture. Based on car analogy, it means delegating the actual implementation of control of different cars to the drivers specifically designed for make, model and engine of the specific car. Libvirt currently supports:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hypervisor&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;simple&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;LXC - Linux Containers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OpenVZ&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;QEMU&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Test - Used for testing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UML - User Mode Linux&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VirtualBox&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VMware ESX&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VMware Workstation/Player&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Xen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microsoft Hyper-V&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IBM PowerVM (phyp)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parallels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remote - Accessing libvirt on remote node through libvirtd (libvirt daemon)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Storage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;simple&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Directory backend&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Local filesystem backend&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Network filesystem backend&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Logical Volume Manager (LVM) backend&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disk backend&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iSCSI backend&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SCSI backend&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multipath backend&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RBD (RADOS Block Device) backend&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sheepdog backend&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Virtual Networks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;simple&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bridging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NAT&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VEPA (Virtual Ethernet Port Aggregator)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VN-LINK&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;libvirt-api-structure&quot; readability=&quot;19&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Libvirt API structure &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;libvirt API structure&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; src=&quot;https://vyomtech.com/_images/libvirt_api_structure.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The figure above shows the five main objects exported by the API:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class=&quot;docutils&quot;&gt;&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;virConnectPtr&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Represents the connection to a hypervisor. Use one of the virConnectOpen functions to obtain connection to the hypervisor which is then used as a parameter to other connection API’s.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;virDomainPtr&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Represents one domain either active or defined (i.e. existing as permanent config file and storage but not currently running on that node). The function virConnectListAllDomains lists all the domains for the hypervisor.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;virNetworkPtr&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Represents one network either active or defined (i.e. existing as permanent config file and storage but not currently activated). The function virConnectListAllNetworks lists all the virtualization networks for the hypervisor.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;virStorageVolPtr&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Represents one storage volume generally used as a block device available to one of the domains. The function virStorageVolLookupByPath finds the storage volume object based on its path on the node.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;virStoragePoolPtr&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Represents a storage pool, which is a logical area used to allocate and store storage volumes. The function virConnectListAllStoragePools lists all of the virtualization storage pools on the hypervisor. The function virStoragePoolLookupByVolume finds the storage pool containing a given storage volume.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;p&gt;These names follow C conventions, but developers of cloud computing platforms and applications do not need to use C directly, there are language bindings available for major languages. Currently libvirt API language bindings  are available for C#, Java, OCaml, Perl, PHP, Python, Ruby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;domain-management-architecture&quot; readability=&quot;46&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Domain Management Architecture&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two distinct means for domain management using libvirt API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Single node domain management&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;libvirt API structure&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; src=&quot;https://vyomtech.com/_images/libvirt_single_node_domain_management.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;As illustrated in the figure above in this mode applications (cloud management platform i.e. CMP applications) and domains exist on the same node. In this scenario applications directly works through the libvirt api on the host operating system (os) to control and manage the local domains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Multi node domain management&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;libvirt API structure&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; src=&quot;https://vyomtech.com/_images/libvirt_multi_node_domain_management.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;As shown in the figure above, applications (CMP applications) using libvirt API and the domains to manage or control are on separate nodes. In this mode a special domain called &lt;strong&gt;libvirtd&lt;/strong&gt; (libvirt daemon) needs to run on remote nodes. The management application nodes use the nodes underlying network communicattion to communicate with remote &lt;em&gt;libvirtd&lt;/em&gt; through the local libvirt using custom protocol. Actually libvirt uses Remote  driver for communicating with remote node and remote API calls are handled synchronously. Remote driver for libvirt supports a range of transports like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class=&quot;docutils&quot;&gt;&lt;dt&gt;&lt;em&gt;tls&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;TLS 1.0 (SSL 3.1) authenticated and encrypted TCP/IP socket, usually listening on a public port number. To use this you will need to generate client and server certificates. The standard port is 16514. This is the &lt;strong&gt;default&lt;/strong&gt; transport, if no other is specified.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;em&gt;unix&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;nix domain socket. Since this is only accessible on the local machine, it is not encrypted, and uses Unix permissions or SELinux for authentication. The standard socket names are /var/run/libvirt/libvirt-sock and /var/run/libvirt/libvirt-sock-ro (the latter for read-only connections).&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;em&gt;ssh&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Transported over an ordinary ssh (secure shell) connection. Requires Netcat (nc) installed and libvirtd should be running on the remote machine. You should use some sort of ssh key management (eg. ssh-agent) otherwise programs which use this transport will stop to ask for a password.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;em&gt;ext&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Any external program which can make a connection to the remote machine by means outside the scope of libvirt.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;em&gt;tcp&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;nencrypted TCP/IP socket. Not recommended for production use, this is normally disabled, but an administrator can enable it for testing or use over a trusted network. The standard port is 16509.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;em&gt;libssh2&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Transport over the SSH protocol using libssh2 instead of the OpenSSH binary. This transport uses the libvirt authentication callback for all ssh authentication calls and therefore supports keyboard-interactive authentication even with graphical management applications. As with the classic ssh transport netcat is required on the remote side.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 01:46:34 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>vikrantrathore</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://vyomtech.com/2013/12/17/libvirt_the_unsung_hero_of_cloud_computing.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>