<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>I suspect many task deadlines are designed to force engineers to work for free</title>
<link>http://misc-stuff.terraaeon.com/articles/engineering-deadlines.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://misc-stuff.terraaeon.com/articles/engineering-deadlines.html</guid>
<description>&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://misc-stuff.terraaeon.com/pics/office-400.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;People at a Desk&quot;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

9-16-20&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Engineering is a frustrating career. Perhaps, that is because engineers have no power and everyone expects them to solve all their problems. And, they expect them to be solved by yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much of the time, a task comes down from someone higher up in an organization whose identity the engineer does not know. He may not know, because his boss wants to keep him in the dark, or because his bosses boss wants to keep his boss in the dark. Much of the time, tasks are thought up by someone who has no clue what he is asking for or how long it will take.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a common scenario that plays out between an engineer and his boss. The engineer's boss, an engineering manager, asks him how long a new task will take to complete. Sometimes the engineer has not done this particular thing before, so he responds honestly that he has no idea how long it will take. His boss will not accept that answer. He asks again. So, the engineer makes a wild guess and his boss responds with, &quot;That's too long.&quot; Even if the engineer knows how long a task will take to complete and gives a realistic estimate, his boss often responds with, &quot;That's too long. You have until Friday.&quot; When the engineer asks how long his boss has known about the task, the boss says he has known for a month. When the engineer asks why he didn't tell him a month ago, the boss just looks at the engineer like he doesn't understand the question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often an engineering manager gives an engineer an impossible deadline like three days to solve a problem that will probably take month. This means he has two choices. He can do a substandard (i.e. lousy) job. Or, he can come back in three days and tell his boss the job has not been completed. Very often, if he chooses to do a lousy job, everyone seems happy that something was produced, even though what was produced may have been total garbage that was good for absolutely nothing. If the engineer comes back in three days and tells his manager that the job has not been completed, his boss asks why. The fact that the engineer was not given enough time is not an acceptable answer. But if the job still has to be done, the engineer is given more time. I suspect that if the job does not have to be done and was never important in the first place, the boss just tells the engineer that his time is up and to go do something else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My suspicion is that this interplay between engineering manager and engineer is nothing but a game. Either to the manager, or to the company. Either it is a show of power by the manager, or it is a strategy for increasing the company's profits. In other words, if a boss is not totally clueless (which some seem to be), he knows an engineer can't complete a job in three days that will take a month. But, he must appear to be playing the company's game. The company wants the engineer working unpaid overtime, as much unpaid over time as the engineer can possibly endure. This is why so many engineers at some companies routinely work 70 hour weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A large number of engineering companies essentially rent out their engineers by the hour to their customers. Engineering companies charge for a job either by the estimated number of hours that the job will take to complete or by the number of engineering hours that it actually takes. They charge the customer for every engineering hour. When their engineers work free over time, that is pure profit for the company. So, companies have huge financial incentives to force engineers to work overtime for free. As a result, many companies try to coerce their engineers into working as much unpaid overtime as possible, even if that means they have to make up fake deadlines to get engineers to work longer hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may wonder whether this behavior is legal. It is legal in the United States, because engineers are salaried, instead of hourly. The only thing &quot;salaried&quot; means is that the employee is paid the same amount every week no matter how many hours he actually works. Why is this legal? It probably has something to do with the fact that large engineering companies can afford to hire lobbyists and engineers cannot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What this means for the United States is that many engineers are over worked and producing garbage output. When your new laptop dies after six months, or your new American-made car blows a head gasket after a year, this may be the reason. Greed and lack of empathy have caused companies to turn their engineering managers and engineers into liars. They are forced to say that a job has been completed when it has not, so the company can make a larger profit. And, the people at the top of companies just don't seem to care. Probably part of the reason is that a high percentage of them are &lt;a href=&quot;http://thecontextofthings.com/2019/10/17/so-are-most-ceos-sociopaths/&quot;&gt;sociopaths&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/ceos-often-have-psychopathic-traits-2017-7?op=1&quot;&gt;psychopaths&lt;/a&gt;. Unfortunately, many of our companies appear to have become Orwellian machines that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/on-small-business/wp/2016/09/16/gene-marks-21-percent-of-ceos-are-psychopaths-only-21-percent/&quot;&gt;put these people in power&lt;/a&gt;, and once there, they create utter chaos for the rest of us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;--Tie&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 19:05:22 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>sT370ma2</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://misc-stuff.terraaeon.com/articles/engineering-deadlines.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>iOS 14 is available today</title>
<link>https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2020/09/ios-14-is-available-today/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2020/09/ios-14-is-available-today/</guid>
<description>&lt;h2 class=&quot;pagebody-header&quot;&gt;Redesigned Home Screen Pages&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New widgets present timely information at a glance and can be added in different sizes on any Home Screen page. Users can choose a Smart Stack of widgets, which uses on-device intelligence to surface the right widget based on time, location, and activity. For example, users might see the News widget in the morning, Calendar events during the day, and their Fitness summary in the evening. Home Screen pages can be customized to show apps and widgets for work, entertainment, sports, and other areas of interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the Home Screen pages is the App Library, a new space that automatically organizes all of a user’s apps into one simple, easy-to-navigate view, and intelligently surfaces apps that are helpful in the moment. Users can also hide Home Screen pages for quicker access to the App Library.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 19:03:36 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>todsacerdoti</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>iOS 14 is available today</og:title>
<og:description>iOS 14 reimagines the iPhone experience, delivering a major update to the Home Screen, widgets, and App Clips.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2020/09/ios-14-is-available-today/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/os/ios/standard/Apple_iphone11_ios14-springboard-widgets_09162020.jpg.og.jpg?202009161922</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2020/09/ios-14-is-available-today/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Nova by Panic</title>
<link>https://nova.app/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://nova.app/</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;meta charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;x-ua-compatible&quot; content=&quot;ie=edge&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;viewport&quot; content=&quot;width=device-width, initial-scale=1, maximum-scale=1, user-scalable=0&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; href=&quot;./nova.css?7170bf8&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot; media=&quot;screen&quot;/&gt;&lt;title&gt;Panic - Nova&lt;/title&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;apple-touch-icon&quot; sizes=&quot;180x180&quot; href=&quot;/apple-touch-icon.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;icon&quot; type=&quot;image/png&quot; sizes=&quot;32x32&quot; href=&quot;/favicon-32x32.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;icon&quot; type=&quot;image/png&quot; sizes=&quot;16x16&quot; href=&quot;/favicon-16x16.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;mask-icon&quot; href=&quot;/safari-pinned-tab.svg&quot; color=&quot;#E6516E&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;title&quot; content=&quot;Nova&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:title&quot; content=&quot;Nova&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;twitter:title&quot; content=&quot;Nova&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;description&quot; content=&quot;The beautiful, fast, flexible, native Mac code editor from Panic.&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:description&quot; content=&quot;The beautiful, fast, flexible, native Mac code editor from Panic.&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;twitter:description&quot; content=&quot;The beautiful, fast, flexible, native Mac code editor from Panic.&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:type&quot; content=&quot;website&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;twitter:card&quot; content=&quot;summary_large_image&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:url&quot; content=&quot;https://nova.app/&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;twitter:url&quot; content=&quot;https://nova.app/&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:image&quot; content=&quot;https://nova.app/social-card.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;twitter:image&quot; content=&quot;https://nova.app/social-card.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;twitter:site&quot; content=&quot;@panic&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;twitter:creator&quot; content=&quot;@panic&quot;/&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; data-mode=&quot;dark&quot; class=&quot;reduce-motion&quot; readability=&quot;97.671473245309&quot;&gt;
&lt;nav class=&quot;top&quot;/&gt;&lt;header readability=&quot;1.5416666666667&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can a native Mac&lt;br/&gt;code editor really be&lt;br/&gt;that much better?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/header&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;section id=&quot;opening&quot; readability=&quot;13.1584&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;subhead&quot;&gt;If we're being honest, Mac apps are a bit of a lost art.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are great reasons to make cross-platform apps — to start, they're cross-platform — but it's just not who we are. Founded as a Mac software company in 1997, our joy at Panic comes from building things that feel truly, well, Mac-like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long ago, we created Coda, an all-in-one Mac web editor that broke new ground. But when we started work on Nova, we looked at where the web was today, and where we needed to be. It was time for a fresh start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;section id=&quot;the_editor&quot; readability=&quot;53&quot;&gt;&lt;h2&gt;The Editor.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;subhead&quot;&gt;It all starts with our first-class text-editor.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's new, hyper-fast, and flexible, with all the features you want: smart autocomplete, multiple cursors, a Minimap, editor overscroll, tag pairs and brackets, and way, way more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;editor.png&quot; alt=&quot;Local website project open for editing in Nova with multiple active cursors, autocomplete, and three active sidebars.&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Autocomplete with Fuzzy Matching&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Minimap&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Issues&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Multiple Cursors&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Git Status&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the curious, Nova has built-in support for &lt;span&gt;CoffeeScript&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span&gt;CSS&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span&gt;Diff&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span&gt;ERB&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span&gt;Haml&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span&gt;HTML&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span&gt;INI&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span&gt;JavaScript&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span&gt;JSON&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span&gt;JSX&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span&gt;Less&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span&gt;Lua&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span&gt;Markdown&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span&gt;Perl&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span&gt;Python&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span&gt;Ruby&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span&gt;Sass&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span&gt;SCSS&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span&gt;Smarty&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span&gt;SQL&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span&gt;TSX&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span&gt;TypeScript&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span&gt;XML&lt;/span&gt;, and &lt;span&gt;YAML&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's also very expandable, with a robust API and a built-in extension browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Here's a little editor story for fun. During beta we found some bugs in Apple's text layout engine that we just could not fix. Our solution? Writing our own text layout manager… from scratch. Not only did this fix the bugs, but it also boosted our editor's performance. We're not messing around!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But even the best text engine in the world means nothing unless you actually enjoy spending your time in the app. So, how does Nova look?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;section id=&quot;the_interface&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;&lt;h2&gt;The Interface.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;subhead&quot;&gt;It's beautiful. And clean. And fun.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can make Nova look exactly the way you want, while still feeling Mac-like. Bright, dark, cyberpunk, it's all you. Plus, themes are CSS-like and easy to write. Nova can even automatically change your theme when your Mac switches from light to dark mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;interface/1.png&quot; id=&quot;interface1&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot showing Bright, a default interface theme in Nova.&quot;/&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;interface/2.png&quot; id=&quot;interface2&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot showing Dark, a default interface theme in Nova.&quot;/&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;interface/3.png&quot; id=&quot;interface3&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot showing Neon, a default interface theme in Nova.&quot;/&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;interface/4.png&quot; id=&quot;interface4&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot showing Palette, a default interface theme in Nova.&quot;/&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;section id=&quot;the_workflows&quot; readability=&quot;18&quot;&gt;&lt;h2&gt;The Workflows.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;subhead&quot;&gt;Nova doesn't just help you code. It helps your code run.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can easily create build and run tasks for your projects. We didn't have them in Coda, but boy do we have them now. They're custom scripts that can be triggered at any time by toolbar buttons or keyboard shortcuts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine building content, and with the single click of a button watching as Nova fires up your local server, grabs the appropriate URL, and opens a browser for you, instantly. Just think of the time you'll save.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nova supports separate &lt;strong&gt;Build&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Run&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Clean&lt;/strong&gt; tasks. It can open a report when run. And the scripts can be written in a variety of languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;section id=&quot;the_tools&quot; readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;h2&gt;The Tools.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;subhead&quot;&gt;Now, this is important. Editing text is just part of what Nova does.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've bundled in extremely useful tools to help you get your work done quickly and efficiently. They're all fast and native too, of course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;tools/new-tab.png&quot; alt=&quot;The New Tab button gives quick access to new Document, File Browser, Local and Remote Terminal tabs&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;New Tab&lt;/strong&gt; button doesn't just open a fresh document. although it does that, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click it to quickly access a feature-packed &lt;strong&gt;Transmit file browser&lt;/strong&gt;, or a super-convenient &lt;strong&gt;Prompt terminal&lt;/strong&gt;, all right inside Nova.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;tools/sidebars.png&quot; alt=&quot;Customize the Sidebar Dock using any of the default options: Clips, Files, Find, Git, Issues, Publish, Remote, Reports, and Symbols&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;Meanwhile, Nova's &lt;strong&gt;sidebar&lt;/strong&gt; is packed with power.         &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sidebar can also be split to show multiple tools at once, on the left and/or right side of your editor. And you can drag your favorite tools into the sidebar dock at the top for one-click access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;tools/git.png&quot; alt=&quot;Git status is integrated across Nova: in the Files sidebar, the editor, and a dedicated Git sidebar&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nova also has &lt;strong&gt;Git&lt;/strong&gt; source control tools built-in. Clone. Click-to-clone. Initialize a repo. Fetch and pull. Stage and unstage. Commit. Push. You know the drill. (We don't have built-in diff yet, but it's on our list!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Git status is available both in the editor and the sidebar. And a useful &quot;Show Last Change for Line&quot; pop-up explains commits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;section id=&quot;the_extensions&quot; readability=&quot;12.542565266742&quot;&gt;&lt;h2&gt;The Extensions.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;subhead&quot;&gt;Nova has a robust &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.nova.app&quot;&gt;extensions API&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Nova extension can do lots of things, like add support for new languages, extend the sidebar, draw beautiful new themes and syntax colors, validate different code, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even better, extensions are written in JavaScript, so anyone can write them. And Nova includes built-in extension templates for fast development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;subhead&quot;&gt;Check out some of this week’s popular extensions…&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;extensions&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;extension&quot; href=&quot;https://extensions.panic.com/extensions/vinecode/vinecode.PHPLint&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://nova.app/images/extensions/vinecode.PHPLint.png&quot; alt=&quot;Extension icon for PHPLint&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;extension-name&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PHPLint&lt;/strong&gt; 0.2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;extension-vendor&quot;&gt;Vine Code Limited&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;extension-description&quot;&gt;Identifies PHP syntax errors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;extension&quot; href=&quot;https://extensions.panic.com/extensions/apexskier/apexskier.typescript&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://nova.app/images/extensions/apexskier.typescript.png&quot; alt=&quot;Extension icon for TypeScript&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;extension-name&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TypeScript&lt;/strong&gt; 1.6.2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;extension-vendor&quot;&gt;Cameron Little&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;extension-description&quot;&gt;Advanced TypeScript and JavaScript language support for Nova&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;extension&quot; href=&quot;https://extensions.panic.com/extensions/alexanderweiss/alexanderweiss.prettier&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://nova.app/images/extensions/alexanderweiss.prettier.png&quot; alt=&quot;Extension icon for Prettier&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;extension-name&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prettier&lt;/strong&gt; 1.2.0&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;extension-vendor&quot;&gt;Alexander Weiss&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;extension-description&quot;&gt;Integrates Prettier for code formatting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;extension&quot; href=&quot;https://extensions.panic.com/extensions/aaff/aaff.SolarEclipse&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://nova.app/images/extensions/aaff.SolarEclipse.png&quot; alt=&quot;Extension icon for SolarEclipse&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;extension-name&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SolarEclipse&lt;/strong&gt; 0.1.3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;extension-vendor&quot;&gt;AAFF&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;extension-description&quot;&gt;A higher contrast solarized dark inspired theme&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;extension&quot; href=&quot;https://extensions.panic.com/extensions/emmetio/emmetio.Emmet&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://nova.app/images/extensions/emmetio.Emmet.png&quot; alt=&quot;Extension icon for Emmet&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;extension-name&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Emmet&lt;/strong&gt; 1.2.2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;extension-vendor&quot;&gt;Emmet&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;extension-description&quot;&gt;Emmet — the essential toolkit for web-developers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;extension&quot; href=&quot;https://extensions.panic.com/extensions/panic/panic.HTMLValidator&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://nova.app/images/extensions/panic.HTMLValidator.png&quot; alt=&quot;Extension icon for HTML Validator&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;extension-name&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HTML Validator&lt;/strong&gt; 0.9&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;extension-vendor&quot;&gt;Panic&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;extension-description&quot;&gt;Integrates the W3C HTML online validator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;feature-link&quot; href=&quot;https://extensions.panic.com&quot;&gt;Browse Extensions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;section id=&quot;the_settings&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;&lt;h2&gt;The Settings.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;subhead&quot;&gt;People have strong editor opinions.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we're here to help. Nova has a whole host of settings. We have easily customizable key bindings. We have custom, quickly-switchable workspace layouts. And we have loads of editor tweaks, from matching brackets to overscroll.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(And if there's something you need to work that Nova doesn't have, just let us know! Nova is always changing, always growing.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; id=&quot;settings-screenshot-general&quot; data-src=&quot;settings/1-general.png&quot; onclick=&quot;document.querySelector('#settings-screenshots').dataset.pane = 'general';&quot; alt=&quot;The General preferences pane&quot;/&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; id=&quot;settings-screenshot-sync&quot; data-src=&quot;settings/2-sync.png&quot; onclick=&quot;document.querySelector('#settings-screenshots').dataset.pane = 'sync';&quot; alt=&quot;The Sync preferences pane&quot;/&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; id=&quot;settings-screenshot-workspace&quot; data-src=&quot;settings/3-workspace.png&quot; onclick=&quot;document.querySelector('#settings-screenshots').dataset.pane = 'workspace';&quot; alt=&quot;The Workspace preferences pane&quot;/&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; id=&quot;settings-screenshot-behaviors&quot; data-src=&quot;settings/4-behaviors.png&quot; onclick=&quot;document.querySelector('#settings-screenshots').dataset.pane = 'behaviors';&quot; alt=&quot;The Behaviors preferences pane&quot;/&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; id=&quot;settings-screenshot-files&quot; data-src=&quot;settings/5-files.png&quot; onclick=&quot;document.querySelector('#settings-screenshots').dataset.pane = 'files';&quot; alt=&quot;The Files preferences pane&quot;/&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; id=&quot;settings-screenshot-editor&quot; data-src=&quot;settings/6-editor.png&quot; onclick=&quot;document.querySelector('#settings-screenshots').dataset.pane = 'editor';&quot; alt=&quot;The Editor preferences pane&quot;/&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; id=&quot;settings-screenshot-theme&quot; data-src=&quot;settings/7-theme.png&quot; onclick=&quot;document.querySelector('#settings-screenshots').dataset.pane = 'theme';&quot; alt=&quot;The Theme preferences pane&quot;/&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; id=&quot;settings-screenshot-key-bindings&quot; data-src=&quot;settings/8-key-bindings.png&quot; onclick=&quot;document.querySelector('#settings-screenshots').dataset.pane = 'key-bindings';&quot; alt=&quot;The Key preferences pane&quot;/&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; id=&quot;settings-screenshot-terminal&quot; data-src=&quot;settings/9-terminal.png&quot; onclick=&quot;document.querySelector('#settings-screenshots').dataset.pane = 'terminal';&quot; alt=&quot;The Terminal preferences pane&quot;/&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; id=&quot;settings-screenshot-servers&quot; data-src=&quot;settings/10-servers.png&quot; onclick=&quot;document.querySelector('#settings-screenshots').dataset.pane = 'servers';&quot; alt=&quot;The Servers preferences pane&quot;/&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; id=&quot;settings-screenshot-keys&quot; data-src=&quot;settings/11-keys.png&quot; onclick=&quot;document.querySelector('#settings-screenshots').dataset.pane = 'keys';&quot; alt=&quot;The Keys preferences pane&quot;/&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; id=&quot;settings-screenshot-transfers&quot; data-src=&quot;settings/12-transfers.png&quot; onclick=&quot;document.querySelector('#settings-screenshots').dataset.pane = 'transfers';&quot; alt=&quot;The Transfers preferences pane&quot;/&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; id=&quot;settings-screenshot-tools&quot; data-src=&quot;settings/13-tools.png&quot; onclick=&quot;document.querySelector('#settings-screenshots').dataset.pane = 'tools';&quot; alt=&quot;The Tools preferences pane&quot;/&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;section id=&quot;much_more&quot;&gt;&lt;h2&gt;And So Much More.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Command Palette&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Project Launcher with Custom Artwork&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multiple Sidebars &amp;amp; Sidebar Splits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Separate Editor &amp;amp; Window Themes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatic Theme Changes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Global &amp;amp; Project Clips&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Project-Wide Indexing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intelligent, Extendable Autocomplete&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Powerful Open Quickly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Git Source Control Sidebar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preview Tabs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Built-in Static Web Server&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remote Publishing via FTP, SFTP, WebDAV, &amp;amp; Clouds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Local &amp;amp; Remote Terminals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Markdown Preview&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Customizable In-App Key Bindings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Panic Sync for Servers &amp;amp; Keys&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Robust Extension API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In-App Extension Library&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;nova&lt;/code&gt; Command Line Tool&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Reopen Recently Closed Files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Small or Large Sidebar Dock Sizes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Project-specific Sidebar Layouts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remote-Bound Workspaces&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quick Tab Overview&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Customizable Event Behaviors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deep-Filtering Files Sidebar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ignored Files in Sidebar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drag-to-Split&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easily Merged JSON Project Settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Files Sidebar Navigation Controls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Single-Click to Open Files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find &amp;amp; Replace in Project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Powerful Find &amp;amp; Replace Wildcards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find Scopes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ignore Specific Files when Indexing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remote Files Sidebar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Server Preferences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Staged Publishing List&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multiple Publishing Destinations per Project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Save &amp;amp; Publish&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rich Editor Typography &amp;amp; Styling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Customizable Line Height&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Text Glow Support in Themes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multiple Insertion Point Styles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Type &amp;amp; Function Separators&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Customizable Editor Overscroll&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Source Control Change Annotations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatic Link Detection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spell Checking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Powerful Clip Wildcard Tokens&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expandable Issue Line Annotations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hierarchical Symbols List&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jump To Definition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dictionary Define Popover&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EditorConfig Support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Customizable Markdown Stylesheets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rainbow Bracket Nesting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rainbow Indentation Guides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Matching Tag Highlighting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identifier Highlighting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatic Closing-Bracket Insertion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bracket Wrapping&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatic Tag Closing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Customizable Wrap Indentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quickly Add Cursors for Successive Lines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Project Issues Sidebar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Git Branch &amp;amp; Switch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Git Commit, Fetch, Push, &amp;amp; Pull&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Image, Audio, &amp;amp; Video Media Viewers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extension Updating Without Restarting IDE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Task Output Reports&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remote Tasks on Unix, Linux, Windows, &amp;amp; PowerShell&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Custom Task Environment Variables&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatic Parsing of Task Output Into Issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Auditory and Visual Terminal Beeps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Customizable Terminal Tab Titles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Terminal Key-Binding Escape Sequences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Terminal &quot;Option as Meta Key&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Terminal URL and file detection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Terminal Mouse Events&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RSA, ECDSA, &amp;amp; ED25519 Keys&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dual-Pane File Browser Tabs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cloud Provider Files Support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Transfer Transcripts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Robust Transfer Settings &amp;amp; Rules&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;External Preview in Browser with Live Reload&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Non-Interruptive Updates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install Updates On Quit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coda 2 Import &amp;amp; Migration Assistant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Transmit 5 Import&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No-Fuss Analytics &amp;amp; Privacy Settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And Now You Know Why This Took Us a Few Years&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;For Extensions: Develop Extensions In-App&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Safe, Sandboxed Environment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Robust JavaScript API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Project &amp;amp; Global Settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rapidly Reload and Test Live&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Filesystem, Network, &amp;amp; Subprocess Access&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Debug Console&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Editor &amp;amp; Project Actions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linters &amp;amp; Validators&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Custom Language Grammars&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expressive Completion Providers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build &amp;amp; Run Task Templates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Custom Sidebars&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Syntax Inspector&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Language Server Protocol Support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Custom Themes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Workspace Notifications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Text Parsing &amp;amp; Encoding Utilities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Secure Credential Storage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Submit Extensions Easily with Validation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;footer readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;© 2020 Panic&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nova is a registered trademark of Panic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;modal&quot; readability=&quot;7.740614334471&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;downloaded&quot; readability=&quot;11.180887372014&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Downloading Now!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nova comes as free, full-featured trial.&lt;br/&gt;Use it for up to 30 days from launch.&lt;br/&gt;If you like it, buy it, and keep it forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;smallprint&quot;&gt;PS: don't forget to drag Nova to your Applications folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 17:59:30 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>0x0</dc:creator>
<og:title>Nova</og:title>
<og:description>The beautiful, fast, flexible, native Mac code editor from Panic.</og:description>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://nova.app/</og:url>
<og:image>https://nova.app/social-card.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://nova.app/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Oculus Quest 2</title>
<link>https://www.oculus.com/blog/introducing-oculus-quest-2-the-next-generation-of-all-in-one-vr-gaming/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.oculus.com/blog/introducing-oculus-quest-2-the-next-generation-of-all-in-one-vr-gaming/</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;_9d3p _9d3r _9d3u _9d4g&quot;&gt;Oculus Quest changed the game for wireless VR. It delivered fresh experiences for enthusiasts and new opportunities for developers, all while introducing immersive gaming to newcomers across the globe. Today, we’re excited to announce Oculus Quest 2, the next generation of all-in-one VR. Quest 2 pushes the state of VR forward with a redesigned all-in-one form factor, new Touch controllers, and our highest-resolution display ever. Quest 2 starts at $299 USD—$100 USD less than the original Quest. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oculus.com/quest-2/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Pre-orders are open now&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and Quest 2 ships October 13.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;_9d3p _9d3r _9d3u _9d4g&quot;&gt;You can pre-order today at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oculus.com/quest-2/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;oculus.com&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and our global retail partners, including: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oculus.com/lynx/?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2F&amp;amp;e=AT1GJyh8PcKgB2Qg1sHEOkq0EQoMYdKJZ-SeDBXTaXY1FnYK01INg76MrqsRcWflUzQ-YQkGLlfnxnWZkC7Q2DwcaQGSUUy9uFfPohuyY-u1wEggdvFoFTJLJ26RVhS8B4j4vceCuhizXnCkCns&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Best Buy&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oculus.com/lynx/?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2F%3Futm_expid%3D.Mt_il0WvRCCtQIafWkaNyQ.0%26utm_referrer%3Dhttps%253A%252F%252Fwww.google.com%252F&amp;amp;e=AT3HtKCxI9sUrl0pm03UGHDmGA8_qQDJ7gDzfuxSglzXDRTHRKJ0V8TZGXNKvLq5BROJD1GCxVgNBcy3M6UOp6qZX8ZZpbf8dFDpSrNCDwHGFbraA2OhYX3vo3yIgTqXLewFEnz_Mpv2QOD4ayM&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;GameStop&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oculus.com/lynx/?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2F&amp;amp;e=AT3yfQJnRUteb7gAr-th48kGJgIRsYIuiKFBQhJ_M_fhmKYZVVK7CR9fZ1rOPu8B7uFLr5GVXtfZxZpCmi9tRETEgVipMafmFWWeVnp7IbRCjfSbuDo3Yab2ZVS6IB-kAUwFnaZbzBktQulwMX8&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Target&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oculus.com/lynx/?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2F&amp;amp;e=AT155hg1XE0KNTdJa-YeEFS3VZYJP_6ObVVjqa0SqGmzAyeOe_hzt6sccomGReCzvik_Ta43v5CgK7yWP8Ii-9zDZuPUMzREOhCJlu0wPY8wZ0LaWhTMrAUUdzRRLqigv3qgKMUrOdOkWB-t760&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Walmart&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in the US; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oculus.com/lynx/?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.currys.co.uk%2Fgbuk%2Findex.html&amp;amp;e=AT1tXZcGgQiPcQAjPWH2g3H-Ft0vStR3xT6hzLBmmopnwaFKClxSGmRMKEZ547Z6IqWSBoO7dPJWJ16xsoVfaHdlaLmXeo0AvUU45fpfv-R7mQxg7e2LJwoHeGAkv77UidZVyg51y0ZHBFMEe5Q&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Currys PC World&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oculus.com/lynx/?u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.fnacdarty.com%2F&amp;amp;e=AT27CKooUVnElto2GNBqCyHBEQPIy_I7PX1hGlYa1fI5zXHumER88GC26WQrZczxnJYVbLB46BuRRwC7Imeaq8vzojAi1Hn-QOwdBDE-L29j1GGcG9NqWSYOsfFT441Kx03t3YBam-U5DysNtiw&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;FNAC Darty&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in the UK and EU; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oculus.com/lynx/?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.amazon.com%2F&amp;amp;e=AT1lTIOWMQG3szQF0Of9XaTTMO4GqUaCNtMBRziIXDsVYj_8Hao9-uaam9wvBF5FTcwNfP7A2ytLgJtuJ78os69Z1vW13TxM4HLLO0xzq0W2d3Sjb0moZJpvXqEuyTeRcnEPK0y9bgS6adaNU_4&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Amazon&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; worldwide. We’re also bringing Oculus products to Japanese retail stores for the first time with Quest 2, including &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oculus.com/lynx/?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.biccamera.co.jp%2F&amp;amp;e=AT0ERZ8pU8MSWxrm6zOVzQIbRMda5G2p45qaDzVfb7hDVMjPkePx7CAmNlJ7N_69lx5OKB8pTwVzahb04BxVXkfmenySBKhix3JDCOK2h4GTbeZ5aFqJZEeTnTGkKRJmbYHJkK10-JLWpXjohH4&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Bic Camera&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oculus.com/lynx/?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.yamada-denki.jp%2F&amp;amp;e=AT0q5TmvlotgNUwh7Jy-UuYMZ0iFBsEcIIITA-2ZNaJfu7dngUW_u-809GC2mO1cqQOpmCgiA9j08no_ZqNamY2vpgJGBYHEg--FDOPx9bfJr7uGuQEwCWhfPeau5eVPhW8qcvGpZF04MTN3RDI&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Yamada Denki&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oculus.com/lynx/?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.yodobashi.com%2F&amp;amp;e=AT2SwY3sL6VkzdzAi-P4DkSMGzQgMYztx5DG6tgW8maJF8rwjAqR00JEhTlez0mqXXtZ2jEe6BEykSkIyxMj95lSW1qxh1YeRwR2y-UvTmBr9gRgeZxOlPKXZQG7d7_UGgdElYLxCQYxu5_EmXo&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Yodobashi Camera&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oculus.com/lynx/?u=https%3A%2F%2Fgeo-online.co.jp%2F&amp;amp;e=AT2_adqSOsd0YpzxrCS95QrlXpntOOqGRjNBaz3DTO4thXopN5CKcmoaiM42t0hJnma5b9tgQazNmu13CuppmKT6I2h7F8OjuItqdOSb3XAn7uZft-qpczFRy04zKduHmOtxPQ4wcY4DOCOWnSc&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;GEO&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_9d3p _9d3r _9d3u _9d4g&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Built for Next-Generation Gaming&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_9d3p _9d3r _9d3u _9d4g&quot;&gt;Quest 2 packs a suite of innovations to power the next generation of VR games and experiences. With the first Quest headset, we debuted a revolutionary all-in-one form factor powered by innovations like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oculus.com/lynx/?u=https%3A%2F%2Ftech.fb.com%2Fthe-story-behind-oculus-insight-technology%2F&amp;amp;e=AT0ab7xEt8O0VpzSbMRtkHyjD9-pj95wKUuimshQvu0LpDtAHtc-Bo0Qu-nSvgr6FrMKMQIca8qwolqOoHfSQonlzgKK7nlJMIf2gZi7hYodu6SjALwfclKhQap3XGRdWem9fWVB4RoA0Bn0wBk&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Oculus Insight&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; tracking system. With Quest 2, we’re taking things even further, starting with a multi-generational leap in processing power with the state-of-the-art Qualcomm® Snapdragon™ XR2 Platform offering higher AI capability, and 6GB of RAM. The new display features 1832 x 1920 pixels per eye—our highest resolution display yet. With 50% more pixels than the original Quest, everything from multiplayer games and productivity apps to 360° videos look better than ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_9d3p _9d3r _9d3u _9d4g&quot;&gt;We didn’t stop there. With Quest 2’s increased graphics processing power, this new display is capable of supporting 90 Hz. You’ll be able to run system applications at 90 Hz on day one, including the Home Environment, Explore, Store, Browser and Oculus TV by opting in via Experimental Features. We’ll open up 90 Hz to all developers soon after launch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;_3zn8&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img&quot; src=&quot;https://scontent.fphx1-1.fna.fbcdn.net/v/t39.2365-6/119752221_769630990276754_2178625335575406924_n.jpg?_nc_cat=1&amp;amp;_nc_sid=ad8a9d&amp;amp;_nc_ohc=c4IMyD21YuUAX8a_Guo&amp;amp;_nc_ht=scontent.fphx1-1.fna&amp;amp;oh=366e1897085b13c011e0b9297939b379&amp;amp;oe=5F8897E0&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_9d3p _9d3r _9d3u _9d4g&quot;&gt;When it comes to game controllers, comfort is crucial, but so is performance. Quest 2 comes with new Touch controllers built to offer better ergonomics—inspired by our original Touch design—with the same intuitive controls that translate gestures directly into VR for unparalleled hand presence in virtual environments. We also optimized controller tracking to make it more efficient, delivering battery life that’s up to four times longer* than Quest’s Touch controllers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_9d3p _9d3r _9d3u _9d4g&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Best VR Games and Experiences&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_9d3p _9d3r _9d3u _9d4g&quot;&gt;Quest 2 gives you access to the full breadth of the Quest content library, which will also include exciting upcoming titles like &lt;em&gt;Star Wars: Tales from the Galaxy’s Edge&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Myst&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Jurassic World Aftermath&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Warhammer 40,000 Battle Sister&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Pistol Whip: 2089&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The Climb 2&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Rez Infinite&lt;/em&gt;, and many more. Quest 2 is also compatible with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oculus.com/blog/play-rift-content-on-quest-with-oculus-link-available-now-in-beta/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Oculus Link&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, so you can enjoy the best of PC VR gaming —including &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oculus.com/experiences/rift/1180401875303371/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;u&gt;Asgard’s Wrath&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oculus.com/experiences/rift/1360938750683878/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;u&gt;Stormland&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oculus.com/experiences/rift/1368187813209608/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;u&gt;Lone Echo&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, as well as upcoming titles like &lt;em&gt;Lone Echo II&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oculus.com/medal-of-honor/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;u&gt;Medal of Honor: Above and Beyond&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. With hundreds of popular Quest and Rift games available, and many more on the way, there’s never been a better time to jump into VR. Click &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oculus.com/blog/games-at-facebook-connect-cinematic-stories-music-and-multiplayer-fan-favorites-and-more/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;here&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to see more of what’s in store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_9d3p _9d3r _9d3u _9d4g&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All-in-One VR for More People&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_9d3p _9d3r _9d3u _9d4g&quot;&gt;From the start, we wanted Quest 2 to help more people discover what VR has to offer. That’s why we redesigned the headset to achieve a slimmer profile, cutting over 10% of the weight from the original Quest so it’s more portable and easier to wear. We also know that adjustable IPD (interpupillary distance) is an important factor when considering VR headsets. Quest 2 includes a built-in IPD adjustment mechanism with three settings, letting people adjust lens position for visual comfort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;_3zn8&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img&quot; src=&quot;https://scontent.fphx1-1.fna.fbcdn.net/v/t39.2365-6/119671334_339738983746581_8157840189691950919_n.jpg?_nc_cat=1&amp;amp;_nc_sid=ad8a9d&amp;amp;_nc_ohc=OwVbZkuUe9EAX-AAmg1&amp;amp;_nc_ht=scontent.fphx1-1.fna&amp;amp;oh=880345048cd613634228abd9f163ff7e&amp;amp;oe=5F869822&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_9d3p _9d3r _9d3u _9d4g&quot;&gt;Quest 2 will also support a new line of optional &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oculus.com/quest-2/accessories/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;accessories&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Designed to enhance fit and comfort, these customizable head straps and facial interface add-ons give people the flexibility to play how they want, where they want. For instance, the Elite Strap with Battery accessory delivers double the playtime with increased balance and ergonomics, helping those who love longer play sessions to stay immersed in their favorite games and experiences. And the Fit Pack provides swappable facial interfaces to fit wider or narrower face shapes. As we welcome more people into our community with Quest 2, we hope these accessories will help make VR more inclusive for a diverse audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_9d3p _9d3r _9d3u _9d4g&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advancing the State of VR&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_9d3p _9d3r _9d3u _9d4g&quot;&gt;Over the past year, we’ve heard from developers and the VR community alike that Quest delivers on the promise of VR better than any other headset. It offers flexibility and comfort while letting people enjoy both wireless Quest titles and the best of high-powered PC VR (through Oculus Link), all with a single all-in-one headset. This is the future of VR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_9d3p _9d3r _9d3u _9d4g&quot;&gt;With a higher resolution panel and the ability to reach a higher refresh rate than Rift S, all in a lighter form factor and at a lower cost, Quest 2 brings a leveled-up PC VR gaming experience to enthusiasts. We’ve worked hard to improve Oculus Link’s performance, stability, and third-party cable compatibility since its launch in November 2019. After months of testing and community feedback, Oculus Link will exit beta this fall with improved fidelity and support for 90 Hz coming soon. And next year, we’ll debut a unified system experience that taps directly into the Quest user interface, so you’ll find your PC games and Quest games all in the same spot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;_3zn8&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img&quot; src=&quot;https://scontent.fphx1-2.fna.fbcdn.net/v/t39.2365-6/119334761_784419705686863_4217554781523352840_n.jpg?_nc_cat=102&amp;amp;_nc_sid=ad8a9d&amp;amp;_nc_ohc=75IgQTNGZ7AAX_fSnxH&amp;amp;_nc_ht=scontent.fphx1-2.fna&amp;amp;oh=90437ea3ef9f7263a8485789d5727318&amp;amp;oe=5F8839B8&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_9d3p _9d3r _9d3u _9d4g&quot;&gt;We’re going to focus on standalone VR headsets moving forward. We’ll no longer pursue PC-only hardware, with sales of Rift S ending in 2021. That said, the Rift Platform isn’t going anywhere. In fact, we've seen significant growth in PC VR via Oculus Link, and the Rift Platform will continue to grow while offering high-end PC VR experiences like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oculus.com/lone-echo/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;u&gt;Lone Echo II&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://oculus.com/medalofhonor&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;u&gt;Medal of Honor: Above and Beyond&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; well into the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_9d3p _9d3r _9d3u _9d4g&quot;&gt;Sales of the original Quest will also end as we bring Quest 2 to retailers worldwide. But that doesn’t mean we’ll stop supporting the original Quest. We’ll continue improving Quest by listening to the people who made its success possible—players from the VR community. We’ll be delivering more new features and gaming experiences moving forward, so stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_9d3p _9d3r _9d3u _9d4g&quot;&gt;Our goal with the original Quest was to bring standalone VR to as many people as possible. We’re doubling down on that goal with Quest 2. It combines the performance gamers want with the flexibility people need, all at a price significantly lower than similarly featured headsets on the market. Quest 2 is more than just the next step in all-in-one VR. It represents years of feedback from developers, gaming enthusiasts, and the broader VR community, and we couldn’t be more grateful for this ongoing support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_9d3p _9d3r _9d3u _9d4g&quot;&gt;We can’t wait to share more with you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_9d3p _9d3r _9d3u _9d4g&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;*Performance may vary based on use.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 17:44:03 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>sidhanthp</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.oculus.com/blog/introducing-oculus-quest-2-the-next-generation-of-all-in-one-vr-gaming/?_fb_noscript=1</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Large-scale Abuse of Contact Discovery in Mobile Messengers [pdf]</title>
<link>https://encrypto.de/papers/HWSDS21.pdf</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://encrypto.de/papers/HWSDS21.pdf</guid>
<description>&lt;a href=&quot;https://encrypto.de/papers/HWSDS21.pdf&quot;&gt;Download PDF&lt;/a&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 16:51:49 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>sizzle</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://encrypto.de/papers/HWSDS21.pdf</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Birds &amp;#039;falling out of the sky&amp;#039; in mass die-off in south-western US</title>
<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2020/sep/16/birds-falling-out-of-the-sky-in-mass-die-off-in-south-western-us-aoe</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2020/sep/16/birds-falling-out-of-the-sky-in-mass-die-off-in-south-western-us-aoe</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Thousands of migrating birds have inexplicably died in south-western US in what ornithologists have described as a national tragedy that is likely to be related to the climate crisis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flycatchers, swallows and warblers are among the species “falling out of the sky” as part of a mass die-off across New Mexico, Colorado, Texas, Arizona and farther north into Nebraska, with growing concerns there could be hundreds of thousands dead already, said Martha Desmond, a professor in the biology department at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/newmexico&quot; data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;New Mexico&lt;/a&gt; State University (NMSU). Many carcasses have little remaining fat reserves or muscle mass, with some appearing to have nose-dived into the ground mid-flight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I collected over a dozen in just a two-mile stretch in front of my house,” said Desmond. “To see this and to be picking up these carcasses and realising how widespread this is, is personally devastating. To see this many individuals and species dying is a national tragedy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long-distance migrants flying south from tundra landscapes in Alaska and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/canada&quot; data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Canada&lt;/a&gt; pass over America’s south-west to reach winter grounds in Central and South America. During this migration it is crucial they land every few days to refuel before continuing their journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2020/sep/12/california-oregon-washington-fires-explained-climate-change&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Historic wildfires&lt;/a&gt; across the western states of the US could mean they had to re-route their migration away from resource-rich coastal areas and move inland over the Chihuahuan desert, where food and water are scarce, essentially meaning they starved to death. “They’re literally just feathers and bones,” Allison Salas, a graduate student at NMSU who has been collecting carcasses, wrote in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/salasphorus/status/1304973069056786432&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Twitter thread&lt;/a&gt; about the die-off. “Almost as if they have been flying until they just couldn’t fly any more.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;element element-rich-link element--thumbnail element-rich-link--not-upgraded&quot; data-component=&quot;rich-link&quot; data-link-name=&quot;rich-link-1 | 1&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;rich-link&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;rich-link__container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;rich-link__header&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;rich-link__title&quot;&gt;World fails to meet a single target to stop destruction of nature – UN report&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;The south-western states of the US have experienced extremely dry conditions – believed to be related to the climate crisis – meaning there could be fewer insects, the main food source for migrating birds. A cold snap locally between 9 and 10 September could have also worsened conditions for the birds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any of these weather events may have triggered birds to start their migration early, having not built up sufficient fat reserves. Another theory is that the smoke from the wildfires may have damaged their lungs. “It could be a combination of things. It could be something that’s still completely unknown to us,” said Salas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The fact that we’re finding hundreds of these birds dying, just kind of falling out of the sky is extremely alarming … The volume of carcasses that we have found has literally given me chills.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first deaths were reported on 20 August on White Sands Missile Range in New Mexico. Initially, incidents were thought to be unrelated, but thanks to online forums, ornithologists noticed that they were happening all across the region. Resident bird species such as curve-billed thrashers, great-tailed grackles and white-winged doves do not appear to have been affected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;u-responsive-ratio&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;gu-image&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; alt=&quot;One of the hundreds of dead birds reported throughout New Mexico over the past two weeks.&quot; src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/2651b5ceec89bc6ad083d0bdfc623b83c400195a/0_0_4032_3024/master/4032.jpg?width=300&amp;amp;quality=85&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=d22e2265787406c89edb74fa2762706b&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

One of the hundreds of dead birds reported throughout New Mexico over the past two weeks. Photograph: Allison Salas/New Mexico State University
&lt;p&gt;Reports suggest some birds have been displaying unusual behaviour before dying – becoming lethargic, approachable and congregating in groups. Species that normally rest in trees and shrubs have been seen hopping around on the ground looking for insects, said Desmond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Large avian mortalities during migration are rare and few have been as large as this one. Records – which go back to the 1800s – show these events are always associated with extreme weather events such as a drop in temperature, snowstorm or hailstorm. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1474-919X.2007.00704.x&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;largest event on record&lt;/a&gt; in the region was a snowstorm in Minnesota and Iowa in March 1904 that killed 1.5 million birds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The climate crisis is also changing the tundra landscape where many of these birds breed, while the destruction of rainforests in Central and South America is damaging their winter habitats. Since 1970, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/environment/blog/2019/sep/19/us-canada-bird-population-losses&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;three&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/environment/blog/2019/sep/19/us-canada-bird-population-losses&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;billion&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/environment/blog/2019/sep/19/us-canada-bird-population-losses&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;birds have been lost&lt;/a&gt; in the US and Canada. Mass die-offs such as this can have an effect on populations of both common and sensitive species. Salas said: “We’re kind of coming at them from all sides … if we don’t do anything to protect their habitat we’re going to lose large numbers of the populations of several species.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carcasses are being sent to the US Fish and Wildlife Service forensics laboratory in Oregon and National Wildlife Health Centre in Wisconsin for testing, which is expected to take at least two weeks. Scientists are urging people in the area to log any sightings of dead birds on the citizen science website &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inaturalist.org/projects/southwest-avian-mortality-project&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;inaturalist&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tristanna Bickford, the communications director at New Mexico department of Game and Fish, said it was a possibility that the climate crisis had affected the migration. “Until we get the actual reports back from the National &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/environment/wildlife&quot; data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Wildlife&lt;/a&gt; Health Centre, we can’t say what is happening or is not happening,” she added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Find more &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/environment/series/the-age-of-extinction&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;age of extinction coverage here&lt;/a&gt;, and follow biodiversity reporters &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/phoeb0?lang=en&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Phoebe Weston&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/pgreenfielduk?lang=en&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Patrick Greenfield&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter for all the latest news and features&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 14:47:07 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>orf</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://www.theguardian.com/environment/2020/sep/16/birds-falling-out-of-the-sky-in-mass-die-off-in-south-western-us-aoe</og:url>
<og:description>Wildfires and climate crisis cited as possible causes for the deaths of thousands of migrating species heading south for the winter</og:description>
<og:image>https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c0726972a4613e7cd601123c8b936571552bb574/65_0_1215_729/master/1215.jpg?width=1200&amp;height=630&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;overlay-align=bottom%2Cleft&amp;overlay-width=100p&amp;overlay-base64=L2ltZy9zdGF0aWMvb3ZlcmxheXMvdGctZGVmYXVsdC5wbmc&amp;enable=upscale&amp;s=5abaaf075512c2742a34f7119bb4eb96</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Birds 'falling out of the sky' in mass die-off in south-western US</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2020/sep/16/birds-falling-out-of-the-sky-in-mass-die-off-in-south-western-us-aoe</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>DMT drug study investigates the ‘entities’ people meet while tripping</title>
<link>https://bigthink.com/mind-brain/dmt-beings</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://bigthink.com/mind-brain/dmt-beings</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Even in sleep, we partake in the becoming of the world,&quot; to utter the echo in Czesław Miłosz's poem &quot;A Magic Mountain.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;164.5&quot;&gt;Lying awake at night, I have sometimes found myself turning this idea over in my head. Like millions of slumberless souls, I have suffered with regular bouts of insomnia, which, in my case, were triggered by overworking, psychological pressure, and obsessive thoughts. Insomniac sleep deprivation provoked in me a profound anxiety, shades of paranoia, and the promise of depression. However, during one tempestuous summer a few years ago, I found an aural way to silence it.Beleaguered in the stifling intensity of two interim jobs, I worked too much, too hard and too long; stress-ridden and marooned in the city, I fell over the edge into a nightly insomnia. Like quicksand, the more I tried to sleep and ignore the freneticism of my racing thoughts, the harder it became to drift off – I couldn't say how I partook in Miłosz's becoming. I tried everything, from books on balmy midnight sleepwalks to friendly lectures on temperance. Nothing worked. A sleeping pill prescription was complicated by side-effect trepidation spawned by my state of nervous distress; my mental health suffered and I feared a repeat of depressive episodes. In the past, I had used music to modulate my emotions, so I trialled a kind of self-directed musical hypnosis. Finally, here was something that hit a chord.After weeks of wakeful anxiety, in the soft strains of music I found a medium that regulated my mood, toned down the stress and tuned into my sleep patterns. Not a total cure for my affliction, but certainly a vital accompaniment. After the temporary projects eventually flourished to a crescendo, music had become the requiem to my insomnia.
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This should not have come as a surprise to me considering the scale to which I delved into psychiatric research on the topic at the time. &quot;One of the features which makes music a low-cost alternative to sleep medication is the distracting function of music,&quot; explains Helle Nystrup Lund, a Danish PhD researcher and music therapist at the Unit for Psychiatric Research at &amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Aalborg University Hospital&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;, whose current research is focused on whether music can improve sleep quality for patients suffering from depression and insomnia. &quot;Stress and depression are likely to be followed by worries and thoughts,&quot; she tells me. &quot;Thoughts and restlessness are preventing sleep initiation. Music may distract from feelings and thoughts and help the individual to fall asleep. Calm music supports relaxation and this is also helpful to improve sleep.&quot;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Sleeping in uncertain times&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;For me and millions of others, insomnia is the product of mental or emotional pressure, which can increase stress levels and engender a tortuously vicious cycle. The recent outbreak of the COVID-19 pandemic has brought with it its own collateral miasma of stressfulness and sleeplessness, a factor reinforced by a scientific paper in the &amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Journal of Sleep Research&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt; detailing the quarantine's inimical effects on stress-inflected insomnia and emotional regulation.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;While it may seem negligible compared to the widespread devastation of the coronavirus, issues ranging from epidemiological fears of infection to the economic worries of personal finance are preventing proper sleep. As a 2012 research paper from Korea University suggests, such worries can aggravate the triggers of insomnia, inducing the body to secrete excessive amounts of the hormone cortisol and leading to the hyper-alertness that breeds insomniac states. Quality sleep is not a panacea and cannot resolve all the acute nightmares of the pandemic; however, as subjective experience can attest to, music can be a practical leitmotif for a healthy regimen of rest.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Jimi Tormey, a musician who has also suffered with insomnia, tells me of his own sonic self-medication: &quot;I find that repetition is one of the key musical elements that helps me sleep, but dynamic percussive sounds somehow feel 'closer' to me, which can be disruptive when trying to get to sleep,&quot; he affirms. &quot;To silence sleep-preventing thoughts, I listen to minimalist composers and albums that have an overall sense of regularity and calmness to prevent spikes in tempo or timbre.&quot; His account seems to be pitched in unison with scientists at the University of Fribourg's Division of Cognitive Biopsychology and Methods, who have empirically proven that relaxing music can aid sleep. According to their investigations, soundscapes, classical music and ambient noise can all help to dissolve stress by inducing mental relaxation and muscle sedation.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;But what &amp;lt;em&amp;gt;is &amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;music? The definition is infamously elusive. We might say that music involves expression and auditory texture, sonic experiences and tone colour – conventionally, we could call it the art of successive and ordered sounds. For the purposes of this discussion, the term 'music' will be in the key of sleep: from ambient beats and dreamy soundscapes to a piano's delicate strains or the cadences of a sitar.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Take, for instance, the melodic framework of the &amp;lt;em&amp;gt;raga &amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;from the Indian musical tradition. Derived from the Sanskrit word for the act of dyeing or colouring, the term also signifies the imbuing of positive emotional states. Psychological research led by the National Brain Research Centre in India shows that &amp;lt;em&amp;gt;ragas &amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;use different combinations of musical intervals, scales, tonality and tempo to inject rhythmic colour and elicit emotions in the listener. &quot;Neelambari&quot; – an ancient and ubiquitous &amp;lt;em&amp;gt;raga&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt; – has long been thought of as a sleep-inducing lullaby, particularly in the context of the southern, Carnatic musical system. Despite some internal disputes about its soporific effects, the hypnotic pulses and cadences of the piece certainly connote a general sense of sleepiness.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&quot;We don't choose to hear or not in the same way that we can choose to close our eyes,&quot; explains Chris Waller, a researcher at Royal Holloway, University of London, whose work focuses on music in carceral contexts. &quot;Therefore, as Michel Serres suggests, to make our sonic environment feel stable and secure involves 'ear work,' which means determining what is meaningful sound and what is noise, and what the meanings behind those sounds are,&quot; he informs me. &quot;Given that music has such a rich internal logic, often very consistent and symmetrical, it can be a useful resource for the mind to grab onto and construct a predictable sonic environment out of.&quot;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Nightly nocturnes&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Some findings support the notion that classical music has a positive effect on sleep due to its impact on the parasympathetic nervous system – the network responsible for the body's 'rest and digest' responses. That listening to music can be evocatively somnolent is, of course, far from a novel phenomenon. For centuries, classical composers have honed the ability to convey feeling and emotion in their listenership. In the Western canon, the invocation of sleep-inducing emotion plays out in a slightly different key. Often called the 'poet of the piano,' Frédéric Chopin's poignant intensity and romantic finesse single him out as a composer of particular emotional refinement and therefore the perfect amplifier for insomniacs. A fellow insomniac, Chopin ironically complained that, &quot;meanwhile, my manuscripts sleep and I can't sleep&quot; in a letter he wrote in 1838 from his winter sojourn in Mallorca.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;His famous &quot;Nocturnes&quot; – so named for an evocation of the night – follow in the formal tradition of languidly melodic compositions and are often cited as practical preludes to sleep. In my own times of manic wakefulness, I have often depended on his 21 emotive solo piano pieces for a source of equanimity, with their soothing refrains, serenade-like lyricism and dreamlike &amp;lt;em&amp;gt;legato&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;. &quot;The nocturne is oneiric,&quot; echoes Matthew del Novo in &amp;lt;em&amp;gt;The Metaphysics of Night&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;.&amp;lt;em&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&quot;The start of No. 6 in G minor is particularly sleepy as if the notes are shaking drowsiness from them…the notes themselves going off – but not very far – to look for melody, like a mind that wanders into a fantasy by which it is carried away,&quot; he writes. &quot;The slowing pace allows one to drift and Chopin's talent for ending without ending, in the way one never registers the moment one falls asleep is evident here.&quot; His undulating analysis here describes almost exactly the way I have experienced them – each Nocturne like a peregrination of the mind.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;It is not just Chopin's &amp;lt;em&amp;gt;pianissimo&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt; that can exorcize the spirits of sleeplessness. There are reams of popular classical sedatives – from the languorous tempi of Erik Satie's &quot;Gymnopédies&quot; and Claude Debussy's &quot;Rêverie&quot; and &quot;Clair de Lune&quot;, to J.S. Bach's measured violin concertos. Indeed, according to psychological research conducted in the Department of Music at the University of Sheffield, classical music is overwhelmingly the most prevalent genre of music used for sleep. While it is the prevailing prescription, this is because much of it is gently ordered and immersive. Indeed, &amp;lt;em&amp;gt;any&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt; slow music of around 60 to 80 beats per minute (BPM) can help us sleep.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Euphoric whispers&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;As well as euphonic musical structures, ambient soundscapes and the recorded sounds of nature can also be a welcome tonic for those suffering with insomnia and other somnipathies. One example is the sonorous trend of ASMR (autonomous sensory meridian response) videos, which use sonic triggers to induce low-level euphoria and purportedly help with sleep – as is the case with Maya Lane, a postgraduate student in medical anthropology. &quot;I have anxiety that gets worse at night and causes my insomnia. It really heightens all my senses – things like someone talking, a door closing or the pipes in the house can make me feel completely on edge.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&quot;I've realized I need something to completely distract my brain away from concentrating on these sounds and help me sleep,&quot; she tells me. &quot;I either listen to the &amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Sleep Whispers&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt; podcast – someone telling stories in a whisper ASMR style – or the Headspace [a popular mindfulness app – ed. note] eight-hour soundscapes, which are things like rainforest noises, rain and storm noises. I'm not sure if they cause euphoria, but they definitely help relax me and take my mind off trying to sleep.&quot;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;By harmonizing with slow tempos and languid rhythms, both hypnotic sounds and music can lower blood pressure, slow down breathing and encourage the deceleration of heart rate – a synchronization that mimics some of the body's 'falling asleep' processes. As myself and others have discovered, a bedtime routine with a regular relaxing soundtrack sends clear signals to the body to initialize sleep mode and synchronize biological clocks with environmental cues (so-called &amp;lt;em&amp;gt;zeitgebers&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;) such as light. However, the therapeutic or soporific aspect of music is mostly effective in improving sleep indirectly via relaxation. This may help with anxiety and stress-related insomnia, but other bio-physiological sleep disorders such as sleep paralysis and more physical breathing-related issues including sleep apnoea will be unresponsive or less likely to respond directly.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Considering that we spend one third of our lives sleeping (or attempting to do so) the importance of sleep for supporting physical and emotional well-being rings clear as a bell. The echo of an echo: &quot;Even asleep we partake in the becoming of the world.&quot; After sleeplessly hearing his words, I finally understood the true import of Miłosz's maxim. His reminder that we contribute to the world in ways that might forever be unknown to us is like a somniloquy, a sleep-talking motto about self-awareness. How ironic, then, that my secret of sleep was the opposite: to be blissfully drowned in sound, to be unaware of oneself.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;But to be awake, to be besieged by insomnia, does not always correlate to an increased perception of the self. Even as modernity seems to be characterized by the condition of insomnia, it is vital that we listen to our own biological rhythms, to our aural textures of music, and that we keep time with the physiological acoustics of sleep – the rhythm of the night.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Reprinted with permission of &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://przekroj.pl/en&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&amp;gt;Przekrój&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;. Read the original article. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 14:26:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jelliclesfarm</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://bigthink.com/mind-brain/dmt-beings</og:url>
<og:image>https://assets.rebelmouse.io/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiIsInR5cCI6IkpXVCJ9.eyJpbWFnZSI6Imh0dHBzOi8vYXNzZXRzLnJibC5tcy8yMzMwNDM5NC9vcmlnaW4uanBnIiwiZXhwaXJlc19hdCI6MTY0OTIzODg5NH0.olG9qVo188AcWS5oVp6esIVYodQLzVKrfF24IYe15YU/img.jpg?width=1200&amp;coordinates=0%2C160%2C0%2C160&amp;height=600</og:image>
<og:title>DMT drug study investigates the ‘entities’ people meet while tripping</og:title>
<og:description>Why do so many people encounter beings after smoking large doses of DMT?</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://bigthink.com/mind-brain/dmt-beings</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Kirc – A tiny IRC client written in POSIX C99</title>
<link>https://github.com/mcpcpc/kirc</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/mcpcpc/kirc</guid>
<description>&lt;h3 align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/mcpcpc/kirc/master/.github/kirc.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/mcpcpc/kirc/master/.github/kirc.png&quot; alt=&quot;logo&quot; height=&quot;170px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;KISS for IRC, a tiny IRC client written in POSIX C99.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mcpcpc/kirc/blob/master/LICENSE&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/890acbdcb87868b382af9a4b1fac507b9659d9bf/68747470733a2f2f696d672e736869656c64732e696f2f62616467652f6c6963656e73652d4d49542d626c75652e737667&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/license-MIT-blue.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mcpcpc/kirc/releases&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/4d495359ee1e85d634ef8f11353ffd3b32c43795/68747470733a2f2f696d672e736869656c64732e696f2f6769746875622f762f72656c656173652f6d63706370632f6b6972632e737667&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/v/release/mcpcpc/kirc.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://repology.org/metapackage/kirc&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/58c4f7575f66f2fa87255efac4a4487f48934025/68747470733a2f2f7265706f6c6f67792e6f72672f62616467652f74696e792d7265706f732f6b6972632e737667&quot; alt=&quot;Packaging status&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://repology.org/badge/tiny-repos/kirc.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Objectives&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&quot;Do one thing and do it well&quot;&lt;/em&gt; — Emphasis was placed on building simple, short, clear, modular, and extensible code that can be easily maintained and repurposed (per the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unix_philosophy&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Unix philosophy&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Portability&lt;/em&gt; — &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/POSIX&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;POSIX&lt;/a&gt; compliance ensures seamless compatibility and interoperability between variants of Unix and other operating systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Usability&lt;/em&gt; — Commands and shortcuts should feel &quot;natural&quot; when using a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Keyboard_layout&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;standard 104-key US keyboard layout&lt;/a&gt;. Where possible, the number of keystrokes have been minimized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
usage: kirc [-s hostname] [-p port] [-c channel] [-n nick] [-r real name] [-u username] [-k password] [-x init command] [-w columns] [-W columns] [-o path] [-h&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;v&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;V]
-s     server address (default: &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;irc.freenode.org&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;)
-p     server port (default: &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;6667&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;)
-c     channel name (default: &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;#kisslinux&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;)
-n     nickname (required)
-u     server username (optional)
-k     server password (optional)
-r     real name (optional)
-v     version information
-V     verbose output (e.g. raw stream)
-o     output path to log irc stream
-x     send &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;command&lt;/span&gt; to irc server after inital connection
-w     maximum width of the printed left column (default: &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;10&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;)
-W     maximum width of the entire printed stream (default &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;80&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;)
-h     basic usage information
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;No dependencies other than a &lt;a href=&quot;https://gcc.gnu.org/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;C99 compiler&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complies with &lt;a href=&quot;https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc2812&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;RFC 2812&lt;/a&gt; standard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to log the entire chat history (see &lt;em&gt;Usage&lt;/em&gt; section for more information).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Simple command structure:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;message&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;                   Send a message to the current channel.
/m &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;nick&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;channel&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;message&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; Send a message to a specified channel or nick.
/M &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;message&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;                Send a message to NickServ.
/Q &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;message&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;                Send a message and close the host connection.
/x &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;message&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;                Send a message directly to the server.
/j &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;channel&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;                Join a specified channel.
/p &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;channel&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;                Leave (part) a specified channel.
/n                          List all users on the current channel.
/q                          Close the host connection.
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Color scheme definition via &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ANSI_escape_code&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;ANSI 8-bit colors&lt;/a&gt;. Therefore, one could theoretically achieve uniform color definition across all shell applications and tools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Screenshots&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/mcpcpc/kirc/blob/master/.github/example.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/mcpcpc/kirc/raw/master/.github/example.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot 1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building and installing on &lt;strong&gt;KISS Linux&lt;/strong&gt; using the Community repository:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
kiss b kirc
kiss i kirc
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building and installing on &lt;strong&gt;Arch&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Arch-based&lt;/strong&gt; distros using the AUR:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
git clone https://aur.archlinux.org/kirc-git.git
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;cd&lt;/span&gt; kirc
makepkg -si
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building and installing from source (works on &lt;strong&gt;Rasbian&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Debian&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/strong&gt; and many other Unix distributions):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
git clone https://github.com/mcpcpc/kirc.git
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;cd&lt;/span&gt; kirc
make
make install
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 12:14:17 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mcpcpc</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars0.githubusercontent.com/u/37268479?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>mcpcpc/kirc</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/mcpcpc/kirc</og:url>
<og:description>A tiny IRC client written in POSIX C99. Contribute to mcpcpc/kirc development by creating an account on GitHub.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/mcpcpc/kirc</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Amnesty International denied access to court in the Assange extradition hearing</title>
<link>https://twitter.com/JuliaHall18/status/1306197900289019904</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://twitter.com/JuliaHall18/status/1306197900289019904</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/JuliaHall18/status/1306197900289019904&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/JuliaHall18/status/1306197900289019904&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24491776&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24491776&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 254&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 56&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 12:05:01 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>k1m</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mobile.twitter.com/JuliaHall18/status/1306197900289019904</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The majority of 18- to 29-year-olds in the US are now living with their parents</title>
<link>https://www.axios.com/working-from-parents-home-82414f13-156f-43c2-aafa-733bd7541146.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.axios.com/working-from-parents-home-82414f13-156f-43c2-aafa-733bd7541146.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Nearly 30 million Americans are spending their 20s in the same place they spent their grade school years: at home with their parents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The big picture:&lt;/strong&gt; For the first time since the Great Depression, &lt;a class=&quot;gtm-content-click&quot; data-vars-link-text=&quot;the majority&quot; data-vars-click-url=&quot;https://www.pewresearch.org/fact-tank/2020/09/04/a-majority-of-young-adults-in-the-u-s-live-with-their-parents-for-the-first-time-since-the-great-depression/&quot; data-vars-content-id=&quot;82414f13-156f-43c2-aafa-733bd7541146&quot; data-vars-headline=&quot;Working from (your parents') home&quot; data-vars-event-category=&quot;story&quot; data-vars-sub-category=&quot;story&quot; data-vars-item=&quot;in_content_link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.pewresearch.org/fact-tank/2020/09/04/a-majority-of-young-adults-in-the-u-s-live-with-their-parents-for-the-first-time-since-the-great-depression/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the majority&lt;/a&gt; of 18- to 29-year-olds have moved back home. Those living arrangements can come with a great deal of awkwardness and pain, but families across America are making the most of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&quot;I’m worried about it,&quot;&lt;/strong&gt; says Jeffrey Arnett, a psychologist at Clark University, who &lt;a class=&quot;gtm-content-click&quot; data-vars-link-text=&quot;coined the term&quot; data-vars-click-url=&quot;https://link.axios.com/click/21517288.8/aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuYXBhLm9yZy9tb25pdG9yL2p1bjA2L2VtZXJnaW5nP3V0bV9zb3VyY2U9bmV3c2xldHRlciZ1dG1fbWVkaXVtPWVtYWlsJnV0bV9jYW1wYWlnbj1zZW5kdG9fbmV3c2xldHRlcnRlc3Qmc3RyZWFtPXRvcA/598cdd4c8cc2b200398b463bBa91a755b&quot; data-vars-content-id=&quot;82414f13-156f-43c2-aafa-733bd7541146&quot; data-vars-headline=&quot;Working from (your parents') home&quot; data-vars-event-category=&quot;story&quot; data-vars-sub-category=&quot;story&quot; data-vars-item=&quot;in_content_link&quot; href=&quot;https://link.axios.com/click/21517288.8/aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuYXBhLm9yZy9tb25pdG9yL2p1bjA2L2VtZXJnaW5nP3V0bV9zb3VyY2U9bmV3c2xldHRlciZ1dG1fbWVkaXVtPWVtYWlsJnV0bV9jYW1wYWlnbj1zZW5kdG9fbmV3c2xldHRlcnRlc3Qmc3RyZWFtPXRvcA/598cdd4c8cc2b200398b463bBa91a755b&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;coined the term&lt;/a&gt; &quot;emerging adults&quot; for 18- to 29-year olds. &quot;I think we all should be. The rates of being depressed and anxious have really gone up among emerging adults.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reasons for moving home vary.&lt;/strong&gt; The coronavirus recession has hit young people &lt;a class=&quot;gtm-content-click&quot; data-vars-link-text=&quot;especially hard&quot; data-vars-click-url=&quot;https://link.axios.com/click/21517288.8/aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cucGV3cmVzZWFyY2gub3JnL2ZhY3QtdGFuay8yMDIwLzA2LzExL3VuZW1wbG95bWVudC1yb3NlLWhpZ2hlci1pbi10aHJlZS1tb250aHMtb2YtY292aWQtMTktdGhhbi1pdC1kaWQtaW4tdHdvLXllYXJzLW9mLXRoZS1ncmVhdC1yZWNlc3Npb24vP3V0bV9zb3VyY2U9bmV3c2xldHRlciZ1dG1fbWVkaXVtPWVtYWlsJnV0bV9jYW1wYWlnbj1zZW5kdG9fbmV3c2xldHRlcnRlc3Qmc3RyZWFtPXRvcA/598cdd4c8cc2b200398b463bBcf2e168a&quot; data-vars-content-id=&quot;82414f13-156f-43c2-aafa-733bd7541146&quot; data-vars-headline=&quot;Working from (your parents') home&quot; data-vars-event-category=&quot;story&quot; data-vars-sub-category=&quot;story&quot; data-vars-item=&quot;in_content_link&quot; href=&quot;https://link.axios.com/click/21517288.8/aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cucGV3cmVzZWFyY2gub3JnL2ZhY3QtdGFuay8yMDIwLzA2LzExL3VuZW1wbG95bWVudC1yb3NlLWhpZ2hlci1pbi10aHJlZS1tb250aHMtb2YtY292aWQtMTktdGhhbi1pdC1kaWQtaW4tdHdvLXllYXJzLW9mLXRoZS1ncmVhdC1yZWNlc3Npb24vP3V0bV9zb3VyY2U9bmV3c2xldHRlciZ1dG1fbWVkaXVtPWVtYWlsJnV0bV9jYW1wYWlnbj1zZW5kdG9fbmV3c2xldHRlcnRlc3Qmc3RyZWFtPXRvcA/598cdd4c8cc2b200398b463bBcf2e168a&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;especially hard&lt;/a&gt;, and many are living with family because they've lost their jobs or haven't been able to find work after college or grad school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Others wanted some company during lockdowns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&quot;You can’t imagine how great it is to hear that I’m in the majority of my generation,&quot; says Elsa Anschuetz, a 24-year-old working in public relations out of her childhood bedroom. &quot;It is definitely not where I thought I’d be at this stage in my life, but, at least to me, it is definitely better than living in an apartment alone during this crazy pandemic.&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;My friends who are at home or with friends in large roommate groups seem to be faring better than people on their own,&quot; says Alex Jang, a consultant in his early 20s who's living with his parents, grandparents, girlfriend and dogs in Orinda, California.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But there's a host of unforeseen consequences&lt;/strong&gt; that come with moving back in with parents, young people say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Kegan Zimmerman, a junior at the University of Minnesota who lived with his family for a couple of months early in the pandemic, says he had to boot his younger brothers off the WiFi to take Zoom classes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;There was also an issue of feeling like you lose a piece of your personality or character,&quot; he says. &quot;While moving back home during the pandemic makes sense and is seen as socially acceptable or even smart, it also means you are living with people who still see you as your 18-year-old self.&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And for those in their late 20s,&lt;/strong&gt; who likely had been living on their own for years, returning home can be even more painful. &quot;It’s much harder, and it feels like much more of a retreat,&quot; Arnett says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There are silver linings,&lt;/strong&gt; one father tells me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&quot;I'm a dad who is happy to have his daughter and fiancé living with me. They pay the utilities and make me nice meals, and it makes it a lot less lonely here. ... I like the multi-generational thing. I know it won't last forever, but it makes life better for now.&quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;cite&gt;— Robert Legge of Culpeper, Virginia&lt;/cite&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 11:32:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jbegley</dc:creator>
<og:title>Nearly 30 million young adults have moved back in with their parents</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.axios.com/working-from-parents-home-82414f13-156f-43c2-aafa-733bd7541146.html</og:url>
<og:image>https://images.axios.com/QpfUBmJo7dZr1E01PPWL3Ab3PTU=/fit-in/1366x1366/2020/09/15/1600204694445.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>The coronavirus recession has hit young people especially hard.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.axios.com/working-from-parents-home-82414f13-156f-43c2-aafa-733bd7541146.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>