<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Fashion industry emits more carbon than flights and maritime shipping combined</title>
<link>https://www.businessinsider.com/fast-fashion-environmental-impact-pollution-emissions-waste-water-2019-10</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.businessinsider.com/fast-fashion-environmental-impact-pollution-emissions-waste-water-2019-10</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Some parts of modern life are, at this point, widely known to cause environmental harm — flying overseas, using disposable plastic items, and even driving to and from work, for example. But when it comes to our clothes, the impacts are less obvious. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As consumers worldwide buy more clothes, the growing market for cheap items and new styles is taking a toll on the environment. On average, people bought 60% more garments in 2014 than they did in 2000. Fashion production makes up 10% of humanity's carbon emissions, dries up water sources, and pollutes rivers and streams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What's more, 85% of all textiles go to the dump each year. And washing some types of clothes sends thousands of bits of plastic into the ocean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the most significant impacts fast fashion has on the planet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 19:34:40 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>hkmaxpro</dc:creator>
<og:title>The fashion industry emits more carbon than international flights and maritime shipping combined. Here are the biggest ways it impacts the planet.</og:title>
<og:description>The fashion industry is the second-largest consumer of water and the second-largest polluter of water. Here's why.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.businessinsider.com/fast-fashion-environmental-impact-pollution-emissions-waste-water-2019-10</og:url>
<og:image>https://image.businessinsider.com/5da76f5a4af90912ef24bf34?width=1200&amp;format=jpeg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.businessinsider.com/fast-fashion-environmental-impact-pollution-emissions-waste-water-2019-10</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>AWS Customers Rack Up Hefty Bills for Moving Data</title>
<link>https://www.theinformation.com/articles/aws-customers-rack-up-hefty-bills-for-moving-data?pu=hackernews7d0vdx&amp;utm_source=hackernews&amp;utm_medium=unlock</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theinformation.com/articles/aws-customers-rack-up-hefty-bills-for-moving-data?pu=hackernews7d0vdx&amp;utm_source=hackernews&amp;utm_medium=unlock</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;first&quot;&gt;There are a lot of ways companies can rack up high bills for using cloud services, sometimes unexpectedly. One particularly stiff expense is the cost of shifting data from one cloud provider’s servers to another provider, or to a company’s own data center. The Information has learned just how much some companies have had to pay for these “data transfer” costs, as they’re called.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chart above shows how much 10 of the top customers of Amazon Web Services—the dominant cloud provider—paid for data transfer services in 2017 and 2018. The chart, which is based on internal AWS sales figures obtained by The Information, show that data transfer charges for one customer, Apple, approached $50 million in 2017. That represented about 6.5% of Apple’s total AWS bill of $775 million for that year, the sales figures show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seven of the 10 companies saw increases of at least 50% in their AWS data transfer bills last year compared to the year before. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;takeaway-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;label&quot;&gt;The Takeaway&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;• ‘Transfer fees’ stem from moving data to new geographies, out of AWS&lt;br/&gt;• Apple saw nearly $50 million in such fees in 2017&lt;br/&gt;• Pinterest, Netflix, others saw transfer fee increases of over 50% last year&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;continue-reading&quot; readability=&quot;120.74905731523&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It couldn’t be learned why the companies on our list had such hefty data transfer bills. The charges can stem from growth in the number of users on a company’s web service, longer-than-average usage sessions and the addition of data-intensive features such as video, said Miles Ward, CTO at Sada Systems, a company that works with Google Cloud customers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The size of these costs has long been an issue for corporate customers of public cloud providers. AWS, Microsoft and Google all let companies move their data into the cloud for free. But moving data out—what are called “egress fees”—can be high enough to deter customers from doing so. But companies can incur data transfer fees from their cloud providers for other reasons, including when they move large amounts of information to servers in a new geographic location to speed up internet services there. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the data transfer costs have caught some customers flat-footed, they haven’t been enough to deter most companies from flocking to cloud services, which many corporate customers have found more flexible and cheaper overall than running their own computers. Still, even innovative new technologies have hidden or overlooked costs that only become more apparent over time.      &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recouping Costs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The charges don’t appear to be a case of cloud providers gouging their customers. Cloud providers need some way of recouping the costs associated with moving customer data from one location to another. A person close to AWS said its data transfer charges reflect a range of technology costs customers would normally pay if they weren’t using cloud services, including fiber optic connections, networking hardware devices and software, cybersecurity services and network monitoring software. Google and Microsoft also charge data transfer fees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The charges reflect the tradeoff companies make in exchange for getting the benefits of the cloud model, such as paying only for what you use and paying for services incrementally instead of all at once in advance,” said Patrick McClory, founder and CEO of IntrospectData, an AI-focused technology services firm. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Typically, customers pay only pennies per gigabyte of data moved, with charges kicking in after a small allotment of free transfers. At the huge scale many top customers operate at though, the fees can add up. For 2018, Pinterest had the highest overall AWS data transfer bill on our list at $26.4 million, up 78% from its $14.7 million bill in 2017, according to the AWS records seen by The Information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capital One’s data transfer charges grew 181% to $4 million in 2018 from the prior year, while Snap’s grew 588% to around $9.2 million in 2018 from the year before. Airbnb saw its data transfer bill rise 163% to $14.1 million in 2018 from 2017, according to the records.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Companies can get hit with data transfer fees when they back up data, so they store data in multiple data centers across geographic regions to ensure that an application remains available during service outages. In the case of Pinterest, for example, its bill shot up over a period when its active monthly users jumped to 265 million at the end of 2018 from 175 million at the start of 2017, according to its regulatory filings. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For other customers, the fees could indicate they are moving some of their cloud operations out of AWS. Apple, for one, sharply scaled back its usage of Amazon’s cloud service between 2017 and 2018, as The Information has previously reported. Instead, it began operating more of its own cloud storage, a move it made to ensure better performance for users in certain geographical regions and also to gain more leverage in negotiations with cloud providers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apple’s Big Bill&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whopping $50 million data transfer bill Apple received from AWS in 2017 could reflect that decision. Apple’s charges plummeted to $4 million last year, according to the records seen by The Information.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The charges represented a small portion of the customers’ overall AWS bills—some of which The Information has previously reported—during 2018 and 2017. The data transfer fees likely reflect heavy discounts that big companies often negotiate with AWS, one cloud industry analyst said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, AWS data transfer fees vary depending on where customers are moving their data. Figuring them out can be challenging for cloud customers, so much so that one cloud consultant created an intricate diagram to help clarify them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To better manage data transfer costs, AWS advises companies to use services like Direct Connect, which creates a private connection between AWS and the customers’ private data centers, reducing bandwidth charges from internet providers, the person close to AWS said.  AWS also recommends they use CloudFront, a content delivery network service, which helps minimize the distance data has to travel, the person said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;in-article-cta&quot; readability=&quot;27.59&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;card p3 bordered&quot; readability=&quot;6.23&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;serif bold type font-5 mt2 mb3&quot; id=&quot;lead-cap-title&quot;&gt;Sign up to receive 5 free days of our daily summary for tech news.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;type font-8 quiet mt2 mb0&quot;&gt;Already a subscriber? &lt;a class=&quot;track-click quiet-link&quot; data-name=&quot;Login&quot; data-type=&quot;link&quot; data-location=&quot;email capture form&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theinformation.com/sessions/new&quot;&gt;Log in here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spokespersons from Apple, Adobe, Netflix, Intuit, Airbnb and Pinterest declined to comment. Spokespersons from Salesforce and Snap didn’t have a comment. Spokespersons from Workday and Capital One didn’t respond to requests for comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;last-paragraph&quot;&gt;Spokespersons from Microsoft and Google Cloud declined to comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 16:50:20 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ballmers_peak</dc:creator>
<og:title>AWS Customers Rack Up Hefty Bills for Moving Data</og:title>
<og:description>There are a lot of ways companies can rack up high bills for using cloud services, sometimes unexpectedly. One particularly stiff expense is the cost of shifting data from one cloud provider’s servers to another provider, or to a company’s own data center. The Information has learned just how ...</og:description>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.theinformation.com/articles/aws-customers-rack-up-hefty-bills-for-moving-data</og:url>
<og:image>https://dmxvlyap9srmn.cloudfront.net/production/articles/3969/small_eb45dde6-f1b9-4964-9b1e-d17e5a55a1e0.jpg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theinformation.com/articles/aws-customers-rack-up-hefty-bills-for-moving-data?pu=hackernews7d0vdx</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Google attempted to shut down a unionization meeting in Zurich</title>
<link>https://www.vox.com/recode/2019/10/21/20924697/google-unionization-switzerland-zurich-syndicom-zooglers</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.vox.com/recode/2019/10/21/20924697/google-unionization-switzerland-zurich-syndicom-zooglers</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;y2aCPM&quot;&gt;A group of dozens of full-time Google employees at the company’s largest mainland European office, which is located in Zurich, Switzerland, met to discuss unionization on Monday in defiance of their employer’s attempt to cancel the meeting. The tensions surrounding this meeting reflect Google’s growing struggles with employee discontent over workplace issues that go beyond just labor organizing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;sa7LnO&quot;&gt;The talk, titled “Unions in Switzerland,” was led by two representatives from a Swiss media and telecoms union called syndicom, and organized by Google employees. Last Wednesday, Google’s site leadership team attempted to stop the event by sending out an email announcing that it would be canceled, according to an email reviewed by Recode. In the email, Google said it was canceling the meeting because the company prefers to only host events on the topic organized in partnership with Google’s site leadership team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;yDNnDg&quot;&gt;Instead, Google leadership wrote in the note that it would host its own talks about labor laws and employee rights that bring “a diverse set of presenters and perspectives.” That upset many Google employees both inside and outside the Zurich office, who told Recode the company has been trying to block employees from hearing unfiltered information about workplace organizing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;nhMQU3&quot;&gt;Despite management’s notice that the meeting was canceled, employees in Zurich met anyway in Google’s on-site meeting rooms. So far, management has not stated it will take any action against people who organized or attended the meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;jUwm4N&quot;&gt;Google declined to comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;wG8bjD&quot;&gt;Historically, full-time white-collar workers at major tech companies like Google have been &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/07/08/technology/tech-companies-union-organizing.html&quot;&gt;reluctant to unionize or even openly discuss unionization&lt;/a&gt;. But attitudes have been shifting as a growing group of tech workers at Google and other companies have become more vocal about demanding greater labor rights and input on important company decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;Z7bf36&quot;&gt;These workers have begun organizing over disputes around issues such as retaliation after reporting &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/recode/2019/9/9/20853647/google-employee-retaliation-harassment-me-too-exclusive&quot;&gt;sexual harassment&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/03/04/technology/google-gender-pay-gap.html&quot;&gt;pay equity&lt;/a&gt;, and company participation in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/2018/8/17/17704526/google-dragonfly-censored-search-engine-china&quot;&gt;controversial government&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.com/2019/03/01/google-project-maven-contract/&quot;&gt;contracts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;1DEZuL&quot;&gt;Last month, Google contractors in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, some of whom make $40,000 a year for technical work, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/recode/2019/9/24/20880727/google-workers-unionized-contractors-hcl-tech-activism&quot;&gt;voted to form the first white-collar-led union at the company&lt;/a&gt;. Google management has so far stayed neutral in those efforts, but the company seems to have taken a more reactive stance in Europe by attempting to cancel this talk and a similar one about labor law and employee rights back in June.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;G9799P&quot;&gt;In the end, Google’s attempt to cancel and reschedule Monday’s meeting ended up drawing more attention to it and riling up rank-and-file support for labor organizing, several sources say. The Zurich office is one of Google’s largest outside its main campus in Mountain View, with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/google-zurich-headquarters-tour-2018-1&quot;&gt;2,000 employees who work on important products such as Google Maps, YouTube, and Gmail&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;xvUTEZ&quot;&gt;On Friday, Google’s site leadership team followed up in an email to Zurich staff with more details about the three talks it plans to host in lieu of the original worker-led event. The email stated that for the first talk, representatives from several Swiss unions, including the original one invited to speak, syndicom, were all invited to speak in a conversation moderated by Google management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;BkgxgJ&quot;&gt;This is still being viewed as unwelcome interference by some Google employees in support of the originally programmed event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;WwUz3X&quot;&gt;“It is disappointing that leadership persists in actively preventing Zurich Googlers from learning and exercising their rights, and is still trying to spin this as support for collaboration and healthy debate,” an organizer of the Zurich talk said in a statement posted on an internal Google communication platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;GgkAVk&quot;&gt;“Googlers are smart enough to recognize this for what it is: an irrational fear of anything that could possibly lead to systemic change.” The note went on to explain how employees in Zurich are uniquely vulnerable because the “vast majority” are not Swiss citizens and could get kicked out of the country if they lose their job at Google — and because Switzerland has relatively &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lexology.com/library/detail.aspx?g=efe1868e-b85f-4b7f-94c9-5df1ac65bdcc&quot;&gt;fewer labor protections&lt;/a&gt; than other European countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;AENoFK&quot;&gt;“You can imagine the climate that it creates for victims of harassment or discrimination, or people who want to speak up for what’s right even when that displeases management,” the note said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;lAexda&quot;&gt;Meanwhile, in other offices, Google employees have been posting memes in solidarity with their Zurich colleagues, criticizing management for trying to control the talk about unionization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;Mbnm3B&quot;&gt;“Some people were not interested in the talk in the first place, but because it had been canceled — they wanted to be involved and get to the bottom of it,” one Google employee, who asked to speak anonymously, told Recode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;cHaaV9&quot;&gt;“I do not understand it. It looks like [management] is afraid, but maybe it’s just because they are not used to the idea of having an elected body representing employees,” said the employee. “I think in the long-term, a healthy dialogue can be fostered.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;ELJi8N&quot;&gt;At this time, it’s not clear if Zurich employees will actually attempt to form a union; so far, discussions have been preliminary and educational. But nearly a year after &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/2018/11/1/18051884/google-employee-walkouts-explained&quot;&gt;20,000 employees walked out of work&lt;/a&gt; over the company &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/10/25/technology/google-sexual-harassment-andy-rubin.html&quot;&gt;giving executives&lt;/a&gt; over a hundred million dollars in payouts after sexual misconduct charges, it’s a sign of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/recode/2019/8/2/20751822/google-employee-dissent-james-damore-cernekee-conservatives-bias&quot;&gt;continued employee dissent brewing beneath the surface&lt;/a&gt; at Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;p-entry-hr&quot; id=&quot;8IgP4R&quot;/&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;UJeq3s&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Listen to&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reset&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;FuRIzt&quot;&gt;When Google announced its new Pixel 4 phone, one of the features it touted was Face Unlock, which uses facial recognition to unlock the phone. But the advancement came with a price - for black people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;SOQ4ZF&quot;&gt;Subscribe to &lt;em&gt;Reset&lt;/em&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;http://applepodcasts.com/reset&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apple Podcasts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;,&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://stitcherapp.com/reset&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stitcher&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;,&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/show/4UymEg74pIuiiLZTROIx4w&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spotify&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;, or&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://pod.link/reset/listen&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;wherever you listen to podcasts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 16:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>imartin2k</dc:creator>
<og:description>Management tried to shut down an employee-led talk on unionization at its Zurich office, but it happened anyway.</og:description>
<og:image>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lTQgaYQycxVTEC9Z0R6IxKcOqoE=/0x215:3000x1786/fit-in/1200x630/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13372713/1056086262.jpg.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Google’s attempt to shut down a unionization meeting just riled up its employees</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.vox.com/recode/2019/10/21/20924697/google-unionization-switzerland-zurich-syndicom-zooglers</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.vox.com/recode/2019/10/21/20924697/google-unionization-switzerland-zurich-syndicom-zooglers</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Bank of America&amp;#039;s CEO says it&amp;#039;s saved $2B per year by building its own cloud</title>
<link>https://www.businessinsider.com/bank-of-americas-350-million-internal-cloud-bet-striking-payoff-2019-10</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.businessinsider.com/bank-of-americas-350-million-internal-cloud-bet-striking-payoff-2019-10</guid>
<description>&lt;ul class=&quot;summary-list&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bank of America has bucked the Wall Street trend by building its own private cloud software rather than outsourcing to companies like Amazon, Microsoft, and Google.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The investment, including a $350 million charge in 2017, hasn't been cheap, but it has had a striking payoff, CEO Brian Moynihan said during the company's third-quarter earnings call. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He said the decision helped reduce the firm's servers to 70,000 from 200,000 and its data centers to 23 from 60, and it has resulted in $2 billion in annual infrastructure savings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/?hprecirc-bullet&quot;&gt;Visit Business Insider's homepage for more stories&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wall Street CEOs relish proving their critics wrong — and Bank of America's Brian Moynihan is no exception.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Discussing the &lt;a href=&quot;https://markets.businessinsider.com/news/stocks/bank-of-america-third-quarter-earnings-beats-wall-street-targets-2019-10-1028603152&quot;&gt;bank's third-quarter earnings results on Wednesday&lt;/a&gt;, Moynihan didn't hesitate to point out that many of the analysts on the call had doubted the company's capacity to shave billions off of its annual expenses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He said: &quot;2.5 years ago, we said we'd operate this year on $53 billion and change in expenses, and we hit that number — and a lot of you had us in at $57 billion.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did Bank of America do it? The company has made &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/big-banks-say-expensive-tech-efforts-paying-off-in-savings-2019-6&quot;&gt;massive bets on technology&lt;/a&gt; that have had a striking payoff, including billions in annual savings, Moynihan went on to explain. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bank, which has a $10 billion annual tech budget, has made an array of tech investments across its wide-ranging divisions — chatbots, automated mortgages, improvements to its mobile app — but Moynihan specifically highlighted the firm's decision to buck &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/banks-public-cloud-aws-google-microsoft-2019-3&quot;&gt;the Wall Street trend&lt;/a&gt; and build out its own internal cloud architecture rather than shelling out millions to public-cloud companies like Amazon, Microsoft, and Google.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This effort, which initially began in 2013, didn't come cheap. Moynihan reminded analysts the bank took a $350 million charge in 2017 in part to execute the changeover to its private cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the results have been dramatic. The company once had 200,000 servers and roughly 60 data centers. Now, it's pared that down to 70,000 servers, of which 8,000 are handling the bulk of the load. And they've more than halved their data centers down to 23.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;We reduced expenses by basically around 40%, or $2 billion a year, on our backbone,&quot; Moynihan said, adding that they've simultaneously seen their transaction load balloon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/bank-of-america-revives-dealmaking-via-portland-nashville-denver-2019-9&quot;&gt;Bank of America wants to dominate middle-market investment banking. Here are the new teams, hires, and cities it's adding to make that happen.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The new, more operationally lithe Bank of America is up 86% in mobile logins and 39% in wire transactions, while digital payments have climbed 29% to $424 billion compared with the third quarter of 2017. And the list goes on. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Howard Boville, Bank of America's chief technology officer, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/bank-of-america-cto-discussed-cloud-strategy-and-tech-savings-2019-5&quot;&gt;told Business Insider this summer&lt;/a&gt; that the bank would save $2.1 billion in infrastructure costs in 2019, a large part of which comes from moving a majority of its workloads from traditional on-premise servers to its private cloud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;lazy-holder lazy-holder&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy-image&quot; src=&quot;data:image/svg+xml,%3Csvg%20xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2000/svg'%20viewBox='0%200%201%201'%3E%3C/svg%3E&quot; data-content-type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot; data-image-base=&quot;//image.businessinsider.com&quot; data-srcs=&quot;{&amp;quot;5cfe782cea920805013b40ee&amp;quot;:{&amp;quot;contentType&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;image/jpeg&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;aspectRatio&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;4x3&amp;quot;}}&quot; alt=&quot;2018 tech budget large US banks chart&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://image.businessinsider.com/5cfe782cea920805013b40ee?width=600&amp;amp;format=jpeg&amp;amp;auto=webp&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;image-source-only&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-source&quot; data-e2e-name=&quot;image-source&quot;&gt;Shayanne Gal/Business Insider&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's how Boville explained the cloud's benefits and cost reductions to Business Insider:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A private cloud essentially uses software to lash together existing data center hardware into a single unified platform — making more efficient use of each individual server, while also making it easier for developers to access and scale up their resources.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's not just cost benefits Bank of America has recognized from the move to its private cloud, Boville said. The bank also has a better sense of its client interactions — of which on the consumer side there are 26 million daily. Everything from a customer's ATM card not working to a credit-card transaction taking slightly longer to be approved is monitored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now, the bank estimates its private cloud is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/bank-of-america-cto-discuss-not-moving-to-public-cloud-2019-6&quot;&gt;25 to 30% cheaper than public providers&lt;/a&gt;, though it also recognizes that probably won't last forever. Still, the company believes the architecture it has built will give it leverage in negotiating contracts with these companies — a process that is already under way, Moynihan said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;But so far, we're still cheaper, and so far, we have to make sure that the external providers are safe, sound, leave the data just for us to use for our customers, don't mix with other people's data, etc.,&quot; Moynihan said. &quot;And that discussion, negotiation, goes on as we speak.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Bank of America's peers haven't been as forthcoming on what they're spending on cloud services, prompting Mike Mayo, an analyst with Wells Fargo, to thank Moynihan for &quot;providing data that others have not provided yet.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moynihan's transparency is laudable, though, of course, it's easier divulging details when it involves revealing billions in savings and proving your critics wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 16:03:16 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>sogen</dc:creator>
<og:title>Bank of America's CEO says that it's saved $2 billion per year by ignoring Amazon and Microsoft and building its own cloud instead</og:title>
<og:description>Brian Moynihan, Bank of America's CEO, highlighted the firm's decision to move to a private cloud on its third-quarter earnings call.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.businessinsider.com/bank-of-americas-350-million-internal-cloud-bet-striking-payoff-2019-10</og:url>
<og:image>https://image.businessinsider.com/5da73d0bcc4a0a650659814a?width=1200&amp;format=jpeg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.businessinsider.com/bank-of-americas-350-million-internal-cloud-bet-striking-payoff-2019-10</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The most successful people are just the luckiest, a new computer model confirms</title>
<link>https://www.technologyreview.com/s/610395/if-youre-so-smart-why-arent-you-rich-turns-out-its-just-chance/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.technologyreview.com/s/610395/if-youre-so-smart-why-arent-you-rich-turns-out-its-just-chance/</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;jsx-671803276&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;jsx-671803276&quot;&gt;The distribution of wealth follows a well-known pattern sometimes called an 80:20 rule: 80 percent of the wealth is owned by 20 percent of the people. Indeed, a report last year concluded that just eight men had a total wealth equivalent to that of the world’s poorest 3.8 billion people.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;jsx-671803276&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;jsx-671803276&quot;&gt;This seems to occur in all societies at all scales. It is a well-studied pattern called a power law that crops up in a wide range of social phenomena. But the distribution of wealth is among the most controversial because of the issues it raises about fairness and merit. Why should so few people have so much wealth?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;jsx-671803276&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;jsx-671803276&quot;&gt;The conventional answer is that we live in a meritocracy in which people are rewarded for their talent, intelligence, effort, and so on. Over time, many people think, this translates into the wealth distribution that we observe, although a healthy dose of luck can play a role.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;jsx-671803276&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;jsx-671803276&quot;&gt;But there is a problem with this idea: while wealth distribution follows a power law, the distribution of human skills generally follows a normal distribution that is symmetric about an average value. For example, intelligence, as measured by IQ tests, follows this pattern. Average IQ is 100, but nobody has an IQ of 1,000 or 10,000.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;jsx-671803276&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;jsx-671803276&quot;&gt;The same is true of effort, as measured by hours worked. Some people work more hours than average and some work less, but nobody works a billion times more hours than anybody else.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;jsx-671803276&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;jsx-671803276&quot;&gt;And yet when it comes to the rewards for this work, some people do have billions of times more wealth than other people. What’s more, numerous studies have shown that the wealthiest people are generally not the most talented by other measures.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;jsx-671803276&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;jsx-671803276&quot;&gt;What factors, then, determine how individuals become wealthy? Could it be that chance plays a bigger role than anybody expected? And how can these factors, whatever they are, be exploited to make the world a better and fairer place?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;jsx-671803276&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;jsx-671803276&quot;&gt;Today we get an answer thanks to the work of Alessandro Pluchino at the University of Catania in Italy and a couple of colleagues. These guys have created a computer model of human talent and the way people use it to exploit opportunities in life. The model allows the team to study the role of chance in this process.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;jsx-671803276&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;jsx-671803276&quot;&gt;The results are something of an eye-opener. Their simulations accurately reproduce the wealth distribution in the real world. But the wealthiest individuals are not the most talented (although they must have a certain level of talent). They are the luckiest. And this has significant implications for the way societies can optimize the returns they get for investments in everything from business to science.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;jsx-671803276&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;jsx-671803276&quot;&gt;Pluchino and co’s model is straightforward. It consists of &lt;em&gt;N&lt;/em&gt; people, each with a certain level of talent (skill, intelligence, ability, and so on). This talent is distributed normally around some average level, with some standard deviation. So some people are more talented than average and some are less so, but nobody is orders of magnitude more talented than anybody else.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;jsx-671803276&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;jsx-671803276&quot;&gt;This is the same kind of distribution seen for various human skills, or even characteristics like height or weight. Some people are taller or smaller than average, but nobody is the size of an ant or a skyscraper. Indeed, we are all quite similar.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;jsx-671803276&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;jsx-671803276&quot;&gt;The computer model charts each individual through a working life of 40 years. During this time, the individuals experience lucky events that they can exploit to increase their wealth if they are talented enough.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;jsx-671803276&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;jsx-671803276&quot;&gt;However, they also experience unlucky events that reduce their wealth. These events occur at random.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;jsx-671803276&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;jsx-671803276&quot;&gt;At the end of the 40 years, Pluchino and co rank the individuals by wealth and study the characteristics of the most successful. They also calculate the wealth distribution. They then repeat the simulation many times to check the robustness of the outcome.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;jsx-671803276&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;jsx-671803276&quot;&gt;When the team rank individuals by wealth, the distribution is exactly like that seen in real-world societies. “The ‘80-20’ rule is respected, since 80 percent of the population owns only 20 percent of the total capital, while the remaining 20 percent owns 80 percent of the same capital,” report Pluchino and co.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;jsx-671803276&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;jsx-671803276&quot;&gt;That may not be surprising or unfair if the wealthiest 20 percent turn out to be the most talented. But that isn’t what happens. The wealthiest individuals are typically not the most talented or anywhere near it. “The maximum success never coincides with the maximum talent, and vice-versa,” say the researchers.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;jsx-671803276&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;jsx-671803276&quot;&gt;So if not talent, what other factor causes this skewed wealth distribution? “Our simulation clearly shows that such a factor is just pure luck,” say Pluchino and co.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;jsx-671803276&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;jsx-671803276&quot;&gt;The team shows this by ranking individuals according to the number of lucky and unlucky events they experience throughout their 40-year careers. “It is evident that the most successful individuals are also the luckiest ones,” they say. “And the less successful individuals are also the unluckiest ones.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;jsx-671803276&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;jsx-671803276&quot;&gt;That has significant implications for society. What is the most effective strategy for exploiting the role luck plays in success?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;jsx-671803276&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;jsx-671803276&quot;&gt;Pluchino and co study this from the point of view of science research funding, an issue clearly close to their hearts. Funding agencies the world over are interested in maximizing their return on investment in the scientific world. Indeed, the European Research Council recently invested $1.7 million in a program to study serendipity—the role of luck in scientific discovery—and how it can be exploited to improve funding outcomes.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;jsx-671803276&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;jsx-671803276&quot;&gt;It turns out that Pluchino and co are well set to answer this question. They use their model to explore different kinds of funding models to see which produce the best returns when luck is taken into account.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;jsx-671803276&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;jsx-671803276&quot;&gt;The team studied three models, in which research funding is distributed equally to all scientists; distributed randomly to a subset of scientists; or given preferentially to those who have been most successful in the past. Which of these is the best strategy?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;jsx-671803276&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;jsx-671803276&quot;&gt;The strategy that delivers the best returns, it turns out, is to divide the funding equally among all researchers. And the second- and third-best strategies involve distributing it at random to 10 or 20 percent of scientists.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;jsx-671803276&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;jsx-671803276&quot;&gt;In these cases, the researchers are best able to take advantage of the serendipitous discoveries they make from time to time. In hindsight, it is obvious that the fact a scientist has made an important chance discovery in the past does not mean he or she is more likely to make one in the future.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;jsx-671803276&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;jsx-671803276&quot;&gt;A similar approach could also be applied to investment in other kinds of enterprises, such as small or large businesses, tech startups, education that increases talent, or even the creation of random lucky events.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;jsx-671803276&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;jsx-671803276&quot;&gt;Clearly, more work is needed here. What are we waiting for?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;jsx-671803276&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;jsx-671803276&quot;&gt;Ref: &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/abs/1802.07068&quot;&gt;arxiv.org/abs/1802.07068&lt;/a&gt; : Talent vs. Luck: The Role of Randomness in Success and Failure&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 14:56:39 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>yarapavan</dc:creator>
<og:title>If you’re so smart, why aren’t you rich? Turns out it’s just chance.</og:title>
<og:description>The most successful people are not the most talented, just the luckiest, a new computer model of wealth creation confirms. Taking that into account can maximize return on many kinds of investment.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.technologyreview.com/s/610395/if-youre-so-smart-why-arent-you-rich-turns-out-its-just-chance/</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn.technologyreview.com/i/images/talent-v-luck-diagram.png?cx=3&amp;cy=89&amp;cw=401&amp;ch=225&amp;sw1200</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.technologyreview.com/s/610395/if-youre-so-smart-why-arent-you-rich-turns-out-its-just-chance/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Blizzard Postpones World of Warcraft 15th Anniversary Event in Taiwan</title>
<link>https://www.polygon.com/2019/10/17/20919539/blizzard-entertainment-world-of-warcraft-event-taiwan-hong-kong-protests</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.polygon.com/2019/10/17/20919539/blizzard-entertainment-world-of-warcraft-event-taiwan-hong-kong-protests</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;zHwn17&quot;&gt;Blizzard Entertainment has postponed its 15th anniversary &lt;em&gt;World of Warcraft&lt;/em&gt; event in Taiwan. The company made &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/WarcraftZHTW/photos/a.499668883677/10157881473878678/?type=3&amp;amp;__xts__%5B0%5D=68.ARC7l5hX6Q2V8051bE0DyPhJRhuky4HPurLfVj-F0uK52aSV8tfnpY4ZLsUjqjXdVxRVXEt0B5x6ONQkHPwcwtQgCOAny4RMlgGGPPM4JdBwVK-OWSon5ReXQBNh9nwF_dL73w0Q60-q2PbQqjMmTXYZYfcQM1n_yS8RVtIldeXGEgMf6s2Wu-PiPlSoUTAMj5Y6PBcBGeoPvnZKQrULIXwMRhJ40aIT-JuMHHNpOFO28G8dU3t_ApfQT8LJeyBMwqwvmFXFViQPI9KeBRYt-kGLQv6BNo-xp59yiQoipB7fs-4RIXxgUU4Rz1M4R6OqOISK4B50qyWhk4hLg3Oa&amp;amp;__tn__=-R&quot;&gt;an announcement on Facebook on Oct. 15&lt;/a&gt;, noting that the event — originally scheduled for this weekend — will be held at a later date. World of Warcraft was released on Nov. 23, 2004.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;ajgIEz&quot;&gt;Blizzard did not give a reason for canceling the event. Since posting, people have flooded Blizzard’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/WarcraftZHTW/photos/a.499668883677/10157881473878678/?type=3&amp;amp;theater&quot;&gt;Taiwanese &lt;em&gt;World of Warcraft&lt;/em&gt; Facebook page&lt;/a&gt; with support for pro-democracy protests in Hong Kong — a response that is likely influencing the event’s cancellation. A Blizzard spokesperson told Polygon it doesn’t have a statement “at this time.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;uPle8B&quot;&gt;Blizzard faced criticism internally and from fans after it &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.polygon.com/2019/10/8/20904303/hearthstone-grandmasters-blizzard-hong-kong-protest-player-suspended&quot;&gt;suspended&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;Hearthstone&lt;/em&gt; player Chung “blitzchung” Ng Wai for supporting Hong Kong demonstrators on an official &lt;em&gt;Hearthstone&lt;/em&gt; broadcast. Chung appeared on a stream wearing a gas mask — a symbol of the protests — and shouted “liberate Hong Kong, revolution of our time.” Blizzard stripped Chung of the money he won in a recent event and suspended him for a year, but later &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.polygon.com/2019/10/11/20910674/blizzard-statement-blitzchung-ban-update-hearthstone&quot;&gt;shortened the suspension to six months&lt;/a&gt; and returned his prize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;tCf0fB&quot;&gt;This week, the company &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.polygon.com/2019/10/15/20915358/overwatch-launch-event-cancelled-nintendo-nyc-store&quot;&gt;canceled its &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt; on Nintendo Switch launch event&lt;/a&gt; scheduled to be held Oct. 16 at Nintendo’s New York City store. As with the &lt;em&gt;World of Warcraft&lt;/em&gt; event’s cancellation announcement, people responded in support of protesters in Hong Kong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;CfPmBk&quot;&gt;Players and fans have since begun a boycott of Blizzard products, and others have started organizing protests for next month’s BlizzCon, the company’s annual fan convention in Anaheim, California. Protests continue in Hong Hong, with demonstrators now demanding “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/world/2019/8/22/20804294/hong-kong-protests-9-questions&quot;&gt;universal suffrage&lt;/a&gt;” in the region.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 14:54:20 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ilamont</dc:creator>
<og:description>A post to the Taiwanese World of Warcraft Facebook page is flooded with messages of support for Hong Kong</og:description>
<og:image>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pjIJ_PqD0VFcrs2gzMIbvuPT31M=/0x75:3840x2085/fit-in/1200x630/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19296563/ClassicLaunch_WoW_Onyxia_3840x2160.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Blizzard postpones event in Taiwan amid Hong Kong protests</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.polygon.com/2019/10/17/20919539/blizzard-entertainment-world-of-warcraft-event-taiwan-hong-kong-protests</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.polygon.com/2019/10/17/20919539/blizzard-entertainment-world-of-warcraft-event-taiwan-hong-kong-protests</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>NordVPN confirms it was hacked</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/21/nordvpn-confirms-it-was-hacked/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/21/nordvpn-confirms-it-was-hacked/</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot;&gt;NordVPN, a virtual private network provider that promises to “protect your privacy online,” has confirmed it was hacked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The admission comes following rumors that the company had been breached. It first emerged that NordVPN had &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hexdefined/status/1186106695073726466?s=21&quot;&gt;an expired internal private key exposed&lt;/a&gt;, potentially allowing anyone to spin out their own servers imitating NordVPN.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VPN providers are increasingly popular as they ostensibly provide privacy from your internet provider and visiting sites about your internet browsing traffic. That’s why journalists and activists often use these services, particularly when they’re working in hostile states. These providers channel all of your internet traffic through one encrypted pipe, making it more difficult for anyone on the internet to see which sites you are visiting or which apps you are using. But often that means displacing your browsing history from your internet provider to your VPN provider. That’s left many providers open to scrutiny, as often it’s not clear if each provider is logging every site a user visits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For its part, NordVPN has claimed a “zero logs” policy. “We don’t track, collect, or share your private data,” &lt;a href=&quot;https://nordvpn.com/features/strict-no-logs-policy/&quot;&gt;the company says&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the breach is likely to cause alarm that hackers may have been in a position to access some user data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NordVPN told TechCrunch that one of its data centers was accessed in March 2018. “One of the data centers in Finland we are renting our servers from was accessed with no authorization,” said NordVPN spokesperson Laura Tyrell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The attacker gained access to the server — which had been active for about a month — by exploiting an insecure remote management system left by the data center provider; NordVPN said it was unaware that such a system existed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NordVPN did not name the data center provider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The server itself did not contain any user activity logs; none of our applications send user-created credentials for authentication, so usernames and passwords couldn’t have been intercepted either,” said the spokesperson. “On the same note, the only possible way to abuse the website traffic was by performing a personalized and complicated man-in-the-middle attack to intercept a single connection that tried to access NordVPN.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the spokesperson, the expired private key could not have been used to decrypt the VPN traffic on any other server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NordVPN said it found out about the breach a “few months ago,” but the spokesperson said the breach was not disclosed until today because the company wanted to be “100% sure that each component within our infrastructure is secure.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A senior security researcher we spoke to who reviewed the statement and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/6506133-NordVPN-output.html&quot;&gt;other evidence of the breach&lt;/a&gt;, but asked not to be named as they work for a company that requires authorization to speak to the press, called these findings “troubling.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“While this is unconfirmed and we await further forensic evidence, this is an indication of a full remote compromise of this provider’s systems,” the security researcher said. “That should be deeply concerning to anyone who uses or promotes these particular services.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NordVPN said “no other server on our network has been affected.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the security researcher warned that NordVPN was ignoring the larger issue of the attacker’s possible access across the network. “Your car was just stolen and taken on a joy ride and you’re quibbling about which buttons were pushed on the radio?” the researcher said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company confirmed it had installed intrusion detection systems, a popular technology that companies use to detect early breaches, but “no-one could know about an undisclosed remote management system left by the [data center] provider,” said the spokesperson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“They spent millions on ads, but apparently nothing on effective defensive security,” the researcher said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NordVPN was recently recommended by TechRadar and PCMag. CNET described it as its “favorite” VPN provider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s also believed several other VPN providers may have been breached around the same time. Similar records &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hexdefined/status/1186106695073726466&quot;&gt;posted online&lt;/a&gt; — and seen by TechCrunch — suggest that TorGuard and VikingVPN may have also been compromised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A spokesperson for TorGuard told TechCrunch that a “single server” was compromised in 2017 but denied that any VPN traffic was accessed. TorGuard also put out &lt;a href=&quot;https://torguard.net/blog/why-torguards-network-is-secure-after-an-isolated-2017-server-breach/&quot;&gt;an extensive statement&lt;/a&gt; following &lt;a href=&quot;https://torguard.net/blog/when-bug-bounties-border-on-blackmail/&quot;&gt;a May blog post&lt;/a&gt;, which first revealed the breach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Updated with comment from TorGuard. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@zackwhittaker/how-to-contact-me-securely-38dc5c5bc756&quot;&gt;Got a tip?&lt;/a&gt; You can send tips securely over Signal and WhatsApp to +1 646-755-8849. You can also send PGP email with the fingerprint: 4D0E 92F2 E36A EC51 DAAE 5D97 CB8C 15FA EB6C EEA5.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 14:26:39 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>afshinmeh</dc:creator>
<og:title>NordVPN confirms it was hacked – TechCrunch</og:title>
<og:description>NordVPN, a virtual private network provider that promises to “protect your privacy online,” has confirmed it was hacked. The admission comes following rumors that the company had been breached. It first emerged that NordVPN had an expired internal private key exposed, potentially allowi…</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/GettyImages-512136509.jpg?w=534</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2019/10/21/nordvpn-confirms-it-was-hacked/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/21/nordvpn-confirms-it-was-hacked/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Elm 0.19.1</title>
<link>https://elm-lang.org/news/the-syntax-cliff</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://elm-lang.org/news/the-syntax-cliff</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://elm-lang.org/news/the-syntax-cliff&quot;&gt;https://elm-lang.org/news/the-syntax-cliff&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=21312109&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=21312109&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 318&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 131&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 13:40:42 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>roebk</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://elm-lang.org/news/the-syntax-cliff</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>BlizzCon 2019 Protest “Full-Steam Ahead,” Say Organizers</title>
<link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/blizzcon-2019-protest-full-steam-ahead-say-organiz/1100-6470690/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.gamespot.com/articles/blizzcon-2019-protest-full-steam-ahead-say-organiz/1100-6470690/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;GameSpot may get a commission from retail offers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;66.529411764706&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the wake of Blizzard's &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hearthstone-pro-banned-over-hong-kong-protest-supp/1100-6470418/&quot; data-ref-id=&quot;1100-6470418&quot;&gt;high-profile punitive action&lt;/a&gt; against a professional Hearthstone player, a protest at BlizzCon is moving forward as planned, according to its organizers. In a statement to GameSpot, organizer Dayton Young said that while the company's &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gamespot.com/articles/banned-hearthstone-player-speaks-out-after-blizzar/1100-6470512/&quot; data-ref-id=&quot;1100-6470512&quot;&gt;reduction of Blitzchung's penalty&lt;/a&gt; was &quot;a small step in the right direction,&quot; its decisions still deserve censure from the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Young cited Blizzard's punishment of Blitzchung, as well as the event casters and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gamespot.com/articles/blizzard-bans-hearthstone-streamers-who-protested-/1100-6470610/&quot; data-ref-id=&quot;1100-6470610&quot;&gt;American University students who protested in solidarity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;That Blizzard has shown a willingness to re-evaluate their decision is a small step in the right direction, but make no mistake; Blizzard continues to punish these individuals despite widespread outrage from gamers around the world,&quot; Young said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;We understand that game publishers and developers have a responsibility to moderate the content that appears on their platforms to ensure that gamers are safe from harassment, threats of violence, and other dangerous behavior. But silencing gamers who speak up about issues that affect their freedom makes us all less safe from oppression and institutional abuse.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For that reason, Young said the protest plans are &quot;moving forward full-steam ahead.&quot; The demonstration is scheduled for November 1, the first day of BlizzCon, at 12 PM. It will take place outside the Anaheim Convention Center venue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blizzard initially sparked a firestorm of controversy when it punished professional Hearthstone player Ng Wai Chung aka Blitzchung after he &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hearthstone-pro-banned-over-hong-kong-protest-supp/1100-6470418/&quot; data-ref-id=&quot;1100-6470418&quot;&gt;spoke out in support of Hong Kong protests&lt;/a&gt; in a post-match interview. This led to calls for a boycott of Blizzard products and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gamespot.com/articles/blizzcon-2019-may-see-hong-kong-protests/1100-6470502/&quot; data-ref-id=&quot;1100-6470502&quot;&gt;announcement of a planned BlizzCon protest&lt;/a&gt;. The company &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gamespot.com/articles/banned-hearthstone-player-speaks-out-after-blizzar/1100-6470512/&quot; data-ref-id=&quot;1100-6470512&quot;&gt;partially rescinded its punishment&lt;/a&gt;, giving back Chung's monetary winnings and reducing his ban from one year to six months. It also reduced its punishment for the event casters, and gave a matching punishment to the AU students--who made a point of criticizing Blizzard for failing to give equal punishment for the same offense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That didn't appear to quell the controversy entirely, however. Blizzard abruptly &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gamespot.com/articles/blizzard-cancels-overwatch-event-in-new-york-city/1100-6470548/&quot; data-ref-id=&quot;1100-6470548&quot;&gt;cancelled an Overwatch launch event&lt;/a&gt; in NYC, and while it didn't state its reasons, the ongoing backlash appeared related. The company is now reportedly &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/18/20921301/blizzard-bans-hearthstone-twitch-chat-pro-hong-kong&quot; data-target=&quot;true&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;banning users in its Twitch chat&lt;/a&gt; who express support for Hong Kong. Most recently a group of five members of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gamespot.com/articles/congress-criticizes-blizzards-hong-kong-player-ban/1100-6470692/&quot; data-ref-id=&quot;1100-6470692&quot;&gt;US Congress wrote a joint letter to Activision CEO Bobby Kotick&lt;/a&gt; urging the company to reconsider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 13:14:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>partingshots</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://gamespot1.cbsistatic.com/uploads/screen_kubrick/1585/15855271/3594277-blizzcon.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>BlizzCon 2019 Protest &quot;Full-Steam Ahead,&quot; Say Organizers</og:title>
<og:description>Following Blizzard's decision to partially rescind its harsh punishment against a professional Hearthstone player, the organizers behind a BlizzCon protest say it's still going ahead as planned.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/blizzcon-2019-protest-full-steam-ahead-say-organiz/1100-6470690/</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/blizzcon-2019-protest-full-steam-ahead-say-organiz/1100-6470690/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Apparently NordVPN Was Compromised</title>
<link>https://twitter.com/hexdefined/status/1185864801261477891</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://twitter.com/hexdefined/status/1185864801261477891</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hexdefined/status/1185864801261477891&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/hexdefined/status/1185864801261477891&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=21311475&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=21311475&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 270&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 207&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 12:30:21 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>doener</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mobile.twitter.com/hexdefined/status/1185864801261477891</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>