<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Show HN: Open Logos – Free logos for open source projects</title>
<link>http://openlogos.org/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://openlogos.org/</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;header__text&quot;&gt;Hello software people &lt;span class=&quot;text--emoji&quot;&gt;👋&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I designed these &lt;em class=&quot;text--bold&quot;&gt;free logos for your open source projects.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;header__text text--hidden-sm&quot;&gt;You can claim any, community will decide which project should get it. &lt;a class=&quot;header__rules-expand&quot; href=&quot;http://openlogos.org/#header__rules&quot;&gt;How it works&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul id=&quot;header__rules&quot; class=&quot;header__rules text--hidden-sm&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;To claim a logo, you need to have an active open source project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One logo can be only given to one project. This project will have all exclusive rights of the logo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Every logo has one github issue that you can introduce your project to and claim.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Community can upvote your comment and you can upvote other projects as well under these issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Starting from 1st of July, I will give one logo per day until the end of month according to these upvotes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header__cta&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/arasatasaygin/openlogos&quot;&gt;Claim your logo in Github&lt;/a&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 07:16:10 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>arasatasaygin</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://openlogos.org/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How I use Wireshark</title>
<link>https://jvns.ca/blog/2018/06/19/what-i-use-wireshark-for/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://jvns.ca/blog/2018/06/19/what-i-use-wireshark-for/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Hello! I was using Wireshark to debug a networking problem today, and I realized I’ve never written a blog post about Wireshark! Wireshark is one of my very favourite networking tools, so let’s fix that :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wireshark is a really powerful and complicated tool, but in practice I only know how to do a very small number of things with it, and those things are really useful! So in this blog post, I’ll explain the 5 main things I use Wireshark for, and hopefully you’ll have a slightly clearer idea of why it’s useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-s-wireshark&quot;&gt;what’s Wireshark?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wireshark.org/&quot;&gt;Wireshark&lt;/a&gt; is a graphical network packet analysis tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Mac, you can download &amp;amp; install it from their homepage, and on Debian-based distros, you can install it like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;sudo add-apt-repository ppa:wireshark-dev/stable
sudo apt update
sudo apt install wireshark
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wireshark is also in Debian’s apt repository so you can also just &lt;code&gt;sudo apt install wireshark&lt;/code&gt; but in my experience Wireshark updates are useful enough that it’s worth installing a more up-to-date version. The &lt;code&gt;wireshark-dev&lt;/code&gt; PPA is maintained by the Wireshark maintainers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wireshark looks like this, and it can be a little overwhelming at first. There’s a slightly mysterious search box, and a lot of packets, and how do you even use this thing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jvns.ca/images/wireshark_screenshot.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://jvns.ca/images/wireshark_screenshot.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;use-wireshark-to-analyze-pcap-files&quot;&gt;Use Wireshark to analyze pcap files&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usually I use Wireshark to debug networking problems in production. My Wireshark workflow is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Capture packets with tcpdump (typically something like &lt;code&gt;sudo tcpdump port 443 -w output.pcap&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;scp the pcap file to my laptop (&lt;code&gt;scp host:~/output.pcap .&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the pcap file in Wireshark (&lt;code&gt;wireshark output.pcap&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;That’s pretty simple! But once you have a pcap file with a bunch of packets on your laptop, what do you do with it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;look-at-a-single-tcp-connection&quot;&gt;Look at a single TCP connection&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often when I’m debugging something in Wireshark, what’s happened is that there’s some TCP connection, and something went wrong with the connection for some reason. Wireshark makes it really easy to look at the lifetime of a TCP connection and see what happened!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can do that by right clicking on a packet and clicking “Conversation filter” -&amp;gt; “TCP”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jvns.ca/images/wireshark_filter.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://jvns.ca/images/wireshark_filter.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then Wireshark will just show you other packets from the same TCP connection as that packet!! Here you’ll see a successful SSL connection – there’s are packets that say “client hello”, “service hello”, “certificate”, “server key exchange”, which are all part of setting up a SSL connection. Neat!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jvns.ca/images/wireshark_tcp.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://jvns.ca/images/wireshark_tcp.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually used this today to debug an SSL issue – at work today, some connections were being reset, and I noticed that after the “client hello” packet was sent, the client was sending a “FIN ACK” packet which terminates the TLS connection. This was useful because I could tell that the &lt;strong&gt;client&lt;/strong&gt; was terminating the connection, not the server! So immediately I knew that the client was to blame and I could focus my investigations there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This pattern is pretty typical of how I use Wireshark. Usually there’s a client and a server, and there’s a bug or configuration error on either the client or the server. Wireshark is invaluable for helping me figure out whether I should blame the client or the server :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;decode-as&quot;&gt;“Decode as”&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wireshark uses the port to try to guess what kind of packet every packet is, and often it does a good job! If it sees traffic on port 80, it’ll assume it’s HTTP traffic, and it’s usually right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But sometimes you have HTTP traffic happening on an unusual port, and you need to give Wireshark some hints. If you right click on a packet and click “Decode as”, you can tell Wireshark what protocol packets on that port are and then it’ll be much easier to navigate and search.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;see-the-contents-of-a-packet&quot;&gt;See the contents of a packet&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wireshark has an AMAZING details view that explains the contents of any packet. Let’s take the “client hello” packet from the details above. This packet is the first packet sent during a SSL connection – the client is saying “hello! here I am!”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wireshark gives you two super useful tools for investigating the contents of a packet. The first one is this view where you can expand every header the packet has (ethernet header! IP header! TCP header!) and look at what’s in it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jvns.ca/images/wireshark_packet_details_list.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://jvns.ca/images/wireshark_packet_details_list.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second view, which is really magical, is this one which shows you the raw bytes of a packet. The neat thing about this is that if you hover over one of the bytes with your mouse (like here I’ve hovered over &lt;code&gt;tiles.services.mozilla.com&lt;/code&gt;), it’ll tell you at the bottom of the screen what field those bytes correspond to here (in this case the “Server Name” field) and the Wireshark codename for that field (in this case &lt;code&gt;ssl.handshake.extensions_server_name&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jvns.ca/images/wireshark_packet_details.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://jvns.ca/images/wireshark_packet_details.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;search-for-specific-packets&quot;&gt;Search for specific packets&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wireshark has a great query language, and you can really easily search for specific packets! I usually just use really simple queries with Wireshark. Here are a few examples of the kinds of searches I do:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;frame contains &quot;mozilla&quot;&lt;/code&gt; – search for the string “mozilla” anywhere in the packet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;tcp.port == 443&lt;/code&gt; – tcp port is 443&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;dns.resp.len &amp;gt; 0&lt;/code&gt; – all DNS responses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;ip.addr == 52.7.23.87&lt;/code&gt; – source or dest IP address is 52.7.23.87&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wireshark’s packet search language is much more powerful than tcpdump’s (and it has tab completion!!), so I’ll often capture a large amount of packets with tcpdump (“all packets on port 443”) and then do some more in depth searching using Wireshark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;see-statistics-on-tcp-connection-duration&quot;&gt;see statistics on TCP connection duration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I want to specifically investigate slow TCP connections. But what if I have a packet capture file with many thousands of packets?! How do I find the slow TCP connection?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you click ‘Statistics’ in the menu then ‘Conversations’, Wireshark will give you this amazing statistics view that looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jvns.ca/images/wireshark_statistics.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://jvns.ca/images/wireshark_statistics.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This shows me the duration of every single TCP connection, so I can find the long ones and then investigate them in more detail! So useful :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;use-the-latest-wireshark-version&quot;&gt;use the latest Wireshark version&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t upgraded Wireshark in a while, it’s worth upgrading! I was looking at some HTTP/2 packets on my work laptop recently and was having a tough time. But then I looked at the docs and realized I was running an old version of Wireshark. I upgraded, and Wireshark’s HTTP/2 support had really improved in the newest version!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;use-wireshark-to-learn-networking-protocols&quot;&gt;use Wireshark to learn networking protocols&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s some networking jargon in this post (“frame”, “tcp port”, “dns response”, “source IP address”, “SSL client hello”). I left it in because Wireshark definitely doesn’t abstract networking details away from you. That can definitely be intimidating at first!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Wireshark can actually be a great tool to learn a bit more about networking protocols. For example, I don’t know too much about the details of how the TLS/SSL protocol works! But I can see that the first two packets are “client hello” and “server hello”, and it makes the protocol seem less like a scary mystery and more like a concrete thing that I can easily look at the details of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;that-s-all-for-now&quot;&gt;that’s all for now&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wireshark has a TON of features and I definitely only use a small fraction of its features. The 5 tricks I’ve described here are probably 95% of what I use Wireshark for – you only need to know a little Wireshark to start using it to debug networking issues!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 06:54:59 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ingve</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://jvns.ca/blog/2018/06/19/what-i-use-wireshark-for/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>New tariffs will push US manufacturing offshore</title>
<link>https://www.bunniestudios.com/blog/?p=5349</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bunniestudios.com/blog/?p=5349</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://ustr.gov/about-us/policy-offices/press-office/press-releases/2018/june/ustr-issues-tariffs-chinese-products&quot;&gt;new 25% tariffs announced by the USTR&lt;/a&gt;, set to go into effect on July 6th, are decidedly anti-Maker and ironically pro-offshoring. I’ve examined the tariff lists (&lt;a href=&quot;https://ustr.gov/sites/default/files/enforcement/301Investigations/List%201.pdf&quot;&gt;List 1&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://ustr.gov/sites/default/files/enforcement/301Investigations/List%202.pdf&quot;&gt;List 2&lt;/a&gt;), and it taxes the import of basic components, tools and sub-assemblies, while giving fully assembled goods a free pass. The USTR’s press release is careful to mention that the tariffs “do not include goods commonly purchased by American consumers such as cellular telephones or televisions.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Think about it – big companies with the resources to organize thousands of overseas workers making TVs and cell phones will have their outsourced supply chains protected, but small companies that still assemble valuable goods from basic parts inside the US are about to see significant cost increases. Worse yet educators, already forced to work with a shoe-string budget, are going to return from their summer recess to find that basic parts, tools and components for use in the classroom are now significantly more expensive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.adafruit.com/product/170&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bunniefoo.com/bunnie/tariff-illustration.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Above: The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.adafruit.com/product/170&quot;&gt;Adafruit MetroX Classic Kit&lt;/a&gt; is representative of a typical electronics education kit. Items marked with an “X” in the above image are potentially impacted by the new USTR tariffs.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Tariffs Reward Offshoring, Encourage IP Flight&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the most compelling jobs to bring back to the US are the so-called “last screw” system integration operations. These often involve the complex and precise process of integrating simple sub-assemblies into high-value goods such as 3D printers or cell phones. Quality control and IP protection are paramount. I often advise startups to consider putting their system integration operations in the US because difficult-to-protect intellectual property, such as firmware, never has to be exported if the firmware upload operation happens in the US. The ability to leverage China for low-value subassemblies opens more headroom to create high-value jobs in the US, improving the overall competitiveness of American companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the structure of the new tariffs are exactly the opposite of what you would expect to bring those jobs back to the US. Stiff new taxes on simple components, sub-assemblies, and tools like soldering irons contrasted against a lack of taxation on finished goods pushes business owners to send these “last screw” operation overseas. Basically, with these new tariffs the more value-add sent outside the borders of the US, the more profitable a business will be. Not even concerns over IP security could overcome a 25% increase in base costs and keep operations in the US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems the intention of the new tariff structure was to minimize the immediate pain that voters would feel in the upcoming mid-terms by waiving taxes on finished goods. Unfortunately, the reality is it gives small businesses that were once considering setting up shop in the US a solid reason to look off-shore, while rewarding large corporations for heavy investments in overseas operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Tariffs Hurt Educators and Makers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learning how to blink a light is the de-facto introduction to electronics. This project is often done with the help of a circuit board, such as a &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2tjWMfD&quot;&gt;Microbit&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2liZIFH&quot;&gt;Chibi Chip&lt;/a&gt;, and a type of light known as an LED. Unfortunately, both of those items – simple circuit boards and LEDs – are about to get 25% more expensive with the new tariffs, along with other Maker and educator staples such as capacitors, resistors, soldering irons, and oscilloscopes. The impact of this cost hike will be felt throughout the industry, but most sharply by educators, especially those serving under-funded school districts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bunniefoo.com/bunnie/ltcvol1-clipped-title.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Above: Learning to blink a light is the de-facto introduction to electronics, and it typically involves a circuit board and an LED, like those pictured above.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somewhere on the Pacific Ocean right now floats a container of goods for ed-tech startup &lt;a href=&quot;https://chibitronics.com/&quot;&gt;Chibitronics&lt;/a&gt;. The goods are slated primarily for educators and Makers that are stocking up for the fall semester. It will arrive in the US the second week of July, and will likely be greeted by a heavy import tax. I know this because &lt;a href=&quot;https://chibitronics.com/about-chibitronics/&quot;&gt;I’m directly involved in the startup’s operations&lt;/a&gt;. Chibitronics’ core mission is to serve the educator market, and as part of that we routinely offered deep discounts on bulk products for educators and school systems. Now, thanks to the new tariffs on the basic components that educators rely upon to teach electronics, we are less able to fulfill our mission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot; readability=&quot;9.4144144144144&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; xml:lang=&quot;en&quot; xml:lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Heads up! Prices for our products may have to rise in a couple weeks once 25% import tariffs are implemented (US only). If you've been on the fence, now is a good time to buy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— chibitronics (@chibitronics) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/chibitronics/status/1008807907620675584?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 18, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A 25% jump in base costs forces us to choose between immediate price increases or cutting the salaries of our American employees who support the educators. These new tariffs are a tax on America’s future – it deprives some of the most vulnerable groups of access to technology education, making future American workers less competitive on the global stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chibitronics.com/lovetocode&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bunniefoo.com/bunnie/ltc-craft-title3.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Above: Educator-oriented learning kits like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://chibitronics.com/lovetocode&quot;&gt;Chibitronics “Love to Code”&lt;/a&gt; are slated for price increases this fall due to the new tariffs.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Protectionism is Bad for Technological Leadership&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I was sent photos by Hernandi Krammes of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bunniestudios.com/blog/?p=5210&quot;&gt;network card that was manufactured in Brazil around 1992&lt;/a&gt;. One of the most striking features of the card was how retro it looked – straight out of the 80’s, a full decade behind its time. This is a result of Brazil’s policy of protectionist tariffs on the import of high-tech components. While stiff tariffs on the import of microchips drove investment in local chip companies, trade barriers meant the local companies didn’t have to be as competitive. With less incentive to re-invest or upgrade, local technology fell behind the curve, leading ultimately to anachronisms like the Brazilian Ethernet card pictured below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bunniefoo.com/ntw/ntw_feb_2018.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bunniefoo.com/ntw/ntw_feb_2018_sm.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Above: this Brazilian network card from 1992 features design techniques from the early 80’s. It is large and clunky compared to contemporaneous cards.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Significantly, it’s not that the Brazilian engineers were any less clever than their Western counterparts: they displayed considerable ingenuity getting a network card to work at all using primarily domestically-produced components. The tragedy is instead of using their brainpower to create industry-leading technology, most of their effort went into playing catch-up with the rest of the world. By the time protectionist policies were repealed in Brazil, the local industry was too far behind to effectively compete on a global scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Should the US follow Brazil’s protectionist stance on trade, it’s conceivable that some day I might be remarking on the quaintness of American network cards compared to their more advanced Chinese or European counterparts. Trade barriers don’t make a country more competitive – in fact, quite the opposite. In a competition of ideas, you want to start with the best tech available &lt;em&gt;anywhere&lt;/em&gt;; otherwise, you’re still jogging to the starting line while the competition has already finished their first lap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stand Up and Be Heard&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a sliver of good news in all of this for American Makers. The list of commodities targeted in the trade war is not yet complete. The “List 2” items – which include all manner of microchips, motors, and plastics (such as 3D printer PLA filament and acrylic sheets for laser cutting) that are building blocks for small businesses and Makers – have yet to be ratified. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://ustr.gov/about-us/policy-offices/press-office/press-releases/2018/june/ustr-issues-tariffs-chinese-products&quot;&gt;USTR website&lt;/a&gt; has indicated in the coming weeks they will disclose a process for public review and comment. Once this process is made transparent – whether you are a small business owner or the parent of a child with technical aspirations – I encourage you to please share your stories and concerns on how you will be negatively impacted by these additional tariffs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Some of the List 2 items still under review include:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; border=&quot;1&quot; readability=&quot;29.5&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;9030.31.00&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Multimeters for measuring or checking electrical voltage, current, resistance or power, without a recording device&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;8541.10.00&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Diodes, other than photosensitive or light-emitting diodes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;8541.40.60&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Diodes for semiconductor devices, other than light-emitting diodes, nesoi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;8542.31.00&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Electronic integrated circuits: processors and controllers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;8542.32.00&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Electronic integrated circuits: memories&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;8542.33.00&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Electronic integrated circuits: amplifiers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;8542.39.00&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Electronic integrated circuits: other&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;8542.90.00&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Parts of electronic integrated circuits and microassemblies&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;8501.10.20&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Electric motors of an output of under 18.65 W, synchronous, valued not over $4 each&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;8501.10.60&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Electric motors of an output of 18.65 W or more but not exceeding 37.5 W&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;8501.31.40&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;DC motors, nesoi, of an output exceeding 74.6 W but not exceeding 735 W&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;8544.49.10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Insulated electric conductors of a kind used for telecommunications, for a voltage not exceeding 80 V, not fitted with connectors&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;8544.49.20&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Insulated electric conductors nesoi, for a voltage not exceeding 80 V, not fitted with connectors&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;3920.59.80&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Plates, sheets, film, etc, noncellular, not reinforced, laminated, combined, of other acrylic polymers, nesoi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;3916.90.30&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Monafilament nesoi, of plastics, excluding ethylene, vinyl chloride and acrylic polymers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here’s some of the “List 1” items that are set to become 25% more expensive to import from China, come July 6th:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Staples used by every Maker or electronics educator:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; border=&quot;1&quot; readability=&quot;11.5&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;8515.11.00&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Electric soldering irons and guns&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;8506.50.00&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Lithium primary cells and primary batteries&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;8506.60.00&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Air-zinc primary cells and primary batteries&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;9030.20.05&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Oscilloscopes and oscillographs, specially designed for telecommunications&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;9030.33.34&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Resistance measuring instruments&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;9030.33.38&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Other instruments and apparatus, nesoi, for measuring or checking electrical voltage, current, resistance or power, without a recording device&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;9030.39.01&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Instruments and apparatus, nesoi, for measuring or checking&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;Circuit assemblies (like Microbit, Chibi Chip, Arduino):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; border=&quot;1&quot; readability=&quot;3.5&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;8543.90.68&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Printed circuit assemblies of electrical machines and apparatus, having individual functions, nesoi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;9030.90.68&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Printed circuit assemblies, NESOI&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;Basic electronic components:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; border=&quot;1&quot; readability=&quot;65&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;8532.21.00&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Tantalum fixed capacitors&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;8532.22.00&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Aluminum electrolytic fixed capacitors&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;8532.23.00&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Ceramic dielectric fixed capacitors, single layer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;8532.24.00&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Ceramic dielectric fixed capacitors, multilayer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;8532.25.00&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Dielectric fixed capacitors of paper or plastics&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;8532.29.00&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Fixed electrical capacitors, nesoi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;8532.30.00&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Variable or adjustable (pre-set) electrical capacitors&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;8532.90.00&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Parts of electrical capacitors, fixed, variable or adjustable (pre-set)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;8533.10.00&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Electrical fixed carbon resistors, composition or film types&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;8533.21.00&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Electrical fixed resistors, other than composition or film type carbon resistors, for a power handling capacity not exceeding 20 W&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;8533.29.00&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Electrical fixed resistors, other than composition or film type carbon resistors, for a power handling capacity exceeding 20 W&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;8533.31.00&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Electrical wirewound variable resistors, including rheostats and potentiometers, for a power handling capacity not exceeding 20 W&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;8533.40.40&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Metal oxide resistors&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;8533.40.80&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Electrical variable resistors, other than wirewound, including rheostats and potentiometers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;8533.90.80&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Other parts of electrical resistors, including rheostats and potentiometers, nesoi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;8541.21.00&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Transistors, other than photosensitive transistors, with a dissipation rating of less than 1 W&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;8541.29.00&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Transistors, other than photosensitive transistors, with a dissipation rating of 1 W or more&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;8541.30.00&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Thyristors, diacs and triacs, other than photosensitive devices&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;8541.40.20&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Light-emitting diodes (LED’s)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;8541.40.70&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Photosensitive transistors&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;8541.40.80&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Photosensitive semiconductor devices nesoi, optical coupled isolators&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;8541.40.95&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Photosensitive semiconductor devices nesoi, other&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;8541.50.00&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Semiconductor devices other than photosensitive semiconductor devices, nesoi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;8541.60.00&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Mounted piezoelectric crystals&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;8541.90.00&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Parts of diodes, transistors, similar semiconductor devices, photosensitive semiconductor devices, LED’s and mounted piezoelectric crystals&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;8504.90.75&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Printed circuit assemblies of electrical transformers, static converters and inductors, nesoi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;8504.90.96&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Parts (other than printed circuit assemblies) of electrical transformers, static converters and inductors&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;8536.50.90&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Switches nesoi, for switching or making connections to or in electrical circuits, for a voltage not exceeding 1,000 V&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;8536.69.40&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Connectors: coaxial, cylindrical multicontact, rack and panel, printed circuit, ribbon or flat cable, for a voltage not exceeding 1,000 V&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;8544.49.30&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Insulated electric conductors nesoi, of copper, for a voltage not exceeding 1,000 V, not fitted with connectors&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;8544.49.90&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Insulated electric conductors nesoi, not of copper, for a voltage not exceeding 1,000 V, not fitted with connectors&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;8544.60.20&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Insulated electric conductors nesoi, for a voltage exceeding 1,000 V, fitted with connectors&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;8544.60.40&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Insulated electric conductors nesoi, of copper, for a voltage exceeding 1,000 V, not fitted with connectors&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;Parts to fix your phone if it breaks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; border=&quot;1&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;8537.10.80&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Touch screens without display capabilities for incorporation in apparatus having a display&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;9033.00.30&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Touch screens without display capabilities for incorporation in apparatus having a display&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;9013.80.70&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Liquid crystal and other optical flat panel displays other than for articles of heading 8528, nesoi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;9033.00.20&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;LEDs for backlighting of LCDs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;8504.90.65&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Printed circuit assemblies of the goods of subheading 8504.40 or 8504.50 for telecommunication apparatus&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;Power supplies:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; border=&quot;1&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;9032.89.60&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Automatic regulating or controlling instruments and apparatus, nesoi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;9032.90.21&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Parts and accessories of automatic voltage and voltage-current regulators designed for use in a 6, 12, or 24 V system, nesoi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;9032.90.41&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Parts and accessories of automatic voltage and voltage-current regulators, not designed for use in a 6, 12, or 24 V system, nesoi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;9032.90.61&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Parts and accessories for automatic regulating or controlling instruments and apparatus, nesoi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;23&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;8504.90.41&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Parts of power supplies (other than printed circuit assemblies) for automatic data processing machines or units thereof of heading 8471&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;postmetadata alt&quot;&gt;&lt;small&gt;This entry was posted on Tuesday, June 19th, 2018 at 12:13 pm and is filed under &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bunniestudios.com/blog/?cat=5&quot; rel=&quot;category&quot;&gt;Ponderings&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bunniestudios.com/blog/?cat=3&quot; rel=&quot;category&quot;&gt;Social&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bunniestudios.com/blog/?cat=19&quot; rel=&quot;category&quot;&gt;The Factory Floor&lt;/a&gt;. You can follow any responses to this entry through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bunniestudios.com/blog/?feed=rss2&amp;amp;p=5349&quot;&gt;RSS 2.0&lt;/a&gt; feed. You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bunniestudios.com/blog/?p=5349#respond&quot;&gt;leave a response&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bunniestudios.com/wordpress/wp-trackback.php?p=5349&quot; rel=&quot;trackback&quot;&gt;trackback&lt;/a&gt; from your own site.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 04:40:30 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Taniwha</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bunniestudios.com/blog/?p=5349</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Elon Musk emails employees about &amp;#039;extensive and damaging sabotage&amp;#039; by employee</title>
<link>https://www.cnbc.com/2018/06/18/elon-musk-email-employee-conducted-extensive-and-damaging-sabotage.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.cnbc.com/2018/06/18/elon-musk-email-employee-conducted-extensive-and-damaging-sabotage.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;group&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tesla CEO &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/elon-musk/&quot;&gt;Elon Musk&lt;/a&gt; sent an email to all employees on Monday morning &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2018/06/18/elon-musk-email-tesla-factory-paint-shop-fire-sunday.html&quot;&gt;about a factory fire&lt;/a&gt;, and seemed to reference possible sabotage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, CNBC has learned that Musk also sent an e-mail to all employees at &lt;a class=&quot;inline_quotes&quot; data-gdsid=&quot;74213&quot; data-inline-quote-symbol=&quot;TSLA&quot; href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/quotes/?symbol=TSLA&quot;&gt;Tesla&lt;/a&gt; late on Sunday night alleging that he has discovered a saboteur in the company's ranks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Musk said this person had conducted &quot;quite extensive and damaging sabotage&quot; to the company's operations, including by changing code to an internal product and exporting data to outsiders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2016, after a SpaceX rocket exploded while being fueled up before an engine test, Musk and SpaceX COO and President Gwynne Shotwell also &lt;a class=&quot;inline_asset&quot; href=&quot;http://spacenews.com/spacexs-musk-says-sabotage-unlikely-cause-of-sept-1-explosion-but-still-a-worry/&quot; title=&quot;http://spacenews.com/spacexs-musk-says-sabotage-unlikely-cause-of-sept-1-explosion-but-still-a-worry/&quot;&gt;looked into&lt;/a&gt; the possibility of sabotage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;group&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several employees, from different divisions within Tesla, confirmed receipt of the e-mail to CNBC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tesla is currently ramping up production to make its previously stated goal of 5,000 Model 3s per week by the end of June. Last week, Tesla announced a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2018/06/12/tesla-to-cut-about-9-percent-of-jobs-across-company-report.html&quot;&gt;broad restructuring&lt;/a&gt;, slashing at least 9 percent of its workforce. Workers who are actively involved in Model 3 production would not be affected, the company said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tesla declined to comment on the e-mail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's the full email:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From: Elon Musk&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To: Everybody&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subject: Some concerning news&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;June 17, 2018&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11:57 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was dismayed to learn this weekend about a Tesla employee who had conducted quite extensive and damaging sabotage to our operations. This included making direct code changes to the Tesla Manufacturing Operating System under false usernames and exporting large amounts of highly sensitive Tesla data to unknown third parties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The full extent of his actions are not yet clear, but what he has admitted to so far is pretty bad. His stated motivation is that he wanted a promotion that he did not receive. In light of these actions, not promoting him was definitely the right move.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, there may be considerably more to this situation than meets the eye, so the investigation will continue in depth this week. We need to figure out if he was acting alone or with others at Tesla and if he was working with any outside organizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you know, there are a long list of organizations that want Tesla to die. These include Wall Street short-sellers, who have already lost billions of dollars and stand to lose a lot more. Then there are the oil &amp;amp; gas companies, the wealthiest industry in the world — they don't love the idea of Tesla advancing the progress of solar power &amp;amp; electric cars. Don't want to blow your mind, but rumor has it that those companies are sometimes not super nice. Then there are the multitude of big gas/diesel car company competitors. If they're willing to cheat so much about emissions, maybe they're willing to cheat in other ways?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the time, when there is theft of goods, leaking of confidential information, dereliction of duty or outright sabotage, the reason really is something simple like wanting to get back at someone within the company or at the company as a whole. Occasionally, it is much more serious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please be extremely vigilant, particularly over the next few weeks as we ramp up the production rate to 5k/week. This is when outside forces have the strongest motivation to stop us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you know of, see or suspect anything suspicious, please send a note to [&lt;em&gt;email address removed for privacy&lt;/em&gt;] with as much info as possible. This can be done in your name, which will be kept confidential, or completely anonymously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking forward to having a great week with you as we charge up the super exciting ramp to 5000 Model 3 cars per week!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will follow this up with emails every few days describing the progress and challenges of the Model 3 ramp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Thanks for working so hard to make Tesla successful,&lt;br/&gt;Elon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;group&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 22:26:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>yasp</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.cnbc.com/2018/06/18/elon-musk-email-employee-conducted-extensive-and-damaging-sabotage.html</og:url>
<og:image>https://fm.cnbc.com/applications/cnbc.com/resources/img/editorial/2017/10/10/104763989-GettyImages-855370098-elon-musk.1910x1000.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Elon Musk sends company email about 'extensive and damaging sabotage' by employee</og:title>
<og:description>Tesla CEO Elon Musk sent an e-mail to all employees late on Sunday night alleging a saboteur within the company's ranks had tweaked code on internal products and sent company data out without authorization.</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.cnbc.com/2018/06/18/elon-musk-email-employee-conducted-extensive-and-damaging-sabotage.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Amazon shareholders demand it stop selling facial recognition to governments</title>
<link>https://www.independent.co.uk/news/business/amazon-recognition-shareholders-jeff-bezos-letter-privacy-surveillance-facial-recognition-a8405221.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.independent.co.uk/news/business/amazon-recognition-shareholders-jeff-bezos-letter-privacy-surveillance-facial-recognition-a8405221.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;A group of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.independent.co.uk/topic/amazon&quot;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; shareholders is asking CEO &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.independent.co.uk/topic/jeff-bezos&quot;&gt;Jeff Bezos&lt;/a&gt; to stop selling and marketing pattern-recognition technology to governments after civil liberties groups warned of the potential for abuse.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, a group of advocacy organisations led by the American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU) published a report detailing how Amazon was marketing its Rekognition tool to American law enforcement agencies. In addition to touting the technology as helping to find suspects by allowing law enforcement to sift through images of faces, Amazon has said it could be used to preemptively identify “persons of interest” and prevent crimes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A letter signed by 19 shareholders - and provided to &lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Independent&lt;/em&gt; by the ACLU - urges Mr Bezos to halt the tool’s expansion until those concerns can be addressed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Furnishing police and sheriff’s departments with the tool would bolster “government surveillance infrastructure technology” and could drive down Amazon’s value, the letter warned. It also echoed concerns about the potential for misuse.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“While Rekognition may be intended to enhance some law enforcement activities, we are deeply concerned it may ultimately violate civil and human rights”, the letter said. “We are concerned the technology would be used to unfairly and disproportionately target and surveil people of colour, immigrants, and civil society organisations”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Outside of the United States, authoritarian regimes in other countries could use the tool to intimidate democracy advocates, the letter warned.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;556&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;1/50&lt;/span&gt; 18 June 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Residents pass by a temple gate collapsed by an earthquake in Ibaraki, Osaka Prefecture, western Japan. The earthquake, which struck western Japan, killed three people and injured more than 50.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EPA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;2/50&lt;/span&gt; 17 June 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Juan Carlos Osorio, manager of Mexico's national football team, celebrates their World Cup victory against Germany&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getty&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;3/50&lt;/span&gt; 16 June 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kashmiri youths through stones during clashes between protestors and Indian government forces in Srinagar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AFP/Getty Images&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;4/50&lt;/span&gt; 16 June 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People are silhouetted on the flybridge of a yacht as fireworks illuminates the sky over the Yas Viceroy luxury hotel on the first day of the Muslim holiday of Eid Al-Fitr at the Marina on Yas Island, Abu Dhabi&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EPA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;5/50&lt;/span&gt; 15 June 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somali Muslims take part in Eid al-Fitr prayer which marks the end of the holy month of Ramadan at the football pitch of the Jamacadaha stadium in Mogadishu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AFP/Getty Images&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;6/50&lt;/span&gt; 14 June 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Artists perform during the opening ceremony of the 2018 World Cup in Russia ahead of the group A match between Russia and Saudi Arabia at Luzhniki Stadium in Moscow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getty&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;7/50&lt;/span&gt; 13 June 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pope Francis arrives to lead the Wednesday general audience in Saint Peter's square at the Vatican&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reuters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;8/50&lt;/span&gt; 12 June 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;US President Donald Trump shakes hands with North Korean leader Kim Jong Un during their historic meeting at the Capella Hotel on Sentosa island in Singapore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reuters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;9/50&lt;/span&gt; 11 June 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;US President Donald Trump looking at a cake being brought for him during a working lunch with Singapore's Prime Minister Lee Hsien Loong during his visit to The Istana, the official residence of the prime minister, in Singapore. Kim Jong Un and Donald Trump will meet on June 12 for an unprecedented summit, with the US President calling it a &quot;one time shot&quot; at peace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AFP/Getty&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;10/50&lt;/span&gt; 10 June 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Muharrem Ince, presidential candidate of Turkey's main opposition Republican People's Party (CHP), delivers a speech from the roof of a bus during a campaign meeting in Istanbul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AFP/Getty&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;11/50&lt;/span&gt; 9 June 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;French President Emmanuel Macron, German Chancellor Angela Merkel and Japan's Prime Minister Shinzo Abe speaking to US Presidend Donald Trump during the second day of the G7 meeting in Charlevoix, Canada. Looking on is US National Security Advisor John Bolton.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EPA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;12/50&lt;/span&gt; 8 June 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Former South African President Jacob Zuma sings and dances on stage after delivering a speech during a rally in his support outside the High Court, in Durban.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AFP/Getty&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;13/50&lt;/span&gt; 7 June 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Russian President Vladimir Putin listens to a question during his annual call-in show in Moscow. Putin hosts call-in shows every year, which typically provide a platform for ordinary Russians to appeal to the president on issues ranging from foreign policy to housing and utilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AP&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;14/50&lt;/span&gt; 6 June 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Protesters wave flags and shout slogans during a demonstration against the use of the term &quot;Macedonia&quot; in any solution to a dispute between Athens and Skopje over the former Yugoslav republic's name, in the northern town of Pella, Greece.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reuters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;15/50&lt;/span&gt; 5 June 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Police officers salute as the caskets of policewomen Soraya Belkacemi, 44, and Lucile Garcia, 54, arrive during their funeral in Liege. The two officers, and one bystander were killed in Liege on Tuesday by a gunman. Police later killed the attacker, and other officers were wounded in the shooting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AP&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;16/50&lt;/span&gt; 4 June 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A rescue worker carries a child covered with ash after a volcano erupted violently in El Rodeo, Guatemala. Volcan de Fuego, whose name means &quot;Volcano of Fire&quot;, spewed an 8km (5-mile) stream of red hot lava and belched a thick plume of black smoke and ash that rained onto the capital and other regions. Dozens were killed across three villages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reuters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;17/50&lt;/span&gt; 3 June 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A recycler drags a huge bag of paper sorted for recycling past a heap of non-recyclable material at Richmond sanitary landfill site in the industrial city of Bulawayo. Plastic waste remains a challenging waste management issue due to its non-biodegrable nature, if not managed properly plastic ends up as litter polluting water ways, wetlands and storm drains causing flash flooding around Zimbabwe's cities and towns. Urban and rural areas are fighting the continuous battle against a scourge of plastic litter. On June 5, 2018 the United Nations mark the World Environment Day which plastic pollution is the main theme this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AFP/Getty&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;18/50&lt;/span&gt; 2 June 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Palestinian mourners carry the body of 21-year-old medical volunteer Razan al-Najjar during her funeral after she was shot dead by Israeli soldiers near the Gaza border fence on June 1, in another day of protests and violence. She was shot near Khan Yunis in the south of the territory, health ministry spokesman Ashraf al-Qudra said, bringing the toll of Gazans killed by Israeli fire since the end of March to 123.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AFP/Getty&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;19/50&lt;/span&gt; 1 June 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spain's new Prime Minister Pedro Sanchez poses after a vote on a no-confidence motion at the Spanish Parliament in Madrid. Spain's parliament ousted Prime Minister Mariano Rajoy in a no-confidence vote sparked by fury over his party's corruption woes, with his Socialist arch-rival Pedro Sanchez automatically taking over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AFP/Getty&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;20/50&lt;/span&gt; 31 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zinedine Zidane looks on after a press conference to announce his resignation as manager from Real Madrid. He confirmed he was leaving the Spanish giants, just days after winning the Champions League for the third year in a row.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AFP/Getty&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;21/50&lt;/span&gt; 30 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A worker cleans up the Millenaire migrants makeshift camp along the Canal de Saint-Denis near Porte de la Villette, northern Paris, following its evacuation on May 30. More than a thousand migrants and refugees were evacuated early in the morning from the camp that had been set up for several weeks along the Canal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AFP/Getty&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;22/50&lt;/span&gt; 29 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Police and ambulances are seen at the site where a gunman shot dead three people, two of them policemen, before being killed by elite officers, in the eastern Belgian city of Liege.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AFP/Getty&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;23/50&lt;/span&gt; 28 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;French President Emmanuel Macron meets with Mamoudou Gassama, 22, from Mali, at the presidential Elysee Palace in Paris. Gassama living illegally in France is being honored by Macron for scaling an apartment building over the weekend to save a 4-year-old child dangling from a fifth-floor balcony.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AP&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;24/50&lt;/span&gt; 27 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Migrants wait to disembark from the ship Aquarius in the Sicilian harbour of Catania, Italy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reuters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;25/50&lt;/span&gt; 26 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ireland awaits the official result of a referendum that could end the country’s ban on abortion. Co-Director of Together For Yes Ailbhe Smyth speaks to the media after exit polls suggested victory for the Yes campaign.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PA Wire/PA Images&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;26/50&lt;/span&gt; 25 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Film producer Harvey Weinstein arrives at the 1st Precinct in Manhattan where he turned himself in to New York police for sexual misconduct charges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reuters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;27/50&lt;/span&gt; 24 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Russian President Vladimir Putin (R) meets with his French counterpart Emmanuel Macron at the Konstantin Palace in Strelna, outside Saint Petersburg, on May 24, 2018&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getty Images&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;28/50&lt;/span&gt; 23 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People protest outisde the Tamil Nadu House after at least 10 people were killed when police fired on protesters seeking closure of plant on environmental grounds in town of Thoothukudi in southern state of Tamil Nadu, in New Delhi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ANI via Reuters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;29/50&lt;/span&gt; 22 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People demonstrate in Paris during a nationwide day protest by French public sector employees and public servants against the overhauls proposed by French President Emmanuel Macron, calling them an &quot;attack&quot; by the centrist leader against civil services as well as their economic security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AFP/Getty&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;30/50&lt;/span&gt; 21 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Newly appointed Catalan president Quim Torra arrives to visit jailed Catalan separatist politicians at the Estremera jail near Madrid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AFP/Getty&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;31/50&lt;/span&gt; 20 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Venezuelan President Nicolas Maduro casts his vote during the presidential elections in Caracas. Maduro was seeking a second term in power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AFP/Getty&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;32/50&lt;/span&gt; 19 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Channelized lava emerges on Kilauea Volcano's lower East Rift Zone on Hawaii. The USGS said on its website that &quot;a fast-moving pahoehoe lava flow that emerged from fissure 20... continues to flow southeast,&quot; with the quickest of three &quot;lobes&quot; progressing at 230 yards (210 meters) per hour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AFP/US Geological Survey&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;33/50&lt;/span&gt; 18 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Santa Fe High School student Dakota Shrader is comforted by her mother Susan Davidson following a shooting at the school in Texas. Shrader said her friend was shot in the incident. Multiple people have been killed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stuart Villanueva/The Galveston County Daily News via AP&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;34/50&lt;/span&gt; 17 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;French President Emmanuel Macron, British Prime Minister Theresa May and German Chancellor Angela Merkel meeting during the EU-Western Balkans Summit in Sofia, Bulgaria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reuters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;35/50&lt;/span&gt; 16 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People hold flags with the state coat of arms of Russia as they drive along a bridge, which was constructed to connect the Russian mainland with the Crimean Peninsula across the Kerch Strait.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reuters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;36/50&lt;/span&gt; 15 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Palestinians run away from tear gas shot at them by Israeli forces during a protest in Ramallah, in the occupied West Bank&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AFP/Getty&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;37/50&lt;/span&gt; 14 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Palestinian demonstrator runs during a protest against the US embassy move to Jerusalem and ahead of the 70th anniversary of the Nakba at the Israel-Gaza border.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;REUTERS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;38/50&lt;/span&gt; 13 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A bullet hole on the window of a cafe in Paris, the day after a knifeman killed one man and wounded four other people before being shot dead by police&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AFP/Getty&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;39/50&lt;/span&gt; 12 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Germany's Chancellor Angela Merkel looks on after receiving the 'Lamp of Peace, the &quot;Nobel&quot; Catholic award for &quot;her work of conciliation for the peaceful cohabitation of peoples&quot; at The Basilica Superiore of St Francis of Assisi in Italy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AFP/Getty&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;40/50&lt;/span&gt; 11 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Police forensics investigate the death of seven people in a suspected murder-suicide in Australia. Four children are among seven people that were found dead at a rural property in Osmington, near Margaret River. Detectives are investigating the incident, which was said to be treated as a murder-suicide, media reported. Two firearms were found at the scene, Western Australia Police said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EPA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;41/50&lt;/span&gt; 10 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Missiles rise into the sky as Israeli missiles hit air defense position and other military bases, in Damascus, Syria. The Israeli military on Thursday said it attacked &quot;dozens&quot; of Iranian targets in neighboring Syria in response to an Iranian rocket barrage on Israeli positions in the Golan Heights, in the most serious military confrontation between the two bitter enemies to date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reuters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;42/50&lt;/span&gt; 9 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iranian MPs burning a US flag in the parliament in Tehran. Iran said it will hold talks with signatories to a nuclear deal after US President Donald Trump's decision to withdraw from the accord, which it branded &quot;psychological warfare&quot;. President Hassan Rouhani also said Iran could resume uranium enrichment &quot;without limit&quot; in response to Trump's announcement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AFP/Islamic Consultative Assembly News Agency&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;43/50&lt;/span&gt; 8 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Newly elected Prime Minister of Armenia Nikol Pashinian addresses the crowd in Republic Square in Yerevan. The leader of protests that gripped Armenia for weeks was named the country's new prime minister on Tuesday, overcoming the immediate political turmoil but raising uncertainty about the longer term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AP&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;44/50&lt;/span&gt; 7 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Russian President Vladimir Putin walks before his President inauguration ceremony at the Kremlin in Moscow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reuters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;45/50&lt;/span&gt; 6 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lava from a robust fissure eruption on Kilauea's east rift zone consumes a home, then threatens another, near Pahoa, Hawaii. The total number of homes lost within the Leilani Estates subdivision thus far is 21, and geologists from the Hawaii Volcanoes Observatory do not expect the eruption to cease any time soon. A local state of emergency has been declared after Mount Kilauea erupted near residential areas, forcing mandatory evacuation of about 1,700 citizens from their nearby homes. The crater's floor collapsed on 01 May and is since then continuing to erode its walls and generating huge explosions of ashes. Several earthquakes have been recorded in the area where the volcanic eruptions continue, including a 6.9 magnitue earthquake which struck the area on 4 May.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EPA/PARADISE HELICOPTERS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;46/50&lt;/span&gt; 5 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Russian police carrying struggling opposition leader Alexei Navalny at a demonstration against President Vladimir Putin in Moscow. Thousands of demonstrators denouncing Putin's upcoming inauguration into a fourth term gathered in the capital's Pushkin Square.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AP&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;47/50&lt;/span&gt; 4 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chinese President Xi Jinping speaks at an event to mark Karl Marx’s 200th birthday at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AP&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;48/50&lt;/span&gt; 3 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;President Vladimir Putin meets with FIFA president Gianni Infantino in Sochi, ahead of the 2018 World Cup in Russia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AFP/Getty&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;49/50&lt;/span&gt; 2 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supporters of opposition lawmaker Nikol Pashinyan protest in Republic Square in Yerevan, Armenia. Pashinyan has urged his supporters to block roads, railway stations and airports after the governing Republican Party voted against his election as prime minister.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AP&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;50/50&lt;/span&gt; 1 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cubans march during the May Day rally at Revolution Square in Havana.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AFP/Getty&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;1/50&lt;/span&gt; 18 June 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Residents pass by a temple gate collapsed by an earthquake in Ibaraki, Osaka Prefecture, western Japan. The earthquake, which struck western Japan, killed three people and injured more than 50.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EPA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;2/50&lt;/span&gt; 17 June 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Juan Carlos Osorio, manager of Mexico's national football team, celebrates their World Cup victory against Germany&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getty&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;3/50&lt;/span&gt; 16 June 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kashmiri youths through stones during clashes between protestors and Indian government forces in Srinagar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AFP/Getty Images&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;4/50&lt;/span&gt; 16 June 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People are silhouetted on the flybridge of a yacht as fireworks illuminates the sky over the Yas Viceroy luxury hotel on the first day of the Muslim holiday of Eid Al-Fitr at the Marina on Yas Island, Abu Dhabi&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EPA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;5/50&lt;/span&gt; 15 June 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somali Muslims take part in Eid al-Fitr prayer which marks the end of the holy month of Ramadan at the football pitch of the Jamacadaha stadium in Mogadishu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AFP/Getty Images&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;6/50&lt;/span&gt; 14 June 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Artists perform during the opening ceremony of the 2018 World Cup in Russia ahead of the group A match between Russia and Saudi Arabia at Luzhniki Stadium in Moscow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getty&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;7/50&lt;/span&gt; 13 June 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pope Francis arrives to lead the Wednesday general audience in Saint Peter's square at the Vatican&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reuters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;8/50&lt;/span&gt; 12 June 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;US President Donald Trump shakes hands with North Korean leader Kim Jong Un during their historic meeting at the Capella Hotel on Sentosa island in Singapore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reuters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;9/50&lt;/span&gt; 11 June 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;US President Donald Trump looking at a cake being brought for him during a working lunch with Singapore's Prime Minister Lee Hsien Loong during his visit to The Istana, the official residence of the prime minister, in Singapore. Kim Jong Un and Donald Trump will meet on June 12 for an unprecedented summit, with the US President calling it a &quot;one time shot&quot; at peace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AFP/Getty&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;10/50&lt;/span&gt; 10 June 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Muharrem Ince, presidential candidate of Turkey's main opposition Republican People's Party (CHP), delivers a speech from the roof of a bus during a campaign meeting in Istanbul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AFP/Getty&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;11/50&lt;/span&gt; 9 June 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;French President Emmanuel Macron, German Chancellor Angela Merkel and Japan's Prime Minister Shinzo Abe speaking to US Presidend Donald Trump during the second day of the G7 meeting in Charlevoix, Canada. Looking on is US National Security Advisor John Bolton.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EPA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;12/50&lt;/span&gt; 8 June 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Former South African President Jacob Zuma sings and dances on stage after delivering a speech during a rally in his support outside the High Court, in Durban.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AFP/Getty&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;13/50&lt;/span&gt; 7 June 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Russian President Vladimir Putin listens to a question during his annual call-in show in Moscow. Putin hosts call-in shows every year, which typically provide a platform for ordinary Russians to appeal to the president on issues ranging from foreign policy to housing and utilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AP&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;14/50&lt;/span&gt; 6 June 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Protesters wave flags and shout slogans during a demonstration against the use of the term &quot;Macedonia&quot; in any solution to a dispute between Athens and Skopje over the former Yugoslav republic's name, in the northern town of Pella, Greece.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reuters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;15/50&lt;/span&gt; 5 June 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Police officers salute as the caskets of policewomen Soraya Belkacemi, 44, and Lucile Garcia, 54, arrive during their funeral in Liege. The two officers, and one bystander were killed in Liege on Tuesday by a gunman. Police later killed the attacker, and other officers were wounded in the shooting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AP&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;16/50&lt;/span&gt; 4 June 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A rescue worker carries a child covered with ash after a volcano erupted violently in El Rodeo, Guatemala. Volcan de Fuego, whose name means &quot;Volcano of Fire&quot;, spewed an 8km (5-mile) stream of red hot lava and belched a thick plume of black smoke and ash that rained onto the capital and other regions. Dozens were killed across three villages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reuters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;17/50&lt;/span&gt; 3 June 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A recycler drags a huge bag of paper sorted for recycling past a heap of non-recyclable material at Richmond sanitary landfill site in the industrial city of Bulawayo. Plastic waste remains a challenging waste management issue due to its non-biodegrable nature, if not managed properly plastic ends up as litter polluting water ways, wetlands and storm drains causing flash flooding around Zimbabwe's cities and towns. Urban and rural areas are fighting the continuous battle against a scourge of plastic litter. On June 5, 2018 the United Nations mark the World Environment Day which plastic pollution is the main theme this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AFP/Getty&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;18/50&lt;/span&gt; 2 June 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Palestinian mourners carry the body of 21-year-old medical volunteer Razan al-Najjar during her funeral after she was shot dead by Israeli soldiers near the Gaza border fence on June 1, in another day of protests and violence. She was shot near Khan Yunis in the south of the territory, health ministry spokesman Ashraf al-Qudra said, bringing the toll of Gazans killed by Israeli fire since the end of March to 123.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AFP/Getty&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;19/50&lt;/span&gt; 1 June 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spain's new Prime Minister Pedro Sanchez poses after a vote on a no-confidence motion at the Spanish Parliament in Madrid. Spain's parliament ousted Prime Minister Mariano Rajoy in a no-confidence vote sparked by fury over his party's corruption woes, with his Socialist arch-rival Pedro Sanchez automatically taking over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AFP/Getty&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;20/50&lt;/span&gt; 31 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zinedine Zidane looks on after a press conference to announce his resignation as manager from Real Madrid. He confirmed he was leaving the Spanish giants, just days after winning the Champions League for the third year in a row.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AFP/Getty&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;21/50&lt;/span&gt; 30 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A worker cleans up the Millenaire migrants makeshift camp along the Canal de Saint-Denis near Porte de la Villette, northern Paris, following its evacuation on May 30. More than a thousand migrants and refugees were evacuated early in the morning from the camp that had been set up for several weeks along the Canal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AFP/Getty&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;22/50&lt;/span&gt; 29 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Police and ambulances are seen at the site where a gunman shot dead three people, two of them policemen, before being killed by elite officers, in the eastern Belgian city of Liege.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AFP/Getty&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;23/50&lt;/span&gt; 28 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;French President Emmanuel Macron meets with Mamoudou Gassama, 22, from Mali, at the presidential Elysee Palace in Paris. Gassama living illegally in France is being honored by Macron for scaling an apartment building over the weekend to save a 4-year-old child dangling from a fifth-floor balcony.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AP&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;24/50&lt;/span&gt; 27 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Migrants wait to disembark from the ship Aquarius in the Sicilian harbour of Catania, Italy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reuters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;25/50&lt;/span&gt; 26 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ireland awaits the official result of a referendum that could end the country’s ban on abortion. Co-Director of Together For Yes Ailbhe Smyth speaks to the media after exit polls suggested victory for the Yes campaign.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PA Wire/PA Images&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;26/50&lt;/span&gt; 25 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Film producer Harvey Weinstein arrives at the 1st Precinct in Manhattan where he turned himself in to New York police for sexual misconduct charges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reuters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;27/50&lt;/span&gt; 24 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Russian President Vladimir Putin (R) meets with his French counterpart Emmanuel Macron at the Konstantin Palace in Strelna, outside Saint Petersburg, on May 24, 2018&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getty Images&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;28/50&lt;/span&gt; 23 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People protest outisde the Tamil Nadu House after at least 10 people were killed when police fired on protesters seeking closure of plant on environmental grounds in town of Thoothukudi in southern state of Tamil Nadu, in New Delhi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ANI via Reuters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;29/50&lt;/span&gt; 22 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People demonstrate in Paris during a nationwide day protest by French public sector employees and public servants against the overhauls proposed by French President Emmanuel Macron, calling them an &quot;attack&quot; by the centrist leader against civil services as well as their economic security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AFP/Getty&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;30/50&lt;/span&gt; 21 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Newly appointed Catalan president Quim Torra arrives to visit jailed Catalan separatist politicians at the Estremera jail near Madrid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AFP/Getty&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;31/50&lt;/span&gt; 20 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Venezuelan President Nicolas Maduro casts his vote during the presidential elections in Caracas. Maduro was seeking a second term in power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AFP/Getty&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;32/50&lt;/span&gt; 19 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Channelized lava emerges on Kilauea Volcano's lower East Rift Zone on Hawaii. The USGS said on its website that &quot;a fast-moving pahoehoe lava flow that emerged from fissure 20... continues to flow southeast,&quot; with the quickest of three &quot;lobes&quot; progressing at 230 yards (210 meters) per hour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AFP/US Geological Survey&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;33/50&lt;/span&gt; 18 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Santa Fe High School student Dakota Shrader is comforted by her mother Susan Davidson following a shooting at the school in Texas. Shrader said her friend was shot in the incident. Multiple people have been killed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stuart Villanueva/The Galveston County Daily News via AP&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;34/50&lt;/span&gt; 17 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;French President Emmanuel Macron, British Prime Minister Theresa May and German Chancellor Angela Merkel meeting during the EU-Western Balkans Summit in Sofia, Bulgaria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reuters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;35/50&lt;/span&gt; 16 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People hold flags with the state coat of arms of Russia as they drive along a bridge, which was constructed to connect the Russian mainland with the Crimean Peninsula across the Kerch Strait.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reuters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;36/50&lt;/span&gt; 15 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Palestinians run away from tear gas shot at them by Israeli forces during a protest in Ramallah, in the occupied West Bank&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AFP/Getty&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;37/50&lt;/span&gt; 14 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Palestinian demonstrator runs during a protest against the US embassy move to Jerusalem and ahead of the 70th anniversary of the Nakba at the Israel-Gaza border.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;REUTERS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;38/50&lt;/span&gt; 13 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A bullet hole on the window of a cafe in Paris, the day after a knifeman killed one man and wounded four other people before being shot dead by police&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AFP/Getty&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;39/50&lt;/span&gt; 12 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Germany's Chancellor Angela Merkel looks on after receiving the 'Lamp of Peace, the &quot;Nobel&quot; Catholic award for &quot;her work of conciliation for the peaceful cohabitation of peoples&quot; at The Basilica Superiore of St Francis of Assisi in Italy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AFP/Getty&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;40/50&lt;/span&gt; 11 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Police forensics investigate the death of seven people in a suspected murder-suicide in Australia. Four children are among seven people that were found dead at a rural property in Osmington, near Margaret River. Detectives are investigating the incident, which was said to be treated as a murder-suicide, media reported. Two firearms were found at the scene, Western Australia Police said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EPA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;41/50&lt;/span&gt; 10 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Missiles rise into the sky as Israeli missiles hit air defense position and other military bases, in Damascus, Syria. The Israeli military on Thursday said it attacked &quot;dozens&quot; of Iranian targets in neighboring Syria in response to an Iranian rocket barrage on Israeli positions in the Golan Heights, in the most serious military confrontation between the two bitter enemies to date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reuters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;42/50&lt;/span&gt; 9 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iranian MPs burning a US flag in the parliament in Tehran. Iran said it will hold talks with signatories to a nuclear deal after US President Donald Trump's decision to withdraw from the accord, which it branded &quot;psychological warfare&quot;. President Hassan Rouhani also said Iran could resume uranium enrichment &quot;without limit&quot; in response to Trump's announcement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AFP/Islamic Consultative Assembly News Agency&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;43/50&lt;/span&gt; 8 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Newly elected Prime Minister of Armenia Nikol Pashinian addresses the crowd in Republic Square in Yerevan. The leader of protests that gripped Armenia for weeks was named the country's new prime minister on Tuesday, overcoming the immediate political turmoil but raising uncertainty about the longer term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AP&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;44/50&lt;/span&gt; 7 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Russian President Vladimir Putin walks before his President inauguration ceremony at the Kremlin in Moscow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reuters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;45/50&lt;/span&gt; 6 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lava from a robust fissure eruption on Kilauea's east rift zone consumes a home, then threatens another, near Pahoa, Hawaii. The total number of homes lost within the Leilani Estates subdivision thus far is 21, and geologists from the Hawaii Volcanoes Observatory do not expect the eruption to cease any time soon. A local state of emergency has been declared after Mount Kilauea erupted near residential areas, forcing mandatory evacuation of about 1,700 citizens from their nearby homes. The crater's floor collapsed on 01 May and is since then continuing to erode its walls and generating huge explosions of ashes. Several earthquakes have been recorded in the area where the volcanic eruptions continue, including a 6.9 magnitue earthquake which struck the area on 4 May.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EPA/PARADISE HELICOPTERS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;46/50&lt;/span&gt; 5 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Russian police carrying struggling opposition leader Alexei Navalny at a demonstration against President Vladimir Putin in Moscow. Thousands of demonstrators denouncing Putin's upcoming inauguration into a fourth term gathered in the capital's Pushkin Square.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AP&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;47/50&lt;/span&gt; 4 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chinese President Xi Jinping speaks at an event to mark Karl Marx’s 200th birthday at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AP&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;48/50&lt;/span&gt; 3 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;President Vladimir Putin meets with FIFA president Gianni Infantino in Sochi, ahead of the 2018 World Cup in Russia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AFP/Getty&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;49/50&lt;/span&gt; 2 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supporters of opposition lawmaker Nikol Pashinyan protest in Republic Square in Yerevan, Armenia. Pashinyan has urged his supporters to block roads, railway stations and airports after the governing Republican Party voted against his election as prime minister.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AP&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;50/50&lt;/span&gt; 1 May 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cubans march during the May Day rally at Revolution Square in Havana.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AFP/Getty&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Experience has shown repressive governments tend toward incarceration and torture of identified people who are opposing repressive practices, and the surveillance technologies will tend to harden this circle of repression”, the document said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A representative of Amazon declined to comment on the record.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shareholders of major technology companies have increasingly been broadcasting their concerns about the financial and reputational damage of privacy violations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a tense Facebook shareholder meeting last month, one investor accused the company of a “human rights violation” for failing to steward a reservoir of consumer data that was revealed to have ended up in the hands of consulting firm Cambridge Analytica.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 21:13:23 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pmoriarty</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.independent.co.uk/news/business/amazon-recognition-shareholders-jeff-bezos-letter-privacy-surveillance-facial-recognition-a8405221.html</og:url>
<og:title>Amazon shareholders want Jeff Bezos to stop selling a controversial facial recognition tool</og:title>
<og:description>Concerns that surveillance technology could be used to target activists, immigrants and people of colour</og:description>
<og:image>https://static.independent.co.uk/s3fs-public/thumbnails/image/2018/06/18/19/jeff-bezos.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.independent.co.uk/news/business/amazon-recognition-shareholders-jeff-bezos-letter-privacy-surveillance-facial-recognition-a8405221.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Machine Learning: The High Interest Credit Card of Technical Debt (2014)</title>
<link>https://ai.google/research/pubs/pub43146</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://ai.google/research/pubs/pub43146</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Machine learning offers a fantastically powerful toolkit for building complex systems quickly. This paper argues that it is dangerous to think of these quick wins as coming for free. Using the framework of technical debt, we note that it is remarkably easy to incur massive ongoing maintenance costs at the system level when applying machine learning. The goal of this paper is highlight several machine learning specific risk factors and design patterns to be avoided or refactored where possible. These include boundary erosion, entanglement, hidden feedback loops, undeclared consumers, data dependencies, changes in the external world, and a variety of system-level anti-patterns.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 19:48:26 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>amzans</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://ai.google/static/images/share.png</og:image>
<og:title>Machine Learning: The High Interest Credit Card of Technical Debt – Google AI</og:title>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://ai.google/research/pubs/pub43146</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://ai.google/research/pubs/pub43146</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How modern Linux systems boot</title>
<link>https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/linux/LinuxBootOverview?</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/linux/LinuxBootOverview?</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;For &lt;a href=&quot;https://old.reddit.com/r/programming/comments/8rhvfv/how_does_linux_start_up/e0rm0bu/&quot;&gt;reasons beyond the scope of this entry&lt;/a&gt;, today I feel like writing down a broad and simplified overview of how modern Linux systems boot. Due to being a sysadmin who has stubbed his toe here repeatedly, I'm going to especially focus on points of failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol readability=&quot;33.835144409494&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;2.6102719033233&quot;&gt;The system loads and starts the basic bootloader somehow, through either BIOS MBR booting or UEFI. This can involve many steps on its own and any number of things can go wrong, such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/linux/Fedora27SecureBootMistake&quot;&gt;unsigned UEFI bootloaders on a Secure Boot system&lt;/a&gt;. Generally these failures are the most total; the system reports there's nothing to boot, or it repeatedly reboots, or the bootloader aborts with what is generally a cryptic error message.
&lt;p&gt;On a UEFI system, the bootloader needs to live in the EFI system partition, which is always a FAT32 filesystem. Some people have had luck making this a software RAID mirror with &lt;a href=&quot;https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/linux/SoftwareRaidSuperblockFormats&quot;&gt;the right superblock format&lt;/a&gt;; see the comments on &lt;a href=&quot;https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/linux/Grub2UEFIBigMistake&quot;&gt;this entry&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;9.6296296296296&quot;&gt;The bootloader loads its configuration file and perhaps additional modules from somewhere, usually your &lt;code&gt;/boot&lt;/code&gt; but also perhaps your UEFI system partition. Failures here can result in &lt;a href=&quot;https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/linux/GrubDiskMismatchError&quot;&gt;extremely cryptic errors&lt;/a&gt;, dropping you into a GRUB shell, or ideally a message saying 'can't find your menu file'. The configuration file location is usually hardcoded, which is sometimes unfortunate if your distribution has picked &lt;a href=&quot;https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/linux/Grub2UEFIBigMistake&quot;&gt;a bad spot&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;For GRUB, this spot has to be on a filesystem and storage stack that GRUB understands, which is not necessarily the same as what your Linux kernel understands. Fortunately GRUB understands a lot these days, so under normal circumstances you're unlikely to run into this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Some GRUB setups have a two stage configuration file, where the first stage just finds and loads the second one. This allows you more flexibility in where the second stage lives, which can be important on UEFI systems.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;4.3294117647059&quot;&gt;Using your configuration file, the bootloader loads your chosen Linux kernel and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Initial_ramdisk&quot;&gt;an initial ramdisk&lt;/a&gt; into memory and transfers control to the kernel. The kernel and initramfs image also need to come from a filesystem that your bootloader understands, but with GRUB the configuration file allows you to be very flexible about &lt;a href=&quot;https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/linux/MigratingBootFSIntoRootFS&quot;&gt;how they're found and where they come from&lt;/a&gt; (and it doesn't have to be the same place as &lt;code&gt;grub.cfg&lt;/code&gt; is, although on a non-UEFI system both are usually in &lt;code&gt;/boot&lt;/code&gt;).
&lt;p&gt;There are two things that can go wrong here; your &lt;code&gt;grub.cfg&lt;/code&gt; can have entries for kernels that don't exist any more, or GRUB can fail to locate and bring up the filesystem where the kernel(s) are stored. The latter can happen if, for example, &lt;a href=&quot;https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/linux/Grub2MoveBootDisk&quot;&gt;your &lt;code&gt;grub.cfg&lt;/code&gt; has the wrong UUIDs for your filesystems&lt;/a&gt;. It's possible to patch this up on the fly so you can boot your system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;23.929384965831&quot;&gt;The kernel starts up, creates PID 1, and runs &lt;code&gt;/init&lt;/code&gt; from the initramfs as PID 1. This process and things that it run then flail around doing various things, with the fundamental goal of finding and mounting your real root filesystem and transferring control to it. In the process of doing this it will try to &lt;a href=&quot;https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/linux/ModernSoftwareRaidAssembly&quot;&gt;assemble software RAID devices and other storage stuff like LVM&lt;/a&gt;, perhaps &lt;a href=&quot;https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/linux/FedoraInitramfsSysctl&quot;&gt;set sysctls&lt;/a&gt;, and so on. The obvious and traditional failure mode here is that the initramfs can't find or mount your root filesystem for some reason; this usually winds up dropping you into some sort of very minimal rescue shell. If this happens to you, you may want to boot from a USB live image instead; they tend to have more tools and a better environment.
&lt;p&gt;(Sometimes the reasons for failure are &lt;a href=&quot;https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/linux/RaidGrowthGotcha&quot;&gt;obscure and annoying&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On many traditional systems, the initramfs &lt;code&gt;/init&lt;/code&gt; was its own separate thing, often a shell script, and was thus independent from and different from your system's real init. On systemd based systems, the initramfs &lt;code&gt;/init&lt;/code&gt; is actually systemd itself and so even very early initramfs boot is under systemd's control. In general, a modern initramfs is a real (root) filesystem that processes in the initramfs will see as &lt;code&gt;/&lt;/code&gt;, and its contents (both configuration files and programs) are usually copied from the versions in your root filesystem. You can inspect the whole thing with &lt;code&gt;lsinitrd&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;lsinitramfs&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: It turns out that the initramfs init is still a shell script in some Linux distributions, prominently Debian and Ubuntu. The initramfs init being systemd may be a Red Hat-ism (Fedora and RHEL). Thanks to Ben Hutchings in the comments for the correction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How the initramfs &lt;code&gt;/init&lt;/code&gt; pivots into running your real system's init daemon on your real system's root filesystem is beyond the scope of this entry. The commands may be simple (systemd just runs '&lt;code&gt;systemctl switch-root&lt;/code&gt;'), but how they work is complicated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(That systemd is the initramfs &lt;code&gt;/init&lt;/code&gt; is convenient in a way, because it means that you don't need to learn an additional system to inspect how your initramfs works; instead you can just look at the systemd units included in the initramfs and follow along in the systemd log.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;Your real init system starts up to perform basic system setup to bring the system to a state that we think of as the normal basic way it is; basically, this is everything you usually get if you boot into a modern single user mode. This does things like set the hostname, mount the root filesystem so it can be written to, apply your sysctl settings (from the real root filesystem this time), configure enough networking so that you have a loopback device and the IPv4 and IPv6 localhost addresses, have udev fiddle around with hardware, and especially mount all of your local filesystems (which includes activating underlying storage systems like software RAID and LVM, if they haven't been activated already in the initramfs).
&lt;p&gt;The traditional thing that fails here is that one or more of your local filesystems can't be mounted. This often causes this process to abort and drop you into a single user rescue shell environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(On a systemd system the hostname is actually set twice, once in the initramfs and then again in this stage.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;With your local filesystems mounted and other core configuration in place, your init system continues on to boot your system the rest of the way. This does things like configure your network (well, perhaps; these days some systems may defer it until you log in), start all of the system's daemons, and eventually enable logins on text consoles and perhaps start a graphical login environment like GDM or LightDM. At the end of this process, your system is fully booted.
&lt;p&gt;Things that fail here are problems like a daemon not starting or, more seriously, the system not finding the network devices it expects and so not getting itself on the network at all. Usually the end result is that you still wind up with a login prompt (either a text console or graphics), it's just that there were error messages (which you may not have seen) or some things aren't working. Very few modern systems abort the boot and drop into a rescue environment for failures during this stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a systemd system, this transfers control from the initramfs systemd to the systemd binary on your root filesystem (which takes over as PID 1), but systemd maintains continuity of its state and boot process and you can see the whole thing in &lt;code&gt;journalctl&lt;/code&gt;. The point where the switch happens is reported as 'Starting Switch Root...' and then 'Switching root.'&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;All of System V init, Upstart, and systemd have this distinction between the basic system setup steps and the later 'full booting' steps, but they implement it in different ways. Systemd doesn't draw a hard distinction between the two phases and you can shim your own steps into either portion in basically the same way. System V init tended to implement the early 'single user' stage as a separate nominal runlevel, runlevel 'S', that the system transitioned through on the way to its real target runlevel. Upstart is sort of a hybrid; it has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.systutorials.com/docs/linux/man/7-startup/&quot;&gt;a &lt;code&gt;startup&lt;/code&gt; event&lt;/a&gt; that's emitted to trigger a number of things before things start fully booting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(This really is an overview. Booting Linux on PC hardware has become a complicated process at the best of times, with a lot of things to set up and fiddle around with.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 17:31:31 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>adamnemecek</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/linux/LinuxBootOverview?</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>X86 assembly doesn’t have to be scary</title>
<link>https://blog.benjojo.co.uk/post/interactive-x86-bootloader-tutorial</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.benjojo.co.uk/post/interactive-x86-bootloader-tutorial</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Assembly programming can be intimidating for people who have never looked into it any deeper than a glance, but giving that it underpins how the computers we use work it can be helpful having context in regards to what is actually being run by the CPU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.benjojo.co.uk/asset/EZp0wqx9xN&quot; alt=&quot;IBM PC&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Photo by: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/136804333@N03/22561463609/&quot;&gt;Drew Sadik&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;x86 PCs are impressive in that they are fully backwards compatible with the original IBM PC. All the way down to timing circuits and boot process. This is both great in that almost all PCs should be able to run software from 1983, but this backwards compatibility also has a very high cost. The x86 ISA is inframous in it’s edge cases and complexity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To boot a modern x86 PC, you need to step through the history of x86, this is handled by the bootloader in 99% of cases:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.benjojo.co.uk/asset/m9a5CyE1Ef&quot; alt=&quot;flow of a modern system booting&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the case of our demo’s we are going to focus on the first mode. 16 bit “real mode” is the mode that DOS and other vintage operating systems run on. This mode offers no system security that we are used to on our modern systems. When a program is run it has full access to the system and can alter the operating system if it wants to. This allowed a creative virus scene to spring up for DOS (though these viruses were more annoying than actually malicious)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This mode also has a very simple model for interacting with hardware. Because PCs had a wide range of hardware they outsourced a lot of the code to interact with hardware with software interrupts (often handled by the BIOS)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This makes the initial stages of OS development easy, since you only need to know a handful of software interrupts to get most of of the I/O work done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that, we can start on our first demo:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;textarea id=&quot;nasm_1&quot;&gt;&lt;/textarea&gt;&lt;textarea id=&quot;output_1&quot; disabled=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/textarea&gt;&lt;button id=&quot;compile_1&quot;&gt;Run&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can play around with the demo above. The assembler (NASM) and VM is being run in your browser thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kripken/emscripten&quot;&gt;emscripten&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/copy/v86&quot;&gt;V86&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what is happening here? The &lt;code&gt;mov&lt;/code&gt; instruction moves data from one place to another. In this case we are purely setting registers in the CPU and not touching RAM in the code. The &lt;code&gt;int&lt;/code&gt; instruction fires off a software interrupt, in our case the 16th one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that, we invoke &lt;code&gt;hlt&lt;/code&gt; to stop the CPU from doing anything else. Since we are done with what we wanted to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But hang on, how did we even get to this stage? What did the computer do to get our code running just then?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The BIOS is generally the first thing that gets run on the system, its job is to setup and test that the computer is working correctly, It also writes out information about the system so that operating systems later on can easily detect hardware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assuming the BIOS knows what device it wants to boot off, it will load the first sector (512 bytes) from that, into a standardised position of memory, and then hand over control by jumping to that part of memory&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.benjojo.co.uk/asset/bvv1rGqfV4&quot; alt=&quot;memory loading&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the demo above, the browser made the 512 byte payload, padded it into a 1.4MB floppy disk image, and gave it into a emulator to run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what happens when the program you need to run is more than 512 bytes?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily for us the BIOS has us covered with disk I/O as well with int 13h calls that allow easy access to the drives in the system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;textarea id=&quot;nasm_2&quot;&gt;&lt;/textarea&gt;&lt;textarea id=&quot;output_2&quot; disabled=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/textarea&gt;&lt;button id=&quot;compile_2&quot;&gt;Run&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This code loads a segment from the next sector of the virtual floppy disk, and then jumps to it! The int 13h API is pretty simple, and gives away some of the low level details of how storage works (though with the invention of flash memory, a lot of these values are emulated to retain compatibility)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.benjojo.co.uk/asset/c7iWI5c9mK&quot; alt=&quot;int13 breakdown&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of BIOS provided services out there, some are more official than others, there is a great reference guide at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ctyme.com/intr/rb-0608.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.ctyme.com/intr/rb-0608.htm&lt;/a&gt; (Though I do warn you about the 90’s style porn banner ads at the bottom of these pages)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully this was a fun intro, You can move onwards and &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.osdev.org/GCC_Cross-Compiler&quot;&gt;even switch to C&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/charliesome/rustboot&quot;&gt;or Rust!&lt;/a&gt;) and find more information about the underlying hardware of most of the computers you sit down and use daily on &lt;a href=&quot;http://wiki.osdev.org/&quot;&gt;http://wiki.osdev.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you found this post interesting, you might like the other things I’ve done! If not you can always stay up to date with when I push out a new post by following me on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/benjojo12&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, or using my blog’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.benjojo.co.uk/rss.xml&quot;&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt; if that is more of your thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until next time!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 17:11:14 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>signa11</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.benjojo.co.uk/post/interactive-x86-bootloader-tutorial</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Diablo devolved – magic behind the 1996 computer game</title>
<link>https://github.com/galaxyhaxz/devilution</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/galaxyhaxz/devilution</guid>
<description>&lt;h3&gt;README.md&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diablo devolved - magic behind the 1996 computer game&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reverse engineered by GalaXyHaXz in 2018&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Diablo was everything but loved by Blizzard. The last update to the game was in 2001, and Blizzard stopped supporting/selling it altogether a few years ago. I took up a mission to fix this problem. Diablo was a game I played extensively as a teenager; but as time passed, it became difficult to run the game on newer hardware. The lack of new content also took away from the re-playability. The ideal solution would be to modernize the source, but reversing the whole game initially sounded impossible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, there was a little oversight in 1998. Blizzard gave Diablo's source code to two developers: Synergestic Software (to create an expansion), and Climax Studios (to create a Playstation port). Now Sony of Japan has long been known for letting things slide in their QA department. Anything from prototypes to full source code leaks (Beatmania), and Diablo was no exception. A symbolic file was accidentally left on the Japanese port, which contained a layout of everything in the game. This includes functions, data, types, and more! A beta version of the port also leaked, which contained yet another one of these files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To top it all off, a debug build of the PC version is contained right there on your Diablo disc! Hidden in &lt;code&gt;DIABDAT.MPQ -&amp;gt; D1221A.MPQ -&amp;gt; DIABLO.EXE&lt;/code&gt;. This build contains debug tools not found in the retail game, and many assert strings giving away code information. Combining these aspects not only makes reversing the game much easier, but it makes it far more accurate. File names, function names, and even line numbers will be fairly close to the real deal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After four months of hard work, I present to you Devilution! Instead of seeing how Diablo evolved, we'll see it devolved!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having the source code makes things much easier to maintain. For years mod-makers had to rely on tedious code editing and memory injection. A few even went even further and reversed a good chunk of the game (such as Belzebub/The Hell). The problem is that they never released their sources. Usually being a one-man job, they move on with their lives inevitably due to the amount of time/work required or lack of interest. This leaves people with a half-finished mod; one which had countless hours put into it, but left full of bugs and unfinished potential. So we're back to square one. Devilution aims to fix this, by making the source code of Diablo freely available to all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of Devilution itself is to recreate the original source code as accurately as possible, in order to ensure that everything is preserved. This goes as far as bugs and badly written code in the original game. However, it becomes a solid base for developers to work with; making it much easier than before to update, fix, and port the game to other platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a side goal, Devilution helps document the unused and cut content from the final game. Development of Diablo was rushed near the end--many ideas were scrapped and Multiplayer was quickly hacked in. By examining the source, we can see various quirks of planned development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Development of Diablo began around the time Windows 95 released, for which it was optimized. The compiler used was Microsoft Visual C++ 4.20, which was upgraded to 5.10 in later patches (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/galaxyhaxz/devilution/blob/master/Support/linker.xls&quot;&gt;ref: spreadsheet&lt;/a&gt;). Compatibility with these tools is retained to help ensure the reversal is as accurate as possible. There are also Makefiles provided to compile with modern tools as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building with Visual C++ 5.10&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Make sure Service Pack 3 is installed in order to update the linker from 5.00 -&amp;gt; 5.10! Newer versions of Visual Studio work as well, but will upgrade the project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the project workspace &lt;code&gt;Diablo.dsw&lt;/code&gt; and select &lt;code&gt;Build Diablo.exe&lt;/code&gt;. This will build all dependencies and only takes a few seconds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Building with MinGW(32/64)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Ensure that the MinGW binary paths have been added to the command line.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For MinGW32, navigate to the project root and execute &lt;code&gt;mingw32-make -f Makefile32&lt;/code&gt;. The process will take longer than Visual Studio.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For MinGW64, refer to the respective documentation: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/galaxyhaxz/devilution/blob/master/Support/INSTALL_linux.md&quot;&gt;Linux&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/galaxyhaxz/devilution/blob/master/Support/INSTALL_windows.md&quot;&gt;Windows&lt;/a&gt;. Note that only x86 systems may be targeted for the time being.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Compiling Definitions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;COPYPROT&lt;/code&gt; (default: on) will define whether or not to use the CD drive for DIABDAT.MPQ&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;DEBUGGER&lt;/code&gt; (default: off) will define whether to skip reloading for direct execution through debuggers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;SLEEP&lt;/code&gt; (default: off) will define whether to sleep the program to prevent 100% CPU usage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;_DEBUG&lt;/code&gt; (default: off) will define whether to include debug features (refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/galaxyhaxz/devilution/blob/master/Support/debug.md&quot;&gt;Debugging Document&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once compiled, the Devilution binary will serve as a replacement for &lt;code&gt;Diablo.exe&lt;/code&gt;. A clean installation of Diablo patched to 1.09(b) is needed to run the game. Either copy Devilution into Diablo's installation folder, or make sure the following files are present:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;DIABDAT.MPQ&lt;/code&gt; : if &lt;code&gt;COPYPROT&lt;/code&gt; was defined, then the Diablo CD will be required&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;DiabloUI.dll&lt;/code&gt; : provides module for the title screen interface&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;SmackW32.dll&lt;/code&gt; : provides library for playing Smacker video files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Storm.dll&lt;/code&gt; : provides various &quot;standard&quot; functions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;To run the game in windowed mode, a DirectDraw wrapper will be needed. Strange Bytes' &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.strangebytes.com/index.php/projects/1-diablo-1-windows-7-vista-patch&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;DirectDraw patch&lt;/a&gt; is recommended. To install, place the &lt;code&gt;ddraw.dll&lt;/code&gt; into the same location as the Devilution binary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Devilution should produce a binary close to the original (compatible with Windows 95/NT), it may cause issues on newer systems. It has been reported to frequently crash on some setups, although for many it appears to be running flawless otherwise. Windows 7, Linux-WINE, and Windows 10 have all reported success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that newer compilers may need to be tweaked to properly produce an executable. Currently this is being worked on to provide multiple Makefiles for a variety of systems. To ensure the best results, either MinGW or Visual Studio 2003/older should be used for the time being.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wow, does this mean I can download and play Diablo for free now?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, you'll need access to the data from the original game. Blizzard has discontinued Diablo, but there's plenty of used copies floating around. (I'm still using an original 1996-disc in 2018 without problems)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cool, so I fired your mod up, but there's no 1080p or new features?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Devilution aims to keep the original code unaltered, for documentation purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So will you ever add cross-platform support or new features in the future?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes! However, this will be a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;side project&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; based on Devilution. I have yet to announce the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When and what can I expect from the upcoming project?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly I have no idea. More than 1,200 hours went into creating Devilution, and I have other things going on right now. Maybe in 6-12 months? The goal is to create a native Linux port, convert to OpenGL, modernize the UI, etc. you get the drill. There has to be some surprises. ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, so I'm playing Devilution now and all the sudden it crashed. NOW WHAT??&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try to remember as many details about the crash as possible. Inside the Diablo folder should be a log file containing crash information. Open an issue, upload the log, and provide as much information as possible (OS version, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought I'd fix the crash myself, but after looking at the code its a disaster. Do you speak v2-34-v8?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is the result of decompiled code. Whenever a program is compiled, much of the source is optimized and stripped away, so it's nearly impossible to decompile it back. Have patience. Everything will be cleaned up eventually. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will you be reverse engineering Diablo II next? Ooooh please!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Absolutely not. Diablo II is still supported, sold, and maintained by Blizzard. Setting the legal implications aside, there's about 8x as much code, and a chance Blizzard will remaster the game soon anyway. (as of 2018)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you interested in working for me? I have this game I want you to reverse...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sorry, but no. Money takes the passion out of it. Forgoing that, Diablo was an exception given that symbolic information was readily available. Even then it took countless hours to pick apart such a tiny game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that's about all, but is Devilution even legal?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's a tricky question. Under the DMCA, reverse-engineering has exceptions for the purpose of documentation and interoperability. Devilution provides the necessary documentation needed to achieve the latter. However, it falls into an entirely grey area. The real question is whether or not Blizzard deems it necessary to take action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently there are a few issues with the decompiled code. The focus should be on fixing these issues for now instead of cleaning up the code. Currently only Diablo.exe has been reversed, the other files are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Battle.snp&lt;/code&gt;: code for battle.net, outdated protocol and not worth the time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;DiabloUI.dll&lt;/code&gt;: code for the main menu, this is entirely Windows specific and poorly written. However, it needs to be reversed to complete the source code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;SmackW32.dll&lt;/code&gt;: code for the Smacker video library, not worth the time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Standard.snp&lt;/code&gt;: code for local multiplayer, again outdated. Starcraft uses the same format and TCP/IP was added in a later patch. Reversing the UDP portion is desired.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Storm.dll&lt;/code&gt;: we want Diablo to be independent of this library, the main file functions have been reversed as part of StormLib.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;VidSize.exe&lt;/code&gt;: changes one byte in registry, ignore.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you are experienced with reversing, help is needed to reverse the user interface (DiabloUI) to help make Diablo cross-platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some screenshots of a few things I tinkered around with, to demonstrate the relative ease of improving the game:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/9426dfe5fc03654a8f1d3c024019cd7c5fb468b6/68747470733a2f2f7333332e706f7374696d672e63632f36786e6e68686c6d6e2f6469616275696d6f6e2e706e67&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/9426dfe5fc03654a8f1d3c024019cd7c5fb468b6/68747470733a2f2f7333332e706f7374696d672e63632f36786e6e68686c6d6e2f6469616275696d6f6e2e706e67&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot 1: Monster lifebar+items&quot; title=&quot;Monster lifebar+items&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://s33.postimg.cc/6xnnhhlmn/diabuimon.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/c1b4f8890a676b46fe2b5cae7764c9fae252c7b2/68747470733a2f2f7332322e706f7374696d672e63632f7a3866687575746b312f6469616273746f72652e706e67&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/c1b4f8890a676b46fe2b5cae7764c9fae252c7b2/68747470733a2f2f7332322e706f7374696d672e63632f7a3866687575746b312f6469616273746f72652e706e67&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot 2: New trade screen&quot; title=&quot;New trade screen&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://s22.postimg.cc/z8fhuutk1/diabstore.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sanctuary&quot;&gt;sanctuary&lt;/a&gt; - documenting the Windows-specific Diablo code (engine, mpq, directx)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bwapi&quot;&gt;BWAPI Team&lt;/a&gt; - providing library API to work with Storm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ladislav-zezula&quot;&gt;Ladislav Zezula&lt;/a&gt; - decompiling PKWARE library, decompiling Storm (StormLib)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/fearedbliss&quot;&gt;fearedbliss&lt;/a&gt; - being awe-inspiring&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Climax Studios &amp;amp; Sony - secretly helping with their undercover QA :P&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blizzard North - wait, this was a typo!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Depression - reason to waste four months of my life doing this ;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is being released to the Public Domain. No assets of Diablo are being provided. You must own a copy of Diablo and have access to the assets beforehand in order to use this software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Battle.net(R) - Copyright (C) 1996 Blizzard Entertainment, Inc. All rights reserved. Battle.net and Blizzard Entertainment are trademarks or registered trademarks of Blizzard Entertainment, Inc. in the U.S. and/or other countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diablo(R) - Copyright (C) 1996 Blizzard Entertainment, Inc. All rights reserved. Diablo and Blizzard Entertainment are trademarks or registered trademarks of Blizzard Entertainment, Inc. in the U.S. and/or other countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This software is in no way associated with or endorsed by Blizzard Entertainment(R).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 15:23:16 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>cyberfart</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars3.githubusercontent.com/u/15209402?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>galaxyhaxz/devilution</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/galaxyhaxz/devilution</og:url>
<og:description>devilution - Diablo devolved - magic behind the 1996 computer game</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/galaxyhaxz/devilution</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Apple sets up iPhones to relay location for 911 calls</title>
<link>http://www.wpri.com/news/us-and-world/apple-sets-up-iphones-to-relay-location-for-911-calls-1/1246399748</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.wpri.com/news/us-and-world/apple-sets-up-iphones-to-relay-location-for-911-calls-1/1246399748</guid>
<description>&lt;aside class=&quot;mod-inline media&quot;&gt;
Credit: Apple&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;modal-magnify-photo-&quot; class=&quot;reveal-modal&quot; data-reveal=&quot;&quot; aria-labelledby=&quot;modalTitle&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; role=&quot;dialog&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.wpri.com/nxs-wpritv-media-us-east-1/photo/2017/11/06/apple-products-iphone_38459369_ver1.0_640_360.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Apple sets up iPhones to relay location for 911 calls&quot;/&gt;&lt;small class=&quot;copyright&quot;&gt;Copyright by WPRI - All rights reserved&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Credit: Apple &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SAN FRANCISCO (AP) — Apple is trying to drag the U.S.'s antiquated system for handling 911 calls into the 21st century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it lives up to Apple's promise, the iPhone's next operating system will automatically deliver quicker and more reliable information pinpointing the location of 911 calls to about 6,300 emergency response centers in the U.S.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple is trying to solve a problem caused by the technological mismatch between a 50-year-old system built for landlines and today's increasingly sophisticated smartphones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An estimated 80 percent of roughly 240 million emergency calls in the U.S. this year will come from mobile phones, most of which are capable of precisely tracking where their users are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emergency calling centers, however, don't get that detailed location information from mobile 911 calls. Instead, they get the location of the cellular tower transmitting the call, and must rely on other methods to figure out where the caller is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That can take up precious time and often isn't very accurate, especially when calls come from inside a building. Emergency responders are sometimes dispatched a mile or more away from a caller's location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple's upcoming 911 feature relies on technology from RapidSOS, a New York startup. The approach developed by Apple and RapidSOS sends location data from an iPhone to a &quot;clearinghouse&quot; accessible to emergency calling centers. Only the 911 calling centers will be able to see the data during the call, and none of it can be used for non-emergency purposes, according to Apple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Individual call centers will each have to embrace the technology required to communicate with the RapidSOS clearinghouse. Some centers already have the compatible software, according to Apple, but others will have to install upgrades to their existing software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple expects calling centers for large metropolitan areas to upgrade more quickly than those in rural areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tom Wheeler, a former chairman for the Federal Communications Commission, believes Apple's new approach for locating 911 calls will set a new industry standard. &quot;This is going to save a lot of lives,&quot; said Wheeler, now a visiting professor at Harvard University. He said he hopes other phone makers will follow Apple's lead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The planned changes were announced Monday in Nashville, Tennessee during a 911 convention. They'll be part of iOS 12, the next version of Apple's iPhone software, which the company will release in September as a free update.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 14:57:45 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>chmaynard</dc:creator>
<og:title>Apple sets up iPhones to relay location for 911 calls</og:title>
<og:description>Apple is trying to drag the U.S.'s antiquated system for handling 911 calls into the 21st century.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>http://www.wpri.com/news/us-and-world/apple-sets-up-iphones-to-relay-location-for-911-calls-1/1246399748</og:url>
<og:image>https://media.wpri.com/nxs-wpritv-media-us-east-1/photo/2017/11/06/apple-products-iphone_38459369_ver1.0_1280_720.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.wpri.com/news/us-and-world/apple-sets-up-iphones-to-relay-location-for-911-calls-1/1246399748</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>