<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Software made me loathe my car</title>
<link>https://mikkel.hoegh.org/2019/08/29/how-software-made-me-loathe-my-luxury-car</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://mikkel.hoegh.org/2019/08/29/how-software-made-me-loathe-my-luxury-car</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://mikkel.hoegh.org/2019/08/29/how-software-made-me-loathe-my-luxury-car&quot;&gt;https://mikkel.hoegh.org/2019/08/29/how-software-made-me-loathe-my-luxury-car&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20832570&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20832570&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 265&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 320&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2019 19:05:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mikl</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mikkel.hoegh.org/2019/08/29/how-software-made-me-loathe-my-luxury-car/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Uber proposes policy that would pay drivers a minimum wage of $21 per hour</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/28/uber-proposes-policy-that-would-pay-drivers-a-minimum-wage-of-21-per-hour/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/28/uber-proposes-policy-that-would-pay-drivers-a-minimum-wage-of-21-per-hour/</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot;&gt;On the heels of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/27/uber-and-lyft-drivers-are-not-letting-up-on-the-fight-for-ab-5-and-a-union/&quot;&gt;driver-led protest outside Uber’s San Francisco headquarters, where&lt;/a&gt; drivers showed their support for gig worker protections legislation (via Assembly Bill 5) and demanded a union, &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/uber&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;uber&quot;&gt;Uber&lt;/a&gt; is circulating a petition urging people to “protect ridesharing in California.” In the petition, &lt;a href=&quot;https://p2a.co/H9gttWA&quot;&gt;Uber advocates for a policy&lt;/a&gt; that would offer drivers a minimum of $21 per hour while on a trip,* paid time off, sick leave and compensation if they are injured while driving, as well as a collective voice and “the ability to influence decisions about their work.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uber has also created a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.independentdriver.org/&quot;&gt;new website called “Independent Driver&lt;/a&gt;” to showcase stories from drivers who want to remain independent contractors. Lyft, similarly, &lt;a href=&quot;https://p2a.co/UnOU7gO&quot;&gt;is circulating a petition urging people to demand legislators “fix AB 5&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We agree with the bill’s goal to protect workers, but we don’t agree that this protection should come at the cost of the flexibility our community relies on to supplement their income, support their families, and set their own schedules,” Lyft wrote in its petition. “After talking with thousands of California drivers and listening to experts in labor laws, we’re proposing a revision that protects driver earnings and the flexibility to earn when and how you want. Our proposal includes additional workplace protections for drivers and a minimum earnings floor.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;48.361823361823&quot;&gt;Gig Workers Rising, one of the organizations responsible for bringing drivers together to support AB-5 and demand the right to unionize, said it’s no coincidence that Uber and Lyft started circulating these messages on the last day of a statewide action demanding AB5 and a union that Uber and Lyft would begin circulating these messages to drivers and passengers.
&lt;p&gt;“Everything that Uber and Lyft are offering is insulting to drivers,” Lauren Casey of Gig Workers Rising told TechCrunch. “This is nothing new. All they’ve done since AB5 was introduced is spread misinformation and fear. This shows us that Uber and Lyft are worried. Drivers have been organizing and fighting hard for AB5 for months, and, it’s working.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These petitions are clearly Hail Marys by Lyft and Uber to try to prevent the passage of AB-5, which seeks to codify the ruling established in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.courts.ca.gov/opinions/archive/S222732.PDF&quot;&gt;Dynamex Operations West, Inc. v Superior Court of Los Angeles&lt;/a&gt;. In that case, the court applied the ABC test and decided Dynamex wrongfully classified its workers as independent contractors based on the presumption that “a worker who performs services for a hirer is an employee for purposes of claims for wages and benefits…”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.courts.ca.gov/opinions/archive/S222732.PDF&quot;&gt;ABC test&lt;/a&gt;, in order for a hiring entity to legally classify a worker as an independent contractor, it must prove the worker is free from the control and direction of the hiring entity, performs work outside the scope of the entity’s business and is regularly engaged in an “independently established trade, occupation, or business of the same nature as the work performed.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, AB-5, which has already passed in the California State Assembly, would ensure gig economy workers are entitled to minimum wage, workers’ compensation and other benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;*This story has been updated to clarify that Uber is proposing to pay drivers $21 per hour while on a trip. We regret the lack of clarity. We’ve also updated the post with a comment from Gig Workers Rising&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;a&lt;br/&gt;https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/27/uber-and-lyft-drivers-are-not-letting-up-on-the-fight-for-ab-5-and-a-union/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2019 16:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>docker_up</dc:creator>
<og:title>Uber proposes policy that would pay drivers a minimum wage of $21 per hour while on a trip – TechCrunch</og:title>
<og:description>On the heels of a driver-led protest outside Uber’s San Francisco headquarters, where drivers showed their support for gig worker protections legislation (via Assembly Bill 5) and demanded a union, Uber is circulating a petition urging people to “protect ridesharing in California.&amp;#8221…</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/4161F81F-7DC6-4649-AD06-367947018560.jpeg?w=533</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2019/08/28/uber-proposes-policy-that-would-pay-drivers-a-minimum-wage-of-21-per-hour/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/28/uber-proposes-policy-that-would-pay-drivers-a-minimum-wage-of-21-per-hour/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Thank you, Chris</title>
<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/blog/2019/08/29/thank-you-chris/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.mozilla.org/blog/2019/08/29/thank-you-chris/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Thank you, Chris.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris Beard has been Mozilla Corporation’s CEO for 5 and a half years. &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/blog/2019/08/29/my-next-chapter/&quot;&gt;Chris has announced&lt;/a&gt; 2019 will be his last year in this role. I want to thank Chris from the bottom of my heart for everything he has done for Mozilla. He has brought Mozilla enormous benefits — new ideas, new capabilities, new organizational approaches. As CEO Chris has put us on a new and better path. Chris’ tenure has seen the development of important organization capabilities and given us a much stronger foundation on which to build. This includes reinvigorating our flagship web browser Firefox to be once again a best-in-class product. It includes recharging our focus on meeting the online security and privacy needs facing people today. And it includes expanding our product offerings beyond the browser to include a suite of privacy and security-focused products and services from Facebook Container and Enhanced Tracking Protection to Firefox Monitor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris will remain an advisor to the board. We recognize some people may think these words are a formula and have no deep meaning. We think differently. Chris is a true “Mozillian.” He has been devoted to Mozilla for the last 15 years, and has brought this dedication to many different roles at Mozilla. When Chris left Mozilla to join Greylock as an “executive-in-residence” in 2013, he remained an advisor to Mozilla Corporation. That was an important relationship, and Chris and I were in contact when it started to become clear that Chris could be the right CEO for MoCo. So over the coming years I expect to work with Chris on mission-related topics. And I’ll consider myself lucky to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the accomplishments of Chris’ tenure is the strength and depth of Mozilla Corporation today. The team is strong. Our organization is strong, and our future full of opportunities. It is precisely the challenges of today’s world, and Mozilla’s opportunities to improve online life, that bring so many of us to Mozilla. I personally remain deeply focused on Mozilla. I’ll be here during Chris’ tenure, and I’ll be here after his tenure ends. I’m committed to Mozilla, and to making serious contributions to improving online life and developing new technical capabilities that are good for people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris will remain as CEO during the transition. We will continue to develop the work on our new engagement model, our focus on privacy and user agency. To ensure continuity, I will increase my involvement in Mozilla Corporation’s internal activities. I will be ready to step in as interim CEO should the need arise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Board has retained Tuck Rickards of the recruiting firm Russell Reynolds for this search. We are confident that Tuck and team understand that Mozilla products and technology bring our mission to life, and that we are deeply different than other technology companies. We’ll say more about the search as we progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The internet stands at an inflection point today. Mozilla has the opportunity to make significant contributions to a better internet. This is why we exist, and it’s a key time to keep doing more. We offer heartfelt thanks to Chris for leading us to this spot, and for leading the rejuvenation of Mozilla Corporation so that we are fit for this purpose, and determined to address big issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mozilla’s greatest strength is the people who respond to our mission and step forward to take on the challenge of building a better internet and online life. Chris is a shining example of this. I wish Chris the absolute best in all things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll close by stating a renewed determination to find ways for everyone who seeks safe, humane and exciting online experiences to help create this better world.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2019 13:56:30 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>lasr21</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://blog.mozilla.org/blog/2019/08/29/thank-you-chris</og:url>
<og:title>Thank you, Chris – The Mozilla Blog</og:title>
<og:description>Thank you, Chris. Chris Beard has been Mozilla Corporation’s CEO for 5 and a half years. Chris has announced 2019 will be his last year in this role. I want ...</og:description>
<og:image>https://blog.mozilla.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Screen-Shot-2019-02-13-at-7.36.23-AM.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.mozilla.org/blog/2019/08/29/thank-you-chris/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Is Perl 6 Being Renamed?</title>
<link>http://blogs.perl.org/users/ovid/2019/08/is-perl-6-being-renamed.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://blogs.perl.org/users/ovid/2019/08/is-perl-6-being-renamed.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;By now, many of you have seen the Perl 6 Github issue &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/perl6/problem-solving/issues/81&quot;&gt;&quot;Perl&quot; in the name &quot;Perl 6&quot; is confusing and irritating&lt;/a&gt;. The issue suggested renaming Perl 6. While some may think that the name of the issue is trolling, or offensive, the actual issue was created by Elizabeth (Liz) Mattijsen, one of the core Perl 6 developers, a long-time Perl 5 developer, and with her spouse, Wendy, has long been an enthusiastic support of Perl 5/6. There is no trolling here. There is a lot of deep thought, careful discussion, and a genuine desire to find a way to bypass some deeply divisive issues in the Perl community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the proposed name was &quot;camelia&quot;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/perl6/problem-solving/issues/81#issuecomment-519776528&quot;&gt;Damian Conway made a strong argument in favor of &quot;raku&quot;&lt;/a&gt; and it appears the community is leaning towards this name for various reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is my attempt to summarize what's going on for those who have missed it. Any errors are, of course, Damian's. (just kidding!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What follows isn't about &lt;em&gt;facts&lt;/em&gt;. It's about &lt;em&gt;opinions&lt;/em&gt;. If someone feels that X is awesome, it doesn't matter if you disagree. That's still their opinion. Further, you can try to change their mind, but be aware that when someone strongly disagrees with you, you usually want to start discussion from the points you can agree on and then slowly move to the points on which you disagree. However, that's not been the story of Perl 5/6. People disagree and immediately jump to disagreements rather than trying to find common ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The far, far too terse backstory: the Perl 6 community seems to be split between those who view Perl 6 as a &lt;em&gt;sister language&lt;/em&gt; to Perl 5 and those who view Perl 6 as a &lt;em&gt;successor&lt;/em&gt; to Perl 5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Perl 5 community, meanwhile, is split between &quot;f*ck yeah&quot; and &quot;f*ck you&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To say that this issue has been bitterly divisive would be an understatement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Perl 6 was announced, it was seen the way that Perl 2, Perl 3, Perl 4, and Perl 5 were seen: replacements for &quot;$VERSION - 1&quot;. Over time, it became clear that though Perl 6 was in the same family as Perl 5, a straightforward migration path was unlikely. One only needs to look at the problems with Python 2 and Python 3 and the upgrade obstacles with their minor syntactic differences to understand that an upgrade from Perl 5 to Perl 6 isn't trivial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was, if I'm not mistaken (if I am, remember that it's Damian's fault 😃), that Carl Mäsak, is the person who first suggested that Perl 6 be considered a &lt;em&gt;sister language&lt;/em&gt; to Perl 5 in the way that C++ might be a sister language to C (though the upgrade path on the latter is probably easier). But that didn't satisfy some people. In fact, there were/are still people in the Perl 6 community who view Perl 6 as the successor language. To many people in the Perl 5 community, this says &quot;Perl 5 is dead; wait for Perl 6&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only have many Perl 5 developers been offended by effectively being told by some Perl 6 developers that their language is dead or dying, but it had real-world financial consequences. I can't tell you how many times I've talked to potential clients who've told me &quot;yeah, our Perl 5 codebase is old and we want to upgrade, but we have to wait for the next version (Perl 6) because any upgrade will be throwing money away.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And they've been waiting two decades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The BBC, the world's largest broadcaster, had Perl everywhere. They decided to ditch it. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mongodb.com/blog/post/the-mongodb-perl-driver-is-being-deprecated&quot;&gt;MongoDB claims that their clients aren't developing any new projects in Perl&lt;/a&gt;, so they're ditching Perl 5 support. Other companies are continuing this trend and this is, as potential clients have told me, because they're tired of waiting for Perl 6. They &lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt; Perl 6 is the successor to Perl 5 and given the name, it makes perfect sense. Combine that with the negative press about Perl 5 and you get into &quot;nobody got fired for buying IBM&quot; territory, but &lt;code class=&quot;prettyprint&quot;&gt;s/Perl/$other_language/g&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also (I can't remember if this was said publicly or not), but there are those who've suggested Perl 6 solutions and been rejected out of hand because &quot;Perl&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liz summed it up succinctly as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;24&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perl 6 was initially conceived to be the next version of Perl. It took way too long to mature to an initial release. Meanwhile, people interested in taking Perl 5 along, took back the reigns and continued developing Perl 5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having two programming languages that are sufficiently different to not be source compatible, but only differ in what many perceive to be a version number, is hurting the image of both Perl 5 and Perl 6 in the world. Since the word &quot;Perl&quot; is still perceived as &quot;Perl 5&quot; in the world, it only seems fair that &quot;Perl 6&quot; changes its name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Larry has indicated, in his video message to the participants of PerlCon 2019 in Riga, that the two sister languages are now old and wise enough to take care of themselves, such a name change would no longer require the approval of the BDFL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the video to which she refers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/T2e0xSOHd-0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of the 143 emoji responses to her initial post, 134 were clearly supportive with only 5 being unsupportive (4 being neutral).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What's worse is that Perl 6 is often tainted by the name &quot;Perl&quot;. Routinely I see in numerous online discussions that people refuse to even consider Perl 6 because they hate Perl. Or there are younger people who think of Perl as &quot;their grandfather's language&quot; (in much the same way people in my generation view COBOL). So there are people in the Perl 6 community who want to change the name simply to avoid an unjustified negative perception of the language. In fact, it's been suggested that the rename of Perl 6 might allow more people to come into the language by side-stepping this issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So yeah, there's bitterness and the Perl community not only needs to heal, but we need to find a way forward for both languages. The suggestion to change the name of Perl 6 to &quot;raku&quot; is effectively designed to make this happen. Perl 5 can figure out how to get beyond the branding issue that's been plaguing it and Perl 6 can do the same thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perl 6 performance has now gotten to the point where it's often comparable to Perl 5 or surpasses it. It still needs some work in this area, but the work is clear, the goals are straightforward, and Perl 6 is going to easily oustrip Perl 5 in terms of performance. If the Perl 6 community wants to rename, it's perhaps the perfect time to do so. It doesn't look like a bad choice if performance is a primary concern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But all of this brings me to the most important point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're in a bubble. If you're reading this, you're probably part of the Perl commmunity. Most of what I've said above isn't news to you. But who's outside the community?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People who sign contracts. People who decide what their next project will be built in. People who decide if they're going to rebuild their legacy Perl 5 system in Perl 5 or a language they don't have to justify to their bosses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, for many people the debate comes down to whether or not they have a financial future in working with a languagea they love. But they don't get to make that decision; people who control the purse strings do. Trademark law often deals with the concept of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Confusing_similarity&quot;&gt;confusing similarity&lt;/a&gt; because the market can easily get confused when two names are so very similar. And as any any competent salesperson can tell you, when your customer is confused, they don't buy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that's where we are. We have a very confusing issue which, it appears, that much of the Perl 6 community agrees needs to be sorted. Much of the Perl 5 community appears to feel the same way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None of this should be intended as a critique of what's gone on in the past because, frankly, I don't think anyone expected that this confusion would drag out for two decades. The various shifts we've made over time (from successor, to sister language, to creating an alias for the language), have led to the point we're at now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for myself: I would definitely program in Perl 6 is I could make a living at it. Right now that's not possible, so I'm still developing in Perl 5. I think Perl 6 corrects many core issues with Perl 5 (powerful OO, gradual typing, working concurrency, robust signatures, a cleaner syntax, etc.), but I also love the quirks of Perl 5. Sue me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let me end with a quote from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quotes.net/mquote/60274&quot;&gt;Neo from the Matrix&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know you're out there. I can feel you now. I know that you're afraid... you're afraid of us. You're afraid of change. I don't know the future. I didn't come here to tell you how this is going to end. I came here to tell you how it's going to begin. I'm going to hang up this phone, and then I'm going to show these people what you don't want them to see. I'm going to show them a world without you. A world without rules and controls, without borders or boundaries. A world where anything is possible. Where we go from there is a choice I leave to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: The above quote from the Matrix was intended solely to be vaguely humorous, vaguely relevant, and not at all serious. However, as my 8-year old daughter is quick to remind me: &quot;your jokes aren't funny, papa.&quot; As with my daughter, please take it as a joke that laid there and twitched (though I suspect she wouldn't phrase things quite the same way).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2019 13:05:49 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mtmail</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://blogs.perl.org/users/ovid/2019/08/is-perl-6-being-renamed.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Apple expands parts access to more independent repair businesses</title>
<link>https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2019/08/apple-offers-customers-even-more-options-for-safe-reliable-repairs/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2019/08/apple-offers-customers-even-more-options-for-safe-reliable-repairs/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Cupertino, California — Apple today announced a new repair program, offering customers additional options for the most common out-of-warranty iPhone repairs. Apple will provide more independent repair businesses — large or small —  with the same genuine parts, tools, training, repair manuals and diagnostics as its Apple Authorized Service Providers (AASPs). The program is launching in the US with plans to expand to other countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“To better meet our customers’ needs, we’re making it easier for independent providers across the US to tap into the same resources as our Apple Authorized Service Provider network,” said Jeff Williams, Apple’s chief operating officer. “When a repair is needed, a customer should have confidence the repair is done right. We believe the safest and most reliable repair is one handled by a trained technician using genuine parts that have been properly engineered and rigorously tested.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new independent repair provider program complements Apple’s continued investment in its growing global network of over 5,000 AASPs that lead the industry for customer satisfaction and help millions of people with both in- and out-of-warranty service for all Apple products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;pagebody-copy&quot; readability=&quot;39.212814645309&quot;&gt;There is no cost to join Apple’s independent repair program. To qualify for the new program, businesses need to have an Apple-certified technician who can perform the repairs. The process for certification is simple and free of charge. To learn more and apply, visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.apple.com/irp-program/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;support.apple.com/irp-program&lt;/a&gt;. Qualifying repair businesses will receive Apple-genuine parts, tools, training, repair manuals and diagnostics at the same cost as AASPs.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past year, Apple has launched a successful pilot with 20 independent repair businesses in North America, Europe and Asia who are currently offering genuine parts for repairs. Today’s announcement follows Apple’s recent major expansion of its authorized service network into every Best Buy store in the US, tripling the number of US AASP locations compared to three years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2019 12:57:57 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ehPReth</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Apple offers customers even more options for safe, reliable repairs</og:title>
<og:description>Apple today announced a new repair program, offering customers additional options for the most common out-of-warranty iPhone repairs.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2019/08/apple-offers-customers-even-more-options-for-safe-reliable-repairs/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/product/iphone/standard/Apple_Global-Repair-Update_082919_LP_hero.jpg.og.jpg?201908291207</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2019/08/apple-offers-customers-even-more-options-for-safe-reliable-repairs/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Emacs 26.3</title>
<link>https://lists.gnu.org/archive/html/emacs-devel/2019-08/msg00577.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://lists.gnu.org/archive/html/emacs-devel/2019-08/msg00577.html</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;title&gt;Emacs 26.3 released&lt;/title&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;Content-Type&quot; content=&quot;text/html; charset=utf-8&quot; /&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;29.149403341289&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;2&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; bgcolor=&quot;#000000&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; bgcolor=&quot;#FFFFCC&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;big&gt;&lt;strong&gt;emacs-devel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.gnu.org/archive/html/emacs-devel/2019-08/msg00576.html&quot;&gt;Date Prev&lt;/a&gt;][&lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.gnu.org/archive/html/emacs-devel/2019-08/msg00578.html&quot;&gt;Date Next&lt;/a&gt;][&lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.gnu.org/archive/html/emacs-devel/2019-08/msg00563.html&quot;&gt;Thread Prev&lt;/a&gt;][&lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.gnu.org/archive/html/emacs-devel/2019-08/msg00592.html&quot;&gt;Thread Next&lt;/a&gt;][&lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.gnu.org/archive/html/emacs-devel/2019-08/index.html#00577&quot;&gt;Date Index&lt;/a&gt;][&lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.gnu.org/archive/html/emacs-devel/2019-08/threads.html#00577&quot;&gt;Thread Index&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Emacs 26.3 released&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody readability=&quot;1.5&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Nicolas Petton&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subject&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Emacs 26.3 released&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Wed, 28 Aug 2019 23:35:18 +0200&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;pre&gt;
Hi!

Version 26.3 of the Emacs text editor is now available.

For more information on Emacs, see:
  &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs&quot;&gt;https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs&lt;/a&gt;

You can retrieve the source from your nearest GNU mirror by using one
of the following links:
  &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://ftpmirror.gnu.org/emacs/emacs-26.3.tar.xz&quot;&gt;https://ftpmirror.gnu.org/emacs/emacs-26.3.tar.xz&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://ftpmirror.gnu.org/emacs/emacs-26.3.tar.gz&quot;&gt;https://ftpmirror.gnu.org/emacs/emacs-26.3.tar.gz&lt;/a&gt;

You can get the PGP signatures[1] at
  &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://ftp.gnu.org/gnu/emacs/emacs-26.3.tar.xz.sig&quot;&gt;https://ftp.gnu.org/gnu/emacs/emacs-26.3.tar.xz.sig&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://ftp.gnu.org/gnu/emacs/emacs-26.3.tar.gz.sig&quot;&gt;https://ftp.gnu.org/gnu/emacs/emacs-26.3.tar.gz.sig&lt;/a&gt;

The tarball is signed with the following GPG key, which can be found on
public PGP key servers:

  D405AA2C862C54F17EEE6BE0E8BCD7866AFCF978

You can choose a mirror explicitly from the list at:
  &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/prep/ftp.html&quot;&gt;https://www.gnu.org/prep/ftp.html&lt;/a&gt;

Mirrors may take some time to update; the main GNU ftp server is at:
  &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://ftp.gnu.org/gnu/emacs/&quot;&gt;https://ftp.gnu.org/gnu/emacs/&lt;/a&gt;

This release is mainly a maintenance release, which contains a new GPG key for
GNU ELPA packages.

For more information about this release, see the etc/NEWS file, which
you can view from Emacs with `C-h n'.

For the complete list of changes and the people who made them, see the
various ChangeLog files in the source distribution.  For a summary of
all the people who have contributed to Emacs, see the etc/AUTHORS file.

The online manuals will be updated shortly.

Printed copies of the Emacs manual are available for purchase from the
Free Software Foundation's online store at:
&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://shop.fsf.org/product/emacs-manual/&quot;&gt;https://shop.fsf.org/product/emacs-manual/&lt;/a&gt;

Regards,
Nico
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.gnu.org/archive/html/emacs-devel/2019-08/pgpUQ8fuwlyb2.pgp&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lists.gnu.org/icons/generic.png&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;Attachment:&quot; width=&quot;20&quot; height=&quot;22&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.gnu.org/archive/html/emacs-devel/2019-08/pgpUQ8fuwlyb2.pgp&quot;&gt;&lt;tt&gt;signature.asc&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Description:&lt;/em&gt; PGP signature&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Emacs 26.3 released&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Nicolas Petton&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&amp;lt;=&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2019 10:33:44 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Anon84</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://lists.gnu.org/archive/html/emacs-devel/2019-08/msg00577.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>3.8M-year-old skull of an early ape-like human ancestor discovered in Ethiopia</title>
<link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-49486980</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-49486980</guid>
<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape has-caption full-width lead&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                &lt;img class=&quot;js-image-replace&quot; alt=&quot;Composite of Australopithecus anamensis skull and face&quot; src=&quot;https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/320/cpsprodpb/6042/production/_108524642_composite_index_976.jpg&quot; width=&quot;976&quot; height=&quot;549&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;CMNH/MattCrow&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    The discovered skull (R) with an artist's rendering (L) of what Anamensis might have looked like
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body__introduction&quot;&gt;Researchers have discovered a nearly complete 3.8-million-year-old skull of an early ape-like human ancestor in Ethiopia. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;An analysis of the new specimen challenges ideas about how the first humans evolved from ape-like ancestors.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The current view that an ape named Lucy was among &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/sci/tech/5363328.stm&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;a species that gave rise to the first early humans&lt;/a&gt; may have to be reconsidered.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The discovery is reported in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-019-1513-8&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link-external&quot;&gt;journal Nature&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The skull was found by Prof Yohannes Haile-Selassie at a place called Miro Dora, which is in the Mille District of Ethiopia's Afar Regional State. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The scientist, who's affiliated to the Cleveland Museum of Natural History in Ohio, US, said he immediately recognised the significance of the fossil.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;I thought to myself, 'oh my goodness - am I seeing what I think I am seeing?'. And all of a sudden I was jumping up and down and that was when I realised that this was what I had dreamt,&quot; he told BBC News.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;More stories like this:&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Prof Haile-Selassie says the specimen is the best example yet of the ape-like human ancestor called &lt;i&gt;Australopithecus anamensis&lt;/i&gt; - the oldest known australopithecine whose kind may have existed as far back as 4.2 million years ago.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It had been thought that&lt;i&gt; A&lt;/i&gt;. &lt;i&gt;anamensis &lt;/i&gt;was the direct ancestor of a later, more advanced species called &lt;i&gt;Australopithecus afarensis,&lt;/i&gt; which in turn has been considered a direct ancestor of the first early humans in the grouping, or genus, known as &lt;i&gt;Homo&lt;/i&gt;, and which includes all humans alive today.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape has-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
                 &lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;Cleveland Museum of Natural History&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    Different aspects of the new specimen's face and view (bottom-left) looking at its upper-jaw from below. The creature had protruding jaws and small earholes
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;The discovery of the first &lt;i&gt;afarensis&lt;/i&gt; skeleton in 1974 caused a sensation. She was nicknamed Lucy by researchers after the Beatles song, Lucy in the Sky With Diamonds, which was playing at the excavation site. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hailed as &quot;the first ape to have walked&quot;, Lucy captured the public's attention. But writing a commentary in Nature, Prof Fred Spoor, of London's Natural History Museum, said that &lt;i&gt;anamensis &lt;/i&gt;&quot;looks set to become another celebrated icon of human evolution&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The reason for this likely elevated status is because we can now say that &lt;i&gt;anamensis &lt;/i&gt;and &lt;i&gt;afarensis&lt;/i&gt; actually overlapped in time. The former did not evolve directly into the latter in a neat linear manner, as previously supposed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The realisation comes about through the reinterpretation that the new fossil brings to bear on a previously discovered 3.9-million-year-old skull fragment. That fragment had been assigned to &lt;i&gt;anamensis. &lt;/i&gt;Scientists can now see it is actually the remains of an &lt;i&gt;afarensis,&lt;/i&gt; pushing this species' origin deeper into the past.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's apparent now the two species must have co-existed for at least 100,000 years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;idt2&quot;&gt;&lt;div data-idt-uuid=&quot;d9479d73-42c6-4a7a-89fc-6c1e9e7ebe21&quot;&gt;&lt;div data-graphicuuid=&quot;d9479d73-42c6-4a7a-89fc-6c1e9e7ebe21&quot; class=&quot;PicContainer-iky41v-0 dkfFzK&quot; readability=&quot;7.5&quot;&gt;&lt;div data-graphicpic=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;Img__PicImage-s1jp862x-1 dtAYqF&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.files.bbci.co.uk/include/idt2/assets/b6c2ee47-7e32-4d4b-9323-11243debef9c&quot; alt=&quot;Prof Yohannes Haile-Selassie holding the skull he found&quot; class=&quot;Img__Image-s1jp862x-0 lmLsXj&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cleveland Museum of Natural History&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;blockquote dir=&quot;ltr&quot; class=&quot;PicQuote-s138d390-0 eZwimE&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;&lt;svg xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot; width=&quot;30&quot; height=&quot;25&quot; aria-label=&quot;Quote&quot; class=&quot;Quote__SVG-s1rj7ts5-0 jBAUmy&quot;&gt;&lt;g fill=&quot;#C9A975&quot; fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot;&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;M0 15.614c0-4.538 1.106-8.074 3.319-10.61C5.53 2.47 8.697.801 12.817 0v4.626c-3.143.89-5.234 2.55-6.271 4.983-.58 1.304-.809 2.535-.687 3.692H13V25H0v-9.386zM17 15.614c0-4.538 1.106-8.074 3.319-10.61C22.53 2.47 25.697.801 29.817 0v4.626c-3.143.89-5.234 2.55-6.271 4.983-.58 1.304-.809 2.535-.687 3.692H30V25H17v-9.386z&quot;/&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;p&gt;I thought to myself 'Oh my goodness, am I seeing what I think I'm seeing?'&lt;/p&gt;&lt;svg xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot; width=&quot;43&quot; height=&quot;3&quot; viewbox=&quot;0 0 43 3&quot; class=&quot;RuleBreak__SVG-lfivii-0 lazDte&quot;&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;M1.5 1.5h40&quot; stroke=&quot;#C9A975&quot; stroke-width=&quot;3&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; stroke-linecap=&quot;square&quot;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;What most likely happened was that a small group of &lt;i&gt;anamensis &lt;/i&gt;isolated itself from the main population and over time evolved into &lt;i&gt;afarensis&lt;/i&gt; because of adaptations to local conditions. The two types rubbed along for a while before the remnant &lt;i&gt;anamensis&lt;/i&gt; died out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The finding is important because it suggests that additional overlaps with other advanced ape-like species may also have occurred, increasing the number of potential evolutionary routes to the first humans.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In short, although this latest discovery does not disprove that Lucy's kind gave rise to the &lt;i&gt;Homo&lt;/i&gt; group, it does bring other recently named species into contention. Prof Haile-Selassie agreed that &quot;all bets are now off&quot; as to which species is humanity's direct ancestor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He explained: &quot;For a long time, &lt;i&gt;afarensis &lt;/i&gt;was considered the best candidate as an ancestor to our kind, but we are not in that position any more. Now we can look back at all the species that might have existed at the time and examine which one may have been most like the first human.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-portrait has-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
                 &lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;P.PLAILLY/E.DAYNES/SPL&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    The remains of an ape named Lucy thought to be the ancestor of the first humans
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;The term &quot;missing link&quot; drives anthropologists crazy when they hear anyone, especially journalists, use it to describe a fossil that is part-ape and part-human. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indeed Dr Henry Gee, a senior editor at Nature, once threatened to &quot;rip my liver out and eat it with onions, borlotti beans and a glass of claret&quot; if I did so when reporting a previous discovery.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are many reasons for Henry's irritation, but chief among them is the recognition that there are many links in the chain of human evolution and most if not nearly all of them are still missing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Anamensis&lt;/i&gt; is the latest in a string of recent discoveries that shows that there was no smooth line of ascent to modern humans.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The truth is far more complex and far more interesting. It tells a story of evolution &quot;trying out&quot; different &quot;prototype&quot; human ancestors in different places until some of them were resilient and clever enough to withstand the pressures wrought by changes in climate, habitat and food scarcity - and evolve into us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Prof Haile-Selassie is one of the few African scientists working in human evolution. He is now a recognised name but he says it's hard for well qualified African researchers to get the necessary financial backing from Western-based research funding organisations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Most of the fossil evidence related to our origin comes from Africa and I think Africans should be able to use the resources available in their own continent and advance their career in palaeoanthropology. Their limitations getting to this field of study is usually funding,&quot; he told me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BBCPallab&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link-external&quot;&gt;Follow Pallab on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            </description>
<pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2019 07:50:23 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>iamben</dc:creator>
<og:title>Advanced ape skull find changes human origin ideas</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>The discovery of an ancient skull in Ethiopia underlines the complexity in the evolution of humans.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.bbc.com/news/science-environment-49486980</og:url>
<og:image>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/6042/production/_108524642_composite_index_976.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-GB</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-49486980</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Google just deleted my nearly 10-year-old free and open-source Android app</title>
<link>https://medium.com/@mmathieum/google-just-deleted-my-nearly-10-year-old-free-open-source-android-app-7fbc52edc50a</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://medium.com/@mmathieum/google-just-deleted-my-nearly-10-year-old-free-open-source-android-app-7fbc52edc50a</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;5017&quot; class=&quot;jp jq fo bs jr b js jt ju jv jw jx jy jz ka kb kc&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;jr lm&quot;&gt;Why my account was terminated?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;fa6d&quot; class=&quot;jp jq fo bs jr b js jt ju jv jw jx jy jz ka kb kc&quot;&gt;4 of my apps were reviewed and suspended on Friday morning for the exact same issue (same email):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;ml mm mn&quot; readability=&quot;9.4588744588745&quot;&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;f4fc&quot; class=&quot;jp jq fo kd jr b js jt ju jv jw jx jy jz ka kb kc&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;bs&quot;&gt;“Violation of&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/about/ip-deception-spam/deceptive-behavior/&quot; class=&quot;bb cn la lb lc ld&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;bs&quot;&gt;Deceptive Behavior policy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;4f10&quot; class=&quot;jp jq fo kd jr b js jt ju jv jw jx jy jz ka kb kc&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;bs&quot;&gt;We don’t allow apps that attempt to deceive users or enable dishonest behavior. Apps must provide accurate disclosure of their functionality and should perform as reasonably expected by the user. Apps must not attempt to mimic functionality or warnings from the operating system or other apps. Any changes to device settings must be made with the user’s knowledge and consent and be easily reversible by the user.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;8b5c&quot; class=&quot;jp jq fo bs jr b js jt ju jv jw jx jy jz ka kb kc&quot;&gt;Shortly after these multiple [similar] strikes, I received an email informing me that my developer account was terminated:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;ml mm mn&quot; readability=&quot;9.2028169014085&quot;&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;57ab&quot; class=&quot;jp jq fo kd jr b js jt ju jv jw jx jy jz ka kb kc&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;bs&quot;&gt;“REASON FOR TERMINATION: Multiple violations of the&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/about/developer-content-policy.html&quot; class=&quot;bb cn la lb lc ld&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;bs&quot;&gt;Developer Program Policies&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em class=&quot;bs&quot;&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.android.com/us/developer-distribution-agreement.html&quot; class=&quot;bb cn la lb lc ld&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;bs&quot;&gt;Developer Distribution Agreement&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em class=&quot;bs&quot;&gt;as outlined in previous emails sent to the registered email address of your Publisher account.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;c1ee&quot; class=&quot;jp jq fo kd jr b js jt ju jv jw jx jy jz ka kb kc&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;bs&quot;&gt;Google Play Publisher terminations are associated with developers, and may span multiple account registrations and related Google services.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;01df&quot; class=&quot;jp jq fo bs jr b js jt ju jv jw jx jy jz ka kb kc&quot;&gt;After appealing the decision, I’ve received an email informing me about the confirmation of the initial decision:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;ml mm mn&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;34df&quot; class=&quot;jp jq fo kd jr b js jt ju jv jw jx jy jz ka kb kc&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;bs&quot;&gt;“After reviewing your appeal, we have confirmed our initial decision and will not be able to reinstate your developer account.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2019 04:11:44 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>lladnar</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Google just deleted my nearly 10-year-old free &amp; open-source Android app</og:title>
<og:description>google@play-store: sudo rm -rf org.mtransit.android*</og:description>
<og:url>https://medium.com/@mmathieum/google-just-deleted-my-nearly-10-year-old-free-open-source-android-app-7fbc52edc50a</og:url>
<og:image>https://miro.medium.com/max/1200/1*Xp9UZ2P6TQjURctIidyQ6w.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://medium.com/@mmathieum/google-just-deleted-my-nearly-10-year-old-free-open-source-android-app-7fbc52edc50a</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>John Carmack on the Joe Rogan Experience [video]</title>
<link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=udlMSe5-zP8</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=udlMSe5-zP8</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;eow-description&quot; class=&quot;&quot;&gt;John Carmack is a computer programmer, video game developer and engineer. He co-founded id Software and was the lead programmer of its video games Commander Keen, Wolfenstein 3D, Doom, Quake, Rage and their sequels. Currently he is the CTO at Oculus.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2019 02:37:19 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>sexy_seedbox</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=udlMSe5-zP8</og:url>
<og:title>Joe Rogan Experience #1342 - John Carmack</og:title>
<og:image>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/udlMSe5-zP8/hqdefault.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>John Carmack is a computer programmer, video game developer and engineer. He co-founded id Software and was the lead programmer of its video games Commander ...</og:description>
<og:type>video.other</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=udlMSe5-zP8</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Bontrager’s WaveCel material more effective at preventing concussions than MIPS</title>
<link>https://pelotonmagazine.com/gear/bontragers-new-wavecel-bests-mips-at-concussion-prevention/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://pelotonmagazine.com/gear/bontragers-new-wavecel-bests-mips-at-concussion-prevention/</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;We hear lots of noise about ‘revolutionary’ new products in cycling. They are essentially never revolutionary, and frequently aren’t even new. But when Trek starts teasing a new product with the tag, “A change like this happens once every 30 years,” we’re pretty sure it’s a big deal. Speculation started. Was the lime green material teased a new frame material? Trek launched OCLV carbon about 30 years ago. But the biggest clue was that Bontrager touted the material as well, and it did look a bit like the Koroyd material used in Smith helmets. Now we know. Bontrager is incorporating a new material called WaveCel into its helmets which it claims is 48x more effective than EPS foam at preventing concussions during unplanned dismounts.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;• WaveCel is a collapsible cellular material that reduces the effect of oblique head impacts that generate the rotational forces that can cause so much brain trauma.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;• WaveCel is an alternative to the now ubiquitous MIPS layer used by Bontrager in many helmets and most other helmet manufacturers as well.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;pelot-post-injection&quot; id=&quot;pelot-2101566541&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pel.magserv.com/cgi-bin/subscribe?qt=new&amp;amp;Keyed_effort=W2019&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;1208&quot; height=&quot;160&quot; src=&quot;https://pelotonmagazine.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/COFFEE_CUP_JULY_2019.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;https://pelotonmagazine.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/COFFEE_CUP_JULY_2019.jpg 1208w, https://pelotonmagazine.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/COFFEE_CUP_JULY_2019-300x40.jpg 300w, https://pelotonmagazine.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/COFFEE_CUP_JULY_2019-768x102.jpg 768w, https://pelotonmagazine.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/COFFEE_CUP_JULY_2019-1024x136.jpg 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1208px) 100vw, 1208px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;• According to a study at the Legacy Research Institute in Portland, Oregon, WaveCel is significantly more effective than MIPS in reducing both linear impact forces and rational forces on the brain.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;• While similar in appearance to Koroyd used by Smith, Koroyd-equipped helmets still use a MIPS layer.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;• WaveCel adds a little over 50 grams compared to non-WaveCel helmet’s weight.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;As most people in cycling now know, it’s not the blunt impacts we should fear, it’s the oblique, angular impacts at high speed that cause so many concussion as well as life altering traumatic brain injury. Brain cells do not respond well to shearing forces. In the 10-15 milliseconds after an oblique impact it’s crucially important to spread that force out with 10-15mm of movement. If the helmet doesn’t provide that movement, your brain provides it by rotating in your skull. Yeah, that’s as bad as it sounds. Axons connecting brain cells go ‘snap.’&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-45529&quot; src=&quot;https://pelotonmagazine.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/WaveCel-Material-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;3565&quot; height=&quot;2025&quot; srcset=&quot;https://pelotonmagazine.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/WaveCel-Material-1.jpg 3565w, https://pelotonmagazine.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/WaveCel-Material-1-300x170.jpg 300w, https://pelotonmagazine.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/WaveCel-Material-1-768x436.jpg 768w, https://pelotonmagazine.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/WaveCel-Material-1-1024x582.jpg 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 3565px) 100vw, 3565px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;WaveCel provides that movement thanks to the design of its cellular material. Bontrager calls it ‘Flex, Crumple, Glide.’ In scientific circles this is called ‘rotational suspension’. The material has a flexible crease built in, then once that flex is used up, the material crumples on itself. Then, under rotational forces, it folds on itself and then finally it slides along the EPS foam exterior – ‘Flex, Crumple, Glide’. WaveCel works with ESP foam—it is not a replacement for it. It should also be noted that, like EPS foam, WaveCel only works once. After a crash, get a new helmet.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/QdobumYx-uE&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Bontrager worked with an orthopedic surgeon, Dr. Steve Madey, and a biomechanics engineer, Dr. Michael Bottlang, for four years to create and integrate this new material with its helmets. Today Bontrager has launched four new helmets with WaveCel. The XXX WaveCel Road helmet is the top end road lid and will be used by the Trek-Segafredo pro team. It retails for $300. For $150, WaveCel can be had in the Specter road helmet, and WaveCel commuting and MTB helmets are also available: the Charge and Blaze for $150 and $300 respectively.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pelotonmagazine.com/gear/viginia-tech-debuts-helmet-ratings/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Check out Virginia Tech’s first published helmet ratings – the first third party rating in the cycling helmet industry. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;WaveCel adds an average of 53 grams across all sizes to the helmet. That puts a small XXX WavCel Road at 325 grams—certainly not the lightest helmet, but on par with many MIPS equipped helmets from other manufacturers. For comparison, a MIPS equipped Bontrager Velocis helmet is 279 grams. The weight-for-safety trade-off does not concern us. The XXX WaveCel has the look of an aero road helmet, although no aero numbers were provided. It has seven large vents up front and three exhaust vents in back, although how well the exhaust vents draw across the head with the WaveCel material in the way is yet to be determined—which is what has &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;us a bit worried: high speed venting. The cellular structure of WaveCel is vertical in relation to your head, and we imagine at high speed it will reduce flow and cooling. No ventilation comparisons were provided by Bontrager. Perhaps in the heat of the tour, Trek riders will opt for the Velocis or event the Specter, which is a bit lighter and has more-traditional venting. We look forward to a full summer road test to find out. &lt;/span&gt;The XXX feature BOPA adjustment, AgION antimicrobial pads with a silicon strip to channel sweat away from your eyes as well as free replacement in year one if you have a crash. The XXX WaveCel is a handsome helmet, although we like the more subdued smoke color for the WaveCel than the hi-vis lime green.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-45528 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://pelotonmagazine.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Bonty-XXX-WaveCel-Mash-up.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1491&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; srcset=&quot;https://pelotonmagazine.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Bonty-XXX-WaveCel-Mash-up.jpg 1491w, https://pelotonmagazine.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Bonty-XXX-WaveCel-Mash-up-300x161.jpg 300w, https://pelotonmagazine.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Bonty-XXX-WaveCel-Mash-up-768x412.jpg 768w, https://pelotonmagazine.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Bonty-XXX-WaveCel-Mash-up-1024x549.jpg 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1491px) 100vw, 1491px&quot;/&gt;The XXX WaveCel is available in five colors plus a limited edition Purple Phaze. It costs $300 and weighs 325grams for a size small.
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Bontrager provides some pretty startling force reduction numbers. Its WaveCel helmets can prevent concussions 99% of the time from common cycling accidents and is 48x more effective than a traditional EPS helmet. But we don’t need to take Bontrager’s word for it. It has a peer reviewed study from the Biomechanics Laboratory at the Legacy Research Institute in Portland, Oregon as well as top five-star marks for all its WaveCel helmets from the Virginia Tech’s helmet test lab. We’ll dig into the testing below, but if you want it from the horse’s mouth, you can get to them directly with the links below. It is important note that WaveCel inventors, Dr. Steve Madey and Dr. Michael Bottlang, are authors of the study, as well as founders and co-directors of the Legacy Research Institute.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://trekbikes.com/wavecel&quot;&gt;trekbikes.com/wavecel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;. &lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt;               &lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://helmet.beam.vt.edu/bicycle-helmet-ratings.html&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;helmet.beam.vt.edu/bicycle-helmet-ratings.html&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Interestingly, for the study performed at the Legacy Research Institute, no Bontrager helmets were used. Instead the SCOTT ARX was used in three forms – the traditional ESP ARX as control, the MIPS equipped ARX Plus and then an ARX adapted for WaveCel. 15mm of EPS foam was robotically milled out of a traditional ARX helmet and then replaced with WaveCel to simulate the helmet’s original thickness.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Twenty each of these helmets were tested using a Hybrid IIII test head and neck assembly fitted with accelerometers. Five helmets of each specification were used for each impact and then the results were averaged. From a vertical rig, the helmets fitted to head and neck form were dropped onto an anvil in the following scenarios: drops at 4.8 meters per second onto 30, 45 and 60 degree anvils, then at 6.2 m/s onto a 45 degree anvil. For reference, 4.8m/s is almost 11mph and&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;6.2m/s is almost 14mph. Each drop used a brand new helmet.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-45527&quot; src=&quot;https://pelotonmagazine.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Bonty-XXX-WaveCel-Mash-up-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1491&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; srcset=&quot;https://pelotonmagazine.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Bonty-XXX-WaveCel-Mash-up-2.jpg 1491w, https://pelotonmagazine.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Bonty-XXX-WaveCel-Mash-up-2-300x161.jpg 300w, https://pelotonmagazine.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Bonty-XXX-WaveCel-Mash-up-2-768x412.jpg 768w, https://pelotonmagazine.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Bonty-XXX-WaveCel-Mash-up-2-1024x549.jpg 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1491px) 100vw, 1491px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;WaveCel performed exceptionally well in this study. In reduction of straight-up linear impacts, the thin MIPS layer unsurprisingly does not reduce that force at all compared to a traditional EPS helmet. The WaveCel performed very well, reducing the force of linear impacts on the head by 16 percent on the 60 degree impact and 26 percent on the 30 degree anvil. At 6.8 m/s, all three helmets provided essentially the same reduction.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;But MIPS is not about linear impacts, it’s all about reducing rotational force. How do MIPS and WaveCel compare there? Rotational forces are measured in two ways: rotational acceleration and the ultimate velocity of the rotation. The MIPS equipped ARX helmet was very good at reducing these forces. Compared to the non-MIPS equipped ARX, at slow speeds rotational acceleration is reduced by between 21 and 44 percent at 30 and 45 degree impacts respectively by MIPS. At 6.8 m/s, the reductions were less dramatic for the MIPS helmet. The WaveCel-equipped helmet performed even better. At the low end, a 34 percent reduction at 60 degree impacts at 4.8 m/s and up to a whopping 73 percent reduction at 45 degrees at 6.2 m/s.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pelotonmagazine.com/gear/giro-aether-mips-slip-plane-beauty/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RELATED: Read the story behind the MIPS Spherical design of the Giro Aether&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;How about rotational velocity? Again, MIPS performs well, but not as well as WaveCel. Compared to the control ARX helmet, MIPS reduced overall rotational velocity by 15 percent during 30 degree impacts at 4.8 m/s and 67 percent during impacts of the 60 degree anvil at 4.8 m/s. WaveCel saw reductions in ultimate rotational velocity by 50 percent during a 30 degree impact at 4.8 m/s. And that number jumps all the way up to an 84 percent reduction at the high speed 6.8 m/s impacts of the 45 degree anvil.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-45533&quot; src=&quot;https://pelotonmagazine.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/WaveCel-in-Action.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1600&quot; height=&quot;897&quot; srcset=&quot;https://pelotonmagazine.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/WaveCel-in-Action.jpg 1600w, https://pelotonmagazine.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/WaveCel-in-Action-300x168.jpg 300w, https://pelotonmagazine.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/WaveCel-in-Action-768x431.jpg 768w, https://pelotonmagazine.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/WaveCel-in-Action-1024x574.jpg 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;What do these reductions in forces mean as far as reducing actual brain injury? A lot, actually. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Metrics have been created to predict brain injury and the results are amazing. It’s called the BrIC—Brain Injury Criterion—and using peak rotation velocity as recorded by the head form’s accelerometers, the chances of sustaining an AIS 2 level brain injury —that’s a mild to severe concussion with potential loss of consciousness—can be calculated. Compared to the control helmet, the MIPS ARX was very good, reducing chances of an AIS 2 brain injury by 32 percent during slow speed impact at 30 degrees and up to 91 percent during slow speed impacts at 60 degrees. As good as this is, WaveCel was better, reducing the chance of AIS 2 injury over the control helmet by 81 percent during slow impacts at 30 degrees and by a staggering 98 percent at 45 degrees during fast impacts. When looking at the ‘injury probability’ bar graph included in the study, the WaveCel equipped helmet is basically a tiny sliver at the bottom of the chart—almost undetectable. That’s the kind of injury probability we want: undetectable.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;While this new material may not be as sexy as an über-stiff, lightweight new frame material, from a safety perspective—assuming the data is good—WaveCel is certainly new and indeed revolutionary. We may all feel superior to football fans as we go for a long ride on Super Bowl Sunday and feature lower BMI’s, but when it comes to concussions, we’re in the same boat as those football players. It’s a problem the sport needs to take more seriously and WaveCel from Bontrager looks like a great place to start.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look for a ride test in the pages of PELOTON soon and for more info now head to &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://trekbikes.com/wavecel&quot;&gt;trekbikes.com/wavecel&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2019 00:26:05 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Alex3917</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Bontrager’s New WaveCel Bests MIPS at Concussion Prevention - Peloton Magazine</og:title>
<og:description>We hear lots of noise about ‘revolutionary’ new products in cycling. They are essentially never revolutionary, and frequently aren’t even new. But when Trek starts teasing a new product with the tag, “A change like this happens once every 30 years,” we’re pretty sure it’s a big deal. Speculation started. Was the lime green material …</og:description>
<og:url>https://pelotonmagazine.com/gear/bontragers-new-wavecel-bests-mips-at-concussion-prevention/</og:url>
<og:image>https://pelotonmagazine.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Bonty-XXX-WaveCel-Hero.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://pelotonmagazine.com/gear/bontragers-new-wavecel-bests-mips-at-concussion-prevention/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>