<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>How journalists use youtube-dl</title>
<link>https://freedom.press/news/riaa-github-youtube-dl-journalist-tool/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://freedom.press/news/riaa-github-youtube-dl-journalist-tool/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The popular free software project “youtube-dl” was removed from Github on Friday following a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/github/dmca/blob/master/2020/10/2020-10-23-RIAA.md&quot;&gt;legal notice from the Recording Industry Association of America&lt;/a&gt; claiming it violates U.S. copyright law. According to the RIAA, the tool's “clear purpose” includes reproducing and distributing “music videos and sound recordings ... without authorization.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtube-dl.org/&quot;&gt;youtube-dl&lt;/a&gt; is a powerful general purpose media tool that allows users to make local copies of media from a very broad range of sites. That versatility has secured it a place in the toolkits of many reporters, newsroom developers, and archivists. For now, the code remains available to download through youtube-dl's own site, but the disruption of its development hub and the RIAA saber-rattling jeopardizes both the future of the software and the myriad journalistic workflows that depend on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Numerous reporters told Freedom of the Press Foundation that they rely on youtube-dl when reporting on extremist or controversial content. Øyvind Bye Skille, a journalist who has used youtube-dl at the Norwegian Broadcasting Corporation and as a fact checker with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.faktisk.no/&quot;&gt;Faktisk.no&lt;/a&gt;, said, “I have also used it to secure a good quality copy of video content from Youtube, Twitter, etc., in case the content gets taken down when we start reporting on it.” Skille pointed to a specific instance of videos connected to the terrorist murder of a Norwegian woman in Morocco. “Downloading the content does not necessarily mean we will re-publish it, but it is often important to secure it for documentation and further internal investigations.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Justin Ling, a freelance investigative reporter who often covers security and extremism for outlets including Foreign Policy and VICE News, described the scenario of reporting on the rise of conspiracy theories as the relevant posts face removal and bans. Youtube “has been a crucial hub for QAnon organizing and propaganda: I've often used youtube-dl to store those videos for my own benefit. Good thing, too, as Youtube often, without warning, mass-removes that sort of content, which can be ruinous for those of us using those Youtube accounts to trace the spread of these conspiracies.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other cases, local copies are necessary to conduct more rigorous analysis than is possible online, and journalists turn to youtube-dl for the highest quality copy of the video available. John Bolger, a software developer and systems administrator who does freelance and data journalism, recounted the experience of reporting &lt;a href=&quot;https://hunterenvoy.net/articles/nypd-baruch&quot;&gt;an award-winning investigation&lt;/a&gt; as the News Editor of the college paper the &lt;em&gt;Hunter Envoy&lt;/em&gt; in 2012. In that story, the &lt;em&gt;Envoy&lt;/em&gt; used video evidence to contradict official reports denying a police presence at an on-campus Occupy Wall Street protest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“In order to reach my conclusions about the NYPD’s involvement... I had to watch this video hundreds of times—in slow motion, zoomed in, and looping over critical moments—in order to analyze the video I had to watch and manipulate it in ways that are just not possible” using the web interface. Youtube-dl is one effective method for downloading the video at the maximum possible resolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jake, a member of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://lucyparsonslabs.com/&quot;&gt;Chicago-based transparency group Lucy Parsons Labs&lt;/a&gt;, uses youtube-dl to save copies of recorded incidents involving police use of force or abusive behavior. Once copied, the videos can be stored in an archive or modified before publication, such as by blurring the faces of bystanders or victims. “We have sometimes been able to take a closer look at individual frames after downloading with youtube-dl to identify officers when they are not wearing their badges intentionally or obfuscating them with things to avoid accountability.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One misinformation researcher told Freedom of the Press Foundation about using youtube-dl to create a baseline for machine learning models developed to do automated real-time fact-checking. “While our production systems are designed to be used on live video streams, it's not feasible to test on live video. Youtube-dl allows us to greatly increase the speed of our research development and allow us to be able to actually test our software on a day-to-day basis, not just when politicians happen to have a speech.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, a number of reporters described using youtube-dl for nuts-and-bolts workflows such as transcribing videos they’re covering. Jeremy Gray, a data scientist with The Globe and Mail, described a Slack tool he provides to journalists to allow them to automatically transcribe their own interviews and, until Friday, to transcribe Youtube videos from a URL. “It used youtube-dl, and now that part is broken.” Another journalist, who works at a “small-ish public media newsroom,” described a common situation where a reporter needs “a recording of a public meeting for a story but is on deadline and doesn’t want the hassle of recording the parts they want it in realtime or wants the full file for something like AI transcription.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That same journalist described how youtube-dl helps address the challenge of incorporating user-generated content on-air. In the immediate aftermath of an earthquake, their newsroom began expansive continuous coverage and sought to include photos and videos that locals had recorded. “We are scrupulous about making sure we get permission (and the person granting it actually owns the copyright), but especially right after an earthquake asking people to send the video to us specifically can be a much bigger ask than just allowing us to use it (if they even have a recording, which they probably don’t for a livestream), so often after getting permission I’d just download it straight from social media to transcode for TV.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That use case is common. Reporters frequently need high-fidelity copies of video or audio tracks for publication or reporting. Ling, the freelance security reporter, said he also uses youtube-dl to “get the best audio quality” when downloading copies of press conferences or news events “to grab snippets of audio for use in podcasts or radio work.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, numerous reporters described using youtube-dl to download copies of their own works. Freedom of the Press Foundation has previously worked to &lt;a href=&quot;https://freedom.press/news/preserving-threatened-archives-splinter-and-deadspin/&quot;&gt;help writers preserve portfolio copies of their articles&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://freedom.press/news/archiving-alternative-press-threatened-wealthy-buyers/&quot;&gt;to help full news archives stay online&lt;/a&gt; when the outlet itself is under threat. Youtube-dl plays an important role in that ecosystem as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Github has not publicly commented on its removal of one of its most popular repositories. Clearly, youtube-dl in particular and the ability to download and manipulate online videos in general are an important part of the work of journalism and contemporary media literacy. Given the important role that youtube-dl plays in public interest reporting and archiving, the RIAA’s efforts to have the tool removed represent an extraordinary overreach with the possibility for dramatic unforeseen consequences. We urge RIAA to reconsider its threat, and Github to reinstate the account in full.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 19:03:10 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>thisisparker</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://freedom.press/news/riaa-github-youtube-dl-journalist-tool/</og:url>
<og:title>Music industry forces widely used journalist tool offline</og:title>
<og:description>The popular free software project “youtube-dl” was removed from Github on Friday following a legal notice from the Recording Industry Association of America claiming it violates copyright law. The tool is widely used by journalists for various reporting purposes.</og:description>
<og:image>https://freedom.press/media/images/ytdl-code.original.png</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://freedom.press/news/riaa-github-youtube-dl-journalist-tool/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Twitter still hasn&amp;#039;t unlocked the New York Post&amp;#039;s account</title>
<link>https://www.melovedata.com/twitter-still-hasnt-unlocked-the-new-york-posts-account/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.melovedata.com/twitter-still-hasnt-unlocked-the-new-york-posts-account/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;entry-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-columns&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-column&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disclaimer: I’m a registered voter with no party affiliation. I have a personal interest in tracking major news networks such as CNN, Fox News, Breitbart, the New York Times, and other outlets who publish misleading information since 2008. Twitter is a recent example of a large, influential medium that has now subjectively interfered with information flow to the public.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been over 10 days since the famous &lt;a href=&quot;https://nypost.com/2020/10/14/hunter-biden-emails-show-leveraging-connections-with-dad-to-boost-burisma-pay/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;New York Post story&lt;/a&gt; discussing Hunter Biden’s activities with the Ukranian energy firm Burisma. Twitter reacted by locking the New York Post’s Twitter account from any activity, citing they were trying to prevent the spread of hacked information. Twitter CEO Jack Dorsey admits &lt;a href=&quot;https://variety.com/2020/digital/news/twitter-ceo-nypost-block-wrong-hacked-materials-policy-1234807399/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;blocking the story was a mistake&lt;/a&gt; and ended up reallowing the sharing of the story on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Then one must ask, &lt;em&gt;why is the New York Post’s Twitter account still locked?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the decision was reversed, why isn’t the New York Post’s account unlocked? Why isn’t the New York Times account locked due to releasing Trump’s tax returns that were clearly stolen or “hacked”? Especially after the New York Times declined to share their evidence? Here’s a quote from the NYT article where they decline to share:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;wp-block-quote&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“…Alan Garten, a lawyer for the Trump Organization, said that “most, if not all, of the facts appear to be inaccurate” and requested the documents on which they were based. After The Times declined to provide the records, in order to protect its sources…”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;cite&gt;https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2020/09/27/us/donald-trump-taxes.html&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So no records have been released “in order to protect sources”, which isn’t an explanation as to why the actual documents haven’t been published. You can publish tax returns without exposing your sources (for an example, look at &lt;a href=&quot;https://wikileaks.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;all of the WikiLeaks releases&lt;/a&gt; over time). Ironically, by publishing the tax returns, you’ll force the hand of Trump to actually release his returns. Instead, all we have is the NYT claiming to have records that they won’t show and have obtained without permission. &lt;strong&gt;So why is the New York Post account locked and the NYT account not?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A speculation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe the answer lies in Twitter’s rules and policies, which &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.twitter.com/en/rules-and-policies/public-interest&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;give plenty of wiggle room&lt;/a&gt; by utilizing “exceptions” that they alone determine is best for the public interest. Apparently unverified and unreleased tax returns are important for the public interest, but direct evidence of high-ranking US politician’s family member &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/TrumpWarRoom/status/1196831901597806599?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1196831901597806599%7Ctwgr%5Eshare_3%2Ccontainerclick_1&amp;amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.breitbart.com%2Fpolitics%2F2019%2F11%2F19%2Fbackfire-vindman-admits-hunter-biden-seemed-unqualified-for-burisma-role%2F&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;receiving a highly paid position without prior credentials&lt;/a&gt; is not of concern to the American public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe it turns out that Twitter is in fact biased? Considering it’s difficult, if not impossible for a human being to truly be entirely objective, Twitter’s review units are undoubtedly biased themselves since they’re made up of humans. Should there be insights into who makes up the committees that Twitter uses to review posts and their potential biases? Either way, the main question is; why are they subjectively trying to change the flow of information to the American public?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll have to come to your own conclusion on that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;To be transparent, this is my opinion.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any institution (private or public) with the power to influence outcomes of anything at scale, are incentivized to take a side. Since humans make up these institutions, they are inherently biased, no matter how hard they try to be unbiased. The resulting bias from the institution’s parts eventually come through as the bias of the whole institution. It’s inevitable and unavoidable, and this is what we’re seeing on Twitter’s decision to lock the New York Post’s account but not the New York Times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The New York Post should be able to post their own articles without limitation unless other media outlets are restricted as well (such as BuzzFeed news). Unless every single news article is researched by a transparent committee with their justification on blocking/allowing it, one side will always benefit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-column&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp&quot; data-blog-id=&quot;177716820&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;components-placeholder&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_notification wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_processing&quot; role=&quot;status&quot;&gt;Processing…&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_notification wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_success&quot; role=&quot;status&quot;&gt;Success! You're on the list.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_notification wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_error&quot; role=&quot;alert&quot;&gt;Whoops! There was an error and we couldn't process your subscription. Please reload the page and try again.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator is-style-default&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Usually I write about data stuff, but sometimes I write articles like these. Subscribe if you want to get notifications of new articles!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp&quot; data-blog-id=&quot;177716820&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;components-placeholder&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_notification wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_processing&quot; role=&quot;status&quot;&gt;Processing…&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_notification wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_success&quot; role=&quot;status&quot;&gt;Success! You're on the list.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_notification wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_error&quot; role=&quot;alert&quot;&gt;Whoops! There was an error and we couldn't process your subscription. Please reload the page and try again.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;robots-nocontent sd-block sd-social sd-social-icon-text sd-sharing&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Share this:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-block sd-like jetpack-likes-widget-wrapper jetpack-likes-widget-unloaded&quot; id=&quot;like-post-wrapper-177716820-660-5f9733d931027&quot; data-src=&quot;https://widgets.wp.com/likes/#blog_id=177716820&amp;amp;post_id=660&amp;amp;origin=www.melovedata.com&amp;amp;obj_id=177716820-660-5f9733d931027&quot; data-name=&quot;like-post-frame-177716820-660-5f9733d931027&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;likes-widget-placeholder post-likes-widget-placeholder&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;button&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Like&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;loading&quot;&gt;Loading...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;comment-content entry-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[…] Read More […]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;comment-content entry-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[…] &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.melovedata.com/twitter-still-hasnt-unlocked-the-new-york-posts-account/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow ugc&quot;&gt;https://www.melovedata.com/twitter-still-hasnt-unlocked-the-new-york-posts-account/&lt;/a&gt; […]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 18:12:35 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dsaavy</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Twitter still hasn't unlocked the New York Post's account - melovedata</og:title>
<og:description>Then one must ask, why is the New York Post's Twitter account still locked?</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.melovedata.com/twitter-still-hasnt-unlocked-the-new-york-posts-account/</og:url>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.melovedata.com/twitter-still-hasnt-unlocked-the-new-york-posts-account/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Parsing Algorithms</title>
<link>http://dmitrysoshnikov.com/courses/parsing-algorithms/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://dmitrysoshnikov.com/courses/parsing-algorithms/</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;donate-block&quot;&gt;&lt;button name=&quot;submit&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;⭐️&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.paypal.me/dmitrysoshnikov/10USD&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Donate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/button&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Support this project&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;If you like this work and find it useful, consider &lt;span&gt;donating&lt;/span&gt; to support &lt;span&gt;ads-free&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span&gt;high-quality&lt;/span&gt; education.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;course-overview&quot; class=&quot;header-link&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dmitrysoshnikov.com/courses/parsing-algorithms/#course-overview&quot;&gt;Course overview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Parsing&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;syntactic analysis&lt;/strong&gt; is one of the first stages in designing and implementing a &lt;em&gt;compiler&lt;/em&gt;. A well-designed &lt;em&gt;syntax&lt;/em&gt; of your programming language is a big motivation why users would prefer and choose exactly your language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;note&quot;&gt;Follow the &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24898210&quot;&gt;Hacker news thread&lt;/a&gt; for details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://dmitrysoshnikov.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/EoP_logo_small.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The problem with “parsers theory” in classic compiler schools and books is that this theory is often considered as “too advanced”, going right into complicated formal descriptions from the Theory of Computation and formal grammars. As a result students may lose an interest in building a compiler already at parsing stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The opposite problem often seen in describing a parser is a superficial approach describing only manual (usually recursive descent) parsing, leaving the students with issues understanding the actual techniques behind the automated parsers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;I believe this deep dive into the parsing theory should be combined together with a &lt;em&gt;hands-on approach&lt;/em&gt;, which goes in parallel and allows seeing all the learned theoretical material &lt;em&gt;on practice&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;strong&gt;Essentials of Parsing&lt;/strong&gt; (aka &lt;strong&gt;Parsing Algorithms&lt;/strong&gt;) class we dive into different aspects of the parsing theory, describing in detail the &lt;strong&gt;LL&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;LR&lt;/strong&gt; parsers. However at the same time to make the learning process and understanding easy and fun, we build in parallel an &lt;em&gt;automatic parser&lt;/em&gt; for a full programming language, similar to JavaScript or Python, from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After this class not only you will be able to &lt;em&gt;use&lt;/em&gt; a parser generator to build parsers for programming languages, but will also &lt;em&gt;understand&lt;/em&gt; how the parser generators work under the hood themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Implementing a parser for a programing language would also make your practical usage of other programming languages more professional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://dmitrysoshnikov.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/EoP_screen_2_small.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;how-to&quot; class=&quot;header-link&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dmitrysoshnikov.com/courses/parsing-algorithms/#how-to&quot;&gt;How to?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can watch preview lectures, and also enroll to the full course, describing LL and LR parsing algorithms and covering implementation of an automatic parser from scratch, in animated and live-annotated format. See details below what is in the course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; use &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dmitrysoshnikov.education/p/essentials-of-parsing/?product_id=2530589&amp;amp;coupon_code=DS_EOP_LAUNCH&quot;&gt;DS_EOP_LAUNCH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; limited coupon code to get this course with launch-time discount.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h5 id=&quot;who-this-class-is-for&quot; class=&quot;header-link&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dmitrysoshnikov.com/courses/parsing-algorithms/#who-this-class-is-for&quot;&gt;Who this class is for?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This class is for any &lt;strong&gt;curious engineer&lt;/strong&gt;, who would like to gain skills of building complex systems (and building a parser for a programing language is a pretty advanced engineering task!), and obtain a transferable knowledge for building such systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested specifically in compilers, interpreters, and source code transformation tools, then this class is also for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only pre-requisite for this class is &lt;em&gt;basic data structures and algorithms&lt;/em&gt;: trees, lists, traversal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you took or going to take class on &lt;a href=&quot;http://dmitrysoshnikov.com/courses/essentials-of-interpretation/&quot;&gt;Building an Interpreter from scratch&lt;/a&gt;, the parsers class can be a syntax frontend for the interpreter built in that class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;what-is-used-for-implementation&quot; class=&quot;header-link&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dmitrysoshnikov.com/courses/parsing-algorithms/#what-is-used-for-implementation&quot;&gt;What is used for implementation?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we build a language very similar in semantics to JavaScript or Python (the two most popular programming languages today) we use specifically JavaScript — its elegant multi-paradigm structure which combines functional programming, class-based, and prototype-based OOP fits ideal for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many engineers are familiar with JavaScript so it should be easier to start coding right away. To generate the automated parser we use &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@DmitrySoshnikov/syntax-language-agnostic-parser-generator-bd24468d7cfc&quot;&gt;Syntax&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; tool which is a language-agnostic parser generator, and supports plugins for Python, Ruby, C#, PHP, Java, Rust, etc. That is, the implementation of this parser can easily be transferred to any other language of your choice and taste.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; we want our students to actually follow, understand and implement every detail of the parser themselves, instead of just copy-pasting from final solution. The full source code for the language is available in video lectures, showing and guiding how to structure specific modules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;whats-specific-in-this-class&quot; class=&quot;header-link&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dmitrysoshnikov.com/courses/parsing-algorithms/#whats-specific-in-this-class&quot;&gt;What’s specific in this class?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://dmitrysoshnikov.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/EoI-screen-2.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main features of these lectures are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concise and straight to the point.&lt;/strong&gt; Each lecture is self-sufficient, concise, and describes information directly related to the topic, not distracting on unrelated materials or talks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Animated presentation&lt;/strong&gt; combined with &lt;strong&gt;live-editing notes&lt;/strong&gt;. This makes understanding of the topics easier, and shows how (and &lt;em&gt;when&lt;/em&gt; at time) the object structures are connected. Static slides simply don’t work for a complex content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Live coding session&lt;/strong&gt; end-to-end with &lt;strong&gt;assignments&lt;/strong&gt;. The full source code, starting from scratch, and up to the very end is presented in video lectures of the class&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h5 id=&quot;what-is-in-the-course&quot; class=&quot;header-link&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dmitrysoshnikov.com/courses/parsing-algorithms/#what-is-in-the-course&quot;&gt;What is in the course?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The course is divided into &lt;strong&gt;four parts&lt;/strong&gt;, in total of &lt;strong&gt;22 lectures&lt;/strong&gt;, and many &lt;em&gt;sub-topics&lt;/em&gt; in each lecture. Below is the &lt;em&gt;table of contents and curriculum&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://dmitrysoshnikov.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/EoP_screen_1_small.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;part-1-context-free-grammars-and-languages&quot; class=&quot;header-link&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dmitrysoshnikov.com/courses/parsing-algorithms/#part-1-context-free-grammars-and-languages&quot;&gt;Part 1: Context-free grammars and languages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this part we describe different parsing pipelines, talk about formal grammars, derivations, what is ambiguous and unambitious grammar, and start building our programming language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id=&quot;lecture1&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VZ5DJopq5JA&quot;&gt;Lecture 1: Formal grammars, context-free&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VZ5DJopq5JA&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;350&quot; src=&quot;http://dmitrysoshnikov.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/EoP_Lecture_1_cover_small.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Course overview&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parsing pipeline&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tokenizer module&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parser module&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AST: Abstract syntax tree&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hand-written vs. Automatic parsers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recursive descent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LL and LR parsing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Formal grammars&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Terminal, non-terminals and productions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chomsky grammar hierarchy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Context-free grammars&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;lecture2&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lecture 2: Grammar derivations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;350&quot; src=&quot;http://dmitrysoshnikov.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/EoP_Lecture_2_Derivations_cover_small.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;BNF notation (Backus-Naur form)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RegExp notation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tokenizer and Parser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Derivation process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Left-most and Right-most derivations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parse trees&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Depth-first traversal — string on leaves&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ambiguous grammars&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;lecture3&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lecture 3: Ambiguous grammars&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;350&quot; src=&quot;http://dmitrysoshnikov.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/EoP_Lecture_3_-Ambiguous_Grammars_cover-_small.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Ambiguous grammars&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Left- and Right-associativity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Operator precedence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Left recursion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Non-terminal levels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unambiguous grammars&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;lecture4&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VjvPnpzcJh4&quot;&gt;Lecture 4: Syntax tool | Letter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VjvPnpzcJh4&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;350&quot; src=&quot;http://dmitrysoshnikov.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/EoP_Lecture_4_Syntax_tool_cover_small.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Syntax tool introduction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parser generators&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BNF grammar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Associativity and precedence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LALR(1) parsing mode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Letter programming language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;lecture5&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VKM1eLoN-gI&quot;&gt;Lecture 5: Abstract Syntax Trees&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VKM1eLoN-gI&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;350&quot; src=&quot;http://dmitrysoshnikov.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/EoP_Lecture_5_AST_cover_small.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;CST: Concrete Syntax Tree (aka Parse Tree)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AST: Abstract Syntax Tree&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Semantic actions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inline interpreter for simple DSLs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AST nodes generation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parenthesized expression&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h6 id=&quot;part-2-top-down-ll-parsing&quot; class=&quot;header-link&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dmitrysoshnikov.com/courses/parsing-algorithms/#part-2-top-down-ll-parsing&quot;&gt;Part 2: Top-down LL parsing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this part we talk in detail about Top-down parsing, describing manual recursive and backtracking parser, and also dive into the LL(1) parsing algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id=&quot;lecture6&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IEEU6i_3J8g&quot;&gt;Lecture 6: Backtracking parser&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IEEU6i_3J8g&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;350&quot; src=&quot;http://dmitrysoshnikov.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/EoP_Lecture_6_Backtracking_cover_small.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Top-down parsers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bottom-up parsers aka Shift-Reduce&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Left recursion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recursive descent parser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Backtracking parser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Left factoring&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;lecture7&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lecture 7: Left-recursion and Left-factoring&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;350&quot; src=&quot;http://dmitrysoshnikov.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/EoP_Lecture_7_LeftRec_LeftFactor_cover_small.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Common prefix rules&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why backtracking is slow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Left-factoring&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Left-recursion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Indirect recursion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;lecture8&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lecture 8: Predictive Recursive descent parser&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;350&quot; src=&quot;http://dmitrysoshnikov.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/EoP_Lecture_8_Recursive_descent_parser_cover_small.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Predictive parsing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Concept of Lookahead tokens&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recursive descent parser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First &amp;amp; Follow sets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;lecture9&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lecture 9: LL(1) parsing: First &amp;amp; Follow sets&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;350&quot; src=&quot;http://dmitrysoshnikov.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/EoP_Lecture_9_First_Follow_Sets_cover_small.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Predictive parsing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Concept of Lookahead tokens&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Structure of the LL(1) parser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First set calculation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Follow set calculation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Syntax tool example&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;lecture10&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lecture 10: Construction of LL(1) parsing table&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;350&quot; src=&quot;http://dmitrysoshnikov.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/Lecture_10_LL1_Parsing_Table_cover_small.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Lookahead tokens&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Structure of LL(1) parser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First &amp;amp; Follow sets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LL(1) parsing table&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Predict set&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LL(1) conflicts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;lecture11&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9evmTyJSNms&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lecture 11: LL(1) parsing algorithm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9evmTyJSNms&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;350&quot; src=&quot;http://dmitrysoshnikov.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/Lecture_11_LL1_Parser_cove_small.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Structure of LL(1) parser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LL(1) parsing table&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parsing stack (Push-down automata)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Left-most derivation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Abstract algorithm of the LL(1) parser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h6 id=&quot;part-3-bottom-up-lr-parsing&quot; class=&quot;header-link&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dmitrysoshnikov.com/courses/parsing-algorithms/#part-3-bottom-up-lr-parsing&quot;&gt;Part 3: Bottom-up LR parsing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this part we describe Bottom-up parsers and LR parsing algorithm. In parallel we continue building our programming language, analyzing shift-reduce conflicts and fixing them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id=&quot;lecture12&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lecture 12: Back to practice: Statements | Blocks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;350&quot; src=&quot;http://dmitrysoshnikov.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/Lecture_12_Statements_and_Blocks_cover_small.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Module include: reusing helper functions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AST formats: explicit and S-expression format&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Statements and Statement lists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Program: main entry point&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blocks: groups of statements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;lecture13&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lecture 13: Function Declarations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;350&quot; src=&quot;http://dmitrysoshnikov.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/Lecture_13_Functions_If_Shift-Reduce-cover_small.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Optional statements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Empty blocks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Function declarations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If-else statements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shift-reduce conflict example&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;lecture14&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lecture 14: LR parsing: Canonical Collection of LR-items&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;350&quot; src=&quot;http://dmitrysoshnikov.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/EoP_Lecture_14_LR_Parsing_Canonical_Collection_cover_small.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;LR-parser structure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Canonical Collection of LR-items&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LR-items&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Closure &amp;amp; Goto operations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DFA: Deterministic Finite Automata (State Machine)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PDA: Push-Down Automata&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;lecture15&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lecture 15: LR parsing table: LR(0) and SLR(1)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;350&quot; src=&quot;http://dmitrysoshnikov.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/EoP_Lecture_15_LR_Parsing_table_cover_small.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;LR parsing table&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Action &amp;amp; Goto&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LR(0) parsing mode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SLR(1) parsing mode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shift/Reduce conflicts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduce/Reduce conflicts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;lecture16&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lecture 16: CLR(1) and LALR(1) parsing tables&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;350&quot; src=&quot;http://dmitrysoshnikov.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/EoP_Lecture_16_CLR_LALR_cover_small.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;LR(0) vs. LR(1) items&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lookahead sets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CLR(1) parsing table&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LALR(1) parsing table&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comparison of parsers: LL and LR&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;lecture17&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lecture 17: LR(1) parsing algorithm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;350&quot; src=&quot;http://dmitrysoshnikov.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/EoP_Lecture_17_LR_Parser_cover_small.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;LR(1) parsing process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shift-reduce algorithm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RHS handles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parsing stack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Abstract LR algorithm description&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h6 id=&quot;part-4-practice-and-final-parser&quot; class=&quot;header-link&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dmitrysoshnikov.com/courses/parsing-algorithms/#part-4-practice-and-final-parser&quot;&gt;Part 4: Practice and final parser&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final part of the course is completely practical, we’re finishing our Letter programming language, building variables, functions, cycles, control structures, object-oriented programming, and the final parser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id=&quot;lecture18&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lecture 18: Control structures: If-statement&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;350&quot; src=&quot;http://dmitrysoshnikov.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/EoP_Lecture_18_If_Else_precedence_cover_small.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;If-statement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shift-Reduce conflict&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Relational expression&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Equality expression&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Boolean literals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;lecture19&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lecture 19: Variables | Assignment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;350&quot; src=&quot;http://dmitrysoshnikov.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/EoP_Lecture_19_Variables_Assignment_cover_small.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Logical AND expression&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Logical OR expression&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assignment expression&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chained assignment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Variable declaration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;lecture20&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lecture 20: Function calls | Unary expression&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;350&quot; src=&quot;http://dmitrysoshnikov.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/EoP_Lecture_20_Function_Calls_Unary_cover_small.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Call expression and Function calls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unary expression&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chained calls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arguments list&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;lecture21&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lecture 21: Member expression | Iteration&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;350&quot; src=&quot;http://dmitrysoshnikov.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/EoP_Lecture_21_Iteration_Member_cover_small.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Member expression&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Property access&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Array indicies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;String literals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Iteration statement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While, Do, For loops&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;lecture22&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lecture 22: OOP | Final parser&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;350&quot; src=&quot;http://dmitrysoshnikov.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/EoP_Lecture_22_OPP_cover_small.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Object-oriented programming&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Class declaration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Super calls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New expression&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parser generation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Final executable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;I hope you’ll enjoy the class, and will be glad to discuss any questions and suggestion in comments.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 16:50:28 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>DmitrySoshnikov</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://dmitrysoshnikov.com/courses/parsing-algorithms/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Parsing Algorithms</og:title>
<og:description></og:description>
<og:image></og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://dmitrysoshnikov.com/courses/parsing-algorithms/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Fastly hires entire Wasmtime team from Mozilla</title>
<link>https://bytecodealliance.org/articles/1-year-update#the-lucet-and-wasmtime-teams-join-forces</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://bytecodealliance.org/articles/1-year-update#the-lucet-and-wasmtime-teams-join-forces</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;We announced the Bytecode Alliance nearly a year ago, and since then it has been… quite a year 😬&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the 2020-ness of this year has slowed us down on some fronts, we’ve also made a lot of progress on others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we’ve adjusted to the new normal, we’re gearing up to accelerate on &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; fronts. But before we do that, we wanted to share some highlights of what we’ve achieved to date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;progress-on-the-nanoprocess-model&quot;&gt;Progress on the nanoprocess model&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our goal is to evolve WebAssembly from a compilation target that you compile monolithic applications &lt;em&gt;to&lt;/em&gt;, to a modular ecosystem that you compose applications &lt;em&gt;from&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we do this, we have a chance to fix many longstanding problems with the way software is developed. For example, we can make it much safer for your application to use dependencies that you didn’t code yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is why the &lt;a href=&quot;https://hacks.mozilla.org/2019/11/announcing-the-bytecode-alliance/&quot;&gt;nanoprocess model&lt;/a&gt; is so important. It’s the paradigm shift necessary to empower developers to defend themselves against these problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are three core pieces of the nanoprocess model that are still in progress:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;WASI, the WebAssembly System Interface&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Module linking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interface types&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can think of WASI as the way that the host and a WebAssembly module talk to each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can think of module linking as the way that two WebAssembly modules talk to each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bytecodealliance.org/articles/img/1-year-update/nanoprocess-wasi-module-linking.png&quot; alt=&quot;On the left, a WebAssembly module and host talking to each other using WASI. On the right, two WebAssembly modules talking to each other using module linking.&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In both of these cases, the two sides are often written in different source languages. This means they might represent values and handles to resources in different ways. Basically, they speak foreign languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interface types are like a foreign-language dictionary that the engine uses to help them communicate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bytecodealliance.org/articles/img/1-year-update/nanoprocess-interface-types.png&quot; alt=&quot;On both sides, the engine helps the two talk to each other using interface types.&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s see where the work on these stands today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: The Bytecode Alliance doesn’t host specifications. While BA members are driving specs mentioned below, they are doing that in collaboration with others in the W3C WebAssembly CG. Bytecode Alliance projects include implementations of these specs.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;wasi-the-webassembly-system-interface&quot;&gt;WASI, the WebAssembly System Interface&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we introduced WASI, we compared it to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/POSIX&quot;&gt;POSIX&lt;/a&gt; and other system interfaces. That was a bit of an oversimplification, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bytecodealliance.org/articles/img/1-year-update/wasi-low-level.png&quot; alt=&quot;A file directory structure on the left, with a protective barrier in the middle containing the operating system kernel, and an application knocking for access on the right&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While WASI does aim to provide a set of standardized modules that provide these low-level system interface operations, we also intend to standardize modules for specialized higher-level host APIs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve made progress on both of these fronts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;low-level-system-interface-level&quot;&gt;Low-level system interface level&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the low-level system interface level, the work has been focused on quality of implementation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the spec side, that has been identifying and addressing problems with cross-platform implementability of the spec. One example of this is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/WebAssembly/WASI/pull/312&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;wasi-socket&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; API (which was &lt;a href=&quot;https://radu-matei.com/blog/towards-sockets-networking-wasi/&quot;&gt;recently prototyped in Wasmtime&lt;/a&gt;). In this case, the conversation has centered on the right way to apply capabilities-based security to the handling of sockets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bytecodealliance.org/articles/img/1-year-update/portability.png&quot; alt=&quot;A .wasm file running across three different operating systems&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the implementation side, we’ve done a lot of work to improve the security and reliability of our implementation. Part of this has been developing robust fuzzing measures (which we describe more below).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another thing we’ve done is factored out the security-critical operations into a dedicated library, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sunfishcode/cap-std&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;cap-std&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a cross-platform library which provides much of the functionality of Rust’s standard library in a capabilities-oriented way. This allows us to fully focus on getting those security-critical foundations right on all platforms. As a next step, we’ll make use of &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;cap-std&lt;/code&gt; in our WASI implementation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;specialized-higher-level-host-apis&quot;&gt;Specialized higher-level host APIs&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the specialized higher-level host APIs, there has been exciting work on proposals for completely new API modules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One great example of this is &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/WebAssembly/wasi-nn&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;wasi-nn&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6O44X76rgIg&quot;&gt;standardized interface for neural networking&lt;/a&gt;. This is useful because trained machine learning models are typically deployed on a variety of different devices with different architectures and operating systems. Using &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;wasi-nn&lt;/code&gt;, the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.wasm&lt;/code&gt; file can do things like describe tensors and execute inference requests in a portable way, regardless of the underlying ISA and OS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re implementing all of these in Wasmtime as they develop. That way, people can try them out and real world usage can inform the specification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;module-linking&quot;&gt;Module linking&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we’re going to have an ecosystem of reusable code, we need a good way to link modules together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now, you can link modules together using host APIs. For example, on the web you can string together a bunch of &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;WebAssembly.instantiate&lt;/code&gt; calls to link a set of modules together. In Wasmtime, you use the &lt;a href=&quot;https://bytecodealliance.github.io/wasmtime/examples-c-linking.html&quot;&gt;linker APIs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there are a few downsides to this imperative style, including the fact that it’s fairly cumbersome, not that fast and requires the host to include some type of garbage or cycle collector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the module linking proposal, linking becomes declarative. This means that it’s much easier to use. It also means that even at compile time, the engine has all of the information about how modules are connected to each other. This opens up lots of potential optimizations and features and removes the possibility of cycles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, we’re focusing on load-time linking, which will enable modules to factor out common library code. And for that, the proposal is pretty much complete. Longer term, we’ll be able to add run-time dynamic linking as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our next step is to finish a prototype implementation, which should be complete within the next few months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;interface-types&quot;&gt;Interface types&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/WebAssembly/interface-types&quot;&gt;Interface Types proposal&lt;/a&gt; is evolving nicely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interface Types can now talk about a rich set of values. The design is also more efficient now, removing the need for an intermediate copy of values in almost all cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what’s left to do in the short term?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Interface Types can talk about values, they can’t yet talk about &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/WebAssembly/interface-types/issues/87&quot;&gt;handles to resources&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/WebAssembly/interface-types/issues/68&quot;&gt;buffers&lt;/a&gt;. Both are important to support WASI and other APIs, because things like files should use handles, and it should be possible to read a file and write directly into a buffer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bytecodealliance.org/articles/img/1-year-update/interface-types.png&quot; alt=&quot;On the left, types that are done, including strings, numbers, references, booleans, enums, objects, and unions. On the right, types left to be done: handles and buffers.&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once those features are in place, Interface Types will have everything it needs to support both WASI and Module Linking, making it possible for them to talk about values and resources in a source-language independent way. So we’ll continue working on the spec in the W3C.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the implementation, we’ve set the stage to execute quickly. We’ve already implemented the new features in Wasm core which Interface Types depend on, such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://bytecodealliance.org/articles/bytecodealliance.org/articles/reference-types-in-wasmtime&quot;&gt;Reference Types&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://bytecodealliance.org/articles/multi-value-all-the-wasm&quot;&gt;multi-value&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bytecodealliance/wasmtime/pull/2263&quot;&gt;multi-memory support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re also working on tools for using Interface Types. Currently, people can use &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rustwasm/wasm-bindgen&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;wasm-bindgen&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to create bindings for JS code. In the coming year, we’ll add direct support for Interface Types to language toolchains, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bytecodealliance/wasm-interface-types&quot;&gt;starting with Rust&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We expect to complete most of this work within the next six months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, for people wanting to get things done today but in a forward compatible way, you can define your interface using &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/WebAssembly/WASI/blob/master/docs/witx.md&quot;&gt;WITX&lt;/a&gt;. You can learn more about how to do this from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LCA9NnH7DxE&quot;&gt;this presentation&lt;/a&gt; by Pat Hickey, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://radu-matei.com/blog/wasm-api-witx/&quot;&gt;this blog post&lt;/a&gt; from Radu Matei.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;supporting-more-languages&quot;&gt;Supporting more languages&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To bring the nanoprocess model to as many people as possible, we need to integrate with as many languages as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;more-languages-compiling-into-the-webassembly-nanoprocess-model&quot;&gt;More languages compiling into the WebAssembly nanoprocess model&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to produce code that uses the nanoprocess model, you need a compiler that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;can target WebAssembly, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;has support for these cutting edge standards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;To help language communities speed up their adoption, we’ve started building out &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bytecodealliance/wasm-tools&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;wasm-tools&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. This is a standard set of tools that other compilers can use to target WebAssembly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are all tools that we use in Wasmtime, so as new WebAssembly features come online, they are supported here. For example, we’ve already started building support for module-linking into these tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tools currently include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bytecodealliance/wasm-tools/tree/main/crates/wasmparser&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;wasmparser&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which is a parser for WebAssembly files. It’s quite cheap because it doesn’t do any extra allocations, and can parse in a streaming fashion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bytecodealliance/wasm-tools/tree/main/crates/wasmprinter&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;wasmprinter&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which translates a .wasm binary format into the .wat text format, which is useful for debugging and testing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bytecodealliance/wasm-tools/tree/main/crates/wat&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;wat&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bytecodealliance/wasm-tools/tree/main/crates/wast&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;wast&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which translate the .wat and .wast text formats into the binary format, which is useful for running tests (since it’s easier to maintain tests in the text format).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bytecodealliance/wasm-tools/tree/main/crates/wasm-smith&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;wasm-smith&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://fitzgeraldnick.com/2020/08/24/writing-a-test-case-generator.html&quot;&gt;test case generator&lt;/a&gt;. It generates pseudo-random Wasm modules, guaranteed to be valid Wasm modules, which we use for fuzzing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;We will be adding more tools over the next year. For example, we will host the language-independent parts of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bytecodealliance/wasm-interface-types&quot;&gt;Rust Interface Types toolkit&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;wasm-tools&lt;/code&gt;, which will make it easier for languages that compile to WebAssembly to start supporting Interface Types. We also plan to collaborate with language communities on integrating these tools as they come online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;more-languages-embedding-webassembly-via-wasmtime&quot;&gt;More languages embedding WebAssembly via Wasmtime&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have a whole WebAssembly application, you can run that directly in a runtime like Wasmtime. But sometimes, you just want to run a little bit of WebAssembly in your project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, you might be writing some Python code, but want to do some intensive computations. Python may be too slow, and native extensions may be too frustrating to use portably, so you could use a WebAssembly module instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wasmtime is enabling this for many languages, through embeddings into the language runtimes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bytecodealliance.org/articles/img/1-year-update/wasmtime-embedding.png&quot; alt=&quot;&amp;quot;Wasmtime in the center, with arrows pointing to logos for all of the languages listed below&amp;quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These languages now have support for running WebAssembly in Wasmtime:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As new nanoprocess features come online, they get added to Wasmtime. We don’t consider feature development complete until the feature is exposed in the language embeddings that we maintain. That means that these languages can run the most cutting-edge WebAssembly modules as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also means that these language communities don’t have to come up with their own ways of doing linking and binding. They can just depend on the WebAssembly standards, which makes everything more interoperable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the last year, we’ve transitioned the embeddings we maintain to use the standard &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/WebAssembly/wasm-c-api&quot;&gt;Wasm C API&lt;/a&gt;, and we’re keeping our Rust embedding API and the C API updated in lock-step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;wins-in-multi-stakeholder-collaboration&quot;&gt;Wins in multi-stakeholder collaboration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve said it before, but building out these foundations is too big a task to tackle alone. That’s why effective multi-stakeholder collaboration is so important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the changes we’ve made over the past year to make that collaboration even better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-new-backend-for-cranelift&quot;&gt;A new backend for Cranelift&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cranelift is the code generator used in many runtimes, including Wasmtime, Lucet, and SpiderMonkey, and other projects like an &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bjorn3/rustc_codegen_cranelift/&quot;&gt;alternative backend for the Rust compiler&lt;/a&gt;. It turns Wasm into machine code. With the new backend, we’ve made it much easier to add support for new ISAs, and to collaborate on improving existing ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cranelift’s previous backend used one intermediate representation (IR) for everything. It also had some obscure abstractions that were hard to work with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new system splits the process into two phases, adding a second IR that is machine specific. This way, each IR can be specialized to its task at-hand. The new system also removes the obscure abstractions (you can learn more about this in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bytecodealliance/wasmtime/issues/1141&quot;&gt;Kill Recipes With Fire 🔥&lt;/a&gt; bug).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also added a new tool called &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bytecodealliance/wasmtime/tree/main/cranelift/peepmatic&quot;&gt;Peepmatic&lt;/a&gt;. With this tool, we can apply peephole optimizations when the code is still portable, before we get to the second IR. And we’re in the process of making Peepmatic even more flexible so that we can apply peephole optimizations in the second phase, too, when the IR is machine specific.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal is that anything that is not a control-flow transformation can go through Peepmatic. With this, we’ll have a lot less one-off, hand-written code in Cranelift, which improves maintainability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also helps with correctness: the DSL Peepmatic uses makes some correctness issues impossible, and is easier to reason about than hand-written code. We also have plans to add verification of our peephole optimizations. This way, we can detect when an optimization isn’t correct for all inputs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To realize the full potential of Peepmatic and the WebAssembly sandbox in general, we’re working with academic researchers. For example, we’re working with &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/johnregehr&quot;&gt;John Regehr&lt;/a&gt; and his student &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jubitaneja&quot;&gt;Jubi Teneja&lt;/a&gt; on adding superoptimizations through integration with &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/google/souper&quot;&gt;Souper&lt;/a&gt;. And we now have promising approach for mitigating side channel attacks in Cranelift thanks to researchers at UCSD and the Helmholz Center for Information Security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;improving-testing-with-fuzzing&quot;&gt;Improving testing with fuzzing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have lots of people from lots of organizations adding new features, you need guardrails in place to make sure they aren’t breaking each other’s functionality in the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One really great way to catch edge case-y bugs is fuzzing. We’ve put substantial effort into building top-notch fuzzing infrastructure. We even &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/google/oss-fuzz/pull/3285&quot;&gt;became the first project&lt;/a&gt; written primarily in Rust to be accepted to Google’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://google.github.io/oss-fuzz/&quot;&gt;OSS-Fuzz&lt;/a&gt; continuous fuzzing service. Since then, OSS-Fuzz has found 80-90 bugs which might not have been found otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what kind of fuzzing do we do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We fuzz WebAssembly execution. As mentioned above, we have the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bytecodealliance/wasm-tools/tree/main/crates/wasm-smith&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;wasm-smith&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; test case generator, which is really good at creating interesting test cases as different inputs for fuzzing. We also do differential fuzzing, comparing results we get &lt;em&gt;with&lt;/em&gt; optimizations and those we get &lt;em&gt;without&lt;/em&gt; optimizations to make sure that we get the same results. And we do Peepmatic-specific fuzzing, plus &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bytecodealliance/wasmtime/tree/main/fuzz/fuzz_targets&quot;&gt;various other configurations&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make sure the calls into the library work, we also fuzz the API. And we &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/google/oss-fuzz/pull/4111&quot;&gt;fuzz wasm-tools&lt;/a&gt; to make sure they can roundtrip everything. If the bytes the fuzzer gives us successfully parse as Wasm with &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;wasmparser&lt;/code&gt;, then we will print them with &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;wasmprinter&lt;/code&gt; to make sure that they successfully print to the text format, and then we’ll make sure that the text parsers can parse the result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Cranelift, we don’t just fuzz at the entry IR level. We also have a second entry point near the end of the pipeline that we can also fuzz at. This makes it a lot easier to hit all of the corner cases of the register allocator algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And to make sure we continue to have top-notch fuzzing, we’ve instituted a new rule: a feature isn’t considered done until you’ve added fuzzing for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;improving-documentation&quot;&gt;Improving documentation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, it’s hard to collaborate on something if you don’t know how it works. To this end, we’ve improved our &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.wasmtime.dev/&quot;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; and examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll be putting more effort into this over the coming year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-lucet-and-wasmtime-teams-join-forces&quot;&gt;The Lucet and Wasmtime teams join forces&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Merging Lucet and Wasmtime has been the plan since we announced the BA. And it’s about to get a lot easier to execute on that plan, since the Wasmtime team is moving to Fastly! 🎉&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bytecodealliance.org/articles/img/1-year-update/merge-day.png&quot; alt=&quot;&amp;quot;Lucet and Wastime high fiving under a Happy Merge Day banner, while engineers party around them&amp;quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does this mean for Bytecode Alliance projects?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mozilla will continue to have a team working on WebAssembly in Firefox, focused exclusively on the needs of web developers. As part of this, they will continue working on the Cranelift code generator, used by many projects including Firefox, Lucet, and Wasmtime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fastly will take on sponsorship for the work on the outside-the-browser projects that were hatched at Mozilla, including Wasmtime and WASI, and we look forward to expanding the scope of that work further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a testament to the collaborative, multi-stakeholder setup of the Bytecode Alliance. It doesn’t matter where we work—we’re still working together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;bringing-all-of-this-to-users&quot;&gt;Bringing all of this to users&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This process is all great. But it doesn’t mean anything if we don’t get it into the hands of users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some projects that are doing just that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;firefox-shipping-cranelift-for-arm-64-support&quot;&gt;Firefox shipping Cranelift for Arm 64 support&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firefox’s WebAssembly support on x86/x64 has always been best-in-class. However, because of architectural constraints, its performance on Arm wasn’t keeping up. Cranelift was started specifically to get a backend with an architecture that works as well for Arm and other platforms as it does for x86/x64.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is now bearing fruit. Cranelift is now used by default for WebAssembly content in Firefox Nightly on Arm64 platforms, and work is ongoing to use it on x86/x64, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is another way that the Bytecode Alliance helps accelerate the whole ecosystem. By having our WebAssembly experts team up with the CPU architecture experts at Arm and Intel, we’ve been able to reach better designs that help us move faster and get better results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;serverless-on-fastlys-edge-powered-by-lucet&quot;&gt;Serverless on Fastly’s Edge, powered by Lucet&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fastly’s goal has always been to enable developers to move data and applications to the edge. And recently, they’ve made some huge advances towards that goal using WebAssembly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They were one of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/291584445&quot;&gt;first companies to see WebAssembly’s potential&lt;/a&gt; on the server-side. They’ve since developed that into a serverless compute environment with startup times 100x faster than other alternatives, called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fastly.com/products/edge-compute/serverless&quot;&gt;Compute@Edge&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;shopify&quot;&gt;Shopify&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shopify powers over one million different merchants globally. And these customers all have different needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To keep the codebase and user experience simple, Shopify has a product principle: Build what most merchants need, most of the time. If merchants need features beyond that core set, Shopify provides an App Store with third party apps to solve for that long tail of requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of those apps are hosted on their own infrastructure, and during flash sale events are sometimes taken down by the surge in load. To help app developers build more stable apps, Shopify wants to allow app code to run internally right within Shopify.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how can you run this third-party code in a fast and safe way? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=h4bWS1Mmnaw&quot;&gt;By using WebAssembly&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With their new platform, built on top of Lucet, they’ve been able to run a flash sale with 120,000 WebAssembly modules spinning up and executing in a 60 second flash sale window, while maintaining a runtime performance of under 10 ms per module.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;extending-wasmtime-for-specific-use-cases&quot;&gt;Extending Wasmtime for specific use cases&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Wasmtime is a great general purpose WebAssembly runtime, sometimes you want something that is tailored to your use case. A number of developers are building more complex purpose-built runtimes on top of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These runtimes will help developers get their products into users’ hands faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/enarx/enarx/wiki/Enarx-Introduction&quot;&gt;Enarx&lt;/a&gt; is a Trusted Execution Environment. It keeps your data completely confidential, even from the hardware it’s running on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/deislabs/krustlet&quot;&gt;Krustlet&lt;/a&gt; is a tool to run WebAssembly workloads natively on Kubernetes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wascc.dev/&quot;&gt;WaSCC&lt;/a&gt; implements an actor framework for connecting to cloud-native services, such as message brokers and databases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-next&quot;&gt;What’s next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what will we be focusing on next?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;more-members&quot;&gt;More members&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One big focus is formalizing the governance model so we can bring on new members. There are some fantastic prospective members doing critical work in the ecosystem who we’d love to bring on. To do so, we need to define processes for things like how elections are held and important technical decisions are made. And we need to put all that into bylaws, so our partners know what they’re signing up for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year’s crises have distracted from that work, but after adjusting to the new normal, we’ve made good progress. At this point, we’re just working on the finishing touches. Once these are in place, we’ll be able to accept new members and work on scaling the organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;an-mvp-of-the-nanoprocess-model&quot;&gt;An MVP of the nanoprocess model&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we mentioned above, both the Module Linking proposal and Interface Types proposals are coming along nicely. We’ll be focused on getting those proposals to an MVP, and implementing support in runtimes and toolchains. We expect to have much of this work done in the first half of 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;better-language-support&quot;&gt;Better language support&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the MVP for Interface Types is in place, we’ll be able to start working with language communities to map their language’s types to Interface Types. This way, we’ll be able to have maximum interoperability between modules written in different languages, and easily run these modules in WebAssembly hosts with WASI support.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 16:06:33 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>swyx</dc:creator>
<og:title>Bytecode Alliance: One year update</og:title>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://bytecodealliance.org/articles/1-year-update</og:url>
<og:image>https://bytecodealliance.org/articles/img/1-year-update/wasmtime-embedding.png</og:image>
<og:description>We announced the Bytecode Alliance nearly a year ago, and since then it has been… quite a year 😬</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://bytecodealliance.org/articles/1-year-update</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>25 Years In Speech Technology and I still don’t talk to my computer</title>
<link>https://matthewkaras.medium.com/25-years-in-speech-technology-d5f9dfd98429</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://matthewkaras.medium.com/25-years-in-speech-technology-d5f9dfd98429</guid>
<description>&lt;div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;fe&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;n cd ff fg fh&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;o n&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ab fi fj&quot;&gt;

&lt;img alt=&quot;Matthew Karas&quot; class=&quot;w fp fj fi&quot; src=&quot;https://miro.medium.com/fit/c/56/56/0*hOe4fXRhHWn5BPP4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;28&quot; height=&quot;28&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;ede7&quot; class=&quot;ge gf ei gg b gh gi gj gk gl gm gn go gp gq gr gs gt gu gv gw gx dc dh&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;gg cp&quot;&gt;…and I still don’t talk to my computer.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;be4f&quot; class=&quot;ge gf ei gg b gh gy gi gj gk gz gl gm gn ha go gp gq hb gr gs gt hc gu gv gx dc dh&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;hd&quot;&gt;These are personal reflections and observations, some of which might seem opinionated or simply be mistaken. Feel free to comment, I probably won’t be offended.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;9ac1&quot; class=&quot;ge gf ei gg b gh gy gi gj gk gz gl gm gn ha go gp gq hb gr gs gt hc gu gv gx dc dh&quot;&gt;While I was a post-grad at Cambridge in 1994, I was taught by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Steve_Young_(academic)&quot; class=&quot;dk he&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;Steve &lt;span id=&quot;rmm&quot;/&gt;Young&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tony_Robinson_(speech_recognition)&quot; class=&quot;dk he&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;Tony Robinson&lt;/a&gt;, who had created some of the best speech recognition systems in the world. However, the most important thing I learned in my first few days, was something I would never have guessed from seeing early versions of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DragonDictate#Original_DragonDictate&quot; class=&quot;dk he&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;DragonDictate&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strong class=&quot;gg cp&quot;&gt;They had already cracked it&lt;/strong&gt;. A modestly powerful computer could convert continuous natural speech into text, as it was being spoken, with about 95% accuracy, i.e. the technology was already better than all but the best-trained professionals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;df37&quot; class=&quot;ge gf ei gg b gh gy gi gj gk gz gl gm gn ha go gp gq hb gr gs gt hc gu gv gx dc dh&quot;&gt;Why has it taken until the last few years for speech recognition to be adopted in day-to-day use? The technology has many hidden industrial applications, but as a real-time user interface for day-to-day use, i.e. talking to your computer, adoption has been unbelievably slow. When I was studying in the 90s, I read about a sort of reverse Turing test, which demonstrated one reason why. Volunteers believed they were talking to a computer, but responses were actually provided by a human being typing “behind the curtain”. The observations and subsequent interviews showed that, &lt;strong class=&quot;gg cp&quot;&gt;back then, people simply didn’t like it&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;49ef&quot; class=&quot;ge gf ei gg b gh gy gi gj gk gz gl gm gn ha go gp gq hb gr gs gt hc gu gv gx dc dh&quot;&gt;So, what’s the problem?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;d98d&quot; class=&quot;ge gf ei gg b gh gy gi gj gk gz gl gm gn ha go gp gq hb gr gs gt hc gu gv gx dc dh&quot;&gt;I’m sure that in part, it is just unfamiliarity, and so there is a generational effect. My kids talk to computers more than I do. However, there really are serious problems with speech as a primary user interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;li id=&quot;02c0&quot; class=&quot;ge gf ei gg b gh gy gi gj gk gz gl gm gn ha go gp gq hb gr gs gt hc gu gv gx hf hg hh dh&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;gg cp&quot;&gt;Privacy:&lt;/strong&gt; do you want others to hear your search terms and messages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;b6aa&quot; class=&quot;ge gf ei gg b gh hi gi gj gk hj gl gm gn hk go gp gq hl gr gs gt hm gu gv gx hf hg hh dh&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;gg cp&quot;&gt;Immature tech:&lt;/strong&gt; it isn’t quite there yet - go into a crowded coffee shop and say “Hey Siri …”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;7e03&quot; class=&quot;ge gf ei gg b gh hi gi gj gk hj gl gm gn hk go gp gq hl gr gs gt hm gu gv gx hf hg hh dh&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;gg cp&quot;&gt;Time-based:&lt;/strong&gt; you can’t scan for the good bits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p id=&quot;74ac&quot; class=&quot;ge gf ei gg b gh gy gi gj gk gz gl gm gn ha go gp gq hb gr gs gt hc gu gv gx dc dh&quot;&gt;However, when I left college, to work in the real world, I learned a couple things from working with speech recognition, which (luckily for me) were not obvious to all those people demonstrating and discussing speech recognition, who were still focusing on dictation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;a5bc&quot; class=&quot;ge gf ei gg b gh gy gi gj gk gz gl gm gn ha go gp gq hb gr gs gt hc gu gv gx dc dh&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;gg cp&quot;&gt;Lesson 1: speech recognition isn’t for dictation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;d17c&quot; class=&quot;ge gf ei gg b gh gy gi gj gk gz gl gm gn ha go gp gq hb gr gs gt hc gu gv gx dc dh&quot;&gt;I fell into a career, developing scalable digital media products. Among other things, I led the development of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BBC_News_Online&quot; class=&quot;dk he&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;BBC News Online&lt;/a&gt;. Then in 2000, I made a decision to apply my knowledge of speech technology, to solve problems in the media industry, and also to respect my presentiment that people still didn’t like talking to computers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;969b&quot; class=&quot;ge gf ei gg b gh gy gi gj gk gz gl gm gn ha go gp gq hb gr gs gt hc gu gv gx dc dh&quot;&gt;So, with funding from a big software company, I developed some products which revolved around applying speech recognition to recorded speech. This was surprisingly easy, because another company in the same group was SoftSound, founded by my old teacher from Cambridge, Tony Robinson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;7bfa&quot; class=&quot;ge gf ei gg b gh gy gi gj gk gz gl gm gn ha go gp gq hb gr gs gt hc gu gv gx dc dh&quot;&gt;I had been particularly interested in Tony’s lectures, and jumped at the chance of working with him on product development. He had succeeded in competing with the world’s best systems, but using much less memory and processing power, by using &lt;strong class=&quot;gg cp&quot;&gt;neural networks&lt;/strong&gt;. In that sense, we were decades ahead of the crowd, most of whom moved towards neural nets in the mid-2010s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;6a66&quot; class=&quot;ge gf ei gg b gh gy gi gj gk gz gl gm gn ha go gp gq hb gr gs gt hc gu gv gx dc dh&quot;&gt;My team took SoftSound’s speech recognition algorithms, and devised ways to combine them with video, text and image recognition, to create search engines for TV, film and radio archives. We created all kinds of cool things, like editing software allowing a video to be edited just by cutting and pasting the script. This was a little too far ahead of its time to be a hot seller, but we won some awards and got a lot of good press.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;7408&quot; class=&quot;ge gf ei gg b gh gy gi gj gk gz gl gm gn ha go gp gq hb gr gs gt hc gu gv gx dc dh&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;gg cp&quot;&gt;Lesson 2: people are easily put off&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;98ac&quot; class=&quot;ge gf ei gg b gh gy gi gj gk gz gl gm gn ha go gp gq hb gr gs gt hc gu gv gx dc dh&quot;&gt;Seeing people use our speech-based search engines was a revelation. It taught me that people love to spot mistakes, and use them as a reason to dismiss even the most obviously useful of innovations. This was a similar phenomenon to the YouTube clips of Scottish people talking to early versions of Siri.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;5480&quot; class=&quot;ge gf ei gg b gh gy gi gj gk gz gl gm gn ha go gp gq hb gr gs gt hc gu gv gx dc dh&quot;&gt;The TV archives we worked on had all kinds of background noise and music, and recognition accuracy fell from the laboratory rate of 95% to about 65–70%. Interestingly, this still allowed the search engine to find the right clips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;a36b&quot; class=&quot;ge gf ei gg b gh gy gi gj gk gz gl gm gn ha go gp gq hb gr gs gt hc gu gv gx dc dh&quot;&gt;The problem was that if we showed users the transcripts in the results list, despite the fact that these contained their search terms, their eyes would be drawn to the errors (one or two in almost every line). However, the tech &lt;strong class=&quot;gg cp&quot;&gt;was&lt;/strong&gt; working, and it didn’t take long to come up with a solution: instead of showing the full text, we showed a still image from each clip and a list of the matching words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;41b0&quot; class=&quot;ge gf ei gg b gh gy gi gj gk gz gl gm gn ha go gp gq hb gr gs gt hc gu gv gx dc dh&quot;&gt;Instead of scoffing, &lt;strong class=&quot;gg cp&quot;&gt;it suddenly seemed like magic&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;b76d&quot; class=&quot;ge gf ei gg b gh gy gi gj gk gz gl gm gn ha go gp gq hb gr gs gt hc gu gv gx dc dh&quot;&gt;For me, it was a great use of the technology, compared to the dictation packages seen at every trade show. It was genuinely useful, and it didn’t rely on changing anyone’s behaviour too much. It extended what was becoming a ubiquitous human skill — searching for stuff by typing keywords — and applied it to even more stuff: videos as well as web-pages. Our standard demo involved searching for a key word within hundreds of hours of video, and hitting &lt;em class=&quot;hd&quot;&gt;next&lt;/em&gt; over and over again, seeing the video jump to another and another and another person saying the entered word in different contexts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;b918&quot; class=&quot;ge gf ei gg b gh gy gi gj gk gz gl gm gn ha go gp gq hb gr gs gt hc gu gv gx dc dh&quot;&gt;Now, to give Nuance, and DragonDictate credit: by the late 1990s, they had created Dragon NaturallySpeaking, which no longer required the user to speak with gaps between the words, and quite soon after, they were selling their technology, like us, as a toolkit to integrate into any application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;21a7&quot; class=&quot;ge gf ei gg b gh gy gi gj gk gz gl gm gn ha go gp gq hb gr gs gt hc gu gv gx dc dh&quot;&gt;Also, despite not being of interest to me, there were of course, all sorts of people who used speech recognition for dictation — professionals for whom dictation was already the norm, and a wide variety of people for whom keyboards are difficult to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;e336&quot; class=&quot;ge gf ei gg b gh gy gi gj gk gz gl gm gn ha go gp gq hb gr gs gt hc gu gv gx dc dh&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;gg cp&quot;&gt;This time next year, we’ll be millionaires&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;d988&quot; class=&quot;ge gf ei gg b gh gy gi gj gk gz gl gm gn ha go gp gq hb gr gs gt hc gu gv gx dc dh&quot;&gt;Whether at SoftSound, Entropic or Nuance, from the mid-1990s on, we used to joke year after year after year, that “&lt;strong class=&quot;gg cp&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;hd&quot;&gt;Next year will be the big year for speech recognition”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Somehow that has finally crept up on us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;b27a&quot; class=&quot;ge gf ei gg b gh gy gi gj gk gz gl gm gn ha go gp gq hb gr gs gt hc gu gv gx dc dh&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;gg cp&quot;&gt;Siri, Alexa et al&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;ceb0&quot; class=&quot;ge gf ei gg b gh gy gi gj gk gz gl gm gn ha go gp gq hb gr gs gt hc gu gv gx dc dh&quot;&gt;The lessons I learned building real-world applications, are pertinent to the behaviour I have seen in the last few years. Many people still don’t like talking to Siri when they have enough fingers free to type instead. However, just like our success in extending search into new media types, Siri and its cohort have succeeded in extending search into new situations: driving, cooking, bathing the kids etc:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;1474&quot; class=&quot;ge gf ei gg b gh gy gi gj gk gz gl gm gn ha go gp gq hb gr gs gt hc gu gv gx dc dh&quot;&gt;“OK Google … petrol station”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;dabe&quot; class=&quot;ge gf ei gg b gh gy gi gj gk gz gl gm gn ha go gp gq hb gr gs gt hc gu gv gx dc dh&quot;&gt;“Siri, how long should I roast a 2.4 kilo chicken”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;f79d&quot; class=&quot;ge gf ei gg b gh gy gi gj gk gz gl gm gn ha go gp gq hb gr gs gt hc gu gv gx dc dh&quot;&gt;“Alexa, play The Gruffalo on Audible”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;d9f0&quot; class=&quot;ge gf ei gg b gh gy gi gj gk gz gl gm gn ha go gp gq hb gr gs gt hc gu gv gx dc dh&quot;&gt;That said, it is a full ten years on from the launch of Siri, and it is still not that easy to reroute a map, or to correct Alexa quickly, when Audible starts reading “50 Shades” to your kids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;8a5b&quot; class=&quot;ge gf ei gg b gh gy gi gj gk gz gl gm gn ha go gp gq hb gr gs gt hc gu gv gx dc dh&quot;&gt;Audio feedback doesn’t give the user the same reassuring sense of certainty as a graphical user interface. One glance will confirm that I have typed my card number correctly, but you don’t have to be unusually impatient for your heart to sink, when you hear the inhumanly calm words, “I heard 4659 1234 1234 1234. Is that correct? Say yes or press one to confirm”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;7328&quot; class=&quot;ge gf ei gg b gh gy gi gj gk gz gl gm gn ha go gp gq hb gr gs gt hc gu gv gx dc dh&quot;&gt;And as for errors, as well as Scottish accented YouTube clips, by 2016, there were much less jokey news stories, making claims that this was inherently racist technology. If Microsoft Office only worked for 90% of people, there would be uproar. Did this mean that speech recognition was just a novelty, rather than real product, empowering business etc?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;83f4&quot; class=&quot;ge gf ei gg b gh gy gi gj gk gz gl gm gn ha go gp gq hb gr gs gt hc gu gv gx dc dh&quot;&gt;However, neural nets really have come to the rescue, especially for this kind of problem. Having enough of the right training data turns out to be much more important than knowledge of the phonetic differences between accents — the network will work out what those differences are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;3796&quot; class=&quot;ge gf ei gg b gh gy gi gj gk gz gl gm gn ha go gp gq hb gr gs gt hc gu gv gx dc dh&quot;&gt;Even five years ago, we needed to train systems for each regional accent, but nowadays, Siri copes with Scottish accents, just by training its networks on Scottish people reading known texts, i.e. teaching the networks the various ways in which a word can be pronounced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;2bf1&quot; class=&quot;ge gf ei gg b gh gy gi gj gk gz gl gm gn ha go gp gq hb gr gs gt hc gu gv gx dc dh&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;gg cp&quot;&gt;So, will speech replace keyboards and screens? Wrong question.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;61c7&quot; class=&quot;ge gf ei gg b gh gy gi gj gk gz gl gm gn ha go gp gq hb gr gs gt hc gu gv gx dc dh&quot;&gt;Computers have made multi-taskers of us all, and sometimes I think that, as an interface, even for interpersonal communications, speech can sometimes set us back: &lt;strong class=&quot;gg cp&quot;&gt;I can be in several text chats at once, but I can’t be on two voice calls.&lt;/strong&gt; Text and screen interactions have some real advantages, with which speech shouldn’t even try to compete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;f6fa&quot; class=&quot;ge gf ei gg b gh gy gi gj gk gz gl gm gn ha go gp gq hb gr gs gt hc gu gv gx dc dh&quot;&gt;However, for speech technology to reach the potential of what it, uniquely, can do well, it still has much further to go. This is good news for the industry, as more and more startups are funded to solve real-world problems, not dealt with by the big players.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;8db2&quot; class=&quot;ge gf ei gg b gh gy gi gj gk gz gl gm gn ha go gp gq hb gr gs gt hc gu gv gx dc dh&quot;&gt;Technology has to get as good at listening, and at speaking, as human beings are, and then — in some contexts — get better than we are. Here are a few examples from projects, which I and others have been working on lately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;6d74&quot; class=&quot;ge gf ei gg b gh gy gi gj gk gz gl gm gn ha go gp gq hb gr gs gt hc gu gv gx dc dh&quot;&gt;Away from our headsets, speech isn’t really as linear as I have made out. In close proximity to someone speaking, I might whisper a comment to another listener, and still go unheard by anyone else. At a dinner party, I might be involved in more than one conversation at a time, because it is easy, in the 3D space of the real-world, to keep track of who has said what, and to control the volume and direction of my speech to target a specific listener.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;0178&quot; class=&quot;ge gf ei gg b gh gy gi gj gk gz gl gm gn ha go gp gq hb gr gs gt hc gu gv gx dc dh&quot;&gt;Technology to separate speech from different speakers is coming on in leaps and bounds. This is achieved both by analysing the speech more deeply, and by combining the audio data with other sources, like using multiple microphones to measure relative volume and direction, or by using input from cameras to add lip movements and facial expressions to the mix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;12cc&quot; class=&quot;ge gf ei gg b gh gy gi gj gk gz gl gm gn ha go gp gq hb gr gs gt hc gu gv gx dc dh&quot;&gt;In 2016, Google came up with a new approach to speech synthesis, using WaveNet, a neural network, which can be trained to generate almost any kind of sound, and then training it with real human speech. Once trained, it can be fed with quite robotic synthesized speech, and then make it sound human.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;d657&quot; class=&quot;ge gf ei gg b gh gy gi gj gk gz gl gm gn ha go gp gq hb gr gs gt hc gu gv gx dc dh&quot;&gt;Nowadays, the latest developments are routinely shared, and the whole industry takes the latest ideas from Google, NVIDIA, Microsoft and a global community of university researchers, and with their blessing, extends them and applies them in new contexts, adding expertise from their own niche professions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;740b&quot; class=&quot;ge gf ei gg b gh gy gi gj gk gz gl gm gn ha go gp gq hb gr gs gt hc gu gv gx dc dh&quot;&gt;I have spent a lot of time working on systems which analyse accents, mispronunciations and speech impediments. Some people are difficult to understand because they have an unfamiliar accent, or are only just learning a language. We can make it easier to master pronunciation by giving them real-time feedback, but maybe we needn’t bother: morphing accents, and correcting errors in real time are both becoming a reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;4761&quot; class=&quot;ge gf ei gg b gh gy gi gj gk gz gl gm gn ha go gp gq hb gr gs gt hc gu gv gx dc dh&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;gg cp&quot;&gt;Speech recognition saves the human race!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;d899&quot; class=&quot;ge gf ei gg b gh gy gi gj gk gz gl gm gn ha go gp gq hb gr gs gt hc gu gv gx dc dh&quot;&gt;Speech does not only vary by accent, but also by emotional and physical state. When a condition makes someone unintelligible, it is feasible not only to improve intelligibility but to identify what is wrong, perhaps categorising emergency calls, where the speaker is affected by stroke, sedation, drunkenness, concussion, or merely identify that the caller is a child, or speaks a particular language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;d02d&quot; class=&quot;ge gf ei gg b gh gy gi gj gk gz gl gm gn ha go gp gq hb gr gs gt hc gu gv gx dc dh&quot;&gt;Finally, early identification of certain serious long-term neurological conditions is possible by monitoring subtle changes to speech. This can be done without hospital visits or even without targeting those who are at risk. Conveniently for all concerned, we all speak into our phones and computers all the time, so it would only be necessary to opt in, and give permission for your voice to be analysed, without compromising confidentiality by being recorded or listened to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;51f0&quot; class=&quot;ge gf ei gg b gh gy gi gj gk gz gl gm gn ha go gp gq hb gr gs gt hc gu gv gx dc dh&quot;&gt;With the right training data, perhaps the same technology could be trained to recognise whether your cough, is in fact a &lt;strong class=&quot;gg cp&quot;&gt;new persistent dry cough&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 15:34:03 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>samizdis</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>25 Years In Speech Technology</og:title>
<og:description>…and I still don’t talk to my computer.</og:description>
<og:url>https://matthewkaras.medium.com/25-years-in-speech-technology-d5f9dfd98429</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://matthewkaras.medium.com/25-years-in-speech-technology-d5f9dfd98429</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Surviving Disillusionment</title>
<link>https://www.spakhm.com/p/surviving-disillusionment</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.spakhm.com/p/surviving-disillusionment</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;In the past few weeks I wrote about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.spakhm.com/p/how-to-get-promoted&quot;&gt;corporate politics&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.spakhm.com/p/parallel-tracks&quot;&gt;distribution of power&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.spakhm.com/p/an-open-letter-to-my-friends-with&quot;&gt;disregard for ethics&lt;/a&gt;. Dozens of people reached out to say the posts were dark, cynical and depressingly accurate. There are more dark posts I can write— about lies in venture capital, the devastating price of failure, the destructive aspect of creative relationships, the ubiquity of envy. But I think I've gotten my point across. The industry can be depressing. I now want to concentrate on a different question: what to do with this knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word &quot;possession&quot; means owning things, but it also means things owning you. Knowledge can possess people. Once you observe the darker side of human nature in the technology industry, you cannot forget or unsee it. The subsequent cynicism can be so disheartening that the romance of the computer revolution is beat out of people completely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've met many engineers with extraordinary talent who decided to stop making software. They wanted to program computers all their lives. They were born for it. After spending six, eight, ten years in the industry, they quit for good. Now they're running breweries and hydroponic farms, with no desire to ever again touch a compiler, let alone get back into the fray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is nothing wrong with brewing beer or growing hydroponic tomatoes. What's sad is that people weren't pulled into their new occupation by better financial opportunities or conviction; instead they were pushed away from technology. If brewing paid as much as programming, it still wouldn't have been their first choice. Something had to have gone wrong for them to abandon their first love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/35ATS95&quot;&gt;Zen Mind, Beginner's Mind&lt;/a&gt;, Shunryu Suzuki says:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For us, the monastic life was the usual life, and the people who came from the city were unusual people. When we saw them we felt, “Oh, some unusual people have come!” But once I had left Eiheiji and been away for some time, coming back was different. I heard the various sounds of practice—the bells and the monks reciting the sutra—and I had a deep feeling. There were tears flowing out of my eyes, nose, and mouth! It is the people who are outside of the monastery who feel its atmosphere. Those who are practicing actually do not feel anything. I think this is true for everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still remember the feeling when I first glanced inside the monastery. My parents bought me a ZX Spectrum computer connected to an old Soviet TV and cassette player, a few bootleg games, and a Z80 assembly manual printed on a dot matrix printer that was out of ink; about one tenth of the text was unreadable. I spent countless hours playing games, learning BASIC and Z80 assembly, and deciphering the missing parts of the manual. I don't remember much else from that time. That little machine was a window into a different world— limitless, safe, and totally engaging. At the time, nothing else mattered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;image-link image2 image2-455-656&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F0cece565-e603-408e-bf0b-929ca8460009_1511x1046.jpeg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/w_1456,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F0cece565-e603-408e-bf0b-929ca8460009_1511x1046.jpeg&quot; data-attrs=&quot;{&amp;quot;src&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://bucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com/public/images/0cece565-e603-408e-bf0b-929ca8460009_1511x1046.jpeg&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;height&amp;quot;:1008,&amp;quot;width&amp;quot;:1456,&amp;quot;resizeWidth&amp;quot;:656,&amp;quot;bytes&amp;quot;:206242,&amp;quot;alt&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;image/jpeg&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;href&amp;quot;:null}&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My next computer was an IBM machine with an i386 processor, 2MB of RAM (the ZX Spectrum had 16KB), a 30MB hard disk, and a five inch floppy drive. I could load programs in seconds instead of minutes. I could run Dune 2 and Wolfenstein 3D and hex editors and Prince of Persia and MS DOS and Borland Turbo Pascal and Civilization and a C compiler and Windows 3.1. I could save stuff! I remember studying Win16 APIs and feeling like I made contact with an advanced alien civilization. As I type this now, I still have sense memory of that machine. The rubbery smell, the buzzing sound of the CRT monitor, the springy feel of the keyboard (with proper arrow keys and all sorts of extra buttons!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then my friend's parents bought him an i486 machine with 4MB of RAM. It could run Doom. Everything changed again. You didn't even need to play to know that computer history was just delineated into before and after. As soon as you saw the artwork of the game menu, you knew. Doom changed me in a profound way. I used to never think about computers or programming. It was just something I loved to do more than anything else. But a few seconds of Doom gameplay permanently flipped a bit in my brain. It made me aware that programming computers is what I want to be doing for the rest of my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that came the internet, and with it a whirlwind of new worlds. Some were brand new. Others were old, but the internet gave me the opportunity to access them for the first time. Windows 95, newsgroups, geocities, ICQ, Visual Studio, Diablo, Starcraft, 3Dfx Voodoo Banshee, Gamedev.net, IRC, Slashdot, DirectX, Windows NT, Java, OpenGL, NewEgg, Winamp, Napster, Deus Ex, World of Warcraft, Linux, Emacs, GPL, Google, Common Lisp, Standard ML, Smalltalk, the iPhone, Oculus Rift. Each had its own unique atmosphere. Each was a window into a different universe. Each one felt limitless. Safe. Engaging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything, from the first ZX Spectrum to Oculus Rift was punctuated by countless books of science fiction. My dad introduced me to the genre with Jules Verne's The Mysterious Island, in which a team of five end up on an uninhabited island, and use their knowledge and ingenuity to rebuild a technological civilization from scratch. I remember reading this novel over and over, completely enthralled. I tried some of the experiments, with intermittent success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My parents had a few shelves stacked with books, and I spent countless nights losing myself in them. I read everything by Jules Verne I could get my hands on, including From the Earth to the Moon, Twenty Thousand Leagues Under the Sea, Around the World in Eighty Days, and Journey to the Center of the Earth. After Verne I moved on to Ray Bradbury (The Veldt), Arkadiy and Boris Strugatsky (Prisoners of Power), Stanislaw Lem (the fantastical Summa Technologiae). I also read every story we had by Jack London— I couldn't imagine anything more exciting than the combination of science fiction and the romance of the American frontier. Today, nearly thirty years later, I still can't.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After we moved to America I learned that there is an enormous universe of science fiction that I missed as a child. I started filling the gaps and read stories and novels by Isaac Asimov, Arthur Clarke, William Gibson, Neal Stephenson, Ian Banks, Philip Dick, Cory Doctorow, Charlie Stross, Dan Simmons, Jack Vance, and Vernor Vinge. I also continued reading Russian science fiction. I read everything by Strugatsky brothers, and binge-read the pulpy Russian spin on the cyberpunk genre by Sergei Lukyanenko.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I grew older I shifted to reading about megaprojects and the intersection of technology and commerce. I read about railroads, electrification, aviation, radio, television, silicon, and the stories of Bell Labs, Microsoft, The Manhattan Project, and The Apollo program. How the heck did we invent all this stuff, wire the planet, speed up transportation by two orders of magnitude, go to space, put a computer on every desk, and then, as if it weren't enough, put a supercomputer in every pocket?! How did we do all &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt;?!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I imagine what would happen if I could send my ten year old self a letter and tell him I could press a button and read &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2TrADJK&quot;&gt;Masters of Doom&lt;/a&gt; the next day, instantly send a short message to John Carmack from &lt;em&gt;anywhere&lt;/em&gt; using an always connected supercomputer in my pocket, or that I worked for a company that published &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2HsSXQm&quot;&gt;The Making of Prince of Persia&lt;/a&gt;. He would have been over the moon!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But sitting at a mandated retrospective or mindlessly gluing APIs together doesn't put me over the moon. It makes me feel the opposite (whatever the opposite of being over the moon is). And so, engineers are faced with two realities. One reality is the atmosphere of new technology, its incredible power to transform the human condition, the joy of the art of doing science and engineering, the trials of the creative process, the romance of the frontier. The other reality is the frustration and drudgery of operating in a world of corporate politics, bureaucracy, envy and greed— a world &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; depressing, that many people quit in frustration, never to come back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you work in technology, the monastery can be distant and vague, whereas Paul from marketing wants to circle back with you here and now. Then, as you circle back again and again, the monastery recedes further into the distance, and the drudgery appears closer and closer, until it occupies your entire field of vision and you can't see anything else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have friends in the medical field, and they vent about drudgery and endless bureaucracy &lt;em&gt;all the time&lt;/em&gt;. They have more roadblocks than we do, and theirs are objectively worse than ours. The hours are longer, the bureaucracy is more entrenched, the regulators mandate their time be wasted on bullshit, and mistakes can have devastating consequences. Yet I haven't heard of a single doctor who quit his practice and moved to Colorado to run a ski lodge. When I ask why, they all give the same response: the patients. Every day they see patients brought back to health, the bullshit recedes into the background, and they're reminded why they got into medicine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The default in engineering is different. We don't have a daily ritual built into our jobs that reminds us why we got into the field. Without a ritual, the drudgery creeps closer and the vision of the monastery recedes. So we must be very deliberate in developing rituals to keep the two realities in their proper proportion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the reason many engineers have trouble with this is that so much of our field is about knowledge, but rituals aren't about knowledge at all— they're about practice. You must develop a daily mantra, a spell, a routine, whatever you want to call it, and then perform it religiously. I needed a lot of trial and error to get it right, and I’m still playing with the details. The internet desensitized me to text and video. Anything that happens in front of a screen doesn't help with perspective anymore. But I discovered that getting away from the screen and handling physical items does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't know what will work for you, but here are a few ideas. Read used hard cover books on history of technology every day. The smell, the feel of old paper, the knowledge that someone read the book before you is incredibly powerful for bringing the romance of technology back into the field of vision. Buy the first computer you've ever owned on eBay and keep it on your desk. Read a chapter about the development of your favorite childhood computer game every morning. Buy a vintage bolt action hunting rifle and learn to take it apart and put it back together. Flip through an aerospace coffee table book before bed. Quit working for Google. Buy yourself a scale &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.modelerscentral.com/wooden-model-kits/amati-wooden-model-kits/bleriot-plane/&quot;&gt;wooden model&lt;/a&gt; of a complex technological apparatus and spend half an hour a day putting it together. Pick up an analog oscilloscope on Craigslist, get an Arduino and code a game of Pong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe it’s an emergent property, maybe it’s an accident, maybe it’s by design; it doesn’t matter why, but the industry burns through people. If you leave your love of programming and the feeling of the computer revolution romance on autopilot, the industry will burn through you. It’s your responsibility to know &lt;em&gt;exactly&lt;/em&gt; why you’re doing the specific job you’re doing, what your long-term goal is, how to develop a credible plan to achieve it, and what you need to do (and not to do) to keep your underground spring of creativity alive. Don’t outsource this to anyone else, and don’t neglect it. No one can do that job except you, and the job &lt;em&gt;needs&lt;/em&gt; to get done. Unless you want to spend the rest of your life growing hydroponic tomatoes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR:&lt;/strong&gt; Develop a routine to keep drudgery away and the romance of technology close. Practice it religiously. Physical mechanisms and analog circuitry are better than digital; used hardcovers are better than Kindle. Know your long-term goals. Brewing beer and baking bread are canaries in a coal mine. If you find yourself interested in either of those, quit your job immediately and go to Akihabara for a month.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 14:42:16 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mwcampbell</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Surviving disillusionment</og:title>
<og:description>Engineers don't have a daily ritual that reminds us why we got into the field. Without a ritual, the drudgery creeps closer and the vision of the monastery recedes.</og:description>
<og:image>https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/h_600,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F0cece565-e603-408e-bf0b-929ca8460009_1511x1046.jpeg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.spakhm.com/p/surviving-disillusionment</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>CBP Refuses to Tell Congress How It Is Tracking Americans Without a Warrant</title>
<link>https://www.vice.com/en/article/n7vwex/cbp-dhs-venntel-location-data-no-warrant</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.vice.com/en/article/n7vwex/cbp-dhs-venntel-location-data-no-warrant</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;responsive-image__img&quot; alt=&quot;Location data&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image: Stuart Kinlough/Getty Images&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div data-component=&quot;BodyComponentRenderer&quot; readability=&quot;146.80971288943&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;abc__textblock size--article&quot; data-component=&quot;TextBlock&quot;&gt;U.S. Customs and Border Protection is refusing to tell Congress what legal authority the agency is following to use commercially bought location data to track Americans without a warrant, according to the office of Senator Ron Wyden. The agency is buying location data from Americans all over the country, not just in border areas.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;abc__textblock size--article&quot; data-component=&quot;TextBlock&quot;&gt;The lack of disclosure around why CBP believes it does not need a warrant to use the data, as well as the Department of Homeland Security not publishing a Privacy Impact Assessment on the use of such location information, has spurred Wyden and Senators Elizabeth Warren, Sherrod Brown, Ed Markey, and Brian Schatz on Friday to ask the DHS Office of the Inspector General (DHS OIG) to investigate CBP's warrantless domestic surveillance of phones, and determine if CBP is breaking the law or engaging in abusive practices.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;abc__textblock size--article&quot; data-component=&quot;TextBlock&quot;&gt;The news highlights the increased use of app location data by U.S. government agencies. Various services take location data which is harvested from ordinary apps installed on peoples' phones around the world, repackages that, and sells access to law enforcement agencies so they can try to track groups of people or individuals. In this case, CBP has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en/article/k7qyv3/customs-border-protection-venntel-location-data-dhs&quot;&gt;bought the location data&lt;/a&gt; from a firm called Venntel.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;abc__textblock size--article&quot; data-component=&quot;TextBlock&quot;&gt;&quot;CBP officials confirmed to Senate staff that the agency is using Venntel’s location database to search for information collected from phones in the United States without any kind of court order,&quot; the letter signed by Wyden and Warren, and addressed to the DHS OIG, reads. &quot;CBP outrageously asserted that its legal analysis is privileged and therefore does not have to be shared with Congress. We disagree.&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote data-component=&quot;QuoteBlock&quot; class=&quot;abc__quote abc__quote--blockquote&quot; readability=&quot;12.462427745665&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you work at Venntel, Babel Street, or other company providing location data to the government? Are you a customer of such data? We'd love to hear from you. Using a non-work phone or computer, you can contact Joseph Cox securely on Signal on +44 20 8133 5190, Wickr on josephcox, OTR chat on&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:jfcox@jabber.ccc.de&quot;&gt;jfcox@jabber.ccc.de&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;, or email&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:joseph.cox@vice.com&quot;&gt;joseph.cox@vice.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;abc__textblock size--article&quot; data-component=&quot;TextBlock&quot;&gt;Venntel &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/federal-agencies-use-cellphone-location-data-for-immigration-enforcement-11581078600&quot;&gt;sources its data&lt;/a&gt; from weather, games, e-commerce, and other innocuous apps, whose users may be unaware that their location is being sold to the U.S. government. CBP said that it believes the Venntel data is sourced both from software development kits (SDKs)—small bundles of code placed into apps that collect the location information—and bidstream data, according to a Wyden aide. Bidstream data is information gleaned from the real-time bidding that occurs when online advertisers pay to insert their adverts into peoples' browsing sessions; that data can include location data.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;abc__textblock size--article&quot; data-component=&quot;TextBlock&quot;&gt;As well as not obtaining court orders to query the data, CBP said it's not restricting its personnel to only using it near the border, the Wyden aide added.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;abc__textblock size--article&quot; data-component=&quot;TextBlock&quot;&gt;CBP is unable to tell what nationality a particular person is based only on the information provided by Venntel; but what the agency does know is that the Venntel data the agency is using includes the movements of people inside the United States, the Wyden aide said. This corroborates a document &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en/article/n7wakg/cbp-dhs-location-data-venntel-apps&quot;&gt;previously obtained by Motherboard&lt;/a&gt;, which described the Venntel data CBP purchased as &quot;global.&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;abc__textblock size--article&quot; data-component=&quot;TextBlock&quot;&gt;A former Venntel worker &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en/article/k7qyv3/customs-border-protection-venntel-location-data-dhs&quot;&gt;previously told Motherboard&lt;/a&gt; that customers can use Venntel's tool to search an area for devices, or lookup an identifier assigned to a specific device to then see where else that data has been. The data is pseudonymous, with Venntel assigning its own identifier to each device.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;abc__textblock size--article&quot; data-component=&quot;TextBlock&quot;&gt;&quot;If you search a certain house, you're only going to get three or four different signals out of there. I think from that standpoint, you could definitely try and identify specific people,&quot; the source said. A second source who previously worked with Venntel said that identifying someone would be laborious, though.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;abc__textblock size--article&quot; data-component=&quot;TextBlock&quot;&gt;As &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en/article/k7qyv3/customs-border-protection-venntel-location-data-dhs&quot;&gt;Motherboard reported&lt;/a&gt;, CBP paid Venntel nearly half a million dollars in August, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en/article/n7wakg/cbp-dhs-location-data-venntel-apps&quot;&gt;for Venntel's software&lt;/a&gt; &quot;in support of mission critical decision making by providing access to commercially available, multi-sourced, validated, location marketing data via custom geolocation data research requests.&quot; In a statement at the time, CBP told Motherboard that &quot;Consistent with its border security and law enforcement authorities, CBP has acquired limited access to commercial telemetry data through the procurement of a limited number of licenses to a vendor provided interface.&quot; The Wyden aide added that CBP said it was also using the data for national security threats.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;abc__textblock size--article&quot; data-component=&quot;TextBlock&quot;&gt;CBP said that the legal justification for this surveillance without a warrant is privileged, the Wyden aide said. Wyden's office also asked if CBP had taken a position on whether location data sold by Venntel didn't fall under the Supreme Court ruling of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.supremecourt.gov/opinions/17pdf/16-402_h315.pdf&quot;&gt;Carpenter v United States&lt;/a&gt;, which said that location data requires a warrant; CBP also said that information was privileged, the Wyden aide said.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote data-component=&quot;QuoteBlock&quot; class=&quot;abc__quote abc__quote--pullquote&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;CBP outrageously asserted that its legal analysis is privileged and therefore does not have to be shared with Congress. We disagree.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;abc__textblock size--article&quot; data-component=&quot;TextBlock&quot;&gt;Traditionally, the DHS publishes Privacy Impact Assessments that lay out what a particular type of surveillance technology does, its benefits, and its harms to privacy. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en/article/pky47y/cbp-surveillance-license-plate-reader-vigilant&quot;&gt;Motherboard recently reported&lt;/a&gt; on one such assessment for the deployment of a nationwide vehicle tracking database, also sourced from a commercial vendor. But CBP said the DHS had not published a Privacy Impact Assessment of the use of Venntel location data, the Wyden aide said. It is unclear whether the Office has performed such an assessment even if it is not currently published.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;abc__textblock size--article&quot; data-component=&quot;TextBlock&quot;&gt;&quot;CBP is not above the law and it should not be able to buy its way around the Fourth Amendment. Accordingly, we urge you to investigate CBP’s warrantless use of commercial databases containing Americans’ information, including but not limited to Venntel’s location database. We urge you to examine what legal analysis, if any, CBP’s lawyers performed before the agency started to use this surveillance tool. We also request that you determine how CBP was able to begin operational use of Venntel’s location database without the Department of Homeland Security Privacy Office first publishing a Privacy Impact Assessment,&quot; the Senators' letter continues.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;abc__textblock size--article&quot; data-component=&quot;TextBlock&quot;&gt;The Internal Revenue Service also previously &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en/article/xg8by3/irs-phone-tracking-warrant-wyden-warren&quot;&gt;declined to elaborate&lt;/a&gt; on its legal reasoning for using Venntel's data without a warrant. The Inspector General is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en/article/qj479d/irs-investigation-location-data-no-warrant-venntel&quot;&gt;now formally investigating&lt;/a&gt; the IRS' use of the data.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;abc__textblock size--article&quot; data-component=&quot;TextBlock&quot;&gt;CBP did not immediately respond to a request for comment.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 14:23:57 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>elsewhen</dc:creator>
<og:title>CBP Refuses to Tell Congress How it is Tracking Americans Without a Warrant</og:title>
<og:description>The CBP is buying location data harvested from ordinary apps installed on peoples’ phones.</og:description>
<og:image>https://video-images.vice.com//articles/5f92ec9c2d85a1009c5bc727/lede/1603464646573-screenshot-2020-10-23-at-105030.png?image-resize-opts=Y3JvcD0wLjk4OTAwODU5NzIzNTgyNTV4dzoxeGg7Y2VudGVyLGNlbnRlciZyZXNpemU9MTIwMDoqJnJlc2l6ZT0xMjAwOio</og:image>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.vice.com/en/article/n7vwex/cbp-dhs-venntel-location-data-no-warrant</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.vice.com/en/article/n7vwex/cbp-dhs-venntel-location-data-no-warrant</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>We chose Java for our high-frequency trading application</title>
<link>https://medium.com/@jadsarmo/why-we-chose-java-for-our-high-frequency-trading-application-600f7c04da94</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://medium.com/@jadsarmo/why-we-chose-java-for-our-high-frequency-trading-application-600f7c04da94</guid>
<description>&lt;div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;fe&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;n cd ff fg fh&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;o n&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ab fi fj&quot;&gt;

&lt;img alt=&quot;Jad Sarmo&quot; class=&quot;w fp fj fi&quot; src=&quot;https://miro.medium.com/fit/c/56/56/1*HUWkjAmEoywC7op_QLBCRg.png&quot; width=&quot;28&quot; height=&quot;28&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

Image by Gerd Altmann from Pixabay
&lt;p id=&quot;0205&quot; class=&quot;hc hd ei he b hf hg hh hi hj hk hl hm hn ho hp hq hr hs ht hu hv hw hx hy hz dc dh&quot;&gt;In the world of High-Frequency Trading, automated applications process hundreds of millions of market signals every day and send back thousands of orders on various exchanges around the globe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;69ee&quot; class=&quot;hc hd ei he b hf hg hh hi hj hk hl hm hn ho hp hq hr hs ht hu hv hw hx hy hz dc dh&quot;&gt;In order to remain competitive, the reaction time must consistently remain in microseconds, especially during unusual peaks such as a “black swan” event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;5769&quot; class=&quot;hc hd ei he b hf hg hh hi hj hk hl hm hn ho hp hq hr hs ht hu hv hw hx hy hz dc dh&quot;&gt;In a typical architecture, financial exchange signals will be converted into a single internal market data format (exchanges use various protocols such as TCP/IP, UDP Multicast and multiple formats such as binary, SBE, JSON, FIX, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;07d7&quot; class=&quot;hc hd ei he b hf hg hh hi hj hk hl hm hn ho hp hq hr hs ht hu hv hw hx hy hz dc dh&quot;&gt;Those normal&lt;span id=&quot;rmm&quot;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;sed messages are then sent to algorithmic servers, statistics engines, user interfaces, logs servers, and databases of all kind (in-memory, physical, distributed).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;2654&quot; class=&quot;hc hd ei he b hf hg hh hi hj hk hl hm hn ho hp hq hr hs ht hu hv hw hx hy hz dc dh&quot;&gt;Any latency along that path can have expensive consequences such as a strategy making decisions based on an old price or an order reaching the market too late.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;321d&quot; class=&quot;hc hd ei he b hf hg hh hi hj hk hl hm hn ho hp hq hr hs ht hu hv hw hx hy hz dc dh&quot;&gt;To gain those few crucial microseconds, most players invest in expensive hardware: pools of servers with overclocked liquid-cooled CPUs (in 2020 you can buy a server with 56 cores at 5.6 GHz and 1 TB RAM), collocation in major exchange datacentres, high-end nanosecond network switches, dedicated sub-oceanic lines (Hibernian Express is a major provider), even microwave networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;70a0&quot; class=&quot;hc hd ei he b hf hg hh hi hj hk hl hm hn ho hp hq hr hs ht hu hv hw hx hy hz dc dh&quot;&gt;It’s common to see highly customised Linux kernels with OS bypass so that the data “jumps” directly from the network card to the application, IPC (Interprocess communication) and even FPGAs (programmable single-purpose chips).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;a121&quot; class=&quot;hc hd ei he b hf hg hh hi hj hk hl hm hn ho hp hq hr hs ht hu hv hw hx hy hz dc dh&quot;&gt;As for programming languages, C++ appears like a natural contender for the server-side application: It’s fast, as close to the machine code as it gets and, once compiled for the target platform, offers a constant processing time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;692b&quot; class=&quot;hc hd ei he b hf hg hh hi hj hk hl hm hn ho hp hq hr hs ht hu hv hw hx hy hz dc dh&quot;&gt;We made a different choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;ia&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;dd7c&quot; class=&quot;ib ic ei ap id ie if ig ih ii ij hz br&quot;&gt;For the past 14 years, we’ve competed in the FX algorithmic trading space coding in &lt;strong class=&quot;bw&quot;&gt;Java&lt;/strong&gt; and using great but affordable hardware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;3e92&quot; class=&quot;hc hd ei he b hf ik hh hi hj il hl hm hn im hp hq hr in ht hu hv io hx hy hz dc dh&quot;&gt;With a small team, limited resources, and a job market scarce in skilled developers, Java meant we could quickly add software improvements as the Java ecosystem has quicker time-to-market than C derivatives. &lt;strong class=&quot;he cp&quot;&gt;An improvement can be discussed in the morning, and be implemented, tested and released in production in the afternoon&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;047e&quot; class=&quot;hc hd ei he b hf hg hh hi hj hk hl hm hn ho hp hq hr hs ht hu hv hw hx hy hz dc dh&quot;&gt;Compared to big corporations that need weeks or even months for the slightest software update, this is a key advantage. And in a field where one bug can erase a whole year’s profit in seconds, we were not ready to compromise on quality. We implemented a rigorous Agile environment, including Jenkins, Maven, Unit tests, night builds and Jira, using many open source libraries and projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;c4b2&quot; class=&quot;hc hd ei he b hf hg hh hi hj hk hl hm hn ho hp hq hr hs ht hu hv hw hx hy hz dc dh&quot;&gt;With Java, developers can focus on intuitive object-oriented business logic rather than debugging some obscure memory Core dumps or managing pointers like in C++. And, thanks to Java’s robust internal memory management, junior programmers can also add value on day 1 with limited risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;86cc&quot; class=&quot;hc hd ei he b hf hg hh hi hj hk hl hm hn ho hp hq hr hs ht hu hv hw hx hy hz dc dh&quot;&gt;With good design patterns and clean coding habits, &lt;strong class=&quot;he cp&quot;&gt;it is possible to reach C++ latencies with Java&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;3a0e&quot; class=&quot;hc hd ei he b hf hg hh hi hj hk hl hm hn ho hp hq hr hs ht hu hv hw hx hy hz dc dh&quot;&gt;For example, Java will optimise and compile the best path as observed during the application run, but C++ compiles everything beforehand, so even unused methods will still be part of the final executable binary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;a757&quot; class=&quot;hc hd ei he b hf hg hh hi hj hk hl hm hn ho hp hq hr hs ht hu hv hw hx hy hz dc dh&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;he cp&quot;&gt;However there is one issue&lt;/strong&gt;, and a major one to boot. What makes Java such a powerful and enjoyable language is also its downfall (at least for microsecond sensitive applications), namely the &lt;strong class=&quot;he cp&quot;&gt;Java Virtual Machine&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong class=&quot;he cp&quot;&gt;(JVM):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;li id=&quot;7bbd&quot; class=&quot;hc hd ei he b hf hg hh hi hj hk hl hm hn ho hp hq hr hs ht hu hv hw hx hy hz ip iq ir dh&quot;&gt;Java compiles the code as it goes (Just in Time compiler or JIT), which means that the first time it encounters some code, it incurs a compilation delay.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;3abd&quot; class=&quot;hc hd ei he b hf is hh hi hj it hl hm hn iu hp hq hr iv ht hu hv iw hx hy hz ip iq ir dh&quot;&gt;The way Java manages the memory is by allocating chunks of memory in its “heap” space. Every so often, it will clean up that space and remove old objects to make room for new ones. The main issue is that to make an accurate count, application threads need to be momentarily “frozen”. This process is known as &lt;strong class=&quot;he cp&quot;&gt;Garbage Collection (GC).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p id=&quot;2e22&quot; class=&quot;hc hd ei he b hf hg hh hi hj hk hl hm hn ho hp hq hr hs ht hu hv hw hx hy hz dc dh&quot;&gt;The GC is the main reason low latency application developers may discard Java, a priori.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;a588&quot; class=&quot;hc hd ei he b hf hg hh hi hj hk hl hm hn ho hp hq hr hs ht hu hv hw hx hy hz dc dh&quot;&gt;There are a few Java Virtual Machines available on the market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;4011&quot; class=&quot;hc hd ei he b hf hg hh hi hj hk hl hm hn ho hp hq hr hs ht hu hv hw hx hy hz dc dh&quot;&gt;The most common and standard one is the Oracle Hotspot JVM, which is widely used in the Java community, mostly for historical reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;4a5b&quot; class=&quot;hc hd ei he b hf hg hh hi hj hk hl hm hn ho hp hq hr hs ht hu hv hw hx hy hz dc dh&quot;&gt;For very demanding applications, there is a great alternative called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.azul.com/products/zing&quot; class=&quot;dk ix&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;Zing, by Azul Systems&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;d179&quot; class=&quot;hc hd ei he b hf hg hh hi hj hk hl hm hn ho hp hq hr hs ht hu hv hw hx hy hz dc dh&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;he cp&quot;&gt;Zing is a powerful replacement of the standard Oracle Hotspot JVM&lt;/strong&gt;. Zing addresses both the GC pause and JIT compilation issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;3f08&quot; class=&quot;hc hd ei he b hf hg hh hi hj hk hl hm hn ho hp hq hr hs ht hu hv hw hx hy hz dc dh&quot;&gt;Let’s examine some of the issues inherent to using Java and possible solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 12:29:13 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pjmlp</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Why we chose Java for our High-Frequency Trading application</og:title>
<og:description>In the world of High-Frequency Trading, automated applications process hundreds of millions of market signals every day and send back…</og:description>
<og:url>https://medium.com/@jadsarmo/why-we-chose-java-for-our-high-frequency-trading-application-600f7c04da94</og:url>
<og:image>https://miro.medium.com/max/1200/1*a2AftTEKuUP5EBGVxrS7Iw.jpeg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://medium.com/@jadsarmo/why-we-chose-java-for-our-high-frequency-trading-application-600f7c04da94</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>L.A.&amp;#039;s coast was once a DDT dumping ground, but no one could see it until now</title>
<link>https://www.latimes.com/projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.latimes.com/projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;
&lt;section name=&quot;content&quot; readability=&quot;22&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not far from Santa Catalina Island, in an ocean shared by divers and fishermen, kelp forests and whales, David Valentine decoded unusual signals underwater that gave him chills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UC Santa Barbara scientist was supposed to be studying methane seeps that day, but with a deep-sea robot on loan and a few hours to spare, now was the chance to confirm an environmental abuse that others in the past could not. He was chasing a hunch, and sure enough, initial sonar scans pinged back a pattern of dots that popped up on the map like a trail of breadcrumbs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The robot made its way 3,000 feet down to the bottom, beaming bright lights and a camera as it slowly skimmed the seafloor. At this depth and darkness, the uncharted topography felt as eerie as driving through a vast desert at night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;66.487346567662&quot;&gt;
&lt;section name=&quot;content&quot; readability=&quot;80.065761258041&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Holy crap. This is real,” Valentine said. “This stuff really is down there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It has been sitting here this whole time, right off our shore.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tales of this buried secret bubbling under the sea had haunted Valentine for years: a largely unknown chapter in the most infamous case of environmental destruction off the coast of Los Angeles — one lasting decades, costing tens of millions of dollars, frustrating generations of scientists. The fouling of the ocean was so reckless, some said, it seemed unimaginable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As many as half a million of these barrels could still be underwater right now, according to interviews and a Times review of historical records, manifests and undigitized research. From 1947 to 1982, the nation’s largest manufacturer of DDT — a pesticide so powerful that it poisoned birds and fish — was based in Los Angeles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.latimes.com/archives/la-xpm-2000-oct-18-me-38139-story.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;epic Superfund battle&lt;/a&gt; later exposed the company’s disposal of toxic waste through sewage pipes that poured into the ocean — but all the DDT that was barged out to sea drew comparatively little attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shipping logs show that every month in the years after World War II, thousands of barrels of acid sludge laced with this synthetic chemical were boated out to a site near Catalina and dumped into the deep ocean — so vast that, according to common wisdom at the time, it would dilute even the most dangerous poisons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regulators reported in the 1980s that the men in charge of getting rid of the DDT waste sometimes took shortcuts and just dumped it closer to shore. And when the barrels were too buoyant to sink on their own, one report said, the crews simply punctured them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ocean buried the evidence for generations, but modern technology can take scientists to new depths. In 2011 and 2013, Valentine and his research team were able to identify about 60 barrels and collect a few samples during brief forays at the end of other research missions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One sediment sample showed DDT concentrations 40 times greater than the highest contamination recorded at &lt;a href=&quot;https://cumulis.epa.gov/supercpad/SiteProfiles/index.cfm?fuseaction=second.Cleanup&amp;amp;id=0900993#bkground&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the Superfund site&lt;/a&gt; — a federally designated area of hazardous waste that officials had contained to shallower waters near Palos Verdes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-map-box&quot; class=&quot;ai2html&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-map-desktop&quot; class=&quot;g-artboard&quot; data-aspect-ratio=&quot;1.462&quot; data-min-width=&quot;800&quot;&gt;

&lt;img id=&quot;g-map-desktop-img&quot; class=&quot;g-aiImg&quot; alt=&quot;A map of the coast off Los Angeles, showing the DDT barrel dumpsite between the mainland and Santa Catalina Island and the superfund site off the Palos Verdes Penninsula.&quot; src=&quot;https://www.latimes.com/projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/img/ai2html/map-desktop.dd6b75d0.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai0-1&quot; class=&quot;g-Layer_1 g-aiAbs&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle0&quot;&gt;Palos Verdes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle0&quot;&gt;Peninsula&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai0-2&quot; class=&quot;g-Layer_1 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle1&quot;&gt;Santa Monica&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle1&quot;&gt;Basin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai0-3&quot; class=&quot;g-Layer_1 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle2&quot;&gt;SUPERFUND&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle2&quot;&gt;SITE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai0-4&quot; class=&quot;g-Layer_1 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle1&quot;&gt;San Pedro&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle1&quot;&gt;Basin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai0-5&quot; class=&quot;g-Layer_1 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle3&quot;&gt;DDT BARREL&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle3&quot;&gt;DUMPSITE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai0-6&quot; class=&quot;g-Layer_1 g-aiAbs&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle0&quot;&gt;Santa&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle0&quot;&gt;Catalina&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle0&quot;&gt;Island&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-map-tablet&quot; class=&quot;g-artboard&quot; data-aspect-ratio=&quot;1.109&quot; data-min-width=&quot;601&quot; data-max-width=&quot;799&quot;&gt;

&lt;img id=&quot;g-map-tablet-img&quot; class=&quot;g-aiImg&quot; alt=&quot;A map of the coast off Los Angeles, showing the DDT barrel dumpsite between the mainland and Santa Catalina Island and the superfund site off the Palos Verdes Penninsula.&quot; src=&quot;https://www.latimes.com/projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/img/ai2html/map-tablet.2724a2b1.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai1-1&quot; class=&quot;g-Layer_1 g-aiAbs&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle0&quot;&gt;Palos Verdes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle0&quot;&gt;Peninsula&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai1-2&quot; class=&quot;g-Layer_1 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle1&quot;&gt;SUPERFUND&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle1&quot;&gt;SITE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai1-3&quot; class=&quot;g-Layer_1 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle2&quot;&gt;San Pedro&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle2&quot;&gt;Basin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai1-4&quot; class=&quot;g-Layer_1 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle3&quot;&gt;DDT BARREL&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle3&quot;&gt;DUMPSITE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai1-5&quot; class=&quot;g-Layer_1 g-aiAbs&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle0&quot;&gt;Santa&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle0&quot;&gt;Catalina&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle0&quot;&gt;Island&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-map-mobile&quot; class=&quot;g-artboard&quot; data-aspect-ratio=&quot;0.998&quot; data-min-width=&quot;0&quot; data-max-width=&quot;600&quot;&gt;

&lt;img id=&quot;g-map-mobile-img&quot; class=&quot;g-aiImg&quot; alt=&quot;A map of the coast off Los Angeles, showing the DDT barrel dumpsite between the mainland and Santa Catalina Island and the superfund site off the Palos Verdes Penninsula.&quot; src=&quot;https://www.latimes.com/projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/img/ai2html/map-mobile.c2dd193b.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai2-1&quot; class=&quot;g-Layer_1 g-aiAbs&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle0&quot;&gt;Palos Verdes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle0&quot;&gt;Peninsula&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai2-2&quot; class=&quot;g-Layer_1 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle1&quot;&gt;SUPERFUND&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle1&quot;&gt;SITE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai2-3&quot; class=&quot;g-Layer_1 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle2&quot;&gt;San Pedro&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle2&quot;&gt;Basin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai2-4&quot; class=&quot;g-Layer_1 g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle3&quot;&gt;DDT BARREL&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle3&quot;&gt;DUMPSITE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai2-5&quot; class=&quot;g-Layer_1 g-aiAbs&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle4&quot;&gt;Santa Catalina&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle4&quot;&gt;Island&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world today wrestles with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.latimes.com/environment/story/2019-10-02/california-microplastics-ocean-study&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;microplastics,&lt;/a&gt; bisphenol A (BPA), per- and polyfluoroalkyl substances &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.latimes.com/politics/story/2019-10-08/firefighting-foam-leaves-toxic-legacy-california-water&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;(PFAS)&lt;/a&gt; and other toxics so unnatural they don’t seem to ever go away. But DDT — the all-but-indestructible compound dichlorodiphenyltrichloroethane, which first stunned and jolted the public into environmental action — persists as an unsolved and largely forgotten problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Signs warning of tainted fish to this day still cover local piers. Recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4846432/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;studies&lt;/a&gt; show our immune systems may be compromised. A new generation of women — exposed to DDT from their mothers, who were &lt;a href=&quot;https://academic.oup.com/jcem/article/100/8/2865/2836085&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;exposed by&lt;/a&gt; their mothers — grapples with the still-mysterious &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.latimes.com/archives/la-xpm-2007-sep-30-na-ddt30-story.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;risks of breast cancer.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The contamination in sea lions and dolphins continues to stump scientists, and the near extinction of falcons and bald eagles shows how poisoning one corner of the world can ripple across the whole ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decades of bureaucracy and competing environmental issues have diverted the public’s attention. Valentine hoped digging up physical evidence from the seafloor would get more people to care, but calls and emails to numerous officials since his discovery have gone nowhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rallying for the deep ocean is not easy, Valentine acknowledged, even though we rely on the health of these waters far more than we know: “The fact that there could be half a million barrels down there … we owe it to ourselves to figure out what happened, what’s actually down there and how much it’s all spreading.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;data:image/svg+xml,%3Csvg%20xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2000/svg'%20viewBox='0%200%203%202'%3E%3C/svg%3E&quot; data-srcset=&quot;/projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/image/valentine-wide-600.412e8fc2.jpg 600w, /projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/image/valentine-wide-768.1a0b2431.jpg 768w, /projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/image/valentine-wide-1200.0433434d.jpg 1200w&quot; alt=&quot;David Valentine poses for a photo on the beach as a wave splashes in the foreground&quot;/&gt;David Valentine, a professor of geochemistry and microbiology at UC Santa Barbara, had wondered for years whether the DDT waste barrels actually existed 3,000 feet under the sea. (Allen J. Schaben / Los Angeles Times)&lt;/section&gt;&lt;hr class=&quot;section-break ddt&quot;/&gt;&lt;section name=&quot;content&quot; readability=&quot;48&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once hailed as a major scientific achievement, DDT combated both malaria and typhus during World War II. It was so potent that a single application could protect a soldier for months. The U.S. Army’s chief of preventive medicine, Brig. Gen. James Simmons, famously praised the chemical as “the war’s greatest contribution to the future health of the world.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Manufacturers rushed to supply the postwar demand — including Montrose Chemical Corp. of California, which opened its plant near Torrance in 1947. The chemical industry was celebrated at the time for boosting the nation into greater prosperity and preventing crop failures across the globe. The United States used as much as 80 million pounds of DDT in one year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;stacked jumbo&quot; readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;data:image/svg+xml,%3Csvg%20xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2000/svg'%20viewBox='0%200%203%202'%3E%3C/svg%3E&quot; data-srcset=&quot;/projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/image/ddt-beach-600.aea54487.jpg 600w, /projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/image/ddt-beach-768.a882b7a0.jpg 768w, /projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/image/ddt-beach-1200.1982a19c.jpg 1200w&quot; alt=&quot;a truck sprays ddt near unconcerned beachgoers on Long Island in 1945&quot;/&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;data:image/svg+xml,%3Csvg%20xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2000/svg'%20viewBox='0%200%203%202'%3E%3C/svg%3E&quot; data-srcset=&quot;/projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/image/ddt-plane-sheep-600.1dd01578.jpg 600w, /projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/image/ddt-plane-sheep-768.c7e759c8.jpg 768w, /projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/image/ddt-plane-sheep-1200.20c3e2ef.jpg 1200w&quot; alt=&quot;a plane dusts a flock of 1,200 sheep with a cloud of DDT powder&quot;/&gt;DDT was once considered a wonder pesticide, combatting malaria and preventing crop failures across the world. Top, a truck sprays DDT in 1945 to eliminate mosquitoes on Jones Beach on Long Island. Bottom, a plane dusts DDT powder on a flock of sheep in Medford, Ore., in 1948. (Keystone-France/Gamma-Keystone via Getty Images; Associated Press)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there were two edges to this sword. A top U.S. Department of Agriculture scientist had urged the military not to allow DDT insecticides for commercial use without further research, worried about “the effect they may have on soils and on the whole balance of nature.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even Swiss chemist Paul Hermann Müller, who won a Nobel Prize in 1948 for discovering DDT as a pesticide, cautioned that he himself did not fully understand how the chemical interacted with the living world. Decades of painstaking study still lay ahead for biologists, he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rachel Carson, a marine biologist, heeded these words in 1962 and ignited a movement against what she called “the reckless and irresponsible poisoning of the world that man shares with all other creatures.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her revolutionary book “Silent Spring” evoked the sudden silence of songbirds missing in the skies — alerting unknowing people to the dangers of long-term exposure, even in tiny doses, to a chemical that they could not physically avoid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DDT is so stable it can take generations to break down. It doesn’t really dissolve in water but stores easily in fat. Compounding these problems is what scientists today call “biomagnification”: the toxin accumulating in the tissues of animals in greater and greater concentrations as it moves up the food chain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;334.123942226&quot;&gt;
&lt;section name=&quot;content&quot; readability=&quot;26.337152209493&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Montrose executives aggressively defended DDT through the 1960s as the public reckoned with these alarming new concerns about food chains and poisoned ecosystems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They said in letters and editorials that DDT played a vital role in society when properly used and was not a serious threat to human health. They accused environmentalists of scare tactics and misleading information and touted the company’s reputation of making the best DDT in the world — a technical grade sold to other firms that would then dilute it into specific insecticides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company was supplying governments from Brazil to India, they said, and even the World Health Organization. International malaria eradication programs turned to Montrose for supplies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But after years of intense inquiries, government officials &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.epa.gov/epa/sites/production/files/documents/DDT-Ruckelshaus.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;said they were convinced&lt;/a&gt; that the chemical posed unacceptable risks to the environment and potential harm to human health. In 1972, the U.S. finally &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.epa.gov/epa/aboutepa/ddt-ban-takes-effect.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;banned&lt;/a&gt; the use of DDT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Demand was still strong in other countries, however, so the chemical plant in Los Angeles kept churning out more. Montrose managed to operate for another 10 years before the factory, looming over Normandie Avenue near Del Amo Boulevard, finally went dark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;hr class=&quot;section-break dde&quot;/&gt;&lt;section name=&quot;content&quot; readability=&quot;330.52321137924&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the early 1980s, a young scientist at the California Regional Water Quality Control Board in Los Angeles heard whispers that Montrose once dumped barrels of toxic waste directly into the ocean. People at the time were hyper-focused on the contamination problems posed by poorly treated sewage, but Allan Chartrand was curious about the deep-sea dumping and started poking around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He called Montrose, and to his surprise, the staff pulled out all their files. He and a team of regulatory scientists combed through volumes of shipping logs, which showed that more than 2,000 barrels of DDT-laced sludge were dumped each month. They did the math: Between 1947 and 1961, as much as 767 tons of DDT could have gone into the ocean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We found actual photos of the workers at 2 in the morning dumping — not only dumping barrels off of the barges in the middle of the Santa Monica Basin,” he said, “but before they would dump the barrels, they would take a big ax or hatchet to them, and cut them open on purpose so they would sink.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;data:image/svg+xml,%3Csvg%20xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2000/svg'%20viewBox='0%200%203%202'%3E%3C/svg%3E&quot; data-srcset=&quot;/projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/image/shipping-log-600.6925bac8.jpg 600w, /projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/image/shipping-log-768.63b78927.jpg 768w, /projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/image/shipping-log-1200.ac2e886e.jpg 1200w&quot; alt=&quot;A 1958 shipping log shows that 2,310 barrels of “acid sludge” from Montrose Chemical Corporation were dumped in the ocean in the month of January&quot;/&gt;A 1958 shipping log shows that 2,310 barrels of “acid sludge” from Montrose Chemical Corporation were dumped in the ocean in the month of January.
&lt;p&gt;On a recent morning, Chartrand rummaged through stacks of yellowing papers and reports detailing everything he had discovered so many decades ago. Now a seasoned eco-toxicologist in Seattle, he never understood why all this information wound up gathering dust — undigitized and largely forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He pulled out faded reports that his team had published from 1985 to 1989, summarizing what they had found at Montrose and in the water quality control board’s own records. “This makes my heart sing,” he said, as he reread conclusions that still resonate today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;data:image/svg+xml,%3Csvg%20xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2000/svg'%20viewBox='0%200%203%202'%3E%3C/svg%3E&quot; data-srcset=&quot;/projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/image/allan-chartrand-600.651ec5fa.jpg 600w, /projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/image/allan-chartrand-768.53e01517.jpg 768w, /projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/image/allan-chartrand-1200.6fad5b9f.jpg 1200w&quot; alt=&quot;Allan Chartrand looks through old files&quot;/&gt;Allan Chartrand flips through old copies of his studies from the 1980s. (Rosanna Xia / Los Angeles Times)
&lt;p&gt;Chartrand said he was astonished to learn this kind of activity was allowed. Federal ocean dumping laws dated back to 1886, but the rules were focused on clearing the way for ship navigation. It wasn’t until the Marine Protection, Research and Sanctuaries Act of 1972, also known as the Ocean Dumping Act, that environmental impacts were considered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dumping industrial chemicals near Catalina was an accepted practice for decades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Landfills could hold only so much, and people were concerned about burning toxics into the air — but the Pacific Ocean seemed a good alternative. Explosives, oil refinery waste, trash and rotting meats all went into the ocean, along with beryllium, various acid sludges, even cyanide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dilution is the solution to pollution, the saying used to go, but at what cost? The ocean covers more than 70% of the planet, but it can absorb only so much. What we eat, what we breathe is ultimately dictated by what we do to the sea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s just sad, sad, sad,” Chartrand said. “When stuff’s being dumped offshore like that, it’s in the dead of night, nobody’s seeing it. It’s out of sight, out of mind.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For years, a company called California Salvage docked at the Port of Los Angeles, loaded up Montrose’s DDT waste and hauled everything out to sea. Workers were instructed to dump in a designated spot, dubbed Dumpsite No. 1, that was about 10 nautical miles northwest of Catalina.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;blockquote&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;Each container was individually broken before disposal overboard. Drums containing chemicals were emptied and allowed to sink after holes were placed in the top, bottom and sides.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;attribution&quot;&gt;— Chartrand et al, March 1985 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But compliance inspections were infrequent, and crews sometimes took shortcuts. Chartrand discovered notes from California Salvage indicating they had decided to dump elsewhere because Dumpsite No. 1 was in line of a naval weapons firing range.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The report concluded that these companies likely dumped in closer, much shallower waters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Our report caught them red-handed,” Chartrand said. “Here I was this young guy — newly married, just had my first kid, got my new job at the water quality control board — heard about this dumping, went down to Montrose … and it very quickly got so much bigger than me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1990, a few years after Chartrand compiled his reports, the Environmental Protection Agency teamed up with the state and launched a court battle against Montrose and a number of other companies under the Superfund law. Environmental groups expected the lawsuit — the largest in U.S. history alleging natural resource damages from chemical dumping — to be a landmark case in resolving coastal pollution issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chartrand and dozens of others were pulled in to testify. Science was disputed in court, evidence debated, expertise challenged. In numerous depositions, former factory workers were grilled on how they operated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bernard Bratter, a Montrose plant superintendent, described how they would call California Salvage to dump its acid waste in bulk: “The trucks would come in, we’d load the trucks, they would then haul them down to the harbor where they had their barges, and the truck would unload into the barge, and when there was enough liquid in the barge, they’d haul the barge out to the specified area in the ocean and release the acid.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Montrose officials, who had filed counterclaims, asked the court to exclude the evidence presented on ocean dumping — arguing that such dumping wasn’t relevant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They said the government’s natural resources damage claim was based solely on the release of DDT through the sewer system to the Palos Verdes shelf, and that attorneys could not prove that Montrose’s disposal of DDT-contaminated waste into the deep ocean actually hurt various bird species.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They also questioned Chartrand’s calculations of how much DDT went into the ocean and made the point that there was nothing secret or illegal about the dumping at the time. The government, they said, allowed this to happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://beta.documentcloud.org/documents/7218137-Inter-office-correspondance-from-president-of&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;an interoffice correspondence&lt;/a&gt; in 1985, Samuel Rotrosen, Montrose’s president at the time, wrote that “it is true that from 1947, when the plant started up, until sometime in the 1950s we disposed of our waste sulfuric acid at sea through California Salvage Company who barged it out to state-approved dumping areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We stopped this disposal after we installed our acid-recovery plant, at which time we sold the acid to fertilizer makers,” he said. “Because our acid contained traces of DDT (50-250 ppm) … the fertilizer producers would no longer take it, and so we disposed of it at landfills.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;data:image/svg+xml,%3Csvg%20xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2000/svg'%20viewBox='0%200%203%202'%3E%3C/svg%3E&quot; data-srcset=&quot;/projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/image/punctured-barrel-600.11fd6a91.jpg 600w, /projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/image/punctured-barrel-768.b649f10c.jpg 768w, /projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/image/punctured-barrel-1200.36d4fecd.jpg 1200w&quot; alt=&quot;A punctured DDT barrel rests at the bottom of the ocean.&quot;/&gt;Three decades after regulatory scientists found evidence of men taking an ax to these waste barrels before dumping them overboard, an underwater robot came across barrels on the seafloor with puncture marks. (David Valentine / ROV Jason)
&lt;p&gt;As the court battle waged on, a handful of curious scientists kept trying to solve the DDT questions at the bottom of the ocean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chartrand did not have a deep-sea robot, but he figured out a way to collect sediment samples and clumps of tar by dragging a large otter trawl net along the seafloor. He also took samples of rattails, kelp bass and other fish from different depths of the ocean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He called Robert Risebrough, a legend among DDT scientists whose testimonies in the 1960s and early 1970s helped Congress understand why the chemical should be banned. Risebrough, a UC Santa Cruz research ecologist at the time, ran the samples and authored a sweeping study. He confirmed the existence of considerable concentrations of DDT chemicals in both the sediments and the “tar cakes” by the dumpsites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was unclear how much the DDT could move through the water at such depths, where there is little oxygen, he said, but the dumping was close enough to the Channel Islands that the upwelling of deeper water common in this area could stir up what enters the food chain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if the barrels were indeed punctured, he added, some of the sludge could have leaked out on its way down to the seafloor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He had a strong suspicion that the disappearance of bald eagles from Catalina was connected to the dumping operations, but he didn’t have the data to confirm it. DDT contamination was also significantly higher in birds that fed on fish, compared with birds that ate mostly rodents and prey on land — another clue that the DDT from the ocean dumping was harming wildlife.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He called for more studies to connect the dots, but Chartrand had run out of funding. Chartrand held on to what he could — even the remaining samples that neither he nor Risebrough could bear to throw away. Some of that deep sea sediment has yet to be tested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“They’re in a deep freeze now, but because it’s DDT, even though it’s been 30, 40 years, they’re still valid,” Chartrand said. “If we could get the funding, those are still worth running.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;blockquote&quot; readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;“They were supposed to take it out to sea. I think beyond the Continental Shelf. But there was a common joke among people that they only took it as far as they needed to, just out of sight, and started dumping right there.”&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;attribution&quot;&gt;— Deposition of Ferdinand Suhrer, Montrose employee, July 30, 1996 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;M. Indira Venkatesan, a geochemist at UCLA who studied how chemicals moved through the sea, had taken one of these samples in the early 1990s and run her own analyses. She, too, concluded there must be a DDT source in the ocean much larger than just what had come out of the sewage closer to shore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She collected additional sediment cores from the seafloor by a manual pulley that her technicians and graduate students spent hours pulling up. Her team distinguished the DDT “fingerprint” for Montrose’s ocean-dumped waste and discussed the upward and downward diffusion of DDT in the sediments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It gets resuspended and remobilized. That’s why you see it all over the basin,” she said. “I knew, I just knew, this DDT source was significant, just from the chemical analysis, but we couldn’t show the extent of the dumping, nor the number of barrels.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in court, the arguments were focusing on the more tangible: the hundreds of tons of DDT and PCBs, another toxic chemical, that had been released two miles off the coast of Palos Verdes where the sewage emptied into the ocean. Many saw the need to make this public health problem — much closer to shore, with visible harm to humans and the ecosystem — a top priority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The site — spread across more than 17 square miles — was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.latimes.com/archives/la-xpm-1996-07-11-me-23183-story.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;declared a Superfund cleanup in 1996.&lt;/a&gt; About 200 feet deep, it was considered one of the most complicated hazard sites in the United States — at least three times deeper than similar Superfund sites in Boston and New York harbors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;data:image/svg+xml,%3Csvg%20xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2000/svg'%20viewBox='0%200%203%202'%3E%3C/svg%3E&quot; data-srcset=&quot;/projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/image/pv-4-600.fe051e6e.jpg 600w, /projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/image/pv-4-768.89e57bf5.jpg 768w, /projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/image/pv-4-1200.7b100991.jpg 1200w, /projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/image/pv-4-2000.94842454.jpg 2000w, /projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/image/pv-4-2400.1481b6ef.jpg 2400w, /projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/image/pv-4-3000.94920bf9.jpg 3000w&quot; alt=&quot;An aerial view of the cliffs of Palos Verdes, a person can be seen standing on the rocks by the water&quot;/&gt;The Palos Verdes coast has been contaminated with DDT for decades. The attempted cleanup has become one of the most complicated Superfund projects in the United States. (Allen J. Schaben / Los Angeles Times)
&lt;p&gt;By late 2000, the parties decided to settle. They &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.latimes.com/archives/la-xpm-2000-oct-28-mn-43388-story.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;negotiated&lt;/a&gt; a consent decree midway through trial — no sides admitting fault, with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.latimes.com/archives/la-xpm-2000-dec-20-me-2261-story.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;an agreement&lt;/a&gt; that more than $140 million would be paid by Montrose, several other companies that owned or operated a share of the plant, and local governments led by the Los Angeles County Sanitation Districts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The settlement — one of the largest in the nation for an environmental damage claim — would pay for cleanup, habitat restoration and education programs for people at risk of eating contaminated fish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This Decree was negotiated ... in good faith at arm’s length to avoid the continuation of expensive and protracted litigation and is a fair and equitable settlement of claims which were vigorously contested,” according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://beta.documentcloud.org/documents/7218154-Partial-consent-decree-USA-v-Montrose-et-al&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the decree,&lt;/a&gt; which mentioned that the damage claim includes “any ocean dumpsites used for disposing of wastes from the Montrose Plant Property.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;data:image/svg+xml,%3Csvg%20xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2000/svg'%20viewBox='0%200%203%202'%3E%3C/svg%3E&quot; data-srcset=&quot;/projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/image/montrose-1-600.5497ff03.jpg 600w, /projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/image/montrose-1-768.5a1a6680.jpg 768w, /projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/image/montrose-1-1200.093fdb4a.jpg 1200w&quot; alt=&quot;A birds-eye view of the Montrose property, now a large concrete lot with some chemical tanks&quot;/&gt;From 1947 to 1982, the nation’s largest manufacturer of DDT operated in Los Angeles on Normandie Avenue near Del Amo Boulevard. The property is considered one of the most hazardous sites in the United States. (Allen J. Schaben / Los Angeles Times)
&lt;p&gt;Attorneys representing Montrose, when contacted by The Times, declined to comment on the new underwater data and noted that the ocean claims related to the DDT operation were resolved 20 years ago. Litigation continues to this day over other impacts from the former plant. In August, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epa.gov/newsreleases/epa-reaches-566-million-settlement-groundwater-cleanup-los-angeles-area-superfund-sites&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;$56.6-million settlement&lt;/a&gt; was finally reached over groundwater contamination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back at UCLA, on a recent morning in the geology building, Venkatesan thought ruefully back to those DDT years. KCBS had run a local news series on the barrels, and The Times &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.latimes.com/archives/la-xpm-1985-02-28-mn-12731-story.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;followed the story&lt;/a&gt; for a brief period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The information caught the attention of Assemblyman Tom Hayden (D-Santa Monica), the 1960s activist turned lawmaker who married Jane Fonda and was remembered as “the radical inside the system.” For a few years, he &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.latimes.com/archives/la-xpm-1985-03-28-we-29386-story.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;pushed for more information&lt;/a&gt; about the barrels and an action plan, but so many unchecked environmental problems demanded attention back then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even Venkatesan got pulled away. As public concerns shifted from water to air pollution, her research focus changed to aerosols.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She had tried for a while longer to get the word out — giving public lectures in Santa Monica bookstores and telling whoever would listen that the deep ocean also needed healing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I didn’t know what to do with this data; I felt bad,” she said. “As scientists, we thought we could leave it to the politicians and the government to do their job…. But if the government is not proactive, then people don’t care. If people don’t care, then the government doesn’t do anything.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that she’s retired, her filing cabinets — filled with her work since she started in 1975 — have been moved into a basement at UCLA. She recently reviewed the data that the UC Santa Barbara researchers had uncovered with deep-sea robots, which validated Chartrand’s estimates, as well as her own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She held out her hands and said she was trembling with excitement, knowing that people might care about this issue again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Disposing any waste, where you don’t see and forget about it, does not solve the problem,” she said. “The problem eventually comes back to haunt us.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;hr class=&quot;section-break ddmu&quot;/&gt;&lt;section name=&quot;content&quot; readability=&quot;184.51807299613&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;One afternoon in Santa Barbara, hunched over a computer humming with data, Valentine and Veronika Kivenson, a PhD student in marine science, scrolled through the eerie images they had gathered underwater.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They leaned in to examine an icicle-like anomaly growing off one of the barrels — a “toxicle,” they called it — and wondered about the gas that bubbled out when the robot snapped one off. To have gas supersaturated in and around these barrels so deep underwater, where the pressure was 90 times greater than above ground, was unsettling. They couldn’t help but feel like they were poking at a giant Coke can ready to explode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;stacked jumbo&quot; readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;data:image/svg+xml,%3Csvg%20xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2000/svg'%20viewBox='0%200%203%202'%3E%3C/svg%3E&quot; data-srcset=&quot;/projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/image/sediment-sample-600.93208e31.jpg 600w, /projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/image/sediment-sample-768.c1c5b2b3.jpg 768w, /projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/image/sediment-sample-1200.ae40076f.jpg 1200w&quot; alt=&quot;robot takes sediment samples on the ocean floor&quot;/&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;data:image/svg+xml,%3Csvg%20xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2000/svg'%20viewBox='0%200%203%202'%3E%3C/svg%3E&quot; data-srcset=&quot;/projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/image/barrel-ring-600.17d3ec44.jpg 600w, /projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/image/barrel-ring-768.e29d224a.jpg 768w, /projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/image/barrel-ring-1200.8a236cd4.jpg 1200w&quot; alt=&quot;a submerged ddt barrel lying on its side surrounded by a ring of chemical residue&quot;/&gt;About 60 barrels were visually identified by Jason, a remotely operated robot that also collected samples of nearby sediment with large tubes, top. One spot had a DDT concentration 40 times higher than the highest level of surface contamination recorded at the Palos Verdes Superfund site. (David Valentine / ROV Jason)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing was clear, Kivenson said: This stuff is spreading. She had tried to collect sediment many meters from the barrels as a baseline to compare the samples collected right next to the source. But the baseline turned out to also have similarly high concentrations of DDT — most of them higher than the permissible threshold established by the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“These barrels do seem to be leaking over time,” she said. “This toxic waste is just kind of bubbling down there, seeping, oozing, I don’t know what word I want to use. ... It’s not a contained environment.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So much of this data, collected in 2011 and then again in 2013, came down to timing and good luck: The underwater robots had been on loan for a different project, but that research cruise was ahead of schedule, so they had a window of extra time to explore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www2.whoi.edu/staff/dyoerger/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;scientist involved&lt;/a&gt; in the discovery of the Titanic happened to be on board, so he helped them program the robots on where to go and how to search for the barrels. A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www2.whoi.edu/site/chrisreddylab/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;marine geochemistry lab&lt;/a&gt; at Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution ran the samples, and Kivenson, whose graduate fellowship and tuition were the only funding for this research, analyzed them for her PhD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;data:image/svg+xml,%3Csvg%20xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2000/svg'%20viewBox='0%200%203%202'%3E%3C/svg%3E&quot; data-srcset=&quot;/projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/image/submarine-600.c8b533a5.jpg 600w, /projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/image/submarine-768.b0818f78.jpg 768w, /projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/image/submarine-1200.dcfffe9a.jpg 1200w&quot; alt=&quot;A yellow robotic submarine with big cartoon eyes painted on the hull.&quot;/&gt;Scientists aboard the research vessel Atlantis guide Sentry, an autonomous underwater vehicle, down into the water to scope out the seafloor. (David Valentine / UC Santa Barbara)
&lt;p&gt;She tracked down the patent for the DDT acid waste that supposedly went into the barrels. She combed through EBay for out-of-print research books on ocean dumping and flipped through rolls of microfilm in the archive rooms of court buildings and government agencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She validated Venkatesan’s conclusion that the DDT near the barrels did not have the same characteristics as the Superfund site — ruling out the possibility that this was just DDT from Palos Verdes that somehow traveled farther into the ocean and settled onto the deep seafloor. One key difference was that the barrel samples contained no PCBs, which are abundant in the contamination near the sewage outfall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each barrel seemed to contain acid waste with about 0.5% to 2% technical-grade DDT — which, at half a million barrels, would amount to a total of 384 to 1,535 tons of DDT on the seafloor. The distribution was patchy; one hot spot had a concentration of DDT that was 40 times higher than the highest level of surface sediment contamination recorded at the Superfund site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All told, she concluded that the total amount of DDT from the dumping seemed comparable to the estimated 870 to 1,450 tons that had been released through the sewer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;data:image/svg+xml,%3Csvg%20xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2000/svg'%20viewBox='0%200%203%202'%3E%3C/svg%3E&quot; data-srcset=&quot;/projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/image/jason-600.8289d3fe.jpg 600w, /projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/image/jason-768.b8f04914.jpg 768w, /projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/image/jason-1200.be5e0916.jpg 1200w&quot; alt=&quot;a cube-shaped remotely operated robot named Jason&quot;/&gt;When Sentry pinged back anomalies, a larger remotely operated robot named Jason, above, was sent down to take photos and gather samples. (David Valentine / UC Santa Barbara)
&lt;p&gt;But in the end, these are still extrapolations — we don’t know how much is actually down there, said Kivenson, who &lt;a href=&quot;https://pubs.acs.org/doi/pdf/10.1021/acs.est.8b05859?rand=0vxkxul6&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;published these findings&lt;/a&gt; last year in the journal Environmental Science &amp;amp; Technology and is now a postdoctoral fellow at Oregon State University. Logical next steps would be to somehow map and identify just how many barrels there are, determine any hot spots, and study how much the chemical is leaking and spreading and accumulating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Valentine tried calling those with the power to do something about these barrels: the EPA, which has been in charge of cleaning up the Superfund site. But the EPA, it turns out, hasn’t even figured out what to do with the DDT problem that got all the attention and millions of settlement dollars. After more than 20 years of meetings and high-level studies, the site off the Palos Verdes shore has become its own controversial saga.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.latimes.com/archives/la-xpm-2000-mar-25-mn-12629-story.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;pilot experiment&lt;/a&gt; more than a decade ago to bury the DDT under a thick cap of clean sand showed &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.latimes.com/archives/la-xpm-2009-jun-12-me-palos-verdes-pollution12-story.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;mixed results.&lt;/a&gt; Then sampling in 2009 suggested that most of the DDT had &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/the-mystery-of-the-vanishing-ddt-in-the-ocean-near-los-angeles/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;mysteriously vanished&lt;/a&gt; — prompting a burst of headlines and more internal paralysis. The longtime project manager unexpectedly retired, and many of the scientists who had dedicated decades of their careers to the chemical have also either retired or moved on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;data:image/svg+xml,%3Csvg%20xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2000/svg'%20viewBox='0%200%203%202'%3E%3C/svg%3E&quot; data-srcset=&quot;/projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/image/sand-dump-600.e565151c.jpg 600w, /projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/image/sand-dump-768.bcc88aee.jpg 768w, /projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/image/sand-dump-1200.d90dba4b.jpg 1200w&quot; alt=&quot;workers on a barge dump sand over an area of ocean contaminated with ddt&quot;/&gt;More than a decade ago, the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency experimented with burying the DDT on the Palos Verdes shelf under a thick cap of clean sand. (Ken Lubas / Los Angeles Times)
&lt;p&gt;Many, when reached, said they had not been involved with the site for a number of years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I feel like something’s happened at the site; it just sort of died. It’s been very weird,” said Robert Eganhouse, a research chemist at the U.S. Geological Survey who had been studying the Superfund site and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://pubs.acs.org/doi/pdf/10.1021/es7029619&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;breakdown rates of DDT&lt;/a&gt; since the 1970s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His last meaningful exchange with the EPA was in late 2016, when he submitted an immense amount of data and a final synthesis report for the site — a research endeavor that took more than eight years and cost millions of dollars. To this day, Eganhouse, who recently retired, is not quite sure what the EPA did with this information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Judy Huang, the Superfund’s project manager for the past decade, when reached by The Times, directed questions to regional headquarters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an email, an EPA spokeswoman said the agency had suspended capping efforts and collected new data that showed twice as much DDT as the 2009 results. The EPA is now reassessing its approach: “We are updating our evaluation of the mechanisms of how the DDTs and PCBs in the sediment impact human health and the environment in this complex system.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.montroserestoration.noaa.gov/multimedia/publications/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;projects&lt;/a&gt; to restore local kelp forests, wetlands, seabirds and underwater habitats have been supported over the years with the settlement money, as well as &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pvsfish.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;education outreach&lt;/a&gt; that helped prevent anglers and vulnerable communities from eating poisoned fish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fish remain contaminated, but the concentrations seem to be slowly going down, according to findings from the EPA’s most recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://semspub.epa.gov/work/09/100018339.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;five-year review&lt;/a&gt; of the site, released last fall. The bald eagles and peregrine falcons are coming back after years of human assistance, and nature seems to be healing itself over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all these years of costly stops and stalls, some think a so-called monitored natural recovery approach might just be the best solution. The EPA plans to start a new feasibility study that aims to lead to a final cleanup strategy. That study is not expected to be published for another four years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mark Gold, who had championed the DDT problem as a marine scientist since the 1990s, could barely find the words to describe how he felt about the attempted cleanup of the Palos Verdes shelf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“To have the EPA say, 25 years later, that maybe the best thing to do is to just let nature take its course is, frankly, nothing short of nauseating,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When asked about the barrels, he was so shocked he had to pause and grab a calculator to process the amount of DDT that could be in the deep ocean. At an absolute minimum, he said, there needs to be further investigation into how much is actually down there and how much this dumping has harmed the ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gold, who is now Gov. Gavin Newsom’s deputy secretary for coast and ocean policy, said he had heard stories of illegal dumping back when he was helping state and federal officials build the case against Montrose. But there was no firsthand evidence in the 1990s, he said, nor a sense of whether it was five barrels, 10 or 20.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Nobody in their worst nightmares,” he said, “ever thought there would be half a million barrels of DDT waste dumped into the ocean off of L.A. County’s coast.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;hr class=&quot;section-break ddnu&quot;/&gt;&lt;section name=&quot;content&quot; readability=&quot;82.854988399072&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;data:image/svg+xml,%3Csvg%20xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2000/svg'%20viewBox='0%200%203%202'%3E%3C/svg%3E&quot; data-srcset=&quot;/projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/image/garibaldi-600.cf948628.jpg 600w, /projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/image/garibaldi-768.bd8b10a5.jpg 768w, /projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/image/garibaldi-1200.d5195962.jpg 1200w, /projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/image/garibaldi-2000.6edf6962.jpg 2000w, /projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/image/garibaldi-2400.b565c453.jpg 2400w, /projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/image/garibaldi-3000.f6e57e6f.jpg 3000w&quot; alt=&quot;A garibaldi fish swims through a kelp forest off Catalina Island.&quot;/&gt;A garibaldi, the state fish, swims through a kelp forest near Catalina Island. (Allen J. Schaben / Los Angeles Times)
&lt;p&gt;For scientists today, DDT poses a new generation of complications. Dilution, it seems, just means the problem re-accumulates elsewhere. In the environmental health laboratory at San Diego State‘s School of Public Health, Eunha Hoh recently discovered the chemical had wound its way into dolphins in unexpected ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marine mammals, like humans, nurse their young and live long lives. Slow to evolve, their long-term health is a window into the lasting impacts of chronic exposure and accumulation — and how these chemicals get passed onto babies. As some of the largest predators of the sea, they’re also an important indicator of the ocean’s overall health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So when Hoh sampled the blubber of eight adult dolphins that had lived deeper off the coast of Southern California, she was surprised to find significant amounts of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC6310127/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;45 DDT-related compounds.&lt;/a&gt; Every dolphin she tested had washed up dead — and had accumulated much more of these chemicals than dolphins tested in Brazil and elsewhere around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“DDT contamination — is it really going down in Southern California? Can we really say that, or are we missing something,” said Hoh, who also serves on the California Ocean Protection Council’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.opc.ca.gov/science-advisory-team/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;science advisory team.&lt;/a&gt; “Sure it was banned decades ago, it might be manageable globally, but Southern California? We’re different. Our ocean is so much more polluted with DDT. We cannot just say, ‘That’s done; we can move on to other things.’”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hoh’s expertise is in discovering new chemicals, but she remains mystified by how DDT keeps reappearing in new and unexpected ways. Where, she often wonders, is all this DDT coming from?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When she first heard about the barrels scattered across the seafloor, it was as if someone finally handed her missing pieces to a puzzle that had never quite added up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The questions came tumbling out. If that much more DDT is out there but forgotten, and no one knows to study it, she said, how will we ever understand the true legacy of this chemical?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;data:image/svg+xml,%3Csvg%20xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2000/svg'%20viewBox='0%200%203%202'%3E%3C/svg%3E&quot; data-srcset=&quot;/projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/image/fish-kelp-catalina-600.86157ce5.jpg 600w, /projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/image/fish-kelp-catalina-768.66cc02b4.jpg 768w, /projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/image/fish-kelp-catalina-1200.497d9da7.jpg 1200w&quot; alt=&quot;A fish swims through a kelp forest off Catalina Island.&quot;/&gt;The ocean’s health, scientists say, is inseparable from our health and the health of the planet. (Allen J. Schaben / Los Angeles Times)
&lt;p&gt;Current monitoring shows that the local ecosystem, on the whole, is stable. But what’s unclear are these long-term unknowns, said Keith Maruya, who co-authored the dolphin study and retired last year as the Southern California Coastal Water Research Project’s head of chemistry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s not like something’s going off the cliff. But what we don’t know is whether these things are going to have a longer-term, more subtle effect — are some populations really, really slowly going to be declining?” he said. “We don’t know the answer. Moreover, we don’t really have the tools yet to answer that question fully.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He jolted up in his chair when the discovery of the barrels came up in a recent conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Wow. Wait, how many did they find? I need to write this down.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He jotted a few numbers, then silently compared this with the known quantity of DDT dumped at the Superfund site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If nobody accounted for this second source … if you’ve got twice the amount,” he said, thinking aloud. “It’s such a staggering number, but what does this mean? … The bottom line is always going to be: So what? We have a chemical out there, so what?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;hr class=&quot;section-break ddt&quot;/&gt;&lt;section name=&quot;content&quot; readability=&quot;46.934613077385&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the Scripps Institution of Oceanography, in a developmental biology and environmental toxicology lab overlooking the sea, Amro Hamdoun has been pondering this question for much of his life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He’s found through molecular studies that “persistent organic pollutants,” like flame retardants and DDT, can block &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4846432/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a key protein from eliminating toxins&lt;/a&gt; from the human body — a clue, perhaps, into why they bioaccumulate. Even in small amounts, these contaminants could interfere with the human body’s natural ability to defend itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hamdoun teaches “Silent Spring” and DDT to his students as an example of how the world used to be — but can’t help but wonder how much the jobs and science of the future will be dealing with these messes of the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“There’s a broader problem of thinking of the ocean as this unlimited garbage dump that’s going to take up our CO₂, take up our mercury, deal with the plastic that we don’t throw away properly, be a dumping ground for pesticides, deal with whatever is in runoff — and that our health is going to be separable from that,” he said. “But what we’re learning more and more is that our health and the ocean’s health are pretty inseparable.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At what point, he asked, does it become our prerogative, as people who live in a shared society, to decide what it is that we want to put in our environment — and our bodies?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He leaned forward in his chair, hands clasped, head bowed, like Valentine and Chartrand and so many who came before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“These chemicals are still out there, and we haven’t figured out what to do,” he said. “They are an issue, and we still don’t have a plan.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section name=&quot;credits&quot; readability=&quot;2.7772621809745&quot;&gt;&lt;aside class=&quot;methodology&quot; readability=&quot;5.554524361949&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Graphics and design for this story were developed by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.latimes.com/people/sean-greene&quot;&gt;Sean Greene&lt;/a&gt;. Audience engagement by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.latimes.com/people/mary-kate-metivier&quot;&gt;Mary Kate Metivier&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.latimes.com/people/javier-panzar&quot;&gt;Javier Panzar&lt;/a&gt;. Photo editing by Marc Martin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Barrel video provided by David Valentine and ROV Jason. Terrain data for San Pedro Basin are from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://data.noaa.gov/onestop/collections/details/AWb1P_ReHtVRBOAZkDH8&quot;&gt;National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration&lt;/a&gt;. The shape of the Palos Verdes shelf Superfund site was provided by the U.S. EPA and Los Angeles County Sanitation District.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 10:39:31 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rblion</dc:creator>
<og:title>How the waters off Catalina became a DDT dumping ground</og:title>
<og:description>A new generation of scientists have uncovered barrels containing DDT, a toxic pesticide banned decades ago, dumped into the deep ocean.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.latimes.com/projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.latimes.com/projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/assets/meta/social.924874e4.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.latimes.com/projects/la-coast-ddt-dumping-ground/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Vaccine hopes rise as Oxford jab prompts immune response among old and young</title>
<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-health-coronavirus-astrazeneca-vaccin/oxford-covid-19-vaccine-prompts-immune-response-among-adults-old-and-young-astrazeneca-says-idUSKBN27B0IV</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.reuters.com/article/us-health-coronavirus-astrazeneca-vaccin/oxford-covid-19-vaccine-prompts-immune-response-among-adults-old-and-young-astrazeneca-says-idUSKBN27B0IV</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;LONDON (Reuters) - One of the world’s leading COVID-19 experimental vaccines produces an immune response in both young and old adults, raising hopes of a path out of the gloom and economic destruction wrought by the novel coronavirus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;The vaccine, developed by the University of Oxford, also triggers lower adverse responses among the elderly, British drug maker AstraZeneca Plc, which is helping manufacture the vaccine, said on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;A vaccine that works is seen as a game-changer in the battle against the novel coronavirus, which has killed more than 1.15 million people, shuttered swathes of the global economy and turned normal life upside down for billions of people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;“It is encouraging to see immunogenicity responses were similar between older and younger adults and that reactogenicity was lower in older adults, where the COVID-19 disease severity is higher,” an AstraZeneca spokesman said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;“The results further build the body of evidence for the safety and immunogenicity of AZD1222,” the spokesman said, referring to the technical name of the vaccine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;The Oxford/AstraZeneca vaccine is expected to be one of the first from big pharma to secure regulatory approval, along with Pfizer and BioNTech’s candidate, as the world tries to plot a path out of the COVID-19 pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;The news that older people get an immune response from the vaccine is positive because the immune system weakens with age and older people are those most at risk of dying from the virus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;If it works, a vaccine would allow the world to return to some measure of normality after the tumult of the pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;British Health Secretary Matt Hancock said a vaccine was not yet ready but he was preparing logistics for a possible roll out mostly in the first half of 2021.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FILE PHOTO: A test tube labeled with the vaccine is seen in front of AstraZeneca logo in this illustration taken, September 9, 2020. REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/File Photo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;Asked if some people could receive a vaccine this year he told the BBC: “I don’t rule that out but that is not my central expectation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;“The programme is progressing well, (but) we’re not there yet,” Hancock said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;Headline-headline-2FXIq Headline-black-OogpV ArticleBody-heading-3h695&quot;&gt;COMMON COLD VIRUS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;Work began on the Oxford vaccine in January. Called AZD1222 or ChAdOx1 nCoV-19, the viral vector vaccine is made from a weakened version of a common cold virus that causes infections in chimpanzees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;The chimpanzee cold virus has been genetically changed to include the genetic sequence of the so-called spike protein which the coronavirus uses to gain entry to human cells. The hope is that the human body will then attack the novel coronavirus if it sees it again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;Immunogenicity blood tests carried out on a subset of older participants echo data released in July which showed the vaccine generated “robust immune responses” in a group of healthy adults aged between 18 and 55, the Financial Times reported earlier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;Details of the finding are expected to be published shortly in a clinical journal, the FT said. It did not name the publication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;People aware of the results from so-called immunogenicity blood tests carried out on a subset of older participants say the findings echo data released in July that showed the vaccine generated “robust immune responses” in a group of healthy adults aged between 18 and 55.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;AstraZeneca has signed several supply and manufacturing deals with companies and governments around the world as it gets closer to reporting early results of a late-stage clinical trial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;It resumed the U.S. trial of the experimental vaccine after approval by U.S. regulators, the company said on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;Staff at a London hospital trust have been told to be ready to receive the first batches of the Oxford/AstraZeneca vaccine, The Sun newspaper reported on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;6.0394736842105&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Attribution-attribution-Y5JpY&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additional reporting by Bhargav Acharya and Kanishka Singh in Bengaluru; Writing by Guy Faulconbridge in London; Editing by Angus MacSwan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 10:34:59 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pseudolus</dc:creator>
<og:title>Vaccine hopes rise as Oxford jab prompts immune response among old as well as young adults</og:title>
<og:description>One of the world's leading COVID-19 experimental vaccines produces an immune response in both young and old adults, raising hopes of a path out of the gloom and economic destruction wrought by the novel coronavirus.</og:description>
<og:image>https://static.reuters.com/resources/r/?m=02&amp;d=20201026&amp;t=2&amp;i=1538837574&amp;r=LYNXMPEG9P0DR&amp;w=800</og:image>
<og:url>https://www.reuters.com/article/health-coronavirus-astrazeneca-vaccine-idUSKBN27B0J1</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-health-coronavirus-astrazeneca-vaccin/oxford-covid-19-vaccine-prompts-immune-response-among-adults-old-and-young-astrazeneca-says-idUSKBN27B0IV</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>