<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Facebook Asking for Some New Users&amp;#039; Email Passwords</title>
<link>https://www.thedailybeast.com/beyond-sketchy-facebook-demanding-some-new-users-email-passwords</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.thedailybeast.com/beyond-sketchy-facebook-demanding-some-new-users-email-passwords</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Just two weeks after admitting it stored hundreds of millions of its users’ own passwords insecurely, Facebook is demanding some users fork over the password for their outside email account as the price of admission to the social network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook users are being interrupted by an interstitial demanding they provide the password for the email account they gave to Facebook when signing up. “To continue using Facebook, you’ll need to confirm your email,” the message demands. “Since you signed up with [email address], you can do that automatically …”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A form below the message asked for the users’ “email password.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“That’s beyond sketchy,” security consultant Jake Williams told the Daily Beast. “They should not be taking your password or handling your password in the background. If that’s what’s required to sign up with Facebook, you’re better off not being on Facebook.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a statement emailed to The Daily Beast after this story published, Facebook reiterated its claim it doesn’t store the email passwords. But the company also announced it will end the practice altogether.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We understand the password verification option isn’t the best way to go about this, so we are going to stop offering it,” Facebook wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not clear how widely the new measure was deployed, but in its statement Facebook said users retain the option of bypassing the password demand and activating their account through more conventional means, such as “a code sent to their phone or a link sent to their email.” Those options are presented to users who click on the words “Need help?” in one corner of the page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The additional login step &lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/originalesushi/status/1112496649891430401&quot;&gt;was noticed&lt;/a&gt; over the weekend by a cybersecurity watcher on Twitter called “e-sushi.” The Daily Beast tested the claim by establishing a new Facebook account under circumstances the company’s system might flag as suspicious, using a disposable webmail address and connecting through a VPN in Romania. A reporter was taken to the same screen demanding the email password.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“By going down that road, you're practically fishing for passwords you are not supposed to know!,” e-sushi wrote in a tweet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Small print below the password field promises, “Facebook won’t store your password.” But the company has recently been criticized for repurposing information it originally acquired for “security” reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year Facebook &lt;a class=&quot;TrackingLink LinkWrapper&quot; href=&quot;https://www.thedailybeast.com/facebook-lets-anyone-view-your-profile-with-2fa-phone-number&quot;&gt;was caught&lt;/a&gt; allowing advertisers to target its users using phone numbers users provided for two-factor authentication; users handed over their numbers so Facebook could send a text message with a secret code when they log in. More recently the company drew the ire of privacy advocates when it began making those phone numbers searchable, so anyone can locate the matching user “in defiance of user expectations and security best practices,” &lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2019/03/facebook-doubles-down-misusing-your-phone-number&quot;&gt;wrote&lt;/a&gt; the Electronic Frontier Foundation, a civil liberties group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook also has a checkered history when it comes to securely handling passwords. Last month the company acknowledged that &lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/2019/03/facebook-stored-hundreds-of-millions-of-user-passwords-in-plain-text-for-years/&quot;&gt;unencrypted passwords&lt;/a&gt; for hundreds of millions of its users &lt;a class=&quot;TrackingLink LinkWrapper&quot; href=&quot;https://www.thedailybeast.com/facebook-stored-hundreds-of-millions-of-passwords-in-plain-text-report&quot;&gt;had been stored for years&lt;/a&gt; in company logs accessible to 2,000 employees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last month, amid a steady drum beat of fresh privacy scandals, Facebook founder Mark Zuckerberg unleashed a thousand-word manifesto describing  a new “privacy-focused vision” &lt;a class=&quot;TrackingLink LinkWrapper&quot; href=&quot;https://www.thedailybeast.com/mark-zuckerberg-thinks-youve-napped-through-the-last-decade&quot;&gt;for the company&lt;/a&gt; built on strong encryption and cutting-edge security tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even then, Zuckerberg acknowledged that Facebook’s putative pivot-to-privacy would meet with some skepticism. “[F]rankly we don't currently have a strong reputation for building privacy protective services.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 23:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>sharkweek</dc:creator>
<og:title>‘Beyond Sketchy’: Facebook Demands Users’ Email Passwords</og:title>
<og:description>Mark Zuckerberg admitted recently that Facebook doesn’t have a ‘strong reputation’ for privacy. An odd new request for private data probably won’t help with that rep.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.thedailybeast.com/beyond-sketchy-facebook-demanding-some-new-users-email-passwords</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://img.thedailybeast.com/image/upload/c_crop,d_placeholder_euli9k,h_1687,w_3000,x_0,y_0/dpr_2.0/c_limit,w_740/fl_lossy,q_auto/v1554247317/190402-poulsen-facebook-tease_aftcxh</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.thedailybeast.com/beyond-sketchy-facebook-demanding-some-new-users-email-passwords</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Do Buses Bunch?</title>
<link>http://setosa.io/bus/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://setosa.io/bus/</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;http://setosa.io/bus/&quot;&gt;http://setosa.io/bus/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19558482&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19558482&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 224&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 109&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 20:55:44 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>elliekelly</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://setosa.io/bus/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>No one should have to travel in fear</title>
<link>https://medium.com/@andreasgal/no-one-should-have-to-travel-in-fear-b2bff4c460e5</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://medium.com/@andreasgal/no-one-should-have-to-travel-in-fear-b2bff4c460e5</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;uiScale uiScale-ui--regular uiScale-caption--regular u-flexCenter u-marginVertical24 u-fontSize15 js-postMetaLockup&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;u-flex0&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link u-baseColor--link avatar&quot; href=&quot;https://medium.com/@andreasgal?source=post_header_lockup&quot; data-action=&quot;show-user-card&quot; data-action-source=&quot;post_header_lockup&quot; data-action-value=&quot;3408864634d7&quot; data-action-type=&quot;hover&quot; data-user-id=&quot;3408864634d7&quot; dir=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/fit/c/100/100/0*oib1wMtJ4oOIPTf7.jpeg&quot; class=&quot;avatar-image u-size50x50&quot; alt=&quot;Go to the profile of Andreas Gal&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;5b4e&quot; id=&quot;5b4e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;I’ve worked for Silicon Valley companies for more than a decade and international travel is a necessary part of my job. I’ve had my fair share of delays and missed connections, but one thing I’ve never experienced while traveling in airports is fear. That changed last December when I returned from a business trip to Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*vDdOq-Or2dTr2Z5kM4DwwA.jpeg&quot; data-width=&quot;3720&quot; data-height=&quot;2483&quot; data-is-featured=&quot;true&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*vDdOq-Or2dTr2Z5kM4DwwA.jpeg&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*vDdOq-Or2dTr2Z5kM4DwwA.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;a75c&quot; id=&quot;a75c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;Going through customs is usually routine for me. I signed up for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ttp.cbp.dhs.gov/&quot; data-href=&quot;https://ttp.cbp.dhs.gov/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Global Entry&lt;/a&gt; program years ago. It allows me to bypass lines using an electronic kiosk. With my travel schedule, Global Entry is a necessity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;8e2e&quot; id=&quot;8e2e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;On this trip, the kiosk directed me to a Customs and Border Patrol agent who kept my passport and sent me to secondary inspection. There I quickly found myself surrounded by three armed agents wearing bullet proof vests. They started to question me aggressively regarding my trip, my current employment, and my past work for Mozilla, a non-profit organization dedicated to open technology and online privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;658d&quot; id=&quot;658d&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The agents proceeded to search my belongings and demanded that I unlock my smartphone and laptop. This was rather concerning for me. My phone and laptop are property of my employer and contain unreleased software and proprietary information. I’ve signed a non-disclosure agreement promising not to give anyone access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;d2db&quot; id=&quot;d2db&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Because I was uncertain about my legal responsibilities to my employer, I asked the agents if I could speak to my employer or an attorney before unlocking my devices. This request seemed to aggravate the customs officers. They informed me that I had no right to speak to an attorney at the border despite being a U.S. citizen, and threatened me that failure to immediately comply with their demand is a violation of federal criminal code 18 USC 111.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;4605&quot; id=&quot;4605&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I’m not an attorney, and I have no prior experience with federal law enforcement, but I did study the U.S. Constitution as part of my citizenship test three years ago. I wasn’t sure what the legal definition of an unreasonable search and seizure was, but three armed men detaining me, threatening me, and refusing to allow me to consult with an attorney definitely felt like one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;3668&quot; id=&quot;3668&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I declined to answer any further questions, and continued to ask to speak to an attorney instead. The interrogation and threats continued for some time, which I endured silently. Despite initial threats that they would keep my devices if I didn’t unlock them, I was eventually permitted to leave the customs area with my devices. The customs agents did however keep my Global Entry card as a punishment for not complying with their demands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;1ac2&quot; id=&quot;1ac2&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;As I have learned since, my experience was not unique. While CBP has a long history of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gq.com/story/border-patrol-dont-call-cages-cages&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.gq.com/story/border-patrol-dont-call-cages-cages&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;mistreating foreigners, immigrants, and asylum seekers&lt;/a&gt; entering the US, more recently CBP has also started to &lt;a href=&quot;https://publicintegrity.org/immigration/shocked-and-humiliated-lawsuits-accuse-customs-border-officers-of-invasive-searches-of-minors-women/&quot; data-href=&quot;https://publicintegrity.org/immigration/shocked-and-humiliated-lawsuits-accuse-customs-border-officers-of-invasive-searches-of-minors-women/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;aggressively question&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aclu.org/blog/immigrants-rights/ice-and-border-patrol-abuses/us-border-patrol-detained-us-citizens-speaking&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.aclu.org/blog/immigrants-rights/ice-and-border-patrol-abuses/us-border-patrol-detained-us-citizens-speaking&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;unlawfully detain&lt;/a&gt;, and in some cases &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/post-nation/wp/2017/07/13/u-s-family-suing-federal-government-after-11-hour-detention-on-canadian-border/?noredirect=on&amp;amp;utm_term=.1727001cb3eb&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/post-nation/wp/2017/07/13/u-s-family-suing-federal-government-after-11-hour-detention-on-canadian-border/?noredirect=on&amp;amp;utm_term=.1727001cb3eb&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;physically assault&lt;/a&gt; U.S. citizens crossing the border. These so-called border searches are not random. NBC recently reported that CBP maintains &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/immigration/u-s-officials-made-list-reporters-lawyers-activists-question-border-n980301&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/immigration/u-s-officials-made-list-reporters-lawyers-activists-question-border-n980301&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;dossiers of U.S. citizens&lt;/a&gt; and targets lawyers, journalists, and activists, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://papersplease.org/wp/2019/01/10/cbp-finalizes-rules-for-social-media-surveillance/&quot; data-href=&quot;https://papersplease.org/wp/2019/01/10/cbp-finalizes-rules-for-social-media-surveillance/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;monitors social media activity&lt;/a&gt; of U.S. citizens. My past work on encryption and online privacy is well documented, and so is my disapproval of the Trump administration and my history of significant campaign contributions to Democratic candidates. I wonder whether these CBP programs led to me being targeted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;2a4e&quot; id=&quot;2a4e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;If the government intended to scare me, they certainly succeeded. Ever since, I travel in fear. I’ve reduced my international travel and my heart pounds every time I go through U.S. customs. I will, however, not be silent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;0072&quot; id=&quot;0072&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p graf--trailing&quot;&gt;When I became a U.S. citizen I swore to defend the Constitution. I’m a proud U.S. citizen and I take my oath seriously. It is in that spirit that I have filed a civil rights complaint with the help of the ACLU against CBP for unlawfully detaining me and violating my constitutional rights. The time is overdue for Congress to step in and provide meaningful oversight and legislation to reign in CBP’s egregious misconduct.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 20:18:40 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>geofft</dc:creator>
<og:title>No one should have to travel in fear</og:title>
<og:url>https://medium.com/@andreasgal/no-one-should-have-to-travel-in-fear-b2bff4c460e5</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*vDdOq-Or2dTr2Z5kM4DwwA.jpeg</og:image>
<og:description>I’ve worked for Silicon Valley companies for more than a decade and international travel is a necessary part of my job. I’ve had my fair…</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://medium.com/@andreasgal/no-one-should-have-to-travel-in-fear-b2bff4c460e5</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Sci-Hub and Alexandra Basic Information</title>
<link>https://engineuring.wordpress.com/2019/03/31/sci-hub-and-alexandra-basic-information/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://engineuring.wordpress.com/2019/03/31/sci-hub-and-alexandra-basic-information/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I decided to make a quick summary of facts about Sci-Hub and myself, because in our times you cannot fully trust articles published in media, Wikipedia pages. Well, they do present facts about Sci-Hub that are correct in general, but at the same time there are mistakes in minor details. These details however create incorrect impression about the project. So, I want to make a quick look-up page with basic information about Sci-Hub and me that is reliable and first-hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I will add more information to this page later&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who is Alexandra Elbakyan and how the project started?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m a computer programmer behind Sci-Hub. I created the website in September, 2011 in Almaty, Kazakhstan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Kazakhstan, my homeland, access to LiveJournal website was blocked by government. LiveJournal is a blog system, where anyone can write their articles. Hence to access LiveJournal, I had to use ‘anonymizer’ websites. You go to such a website, paste a link to any webpage — for example LiveJournal article — and you can open it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I got the idea: we need the same for research articles. It took me two or three days to write the code and upload it to free PHP webhosting. And so Sci-Hub got live, and started processing requests from users (it almost immediately became very popular)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, I had a dream to write software for easy access to research since 2009. I was an undergaduate student in Kazakh National Tech University and got into problems while trying to access research papers needed for my research project. So I thought it would be cool to write some software to automatically download such papers. However in 2009 it was only a blurry non-specific idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned HTML at age 12 using free tutorial avaiable on the Internet. I started programming in high school and first learned PHP, Delphi and Assembly programming languages on myself, before I got to the university. I was interested in information security and entered Kazakh National Tech University in 2005 to study Information Technologies with a security speicalization. Here I improved programing skills a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After graduation I wanted to continue in science and do research in bioengineering. Apart from computer and information technologies, I was interested in neuroscience, consciousness and artificial intelligence and while studying at university, collected a lot of ebooks on that topic. They were all downloaded from ‘pirate’ websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So in 2010 I tried to work in a few neuroscience research labs in Russia, Germany and United States. I read online that you can write to the professor and s/he will accept you to their lab. So I did the same and that’s how I got into laboratories. Here I also did programming, but for bioengineering applications. However I found it boring. I wanted to work on greater things: such as the Global Brain. I even was lucky to give a talk on that topic in H+ transhumanist conference in Harvard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2011 I returned to Kazakhstan and worked for a few months as a freelance web-programmer. I created websites and applications on PHP language. And finally I was able to code Sci-Hub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Was there any funding for Sci-Hub?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was no. Sci-Hub started by accident, there was no Big Plan behind it. After a couple of months, users asked to add some option to donate and help the project. Sci-Hub is living on the donations for years. There were some big donations, but there was never any specific funding behind the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Was any government involved in creating Sci-Hub?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was interested in politics and always supported communism, but Sci-Hub has always been a personal project. Even if some government helped, for example by sending anonymous donations, it was completely invisible to me. Using the Occam’s razor, no government was involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is there any team behind Sci-Hub?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, and never was. I do all the programming and server configuration myself. I also do all the Twitter posts and communication with users and media. I use Google to search for pictures to use on the website and social networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There a people though, who create mirrors of Sci-Hub articles database. I run a few mirrors and other mirrors are run independently, and Sci-Hub also uses accounts to access library resources provided by others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the relationship between Sci-Hub and Library Genesis projects?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sci-Hub started in 2011 as a web application to download research article requested by user, using library accounts. There was no storage for downloaded articles. In 2012 Library Genesis, that collected e-books, wanted to collect research articles too and started saving papers downloaded by Sci-Hub to their database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2013 the number of requests to Sci-Hub grew, and I re-programmed Sci-Hub to check if article was already stored in Libgen; if it was, the user was redirected to Libgen database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2014, I copied articles collected by Libgen to create Sci-Hub’s own database. I did not &lt;strong&gt;fork&lt;/strong&gt; Libgen: only the papers PDF files were copied. Then I configured new servers to serve these files to Sci-Hub users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today Sci-Hub uses it’s own servers to store research papers. However all new articles downloaded by Sci-Hub are mirrored to Library Genesis databases too. Libgen also publishes torrents to download these papers.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;… and question that is always asked:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How is Sci-Hub different from Aaron Swartz?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How different between each other are PLoS One, arXiv.org and Budapest Open Access Initiative? All these projects work on providing free access to research papers, however it is easy to see: there are very different between each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sci-Hub is a web application that can open research paper requested by user, from database or by downloading it. All downloaded papers are collected in database. The database grew for a few years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A. Swartz, as far as I know his story, made an attempt to download a few million research papers from JSTOR website in 2010. The download was noticed and he got arrested. Perhaps he wanted to upload all downloaded research articles on torrent. In 2009 I did similar things: I downloaded Nature and Scientific American journal volumes and uploaded them on ‘pirate’ websites where people share e-books, and I also shared there volumes on torrents. A lot of people were doing it then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2004 I even programmed a PHP script that could automatically download paywalled e-books from MIT Cognet website, using a bug. Even though it sounds very similar to Sci-Hub, it is completely different in design and function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before Sci-Hub, there were a lot of illegal websites where any person could download e-books for free. Sci-Hub became the first website where you can download articles on a massive scale, not e-books only. Before Sci-Hub there were other websites to get research papers for free but they were also different from Sci-Hub in design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are similarities with A. Swartz but to say they are the same is some kind of an illusion that arises from lack of understanding of complexity. The similar illusion is to think that all black people, or all Chinese people are the same, because white person cannot easily recognize their faces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;jp-post-flair&quot; class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-like-enabled sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;robots-nocontent sd-block sd-social sd-social-official sd-sharing&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Share this:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-block sd-like jetpack-likes-widget-wrapper jetpack-likes-widget-unloaded&quot; id=&quot;like-post-wrapper-8158657-566-5ca467f55a2be&quot; data-src=&quot;//widgets.wp.com/likes/index.html?ver=20190321#blog_id=8158657&amp;amp;post_id=566&amp;amp;origin=engineuring.wordpress.com&amp;amp;obj_id=8158657-566-5ca467f55a2be&quot; data-name=&quot;like-post-frame-8158657-566-5ca467f55a2be&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Like this:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;button&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Like&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;loading&quot;&gt;Loading...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;jp-relatedposts-headline&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Related&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 20:13:51 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>stared</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Sci-Hub and Alexandra basic information</og:title>
<og:url>https://engineuring.wordpress.com/2019/03/31/sci-hub-and-alexandra-basic-information/</og:url>
<og:description>I decided to make a quick summary of facts about Sci-Hub and myself, because in our times you cannot fully trust articles published in media, Wikipedia pages. Well, they do present facts about Sci-…</og:description>
<og:image>https://s0.wp.com/i/blank.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://engineuring.wordpress.com/2019/03/31/sci-hub-and-alexandra-basic-information/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Sweden Wants to Revive Europe’s Overnight Trains</title>
<link>https://www.citylab.com/transportation/2019/04/europe-night-train-sweden-eco-travel-sleeper-car-fossil-free/586228/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.citylab.com/transportation/2019/04/europe-night-train-sweden-eco-travel-sleeper-car-fossil-free/586228/</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;article-section-1&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the quest to reduce the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.citylab.com/transportation/2018/10/un-climate-report-transportation-choices/572494/&quot;&gt;massive carbon footprint from global transportation&lt;/a&gt;, Sweden plans to revive a staple of 20th century travel: the overnight train.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Swedish government announced Sunday that it will fund the creation of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dn.se/nyheter/politik/regeringen-satsar-50-miljoner-pa-nattag-ut-i-europa/&quot;&gt;overnight train services&lt;/a&gt; from Sweden to the European mainland. According to a statement from the Social Democrat-Green coalition government, the state will pump 50 million Kronor ($5.3 million) into creating night links by train to major European destinations, as part of a drive to give Swedes more low-carbon ways to travel long distances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn’t just promising news for people who want to see carbon emissions reduced—it’s also a major shot in the arm for Europe’s night trains overall, which have been struggling to the point of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.citylab.com/transportation/2014/10/goodnight-to-night-trains/382012/&quot;&gt;risking extinction&lt;/a&gt; in recent years. In the 20th century, such services were standard across the continent. Since around the millennium, however, a boom in low-cost airlines has bitten hard into their business, while high-speed trains have made overnight travel less necessary on many routes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;article-section-2&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We do this in order to cope with the climate, build a strong society and to achieve the goal of becoming the world’s fossil-free welfare country,” said Deputy Finance Minister and Green Party representative Per Bolund in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.regeringen.se/pressmeddelanden/2019/03/nattag-till-kontinenten/&quot;&gt;press release&lt;/a&gt;. “More and more people want to be able to travel climate-smart, both on holiday and for work. Now it is up to us politicians to contribute to the train becoming an obvious alternative for getting to [the rest of] Europe.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new funding will be used to research which routes would be most in demand, and to find companies able to run the service. This could possibly mean side-stepping the national rail company SJ (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statens_J%C3%A4rnv%C3%A4gar&quot;&gt;Statens Järnvägar&lt;/a&gt;), which currently runs one international night service (from Stockholm to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Narvik&quot;&gt;Narvik&lt;/a&gt;, Norway) but recently said it would &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thelocal.se/20190331/sweden-to-invest-in-night-trains-to-continent&quot;&gt;wait a decade&lt;/a&gt; before introducing night services to the European mainland. That delay would be in order to wait for the construction of an 11-mile-long rail tunnel between Denmark and Germany called the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.citylab.com/transportation/2015/03/the-tunnel-project-that-could-reshape-the-european-map/388652/&quot;&gt;Fehmarn Belt Fixed Link&lt;/a&gt;, which would reduce the journey time by train from Copenhagen to Hamburg from five hours to just two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s no denying that this link would make travel in the region far faster, but with construction not due to begin until 2020, the tunnel’s inauguration is too far in the distance for Sweden’s Greens. It remains to be seen whether SJ will change its mind to win the night train contract, or whether the government will choose another carrier—such as, for example, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.snalltaget.se/en/about-us&quot;&gt;Snälltåget&lt;/a&gt;, a company that currently runs Sweden’s only other international night services, from Malmö to Berlin and (again) Narvik.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;article-section-3&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;While changes in the travel industry have tended to pressure night trains off the market, it’s clear that there is still some appetite for them among travelers. When Germany’s Deutsche Bahn &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tagesspiegel.de/wirtschaft/auf-der-schiene-unterwegs-wie-die-deutsche-bahn-ihre-nachtzuege-schlechtgerechnet-hat/20748678.html&quot;&gt;halted its night services&lt;/a&gt; in 2017, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thelocal.de/20180709/berlin-budapest-one-of-three-sleeper-train-routes-to-return-to-germany-this-year&quot;&gt;Austrian Federal Railways&lt;/a&gt; took over some of the key routes. The takeover has proved to be a success, with passenger numbers on the services (whose conditions are outlined &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.seat61.com/trains-and-routes/nightjet.htm&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;) rising from 1.4 million to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.manager-magazin.de/unternehmen/artikel/nightjet-nachtzuege-der-oebb-erfolgreich-a-1246563.html&quot;&gt;1.6 million&lt;/a&gt; between 2017 and 2018, a rise in profits, and talk of expansion. Meanwhile, well-established leisure services such as the London-to-Scotland &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sleeper.scot/&quot;&gt;Caledonian Sleeper&lt;/a&gt; continue to thrive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;c-newsletter c-newsletter--promo c-newsletter--cta&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;c-newsletter__title&quot;&gt;Cities are changing fast. Keep up with the &lt;strong&gt;CityLab Daily&lt;/strong&gt; newsletter.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;label for=&quot;promo-email-input-email&quot; class=&quot;c-newsletter__cta c-newsletter__cta--promo&quot;&gt;The best way to follow issues you care about.&lt;/label&gt;

&lt;/section&gt;&lt;p&gt;The overnight train services remain popular because many people actually like them. The duration of travel, of course, is usually far longer than by plane, even when layovers and security are factored in, but there are other compensations. Generally scheduled to leave late evening and arrive before the working day begins, night trains offer the possibility of sleep and more leisurely travel compared to an early-morning rush to the airport. They can also be reasonably priced: On the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nightjet.com/reiseziele/deutschland/berlin.html&quot;&gt;Vienna-to-Berlin night service&lt;/a&gt;, for example, a one-way ticket with a reclining sleeper seat starts at €29 ($32.50), a couchette (a four- or six-person compartment whose bunks fold down into comfortable seating during the day) at €49 ($55), and a single-berth sleeper with private toilet and shower at €139 ($159). If the trip saves you the cost of a hotel room, many people seem to be noting, that’s not a bad deal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So while the outlook seemed bleak just a few years ago, Sweden’s plan arrives at a time when the sector’s fortunes seem to be brightening once more. It’s difficult to say how well the plan will fare, however, without knowing the routes. The most likely candidates for an overnight service to Sweden would be major Northern European cities such as Hamburg, Berlin, Frankfurt and Amsterdam, although other cities somewhat further afield, such as, Brussels and even Prague might be possible options too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;article-section-4&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even a successful Swedish night-train service is likely to remain a niche alternative to flying, rather than a threatening competitor. But getting more people on the rails can only have a positive effect in reducing the carbon footprint of international mobility. The idea of trains full of passengers lying asleep as their train rattles over the points may strike most of us as an image on the past. Maybe—just maybe—it could also be a vision of the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 19:42:15 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>aaronbrethorst</dc:creator>
<og:description>The government says it's the way to become &quot;the world’s fossil-free welfare country.”</og:description>
<og:image>https://cdn.citylab.com/media/img/citylab/2019/04/sweden_night_trains/facebook.jpg?1554218320</og:image>
<og:title>Why Sweden Wants to Revive Europe’s Night Trains</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.citylab.com/transportation/2019/04/europe-night-train-sweden-eco-travel-sleeper-car-fossil-free/586228/</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.citylab.com/transportation/2019/04/europe-night-train-sweden-eco-travel-sleeper-car-fossil-free/586228/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>YOLO: Real-Time Object Detection</title>
<link>https://pjreddie.com/darknet/yolo/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://pjreddie.com/darknet/yolo/</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;dnlogo&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://pjreddie.com/media/image/yologo_2.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You only look once (YOLO) is a state-of-the-art, real-time object detection system. On a Pascal Titan X it processes images at 30 FPS and has a mAP of 57.9% on COCO test-dev.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;415&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/MPU2HistivI&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Comparison to Other Detectors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YOLOv3 is extremely fast and accurate. In mAP measured at .5 IOU YOLOv3 is on par with Focal Loss but about 4x faster. Moreover, you can easily tradeoff between speed and accuracy simply by changing the size of the model, no retraining required!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://pjreddie.com/media/image/map50blue.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Performance on the COCO Dataset&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;Model&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Train&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Test&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;mAP&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;FLOPS&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;FPS&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Cfg&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Weights&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;SSD300&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;COCO trainval&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;test-dev&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;41.2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;46&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1512.02325&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;SSD500&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;COCO trainval&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;test-dev&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;46.5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;19&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1512.02325&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;YOLOv2 608x608&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;COCO trainval&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;test-dev&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;48.1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;62.94 Bn&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;40&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pjreddie/darknet/blob/master/cfg/yolov2.cfg&quot;&gt;cfg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pjreddie.com/media/files/yolov2.weights&quot;&gt;weights&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Tiny YOLO&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;COCO trainval&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;test-dev&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;23.7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5.41 Bn&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;244&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pjreddie/darknet/blob/master/cfg/yolov2-tiny.cfg&quot;&gt;cfg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pjreddie.com/media/files/yolov2-tiny.weights&quot;&gt;weights&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;SSD321&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;COCO trainval&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;test-dev&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;45.4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;16&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1701.06659&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;DSSD321&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;COCO trainval&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;test-dev&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;46.1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;12&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1701.06659&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;R-FCN&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;COCO trainval&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;test-dev&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;51.9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;12&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1605.06409&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;SSD513&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;COCO trainval&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;test-dev&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;50.4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1701.06659&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;DSSD513&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;COCO trainval&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;test-dev&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;53.3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1701.06659&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;FPN FRCN&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;COCO trainval&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;test-dev&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;59.1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1612.03144&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Retinanet-50-500&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;COCO trainval&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;test-dev&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;50.9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;14&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;a&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Retinanet-101-500&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;COCO trainval&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;test-dev&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;53.1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;a&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Retinanet-101-800&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;COCO trainval&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;test-dev&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;57.5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;a&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;YOLOv3-320&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;COCO trainval&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;test-dev&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;51.5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;38.97 Bn&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;45&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pjreddie/darknet/blob/master/cfg/yolov3.cfg&quot;&gt;cfg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pjreddie.com/media/files/yolov3.weights&quot;&gt;weights&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;YOLOv3-416&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;COCO trainval&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;test-dev&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;55.3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;65.86 Bn&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;35&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pjreddie/darknet/blob/master/cfg/yolov3.cfg&quot;&gt;cfg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pjreddie.com/media/files/yolov3.weights&quot;&gt;weights&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;YOLOv3-608&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;COCO trainval&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;test-dev&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;57.9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;140.69 Bn&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pjreddie/darknet/blob/master/cfg/yolov3.cfg&quot;&gt;cfg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pjreddie.com/media/files/yolov3.weights&quot;&gt;weights&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;YOLOv3-tiny&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;COCO trainval&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;test-dev&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;33.1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5.56 Bn&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;220&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pjreddie/darknet/blob/master/cfg/yolov3-tiny.cfg&quot;&gt;cfg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pjreddie.com/media/files/yolov3-tiny.weights&quot;&gt;weights&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;YOLOv3-spp&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;COCO trainval&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;test-dev&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;60.6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;141.45 Bn&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pjreddie/darknet/blob/master/cfg/yolov3-spp.cfg&quot;&gt;cfg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pjreddie.com/media/files/yolov3-spp.weights&quot;&gt;weights&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;h2&gt;How It Works&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior detection systems repurpose classifiers or localizers to perform detection. They apply the model to an image at multiple locations and scales. High scoring regions of the image are considered detections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use a totally different approach. We apply a single neural network to the full image. This network divides the image into regions and predicts bounding boxes and probabilities for each region. These bounding boxes are weighted by the predicted probabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://pjreddie.com/media/image/sayit.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our model has several advantages over classifier-based systems. It looks at the whole image at test time so its predictions are informed by global context in the image. It also makes predictions with a single network evaluation unlike systems like &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rbgirshick/rcnn&quot;&gt;R-CNN&lt;/a&gt; which require thousands for a single image. This makes it extremely fast, more than 1000x faster than R-CNN and 100x faster than &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rbgirshick/fast-rcnn&quot;&gt;Fast R-CNN&lt;/a&gt;. See our &lt;a href=&quot;https://pjreddie.com/media/files/papers/YOLOv3.pdf&quot;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; for more details on the full system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What's New in Version 3?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YOLOv3 uses a few tricks to improve training and increase performance, including: multi-scale predictions, a better backbone classifier, and more. The full details are in our &lt;a href=&quot;https://pjreddie.com/media/files/papers/YOLOv3.pdf&quot;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Detection Using A Pre-Trained Model&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post will guide you through detecting objects with the YOLO system using a pre-trained model. If you don't already have Darknet installed, you should &lt;a href=&quot;https://pjreddie.com/darknet/install/&quot;&gt;do that first&lt;/a&gt;. Or instead of reading all that just run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;git clone https://github.com/pjreddie/darknet
cd darknet
make
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Easy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You already have the config file for YOLO in the &lt;code&gt;cfg/&lt;/code&gt; subdirectory. You will have to download the pre-trained weight file &lt;a href=&quot;https://pjreddie.com/media/files/yolov3.weights&quot;&gt;here (237 MB)&lt;/a&gt;. Or just run this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;wget https://pjreddie.com/media/files/yolov3.weights
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then run the detector!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;./darknet detect cfg/yolov3.cfg yolov3.weights data/dog.jpg
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will see some output like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;layer     filters    size              input                output
    0 conv     32  3 x 3 / 1   416 x 416 x   3   -&amp;gt;   416 x 416 x  32  0.299 BFLOPs
    1 conv     64  3 x 3 / 2   416 x 416 x  32   -&amp;gt;   208 x 208 x  64  1.595 BFLOPs
    .......
  105 conv    255  1 x 1 / 1    52 x  52 x 256   -&amp;gt;    52 x  52 x 255  0.353 BFLOPs
  106 detection
truth_thresh: Using default '1.000000'
Loading weights from yolov3.weights...Done!
data/dog.jpg: Predicted in 0.029329 seconds.
dog: 99%
truck: 93%
bicycle: 99%
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://pjreddie.com/media/image/Screen_Shot_2018-03-24_at_10.48.42_PM.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Darknet prints out the objects it detected, its confidence, and how long it took to find them. We didn't compile Darknet with &lt;code&gt;OpenCV&lt;/code&gt; so it can't display the detections directly. Instead, it saves them in &lt;code&gt;predictions.png&lt;/code&gt;. You can open it to see the detected objects. Since we are using Darknet on the CPU it takes around 6-12 seconds per image. If we use the GPU version it would be much faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've included some example images to try in case you need inspiration. Try &lt;code&gt;data/eagle.jpg&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;data/dog.jpg&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;data/person.jpg&lt;/code&gt;, or &lt;code&gt;data/horses.jpg&lt;/code&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;detect&lt;/code&gt; command is shorthand for a more general version of the command. It is equivalent to the command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;./darknet detector test cfg/coco.data cfg/yolov3.cfg yolov3.weights data/dog.jpg
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don't need to know this if all you want to do is run detection on one image but it's useful to know if you want to do other things like run on a webcam (which you will see &lt;a href=&quot;https://pjreddie.com/darknet/yolo/#demo&quot;&gt;later on&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Multiple Images&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of supplying an image on the command line, you can leave it blank to try multiple images in a row. Instead you will see a prompt when the config and weights are done loading:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;./darknet detect cfg/yolov3.cfg yolov3.weights
layer     filters    size              input                output
    0 conv     32  3 x 3 / 1   416 x 416 x   3   -&amp;gt;   416 x 416 x  32  0.299 BFLOPs
    1 conv     64  3 x 3 / 2   416 x 416 x  32   -&amp;gt;   208 x 208 x  64  1.595 BFLOPs
    .......
  104 conv    256  3 x 3 / 1    52 x  52 x 128   -&amp;gt;    52 x  52 x 256  1.595 BFLOPs
  105 conv    255  1 x 1 / 1    52 x  52 x 256   -&amp;gt;    52 x  52 x 255  0.353 BFLOPs
  106 detection
Loading weights from yolov3.weights...Done!
Enter Image Path:
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter an image path like &lt;code&gt;data/horses.jpg&lt;/code&gt; to have it predict boxes for that image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://pjreddie.com/media/image/Screen_Shot_2018-03-24_at_10.53.04_PM.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once it is done it will prompt you for more paths to try different images. Use &lt;code&gt;Ctrl-C&lt;/code&gt; to exit the program once you are done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Changing The Detection Threshold&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By default, YOLO only displays objects detected with a confidence of .25 or higher. You can change this by passing the &lt;code&gt;-thresh &amp;lt;val&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; flag to the &lt;code&gt;yolo&lt;/code&gt; command. For example, to display all detection you can set the threshold to 0:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;./darknet detect cfg/yolov3.cfg yolov3.weights data/dog.jpg -thresh 0
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which produces:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;![][all]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that's obviously not super useful but you can set it to different values to control what gets thresholded by the model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Tiny YOLOv3&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a very small model as well for constrained environments, &lt;code&gt;yolov3-tiny&lt;/code&gt;. To use this model, first download the weights:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;wget https://pjreddie.com/media/files/yolov3-tiny.weights
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then run the detector with the tiny config file and weights:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;./darknet detect cfg/yolov3-tiny.cfg yolov3-tiny.weights data/dog.jpg
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Real-Time Detection on a Webcam&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running YOLO on test data isn't very interesting if you can't see the result. Instead of running it on a bunch of images let's run it on the input from a webcam!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To run this demo you will need to compile &lt;a href=&quot;https://pjreddie.com/darknet/install/#cuda&quot;&gt;Darknet with CUDA and OpenCV&lt;/a&gt;. Then run the command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;./darknet detector demo cfg/coco.data cfg/yolov3.cfg yolov3.weights
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YOLO will display the current FPS and predicted classes as well as the image with bounding boxes drawn on top of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will need a webcam connected to the computer that OpenCV can connect to or it won't work. If you have multiple webcams connected and want to select which one to use you can pass the flag &lt;code&gt;-c &amp;lt;num&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; to pick (OpenCV uses webcam &lt;code&gt;0&lt;/code&gt; by default).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also run it on a video file if OpenCV can read the video:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;./darknet detector demo cfg/coco.data cfg/yolov3.cfg yolov3.weights &amp;lt;video file&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's how we made the YouTube video above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Training YOLO on VOC&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can train YOLO from scratch if you want to play with different training regimes, hyper-parameters, or datasets. Here's how to get it working on the Pascal VOC dataset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Get The Pascal VOC Data&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To train YOLO you will need all of the VOC data from 2007 to 2012. You can find links to the data &lt;a href=&quot;https://pjreddie.com/projects/pascal-voc-dataset-mirror/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. To get all the data, make a directory to store it all and from that directory run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;wget https://pjreddie.com/media/files/VOCtrainval_11-May-2012.tar
wget https://pjreddie.com/media/files/VOCtrainval_06-Nov-2007.tar
wget https://pjreddie.com/media/files/VOCtest_06-Nov-2007.tar
tar xf VOCtrainval_11-May-2012.tar
tar xf VOCtrainval_06-Nov-2007.tar
tar xf VOCtest_06-Nov-2007.tar
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will now be a &lt;code&gt;VOCdevkit/&lt;/code&gt; subdirectory with all the VOC training data in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Generate Labels for VOC&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we need to generate the label files that Darknet uses. Darknet wants a &lt;code&gt;.txt&lt;/code&gt; file for each image with a line for each ground truth object in the image that looks like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;object-class&amp;gt; &amp;lt;x&amp;gt; &amp;lt;y&amp;gt; &amp;lt;width&amp;gt; &amp;lt;height&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where &lt;code&gt;x&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;y&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;width&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;height&lt;/code&gt; are relative to the image's width and height. To generate these file we will run the &lt;code&gt;voc_label.py&lt;/code&gt; script in Darknet's &lt;code&gt;scripts/&lt;/code&gt; directory. Let's just download it again because we are lazy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;wget https://pjreddie.com/media/files/voc_label.py
python voc_label.py
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a few minutes, this script will generate all of the requisite files. Mostly it generates a lot of label files in &lt;code&gt;VOCdevkit/VOC2007/labels/&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;VOCdevkit/VOC2012/labels/&lt;/code&gt;. In your directory you should see:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;ls
2007_test.txt   VOCdevkit
2007_train.txt  voc_label.py
2007_val.txt    VOCtest_06-Nov-2007.tar
2012_train.txt  VOCtrainval_06-Nov-2007.tar
2012_val.txt    VOCtrainval_11-May-2012.tar
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The text files like &lt;code&gt;2007_train.txt&lt;/code&gt; list the image files for that year and image set. Darknet needs one text file with all of the images you want to train on. In this example, let's train with everything except the 2007 test set so that we can test our model. Run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;cat 2007_train.txt 2007_val.txt 2012_*.txt &amp;gt; train.txt
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we have all the 2007 trainval and the 2012 trainval set in one big list. That's all we have to do for data setup!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Modify Cfg for Pascal Data&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now go to your Darknet directory. We have to change the &lt;code&gt;cfg/voc.data&lt;/code&gt; config file to point to your data:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;  1 classes= 20
  2 train  = &amp;lt;path-to-voc&amp;gt;/train.txt
  3 valid  = &amp;lt;path-to-voc&amp;gt;2007_test.txt
  4 names = data/voc.names
  5 backup = backup
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should replace &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;path-to-voc&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; with the directory where you put the VOC data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Download Pretrained Convolutional Weights&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For training we use convolutional weights that are pre-trained on Imagenet. We use weights from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://pjreddie.com/darknet/imagenet/#darknet53&quot;&gt;darknet53&lt;/a&gt; model. You can just download the weights for the convolutional layers &lt;a href=&quot;https://pjreddie.com/media/files/darknet53.conv.74&quot;&gt;here (76 MB)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;wget https://pjreddie.com/media/files/darknet53.conv.74
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Train The Model&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we can train! Run the command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;./darknet detector train cfg/voc.data cfg/yolov3-voc.cfg darknet53.conv.74
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Training YOLO on COCO&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can train YOLO from scratch if you want to play with different training regimes, hyper-parameters, or datasets. Here's how to get it working on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://mscoco.org/dataset/#overview&quot;&gt;COCO dataset&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Get The COCO Data&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To train YOLO you will need all of the COCO data and labels. The script &lt;code&gt;scripts/get_coco_dataset.sh&lt;/code&gt; will do this for you. Figure out where you want to put the COCO data and download it, for example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;cp scripts/get_coco_dataset.sh data
cd data
bash get_coco_dataset.sh
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now you should have all the data and the labels generated for Darknet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Modify cfg for COCO&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now go to your Darknet directory. We have to change the &lt;code&gt;cfg/coco.data&lt;/code&gt; config file to point to your data:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;  1 classes= 80
  2 train  = &amp;lt;path-to-coco&amp;gt;/trainvalno5k.txt
  3 valid  = &amp;lt;path-to-coco&amp;gt;/5k.txt
  4 names = data/coco.names
  5 backup = backup
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should replace &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;path-to-coco&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; with the directory where you put the COCO data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should also modify your model cfg for training instead of testing. &lt;code&gt;cfg/yolo.cfg&lt;/code&gt; should look like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;[net]
# Testing
# batch=1
# subdivisions=1
# Training
batch=64
subdivisions=8
....
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Train The Model&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we can train! Run the command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;./darknet detector train cfg/coco.data cfg/yolov3.cfg darknet53.conv.74
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to use multiple gpus run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;./darknet detector train cfg/coco.data cfg/yolov3.cfg darknet53.conv.74 -gpus 0,1,2,3
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to stop and restart training from a checkpoint:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;./darknet detector train cfg/coco.data cfg/yolov3.cfg backup/yolov3.backup -gpus 0,1,2,3
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; YOLOv3 on the Open Images dataset&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;wget https://pjreddie.com/media/files/yolov3-openimages.weights

./darknet detector test cfg/openimages.data cfg/yolov3-openimages.cfg yolov3-openimages.weights
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What Happened to the Old YOLO Site?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are using YOLO version 2 you can still find the site here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://pjreddie.com/darknet/yolov2/&quot;&gt;https://pjreddie.com/darknet/yolov2/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Cite&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you use YOLOv3 in your work please cite our paper!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;@article{yolov3,
  title={YOLOv3: An Incremental Improvement},
  author={Redmon, Joseph and Farhadi, Ali},
  journal = {arXiv},
  year={2018}
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 18:31:48 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>headalgorithm</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://pjreddie.com/darknet/yolo/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Editor.js – Block Styled Editor</title>
<link>https://editorjs.io/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://editorjs.io/</guid>
<description>&lt;header class=&quot;docs-header&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://editorjs.io/&quot; class=&quot;docs-header__logo&quot;&gt;
    Editor.js
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/header&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;landing-loader&quot; id=&quot;frame-loader&quot;&gt;
    &lt;svg xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot; xmlns:xlink=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink&quot; class=&quot;ldi-zbvw97&quot; viewbox=&quot;0 0 80 80&quot; preserveaspectratio=&quot;xMidYMid&quot;&gt;&lt;svg xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot; id=&quot;Layer_1&quot; viewbox=&quot;0 0 80 80&quot;&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;style&gt;&lt;![CDATA[
            .st3{fill:#dff0fc}
            .st5{fill:#69cdff}
          ]]&gt;&lt;/style&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;g class=&quot;ld ld-spin&quot;&gt;&lt;path class=&quot;st3&quot; d=&quot;M69.4 28.7c-3-2.8-6.5-4.8-10.3-6-4.6-1.5-7.7-5.8-7.7-10.6V7.5c4.9.2 9.7 1.1 14.2 2.9 7.4 2.9 9.5 12.6 3.8 18.3z&quot; fill=&quot;#dff0fc&quot;/&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;g class=&quot;ld ld-spin&quot;&gt;&lt;path class=&quot;st5&quot; d=&quot;M33 11c-4.4 1.9-8.5 4.6-12.1 8l3.2 3.2c3.4 3.4 8.6 4.2 12.9 2.1 3.6-1.8 7.5-2.8 11.6-3 0-8.1-8.2-13.5-15.6-10.3z&quot; fill=&quot;#69cdff&quot;/&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;g class=&quot;ld ld-spin&quot;&gt;&lt;path class=&quot;st3&quot; d=&quot;M10.4 34.4c-1.8 4.5-2.7 9.3-2.9 14.2H12c4.8 0 9.1-3.1 10.6-7.7 1.3-3.8 3.3-7.3 6.1-10.3-5.7-5.7-15.4-3.6-18.3 3.8z&quot; fill=&quot;#dff0fc&quot;/&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;g class=&quot;ld ld-spin&quot;&gt;&lt;path class=&quot;st5&quot; d=&quot;M11 67c1.9 4.4 4.6 8.5 8 12.1l3.2-3.2c3.4-3.4 4.2-8.6 2.1-12.9-1.8-3.6-2.8-7.5-3-11.6-8.1 0-13.5 8.2-10.3 15.6z&quot; fill=&quot;#69cdff&quot;/&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;g class=&quot;ld ld-spin&quot;&gt;&lt;path class=&quot;st5&quot; d=&quot;M89 33c-1.9-4.4-4.6-8.5-8-12.1l-3.2 3.2c-3.4 3.4-4.2 8.6-2.1 12.9 1.8 3.6 2.8 7.5 3 11.6 8.1 0 13.5-8.2 10.3-15.6z&quot; fill=&quot;#69cdff&quot;/&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;g class=&quot;ld ld-spin&quot;&gt;&lt;path class=&quot;st3&quot; d=&quot;M89.6 65.6c1.8-4.5 2.7-9.3 2.9-14.2H88c-4.8 0-9.1 3.1-10.6 7.7-1.3 3.8-3.3 7.3-6.1 10.3 5.7 5.7 15.4 3.6 18.3-3.8z&quot; fill=&quot;#dff0fc&quot;/&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;g class=&quot;ld ld-spin&quot;&gt;&lt;path class=&quot;st5&quot; d=&quot;M67 89c4.4-1.9 8.5-4.6 12.1-8l-3.2-3.2c-3.4-3.4-8.6-4.2-12.9-2.1-3.6 1.8-7.5 2.8-11.6 3 0 8.1 8.2 13.5 15.6 10.3z&quot; fill=&quot;#69cdff&quot;/&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;g class=&quot;ld ld-spin&quot;&gt;&lt;path class=&quot;st3&quot; d=&quot;M34.4 89.6c4.5 1.8 9.3 2.7 14.2 2.9V88c0-4.8-3.1-9.1-7.7-10.6-3.8-1.3-7.3-3.3-10.3-6.1-5.7 5.7-3.6 15.4 3.8 18.3z&quot; fill=&quot;#dff0fc&quot;/&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;style&gt;&lt;![CDATA[
      .ld-spin {
        will-change: transform;
      }
      @keyframes ld-spin{0%{-webkit-transform:rotate(0);transform:rotate(0);animation-timing-function:cubic-bezier(.55,.055,.675,.19)}50%{-webkit-transform:rotate(180deg);transform:rotate(180deg);animation-timing-function:cubic-bezier(.215,.61,.355,1)}to{-webkit-transform:rotate(360deg);transform:rotate(360deg)}}@-webkit-keyframes ld-spin{0%{-webkit-transform:rotate(0);transform:rotate(0);animation-timing-function:cubic-bezier(.55,.055,.675,.19)}50%{-webkit-transform:rotate(180deg);transform:rotate(180deg);animation-timing-function:cubic-bezier(.215,.61,.355,1)}to{-webkit-transform:rotate(360deg);transform:rotate(360deg)}}path{stroke-width:0}.ld.ld-spin{-webkit-animation:ld-spin 1s infinite;animation:ld-spin 1s infinite}
    ]]&gt;&lt;/style&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  

      &lt;noscript&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mc.yandex.ru/watch/53080309&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;
  </description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 16:10:30 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tortilla</dc:creator>
<og:title>Editor.js</og:title>
<og:description>A block-styled editor with clean JSON output</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://editorjs.io/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>From Show HN to Series D</title>
<link>https://segment.com/blog/show-hn-to-series-d/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://segment.com/blog/show-hn-to-series-d/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Every six months you see a post pop up on Hacker News like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/ff3etg8jeai7jel/Screenshot%202019-04-01%2018.16.54.png?raw=1&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The reality is that it’s hard to build a business from scratch. You need the right people, the right product, the right timing, and more often than not, a lot of luck. But even those things don’t guarantee success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Segment, we’ve had the incredible and unlikely fortune of building a real business in those exact conditions. We launched the very first tiny slice of our product &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=4912076&quot;&gt;6.5 years ago as a Show HN post.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We still have an enormous distance to go on our journey. &lt;strong&gt;However, today is an important milestone.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2019/04/02/1795157/0/en/Segment-Raises-175-Million-Series-D-to-Liberate-Customer-Data-from-CRM-and-Usher-in-a-New-Era-of-Customer-Relationships.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We’re announcing that we’ve raised $175M in Series D funding&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a big moment for us, and one that wouldn’t have happened without the support and feedback from all of our users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like every startup journey, we’ve had our share of ups and downs. In this post, we wanted to give you a window into Segment's journey in that first year; from the &lt;strong&gt;initial product launch&lt;/strong&gt;, to our &lt;strong&gt;first hundred customers&lt;/strong&gt;, to &lt;strong&gt;the pitch deck&lt;/strong&gt; we used to raise our first funding. For all the startups out there in a similar boat, hopefully you can take something from our experience and apply it to your own. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Six years ago, we were just four engineers sitting in an apartment on Russian Hill in San Francisco. We had 6 months of runway, and paid ourselves almost nothing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/joM5sAnXdXEmLmwS5QViHoTfHluuNHgC6N54FUJWHd9bUKQ87snhGiT0Q1USyCXDky2hTG6ggpbkYWQ4Bt2onX0GLwmS9inKCWqAIKsVyQCL_SliUd6P81SbviJu5eLGhsEt0yu0ZEA&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the story of our first year after launching on HN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s start in December, 2012. At the time, the four of us had been working on failed ideas for 18 months. We had 9 months of runway left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To give you the hyper-abbreviated timeline up until this point:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May 2011:&lt;/strong&gt; we were accepted to Y Combinator as part of their summer 2011 batch (as an Edtech startup!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;September 2011:&lt;/strong&gt; we finished the YC batch, raised a seed round, and moved to Boston &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;October 2011:&lt;/strong&gt; after thousands of lines of code, we realized our Edtech startup did not have product market fit, so we pivoted to building a Mixpanel competitor focused on segmentation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May 2012:&lt;/strong&gt; we moved back to SF&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;December 2012:&lt;/strong&gt; 6 product iterations later, nothing was working. We were trying to decide between a group trip planner and what eventually became Segment. It was a dark time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;We realized we had only one last shot. So we decided to open source a library we’d built to send our analytics data to all of the different analytics tools (including our Mixpanel competitor) via a single API. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time, it was a just &lt;strong&gt;a 400-line javascript&lt;/strong&gt; file that could send data to &lt;strong&gt;eight&lt;/strong&gt; destinations: &lt;strong&gt;Google Analytics, KISSmetrics, Mixpanel, Intercom, Customer.io, CrazyEgg, Olark,&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Chartbeat.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/21ua999t97c86px/Screenshot%202019-03-28%2017.35.41.png?raw=1&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Papering over these different APIs seemed like an almost trivial problem… but one that had clearly annoyed us enough to write some code to solve it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We debated internally for 5 days whether this weekend project was actually a viable business. We kept going round in circles, coming up with arguments for and against the idea. Try as we might, we couldn’t come to a consensus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we put it to the test. On 12/12/12, &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=4912076&quot;&gt;we launched it on HN&lt;/a&gt;, and the response was startling:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/q8kr4zw8inv3xkp/Screenshot%202019-03-28%2017.23.18.png?raw=1&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The post sat at the top of Hacker News all day with hundreds of upvotes, dozens of comments, and hundreds of tweets. But most surprisingly, professional engineers were saying “we need this at work.”  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were blown away. We’d finally hit a real problem - but whether we could build a business remained to be seen. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had put up a landing page at segment.io to test whether users wanted a hosted version. We told them to leave their email and then we’d get back to them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That day, we got hundreds of emails like the one below, coming in at all hours of day and night:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/9akg2euk967rtep/interested-signup.png?raw=1&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;We’d finally built something people wanted! We’d finally tapped into something with real potential, and started solving a real business problem. So we hacked for seven days straight to deliver the first version of the product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was minimal — all it did was host Analytics.js for users. They could turn on any of our 10 integrations, enter their configuration, and we would render a custom version behind a Cloudfront CDN.  We’d also collect these events via our Node API, and show the events in in a dashboard, but there wasn’t any data actively being proxied through our servers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/jyhi8bv345jhzww/Screenshot%202019-03-28%2017.58.34.png?raw=1&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The winter holidays were the first time we’d consistently had a steady stream of traffic on our API. We were seeing tens of requests per second come in around the clock. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a far cry from the hundreds of thousands of requests we see today, but it was at least a start:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/GC1ye1sJo0OwhBzWEskusGL0WdWXLxc-kz0dP9H1B1z5yA-j4uqqmpKjpFPMyAb44AjDBrPHDaJlta6mJ9BO370lfcupr1b6ssdEN7QZ6lehm0lsMld4KjI1bVd2Fnqil-ihJbEpg90&quot;/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We came back in January and started going “all in” on Segment.io.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We pitched a few different press outlets to finally announce that we had been funded by YC. We were fortunate enough that &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2013/01/25/yc-backed-segment-io-lets-developers-integrate-with-multiple-analytics-providers-in-hours-not-weeks/&quot;&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2013/01/25/yc-backed-segment-io-lets-developers-integrate-with-multiple-analytics-providers-in-hours-not-weeks/&quot;&gt;wrote about our story.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://paper-attachments.dropbox.com/s_46584B2C564A5E58FAAE704E15060C7254E69C53C7B7A2AD131CC7D48A8C537D_1553834110793_Screenshot+from+2019-03-28+21-34-55.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Spurred on by our early user adoption and attention from press, we next turned our focus towards building features. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most valuable thing we ever did at this stage was enable livechat via &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.olark.com/&quot;&gt;Olark&lt;/a&gt;. It gave us an unparalleled window into what users were asking for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike our earlier ideas, we were now getting &lt;em&gt;constant&lt;/em&gt; feedback on the product. People would start using the product and then just kept asking us for more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/cw8f71d5io12fnm/olark.png?raw=1&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was an invigorating feeling for us. Instead of making vague guesses at what users might want… they told us outright!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we had the very early ‘taste’ of product market fit, we started building like mad. We took a leaf from &lt;a href=&quot;http://paulgraham.com/startuplessons.html&quot;&gt;Paul Graham’s&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://paulgraham.com/startuplessons.html&quot;&gt;(pg)&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://paulgraham.com/startuplessons.html&quot;&gt;startup lessons:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://paper-attachments.dropbox.com/s_46584B2C564A5E58FAAE704E15060C7254E69C53C7B7A2AD131CC7D48A8C537D_1554084592164_Screenshot+from+2019-03-31+19-09-38.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;We took his advice. We kept talking to users and launching features to see what would stick. In those first four months, we added:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;2.5&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6 client libraries&lt;/strong&gt;: Node, Ruby, Python, Java, .NET, PHP &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;23&lt;/strong&gt; server-side integrations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2 mobile libraries&lt;/strong&gt; and native integrations for iOS + Android &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Throughout that time, we only had one medium to announce our products: our &lt;strong&gt;blog&lt;/strong&gt;. We had no real press contacts, no analyst relations, and we certainly didn’t have any money to buy ads. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we built and built, and we highlighted what we had built in our blog…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While publishing on our blog certainly helped us get the word out about what we were building, there was one problem with it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We felt like it didn’t quite capture all of the questions our users had. It helped answer the question “what’s new with Segment?” But it totally ignored the question of “how should I think about analytics?” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back then, analytics was a relatively new concept for many companies. It wasn’t enough to just talk about features; we needed to help businesses understand the most effective ways to use them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To help answer this question, we launched &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/academy/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Analytics Academy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/academy/&quot;&gt;.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Analytics Academy was our first foray into trying to create our own content marketing. We launched it over email to our users (as well as launching it &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=5183824&quot;&gt;on HN&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://paper-attachments.dropbox.com/s_46584B2C564A5E58FAAE704E15060C7254E69C53C7B7A2AD131CC7D48A8C537D_1554089035368_Screenshot+from+2019-03-31+20-23-39.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The premise was simple. Each week, we’d release a new lesson promising to take you from zero to analytics expert. We hoped that it would be a good way to spread all of knowledge we’d gained from working in the analytics ecosystem for the past year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://paper-attachments.dropbox.com/s_46584B2C564A5E58FAAE704E15060C7254E69C53C7B7A2AD131CC7D48A8C537D_1554089261000_Screenshot+from+2019-03-31+20-27-16.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once again, it seemed like we’d hit on something that people wanted! The whole analytics ecosystem was confusing… there were hundreds of different vendors… and our content seemed like it could actually teach our users something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trouble was, it didn’t seem like our content was landing. We weren’t seeing it get re-shared, and the posts didn’t seem to resonate. It all felt lame compared to our earlier success on the blog. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ilya (one of the four of us) sent a draft post to his brother, Mike, who runs his own bootstrapped startup to ask for his feedback. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mike had some brutal, but honest criticism for us on a post we did about Live Chat tools. He sent us back this email:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;19&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question is, do &lt;strong&gt;I feel I learned something unique/valuable from this article? I didn’t think so.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you guys give me something valuable here?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Which chat products are better at what? / how are they different?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- How do you deal with chat volume? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- What are some best ways to use the customer feedback?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bottom line, &lt;strong&gt;give me some juicy knowledge that (a) puts me at ease with adding live chat and (b) gives me specific techniques for benefiting from it. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He pointed out that the Academy posts had piqued his interest… but not really delivered on their core goal: &lt;em&gt;to teach him about analytics.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We set out to do better with the next posts. For each one we focused on a set of specifics. Things that he could immediately take away to help his business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By March, we’d gotten to a better spot:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://paper-attachments.dropbox.com/s_A78A8915BAB12839AFCC9ED17A310BA0491208035A2B51FD54914A43D4E844CA_1554175183407_image_preview+new.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;That lesson has really stuck with us ever since. It’s been our goal for everything that goes on our blog that the content should be both specific and actionable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ended up publishing six different tutorials, from dashboarding to live chat and email tools. It wasn’t easy, but now the academy is still one of our most popular pieces of content to date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite our first taste of success in product-market fit, we started to hit some serious problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In May, our funding was starting to dry up. We still hadn’t started charging for the product, and we were looking at about three months of runway. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We set out to raise $1m as part of a bigger seed round at an $8m valuation. We had public pricing on our site, promising traction and a lot of momentum, but we were still pre-revenue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peter was doing the fundraising, and reached out to all of the investors on our radar. Of the dozens of emails we sent, 3 replied. Among them were e.Ventures and KPCB. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To give you an idea of where the business was at, I’ve included the full set of slides from our &lt;strong&gt;2013 “Series Seed” pitch deck&lt;/strong&gt; down below. Following &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.ycombinator.com/intro-to-the-yc-seed-deck/&quot;&gt;the advice of YC&lt;/a&gt;, we included: 1) extremely clear descriptions of the product 2) the relevant pre-revenue metrics 3) a set of ideas for the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slides 1 &amp;amp; 2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We started with a simple description of the product, and a few screenshots to give investors a grounding in what Segment does. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/kxowq4zy0lutapv/Screenshot%202019-03-28%2015.52.44.png?raw=1&quot;/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/jzztknkujcc2ay1/Screenshot%202019-03-28%2015.55.09.png?raw=1&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;At its heart, Segment is a technical product, so explaining what it does and how it works is key. We’d just launched our mobile libraries a few weeks before, and we were riding off the momentum of our new releases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slides 3 &amp;amp; 4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next came our growth numbers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/hqfx5oq8jlpglm0/Screenshot%202019-03-28%2015.56.10.png?raw=1&quot;/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/cfkxt2cyn03tul8/Screenshot%202019-03-28%2016.04.06.png?raw=1&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The primary metric that mattered to us &lt;strong&gt;was the number of new projects&lt;/strong&gt; (our name for sources at the time) &lt;strong&gt;sending data.&lt;/strong&gt; Our pricing was based upon data volume, and each new project would be paying us at least $10 a month. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The charts shown in the second slide were the ones that we were looking at week over week. Oddly enough, instead of using an analytics tool (we use Mode over Redshift today), we had hooked up a Google sheet. We’ve always loved being able to look at the raw data. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The top left graph shows the number of active projects sending data. You can see that it grows linearly, sometimes dipping on weekends when the smaller projects sent no data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bottom left graph shows the percentage of signups who are actually creating a project (the first step in our funnel). The bottom right graph shows the percentage of projects that actually get to the point of sending data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We put these up on a dashboard in our apartment and monitored them religiously. You can see where we fixed our signup flow to ‘auto-create’ projects about two weeks in, and steadily started seeing higher levels of activation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slides 5 &amp;amp; 6&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we didn’t have much (read: next-to-zero) revenue to speak of at this point, we thought ‘social proof’ would be better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/tihxe4ajp14bpzv/Screenshot%202019-03-28%2016.06.32.png?raw=1&quot;/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/djzlc4wqr0g70yw/Screenshot%202019-03-28%2016.17.27.png?raw=1&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;This last slide became pivotal when we later went to raise our Series A, though looking back on it, we realize how cheeky it was to include at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we made it clear to investors, none of these companies actually &lt;em&gt;used&lt;/em&gt; Segment at the time. They had all expressed interest, and the intent of things they wanted to do. But we hadn’t convinced any of them to actually use the product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we began to raise our Series A one year later, we re-presented this same exact slide, but proudly noted: &lt;em&gt;“a year ago, these six prospects expressed interest. Today, five of the six names on here have become customers.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Segment was here to stay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slides 7 &amp;amp; 8&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To really drive the point home, we included a few slides positioning ourselves in the market, how we might monetize, and spelled out the benefits of using Segment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://paper-attachments.dropbox.com/s_A78A8915BAB12839AFCC9ED17A310BA0491208035A2B51FD54914A43D4E844CA_1554174535411_Screen+Shot+2019-04-01+at+8.08.24+PM.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s changed the most today is how we monetize.&lt;/strong&gt; Back then we thought revenue sharing with partners might be a good idea, but that ended up being a small revenue stream and a conflict of interest in advising customers on the best tools, so we no longer practice revenue sharing with our partners. Instead, we only receive revenue from our customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/9y8dazqzgpufmku/Screenshot%202019-03-28%2016.27.07.png?raw=1&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We no longer charge for premium integrations either&lt;/strong&gt;. We realized quickly that users get the most value from Segment when they integrate more tools. Making users think twice before enabling an integration felt like it was hurting our customers and ourselves more than it helped. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slide 9&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, we wanted to share a few of our ideas for the future. Building a simple way to integrate different tools felt like step 1 for Segment. We saw our bigger path forward as creating the platform for customer data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/ukicn4klrp4m7y8/Screenshot%202019-03-28%2016.29.57.png?raw=1&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;We eventually integrated with 2/3 of these companies (we never got the chance with &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2015/04/20/amazons-aws-acquired-amiato/&quot;&gt;Amiato, who was acquired by Amazon&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the launch of our &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/blog/the-growth-stacks-of-2019/&quot;&gt;Developer Center last month&lt;/a&gt;, this promise has become more and more of a reality. Since that time, &lt;strong&gt;we’ve added 180 integrations.&lt;/strong&gt; In the past month alone, we’ve added &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/webaficionado/status/1103012975894392832&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;25 new integrations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, all built atop Segment Data. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slides 10 &amp;amp; 11&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we explained our ambitions: to be the infrastructure that lets you manage your customer data. As we’ve grown, this pitch has been largely consistent. Segment is &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; place to send your first-party data. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://paper-attachments.dropbox.com/s_A78A8915BAB12839AFCC9ED17A310BA0491208035A2B51FD54914A43D4E844CA_1554174734241_Screen+Shot+2019-04-01+at+8.11.53+PM.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;We wrapped up by sharing every credential we could find within reach. It was a short list for four people who had never worked ‘real’ jobs before… 2 years of experience was enough to make us dangerous though  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/pbjbww03pg06f6l/Screenshot%202019-03-28%2017.21.01.png?raw=1&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;And that was it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We closed $2M in new funding from e.ventures and KPCB, which gave us the necessary runway to make it through the next year, and blow past our first milestone of $1M in annual recurring revenue. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s the email Peter sent to Ray, our partner at KPCB, just after the round closed at $2m raised on $10.5m post-money valuation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://paper-attachments.dropbox.com/s_A78A8915BAB12839AFCC9ED17A310BA0491208035A2B51FD54914A43D4E844CA_1554174884672_Screenshot+2019-03-28+15+new.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;We began hiring for engineering, customer success, and sales that November. And we had our first annual contracts booked in November 2013. We grew from 4 to 10 people that year, and set ourselves on the road to scaling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since those early days, Segment has grown enormously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;17.839285714286&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;analytics.js from the original Show HN is now loaded &lt;strong&gt;15 billion&lt;/strong&gt; distinct times per month across &lt;strong&gt;1 billion&lt;/strong&gt; distinct devices&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;our data volume has grown by &lt;strong&gt;10,000x&lt;/strong&gt;, now processing &lt;strong&gt;over 100,000 messages per second&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;2.8529411764706&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;we now power the customer data infrastructure for some of the worlds largest brands, including &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/industry/enterprise/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IBM&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/industry/enterprise/&quot;&gt;,&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/industry/enterprise/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;21st Century Fox, Intuit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/industry/enterprise/&quot;&gt;, and&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/industry/enterprise/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;VMWare&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-0.4&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;we’ve re-branded from &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=8427713&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Segment.io to Segment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=8427713&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(and&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=8427713&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;got the .com!)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;we’ve expanded the Segment platform and grown our integrations catalog from &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/catalog/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8 integrations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/catalog/&quot;&gt;to&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/catalog/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;more than 250&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;our users now enable over &lt;strong&gt;80,000&lt;/strong&gt; new destinations over the course of the year, which equates to one integration enabled every &lt;strong&gt;1.4 minutes&lt;/strong&gt; of every workday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;0.484375&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;we’ve built out detailed views for understanding both &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/blog/the-new-live-debugger/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;data coming in to Segment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/blog/new-data-visibility-features/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;data going out to all of our destinations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;1.3555555555556&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;we’ve added &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/blog/introducing-segment-warehouses-redshift-postgres/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;support for data warehouses&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and ETL from &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/blog/introducing-sources-your-data-together/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cloud sources like&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/blog/introducing-sources-your-data-together/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/blog/introducing-sources-your-data-together/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tripe,&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/blog/introducing-sources-your-data-together/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/blog/introducing-sources-your-data-together/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;alesforce, and&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/blog/introducing-sources-your-data-together/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Z&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/blog/introducing-sources-your-data-together/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;endesk&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, syncing 20B+ rows each day &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;we’ve added &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/blog/exactly-once-delivery/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;d&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/blog/exactly-once-delivery/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;e-&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/blog/exactly-once-delivery/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;d&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/blog/exactly-once-delivery/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;uplication to ensure messages&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; are processed correctly even in the face of flaky networks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;we’ve re-written our core pipeline to &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/blog/introducing-centrifuge/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;improve the delivery and retry behavior in the face of downstream failures&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;0.14864864864865&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;released a &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/blog/config-api-convenient-and-extensible-workspace-configuration/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;public API for managing workspaces, sources, and destinations &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;0.69473684210526&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;launched &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/blog/put-your-customers-first-with-personas/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;our second product, Personas,&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; which provides audience management atop our core product&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;1.281045751634&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;released our third product, &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/blog/introducing-protocols/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Protocols, a product to help enforce your tracking plan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and our users have created &lt;strong&gt;500&lt;/strong&gt; different tracking plans for customers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;become &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/security/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ISO certified,&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/security/&quot;&gt;and released a new&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/security/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bug bounty program&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the team has grown from &lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;350+&lt;/strong&gt;, now spread across &lt;strong&gt;5 offices&lt;/strong&gt; globally&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;To power all of those product improvements, we’ve also made a number of infrastructure changes. Since our first launch in 2012, we:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, some things haven’t changed. Our blog is still our primary avenue for launching product. We keep open-sourcing our internal tools to share with the community. We keep reading every HN comment and tweet about the business. And we continue to share what we’ve learned. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of all, we’ve just kept trying to build momentum and create value for our customers. Not all of our bets have panned out. But as long as we continue to make bets, &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; of them will. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this most recent fundraise, we have three new ways we want to serve our customers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Continue building out the platform&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past 6 years, we’ve gone from &lt;strong&gt;8&lt;/strong&gt; integrations to more than &lt;strong&gt;250&lt;/strong&gt;. This year, we are focusing on expanding on that number in a major way. We’ll be continuing to provide more powerful ways to integrate via our &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/partners/integration/&quot;&gt;developer center&lt;/a&gt;, and continuing to onboard new partners into the Segment ecosystem. This month alone, we’ve added &lt;strong&gt;25 new partners integrated with Segment.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Iterating on our pricing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve heard the feedback that our pricing can be expensive for early-stage, high volume, consumer-focused startups.  We’ve already taken a first step to address this with &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/industry/startups/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;our startup program&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/industry/startups/&quot;&gt;gives away two years of Segment for free&lt;/a&gt;. And as we speak we’re working with startups all over the world to figure out a pricing structure that will work better for them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Giving you superpowers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our renewed goal this year is to “give you superpowers”. We have a number of products in our pipeline that should give you unparalleled ways of managing your data pipelines, all without changing your tracking code. Advanced filtering, workflows, and privacy products are coming down the pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;On a more personal note, we want to thank everyone who has been along for the ride. To this day, the four of us still re-forward 5-year-old emails from our earliest users and customers. Your excitement about the product gave us the conviction to keep building.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without you, Segment would have been another failed side project. With your help, we’re now able to help thousands of business provide world-class experiences for their customers. And tomorrow, we’re looking forward to helping tens of thousands more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-The Segment Founders&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 15:22:48 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>fullung</dc:creator>
<og:title>From Show HN to Series D</og:title>
<og:url>https://segment.com/blog</og:url>
<og:description></og:description>
<og:image>https://assets.contents.io/asset_PD2Ig3qA.png</og:image>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://segment.com/blog/show-hn-to-series-d/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>What comes after open source</title>
<link>https://words.steveklabnik.com/what-comes-after-open-source</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://words.steveklabnik.com/what-comes-after-open-source</guid>
<description>&lt;time datetime=&quot;2019-04-02&quot; class=&quot;article_time&quot;&gt;April 2, 2019&lt;/time&gt;&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://words.steveklabnik.com/the-culture-war-at-the-heart-of-open-source&quot;&gt;a previous post&lt;/a&gt;, I discussed the history of open source, and ended with this claim:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;large&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today’s developers have never learned about this history, or don’t care about it, or actively think it’s irrelevant. … For the same reasons that “open source” came up with a new name, I think the movement that will arise from today’s developers will also need a new name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We talked about the ideological history of open source, but that’s not what developers object to, really. I don’t think developers are moving back towards a world of making source code private. Instead, it’s something related to a very old discussion in free software. To quote &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/philosophy/free-sw.en.html&quot;&gt;the FSF&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;large&quot; readability=&quot;19&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Free software” means software that respects users’ freedom and community. Roughly, it means that the users have the freedom to run, copy, distribute, study, change and improve the software. Thus, “free software” is a matter of liberty, not price. To understand the concept, you should think of “free” as in “free speech,” not as in “free beer”. We sometimes call it “libre software,” borrowing the French or Spanish word for “free” as in freedom, to show we do not mean the software is gratis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a similar fashion, I don’t think that developers are turning against the concept of “free as in free speech”. I think that they don’t believe that the current definitions of free software and open source actually produce software that is “free as in speech.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-does-quotfreedomquot-mean-anyway_2&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;head_anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://words.steveklabnik.com/what-comes-after-open-source#what-does-quotfreedomquot-mean-anyway_2&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;What does “freedom” mean anyway?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What “free as in speech” means is itself, yet another schism between different camps in the Free Software/Open Source camp. At the root of this schism is a difference of &lt;em&gt;strategy&lt;/em&gt;. The specific tactic is straightforward: there are two kinds of licenses, and which do you choose? The two kinds are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;permissive&lt;/em&gt; licenses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;viral&lt;/em&gt; licenses if you don’t like them, &lt;em&gt;copyleft&lt;/em&gt; licenses if you do&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open Source advocates prefer permissive licenses, and Free Software advocates prefer viral/copyleft licenses. What’s the difference? Well, that’s the topic for a different essay. Because here’s the thing: the jig is up. We’ve already hit the root problem. And you probably didn’t even notice. It took me a long, long time to notice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I expose the trick, a personal interlude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;losing-my-religion_2&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;head_anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://words.steveklabnik.com/what-comes-after-open-source#losing-my-religion_2&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;Losing my religion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to be a card-carrying, passionate advocate of Free Software. I used to see Stallman lecture. I only installed Free Software on my personal computer to the fullest extent possible. I was considering buying a coreboot-compatible laptop to get rid of the rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then, slowly, I stopped caring. It felt really similar to when I decided to leave Catholicism. I started noticing that these beliefs weren’t really actually helpful, and were frankly, mostly harmful. Now, I’m not saying Free Software is harmful. What I am saying is that refusing to use a wifi connection on your laptop because there aren’t free drivers helps basically nobody, and only harms yourself. Even if you are the kind of person who thinks boycotts work, there just aren’t enough free software diehards to form a large enough boycott. And even then, you’d want to do the boycott &lt;em&gt;together&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;simultaneously&lt;/em&gt;, to send the message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realized that a lot of software I used was under a permissive license, and even though I’d prefer if it was GPL’d, the only way to actually realize the dream of improving the software thanks to the source I’d been given was to contribute back, under those terms. So I started to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And at that point, the permissive licenses were becoming more and more popular. So I found myself in a strange position: even though I was a passionate Free Software advocate, I found myself near-exclusively building Open Source software. All around me, I saw the assault on copyleft, from all sides. And copyleft was losing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At some point, I just stopped caring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;free-software-and-open-source-are-about-licen_2&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;head_anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://words.steveklabnik.com/what-comes-after-open-source#free-software-and-open-source-are-about-licen_2&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;Free Software and Open Source are about licenses&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that out of the way, here’s the problem: note that I seamlessly switched above from talking about what Free Software and Open Source &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt;, to immediately talking about &lt;em&gt;licenses.&lt;/em&gt; This is because these two things are effectively synonymous. Quoting &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/licenses/licenses.html&quot;&gt;the FSF again&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;large&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Published software should be free software. To make it free software, you need to release it under a free software license.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://opensource.org/osd&quot;&gt;OSI&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;large&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open source doesn’t just mean access to the source code. The distribution terms of open-source software must comply with the following criteria:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both Free Software and Open Source are, almost by definition, specific design constraints on software licenses. While this started with the FSF, the OSI inherited it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think a quote from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/licenses/licenses.html#WhatIsCopyleft&quot;&gt;further down the FSF’s page&lt;/a&gt; really drives this home:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;large&quot; readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To copyleft a program, we first state that it is copyrighted; then we add distribution terms, which are a legal instrument that gives everyone the rights to use, modify, and redistribute the program’s code or any program derived from it but only if the distribution terms are unchanged. Thus, the code and the freedoms become legally inseparable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The FSF sees copyleft, and therefore copyright, as a legal tool to enforce software freedom. This sometimes puts Free Software advocates in a strange position. For example, they will &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fsf.org/campaigns/drm.html&quot;&gt;campaign passionately against Digital Rights Management&lt;/a&gt;, a software tool to protect copyrighted works, yet also &lt;a href=&quot;https://fsfe.org/news/2019/news-20190326-01.en.html&quot;&gt;support expanding copyright in some cases&lt;/a&gt; when it can further the aims of the GPL. (Due to controversy, they’ve stepped back a bit since, as you can see.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;licenses-are-not-sufficient_2&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;head_anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://words.steveklabnik.com/what-comes-after-open-source#licenses-are-not-sufficient_2&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;Licenses are not sufficient&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why is it a problem that the concepts of free software and open source are intrinsically tied to licenses? It’s that the aims and goals of both of these movements are about &lt;em&gt;distribution&lt;/em&gt; and therefore &lt;em&gt;consumption&lt;/em&gt;, but what people care about most today is about the &lt;em&gt;production&lt;/em&gt; of software. Software licences regulate &lt;em&gt;distribution&lt;/em&gt;, but cannot regulate &lt;em&gt;production&lt;/em&gt;. (technically they can, but practically, they can’t. I get into this below.) This is also the main challenge of whatever comes after open source; they cannot rely on the legal tactics of the last generation. I don’t have solutions here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s talk about what developers want first, and then we’ll get into why licenses can’t accomplish this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;developers-care-about-production_2&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;head_anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://words.steveklabnik.com/what-comes-after-open-source#developers-care-about-production_2&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;Developers care about production&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://words.steveklabnik.com/the-culture-war-at-the-heart-of-open-source&quot;&gt;my previous post&lt;/a&gt;, I claimed that developers are mostly confused about open source. Here’s two concrete examples of what I mean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;4.316742081448&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine a company wants to take some open source software using a permissive license and use it in their product. In the course of using it in their product, they improve it. Are they required to give anything back to the parent project, at all?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;5.6614420062696&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine a company wants to take some free software using a copyleft license and use it in their product. In the course of using it in their product, they improve it. In order to comply with the license, they include a line in their 250 page “software license agreement” that says “Certain components of the software, and third party open source programs&lt;br/&gt;included with the software, have been or may be made available by $COMPANY on its Open Source&lt;br/&gt;web site (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.opensource.mycompany.com/&quot;&gt;http://www.opensource.mycompany.com/&lt;/a&gt;”. That web site contains zip files with the contents of the (heavily modified) source. Are they required to do anything more than that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;When presenting these questions to most developers today, I suspect you’d get these answers to these two questions, in order:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;-0.5&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, and that’s why open source is such a mess; companies take and don’t give back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;… that sounds extremely shady.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Those of you who have been around the block a few times may recognize situation number two: it’s what Apple did with WebKit. There was a project called KHTML, which was licensed under the GPL. Apple forked it, and in order to comply with the GPL, did exactly the above. They were completely within their rights to do so. Yet, many recognized, even at this time, that this “wasn’t in the spirit of open source.” These tactics are sometimes called “source dumps” or “code bombs.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that attitude, that this may be following the letter, &lt;em&gt;but not the spirit&lt;/em&gt;, is the crux of it here. Most developers don’t understand open source to be a particular license that certain software artifacts are in compliance with, but an attitude, an ideology. And that ideology isn’t just about the consumption of the software, but also its production. An open source project should have a public bug tracker. There should be a mailing list, for discussion. You should be able to observe, and ideally participate in, the development of the software. Focusing on the code being open is putting the cart before the horse. In fact, this is one of the reasons why there’s such derision for “source available” licenses; it’s not about the source being open. It’s that the source being open is a necessary, but not sufficient, component of being open source. Now, this is normally framed as a problem of distribution, but I think that many also understand it as a problem of production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe that this focus on process is why the GNU project has fallen out of favor as well. The tools that the GNU project uses to develop its Free Software are arcane, ugly, and unique to them. It’s the same with many of the old-school Open Source projects as well. If I never have to look at a Bugzilla instance again, I will die happy. This is why GitHub took off; it provided a significantly nicer developer experience for building software. You may not personally agree, but the numbers speak for themselves. The FSF didn’t move to GitHub because GitHub is proprietary, and they see that as inconsistent with their values. Most developers see that you can use it for no money, and that the software produced with it is open source. They see this as consistent with their values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When developers talk about problems they see in open source, it’s often that there are production problems. Companies don’t “give back” money or developer hours. Programmers today don’t seem to be upset that, if they’ve developed any proprietary extensions to their open source software, that those extensions are not shared back with the community. They care that the production process is impeded by additional pressure, without providing resources. If a company were to add a proprietary feature to an open source project, yet pays five employees to develop the open source part further, the FSF sees this as a tragedy. The commons has not been enriched. The new generation of open source developers sees this as a responsible company that thankfully is contributing to the development of something they use and care about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Software licenses can only restrict what people can do when they distribute the source code, and that’s it. It cannot force someone to have a bug tracker, or a code of conduct, or accept your patch. Copyleft can force an absolute minimal “contribution” back to your project, but it can’t force a good-faith one. This makes it an inadequate tool towards building something with the kinds of values that many developers care about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-challenges_2&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;head_anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://words.steveklabnik.com/what-comes-after-open-source#the-challenges_2&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;The challenges&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How would one go about building a software movement around the open &lt;em&gt;production&lt;/em&gt; of software? There are a number of challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, do you even want the legal system to enforce such a thing? There are pros and cons. Without legal teeth, companies are unlikely to comply. That’s part of why we’re in this mess to begin with!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, so you want the legal system to somehow enforce this kind of control over the production of software. But how? If we look closer at the strategy used by Free Software and Open Source, they use licenses, which are a form of intellectual property law, which is modeled after property law. Earlier, I said that you can’t use licenses to regulate production, and that’s &lt;em&gt;technically&lt;/em&gt; not true. For example, say that I own a brand, like McDonalds. I own the intellectual property surrounding that brand. I can licence that intellectual property to others, contingent on them producing hamburgers (and whatever else) in a certain way, according to my specification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This doesn’t really work with the way that open source is set up. The entities are in reverse here; it’s the software developers that want to be able to dictate things, but it’s the project that sets the license terms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That got me thinking about a different pattern for doing this kind of thing. Have you ever seen one of these?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://svbtleusercontent.com/wWhQCoC3mGGKwQ1nS6CC9H0xspap.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://svbtleusercontent.com/wWhQCoC3mGGKwQ1nS6CC9H0xspap_small.gif&quot; alt=&quot;1280px-USDA_organic_seal.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This image on a product is part of a process called “certification.” The image itself is referred to as a “certification mark.” In order to use this image on your product, you apply to a “certification body”, in this case, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usda.gov/&quot;&gt;USDA&lt;/a&gt;. This body has set up some kind of tests, and if your product passes them, you gain the ability to say that you’ve passed the certification. I chose organic food on purpose here; most aspects of this certification are about the process by which the food is produced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technology is no stranger to these kinds of processes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://svbtleusercontent.com/fMstP8GhZwpMhHxNdZ3aTn0xspap.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://svbtleusercontent.com/fMstP8GhZwpMhHxNdZ3aTn0xspap_small.png&quot; alt=&quot;windows-certified.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So in theory, one could imagine an organization that produces a different kind of document. Instead of a license for the source code, they would provide a way to say uh, let’s go with “Open Development Certified.” Projects could then submit for certification, they’d get accepted or rejected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not confident this solution would work, however.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For one, even though some parts of our industry have accepted certifications, I feel like software developers have a pretty big bias against them. Beyond that, there’s two other major questions: who would do this certification, and how would they determine the criteria? It’s not clear who has the moral authority to suggest that they are the arbiter of what is correct here, and that a majority of people would agree. And then they would have a big job of actually determining what those sets of rules would be. It does have a nice property of a built-in business model; you can charge for application for the certification. But that also has a host of issues. And even if you sort all of that out, it runs afoul of the same “boycott” problems that I talked about above with Free Software. This certification only makes sense if people demand that the software they use is Open Development Certified. I’m not sure that this would be the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another option is some sort of “Developer Union,” which would put pressure on the companies that those developers work at to contribute back to open source projects. Many developers seem &lt;em&gt;rabidly&lt;/em&gt; anti-union, and tech companies are as well. I’m not sure this is a viable path, today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-where-do-we-go-from-here_2&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;head_anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://words.steveklabnik.com/what-comes-after-open-source#so-where-do-we-go-from-here_2&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;So where do we go from here?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m still, ultimately, left with more questions than answers. But I do think I’ve properly identified the problem: many developers conceive of software freedom as something larger than purely a license that kinds in on redistribution. This is the new frontier for those who are thinking about furthering the goals of the free software and open source movements. Our old tools are inadequate, and I’m not sure that the needed replacements work, or even exist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something to think about, though.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;423&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kudos&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;423&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kudos&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 14:13:48 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>steveklabnik</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://words.steveklabnik.com/what-comes-after-open-source</og:url>
<og:title>What comes after &quot;open source&quot; • Steve Klabnik</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>In a previous post, I discussed the history of open source, and ended with this claim: Today’s developers have never learned about this history, or don’t care about it, or actively think it’s irrelevant. … For the same reasons that “open source”... | Steve Klabnik | “The most violent element in society is ignorance.” - Emma Goldman</og:description>
<og:image>https://svbtleusercontent.com/wWhQCoC3mGGKwQ1nS6CC9H0xspap.gif</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://words.steveklabnik.com/what-comes-after-open-source</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The CIA Campaign to Steal Apple&amp;#039;s Secrets (2015)</title>
<link>https://theintercept.com/2015/03/10/ispy-cia-campaign-steal-apples-secrets/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://theintercept.com/2015/03/10/ispy-cia-campaign-steal-apples-secrets/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;R&lt;/span&gt;ESEARCHERS WORKING&lt;/strong&gt; with the Central Intelligence Agency have conducted a multi-year, sustained effort to break the security of Apple’s iPhones and iPads, according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://firstlook.org/theintercept/document/2015/03/10/tcb-jamboree-2012-invitation/&quot;&gt;top-secret documents&lt;/a&gt; obtained by &lt;em&gt;The Intercept&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The security researchers presented their latest tactics and achievements at a secret annual gathering, called the “Jamboree,” where attendees discussed strategies for exploiting security flaws in household and commercial electronics. The conferences have spanned nearly a decade, with the first CIA-sponsored meeting taking place a year before the first iPhone was released.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By targeting essential security keys used to encrypt data stored on Apple’s devices, the researchers have sought to thwart the company’s attempts to provide mobile security to hundreds of millions of Apple customers across the globe. Studying both “physical” and “non-invasive” techniques, U.S. government-sponsored research has been aimed at discovering ways to decrypt and ultimately penetrate Apple’s encrypted firmware. This could enable spies to plant malicious code on Apple devices and seek out potential vulnerabilities in other parts of the iPhone and iPad currently masked by encryption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CIA declined to comment for this story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The security researchers also claimed they had created a modified version of Apple’s proprietary software development tool, Xcode, which could sneak surveillance backdoors into any apps or programs created using the tool. Xcode, which is distributed by Apple to hundreds of thousands of developers, is used to create apps that are sold through Apple’s App Store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The modified version of Xcode, the researchers claimed, could enable spies to steal passwords and grab messages on infected devices. Researchers also claimed the modified Xcode could “force all iOS applications to send embedded data to a listening post.” It remains unclear how intelligence agencies would get developers to use the poisoned version of Xcode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researchers also claimed they had successfully modified the OS X updater, a program used to deliver updates to laptop and desktop computers, to install a “keylogger.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other presentations at the CIA conference have focused on the products of Apple’s competitors, including Microsoft’s BitLocker encryption system, which is used widely on laptop and desktop computers running premium editions of Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The revelations that the CIA has waged a secret campaign to defeat the security mechanisms built into Apple’s devices come as Apple and other tech giants are loudly resisting pressure from senior U.S. and U.K. government officials to weaken the security of their products. Law enforcement agencies want the companies to maintain the government’s ability to bypass security tools built into wireless devices. Perhaps more than any other corporate leader, Apple’s CEO, Tim Cook, has taken a stand for privacy as a core value, while sharply criticizing the actions of U.S. law enforcement and intelligence agencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If U.S. products are OK to target, that’s news to me,” says Matthew Green, a cryptography expert at Johns Hopkins University’s Information Security Institute. “Tearing apart the products of U.S. manufacturers and potentially putting backdoors in software distributed by unknowing developers all seems to be going a bit beyond ‘targeting bad guys.’ It may be a means to an end, but it’s a hell of a means.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple declined to comment for this story, instead pointing to previous comments Cook and the company have made defending Apple’s privacy record.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap align-bleed full-bleed width-auto&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-article-large wp-image-15901&quot; src=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2015/03/lockheed.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&quot; alt=&quot;lockheed&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;caption overlayed&quot;&gt;Lockheed Martin Dulles Executive Plaza, Herndon, Virginia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;S&lt;/span&gt;ECURITY RESEARCHERS&lt;/strong&gt; from Sandia National Laboratories presented their Apple-focused research at a secret annual CIA conference called the Trusted Computing Base Jamboree. The Apple research and the existence of the conference are detailed in documents provided to &lt;em&gt;The Intercept&lt;/em&gt; by National Security Agency whistleblower Edward Snowden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conference was sponsored by the CIA’s Information Operations Center, which conducts covert cyberattacks. The aim of the gathering, according to a 2012 internal NSA wiki, was to host “presentations that provide important information to developers trying to circumvent or exploit new security capabilities,” as well as to “exploit new avenues of attack.” NSA personnel also participated in the conference through the NSA’s counterpart to the CIA’s Trusted Computing Base, according to the document. The NSA did not provide comment for this story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Jamboree was held at a Lockheed Martin facility inside an executive office park in northern Virginia. Lockheed is one of the largest defense contractors in the world; its tentacles stretch into every aspect of U.S. national security and intelligence. The company is akin to a privatized wing of the U.S. national security state — more than &lt;a href=&quot;http://washpost.bloomberg.com/Story?docId=1376-NISX3H6S972D01-5B1JNR0DBL1LE993AF679RNP18&quot;&gt;80 percent of its total revenue&lt;/a&gt; comes from the U.S. government. Via a subsidiary, Lockheed also operates Sandia Labs, which is funded by the U.S. government. The lab’s researchers have presented Apple findings at the CIA conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Lockheed Martin’s role in these activities should not be surprising given its leading role in the national surveillance state,” says William Hartung, director of the Arms and Security Project at the Center for International Policy and author of &lt;em&gt;Prophets of War&lt;/em&gt;, a book that chronicles Lockheed’s history. “It is the largest private intelligence contractor in the world, and it has worked on past surveillance programs for the Pentagon, the CIA and the NSA. If you’re looking for a candidate for Big Brother, Lockheed Martin fits the bill.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Apple research is consistent with a much broader secret U.S. government program to analyze “secure communications products, both foreign and domestic” in order to “develop exploitation capabilities against the authentication and encryption schemes,” according to the 2013 Congressional Budget Justification. Known widely as the “Black Budget,” the top-secret CBJ was provided to &lt;em&gt;The Intercept&lt;/em&gt; by Snowden and gives a sprawling overview of the U.S. intelligence community’s spending and architecture. The White House did not respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of 2013, according to the classified budget, U.S. intelligence agencies were creating new capabilities against dozens of commercially produced security products, including those made by American companies, to seek out vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week, CIA Director John Brennan announced a major reorganization at the agency aimed, in large part, at expanding U.S. cyber-operations. The Information Operations Center, which organized the Jamboree conferences, will be folded into a new Directorate of Digital Innovation. Notwithstanding its innocuous name, a major priority of the directorate will be offensive cyberattacks, sabotage and digital espionage. Brennan said the CIA reorganization will be modeled after the agency’s Counterterrorism Center, which runs the U.S. targeted killing and drone program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap align-center width-fixed&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-article-medium wp-image-15899&quot; src=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2015/03/iphones-540x272.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;HE DOCUMENTS&lt;/strong&gt; do not address how successful the targeting of Apple’s encryption mechanisms have been, nor do they provide any detail about the specific use of such exploits by U.S. intelligence. But they do shed light on an ongoing campaign aimed at defeating the tech giant’s efforts to secure its products, and in turn, its customers’ private data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Spies gonna spy,” says Steven Bellovin, a former chief technologist for the U.S. Federal Trade Commission and current professor at Columbia University. “I’m never surprised by what intelligence agencies do to get information. They’re going to go where the info is, and as it moves, they’ll adjust their tactics. Their attitude is basically amoral: whatever works is OK.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bellovin says he generally supports efforts by U.S. intelligence to “hack” devices — including Apple’s — used by terrorists and criminals, but expressed concern that such capabilities could be abused. “There are bad people out there, and it’s reasonable to seek information on them,” he says, cautioning that “inappropriate use — mass surveillance, targeting Americans without a warrant, probably spying on allies — is another matter entirely.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the top-secret documents, ranging from 2010 through 2012, the researchers appear particularly intent on extracting encryption keys that prevent unauthorized access to data stored — and firmware run — on Apple products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The Intelligence Community (IC) is highly dependent on a very small number of security flaws, many of which are public, which Apple eventually patches,” the researchers noted in an abstract of their 2011 presentation at the Jamboree. But, they promised, their presentation could provide the intelligence community with a “method to noninvasively extract” encryption keys used on Apple devices. Another presentation focused on physically extracting the key from Apple’s hardware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A year later, at the 2012 Jamboree, researchers described their attacks on the software used by developers to create applications for Apple’s popular App Store. In a talk called “Strawhorse: Attacking the MacOS and iOS Software Development Kit,” a presenter from Sandia Labs described a successful “whacking” of Apple’s Xcode — the software used to create apps for iPhones, iPads and Mac computers. Developers who create Apple-approved and distributed apps overwhelmingly use Xcode, a free piece of software easily downloaded from the App Store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers boasted that they had discovered a way to manipulate Xcode so that it could serve as a conduit for infecting and extracting private data from devices on which users had installed apps that were built with the poisoned Xcode. In other words, by manipulating Xcode, the spies could compromise the devices and private data of anyone with apps made by a poisoned developer — potentially millions of people. “Trying to plant stuff in Xcode has fascinating implications,” says Bellovin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers listed a variety of actions their “whacked” Xcode could perform, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— “Entice” all Mac applications to create a “remote backdoor” allowing undetected access to an Apple computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Secretly embed an app developer’s private key into all iOS applications. (This could potentially allow spies to impersonate the targeted developer.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— “Force all iOS applications” to send data from an iPhone or iPad back to a U.S. intelligence “listening post.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Disable core security features on Apple devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;stylized pull-center&quot; data-shortcode-type=&quot;pullquote&quot; data-pull=&quot;center&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Intelligence Community is highly dependent on a very small number of security flaws, many of which are public, which Apple eventually patches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For years, U.S. and British intelligence agencies have consistently sought to defeat the layers of encryption and other security features used by Apple to protect the iPhone. A joint task force comprised of operatives from the NSA and Britain’s Government Communications Headquarters, formed in 2010, developed surveillance software targeting iPhones, Android devices and Nokia’s Symbian phones. The Mobile Handset Exploitation Team successfully implanted malware on iPhones as part of WARRIOR PRIDE, a GCHQ framework for secretly accessing private communications on mobile devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That program was disclosed in Snowden documents &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/world/2014/jan/27/nsa-gchq-smartphone-app-angry-birds-personal-data&quot;&gt;reported on last year by &lt;em&gt;The Guardian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. A WARRIOR PRIDE plugin called NOSEY SMURF allowed spies to remotely and secretly activate a phone’s microphone. Another plugin, DREAMY SMURF, allowed intelligence agents to manage the power system on a phone and thus avoid detection. PARANOID SMURF was designed to conceal the malware in other ways. TRACKER SMURF allowed ultra-precise geolocating of an individual phone. “[If] its [sic] on the phone, we can get it,” the spies boasted in a secret GCHQ document describing the targeting of the iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of the SMURF malware — including the plugin that secretly turns on the iPhone’s microphone — would first require that agencies bypass the security controls built into the iOS operating system. Spies would either need to hack the phone in order to plant their malware on it, or sneak a backdoor into an app the user installed voluntarily. That was one of the clear aims of the Apple-focused research presented at the CIA’s conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The U.S. government is prioritizing its own offensive surveillance needs over the cybersecurity of the millions of Americans who use Apple products,” says Christopher Soghoian, the principal technologist at the American Civil Liberties Union. “If U.S. government-funded researchers can discover these flaws, it is quite likely that Chinese, Russian and Israeli researchers can discover them, too. By quietly exploiting these flaws rather than notifying Apple, the U.S. government leaves Apple’s customers vulnerable to other sophisticated governments.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Security experts interviewed by &lt;em&gt;The Intercept&lt;/em&gt; point out that the SMURF capabilities were already available to U.S. and British intelligence agencies five years ago. That raises the question of how advanced the current capacity to surveil smartphone users is, especially in light of the extensive resources poured into targeting the products of major tech companies. One GCHQ slide from 2010 stated that the agency’s ultimate goal was to be able to “Exploit any phone, anywhere, any time.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap align-center width-fixed&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-article-medium wp-image-15900&quot; src=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2015/03/jobs_stage-540x360.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&quot; alt=&quot;jobs_stage&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Steve Jobs unveiling the first iPhone on January 9, 2007.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;HE FIRST JAMBOREE&lt;/strong&gt; took place in 2006, just as Apple was preparing to unveil its highly-anticipated iPhone. In March 2010, according to a top-secret document, during a talk called “Rocoto: Implanting the iPhone,” a presenter discussed efforts to target the iPhone 3G. In addition to analyzing the device’s software for potential vulnerabilities, the presentation examined “jailbreak methods,” used within the iPhone community to free phones from their built-in constraints, that could be leveraged by intelligence agencies. “We will conclude with a look ahead at future challenges presented by the iPhone 3GS and the upcoming iPad,” the abstract noted. Over the years, as Apple updates its hardware, software and encryption methods, the CIA and its researchers study ways to break and exploit them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The attempts to target vulnerabilities in Apple’s products have not occurred in a vacuum. Rather, they are part of a vast multi-agency U.S./U.K. effort to attack commercial encryption and security systems used on billions of devices around the world. U.S. intelligence agencies are not just focusing on individual terrorists or criminals — they are targeting the large corporations, such as Apple, that produce popular mobile devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Every other manufacturer looks to Apple. If the CIA can undermine Apple’s systems, it’s likely they’ll be able to deploy the same capabilities against everyone else,” says Green, the Johns Hopkins cryptographer. “Apple led the way with secure coprocessors in phones, with fingerprint sensors, with encrypted messages. If you can attack Apple, then you can probably attack anyone.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the Black Budget, U.S. intelligence agencies have tech companies dead in their sights with the aim of breaking or circumventing any existing or emerging encryption or antiviral products, noting the threat posed by “increasingly strong commercial” encryption and “adversarial cryptography.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Analysis of Target Systems Project produced “prototype capabilities” for the intelligence community, enabled “the defeat of strong commercial data security systems” and developed ways “to exploit emerging information systems and technologies,” according to the classified budget. The project received $35 million in funding in 2012 and had more than 200 personnel assigned to it. By the end of 2013, according to the budget, the project would “develop new capabilities against 50 commercial information security device products to exploit emerging technologies,” as well as new methods that would allow spies to recover user and device passwords on new products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the project’s missions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Analyze “secure communications products, both foreign and domestic produced” to “develop exploitation capabilities against the authentication and encryption schemes.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— “[D]evelop exploitation capabilities against network communications protocols and commercial network security products.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— “Anticipate future encryption technologies” and “prepare strategies to exploit those technologies.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— “Develop, enhance, and implement software attacks against encrypted signals.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— “Develop exploitation capabilities against specific key management and authentication schemes.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— “[D]evelop exploitation capabilities against emerging multimedia applications.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Provide tools for “exploiting” devices used to “store, manage, protect, or communicate data.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— “Develop methods to discover and exploit communication systems employing public key cryptography” and “communications protected by passwords or pass phrases.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Exploit public key cryptography.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Exploit Virtual Private Networks, or VPNs, which allow people to browse the Internet with increased security and anonymity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The black budget also noted that the U.S. intelligence community partners with “National Laboratories” to conduct the type of research presented at the CIA’s annual Jamboree conference. It confirms the U.S. government’s aggressive efforts to steal encryption and authentication keys, as occurred in the NSA and GCHQ &lt;a href=&quot;https://firstlook.org/theintercept/2015/02/19/great-sim-heist/&quot;&gt;operations against Gemalto&lt;/a&gt;, the world’s largest manufacturer of SIM cards, through the use of Computer Network Exploitation attacks. In that case, spy agencies penetrated Gemalto’s internal networks and cyberstalked its employees to steal mass quantities of keys used to encrypt mobile phone communications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CIA’s Information Operations Center is currently the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.washingtonpost.com/world/national-security/cia-plans-major-reorganization-and-a-focus-on-digital-espionage/2015/03/06/87e94a1e-c2aa-11e4-9ec2-b418f57a4a99_story.html&quot;&gt;second largest&lt;/a&gt; of the spy agency’s specialized centers. It not only conducts cyber-ops, but has operated covertly in other nations, working to develop assets from targeted countries to assist in its cyber-surveillance programs, according to the Black Budget. At times, its personnel brief the president.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap align-bleed full-bleed width-auto&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-article-large wp-image-15902&quot; src=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2015/03/obama_ipad-1000x664.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&quot; alt=&quot;obama_ipad&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;caption overlayed&quot;&gt;U.S. President Barack Obama holds up an iPad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;A&lt;/span&gt;T THE CIA’s&lt;/strong&gt; Jamboree in 2011, the computer researchers conducted workshops where they revealed the specifics of their efforts to attack one of the key privacy elements of Apple’s mobile devices. These machines have two separate keys integrated into the silicon of their Apple-designed processors at the point of manufacture. The two, paired together, are used to encrypt data and software stored on iPhones and iPads. One, the User ID, is unique to an individual’s phone, and is not retained by Apple. That key is vital to protecting an individual’s data and — particularly on Apple’s latest devices — difficult to steal. A second key, the Group ID, is known to Apple and is the same across multiple Apple devices that use the same processor. The GID is used to encrypt essential system software that runs on Apple’s mobile devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The focus of the security researchers, as described at the CIA conferences, was to target the GID key, which Apple implants on all devices that use the same processors. For instance, Apple’s A4 processor was used in the iPhone 4, the iPod Touch and the original iPad. All of those devices used the same GID. As Apple designs new processors and faster devices that use those processors, the company creates new GIDs. If someone has the same iPhone as her neighbor, they have the exact same GID key on their devices. So, if intelligence agencies extract the GID key, it means they have information useful to compromising any device containing that key.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the 2011 Jamboree conference, there were two separate presentations on hacking the GID key on Apple’s processors. One was focused on non-invasively obtaining it by studying the electromagnetic emissions of — and the amount of power used by — the iPhone’s processor while encryption is being performed. Careful analysis of that information could be used to extract the encryption key. Such a tactic is known as a “side channel” attack. The second focused on a “method to physically extract the GID key.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever method the CIA and its partners use, by extracting the GID — which is implanted on the processors of all Apple mobile devices — the CIA and its allies could be able to decrypt the firmware that runs on the iPhone and other mobile devices. This would allow them to seek out other security vulnerabilities to exploit. Taken together, the documents make clear that researching each new Apple processor and mobile device, and studying them for potential security flaws, is a priority for the CIA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the 2011 document describing the Jamboree presentations on Apple’s processor, the researchers asserted that extracting the GID key could also allow them to look for other potential gateways into Apple devices. “If successful, it would enable decryption and analysis of the boot firmware for vulnerabilities, and development of associated exploits across the entire A4-based product-line, which includes the iPhone 4, the iPod touch and the iPad.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the CIA conference in 2012, Sandia researchers delivered a presentation on Apple’s A5 processor. The A5 is used in the iPhone 4s and iPad 2. But this time, it contained no abstract or other details, instructing those interested to contact a CIA official on his secure phone or email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If I were Tim Cook, I’d be furious,” says the ACLU’s Soghoian. “If Apple is mad at the intelligence community, and they should be, they should put their lawyers to work. Lawsuits speak louder than words.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap align-bleed full-bleed width-auto&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-article-large wp-image-15903&quot; src=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2015/03/tim_cook-1000x666.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&quot; alt=&quot;tim_cook&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;caption overlayed&quot;&gt;Apple CEO Tim Cook testifies on Capitol Hill in Washington, May 21, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;F&lt;/span&gt;OR YEARS&lt;/strong&gt;, Apple has included encryption features in the products it sells to consumers. In 2014, the company dramatically broadened the types of data stored on iPhones that are encrypted, and it incorporated encryption by default into its desktop and laptop operating system. This resulted in criticism from leading law enforcement officials, including the FBI director. The encryption technology that Apple has built into its products — along with many other security features — is a virtual wall that separates cybercriminals and foreign governments from customer data. But now, because Apple claims it can no longer extract customer data stored on iPhones, because it is encrypted with a key the company does not know, the U.S. government can be locked out too — even with a search warrant. The FBI director and other U.S. officials have referred to the advent of the encryption era — where previously accessible data and communications may now be off limits because of the security technology protecting them — as “going dark.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the face of this rising challenge to its surveillance capabilities, U.S. intelligence has spent considerable time and resources trying to find security vulnerabilities in Apple’s encryption technology, and, more broadly, in its products, which can be leveraged to install surveillance software on iPhones and Macbooks. “The exploitation of security flaws is a high-priority area for the U.S. intelligence community, and such methods have only become more important as U.S. technology companies have built strong encryption into their products,” says the ACLU’s Soghoian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has, for nearly a decade, included BitLocker, an encryption technology that protects data stored on a computer, in its Windows operating system. Unlike Apple, which made encryption available to all customers, Microsoft had included this feature only in its more expensive premium and professional versions of Windows, up until a few years ago. BitLocker is designed to work with a Trusted Platform Module, a special security chip included in some computers, which stores the encryption keys and also protects against unauthorized software modification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also presented at the Jamboree were successes in the targeting of Microsoft’s disk encryption technology, and the TPM chips that are used to store its encryption keys. Researchers at the CIA conference in 2010 boasted about the ability to extract the encryption keys used by BitLocker and thus decrypt private data stored on the computer. Because the TPM chip is used to protect the system from untrusted software, attacking it could allow the covert installation of malware onto the computer, which could be used to access otherwise encrypted communications and files of consumers. Microsoft declined to comment for this story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the wake of the initial Snowden disclosures, Apple CEO Tim Cook has specifically denounced the U.S. government’s efforts to compel companies to provide backdoor access to their users’ data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I want to be absolutely clear that we have never worked with any government agency from any country to create a backdoor in any of our products or services. We have also never allowed access to our servers. And we never will,” Cook said last September in announcing Apple’s new privacy policy. More recently, Cook said, “None of us should accept that the government or a company or anybody should have access to all of our private information. This is a basic human right. We all have a right to privacy. We shouldn’t give it up. We shouldn’t give in to scare-mongering.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As corporations increasingly integrate default encryption methods and companies like Apple incorporate their own indigenous encryption technologies into easy-to-use text, voice and video communication platforms, the U.S. and British governments are panicking. “Encryption threatens to lead all of us to a very dark place,” declared FBI Director James Comey in an October 2014 lecture at the Brookings Institution. Citing the recent moves by Apple to strengthen default encryption on its operating systems, and commitments by Google to incorporate such tools, Comey said, “This means the companies themselves won’t be able to unlock phones, laptops, and tablets to reveal photos, documents, e-mail, and recordings stored within.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under current U.S. regulations, law enforcement agencies can get a court order to access communications channeled through major tech companies and wireless providers. But if those communications are encrypted through a process not accessible by any involved company, the data is essentially meaningless, garbled gibberish. “In a world in which data is encrypted, and the providers don’t have the keys, suddenly, there is no one to go to when they have a warrant,” says Soghoian. “That is, even if they get a court order, it doesn’t help them. That is what is freaking them out.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comey alleged that “even a supercomputer would have difficulty with today’s high-level encryption,” meaning a “brute force” attempt to decrypt intercepted communications would be ineffective, and, even if successful, time-consuming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Encryption isn’t just a technical feature; it’s a marketing pitch,” Comey added. “But it will have very serious consequences for law enforcement and national security agencies at all levels. Sophisticated criminals will come to count on these means of evading detection. It’s the equivalent of a closet that can’t be opened. A safe that can’t be cracked.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few months after Comey’s remarks, Robert Litt, the general counsel for the Office of the Director of National Intelligence, also appeared at Brookings. “One of the many ways in which Snowden’s leaks have damaged our national security is by driving a wedge between the government and providers and technology companies, so that some companies that formerly recognized that protecting our nation was a valuable and important public service now feel compelled to stand in opposition,” Litt said. He appealed to corporations to embrace “a solution that does not compromise the integrity of encryption technology but that enables both encryption to protect privacy and decryption under lawful authority to protect national security.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Green, the Johns Hopkins professor, argues that U.S. government attacks against the products of American companies will not just threaten privacy, but will ultimately harm the U.S. economy. “U.S. tech companies have already suffered overseas due to foreign concerns about our products’ security,” he says. “The last thing any of us need is for the U.S. government to actively undermine our own technology industry.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The U.S. government is certainly not alone in the war against secure communications. British Prime Minister David Cameron has suggested that if he is re-elected, he may seek to ban encrypted chat programs that do not provide backdoor access to law enforcement. “Are we going to allow a means of communications which it simply isn’t possible to read?” Cameron said in a speech in England earlier this year. “My answer to that question is: ‘No, we must not.’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the Chinese government recently tried to force tech companies to install a backdoor in their products for use by Chinese intelligence agencies, the U.S. government denounced China. “This is something that I’ve raised directly with President Xi,” President Obama said in early March. “We have made it very clear to them that this is something they are going to have to change if they are to do business with the United States.” But China was actually following the U.S. government’s lead. The FBI has called for an expansion of U.S. law, which would require Apple and its competitors to design their products so that all communications could be made available to government agencies. NSA officials have expressed similar sentiments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Obama’s comments were dripping with hypocrisy,” says Trevor Timm, executive director of the Freedom of the Press Foundation. “Don’t get me wrong, his actual criticism of China for attempting to force tech companies to install backdoors was spot on — now if only he would apply what he said to his own government. Since he now knows backdooring encryption is a terrible policy that will damage cybersecurity, privacy, and the economy, why won’t he order the FBI and NSA to stop pushing for it as well?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;———&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Documents published with this article:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;———&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Andrew Fishman, Alleen Brown, Andrea Jones, Ryan Gallagher, Morgan Marquis-Boire, and Micah Lee contributed to this story.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: An earlier draft of this story incorrectly suggested that the iOS Group ID is used to sign software. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;An earlier draft also incorrectly stated that Lockheed Martin owns Sandia National Laboratories. Sandia Corporation, a wholly owned subsidiary of Lockheed Martin, operates Sandia National Laboratories as a contractor for the U.S. Department of Energy’s National Nuclear Security Administration. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disclosure: Freedom of the Press Foundation, which Trevor Timm represents, has received grant funding from First Look Media,&lt;/em&gt; The Intercept&lt;em&gt;’s parent company.&lt;/em&gt; Intercept &lt;em&gt;co-founders Glenn Greenwald and Laura Poitras are on the board of the organization.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo: Shutterstock; Google Maps; Simon Dawson/Bloomberg/Getty Images; Tony Avelar/Getty Images; Kevin Lamarque/Reuters/Landov; J. Scott Applewhite/AP&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 14:03:21 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>colinprince</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://theintercept.com/2015/03/10/ispy-cia-campaign-steal-apples-secrets/</og:url>
<og:description>Agency researchers conducted a multi-year effort to break the security of Apple’s iPhones and iPads, presenting their findings at an secret annual “Jamboree.&quot;</og:description>
<og:image>https://prod01-cdn07.cdn.firstlook.org/wp-uploads/sites/1/2015/03/apple-store-feature-hero.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>The CIA Campaign to Steal Apple’s Secrets</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://theintercept.com/2015/03/10/ispy-cia-campaign-steal-apples-secrets/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>