<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Rents are dropping across the US</title>
<link>https://edition.cnn.com/2020/06/16/success/rents-are-dropping-us-cities-coronavirus/index.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://edition.cnn.com/2020/06/16/success/rents-are-dropping-us-cities-coronavirus/index.html</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://edition.cnn.com/2020/06/16/success/rents-are-dropping-us-cities-coronavirus/index.html&quot;&gt;https://edition.cnn.com/2020/06/16/success/rents-are-dropping-us-cities-coronavirus/index.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23555889&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23555889&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 202&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 267&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 19:49:01 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>xbmcuser</dc:creator>
<dc:identifier>https://edition.cnn.com/2020/06/16/success/rents-are-dropping-us-cities-coronavirus/index.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Microsoft pitched facial recognition to the DEA</title>
<link>https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/ryanmac/microsoft-pitched-facial-recognition-dea-drug-enforcement</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/ryanmac/microsoft-pitched-facial-recognition-dea-drug-enforcement</guid>
<description>&lt;div data-module=&quot;subbuzz-text&quot; readability=&quot;57.3833425262&quot;&gt;
  
  




&lt;p&gt;In early June, Microsoft joined &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/carolinehaskins1/amazon-ibm-and-microsoft-wont-say-which-police-departments&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a growing list&lt;/a&gt; of tech companies that pledged not to sell facial recognition technology to police departments until the controversial technology was federally regulated. But that announcement left a loophole: selling facial recognition to the federal government.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Newly released emails show the company has tried to sell the controversial technology to the government for years, including to the Drug Enforcement Administration in late 2017.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Those documents, obtained by the American Civil Liberties Union via a public records lawsuit, provide a rare look into how the Redmond, Washington–based company tried to sell artificial intelligence services to federal agencies six months before its July 2018 call for &quot;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://blogs.microsoft.com/on-the-issues/2018/07/13/facial-recognition-technology-the-need-for-public-regulation-and-corporate-responsibility/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;public regulation and corporate responsibility&lt;/a&gt;&quot; around facial recognition. Last week, Microsoft said &quot;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/carolinehaskins1/amazon-ibm-and-microsoft-wont-say-which-police-departments&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;we do not sell our facial recognition technology&lt;/a&gt; to US police departments today” and committed not to do so “until there is a strong national law grounded in human rights.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But that pledge did not address any potential or ongoing relationships with federal agencies. When asked by BuzzFeed News, Microsoft did not immediately provide comment on whether it has provided or is currently providing its facial recognition technology to federal law enforcement agencies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://data.aclum.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/20-00004-L-OCR.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;emails obtained by the ACLU&lt;/a&gt; show that the company pitched facial recognition as a law enforcement tool to the DEA in late 2017 as the company pushed to expand its offerings on its government cloud platform, Microsoft Azure Government Cloud. In September of that year, an individual whose name has been redacted, but listed their title as the DEA’s chief technology officer, stated that he was hosting the Microsoft Cognitive Services Group “to discuss use-cases for their Media Services.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div data-retailers=&quot;Amazon&quot; data-keywords=&quot;cleaning,fast fashion,skincare&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-text&quot; readability=&quot;132.72345337027&quot;&gt;
  
  




&lt;p&gt;“As you may be aware, Microsoft Azure has many of these services (Translation, Transcription, Video Processing, Facial Recognition, etc.) running in the Public Azure,” the person wrote on Sept. 15, 2017. “Microsoft has only some of these services running in the Microsoft Azure Government (MAG) Cloud and they are looking at what else needs to be transitioned over to MAG.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The person later noted that MAG was approved for “Law Enforcement Sensitive things” and that they wanted to create a pilot project to test a variety of video and audio recording technologies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A DEA spokesperson declined to comment on its conversations with Microsoft or the agency’s tests or deployment of facial recognition.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Other emails show that DEA representatives visited Microsoft’s office in Reston, Virginia, in November 2017 to see a demonstration of a suite of products including translation services, document transcription, “optical character recognition in video,” and Azure facial recognition. In a follow-up message after the meeting, a Microsoft employee, whose name was redacted, gave a brief overview of all the demos his team showed the agency including “Face API: Identify similar faces, develop a face database.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Please let us know when and how we can take the next step on a prototype,” they wrote. Based on the emails, it’s unclear if any prototype was built.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Eight months after those meetings, Microsoft President Brad Smith &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://blogs.microsoft.com/on-the-issues/2018/07/13/facial-recognition-technology-the-need-for-public-regulation-and-corporate-responsibility/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;penned a blog post&lt;/a&gt; calling for “thoughtful government regulation and for the development of norms around acceptable uses” surrounding facial recognition.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“If there are concerns about how a technology will be deployed more broadly across society, the only way to regulate this broad use is for the government to do so,” he wrote, before acknowledging the possibility of racial profiling and misidentification.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite those concerns, Microsoft’s representatives continued to pitch facial recognition as part of its Azure Government offering. In November 2018, a “Sr. Microsoft SME,” whose name was redacted in the email, sent another note to a DEA representative requesting a meeting. Azure has a &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azuregov/federal-agencies-continue-to-advance-capabilities-with-azure-government/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;number of relationships&lt;/a&gt; with federal agencies including the Department of Defense and Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While it’s not clear if the DEA moved forward with Microsoft’s Azure AI offerings, the fact that Microsoft pitched such services in the first place “is concerning,” Kade Crockford of the ACLU Massachusetts told BuzzFeed News. In October, &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.aclu.org/legal-document/aclu-v-doj-face-recognition-surveillance-complaint&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the ACLU sued&lt;/a&gt; the Department of Justice, FBI, and DEA after those agencies failed to comply with a public records request regarding their use of facial recognition and other biometric tracking technology.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Microsoft's recent decision not to provide facial recognition to police departments is “a positive step,” said Crockford, noting that it’s what civil rights organizations have demanded for years after studies showed the technology has &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/daveyalba/amazon-rekognition-facial-recognition-congress-false&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;high rates of misidentification among racial minorities&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The DEA has a long history of racially disparate or racist practices and has been engaged in wildly inappropriate mass surveillance,” they said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;BuzzFeed News previously reported that &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/ryanmac/clearview-ai-fbi-ice-global-law-enforcement&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;individuals associated with the DEA tested Clearview AI&lt;/a&gt;, a controversial facial recognition software that’s been built using billions of photos scraped from social media sites including Facebook, Instagram, and Twitter. As of February, more than 20 users associated with the DEA have run about 2,000 searches according to data viewed by BuzzFeed News.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Following nationwide protests of racial injustices and police brutality faced by Black people, companies have pulled back on their facial recognition offerings. Earlier this month, Amazon said it would place &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/carolinehaskins1/amazon-suspending-facial-recognition-police&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a one-year moratorium&lt;/a&gt; on selling its biometric face identification service, Rekognition, to police, while &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ibm.com/blogs/policy/facial-recognition-susset-racial-justice-reforms/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;IBM said&lt;/a&gt; it would stop developing or researching facial recognition.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When asked by BuzzFeed News, however, Amazon, IBM, and Microsoft &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/carolinehaskins1/amazon-ibm-and-microsoft-wont-say-which-police-departments&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;refused to disclose which police departments&lt;/a&gt;, if any, had previously used their facial recognition services.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Earlier this month, BuzzFeed News also reported that &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/jasonleopold/george-floyd-police-brutality-protests-government&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the Justice Department gave the DEA permission&lt;/a&gt; “to enforce any federal crime committed as a result of the protests over the death of George Floyd.”&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 17:17:50 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tech-historian</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/ryanmac/microsoft-pitched-facial-recognition-dea-drug-enforcement</og:url>
<og:image>https://img.buzzfeed.com/buzzfeed-static/static/2020-06/17/19/campaign_images/6ecdce48df31/microsoft-says-it-wont-sell-facial-recognition-to-2-2770-1592423000-0_dblbig.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Microsoft Says It Won't Sell Facial Recognition To The Police. These Documents Show How It Pitched That Technology To The Federal Government.</og:title>
<og:description>Last week, Microsoft said it would not sell its facial recognition to police departments. But new documents reveal it was pitching that technology to at least one federal agency as recently as two yea</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/ryanmac/microsoft-pitched-facial-recognition-dea-drug-enforcement</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>AWS Snowcone</title>
<link>https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/introducing-aws-snowcone-small-lightweight-edge-storage-and-processing/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/introducing-aws-snowcone-small-lightweight-edge-storage-and-processing/</guid>
<description>&lt;table id=&quot;amazon-polly-audio-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td id=&quot;amazon-polly-audio-tab&quot;&gt;



&lt;div id=&quot;amazon-polly-by-tab&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/polly/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://a0.awsstatic.com/aws-blog/images/Voiced_by_Amazon_Polly_EN.png&quot; width=&quot;554&quot; height=&quot;56&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last month I published my &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/aws-snowball-edge-update/&quot;&gt;AWS Snowball Edge Update&lt;/a&gt; and told you about the latest updates to Snowball Edge, including &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/snowball/latest/developer-guide/specifications.html#specs-storage-optimized&quot;&gt;faster storage-optimized devices&lt;/a&gt; with more memory &amp;amp; vCPUs, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/snowball/latest/developer-guide/aws-opshub.html&quot;&gt;AWS OpsHub for Snow Family&lt;/a&gt; GUI-based management tool, &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/snowball/latest/developer-guide/using-local-iam.html&quot;&gt;IAM for Snowball Edge&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/snowball/latest/developer-guide/automate-task.html&quot;&gt;Snowball Edge Support for AWS Systems Manager&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AWS Snowcone&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Today I would like to introduce you to the newest and smallest member of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/snow/&quot;&gt;AWS Snow Family&lt;/a&gt; of physical edge computing, edge storage, and data transfer devices for rugged or disconnected environments, &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/snowcone/&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;AWS Snowcone&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2020/snowcone_jb_sticker_1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;890&quot; height=&quot;589&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span title=&quot;&quot;&gt;AWS Snowcone&lt;/span&gt; weighs 4.5 pounds and includes 8 terabytes of usable storage. It is small (9″ long, 6″ wide, and 3″ tall) and rugged, and can be used in a variety of environments including desktops, data centers, messenger bags, vehicles, and in conjunction with drones. Snowcone runs on either AC power or an optional battery, making it great for many different types of use cases where self-sufficiency is vital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The device enclosure is both tamper-evident and tamper-resistant, and also uses a Trusted Platform Module (TPM) designed to ensure both security and full chain-of-custody for your data. The device encrypts data at rest and in transit using keys that are managed by &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/kms/&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;AWS Key Management Service (KMS)&lt;/a&gt; and are never stored on the device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like other Snow Family devices, &lt;span title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Snowcone&lt;/span&gt; includes an E Ink shipping label designed to ensure the device is automatically sent to the correct AWS facility and to aid in tracking. It also includes 2 CPUs, 4 GB of memory, wired or wireless access, and USB-C power using a cord or the optional battery. There’s enough compute power for you to launch EC2 instances and to use &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/greengrass/&quot;&gt;AWS IoT Greengrass&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use &lt;span title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Snowcone&lt;/span&gt; for data migration, content distribution, tactical edge computing, healthcare IoT, industrial IoT, transportation, logistics, and autonomous vehicle use cases. You can ship data-laden devices to AWS for offline data transfer, or you can use &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/datasync/&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;AWS DataSync&lt;/a&gt; for online data transfer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ordering a &lt;span title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Snowcone&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The ordering process for &lt;span title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Snowcone&lt;/span&gt; is similar to that for Snowball Edge. I open the &lt;a href=&quot;https://console.aws.amazon.com/importexport/home&quot;&gt;Snow Family Console&lt;/a&gt;, and click &lt;strong&gt;Create Job&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://console.aws.amazon.com/importexport/home&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2020/snow_con_home_2.png&quot; width=&quot;701&quot; height=&quot;669&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I select the &lt;strong&gt;Import into Amazon S3&lt;/strong&gt; job type and click &lt;strong&gt;Next&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2020/snow_job_type_3.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I choose my address (or enter a new one), and a shipping speed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2020/snow_addr_1.png&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;563&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, I give my job a name (&lt;strong&gt;Snowcone2&lt;/strong&gt;) and indicate that I want a Snowcone. I also acknowledge that I will provide my own power supply:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2020/snow_dev_top_3.png&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;682&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deeper into the page, I choose an S3 bucket for my data, opt-in to WiFi connectivity, and choose an EC2 AMI that will be loaded on the device before it is shipped to me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2020/snow_dev_bottom_1.png&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;864&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see from the image, I can choose multiple buckets and/or multiple AMIs. The AMIs must be made from an instance launched from a CentOS or Ubuntu product in &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/marketplace&quot;&gt;AWS Marketplace&lt;/a&gt;, and it must contain a SSH key.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On successive pages (not shown), I specify permissions (an IAM role), choose an &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/kms/&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;AWS Key Management Service (KMS)&lt;/a&gt; key to encrypt my data, and set up a SNS topic for job notifications. Then I confirm my choices and click &lt;strong&gt;Create job&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2020/snow_confirm_1.png&quot; width=&quot;801&quot; height=&quot;507&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I await delivery of my device! I can check the status at any time:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2020/snow_job_detail_2.png&quot; width=&quot;799&quot; height=&quot;562&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As noted in one of the earlier screens, I will also need a suitable power supply or battery (you can find several on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/snowball/latest/snowcone-guide/accessories.html&quot;&gt;Snowcone Accessories&lt;/a&gt; page).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Time passes, the doorbell rings, Luna barks, and my device is delivered…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-medium aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2020/snow_luna_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Luna and a Snowcone&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;855&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The console also updates to show that my device has been delivered:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2020/snow_delivered_1.png&quot; width=&quot;798&quot; height=&quot;154&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On that page, I click &lt;strong&gt;Get credentials&lt;/strong&gt;, copy the &lt;strong&gt;client unlock code&lt;/strong&gt;, and download the manifest file:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2020/sno_unlock_code_1.png&quot; width=&quot;485&quot; height=&quot;528&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Setting up My Snowcone&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I connect the Snowcone to the power supply and to my network, and power up! After a few seconds of initialization, the device shows its IP address and invites me to connect:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2020/snow_main_1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;655&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The IP address was supplied by the DHCP server on my home network, and should be fine. If not, I can touch &lt;strong&gt;Network&lt;/strong&gt; and configure a static IP address or log in to my WiFi network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, I download &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/snowcone/resources/&quot;&gt;AWS OpsHub for Snow Family&lt;/a&gt;, install it, and then configure it to access the device. I select &lt;strong&gt;Snowcone&lt;/strong&gt; and click &lt;strong&gt;Next&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2020/snow_opshub_select_dev_1.png&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;454&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I enter the IP address as shown on the display:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2020/snow_opshub_enter_ip_2.png&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;463&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I enter the unlock code, upload the manifest file, and click &lt;strong&gt;Unlock device&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2020/snow_opshub_unlock_code_1.png&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;473&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a minute or two, the device is unlocked and ready. I enter a name (&lt;strong&gt;Snowcone1&lt;/strong&gt;) that I’ll use within AWS OpsHub and click &lt;strong&gt;Save profile name&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2020/snow_opshub_ready_1.png&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;452&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m all set:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2020/snow_opshub_main_2.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AWS OpsHub for Snow Family&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Now that I have ordered &amp;amp; received my device, installed AWS OpsHub for Snow Family, and unlocked my device, I am ready to start managing some file storage and doing some edge computing!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I click on &lt;strong&gt;Get started&lt;/strong&gt; within &lt;strong&gt;Manage file storage&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Start NFS&lt;/strong&gt;. I have several network options, and I’ll use the defaults:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2020/snow_opshub_start_nfs_1.png&quot; width=&quot;561&quot; height=&quot;446&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The NFS server is ready within a minute or so, and it has its own IP address:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2020/snow_opshub_nfs_ready_3.png&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;661&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once it is ready I can mount the NFS volume and copy files to the Snowcone:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2020/snow_copy_3.png&quot; width=&quot;795&quot; height=&quot;680&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can store process these files locally, or I can use &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/datasync/&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;AWS DataSync&lt;/a&gt; to transfer them to the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I showed you earlier in this post, I selected an EC2 AMI when I created my job. I can launch instances on the Snowcone using this AMI. I click on &lt;strong&gt;Compute&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Launch instance&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2020/snow_opshub_compute_1.png&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;726&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have three instance types to choose from:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;8&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Instance Name&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CPUs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RAM&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;snc1.micro&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;1 GiB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;snc1.small&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;2 GiB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;snc1.medium&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;4 GiB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;I select my AMI &amp;amp; instance type, confirm the networking options, and click &lt;strong&gt;Launch&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2020/snow_opshub_launch_1.png&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;600&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can also create storage volumes and attach them to the instance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ability to build AMIs and run them on Snowcones gives you the power to build applications that do all sorts of interesting filtering, pre-processing, and analysis at the edge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can use &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/datasync/&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;AWS DataSync&lt;/a&gt; to transfer data from the device to a wide variety of AWS storage services including &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/s3/&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Amazon Simple Storage Service (S3)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/efs&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Amazon Elastic File System (EFS)&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/fsx/windows/&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Amazon FSx for Windows File Server&lt;/a&gt;. I click on &lt;strong&gt;Get started&lt;/strong&gt;, then &lt;strong&gt;Start DataSync Agent&lt;/strong&gt;, confirm my network settings, and click &lt;strong&gt;Start agent&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2020/snow_opshub_ds_start_1.png&quot; width=&quot;599&quot; height=&quot;459&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the agent is up and running, I copy the IP address:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2020/snow_ops_datasync_running_1.png&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;408&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I follow the link and create a DataSync agent (the deploy step is not necessary because the agent is already running). I choose an endpoint and paste the IP address of the agent, then click &lt;strong&gt;Get key&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2020/snow_ds_create_agent_1.png&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;732&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I give my agent a name (&lt;strong&gt;SnowAgent&lt;/strong&gt;), tag it, and click &lt;strong&gt;Create agent&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2020/snow_ds_creatification_1.png&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;949&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I configure the NFS server in the Snowcone as a DataSync location, and use it to transfer data in or out using a DataSync Task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;API / CLI&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;While AWS OpsHub is going to be the primary access method for most users, the device can also be accessed programmatically. I can use the Snow Family tools to retrieve the AWS Access Key and Secret Key from the device, create a CLI profile (region is &lt;strong&gt;snow&lt;/strong&gt;), and run commands (or issue API calls) as usual:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;hide-language&quot; readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;unlimited-height-code&quot;&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;lang-bash&quot;&gt;C:\&amp;gt;aws ec2 \
   --endpoint http://192.168.7.154:8008 describe-images \
   --profile snowcone1
{
    &quot;Images&quot;: [
        {
            &quot;ImageId&quot;: &quot;s.ami-0581034c71faf08d9&quot;,
            &quot;Public&quot;: false,
            &quot;State&quot;: &quot;AVAILABLE&quot;,
            &quot;BlockDeviceMappings&quot;: [
                {
                    &quot;DeviceName&quot;: &quot;/dev/sda1&quot;,
                    &quot;Ebs&quot;: {
                        &quot;DeleteOnTermination&quot;: false,
                        &quot;Iops&quot;: 0,
                        &quot;SnapshotId&quot;: &quot;s.snap-01f2a33baebb50f0e&quot;,
                        &quot;VolumeSize&quot;: 8
                    }
                }
            ],
            &quot;Description&quot;: &quot;Image for Snowcone delivery #1&quot;,
            &quot;EnaSupport&quot;: false,
            &quot;Name&quot;: &quot;Snowcone v1&quot;,
            &quot;RootDeviceName&quot;: &quot;/dev/sda1&quot;
        },
        {
            &quot;ImageId&quot;: &quot;s.ami-0bb6828757f6a23cf&quot;,
            &quot;Public&quot;: false,
            &quot;State&quot;: &quot;AVAILABLE&quot;,
            &quot;BlockDeviceMappings&quot;: [
                {
                    &quot;DeviceName&quot;: &quot;/dev/sda&quot;,
                    &quot;Ebs&quot;: {
                        &quot;DeleteOnTermination&quot;: true,
                        &quot;Iops&quot;: 0,
                        &quot;SnapshotId&quot;: &quot;s.snap-003d9042a046f11f9&quot;,
                        &quot;VolumeSize&quot;: 20
                    }
                }
            ],
            &quot;Description&quot;: &quot;AWS DataSync AMI for online data transfer&quot;,
            &quot;EnaSupport&quot;: false,
            &quot;Name&quot;: &quot;scn-datasync-ami&quot;,
            &quot;RootDeviceName&quot;: &quot;/dev/sda&quot;
        }
    ]
}&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get One Today&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;You can order a Snowcone today for use in US locations, including here in Seattle:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/9euPWOLtzuw&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jeffbarr&quot;&gt;Jeff&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 16:56:59 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jeffbarr</dc:creator>
<og:title>Introducing AWS Snowcone – A Small, Lightweight, Rugged, Secure Edge Computing, Edge Storage, and Data Transfer Device | Amazon Web Services</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/introducing-aws-snowcone-small-lightweight-edge-storage-and-processing/</og:url>
<og:description>Last month I published my AWS Snowball Edge Update and told you about the latest updates to Snowball Edge, including faster storage-optimized devices with more memory &amp; vCPUs, the AWS OpsHub for Snow Family GUI-based management tool, IAM for Snowball Edge, and Snowball Edge Support for AWS Systems Manager. AWS Snowcone Today I would like […]</og:description>
<og:image>https://d2908q01vomqb2.cloudfront.net/da4b9237bacccdf19c0760cab7aec4a8359010b0/2020/04/14/snowcone_jb_sticker_1.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/introducing-aws-snowcone-small-lightweight-edge-storage-and-processing/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Millions of abandoned oil wells are leaking methane, a climate menace</title>
<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-drilling-abandoned-specialreport/special-report-millions-of-abandoned-oil-wells-are-leaking-methane-a-climate-menace-idUSKBN23N1NL</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-drilling-abandoned-specialreport/special-report-millions-of-abandoned-oil-wells-are-leaking-methane-a-climate-menace-idUSKBN23N1NL</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;SALYERSVILLE, Kentucky (Reuters) - (This June 16 story corrects comparison in paragraph eight of climate damage from methane leaks to that from U.S. oil consumption. The leaks cause climate damage roughly equivalent to typical U.S. oil consumption in one day, not two days.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;PrimaryAsset_container&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Image_container&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot; readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;LazyImage_container LazyImage_dark&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s4.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;amp;d=20200616&amp;amp;t=2&amp;amp;i=1522450403&amp;amp;r=LYNXMPEG5F0YS&amp;amp;w=20&quot; aria-label=&quot;FILE PHOTO: Hanson Rowe, a landowner who blames a leaky gas well on his property for health problems, smells for the odor of gas emanating from an abandoned well on his property in Salyersville, Kentucky, U.S., February 28, 2020. REUTERS/Bryan Woolston&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;FILE PHOTO: Hanson Rowe, a landowner who blames a leaky gas well on his property for health problems, smells for the odor of gas emanating from an abandoned well on his property in Salyersville, Kentucky, U.S., February 28, 2020. REUTERS/Bryan Woolston&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In May 2012, Hanson and Michael Rowe noticed an overpowering smell, like rotten eggs, seeping from an abandoned gas well on their land in Kentucky. The fumes made the retired couple feel nauseous, dizzy, and short of breath.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regulators responding to the leak couldn’t find an owner to fix it. J.D. Carty Resources LLC had drilled the well near the Rowes’ home in 2006 - promising the family a 12.5% royalty and free natural gas, which they never got. But Carty went bust in 2008 and sold the site to a company that was later acquired by Blue Energy LLC. Lawyers for both companies deny any responsibility for the leak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A year later, Kentucky’s Division of Oil and Gas declared the well an environmental emergency and hired Boots &amp;amp; Coots Inc - the Texas contractor that doused oil-well fires after the Gulf War - to plug it. During the 40-day operation, the Rowes retreated to a trailer on their property and lived with no running water to escape the gases and noise. Regulators determined the leak was a toxic blend of hydrogen sulfide, a common drilling byproduct, and the potent greenhouse gas methane. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I wouldn’t go through this again for $1 million,” said Hanson Rowe, who with his wife is suing the energy companies for compensation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The incident, while extreme, reflects a growing global problem: More than a century of oil and gas drilling has left behind millions of abandoned wells, many of which are leaching pollutants into the air and water. And drilling companies are likely to abandon many more wells due to bankruptcies, as oil prices struggle to recover from historic lows after the coronavirus pandemic crushed global fuel demand, according to bankruptcy lawyers, industry analysts and state regulators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leaks from abandoned wells have long been recognized as an environmental problem, a health hazard and a public nuisance. They have been linked to dozens of instances of groundwater contamination by research commissioned by the Groundwater Protection Council, whose members include state ground water agencies. Orphaned wells have been blamed for a slew of public safety incidents over the years, including a methane blowout at the construction site of a waterfront hotel in California last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They also pose a serious threat to the climate that researchers and world governments are only starting to understand, according to a Reuters review of government data and interviews with scientists, regulators, and United Nations officials. The Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change last year recommended that U.N. member countries start tracking and publishing the amount of methane leaching from their abandoned oil and gas wells after scientists started flagging it as a global warming risk. So far, the United States and Canada are the only nations to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The U.S. figures are sobering: More than 3.2 million abandoned oil and gas wells together emitted 281 kilotons of methane in 2018, according to the data, which was included in the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency’s most recent report on April 14 to the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change. That’s the climate-damage equivalent of consuming about 16 million barrels of crude oil, according to an EPA calculation, or about as much as the United States, the world’s biggest oil consumer, uses in a typical day. (For a graphic on the rise in abandoned oil wells, click &lt;a href=&quot;https://tmsnrt.rs/2MsWInw&quot;&gt;tmsnrt.rs/2MsWInw&lt;/a&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The actual amount could be as much as three times higher, the EPA says, because of incomplete data. The agency believes most of the methane comes from the more than 2 million abandoned wells it estimates were never properly plugged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is less severe in Canada, where the bulk of oil production comes from oil sands mining instead of traditional drilling. The government estimated that its 313,000 abandoned wells emitted 10.1 kt of methane in 2018, far less than in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The global impact is harder to measure. The governments of Russia, Saudi Arabia, and China – which round out the top five world oil-and-gas producers – did not respond to Reuters’ requests for comment on their abandoned wells and have not published reports on the wells’ methane leakage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researchers say it’s impossible to accurately estimate global emissions from leaky abandoned wells without better data. But a rough Reuters calculation, based on the U.S. share of global crude oil and natural gas production, would place the number of abandoned wells around the world at more than 29 million, with emissions of 2.5 million tonnes of methane per year - the climate-damage equivalent of three weeks of U.S. oil consumption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;HIDDEN MENACE&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a forested area of western New York state in February, a group of state regulators, along with researchers from the State University of New York at Binghamton, trudged through the snow. They stopped at a rotting wooden structure encircling a rusted pipe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Department of Environmental Conservation (DEC) official Charlie Dietrich held a bright orange device over the heap. It emitted a high-pitched signal, and its screen showed a code indicating the presence of ignitable gas. A scent of petroleum wafted through the air.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“There’s some methane coming up out of there,” DEC Mineral Resources Specialist Nathan Graber said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The abandoned well lies in the forests of Olean, New York, which was an oil boomtown at the turn of the 20th century. The site was one of 72 locations logged by geophysicists Tim de Smet and Alex Nikulin in December, researchers from Binghamton, using a drone equipped with a metal detector, part of a program launched in 2013 to help New York identify and plug abandoned wells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New York’s DEC has records of 2,200 abandoned wells dating back to the late 1800s. But the state believes the actual number could be much higher, because of incomplete records.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s a lot easier to find stuff when you know where to look,” Nikulin said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The group is among an array of regulators, activists and federal agencies now seeking out abandoned wells from the U.S. Northeast to California. The heightened interest in the climate threat posed by the wells started with a 2014 study by Princeton graduate student Mary Kang, who was the first to measure methane emissions from old drilling sites in Pennsylvania. She concluded in 2016 that abandoned wells represent 5% to 8% of total human-caused methane emissions in the state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s not like they leak for one year, and then they stop,” said Kang, now a professor of civil engineering at McGill University in Montreal. “Some of these have been there maybe for 100 years. And they are going to be there for another 100 years.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the Trump administration has downplayed global warming and its link to fossil fuels, the U.S. Energy Department has been financing efforts to improve data on emissions from abandoned wells. Researchers from DOE’s National Energy Technology Laboratory (NETL) recently took measurements from more than 200 wells in Kentucky and Oklahoma and are planning field work in Texas. They plan to publish their data by next spring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NETL researcher Natalie Pekney said the work was crucial to better understanding the climate impact of abandoned wells. Many wells don’t leak much or at all, she said, while others have “huge” methane emissions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NETL had previously used aerial surveys to locate old wells in Pennsylvania – home to the massive Marcellus gas deposit – so drillers could avoid pushing fluids and gases up through old abandoned well sites deep in the state’s forests. Its researchers found many old wells contained bubbling fluids, an indicator of methane leaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;GROWING PROBLEM&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nationwide, the number of documented abandoned wells has jumped by more than 12% since 2008, around the start of the hydraulic fracturing boom, according to the EPA estimates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many experts believe the number will keep growing. Oil-and-gas firm bankruptcies in the United States and Canada rose 50% to 42 in 2019, and analysts say the rate is likely to accelerate as the pandemic-related slide in energy prices shakes out producers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research firm Rystad Energy estimates that about 73 U.S. drilling companies could go bankrupt this year, with an additional 170 succumbing in 2021, assuming an average oil price of $30 a barrel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“When prices are this low, it becomes a very serious problem. It becomes a fight over who is going to ultimately have to pay” for cleaning up abandoned wells, said John Penn, a bankruptcy attorney with Perkins Coie LLP in Dallas. “It makes it really bad, and it’s going to get worse.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A school district in Beverly Hills, California, was saddled with a bill of at least $11 million to plug 19 oil wells on the property of its high school, after a judge in 2017 absolved Venoco LLC - the bankrupt company that had been operating the wells - of any responsibility for clean-up because other creditors took priority. The city of Beverly Hills is contributing another $11 million to the job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This is an incredible amount of money” siphoned away from education, said Michael Bregy, superintendent of the Beverly Hills Unified School District.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;State and federal regulations normally require drillers to pay an up-front bond to cover future cleanups if they go belly-up. But the rules are a patchwork, with wildly differing requirements, and they seldom leave governments adequately funded. In Pennsylvania, for example, it would take several thousand years to plug its estimated backlog of 200,000 abandoned oil wells at the current rate of spending, according to data from the state regulator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oil-industry lobbyists have been fighting state and federal efforts to increase the bonding, arguing it would hurt jobs and economic growth during an already tough time for the industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“States and the federal government have many sources of funding available to reclaim and plug abandoned wells,” said Reid Porter, a spokesman for the American Petroleum Institute, the country’s largest oil and gas trade group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The API spent $1.44 million in the first quarter of 2020 lobbying on Capitol Hill, with oil well bonding legislation one of the target issues, lobbying disclosures show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Government Accountability Office estimates that cleaning up and plugging an abandoned well runs from $20,000 to $145,000, putting the price tag for cleaning up all of America’s abandoned wells somewhere between $60 billion to $435 billion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;‘SHOOTING OUT OF THE EARTH’&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pollution threat goes beyond climate change. Leaks from abandoned wells have been found to contaminate groundwater and soil. In extreme cases, gas from abandoned wells has caused explosions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Ohio and Texas, state regulators have each found an average of around two groundwater contamination incidents per year related to orphaned wells, according to research by the Groundwater Protection Council published in 2011 and dating to the 1980s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In April 2017, for example, neighbors of Ohio farmer Stan Brenneman alerted him to the smell of oil coming from a drainage ditch on his 111-acre corn and soybean farm near the town of Elida, Brenneman told Reuters. The ditch drains water from the farm and carries it into rivers, streams and eventually Lake Erie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ohio’s Division of Oil &amp;amp; Gas Resources Management excavated 800 feet of the farm’s drainage system to find a well casing - about 130 years old - releasing oil three feet underground. The plugging operation took two months to complete and cost the state $196,915, according to a spokeswoman for the state Department of Natural Resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More recently, in 2018, the U.S. EPA was alerted to the presence of nearly 50 abandoned oil and gas wells on Navajo Nation lands within the borders of Utah and New Mexico that were bubbling water at the surface. Tests showed the way from some of the wells contained potentially dangerous levels of arsenic, sulfate, benzene and chloride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Navajo Nation Environmental Protection Agency said plugging the wells would require “major funds” and that, in the meantime, the public had been warned not to drink the water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In rare cases, gas from long-abandoned wells can cause dangerous accidents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In January of last year, a 1930s-era well sent a geyser of gas and dirt 100 feet into the air at the construction site of a Marriott seaside hotel in Marina del Rey, California, an upscale community in the Los Angeles area, according to a state report. The hotel owners did not respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It was horrifying,” said resident Marilyn Wall, who witnessed the explosion from her home across the street. She said she was stunned “by the extent and the length of time that the stuff was shooting out of the earth.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A worker standing on a construction platform above the plume was sprayed with debris and scrambled to lower himself down with an escape rope, a video of the explosion shows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;DON’T DRINK THE WATER&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Hanson and Michael Rowe, their troubles did not end the day their abandoned well was plugged. They no longer drink from the water well on their property because it gives them diarrhea, they said. Michael Rowe said she still suffers from headaches and coughing spells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kentucky’s Energy and Environment Cabinet is still fighting to recoup the $383,340 cost from the now-defunct J.D. Carty and Blue Energy in an ongoing court battle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An attorney for John Carty, founder of J.D. Carty, said his client had sold what few assets remained in the company and therefore bore no responsibility. A lawyer for Blue Energy said the company denies ever operating the wells on the property and has no responsibility to maintain or plug them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;J.D. Carty was only required to have one $50,000 “blanket bond” to cover all its wells in Kentucky. The amount forfeited to pay for the leaky well on Rowe’s land, determined in part by its depth, was just $2,500 - less than 1% of the cost to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Slideshow_container Slideshow_small Slideshow_standard&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Slideshow_preview-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;LazyImage_container LazyImage_dark&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s4.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;amp;d=20200616&amp;amp;t=2&amp;amp;i=1522450404&amp;amp;r=LYNXMPEG5F0YR&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

Slideshow &lt;span class=&quot;Slideshow_count&quot;&gt;(18 Images)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the incident, Kentucky lawmakers passed a bill last year that effectively doubled bond requirements for shallow wells to help cope with the state’s 13,000 abandoned wells. Still, state regulators say the list of wells is growing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hanson Rowe said he supports fossil fuel development because using natural gas for heat and cooking has improved his quality of life. But the couple say they hope their lawsuit against the companies involved will help change the way the energy industry manages its wells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You lost your health, you’ve lost it all,” Hanson Rowe said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Attribution_container&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Attribution_attribution&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Attribution_content&quot;&gt;Reporting by Nichola Groom; Additional reporting by Ekaterina Golubkova in Moscow, Rania El Gamal in Riyadh; Editing by Richard Valdmanis and Brian Thevenot&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;StandardArticleBody_trustBadgeContainer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;StandardArticleBody_trustBadgeTitle&quot;&gt;Our Standards:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;trustBadgeUrl&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thomsonreuters.com/en/about-us/trust-principles.html&quot;&gt;The Thomson Reuters Trust Principles.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 16:41:23 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>montalbano</dc:creator>
<og:title>Special Report: Millions of abandoned oil wells are leaking methane, a climate menace</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-drilling-abandoned-specialreport-idUSKBN23N1NL</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>(This June 16 story corrects comparison in paragraph eight of climate damage from methane leaks to that from U.S. oil consumption. The leaks cause climate damage roughly equivalent to typical U.S. oil consumption in one day, not two days.)</og:description>
<og:image>https://s4.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;d=20200616&amp;t=2&amp;i=1522450403&amp;w=1200&amp;r=LYNXMPEG5F0YS</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-drilling-abandoned-specialreport/special-report-millions-of-abandoned-oil-wells-are-leaking-methane-a-climate-menace-idUSKBN23N1NL</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Zoom to bring end-to-end encryption to all users, including non-paying</title>
<link>https://blog.zoom.us/wordpress/2020/06/17/end-to-end-encryption-update/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.zoom.us/wordpress/2020/06/17/end-to-end-encryption-update/</guid>
<description>&lt;section class=&quot;individual&quot; readability=&quot;33.517178195144&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;End-to-End Encryption Update&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;individual-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.zoom.us/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/zoom-logo-copy.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Since releasing the draft design of Zoom’s end-to-end encryption (E2EE) on May 22, we have engaged with civil liberties organizations, our CISO council, child safety advocates, encryption experts, government representatives, our own users, and others to gather their feedback on this feature. We have also explored new technologies to enable us to offer E2EE to all tiers of users. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Today, Zoom released an updated E2EE design on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/zoom/zoom-e2e-whitepaper&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;. We are also pleased to share that we have identified a path forward that balances the legitimate right of all users to privacy and the safety of users on our platform. This will enable us to offer E2EE as an advanced add-on feature for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;all&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;of our users around the globe – free and paid – while maintaining the ability to prevent and fight abuse on our platform. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;To make this possible, Free/Basic users seeking access to E2EE will participate in a one-time process that will prompt the user for additional pieces of information, such as verifying a phone number via a text message. Many leading companies perform similar steps on account creation to reduce the mass creation of abusive accounts. We are confident that by implementing risk-based authentication, in combination with our current mix of tools — including our Report a User function — we can continue to prevent and fight abuse.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Additional Information&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;We plan to begin early beta of the E2EE feature in July 2020. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;All Zoom users will continue to use AES 256 GCM transport encryption as the default encryption, one of the strongest encryption standards in use today.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;E2EE will be an optional feature as it limits some meeting functionality, such as the ability to include traditional PSTN phone lines or SIP/H.323 hardware conference room systems. Hosts will toggle E2EE on or off on a per-meeting basis. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Account administrators can enable and disable E2EE at the account and group level. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We are grateful to those who have provided their input on our E2EE design, both technical and philosophical. We encourage everyone to continue to share their views throughout this complex, ongoing process.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 16:32:02 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jmsflknr</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://blog.zoom.us/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/zoom-logo-copy-150x150.png</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>End-to-End Encryption Update - Zoom Blog</og:title>
<og:description>Since releasing the draft design of Zoom’s end-to-end encryption (E2EE) on May 22, we have engaged with a number of organizations to gather feedback.</og:description>
<og:url>https://blog.zoom.us/wordpress/2020/06/17/end-to-end-encryption-update/</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.zoom.us/wordpress/2020/06/17/end-to-end-encryption-update/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Google faces $5B lawsuit for tracking people in incognito mode</title>
<link>https://www.cnet.com/news/google-faces-5-billion-lawsuit-for-tracking-people-in-incognito-mode/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.cnet.com/news/google-faces-5-billion-lawsuit-for-tracking-people-in-incognito-mode/</guid>
<description>&lt;span class=&quot;imageContainer&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cnet1.cbsistatic.com/img/fg9xHnen-pvR09CwbqLiu97alT0=/1092x0/2019/10/09/1e9aced3-dda4-4957-ba23-8834b04380fa/20191008-google-headquarters-campus-mountain-view-002.jpg&quot; class=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;Google headquarters in Mountain View, California&quot; height=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1092&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Google headquarters sprawls across a large campus in Mountain View, California.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;Stephen Shankland/CNET&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;speakableTextP1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnet.com/google/&quot; data-annotation=&quot;true&quot; data-component=&quot;linkTracker&quot; data-link-tracker-options=&quot;{&amp;quot;action&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;inline-annotation|Google|CNET_TAG|340&amp;quot;}&quot; section=&quot;annotation&quot;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt; faces a proposed class action lawsuit that accuses the tech giant of invading people's &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnet.com/tags/privacy/&quot; data-annotation=&quot;true&quot; data-component=&quot;linkTracker&quot; data-link-tracker-options=&quot;{&amp;quot;action&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;inline-annotation|Privacy|CNET_TAG|195&amp;quot;}&quot; section=&quot;annotation&quot;&gt;privacy&lt;/a&gt; and tracking internet use even when browsers are set to &quot;private&quot; mode. The suit, filed Tuesday in the US District Court for the Northern District of California, alleges that Google violates wiretapping and privacy laws by continuing to &quot;intercept, track, and collect communications&quot; even when people use Chrome's incognito mode and other private web browser modes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;speakableTextP2&quot;&gt;&quot;Google tracks and collects consumer browsing history and other web activity data no matter what safeguards consumers undertake to protect their data privacy,&quot; reads the complaint. The search giant surreptitiously collects data through Google Analytics, Google Ad Manager, website plug-ins and other applications, including &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnet.com/topics/mobile-apps/&quot; data-annotation=&quot;true&quot; data-component=&quot;linkTracker&quot; data-link-tracker-options=&quot;{&amp;quot;action&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;inline-annotation|Mobile Apps|CNET_CAT_TOPIC|150&amp;quot;}&quot; section=&quot;annotation&quot;&gt;mobile apps&lt;/a&gt;, according to the complaint. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;newsletter-subscribe-form desktop -inline&quot; section=&quot;subscribeNewsletter&quot; data-track=&quot;newsletter&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;newsletterTitle&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;CNET Daily News&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;newsletter&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Stay in the know. Get the latest tech stories from CNET News every weekday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lawsuit seeks at least $5 billion from Google and its parent company, Alphabet, according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/article/us-alphabet-google-privacy-lawsuit/google-faces-5-billion-lawsuit-in-u-s-for-tracking-private-internet-use-idUSKBN23933H&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-component=&quot;externalLink&quot;&gt;Reuters&lt;/a&gt;. The complaint says the proposed class may include &quot;millions&quot; of Google users and is looking for damages of at least $5,000 for each individual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google said it disputes the claims and plans to defend itself vigorously against them.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;Incognito mode in Chrome gives you the choice to browse the internet without your activity being saved to your browser or device,&quot; said Google spokesperson Jose Castaneda&lt;strong&gt;. &quot;&lt;/strong&gt;As we clearly state each time you open a new incognito tab, websites might be able to collect information about your browsing activity during your session.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plaintiffs in the case are being represented by the law firm Boies Schiller &amp;amp; Flexner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;shortcode video v2&quot; data-video-playlist=&quot;[{&amp;quot;id&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;94438043-979d-4301-a874-683a618b501d&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Prepare for a \u0027new national surveillance system\u0027 in order to wipe out COVID-19&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;description&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Experts warn that to stop the coronavirus we\u0027re on the verge of surrendering critical personal privacy rights to big tech firms and national governments.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;slug&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;prepare-for-a-new-national-surveillance-system-in-order-to-wipe-out-covid-19&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;chapters&amp;quot;:{&amp;quot;data&amp;quot;:[],&amp;quot;paging&amp;quot;:{&amp;quot;total&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;limit&amp;quot;:15,&amp;quot;offset&amp;quot;:0}},&amp;quot;datePublished&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;2020-05-11 18:19:25&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;duration&amp;quot;:390,&amp;quot;mpxRefId&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;WZRaXJtvui8x0MMudouk2CKAy_iJdU3_&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;ratingVChip&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;TV-14&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;primaryTopic&amp;quot;:{&amp;quot;id&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1c1fbb47-c387-11e2-8208-0291187b029a&amp;quot;},&amp;quot;author&amp;quot;:{&amp;quot;id&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;95cf9546-0e20-4da2-bb98-28a346da6509&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;firstName&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Dan&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;lastName&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Patterson&amp;quot;},&amp;quot;primaryCollection&amp;quot;:{&amp;quot;id&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;040fa0bc-bf08-43dc-ac3d-ee7869a9fc85&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;CNET News Video&amp;quot;},&amp;quot;image&amp;quot;:{&amp;quot;path&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https:\/\/cnet3.cbsistatic.com\/img\/jfi1WeKo4hNrd8MS6vBHvu_dPtQ=\/1280x720\/2020\/05\/11\/f3347c95-f43c-47e3-a6e4-58b64a7b33c4\/covid19-privacy-final.jpg&amp;quot;},&amp;quot;thumbnail&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https:\/\/cnet2.cbsistatic.com\/img\/X8g8ttht3KqElyGBSIlc9v68LC4=\/194x109\/2020\/05\/11\/f3347c95-f43c-47e3-a6e4-58b64a7b33c4\/covid19-privacy-final.jpg&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;closedCaptionPath&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;\/videos\/captions\/webvtt\/prepare-for-a-new-national-surveillance-system-in-order-to-wipe-out-covid-19.vtt&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;urlPath&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;\/videos\/prepare-for-a-new-national-surveillance-system-in-order-to-wipe-out-covid-19\/&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;isVertical&amp;quot;:false,&amp;quot;m3u8&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https:\/\/cnetvideo.cbsistatic.com\/vr\/2020\/05\/11\/1736341571951\/314860_hls\/master.m3u8&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;mp4&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https:\/\/cnetvideo.cbsistatic.com\/vr\/2020\/05\/11\/1736341571951\/Covid19_Privacy_FINAL_314859_740.mp4&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;index&amp;quot;:0}]&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embeddedVideoContainer&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot; aria-label=&quot;Play video Prepare for a 'new national surveillance system' in order to wipe out COVID-19&quot; data-load-video=&quot;0&quot; data-video-id=&quot;94438043-979d-4301-a874-683a618b501d&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;videoContainer&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cnet2.cbsistatic.com/img/WwRxlTDRp2SteO2E8z5lrF670bk=/196x110/2020/05/11/f3347c95-f43c-47e3-a6e4-58b64a7b33c4/covid19-privacy-final.jpg&quot; class=&quot;photo&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; width=&quot;196&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;bold&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nowPlaying&quot;&gt;Now playing:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;watchThis&quot;&gt;Watch this:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Prepare for a 'new national surveillance system' in order...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;duration&quot;&gt;6:30&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 16:04:33 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>petercooper</dc:creator>
<og:title>Google faces $5 billion lawsuit for tracking people in incognito mode</og:title>
<og:description>The search giant is accused of invading the privacy of millions of Americans.</og:description>
<og:image>https://cnet2.cbsistatic.com/img/2yNzm8caTWayqA4UtHgJDeAI5x8=/756x567/2019/10/09/1e9aced3-dda4-4957-ba23-8834b04380fa/20191008-google-headquarters-campus-mountain-view-002.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.cnet.com/news/google-faces-5-billion-lawsuit-for-tracking-people-in-incognito-mode/</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.cnet.com/news/google-faces-5-billion-lawsuit-for-tracking-people-in-incognito-mode/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>YC&amp;#039;s Startup School Relaunching as Continuous Program</title>
<link>https://blog.ycombinator.com/startup-school-relaunch/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.ycombinator.com/startup-school-relaunch/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;We’re excited to announce that Startup School (SUS) is relaunching today as a continuous program. This change will allow us to serve many more founders than the traditional annual course we’ve been running since 2017 and better support startup founders year-round.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to this change to continuous admissions, we’ve revamped the Startup School experience to double down on the things our founders have found most useful. Through thousands of founder surveys and dozens of interviews, we’ve discovered that founders get value from SUS in three key areas: &lt;strong&gt;curriculum, accountability and community&lt;/strong&gt;. We’re making changes program-wide to better focus on those pillars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Curriculum&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Startup School’s video lectures and text library are our differentiator. No other resource online so efficiently condenses the information you need to start a company in 2020. With our relaunch, we’re making that curriculum even better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve completely redesigned our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.startupschool.org/curriculum&quot;&gt;curriculum page&lt;/a&gt; to include both recorded lectures and high-value written content. Additionally, we’ve heard from founders that not all lectures are relevant to their specific circumstances, so we’re personalizing the required program curriculum based on your company’s stage (idea, launch or growth). We’re also making it easy to skip content that isn’t relevant to your company right now. Finally, we’ve made it easier to consume our content in whatever order makes sense for your company, since everyone is at a different place. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.startupschool.org/register&quot;&gt;Sign up now&lt;/a&gt; to get access to these features!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accountability&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One reason founders keep coming back to Startup School, in many cases even after participating in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ycombinator.com/about/#whatwedo&quot;&gt;YC’s core program&lt;/a&gt;, is because SUS gives them structure and accountability. We ask founders to submit weekly company updates tracking their goals and most important metrics. These updates encourage founders to talk to users and launch quickly. Consistent progress every week is a prerequisite for success, and updates are one way to track that. As part of our relaunch, we’re introducing &lt;strong&gt;streaks&lt;/strong&gt;. SUS will track the number of consecutive weeks you’ve submitted an update as your streak number, which is important for certification and qualifying for special SUS opportunities. We hope this gives founders extra motivation to consistently work on their company week after week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Community&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting a company can be lonely, especially for the majority of SUS founders that live outside traditional startup hubs. Founders come to Startup School for the personalized advice and camaraderie that a strong community provides. Over 100,000 founders have signed up for Startup School since 2018, and we’re continually improving the quality of our growing community through active moderation and new features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the new relaunch, we are providing exclusive forums for later-stage companies where they can discuss issues specific to their situation. We’re also improving the matching algorithm used for our weekly small-group video calls. Finally, we have new features planned for local founder communities in hundreds of cities around the world, but we’re waiting to roll those out until in-person meetups become less of a safety risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Startup School: It’s about the journey, not the destination&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve always considered Startup School an ongoing program that alumni can return to again and again for content, accountability and community. But the course format — with specific enrollment and graduation dates — didn’t support that message. For our relaunch, we’re doing away with the concept of graduation entirely and replacing it with a &lt;strong&gt;Startup School Certified&lt;/strong&gt; achievement. This change makes it clear that getting certified is just the beginning of your startup (and Startup School!) journey, not an end in and of itself. To get certified, founders must (1) review all relevant Startup School curriculum, (2) participate in at least one weekly group session, and (3) complete an 8-week streak submitting updates. Founders can choose to share their public profile including certification status as evidence of their participation in the program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Startup School will continue to offer founders access to the forum, a record of progress via weekly updates, group sessions with fellow founders, and deals to help accelerate startup growth from partners like AWS, GCP, and Stripe. To learn more about the structure and features of Startup School, read our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.startupschool.org/about&quot;&gt;About&lt;/a&gt; page and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.startupschool.org/faq&quot;&gt;FAQs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New faces&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since our last course began, we’ve added two new faces to the Startup School team! Joan DeGennaro, a YC alumnus and former Startup School mentor, has joined as our full-time community manager. Joan is focusing on providing the best user experience for our founders and making Startup School an inclusive community. Catheryn Li is a product engineer joining us from Facebook. Cat has reimagined core elements of Startup School with a user-centered approach and built much of the new functionality for our relaunch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sign up today!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enrollment in the new program opened today! If you’re a founder there’s no better place to find the support you need to build a successful startup. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.startupschool.org/register&quot;&gt;Sign up now&lt;/a&gt; and let’s build something amazing together!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 16:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kcorbitt</dc:creator>
<og:title>Startup School Relaunching as Continuous Program</og:title>
<og:url>https://blog.ycombinator.com/startup-school-relaunch/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>We’re excited to announce that Startup School (SUS) is relaunching today as a continuous program. This change will allow us to serve many more founders than the traditional annual course we’ve been running since 2017 and better support startup founders year-round. In addition to this change to cont</og:description>
<og:image>https://ycombinator.wpengine.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/YC-logo-1200-1.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.ycombinator.com/startup-school-relaunch/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Postbank to replace 12M bank cards after employees steal &amp;#039;master key&amp;#039;</title>
<link>https://www.timeslive.co.za/sunday-times/news/2020-06-14-postbank-forced-to-replace-12-million-bank-cards-after-employees-steal-master-key/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.timeslive.co.za/sunday-times/news/2020-06-14-postbank-forced-to-replace-12-million-bank-cards-after-employees-steal-master-key/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;article-title article-title-tertiary&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Criminal employees steal code and put millions of grant recipients at risk&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;14 June 2020 - 00:00 &lt;span id=&quot;authors&quot; data-author=&quot;SIPHO MASONDO&quot; class=&quot;heading-author&quot;&gt;By &lt;span class=&quot;authors-list&quot;&gt;SIPHO MASONDO&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Postbank is having to replace about 12-million bank cards at a cost of R1bn after a major security breach that exposes the personal data of millions of social-grant beneficiaries and other account holders.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The breach resulted from the printing of the bank's encrypted master key in plain, unencrypted digital language at the Postbank's old data centre in the Pretoria city centre...&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 15:37:12 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>zdw</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.timeslive.co.za/sunday-times/news/2020-06-14-postbank-forced-to-replace-12-million-bank-cards-after-employees-steal-master-key/</og:url>
<og:title>Postbank forced to replace 12-million bank cards after employees steal 'master key'</og:title>
<og:description>The Postbank is having to replace about 12-million bank cards at a cost of R1bn after a major security breach that exposes the personal data of millions of social-grant beneficiaries and other account holders.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/BrFrkUF77cKzPThlKLm1QdBgpJFH-PYgOJjrdjDCaw39rwyX_5eeaaGhYfG4jVbh6AFtbWfP1OVkKcUzpa9gYQ=s1000</og:image>
<dc:language>en-ZA</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.timeslive.co.za/sunday-times/news/2020-06-14-postbank-forced-to-replace-12-million-bank-cards-after-employees-steal-master-key/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Time to Upgrade Your Monitor</title>
<link>https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/</guid>
<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/cover.gif&quot; /&gt; Illustration by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.behance.net/yuliaprokopova&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Yulia Prokopova&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a programmer. I do not deal with digital painting, photo processing, video editing. I don’t really care for wide gamut or even proper color reproduction. I spend most of my days in a text browser, text editor and text terminal, looking at barely moving letters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I optimize my setup to showing really, really good letters. A good monitor is essential for that. Not nice to have. A MUST. And in “good” I mean, as good as you can get. These are my thoughts, based on my own experience, on what monitors work best for programming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/nikitonsky/status/1260287480638701568&quot;&gt;my research among programmers&lt;/a&gt;, 43% are still using monitors with pixel per inch density less than 150:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/research.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why is this a problem? Because the only way to get good letters is by spending more pixels per letter. That simple. In the past, the displays’ pixel count was small, so we learned to live with that and even invented some very clever tricks to make our lives better. The two important things to understand are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Times of low-resolution displays are over. High-resolution displays are a commodity now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tricks developed for low-resolution displays didn’t magically make text look good. That always was and still is impossible. They just made text slightly less terrible, but it still is terrible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you think that you can somehow make your 1080p display render good text, that it just needs a few more tweaks, NO. This won’t happen. The sooner you accept that the sooner you can start looking for real solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make my claim better founded, let’s look in detail how text &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; looks on a low-resolution display and what can be done about it (spoiler: not much!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;not-enough-pixels&quot;&gt;Not enough pixels&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, there are simply not enough pixels to draw a letter. Let’s take Consolas, a font that was developed specifically for programmers. Microsoft worked really hard to fine-tune it for low-resolution rendering. We set it at 14px, which is default in VS Code (and people often go lower than that!):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/consolas_gray_1x.png&quot; /&gt; Consolas at 14px, macOS
&lt;p&gt;On that size, capital letter B takes up mere 6×9 pixels on a screen. Lowercase letters only have 7 (seven!) vertical pixels to work with. That’s NOT MUCH. I have more fingers than that. No matter how good font is designed, it’s hard to show anything when all you have is seven pixels. Anything slightly more complex than “T” or “H” becomes an illegible pixel mess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look at the “g” in the picture above. It’s hard to say where strokes start or end, or even how many of them are there. It’s just random gray noise or a checkerboard, but not a letter. This is a letter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/consolas_24x.png&quot; /&gt; Consolas at 168px
&lt;p&gt;It’s a shame, really, watching these beautiful fine details getting clamped into mere 7×10 pixels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-dreadful-hinting&quot;&gt;The dreadful hinting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To fight the problem of everything being a gray mess, Windows uses pretty aggressive hinting. Basically, it just bends and moves letter strokes to the nearest pixel, ensuring more crisp boundaries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it works! Fonts do look better with hinting than without it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/hinting.png&quot; /&gt; No hinting (macOS) → Hinting (Windows)
&lt;p&gt;Don’t get your hopes up though: it’s still a mess. It doesn’t make text look &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt;. It makes it look &lt;em&gt;better&lt;/em&gt;, but it is still bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main problem with hinting, though, is that it destroys letter shapes. Pixels are rendered not where they are supposed to be, but rather where pixel grid happens. To give you a taste:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/ttf_hinting.png&quot; /&gt; Verdana (k) and Times New Roman Italic (z) before rasterization at 13px. &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.archive.org/web/20160304021305/http://antigrain.com/research/font_rasterization/index.html&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea is that it’ll look better when rendered to the actual pixels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But even if we just look at vertical hinting of horizontal stems, it’s still changes font way too much:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/hinting_align.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;See how horizontal stems are offset from their actual position in the vector font file? The error here is as big as ¼ pixel!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But hey! If you never saw a high-res Consolas, who cares if &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;g&lt;/code&gt; is the same shape or not? Who cares if stems are in the wrong place if you don’t know where they should’ve been in the first place? Well, sometimes problems are more obvious: circles are not circles, equal distances become not equal, proportions are all wrong, what supposed to be small becomes huge and vice versa, etc. Here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/hinting_numbersign.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;After moving horizontal stems to match pixel grid (by offsetting them up to ½ pixel!), Windows is having a hard time splitting 7 other pixels into three equal gaps. Unfortunately, alternative is no better:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/no_hinting_numbersign.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;From my personal experience &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tonsky/FiraCode/issues?q=is%3Aissue+is%3Aopen+label%3Ahinting&quot;&gt;building Fira Code&lt;/a&gt;, I’ve seen too many ways simple idea “just stick edges to the nearest pixel” can go wrong:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/hinting_failures.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/hinting_failures_2.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a game that just can’t be won.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-fractional-pixel&quot;&gt;A fractional pixel&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you draw a perfect line that is thinner than one pixel?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes. The idea is simple, really. Your display’s pixel consists of three vertical subpixels, each responsible for their color. We can light them up individually, effectively tripling horizontal resolution!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/subpixel_1.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;In practice, though, you can’t implement it literally like that, because you’ll just end up with a christmas light mess:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/subpixel_2.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;So you have to compromise again (inside another compromise!), putting limit of how far can color deviate from black:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/subpixel_3.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Which means letter shapes are not 3× sharper, they are maybe 1.5× sharper, but overall still pretty blurry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/subpixel_4.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the end, there is an improvement in readability, but at the same time, black-on-white text gets a slight teal-and-orange halo around it. It’s not super bad, but you &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; see it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I am trying to say is: all these tricks work. Having them is strictly better than not having them. For low-DPI displays all those are &lt;em&gt;a must&lt;/em&gt;. But at the same time, they are a tight compromise made in times where we didn’t have better displays. Now that we have them, it’s time for all those tricks to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/subpixel_5.png&quot; /&gt; Consolas 14px with ClearType and hinting → Consolas 14px @2x

&lt;p&gt;Retina Macbooks &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; make text look good. However, there are two things you absolutely must do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;turn-off-font-smoothing&quot;&gt;Turn off font smoothing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, turn OFF “Font smoothing” in System Preferences → General:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/no_smoothing.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure what the default value for it is these days, but make sure it’s OFF anyways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That preference name is misleading. It used to be called “LCD font smoothing”, which suggested subpixel antialiasing. But Apple removed subpixel antialiasing from macOS in 2018, the same month it retired its last non-retina notebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other thing the name suggests is that your fonts might not be smoothed at all. This is not the case either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What it actually does is it makes font slightly bolder:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;hoverable&quot; src=&quot;https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/smoothing_anim.png&quot; /&gt; Hover over or click the image to see the difference
&lt;p&gt;So, why would you want it off? Because there’s no automated way to make font bolder. Normally each font weight is carefully designed by a professional type designer. It’s a tricky process that involves millions of constraints. If you try to simulate it by, for example, adding an outline to the letter, it will look terrible:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;hoverable&quot; src=&quot;https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/fake_bold.png&quot; /&gt; Real bold v. Fake bold simulated with an outline. Hover or click to see the outline
&lt;p&gt;But that’s exactly what “Font smoothing” in macOS does! Here’s another example. MacOS blurs pixel-perfect boundaries with “font smoothing”:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/smoothing_artefacts.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Imagine a font designer who carefully balanced every letter, placed each point down to 1/100 of the pixel, only to be ignored by dumb software that thinks it knows better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does that mean for us, programmers? If you take a font that was hand-optimized for particular pixel size (which many programming fonts are, e.g. &lt;a href=&quot;https://input.fontbureau.com/info/&quot;&gt;Input at 11px&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://larsenwork.com/monoid/&quot;&gt;Monoid at 12px&lt;/a&gt;), it will be rendered blurry despite all the efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/smoothing_input.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;And all the other fonts, including system ones, will be slightly more blurry than they need to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UPD: Chris Morgan &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23553486&quot;&gt;mentioned in a comment&lt;/a&gt; that this setting might explain why so many designers put &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;font-weight: 300&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://grumpy.website/post/0PPp8l_pu&quot;&gt;as their default web page font&lt;/a&gt;. They are over-compensating for font emboldement of macOS!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;integer-scaling&quot;&gt;Integer scaling&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I bought my first (and world’s first) Retina Macbook Pro in 2012, it was exactly what was advertised: 2× scaling, every logical pixel rendered to 2×2 screen ones. 2880×1800 screen would be rendered from 1440×900 logical source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly, reason has left Apple since, and at some point, Macbooks started to get weird non-integer scaling as default. E.g. 2880×1800 screen would have 1680×1050 logical resolution. That is 1.7142857143… scaling factor, or 12/7.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why? I guess, someone at Apple decided that more screen real estate sells better. The problem is, it’s not that big an increase: just a mere 15%. I mean, 15% is good, but not game-changing. The terrible part is, it comes at the cost of losing any chance to render ANY pixel-crisp image at all!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s see. 12/7 scaling factor means that for every 7 logical pixels there are 12 corresponding screen pixels. Meaning, every 7 pixels you have a chance to draw a 7-pixel tall rectangle and that’s your only chance to align with the pixel grid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/12by7_grid.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Move 1 pixel up or down—you lose. Make it 1px taller or shorter—you lose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/12by7_grid_offset.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;A pixel-perfect line? Too bad you can’t specify 7/12 of a pixel as the line width. Even worse, each 1px line looks differently depending on its vertical position:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/12by7_lines.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;It shouldn’t come as a surprise that modern icons are mostly made out of single-pixel-wide strokes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/12by7_ui.png&quot; /&gt; Top: 2× scale, bottom: same after 12/7 downscaling
&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to imagine someone who wants to look at &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; on purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(no idea why bottom right pixel is missing on all the icons)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happens with the text? Nothing good. First it is rendered pixel-crisp at 2× resolution, then downscaled at 85.7142857143…% to fit into physical pixels:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/12by7_text.png&quot; /&gt; Monoid at 12px. Top: 2× scale, bottom: same after 12/7 downscaling
&lt;p&gt;That’s right, UI isn’t even rendered in that weird target resolution. Every Mac app thinks it is rendering at 2×, and only after that OS scales it down to the target resolution. There’s a lot of precision and nuance lost due to this two-step resize process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, nothing can do more harm to the look of UI than this. Even old low-dpi UIs are better since their lines at least align with pixels!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And don’t forget: this is the default. Every Macbook is shipped with these settings. Millions of people are working not knowing they were robbed of the joy of the retina screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily for us, this is easy to fix (at least for now). Go to System Preferences → Displays, uncheck Default and select 2× resolution instead:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/scaling.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This will make everything on the screen slightly bigger, leaving you (slightly!) less screen estate. This is expected. My opinion is, a notebook is a constrained environment by definition. Extra 15% won’t magically turn it into a huge comfortable desktop. But at least you can enjoy that gorgeous screen and pixel-crisp fonts. Otherwise, why would you buy a retina screen at all?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;cleartype-on-windows&quot;&gt;ClearType on Windows&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all this talk about downsides of ClearType and how it’s only a must on low-density displays, should you turn it off on 4k display? In theory, yes. In practice, no.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, Windows doesn’t even have a UI to turn it off. I mean, there’s this checkbox:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/windows_cleartype.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;but even if you turn it off, you’ll have to go through configuring ClearType anyway. There’s just no OK button ¯\_(ツ)_/¯.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you turn it off this way, it’ll disappear in some places, but keep appearing in others. I guess those places use different APIs and one respects this setting while other does not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/windows_cleartype_mix.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;And most importantly, text without ClearType looks like shit. It doesn’t have to (it looks perfect on macOS, for example), but particularly on Windows it’s unbearable. I guess they don’t even test this as an option:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/windows_no_cleartype.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just for fun, I retyped all the text labels using the same font, size and color, but on macOS:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/mac_no_cleartype.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;But ClearType-d text on Windows still looks good, even on 4k display. It’s just a shame we can’t let ClearType go yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me express an opinion. This is my blog, after all. I think that notebooks are not good for development. They are great in mobility and convenience, and this argument might outweigh everything else for some people. I accept that. But still, a desktop monitor + external keyboard are &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; better than a notebook. There might be other reasons for not buying a monitor, but having one, I hope, no one would argue it’s a superior dev environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this out of the way, the question arises, which monitor should you get? From what we already discussed, two things should be clear:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;It needs to be at least a 4k monitor. Both 5k and 6k are also great, of course.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You need to use the integer scaling factor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;That means, if you have a 4k monitor (3840×2160), and use 2× scaling, you’ll get an equivalent of 1920×1080 logical pixels. So it’s a basic 1080p monitor in terms of how much you can fit, but with much crisper UI and text in everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, it might be tempting to use, for example, 1.5× scaling. That would give you an equivalent of 2560×1440 logical pixels, which, you might think, is much better. This is not how you should use it! The idea of a 4k monitor is NOT to get more pixels but to get the pixel-perfect, high-density UI rendering. Otherwise, a normal 1440p display would work better. A simple rule to remember: &lt;em&gt;pixel alignment outweighs everything else&lt;/em&gt;. 1440p display is better at displaying 1440p content than 2160p display is at it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s also possible to run a 4k display at native 3840×2160 pixels. It depends on the size of the display, of course, but in my experience, even 27” 4k displays are too small to run at 1×. The UI will be too tiny.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-myth-of-apple-patented-ppi&quot;&gt;The myth of Apple-patented PPI&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bjango.com/articles/macexternaldisplays/&quot;&gt;Some articles&lt;/a&gt; suggest that Apple computers should only be used with 220 PPI displays (pixels per inch) because that’s the number Apple itself uses on all the Macbooks and iMacs. Sometimes people go as far as saying displays with different PPI are unusable with macOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what I think. PPI defines the physical size of the pixel (220 PPI means there are 220 pixels per inch, or 1 pixel is 1/220 inch wide). So Apple ensures that pixels on all its devices have the same size. Does it mean macOS controls have the same physical size? Not anymore, after Apple started applying non-integer scaling by default on Macbooks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, it’s nearly impossible to ensure that &lt;em&gt;perceived&lt;/em&gt; size, or how big the user &lt;em&gt;sees&lt;/em&gt; the control, is the same because the distance to the display is different. For example, on average my eye-to-screen distance is 33 cm with the notebook, but 68 cm with the monitor. That’s 2× difference!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/distance.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;That means that the angular size of the 1/220 Macbook pixel is equivalent to 1/110 monitor pixel. I’m actually having smaller &lt;em&gt;perceived&lt;/em&gt; pixels on 4k 27” monitor than I have on 15” Macbook Pro!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even Apple itself understands that! Their iPhones have higher PPI than Macbooks because they are usually looked at from a closer distance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To sum things up, I don’t see a problem with 24” 4k displays or even 27” displays. I use both with macOS and love both, never had any problems. Of course, 5k or 6k would be better, but those go in the “nice to have” category. 4k is a must-have, an absolute minimum for anyone working with text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world used to be divided into two camps: high-resolution displays and high-frame-rate displays. The former was good for text, latter for gaming, with no middle ground in between. If you like to play competitive games, buy both (and a large table). Gamers had no use for 4k displays since no reasonable game would run at 4k @ 120Hz, and the creative professionals had no use for 120 Hz in photo/text editing. I was in high-res camp since 2014, of course, and would never trade retina text rendering for barely noticeable refresh rate upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/camps.png&quot; /&gt; HP Z27 (4k) v. LG 34GL750-B (120 Hz)
&lt;p&gt;Well, the split does not exist anymore. Since not that long ago (yes, I’m too lazy to check) you can have both! You can have a 4k monitor that runs on 120 Hz. In fact, that discovery was the main motivation for this article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-120hz&quot;&gt;Why 120 Hz?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you, like me, work with text, you might think that you have no use for 120 Hz. And you would be right. This falls into a “nice to have” category, but if you are looking for ways to improve your experience, this is a great way to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;120 Hz gives you a couple of significant improvements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Animations are smoother, up to the point where they start to appear like a continuous motion instead of a very fast slideshow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scrolling is very smooth in particular. Browser, code editing, to name a few.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The whole system feels much more responsive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can play games and work on a single display.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;I can’t show you how 120 Hz feels, of course. But this is what you can do to get the idea: switch to 30 Hz and try to work like that for a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll notice that everything is poorly animated, but also way less responsive. This is because the time between monitor updates is now 32 ms instead of 16 ms at 60 Hz. That means that whatever you do (press a button, move a mouse), the closest moment in time computer might start displaying the result might be as far as 32 ms away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;32 ms is a long time and easily perceivable. On 60 Hz, that time is cut in half: the longest you need to wait is just 16 ms. On 120 Hz, this is time is cut in half again: from 16 ms to 8 ms. In absolute numbers, you lose an additional 8 ms, which means going 60 Hz → 120 Hz is about half as impactful as going 30 Hz → 60 Hz. Still, something to go after, in my opinion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-to-buy&quot;&gt;What to buy?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There isn’t much choice, really. From what I can find, right now there are only four (yes, four!) 4k 120+ Hz displays on the market! I imagine that’s because demand is not that high, but hey, I’m glad we have at least those!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First one is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.asus.com/us/Monitors/ROG-SWIFT-PG27UQ/&quot;&gt;Asus ROG SWIFT PG27UQ&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/asus_pg27uq.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Second one is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.acer.com/ac/en/US/content/predator-series/predatorx27&quot;&gt;Acer Predator X27&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/acer_x27.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Third one is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.acer.com/ac/en/US/content/conceptd-model/UM.HC1AA.P02&quot;&gt;Acer ConceptD CP7&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/acer_cp7.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;All are very nice monitors, I’m sure. But the price is a bit too steep (~$2,000), especially for someone for whom getting 120 Hz is not a question of life and death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are few more &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tomshardware.com/reviews/best-4k-gaming-monitors-pc-144hz,6023.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; with a diagonal size of 55” and more, which would be hard to use on a normal desktop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, by some unbelievable struck of luck, we actually have ONE reasonably priced, reasonably sized 4k 120 Hz monitor. That’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.acer.com/ac/en/US/content/model/UM.HX3AA.P02&quot;&gt;Acer Nitro XV273K&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/acer_xv3.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;And that’s the one that I have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;things-to-look-out-for-windows&quot;&gt;Things to look out for (Windows)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running 4k at 120 Hz is simple on Windows. Make sure your graphics card has DisplayPort 1.4, use it, that’s it. Seriously, it just works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/windows.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;things-to-look-out-for-macos&quot;&gt;Things to look out for (macOS)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MacOS support sucks. Officially none of the Apple computers support anything beyond 60 Hz, even on normal resolutions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/macs_compatibility.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;So buying this display was the pure leap of faith. This is what I figured:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;4k @ 120 Hz requires 3840 × 2160 × 3 bpp × 120 Hz × 8 = 24 Gbit/s. Just below of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DisplayPort#1.3&quot;&gt;25.92 Gbit/s of DisplayPort 1.3 / 1.4&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HDMI 2.0 only provides 18.0 Gbit/s, so it has to be DisplayPort.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thunderbolt 3 can carry DisplayPort 1.4, so if only I can find the adapter, I should be good to go.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Which port does my Macbook have? Easy! Use this Apple-provided diagram:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/ports_diagram.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Okay, so lighting bolt icon means Thunderbolt (not to be confused with Lighting port!), railroad switch means USB-C. Now just look at your Macbook:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/macbook_ports.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I guess you just have to know it ¯\_(ツ)_/¯. Alternatively, one can look at the Apple’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.apple.com/kb/SP794?locale=en_US&quot;&gt;intuitively named page SP794&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/macbook_spec_1.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/macbook_spec_2.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ok, first of all, what does Thunderbolt 3 (USB-C) mean? Is it Thunderbolt 3 or is it USB-C? This might be a difference between “works flawlessly” and “doesn’t work at all”:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/monitor_ports.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then it says “DisplayPort over USB-C” (but we have Thunderbolt 3, not USB-C!). It does not specify the DisplayPort version, and it’s useless without it. It also says USB 3.1 Gen 2 is limited by 10 Gb/s, but I guess USB 3 limits do not apply to USB-C? Also, what kind of name is USB 3.1 Gen 2? Was USB 3.2 already taken?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thunderbolt_(interface)#Thunderbolt_3&quot;&gt;Wikipedia to the rescue&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/thunderbolt_3.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Turns out Thunderbolt 3 &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thunderbolt_(interface)#Thunderbolt_3&quot;&gt;might or might not carry DisplayPort 1.4&lt;/a&gt;. Some of them only go as far as DP 1.2. Which one is in your Macbook? Use my diagram:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/thunderbolt.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think we all can agree that this whole Thunderbolt/USB-C situation is a very strong contender for the “Most confusing port standard ever created by humanity”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long story short, I was lucky. My Macbook Pro 2019 had the correct port and with Thunderbolt 3 (USB-C) to DisplayPort adapter, everything worked. My understanding is, port versions on devices matter, but cables and adapters do not, as long as they physically fit into the hole. In my case, it was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mi.com/commutator-dp&quot;&gt;Xiaomi USB-C → miniDP&lt;/a&gt; converter and miniDP → DP cable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/converter.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Will it work for you? No idea! I hope so. All I know is that you should make sure your Thunderbolt 3 can carry DisplayPort 1.4. That’s the magical combination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;things-to-look-out-for-macoscontinued&quot;&gt;Things to look out for (macOS)—continued&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If that was not confusing enough, there’s more!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your Macbook have to have a discrete graphics card (I think).&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Various Intel UHD / Iris Graphics do not work. eGPU works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/graphics.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;But even if you have the compatible Mac, with compatible ports, compatible cables, this is not enough. Every time I boot my Mac, there’s a ritual I have to perform to get my display to switch to the 120 Hz mode. I call it “120 Hz dance”:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fully boot into macOS. At this point display usually is at 60 Hz.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to System Preferences → Displays.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While holding down Alt / Option key (the one with ⌥ on it), click on “Scaled” resolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/settings_1.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get access to Refresh rate chooser, check the “Show low resolution mode” checkbox. L for logic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/settings_2.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look inside “Refresh Rate”. Most of the time the highest option there is “60 Hz”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/settings_3.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turn display off.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wait a couple of seconds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turn the display on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look again under “Refresh Rate”. Hopefully, there’s now a “119.88 Herz” option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/settings_4.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select “119.88 Herz” in “Refresh Rate”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are magnificent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why is it 119.88 Herz, not 120 Herz? No idea. It seems to work the same. Why can’t macOS remember it? I don’t know. Why doesn’t macOS sees 120 Hz as an option until I turn the monitor off/on? Who knows! The main takeaway is, 120 Hz option might not always appear, but after some dancing around it might, and if it does, it actually works, despite all odds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole situation reminds me of buying 4k display in 2014: there are only a couple of models, ports are confusing, Apple support sucks. Hopefully, in five years 120 Hz will become a standard. Until then we should be grateful that, at great inconvenience, we at least can use modern displays with macOS. Thanks, Apple!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every human needs a dream. At some point, 4k @ 120 Hz will become the commodity, and we might even see 5k @ 120 Hz and more. We might also see Retina screens with ratios of 21:9&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and even 32:9 (more horizontal space), which is always a welcome addition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But even today you can peek into the future, if you have extra $4,000 to spare. This is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dell.com/en-us/work/shop/dell-ultrasharp-32-8k-monitor-up3218k/apd/210-alez/monitors-monitor-accessories&quot;&gt;Dell UP3218K&lt;/a&gt;, world’s first and only 8k monitor:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/dell_up3218k.png&quot; /&gt; Even on a promo page for 8k display, Dell puts out only 1× photos of it.
&lt;p&gt;The pixel density on it is so high (280 PPI) it’s probably best used at 300% scaling (which macOS doesn’t have, of course, but Windows does). It also requires TWO simultaneous DisplayPort cables to work, which is again, a no-go for Macs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But even at 300% it will still give you an effective logical resolution of 2560×1440, which is substantially more than 1920×1080 of modern 4k displays. More pixel density and bigger resolution! Well, one can dream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To sum up, this is the best setup for programmers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Text can’t be made look good on low-resolution displays.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;High-PPI displays are now a commodity, it’s time to switch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notebooks are ok, but a standalone monitor is always better.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4k monitor only makes sense with 2× / 200% scaling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you want to go further, there are now affordable 4k @ 120 Hz options.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Happy coding!&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;div class=&quot;about&quot; readability=&quot;8.456043956044&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;about_inner&quot; readability=&quot;12.461538461538&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m Nikita. Here I write about programming and UI design &lt;a class=&quot;btn-subscribe&quot; href=&quot;https://tonsky.me/blog/how-to-subscribe/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also create open-source stuff: Fira Code, AnyBar, DataScript and Rum. If you like what I do and want to get early access to my articles (along with other benefits), you should &lt;a href=&quot;https://patreon.com/tonsky&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;support me on Patreon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 14:40:45 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>neonbones</dc:creator>
<og:title>Time to upgrade your monitor</og:title>
<og:url>https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>A non-comprehensive and opinionated guide to best monitor for programming</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://tonsky.me/blog/monitors/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>BountySource have turned evil – alternatives?</title>
<link>https://diziet.dreamwidth.org/5938.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://diziet.dreamwidth.org/5938.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I need an alternative to BountySource, who have done an evil thing. Please post recommendations in the comments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
From: Ian Jackson &amp;lt;*****&amp;gt;
To: support@bountysource.com
Subject: Re: Update to our Terms of Service
Date: Wed, 17 Jun 2020 16:26:46 +0100

Bountysource writes (&quot;Update to our Terms of Service&quot;):
&amp;gt; You are receiving this email because we are updating the Bountysource Terms of
&amp;gt; Service, effective 1st July 2020.
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt; What's changing?
&amp;gt; We have added a Time-Out clause to the Bounties section of the agreement:
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt; 2.13 Bounty Time-Out.
&amp;gt; If no Solution is accepted within two years after a Bounty is posted, then the
&amp;gt; Bounty will be withdrawn and the amount posted for the Bounty will be retained
&amp;gt; by Bountysource. For Bounties posted before June 30, 2018, the Backer may
&amp;gt; redeploy their Bounty to a new Issue by contacting support@bountysource.com
&amp;gt; before July 1, 2020. If the Backer does not redeploy their Bounty by the
&amp;gt; deadline, the Bounty will be withdrawn and the amount posted for the Bounty
&amp;gt; will be retained by Bountysource.
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt; You can read the full Terms of Service here
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt; What do I need to do?
&amp;gt; If you agree to the new terms, you don't have to do anything.
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt; If you have a bounty posted prior to June 30, 2018 that is not currently being
&amp;gt; solved, email us at support@bountysource.com to redeploy your bounty.  Or, if
&amp;gt; you do not agree with the new terms, please discontinue using Bountysource.

I do not agree to this change to the Terms and Conditions.
Accordingly, I will not post any more bounties on BountySource.

I currently have one outstanding bounty of $200 on
   https://www.bountysource.com/issues/86138921-rfe-add-a-frontend-for-the-rust-programming-language

That was posted in December 2019.  It is not clear now whether that
bounty will be claimed within your 2-year timeout period.

Since I have not accepted the T&amp;amp;C change, please can you confirm that

(i) My bounty will not be retained by BountySource even if no solution
    is accepted by December 2021.

(ii) As a backer, you will permit me to vote on acceptance of that
    bounty should a solution be proposed before then.

I suspect that you intend to rely on the term in the previous T&amp;amp;C
giving you unlimited ability to modify the terms and conditions.  Of
course such a term is an unfair contract term, because if it were
effective it would give you the power to do whatever you like.  So it
is not binding on me.

I look forward to hearing from you by the 8th of July.  If I do not
hear from you I will take the matter up with my credit card company.

Thank you for your attention.

Ian.
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They will try to say &quot;oh it's all governed by US law&quot; but of course section 75 of the Consumer Credit Act makes the card company jointly liable for Bountysource's breach of contract and a UK court will apply UK consumer protection law even to a contract which says it is to be governed by US law - because you can't contract out of consumer protection. So the card company are on the hook and I can use them as a lever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;address&gt;Edited 2020-06-17 16:28 for a typo in Bountysource's email address&lt;/address&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 13:27:56 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pabs3</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://diziet.dreamwidth.org/5938.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>